In this exercise, we are learning how to validate a credit card.
This is a very common validation a developer has to do if a payment gateway is to be implemented.
When it comes to validating a credit card.
There are different companies having different formats.
In this exercise, I'm going to validate a few commonly used companies like MasterCard, Visa, American
Express, Diner's Club, Discover and JCB.
Let's understand each company's format so that we can create a pattern for it.
I will begin with MasterCard.
The number begins with 51 through 55 or 2 to 2, one through two 7 to 0, and the length is 16 digits.
So it begins with a carrot sign.
We will use parentheses as we have to use a pipe sign to apply our condition here.
But at the same time we won't be capturing the group.
So using question mark and Colon, hope you remember the non capturing group concept.
If not, then you can check it again in the respective tutorial.
Now comes 51 to 55.
That is, first digit will be five and second can be any number between one and five.
Next two digits can be any number between 0 to 9.
This will satisfy the first four digits condition for numbers, starting with 51 through 55.
But there can be another situation.
So we will add a pipe sign.
That is the our condition.
Now we think of 2 to 2 one through two 7 to 0.
The number can be triple to and the last digit can be any number between one and nine.
So this will cover numbers like two, 2 to 1 or let's say two, 2 to 8, etc. or it can start with 22
and third digit can be any number between three and nine, and fourth digit can be any number between
zero and nine.
That is two, two, three, five or 2263 or let's say 2 to 4 eight, or it can start with two.
Then the next digit can be between three and six.
That is all numbers between 2320 600, where the last two digits can be any number between zero and
nine.
For example, 23562687 or let's say two, four, five, three, etc. or it can start with 27.
The second digit can be zero or one third digit can be between zero and nine.
So this will cover all numbers between 2700 to 2719.
Now the last number remaining is two 7 to 0.
So we'll add a pipe sign and say two 7 to 0.
So we are done with the first four digit validation as the total length is 16.
For the rest of the 12 digits, it can be any number between zero and nine.
So this is how a master card validation pattern will look like.
Now let's try Visa card validation.
This one is little easier compared to MasterCard.
The card number begins with digit four.
The length can be 13 for old cards and 16 for newer ones.
So we will begin with a carrot and four as it starts with four.
Then next 12 digits can be any number between zero and nine.
That is in the square bracket.
We'll say zero, dash nine and quantifier 12.
So this validates a 13 digit credit card number.
And there can be three or more digits between zero and nine.
And these three can occur zero times or one time.
So we add a question mark for zero or one occurrence of this group, which we don't want to capture.
So the pattern for visa will be something like this.
And this is all for the Visa card validation.
Now let's see.
American Express validation.
As for American Express, the validation is even simpler.
It begins with 34 or 37 and the length is 15 digits.
So I will straightaway show the pattern.
The pattern will be something like this where it begins with a correct sign.
It begins with three.
Now it can be four or seven.
That is 34 or 37.
Then the rest of the 13 digits may have any number between zero and nine.
The next validation we are going to see is for the Diner's Club credit cards.
The validation for Diners Club includes number beginning with 302, 305, 36 or 38.
The length of digits is 14.
There are few who have 16 digits, but they have tied up with MasterCard.
So for those, the validation will be the same as of the MasterCard.
So we will have to just check 302, 305 36 or 38.
That's the beginning and the length should be 14.
So here it begins with a carrot and then we have three for next three digits.
After three there can be zero and numbers between zero and five for validating 300 to 305.
Or there can be a six or eight after three for second digit and any number as the last digit.
And for the rest of the 11 digits, it can be any number between zero and nine.
So the pattern for Diners Club credit card will be like this.
Four JCB cards beginning with 2131 or 1800 are 15 digits long and cards beginning with 35 are 16 digits
long.
So in a non capturing group we will write to 131 or 1800 or 35 and three digits after eight and rest
of the 11 digits will be with quantifier that is curly brackets 11.
So the final pattern for JCB card is like this.
And the last is the Discover Card.
Discover card numbers begin with 601 are 65 and are 16 digits in length as the pattern is simple and
we have seen quite a few combinations.
I just show you the pattern directly.
This is how it looks.
So we are done with various credit card validations.
Now comes a very important point.
We can either apply different patterns with different conditions or we can merge with a single pattern.
This totally depends on the code requirement, but we have seen individual validations so far.
If at all you are willing to merge, then the complete pattern will look like this.
First we'll put MasterCard, then Visa.
Then I will add American Express, Diner's Club or JCB or Discover.
So it alteration with a pipe sign.
We are going to just give all the patterns together.
Or you can try individual patterns in the code which we have seen so far.