So throughout this training,
when you've seen us run things like compile or clean or package,
those have been goals. Goals are actually just plugins
configured in the Maven install.
So you've seen us run things like clean, compile, test, package, the
various install and deploy commands. Those are all basic goals that
are defined find inside the Super POM.
The Super POM has these goals defined in it,
which are then added to your effective POM.
Now this doesn't make much sense to you right now.
Don't worry about it.
That's what we're actually going to cover in this module.
But basically, we can configure all of these plugins inside of
our own project POM to tune and tweak what we want them to do,
and it's fairly common to do so.
A good example of this is the clean plugin. The
clean plugin is a very basic plugin,
but maybe you'll only want it to run during certain phases,
or you want to have it always run.
Say you wanted to force it to run every time you compile.
You could change which phase it's tied to. Right here,
it's tied to the clean phase, but we could tie it to the initial phase.
So goals are always tied to a phase,
and you can see from this example that it is just set for the clean goal and clean phase.