By default, Maven looks for a src/main/java directory underneath our
project. It compiles all of our code to a target directory, and then
it does all this by referencing our defaults and whatever things we've
overridden in our pom.xml file.
If you look at the image of our Hello World application on
the left that we did in our earlier module,
you can see this basic folder structure in place right now.
Our project name was HelloWorld, subsequently that's also our
artifactId. We're going to talk about that more in a minute.
We can also see the src/main/java directory where our HelloWorld.java
file is located at, the target directory and our POM file as well.
Notice the level at which these are too, src, target, and pom file are all at the top level of our application.