Installation with Spring STS Suite and Eclipses very easy.
It doesn't use the registry, so there's nothing really to install.
We just download and unzip a bundle,
and Java and Maven are installed the same way regardless of using the IDE.
So I have to have Java installed, my JAVA_HOME variable set,
and I have to have Maven installed. Some IDEs do
include a bundled version of Maven,
and you can download Spring STS with a bundled version of Maven.
I personally prefer to install it outside of it because it's where
it finds settings in that type of stuff from,
I don't want to have to configure it in multiple places. It can often be
confusing and lead to errors down the road. To download spring STS, we're just going to go to the URL spring.io/tools.