Our src/main/java directory is where we store all of our Java code.
It's also the beginning of our package declaration.
If you've done much with Java, or C# as well,
you'll know that we have a package declaration at the top of our application.
This is the start of our source code directory.
In our previous example,
we were just using the default package, so it stores it right underneath
src/main/java. But, if we use a package, which you ultimately should, it would
build that folder structure underneath this directory.
What about other languages?
Say we're using Groovy or Scala or Kotlin, or another tool like that,
or that we're generating some web services? We can actually set it up
to use the src/main/groovy or src/main/resources folder, or other
folder structures underneath that. When we talk more about plugins in
a later module,
you'll learn that this is how we keep that code separate or how
we use those different plugins to access the different types of
source code that we're dealing with.
What about testing?
You actually set up a src/test/java directory.
You want to do this for two reasons.
You can keep test code separate from production code,
but we can have them reference the same package structure.
We'll show an example of how this is done down the road, but suffice
it to say, you put all of your test code under src/test/java and all
of your source code under src/main/java.
One thing that's worth mentioning is that src/test/java directory is
specifically for unit tests and not necessarily for things like
integration tests or other types of testing, black box,
white box, etc. It's an automated test, but specifically just for unit tests.