Importing an existing Maven project is really quite easy.
Spring STS or Eclipse has a Maven integration built directly into it.
The integration will allow us to execute the default Maven goals within
our IDE. IDE configuration and the classpath will also be set from our
Maven POM file. To import a project, all we have to do is locate that
project on our disk, right‑click in the Package Explorer, import Maven
and existing Maven projects, and it will show a pop‑up similar to this
where we can say that we want to choose that existing Maven project.
This will go ahead and import all of our source
code and set our classpath for us. Let's go ahead and look at doing that right now.