The JAR plugin is used to package our code into a JAR file,
and it's pretty straightforward as far as its configuration's concern.
Its output result is going to make a JAR,
and it's usually tied to the package phase of our build lifecycle.
Now the Configuration section will allow us to do a couple of things,
but nothing too extravagant here. We can change the includes and
excludes, so if you want to only package certain things inside your
JAR, like maybe you don't want generated source code in there or
you want to include XML files, you can specify what you want in that section.
It will also build our manifest for us.
An example of this is that I can define a plugin in the Configuration
section, tell it to use the default manifest that it can generate, so it
will take our build and make our manifest file for us and package up our application into a JAR automatically.