Now that we've seen some of the goals that we can add to our application,
let's go ahead and change a few things inside of our project.
First, I'm going to go ahead and right‑click on our project,
and go down to Configure, and Convert this to a Maven Project.
It will download a few things for a second,
and set up the structure of our project very similar to what we had before,
but showing it in a different view,
and I'll explain what I mean here in just a second.
I'm going to open up my pom.xml,
and you'll notice that we don't have a dependency section in here yet.
So I'm going to go ahead and give me a little white space between
packaging and the build section that we added,
and add dependencies.
Now one of the reasons I wanted to convert this to a Maven project is it
gets smarter with these suggestions that we add in here.
So I'm going to add our dependency section,
and then I'm going to add a dependency, singular,
inside that section.
And we start off with the three things that we always need,
a groupId, and for our groupId, we want to do org.apache.commons,
And then for our artifactId, we want to add in here commons‑lang3.
Now,
some people get hung up on why there is a number in this particular dependency,
and it's because they have different versions of this code base,
and then they have releases of that code base.
So this is specifically for lang3.
Now the next thing we're going to add in here and the last thing is our version,
and we're looking for 3.8.1.
Now when I click Save,
you're going to see a couple things maybe flash on the screen.
What happens is it will go through,
and it's building my workspace and downloading some dependencies,
and I'm going to show you over here on our left‑hand side,
we now have a Maven Dependencies source folder over here,
and we have commons‑lang3 added to our class path.
So let's automatically pull that down and set it up to build
our application based off that class path.
Let's look and see what this does for our goals off in the command line.
I've gone ahead and gone to the route of our application,
C:\dev\workspace\HelloWorld, and I'm going to type in here maven clean.
We ran this once before,
so it's not going to go ahead and download a bunch of dependencies
like it did before the first time we ran it.
We'll do maven compile,
and this will compile our source code, and we actually haven't changed our
source code, we just added things to our class path.
We could go utilize the Commons library to do something inside
of our source code, but you get the idea here. And then I'm
going to run a new one for you, maven Install.
Now before I click Enter here, I want to point out to you two things.
It's going to go ahead and download all the dependencies that it needs,
package up the application, and then install it in our local repository.
So when I click Enter here,
you'll see it download some dependencies, and we'll go through
and run any tests that we have inside of our application, and
package it up, and then install it.
And if you look at the text,
you can see that it says it's installing
C:\dev\workspace\HelloWorld\target\HelloWorld‑1.0‑SNAPSHOT.jar to this location on
my hard drive.
So everything there in that info section, it can tell you it's doing there.
And if you look and compare that to what we had before,
this is everything that we had specified for our project structure.
We had our groupId of com.pluralsight, our artifact of HelloWorld,
and our version 1.0‑SNAPSHOT, and that's exactly where it installed
it to our local repository,
com.pluralsight\HelloWorld\1.0‑SNAPSHOT, and then the artifactId.
So you're starting to see how it organizes these things in
your local workspace. I want to go a step further though and
pull up my M2 repository directory.
So I'm going to move this out of the way, and I want to go to my
user directory, so we're going to go to C:\Users,
Bryan,, and you'll see this M2 directory.
This is the Maven home. Inside of here, you'll see repository, and
you'll see com, Pluralsight, HelloWorld, our 1.0‑SNAPSHOT, and here
is our artifact that it uploaded for us.
So here's everything from the beginning of us running
that project to running install,
it went through and built this folder structure based off of our
groupId, artifactId, packaging type, and version.
So we have all of our application ran through that configuration and installed based off those POM properties.