The Source Plugin can often be confusing to people because they think it's
doing more than what it actually does for our application.
All it does is package up our source code for us so that we can
distribute it for context‑sensitive help inside of our IDE or to
make some more code‑intensive javadocs.
It's, by default,
also tied to the package phase just like we saw with the JAR Plugin, and
it's frequently even overridden to a later phase than that.
If you're running package a lot and you don't want to sit there and wait for it,
people will just tie it to the install phase or even the deploy
phase just because it's slowing their build down.
If you remember the verify phase,
it's run right before the install and deploy phase. We're going
to walk through an example of altering this plugin to tie it to
a later phase, and in an upcoming demo, we'll do the same thing with the Javadoc Plugin.