To configure the Source Plugin, we're going to just go down in our
plugin section again and add another plugin.
We're going to add this plugin here.
It's another one from org.apache.maven.plugins.
It's the maven‑source‑plugin. The version is 3.1.0, and then
the execution section is where it gets interesting.
As I mentioned before, we were going to tie this to a later phase.
And so we went ahead and added an execution section and a
specific execution inside of there that's tied to the
jar and the install.
So this is one of the latest phases that we could tie it to.
Now I'm going to go ahead and open up our command
line again and do a mvn install, and it will go through,
download anything it needs to, compile the source code,
and then it will build out the jar and the sources.jar to our target directory.
So if we cd to target and do a dir,
you'll see that we now have two jar files in here.
We have our sources.jar and our artifact that we're trying to create.
So it went ahead and created that and pushed it to a later
phase inside of our build lifecycle, and this is what it looked like to configure that.