Hi, everyone.
My name is Bryan Hansen, and welcome to my course, Maven Fundamentals.
I'm the Director of Development at Software Technology
Group and a long‑time Pluralsight author.
The original version of this course was the first course I ever produced for
Pluralsight, and it's still one of my favorite topics to teach.
It was time to update it, though,
to use more recent versions of Maven and also to take
advantage of newer versions of Java.
In this course,
we're going to learn about the changes introduced by
utilizing more recent versions of Java.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include Maven installation,
transitive dependencies, building using Java 11 or newer,
using Maven with existing code,
and other exciting changes that have occurred with
more recent versions of Maven.
By the end of this course,
you'll know how to use Maven in your day to day programming and what
changes were needed to use it with newer versions of Java.
Although not required,
some experience with Java is helpful prior to learning Maven. I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn about Maven Fundamentals.