Dependencies are actually more easily added in the IDE.
In fact, this is one huge benefit to using your IDE.
The Dependencies tab will show us which dependencies we have installed
and allow us to manipulate those dependencies as well.
The Dependency Management section that's also on
this tab is a more advanced topic,
and it's only used if you're using a parent POM,
which is definitely an advanced topic and something
we're not going to cover in this course.
The Add screen has searching capability,
which we're going to cover in a demo now,
which really makes it a nice feature.
We can just go ahead and type in any portion of it,
and it will give us a drop‑down to which we can choose which version we want and have that added to our project for us.