The Dependencies viewer tab inside of your IDE is a lot easier
way to add functionality to your project.
So one of the tabs down below here is Dependencies,
if we click on it and select Add,
I can go to the search box here and just type in JUnit,
for example.
Now one downside is you do have to know which version of
JUnit and which library you're looking for.
I happen to know that we do want the JUnit Jupyter engine,
but I can select that and click OK.
Now if I click the pom.xml tab,
you'll see that it's added a dependency section inside of my pom,
and it has our artifact there.
Likewise, I can go ahead and edit this, and hand key in a dependency.
So let's just add another dependency inside of here.
We'll give it a groupId of org.springframework, and an artifactId of
spring‑core, and then we can give it a version.
You're quickly seeing that this is a lot harder because I have to know all of
this information. So we can say 5.1.2.RELEASE, and I'll be totally honest
with you, I had to remember if it was .RELEASE, or .FINAL, or how their
naming conventions were to signify that this was the final version of this
code while I was doing this example.
So when I say this,
it'll go out and download any of those dependencies, but you can
see over in my Maven Dependencies section now that I have
spring‑core, spring‑jcl, junit‑jupyter, all of that stuff over
here in my Maven Dependencies section.
And if I switch back to my Dependencies tab,
they both show up there. Now one other really cool feature of this
is that I can select that JUnit dependency that we added, and click
Properties, and I can change the Scope.
So one of things I wanted to do was only have that available as test scope,
select test, and click.
OK. I don't have to go in there and remember the exact XML to have
that configured to only be visible during test.
So it's a lot easier to manage those dependencies through that Dependencies tab,
especially if you're new to Maven, and adding those, and you don't
understand the XML very well, or you're trying to look at which version of that library you want to select.