To demonstrate how we can override the default naming convention of
our application, I'm going to go ahead and open up our pom.xml file
again, go into the build section,
and I'm going to override the final name of our application to foo.jar.
So if I save this file, come out to our command line, and run mvn package,
it will go through and build our application,
and the final artifact will be named foo.jar. And you can see
that it already put that out in the output.
But let's go ahead and navigate into our target directory. When I go into
target and do a DIR, you'll see that we have foo.jar here. Just so we
don't leave that out there as foo.jar, let's come in here and delete that
line back out and run it again.
You've got to be up at your project not down in the target
directory. And it'll build our application, and it will build
it with HelloWorld‑1.0‑SNAPSHOT.
Now I want to show you two things here.
If I cd back into our target directory and do a DIR again, because
I did not run clean, I have both foo.jar and
HelloWorld‑1.0‑SNAPSHOT.jar both in my target directory.
So if you're making changes like that,
you probably want to run a mvn clean and then a mvn package and have that
delete that target directory and recreate your application.
So now when we go back into target, we'll only have our HelloWorld‑1.0‑SNAPSHOT.jar.