Repositories are, very simply,
just an HTTP‑accessible location that we can download files from.
Very often they don't have any security wrapped around them,
although for your internal repository you can definitely add it.
Our default location is defined in the file or the super pom.xml.
We've mentioned this before previously. The Super POM is
located inside of our Maven installation.
Generally, you don't need to go into it, the Super POM that is. In fact,
I'll go out on a limb and say you should never really edit the Super
POM because there's other ways to override it.
Either go through a global parent project file or
through your own project's pom.xml.
So don't edit the one that comes with the default Maven installation.
The default location that it's pointing to is repo.maven.apache.org.
This has 95% of what you'll ever want to download,
but it's that extra 5% that we're going to focus on now,
because it's actually a very important part.
The Maven repo that's out there by default has all of the open source projects.
You're never going to upload your company's internal resource
libraries to repo.maven.apache.org, because you probably don't
want other people using that. We should note that multiple
repositories are allowed and, in fact, often encouraged.
You'll have a case where you'll have to download
things from more than one repository,
and that's fine, it's a common practice. To do so, we
can use a corporate repository.
A corporate repository is definitely outside the scope of this course,
but you are encouraged to use one,
though. A few years ago when Maven was getting really popular,
nobody was using a corporate repo yet. Developers actually caused a
denial‑of‑service attack on the main repo.maven.apache.org site.
Two of the most common ones out there are Nexus, that's actually what's
backing repo.maven.apache.org, and there's another one that is almost used is
equally in some other projects called Artifactory.
If I were starting from scratch,
I would probably tell you to look at the Nexus repository,
but Artifactory works well. I've used both on projects and been happy with both of them.