A dependency repository is exactly what it sounds like, it's
where we download all of our dependencies from. It can contain
releases or snapshots or both, for that matter,
but it's not uncommon to have them in separate repositories.
It's very easy for us to define our dependency repository.
It's just a snippet of XML in the repository section of our POM.
Here is an example of that code.
It has to have an id, and in this example,
we're using spring‑snapshot, and generally we want to give it a name,
although it's not required.
But just so it's more descriptive we'll use Spring Maven SNAPSHOT
Repository for our example, and then the URL to our repository.
Now usually organizations are pretty good about labeling
their repository as a snapshot repository,
and you can see on the end of this URL here, libs‑snapshot.
You'll also notice that in this one we have snapshots
enabled to true and releases enabled to false.
If we were going to enable people to download both
snapshots and releases from this repository,
that would just say releases enabled true, pretty straightforward.
Like I said,
you can have multiple repos and it would be another element inside the
repository's element to just define a separate one for releases versus
snapshots. Let's take a look at a demo of how we can download an artifact from that repository.