To demonstrate showing you repositories,
I want to begin by showing you Spring's repo for snapshots.
So we're going to start off by opening up a browser and
going to repo.spring.io/libs‑snapshot/.
This will pull up a repository, and you'll quickly see they're a basic website.
There's nothing really that exciting about it.
I'm going to navigate all the way down to org,
which is about halfway down this page here,
and we're going to use the groupId of our artifact to
navigate into our Spring core artifact.
So if we go to org, and then this will pull up another page,
and we'll go to the Spring Framework,
and I'm actually going to use these search on this page to find it quicker.
Now notice before I click on here that there are three springframeworks here,
and this is another thing I wanted to point out.
Notice the misspellings.
There's springframeWork with a capital W,
springFramework with a capital F, and then all lowercase springframework.
One of the bad things about artifacts, and it's a good thing and a bad thing,
is that once we've created them, they're really not supposed to be deleted.
And so these misspellings of springframeWork with a capital
W and springFramework with a capital F,
we should leave there for anything we build the future.
Now this is a snapshot repository, so we really probably don't care,
but that's why there are three renditions of that spelling.
Let's click on springframework.
Inside of here, we can scroll down and we'll find spring‑core.
If I click on spring‑core, and scroll down to the bottom,
you'll see 5.2.0.BUILD‑SNAPSHOT.
Now, when I click on this,
you're going to see something that you maybe weren't expecting. Inside of here,
there is not a file called BUILD‑SNAPSHOT.
This is where I said the meaning of snapshot has an
extra special something behind it.
Maven knows to go look for the latest timestamp or
increment inside that directory.
So when we give it a groupId of org/springframework and an artifactId
of spring‑core, and a version of whatever‑snapshot,
it goes and looks in that directory for the most
recent code there, every time we build.
So if you do this with other files,
if I back up a directory here and I go to one that's
not listed as a snapshot anymore,
the code inside of here will have specific build numbers on there.
So if I go inside of this RC1, well,
this RC1 doesn't handle the same way snapshots are handled,
and so inside of this directory,
we just have RC1; we don't have these timestamped files.
So you kind of get an idea of what that snapshot is doing.
Inside of there, it has a BUILD‑ year, month,
day, dot hour, minute, second, dash their build number.
So there's been 402 builds of 5.2.0,
and you get to see the timestamp that this was done on May 30th.
So this is how snapshots work inside of Maven.
Now, let's go demonstrate this inside of our project.
I'm going to go ahead and switch to our IDE,
and inside of our IDE, I want to add that dependency,
and I'm going to start off by saying dependency,
and give it a groupId of org.springframework,
and then an artifactId of spring‑core,
and then our version is going to be 5.2.0.BUILD in all uppercase,
SNAPSHOT, and save this.
Now you'll notice, we immediately got a red error.
You can see on line 33, we've got a red X,
and the reason why is this is a snapshot,
and we haven't pulled in that repository.
So we're going to do two things here.
We're going to add a repository that goes ahead and
allows us to download snapshots,
because the main repo doesn't allow you to pull down snapshots.
Now to download that dependency, because you can see we have that red X again.
I need to add another repository,
and I'm going to go down between my dependency's closing element and
my opening build element and say repositories,
and inside of this element, I have to give it the singular repository element.
And in here I've got to give it an id, and for the id,
I'll just do spring‑snapshot, and really,
the id is important to you; it's not important to Maven,
going out and pulling that down.
The next thing we need to add is the URL,
and I've gone ahead and grabbed that URL from our browser,
and its http://repo.spring.io/libs‑snapshot.
And before we close this out, I want to restrict this just to snapshots.
So I'm going to say snapshots enabled, and for sake of screen real estate,
I'm going to do this on the same line,
and then I'm going to create a new line that says releases,
enabled, and false.
So this going to to restrict this to just snapshots.
Now, I want to point out before I save this,
it's going to automatically download that and adjust my project
and will get rid of that red X on line 33.
So I'm going to hit Ctrl+S and save it, and it's already building my application.
You'll notice the red X went away.
Okay, did it actually download it, though?
Well,
we can go check that by going up to our Maven dependencies,
opening it up, and if we scroll down,
you'll see spring‑core 5.2.0.BUILD‑SNAPSHOT.jar, and you'll
notice its path is pointing to our hard drive.
You see the path exactly to where that file is stored.
So if you wanted to go out there and verify it,
you can actually navigate to that in your File Explorer, and see
that it did in fact exist at that location.
So pretty simple.
We showed you that HTTP sites for repositories are just that.
They're very simple websites that a dependency with a snapshot
will not build, because most people don't upload their
snapshots to the central Maven repo.
And to add a repository,
we can go ahead and just add a repositories element below our closing
dependencies tag, but before our build tag, and add a single repository
for snapshots and restrict it to just a snapshot release and no other
final releases from that repository. Really simple to do, but a good way
for you go download code that's possibly under development by a library that you're using.