In this module we went through a bunch of the nuances with dependencies and
we started looking at particular things like versions and that version
numbers are really up to your corporate strategy.
If you have a 1.0 release or a 1.0.0 you can name it final or release,
it really doesn't matter.
We had that hibernate example that was using final in their
own unique way. The only one that has a unique meaning on
the naming convention really,
truthfully, is SNAPSHOT. SNAPSHOTS are always good to force you
to download the latest version of the code,
which is great if you're doing development and things are very volatile and
you want to always be checking for the latest source code.
You never want to go to production with any SNAPSHOTS in your application.
We also looked at supported types and what they mean to your application.
And 99% of the time you're probably just going to be using a jar
dependency, but other than that what's very unique and kind of
interesting is the POM dependency to where you can create a POM file that
will be pulled in with all of the dependencies listed in it and use those
inside of your application.
We saw that POM dependency when we pulled in JUnit,
and it pulled in two other POMs that had all the dependencies listed there.
We also looked at transitive dependencies and how they are downloading. And
the demo we saw that if we pulled down hibernate it would pull all of the
transitive dependencies of hibernate down for us.
In fact, there was even a conflict in there,
and you can see that it resolved and looked for the newest version, which is
generally what we want to do inside of our application.
We also looked at scopes and how they allow us to compile our test code,
but not include artifacts that shouldn't be packaged in our final resource.
So when we include JUnit inside of our application,
we can mark it as test scope,
which is one of the most common ones that we typically scope, and it wouldn't be packaged into our final resource.