Hello and welcome back to the course on power be-I.
In today's tutorial is starting a brand new section and we're talking about maps.
Scatterplot and interactive b i reports it's going to be an exciting couple of tutorials.
So let's get straight to it.
As usual we're going to need a browser and we're going to need to go to w w w dot superdad assigns dot
com slash power be-I.
And if you scroll down here to section for maps and scatterplot you'll see the data set.
So just go ahead and download that.
And in the meantime the comments says that teched Excel file has two tabs you will need to join the
two tables in power.
Interesting so we're going to learn a new technique as well about joining data sets.
All right so the file has been downloaded.
And let's go ahead and open it up in Excel.
There we go.
So here we've got our first stab and it's got Order ID order date the customer name so the person who
placed the order.
The city county region where the order was placed the segment what kind of segment in our company does
that has that order being placed within the shipping date the shipping mode the state of the country
in which the order was placed.
And so then we got the long issue and the latitude of the city of that specific location and then order
breakdown the order breakdown has the breakdown of those orders so sometimes orders can include more
than one more than one item.
So in this order let's have a look.
So we've got a look here so we've got here an order that has two items so the order is the same.
But then there's two items within this order and you can see the product name the discount the sales
the profit the quantity the office the category and the subcarriers.
So that's very interesting here we've got information about the order and where it went who placed it
and so on.
But then the actual sales and profit information is provided on an item level.
And there might be multiple items in order so that's what it meant.
So that's what we mean when we need to only say that we need to join the two tables we need to actually
combine these two tables.
So if you look at this table it has if it goes to the bottom by pressing QUANTRILL down it has four
thousand 118 rows or minus one with the header and this table actually has 8000 rows so there are many
more rows in the second table.
We're going to need to find a way to combine them.
So let's go ahead and get started.
Let's put this data into power be-I we're going to say that.
All right so now I'm going to bring up power be-I And here we're going to hit a click or click and get
data.
It is an excel file.
So let's go find it.
There it is.
And here once it loads you'll see that you have two options.
These are the two tabs that we have the list of orders and the order breakdown.
Now you can select either one which you want to import but in our case we want to import both.
So we're going to select both metrically Kloed give it a second to load.
There we go.
And now we've got two separate tabs or two separate expandable menus here.
And now what happened.
Did they get connected somehow.
How are they.
How do these two data sources interact.
Well to see that we need to go not to this tab not the data tab because the data table tell you how
they are presented the structure of each one one by one but we need to go to this last tab with the
relationships tab.
And here you will see the two data sources that we have and how they are connected.
So this is the first one.
The second one.
And then if you click on this connection if you just double click it you'll see that we've got EDID
relationship here and this is kind of like an advance view of what's going on.
It's many Tujuan and Crossfield so we don't want to really get into into this right down what we want
to do is actually want to just once you've selected the relationship click manage relationships and
this is a much simpler approach and you can see right away how they're connected.
So here you've got the connection specified so the table on the left is order breakdown and then the
column that is being taken is order ID and it has been this table is being connected to this call.
Also on the order ID column and that is correct so we know that the Order ID is a shared column called.
And so you can.
The way you can adjust is if you ever need to can detect.
Right.
If you've updated the tables and or changed something and then it can pick up some relationships.
You can create new relationships right.
So here you can select your table that you want the information to come from.
So we're back at that menu again.
So here you select the column that you want.
Then the second table and then again the second the column that you want and then the type of a relationship.
So one to many one to one or many to one.
I know this is a bit of a complex.
This might seem a bit complex but these are basically left joins inner joins and writes joins.
So the one over here on the left would be a left join.
This is an inner join in this or right join.
I know these things don't make a lot of sense right now but what are we going to do is we're going to
just leave it as it is for now.
So we're just going to leave this relationship as it is because it's been detected correctly and then
in the next three tutorials you will find information on joint information on the joints.
I'm going to include it as an expert with turtles or they might be somewhere else in the course or as
bonus tutorials but you see them there'll be tutorials basically about understanding left or right inner
and outer joins a tutorial on the joins with duplicate values and a tutorial on joining on multiple
fields so after those two journals you'll know everything about Joines if you haven't studied them before
if you know already then feel free to skip those patrols.
But if you'd like to refresh your knowledge or learn more about joins then there will be three very
in-depth tutorials about Joines that explain how all of these things work.
But for now all we need to know is that we've got this table with the order ideas and it's been connected
to this table with the information here what information on the orders.
Here we've got information on the items within those orders.
And then after you've checked out the Joines you can come and have a look at this information and like
I'll give you a heads up right now that this is this is a correct joint so that the joint has been done
correctly.
And one is that well because we remember that in this table we have about 8000 records in this table
have 4000.
So here we do have duplicate values.
So therefore the relationship should be many to 1 so multiple records from here should be joined to
records from here.
And that is exactly what we need because there can be duplicate records here so basically arose from
this table should be duplicated in order to match these.
I know it's a bit complex right now but after you've had a look at the joints turtles it will all make
total sense.
All right so that is how our joint is performed.
And basically from here we can proceed to working on our visualization.
I hope you enjoyed this tutorial and you were able to follow along.
And I look for see you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.