Hello and welcome back.
And today we're talking about types of joins now joins operations that are performed on tables in relational
databases.
So you would perform them in as well Microsoft as well in Oracle and Maya skill in many different platforms
where the data is stored in a structured format.
So let's have a look at some Joines and understand how exactly they work to start off with.
Let's assume that we have two tables table A and Table B.
And in our example table A will have the following rows.
It's got three columns.
Customer gender and age.
And it's basically a table that is describing our customers.
So we've got five customers.
Adam Benjamin Jack Niek And Susan we've got their genders listed and their ages.
Now if we go to Table B it's a table of employees of a certain store of our store basically.
So it's got the employee name the title and the wage.
And so what are we going to try and do and we're going to try and find out which of our customers are
also our employees so basically where where do we have matching roles in these two tables and how are
we going to do that.
Well basically if we look at the tables we can see right away that Jack and Susan both appear in the
customer and in the employee tables.
So how do we do this from an skill perspective for basically from a jointing perspective.
Well if we start off with an inner join then let's have a look at how it will work.
An inner join will take the two tables and it will look at only their intersect so basically if we're
joining our tables on customer equals employee then and it's an inner join.
Then the remaining rows will only be the matching rows.
So in this case Jack is matched with Jack and Susan is matched with Susan because we're just looking
at the customer column in the left table and at the employee column and the right table.
So once that matching is done the rest of the rows which haven't matched are discarded and the remaining
table looks like this.
So it only has those rows that match and kind of glues them together and that's it.
That's what's the result of an inner join on these two tables would look like.
Now let's have a look at the left join.
So there's a few different types of joins.
Now we're going to proceed to the next one was called a left outer join and in short it can also be
called the left join.
So Elif joined basically says that the primary table is the one on the left.
Once again we're joining on the first column of the first table customer equals to the first column
or the second table which is in play.
And since the Left table is a primary one rows cannot be discarded from the left table rows will only
be discarded from the non-primary table so here Jack is mashed with Jack.
Susan is matched with Susan again.
And then the rest of the rows in the second table are discarded because they didn't have a match and
so the resulting table will look like this where there was a match.
The rows are glued together.
And where there was no match the associated columns left blank or some in scale basically those columns
will be nolde.
So let's just keep them blank for now.
That's whole left join works.
And basically the main idea here is that the table in the left of the join is considered to be the primary
table and therefore rows cannot be discarded from the table.
Now let's have a look at the right join a right join works in a very similar way but on this in this
case the table on the right is the primary table.
So once again Jack has much to Jack Susan is much to Susan and the rest of the rows in the left table
are discarded because it is the secondary table it's not the primary rows in the primary table.
On the other hand cannot be discarded.
So the final result here is a table which looks like this.
Once again the two sets of columns have been glued together and where there was no match on the left.
The values in the columns are left blank or Lord.
And finally let's have a look at a full outer join.
So in a full outer join we're looking at the union of the two tables or pillar probably unions not the
right word.
We're looking at all of the rows in the two tables and that's why you see those two circles in the Venn
diagram up at the top of full the yellow.
And that means that we cannot discard or the join will not discard any of the rows in any of the two
tables.
Once again we're looking for matches So Jack is matched with Jack.
Susan is matched with Susan.
And then what happens is no rows are discarded and the tables are glued together.
And that is what the final result looks like.
So on the right there is blank spaces where there was no match to the table on the left and on the left
there is blank spaces where there was no match to the table on the right.
So once again I'll just go back to the previous slide and here you'll see the two table separately and
now off to the join.
This is what the final table will look like.
So that's how a full outer join works.
And now let's just quickly recap on the types of drawings that we discussed.
So we had a look at four different joins the inner join which only looks at the matching rows.
The Left join which keeps the left the table on the left as a primary table the right join which keeps
the table in the right as the primary table and the full join or the full outer join which does not
discard and euros from any of the tables.
So in your work you're probably going to be using inner joins and left joins mostly.
And that is because right joins are rarely used simply because are-I join is the same as a left join
just the tables you just have to switch the tables around.
So put the one on the right on the left and the one that was on the left on the right and you'll get
a left join.
And again so most of the time all personnel use inner joins and left joins.
Sometimes you'll rarely find that people do require full Jones for the task at hand.
So those were the type of joins.
And that brings us to the conclusion of today's tutorial.
Loquats see you next time.