Hello and welcome back to the course on par be-I imperious tutorial we talked about aggregation going
and granularity we created this wonderful chart.
And today we're going to learn how to convert a chart a line chart into an area chart.
All right.
So first things first let's replace a gender now with age because that's a parameter or a column that
we're going to be interested in more.
So let's take a page and replace it over here and put it on top of the gender.
And now we've got all these lines so we've got the separate lines for the separate different categories.
In our age and now all we need to do to replace this chart with a chart is actually just select area
chart over here.
In fact the one we need is a stacked area.
And you'll notice that in both of these cases we get kind of like a bit of a jibberish visualisation
right now.
And I think that this is another bug of Parvi I might be wrong again but this software is really
being developed very rapidly these days so probably by the time you're watching this video you won't
have this problem it'll be working right away but if you still do it's not not a big deal we're going
to just restart oversouls and hopefully that will fix this problem of how the charge is being presented.
So forgive me for this.
We are doing a great job developing and great software and yes bugs happen sometimes so let's close
this week and save changes and let's go and find our position.
So here is Section 3.
And there we go.
So as we can see that didn't really fix the problem.
All right so what are we going to try.
We're going to try to recreate this top part.
We're going take period and drag it back into the access.
And as you can see it all is working OK.
So maybe you don't have to restart your resolution but something like that just replacing one of the
columns or recreating it was positioned while you've got the Richardo chart or sector which are selected
might fix the issue.
And again I think it's a bug might be mistaken there but hopefully that's something that will be looked
into in the future.
So now if we drill down there we go.
That's obvious.
It looks wonderful.
Now the difference between the two area chart and Richard is it's quite straightforward actually.
So here the area charts are behind each other and therefore it's there it looks cluttered right so when
I look at the y axis here it's up to 1.8 million.
If you do a stacked area chart the wax is now up to eight million.
So this the at the top level is actually the total represents the total unemployment for all of these.
And this looks much much better.
There we go.
So that's our stacked area chart.
One other thing I wanted to show you is a way you can investigate your visualization and you can use
this come a legend to actually highlight things.
If you select on individual elements you'll see that they are highlighted.
So it's not probably as prominent but depending on the color you can actually see see better.
You can see the other ones fade outs a bit.
But this one stays the same.
And this can be useful in some physicians or even in this one to actually highlight and bring the users
of your attention to something so you might want to be you might be talking about just this age group
and you want to highlight it so you just click that.
And that way this age group is highlighted.
All right so there we go.
That's how we create an area chart in part B I hope you enjoyed this tutorial and I'll look for see
you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.