Hello and welcome back to the course on par be-I in the first tutorial we created this counterplot.
And today we're going to learn how to apply filters across multiple sheets as well as how to combine
sheets into how to combine charts into one sheet onto one page.
All right.
So let's get started.
So here we've got one chart on this page and we've got another chart on this page.
And let's say we want to apply a filter that will that should work across both of them so filter that
should restrict the amount of rows going into this chart the same way as it restricts them on Roeske
going to this drug.
And so how do we normally apply that.
Well we click on the charts and then we scroll down.
We look at the visual level filters we add filtering to here.
So let's say our filter is going to be by order date right.
And then we just added in to here and that way we would be able to select the dates which we want we
could go on bonspiel like date.
But as you can tell it says visual liberal filters so it's just a filter for this is zation.
It won't affect any other viz..
So again to cancel that and what we actually want to do is we want to apply a filter to either the page
level filters so that if it's like that will affect everything on this page or even a reportable filter
and that's the filter that will affect everything or all of the charts and all of the pages in this
power be-I report or workbook.
And so that's how we're going to do it.
And for in order to create that filter you don't even have to click on the chart itself.
You can just click somewhere on this whitespace.
And as you can see you still have the page little filters and the report filters which makes sense as
a let's go ahead and drag order data into Ruport little filters.
And what we'll do here is here we'll just change to start filtering and let's say we want we only want
items from 2011 right.
So in our dataset we put quite a lot of years.
So we want items from 2011 and will say so it starts is on or after and here will say 2016.
So just click on that.
Which 2011 January 2011 first of June 2011 midnight.
And so then will keep this on condition and then we'll say is on or before I will say click here again
2011 December 1st here we wanted 11:59 p.m..
Just this just make sure it's still December the first Sematary first 11:59 p.m. so on or before and
then reapply.
So you can see our dataset here has changed.
And if we go here.
So has this data changed as well.
Well how would we check that.
Well let's just delete the filter or let's remove the clear the filter so you can see it is more dots
more points and it pre-press contrails are now turn the filter back.
You can see that it does apply.
So basically this filter is now being applied to everything across all of our data sets and it's kind
of like in other tools such as Tablo you would considered it kind of like a data source filter and basically
filters all of the data that comes onto your report.
So basically all the pages and there's no chance for data to go through that filter if it's not supposed
to.
And you will never see those rows in your visualizations.
But as you probably noticed this whole process of applying a filter especially a data filter is quite
tedious because you have to select the data and there's it's not as user friendly as you would imagine
as you would expect it to be.
And the reason for that is that in power be-I filters are not that not that commonly used.
Right so sometimes you would use them but there are better ways to apply these restrictions on your
data than just to use these report level filters or paysan old filters or even viz. little filters and
just that's just stems from the type of tool par be-I is and the way it's been created and the intention
behind it.
And we've actually already looked at one of these examples when we were creating slicers and that's
exactly what we're going to do.
Now again we're going to use the slicer but this time we're going to put both of these charts onto one
page.
So let's go ahead and create your page and this is going to be quite interesting and even exciting to
put these chairs together and how easy compared to other tools such as tabouli you'll see that this
is a very quick and intuitive way of creating this dashboard.
And one of the advantages of RBI.
So I'm going to select this chart and then press conference on my keyboard to copy and paste it into
here.
And reduce the size.
Now let's go to page 2 click here.
Copy paste again reduce the size I the ink like this.
So let's give it some room.
OK so there we go.
And maybe this one is all right now what do we want to do next is what we want to do is add a slicer
here.
Right.
So I'm going to actually I'm going to remove this filter or.
Because we're going to recreate it in another way.
And here I'm going to click on the whitespace and add a slicer.
And now I'm just going to add this order date into our slicer and there it is.
That's s as simple as it gets and now we want just the 2011 year which drags back.
So do them and just change changes to that.
So we can actually select it here.
There we go.
So as simple as that.
And that's all we had to do and as you can see this has been applied to both of these charts at same
time.
Very very straightforward very easy to use very user friendly and that's what I mean when I say that
filters are not that commonly used in some cases they are but it's much easier just to add a slicer
especially if you can put these two charts onto the same page and that is often the case because you're
building a combined combined viz. that you want to analyze together on one page or at the same time
and it's the fastest way to proceed is actually put on the same page.
And now just for fun this out another slicer so click on the whitespace click the slicer.
And in this case let's add region.
So this is a different three different regions of the house or central as you can see that's central
Europe North Europe and then South Europe.
It's so critical slicer.
Now what we can do as well is we can go to formats and then in general orientation changes are too horizontal.
So it actually looks like control buttons.
And then we go and you can actually remove the header from here and then on your position it will look
like control buttons and you can just set set them like that as you can see the desolations moving around.
So it's OK that your scatterplot is moving around that's.
Or maybe that's also a problem.
But let's start with the weasel's.
So how would we fix it.
How do we not let it move around.
We'll just go to format and then go to map controls and then select all of them.
And now when you change the scatterplot of the sun going to zoom in so that's quite powerful.
And this try the same thing for our scatterplot here we're going to need to go to the x axis and we're
going to have to fix it at a certain level so in this case we're going to have to fix it at sixteen
thousand and then we're going to have to do the same for the y axis.
But here we're going to have to make sure that we've got a minimum at a maximum so minus four to a maximal
force over 6000.
So minus 4000 and you've got to type quickly so if you start tapping the minus slowly it will disappear
to type in minus 4000 very quickly and then and is at 6000.
And there we go.
So now when you select your different regions or even the scatterplot doesn't change.
And as you can see it looks pretty amazing this was going on here.
Looks like these circles are moving around and then you can unselect and the number of circle increases.
This is a very powerful resolution already.
Again you can change the date range if you like increasing number of customers number of orders in your
data.
And then just quickly control it like that.
So as you can see very very intuitive and also very very powerful missiles nation that we've created
already.
And you can derive insights from here so understand you know how the different distribution how we have
different distributions of customers where they're more profitable less profitable which regions are
performing better and then drill into them separately and understand what actions need to be taken in
separate regions and separate countries and in different groups of customers by their profitability.
So hopefully you enjoyed this toil and picked up some new skills.
I highly encourage you to practice those skills so just before you proceed to the next tutorial apply
those skills.
Try to create different slicers using different items and different columns available to you in the
data set and try combining different Chara's maybe add some more chairs maybe add a pie chart add a
donut chart add a waterfall chart see what you can add into this zation and see what's different slicers
you can apply to make everything work seamlessly and even look even better than it is looking now because
after all learning these things and learning power be-I and mastering pagi is all about practice practice
practice.
And we've covered quite a substantial amount of new features that you have the flexibility and freedom
now to practice and explore the functionality of this wonderful tool.
And I look forward to seeing you on the next tutorial.
Until then happy analyzing.