Hello welcome back.
Of course the RBI in the previous tutorials that we finalized our data mining part of the challenge
so we found the solution we found the answer to our question.
We know who will get the bonuses it will be.
Matthew the central region Susan in the East region and James in the West region and today what we want
to do is we want to format all of those nation so that it looks fantastic and that's what we're going
to get started on right away.
All right to start the formatting we need to click on a version make sure it's selected and then go
into this tab on the right format.
And here what we want to do is we want to start looking at how we can improve this position so it's
more legible because data size is not only about finding answers.
It's also about communicating them and making them accessible to people who are going to be using your
report.
So let's start by adding the actual values on Tabarin because right now the only way we can find out
the number behind this behind the bar is by looking on the plot on the left or right or using a tool
tip.
But if you for instance if you don't have if you have this report as a printed version or APF version
and then you won't be able to use the tool tip.
So your only source of information will be this access way here.
And that's why we want to add the actual values to the bars themselves.
So let's go on the right here and look at the data labels.
So if we select the labels and put them on you'll see that the labels are here.
Now they don't look best right now and some of them don't even fit.
So we're going to fix this up.
We're going to display them in thousands and we're going to say one decimal point.
So now it's like it's just 3.1.
OK 2.4 K and so on and everybody understands that language.
And we're going to say leave the orientation horizontal and we can set the position as inside and set
the top and we're going to increase the size to 12.
There we go.
So looks wonderful now.
I know you can also change the color if you feel that it's probably better in a different color.
For instance this is yellow and white on yellow maybe not.
Doesn't look as great as you'd want wanted to see you can change that black wearing other color you
like.
So we can leave this one out of black for example in this case.
And next which you want to do is fix up the other things that you have access to here.
So data labels were done with that plot area.
We won't be touching that for now title.
So here we've got the title toll sales by region.
You might want to switch it off completely if you're going to have your own title.
We're in the place where you're going to be adding this is a position where you can change it keep the
title and then change this year so you can say
total
total sales.
Something along those lines.
And then you can increase the size of the title as well.
Personally I'm going to remove the title because I have I'm going to add a title on the left for the
y axis.
Now let's go and look at the legend over here.
And now what we want to do is we want to touch and take the title of The Legend of because it's obvious
that it is region and central east and west.
And here we want to also increase the size to about 12.
OK that's great.
And next what we want to do.
So you can also change the position where you want to be in the top center you can be wherever you like.
So I'm probably going to keep mine where was I just press controls there on my keyboard and returned
the previous action.
You know if we go to the y axis here we're going to change if you think so.
I personally find is better that when the Xs displays the same type of units are in the same format
of units as the actual bars themselves.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So here 3000 we're going to change it to two just three case so let's change the 6000 and one decimal
just in case.
And also we're going to enable the title here so we're going to select a title on so that we can see
total sales on the left over there.
All right so that's all we wanted to change in formatting options.
There's one more thing left.
You may have noticed that when I Hoeber over sometimes the value of the total cells is has lots of digits
after the decimal point.
Sometimes it's ok sometimes has lots of digits.
And even though it's displayed like this actually in the data set it's totally fine as has been calculated
correctly.
There's no such decimal points.
So this is a minor problem bug of how it's being displayed.
And also we wouldn't mind having them dollar signs so we don't see the dollar signs for these values
even though it says total sales.
It's it doesn't actually have those dollar signs so it'd be good to have them as well and we can actually
fix those both.
Both those issues at the same time.
So what are we going to do is we're going to select total sales here and we will go to the maudling
tab at the top.
And here we are going to say it say data types you might say General in your case or or in here in format
it says General and what we're going to change it to.
So we're going to change the data type it's still a small number as it was.
We're going to change the format from general to currency and in currency we're going to select dollar
sign English.
United States if you like that you'll see that the dollar sign up here is everywhere.
Total sales are use in the axis on the chart and in the tool too.
And as you can see that's also got rid of the rounding issue that we were seeing previously.
So there we go that's how we form my charts.
And now it looks a much neater much nicer and can be presented to stakeholders.
And I hope you get to this internal look 14 next time.
And until then happy analyzing.