How can we make the most of the power of SpEL for dynamic dependency injection?
Join me in this module to learn how.
I'm Buddhini Samarakkody, and let's continue our journey from here.
Now we've come to the most exciting part of our course!
We are going to see how we can apply the magic of @Value annotation
along with the power of collection manipulation and expression
templating in SpEL to render order details based on the user's
locale in our E-Commerce application.
I will also show you how to use SpEL in the context of XML Spring
configuration for those of you who might still need to work with it.
Finally,
we will look at some typical situations where you
could possibly think of using SpEL.
By the end of this module,
you will be fully equipped with hands-on experience on how
dynamic dependency injection can be done using SpEL by
manipulating objects or object graphs at runtime.
In this module,
we are going to extend our E-Commerce Application and see how we
can use the @Value annotation with SpEL for dynamic bean property
wiring based on a runtime condition.
We will also look at how collection manipulation in SpEL can be used
when wiring some bean properties and look at how expression templating can be applied in our application.