In this final demo of the module,
I'm going to show you how SpEL can be used with Spring XML configuration.
We'll consider the same E-Commerce application scenario here as well.
You'd probably need this if you are working with an application that doesn't use
annotation-based Spring configuration but uses XML instead.
For this, I will create a Spring Boot project,
this time with an XML configuration and set up the project
with all required beans for our application,
then wire User and Order bean properties in the XML file.
Perform collection manipulation along with expression
templating as well in the XML configuration file.
You should get the same results as before when you run the application.
I've opened up the new Spring Boot project that was created to
demonstrate SpEL with XML here in IntelliJ.
Note that I've added an XML Spring configuration file to it.
I've also added all the required beans for our E-Commerce application.
Now let's go ahead and start adding the SpEL expressions in the XML.
I'll start off by defining the User bean and simply wiring its
name and age properties with literal values.
Note that I'm writing the SpEL expression in the value
attribute to perform the wiring.
Let's set the country and language properties with the
systemProperties predefined variable as before.
Next,
I'm performing a mathematical operation in SpEL for setting
the amount property of the Order bean.
Now let's move ahead by wiring an expression with a relational
operator together with the ternary operator,
using logical 'and' operator to wire the
daysToDeliver property of the Order bean,
then wiring a bean property with method calls as before.
Coming to the interesting bit, collection manipulations.
Let's wire the shippingLocations property by accessing
the map defined in the Shipping bean.
Note that before doing this,
we need to define the Shipping bean and City bean somewhere above it.
Next,
I'm going to do a map selection like before to set the
westernShippingLocations adding two more expressions to wire
two more properties of the Order bean, once again using list selection.
Note in this expression, I'm using the escape character,
&lt, for the less than sign since we are in XML.
Finally,
here you can see that I'm setting the orderSummary as before using expression
templating by mixing literal text with evaluation blocks.
Run this application to see the output.
There we go. That's how we use SpEL with XML.