Hi Everyone.
I'm Buddhini Samarakkody.
Welcome to my course on Spring Expression Language,
which is a powerful feature in Spring that enables developers to
manipulate and query objects and object graphs at runtime,
which makes it possible to perform dynamic bean wiring.
Spring Expression Language, in short SpEL,
is of course not a new feature in Spring.
It has been around from Spring version 3.0 onwards.
In this module, we will look at what SpEL is,
why use SpEL, where to use SpEL, and how to write simple SpEL expressions.
Here we'll focus on writing and parsing some basic SpEL expressions,
as well as using an evaluation context.
In this module,
I'm going to introduce you to a simple case study of an E-Commerce
application where we'll be looking at some interesting
applications of SpEL features that we learn.
By the end of this module,
you will get to know SpEL and be able to make use of it for
simple requirements in an application.
Dynamic bean wiring or dependency injection at runtime.
What does this really mean?
Let's look at a simple requirement.
Imagine that we want to pick a bean or assign a default value to a bean
property at runtime based on some conditional situation.
The conditions could be which hardware platform the application is running on,
which operating system or application server,
or maybe the user's locale and so on.
For example, in our E-Commerce application,
we need to render the order details in a locale-specific manner.
For this, we would need to set the country,
language, and time zone of a User bean based on their locale.
How would you do this?
If you are using Spring MVC, you'd think of using something like LocaleResolver.
However, this will require you to include some additional beans,
which means writing more code.
And it does not involve any dynamic bean wiring,
hence will not be the most dynamic way of doing it.
So this is where SpEL can come in handy.
During this course,
I will show you how SpEL can be used to display order details to
the user based on their locale with dynamic bean wiring and manipulating object graphs at runtime.