Now that we've come to the end of this module, as well as the
course, let's do a quick recap. Throughout this course, you saw
the beauty of SpEL with its capability of performing dependency
injection at runtime.
I demonstrated different aspects of SpEL to you,
starting off by writing and parsing simple expressions using plain
Java code, making use of evaluation context when parsing
expressions. And then, I showed you the magic of the @Value
annotation along with the power of collection,
manipulation, and expression templating.
You saw all these features coming alive in the context
of a simple ecommerce application.
SpEL is an excellent choice for dependency injection
based on conditional situations,
and I hope you'll make use of it in your future
applications. Since we've reached the end of this course on
SpEL, as I mentioned at the beginning,
I believe that you are now fully equipped with hands‑on experience of SpEL,
and I'm sure that it added to your skills as experienced developers.
Thank you for watching my course. I hope you have enjoyed watching.