To see what we've just seen in action,
I will show you how to write and parse some basic
SpEL expressions in plain Java code.
For this, first we will set up a Spring Boot application on IntelliJ.
Any other IDE such as Eclipse would work as well.
Note that this application will be extended throughout this course to
demonstrate SpEL usages in our E-Commerce application scenario.
Next, we will take a look at the dependency requirements.
Then I will show you how to write an expression parser class and
demonstrate parsing of some basic SpEL expressions.
Finally, run the application to see the output on the console.
This is the Spring Boot application that was
created using the Spring initializer, which I've opened in IntelliJ.
We will not need any special dependencies for SpEL in a Spring Boot
application since SpEL is a part of Spring Core technologies,
and all of the core dependencies are added automatically to
the final archive at the time of building.
However, if you are not using Spring Boot,
you'll need to have spring-core and spring-context dependencies in your pom.xml.
As you can see,
here we are using spring-boot-starter-web dependency because
we are going to add some RESTFul web services to the
application later on in this course.
Now let's add a class called AppExpressionParser.
In the main method, create a new SpelExpressionParser object.
Then write a simple string expression, Hello World,
and parse it by calling the parseExpression method of the parser object.
Get the value of the parsed expression as a string
and print it out to the console.
Simply run the class, and you'll see the output like this.
Now let's go ahead and add a few more basic expressions and see their outputs.
A method call, a mathematical operation,
using a relational operator, and, finally, the logical 'and' operator.