Evaluation context.
What is it?
The EvaluationContext is an interface in the SpEL API that is used
when evaluating an expression to resolve fields,
properties, and methods, and to perform type conversions.
The out-of-the-box implementation of this interface that Spring
provides is the StandardEvaluationContext class.
Let's see how evaluation context helps to resolve fields with this code snippet.
Note here that we are using the StandardEvaluationContext and setting a
field called greeting to it with a value of Hello USA.
And then we are parsing an SpEL expression in the
context of that EvaluationContext (ec1).
Now if we print the value of msg, we get the output as USA.
Here,
we've created a new StandardEvaluationContext (ec2) and
set a field with the exact same name, greeting,
to it, this time with a value of Hello UK.
Now when the expression is parsed in the context of
this EvaluationContext (ec2), we get the output as UK.
So you see the point here.
It helps to resolve fields when evaluating expressions.
Further,
the StandardEvaluationContext can be used to specify a root
object against which an expression should be evaluated when
resolving bean properties, methods, and performing type conversions.
It uses reflection to do all of this. We will see this in the upcoming Demos.