In this video
we'll get an overview of Angular.
So what is Angular?
Well Angular is a framework for building modern
single-page applications.
You can get details on the project here at angular.io
that's where you'll see the official documentation
and also a list of Angular tutorials
and a number of other really good resources.
How is a single-page application
different than a Traditional application?
Well in a Traditional application each user action
results in a full HTML page load.
So if you do any work in the browser it'll make a request
at a server and give you a full page every time.
And that's the Traditional application.
However in a single-page application,
a web application is composed of a single page
and based on the user actions the application page
is updated so it normally performs a partial update
instead of a full page load.
Also the single-page application can communicate
with the back-end server.
It can send and retrieve data using the REST API
and also some of this data can be used also to
populate the actual single-page application.
Now you may wonder well I need to see a concrete example
of a single-page application just so I can understand it.
So, if you've used any of the online maps like Google Maps
or Yahoo Maps, those are single-page applications.
They simply make partial updates on the page based on
whatever data or whatever address or location
you're looking for in the map system.
And then also for email so most modern email solutions
they are developed as single-page applications.
So if you've used these before like Gmail and so forth,
it's only partial page updates depending on what you're
doing and so on so there's not a full page refresh
for every submission or for every click.
Just partial updates.
So this is the Angular solution so this is kind of where
Angular comes into place for helping you build
modern single-page applications.
So for your application as a single-page app
you can make use of the Angular technology
for doing partial page updates
and also Angular can communicate to back-end services
using the REST API.
And we'll actually accomplish this in later videos
and so we'll build a full-stack app.
We'll have Angular on the front-end
and we'll have Spring Boot on the back-end.
All working together as a full-stack application.
Okay great so this is all good stuff
and so you're probably wondering okay well
who's using Angular on real-time projects?
Well companies around the world are using Angular
so the Australian Government is using it
for their immigration system,
Citi Bank is using it for their customer service,
Microsoft is using it for their gaming portals,
and that's just a small sample.
You can visit this website here, madewithangular.com
and that'll show you some of the projects out there
that are using Angular in the real world
for real-time projects.
Alrighty so let's take a look at Angular's history so
the first version of AngularJS 1.0
was released in October 2010 and then that worked out
for a while however the Angular team found ways that they
could actually improve the framework and actually make it
better and so in this case they actually did a total rewrite
of the framework so they released Angular 2 in October 2016.
It's a total rewrite of the framework.
It's a clean break from AngularJS 1.0.
So it's actually two separate frameworks,
two separate code bases and so it was a big transition
there between the two.
So using Angular 2 in going forward
then all of those newer versions they simply followed
the same framework approach and they made incremental
improvements so they released Angular 4, 5, 6, 7 and 8.
And again these were incremental improvements
just like you have like Java 7, Java 8, 9, 10, 11, 12.
No major changes here just incremental improvements.
But here the key is that AngularJS 1.0 and Angular 2
a total rewrite, two separate frameworks.
So whenever you see AngularJS that's basically legacy work.
Current work is Angular 2 and higher.
Again, incremental improvements.
Alrighty so let's kind of look at Angular's future
as far as the future releases here so,
the key item here is that a major release will come out
every six months so Angular 9, 10, 11 and 12 and so on.
So one thing to note here is that the dates are simply
general guidance from the Angular team.
It may shift accordingly in the future.
But that's the basic idea.
So don't become alarmed with version numbers if you see
one team at your company using Angular 10
and another team at your company using Angular 9
or Angular 8 just because there's a new version
every six months.
So what about do-it-yourself?
I mean you may wonder well, couldn't I just do it myself
with JavaScript, jQuery and AJAX?
And the answer's like well,
it may work for small basic hobby apps.
But for common features such as data binding,
you may reinvent the wheel and it's also hard to manage
and maintain for enterprise real-time applications
with multiple developers working with you.
And so that's the main reason we have frameworks
such as Angular, React, Vue and so on.
So a lot of other developers realize that this part
is painful and hard to do and they created frameworks
and do all the low level work, all the heavy lifting for us,
so we can simply focus on building our app.
Alrighty that wraps it up, I'll see you in the next video.