In this video
we'll cover the Product Master-Detail View.
So with Master-Detail View we have the
master views of all the products
and then when a user clicks on the product
we want to show the actual details.
So the application will show the details
for a selected products.
So we'll have a product image, the title, price,
cart buttons, description, and so on.
Alrighty so here's our development process.
So the first thing we'll do is we'll create
a new component for product details,
then we'll add a new Angular route for product details,
next we'll add router links
to the product-list-grid HTML page,
and then we'll enhance the ProductDetailsComponent
to retrieve the product from the ProductService.
Then we'll update the ProductService to call the URL
on the Spring Boot app.
And then finally we'll update the HTML page
for the ProductDetailsComponent
to display those product details.
All right step one of creating
the new component for product details.
And this is really easy, right?
We simply use the ng generate component
and then we give components/ProductDetails.
And then in step two we'll add
a new Angular route for product details
so in our add mod.ts files we'll add a new entry
here for the route so we have path: 'products/:id'
and then the actual component.
So the :id is the parameter
and then the component is the ProductDetailsComponent.
So this is the actual component that we created
on the previous slide.
In step three we're going to add the router links
to the product-list-grid HTML.
So here's our main page here
and so basically when the user clicks the product
then we want to show the details.
So when you add a link on the product image
and also add a link on the product name.
All right so a bit more here on the step three,
the actual coding, so product-list-grid ocmponent.HTML
on our section of looping over the collection of products
we're going to add a link on the product image
using our anchor router link.
And then we'll do a similar thing here
for adding a link on the product name.
And so notice here we're actually passing
over the parameter value here
so we pass over the tempProduct.id
for the image and also tempProduct.id for the given name.
Then in step four we're going to enhance
the ProductDetailsComponent
to retrieve the product from ProductService.
So the first thing we do is we get the id parameter string,
we do that by saying paramMap.get('id').
And remember we set up this given parameter name
based on the app module ts when we set up the given route.
And then we do the normal stuff here
converting the string to a number using a plus symbol.
So finally on the left hand side
we'll have const theProductId which is a number
as assigned to this given value.
And then we actually retrieve
the product from the ProductService.
So this getProduct is a new method
that we'll actually create in the ProductService
for retrieving a given product.
Alrighty step five of updating the product service
to call the URL on the Spring Boot app.
So here's our ProductService its.
Here's that new method getProduct.
So in this method we need to build the URL
based on the product id so we make use of that
localhost.8080/api/products/$(theProductId).
And then we make a call to the REST API
using the product URL.
This returns an observable and in this case
the JSON Data return can be converted directly
to a product object.
So here there's no need to unwrap the JSON
from Spring Data REST, there's no _embedded entry
and we'll see more of that on the next slide.
So mapping the JSON to product.
So here's the URL for retrieving a product id
for example two, we give localhost.8080/api/products/2.
Also give us this JSON
and note this is a built-in feature of Spring Data REST.
There's no additional coding or configuration required,
you get this out of the box.
And over on the right hand side
we have our product.ts class.
So this JSON Data can be converted directly
to the Product object so the JSON properties
map directly to properties in the Product class.
So here's our JSON,
note the items here that's highlighted.
Then this converts over to the actual product
and again matching directly on those given property names.
So note here there's no underscore embedded,
there's no additional interface or mapping that we need.
We can kind of go one to one here.
Alrighty step six of updating the HTML page
for ProductDetailsComponent to display the product details.
So in our details page we want to have the image,
we want to have the name of the product,
the price, cart button,
and also the actual description of the product,
and also a navigation link to go back
to the main product list.
So let's come look at the coding here
and this is mainly just an HTML exercise.
So here's our ProductDetailsComponent.HTML.
So we have the image source equals product.image URL
so it'll also give us the image.
We have information over here for the product name,
the price, the cart button.
Then we have the actual description
and then finally we have a link back to the product list
using a router link.
And that's basically it for the coding on
the product details HTML page.
Okay, so this looks great.
Let' go ahead and move into our IDE
and let's start writing the code.