In this video,
we're going to secure our communication with HTTPS.
We've secured an Angular front-end
so this is in place.
Now, let's secure the Spring Boot backend
to make use of HTTPS.
Here's our development process.
So in the first step,
we're going to generate the key in a self-signed certificate,
and we'll also update the application properties
with security configs.
Now, Java provides support for keys and certificates.
A Keystore is a file that contains keys and certificates.
And the entries and the key file are associated
with an alias and the password.
So here's our Java Keystore,
a collection of keys and certificates.
So we'll have one alias here that references a given key,
key pair, and certificate.
We can also have additional entries here,
so an alias2 for another key pair and certificate.
So the Keystore is a file
that's a collection of keys and certificates,
and we'll use a keystore
to secure our Spring Boot application.
Alrighty.
In step one,
we're going to generate the key and self-signed certificate.
We'll actually make use the JDK utility: keytool.
And this is already a part of the JDK.
There's nothing additional you have to install
to use the keytool.
So here's an example here of using a keytool.
So at our command line,
we simply say, keytool, genkeypair, no prompt.
So we don't prompt the user.
We give the alias luv2code,
the keypass of secret,
the keystore, source main resources luv2code keystore.p12.
So that's the location of the Java Keystore file
that we're going to create or reference.
Here, we have the storeType of PKCS12
that's simply a format for keystores.
We specify the keys to our password of secret.
Then, we specify the algorithms.
So key algorithms RSA,
a key size of 2048 bits
and the validity of 365 days.
Then, we have the dname.
So the dname is the distinguished name.
Basically, meta data or information
about your given certificate.
So we give our country state locality.
So here for my example,
U.S., Pennsylvania, Philadelphia.
I get the organization, luv2code.
The organizational unit, Training Backend.
And then the CN,
which is the common name,
which is similar to the fully qualified domain name.
In this example, localhost.
And then finally,
we have an extension that we add here
for the Subject Alternative Name,
and we have the DNS of localhost.
So here, we can specify any additional hosts
or IP addresses that'll be associated
with this given certificate.
And we'll see this all in action
when we make it into the coding video.
And if you'd like to get more details on this given keytool,
you can go to the link that I have here on the slide
and it'll redirect you to the official documentation
for the Java keytool.
All right. So in step two,
we're going to update the application properties
with security configs.
So when I add properties file,
we set up our server web port 8, 4, 4, 3.
So that's going to be the port we're going to listen on for HTTPS.
We're going to enable HTTPS support.
So here we're going to only accept HTTPS requests.
So we have a server that SSL dot enabled equals true.
Then we set up the alias that identifies
the key in the key store.
So the alias is luv2code.
And this is based on the key tool command
from the previous slide.
So in that previous slide, we had dash alias luv2code.
So here you have to match it up here
in the spring boot configuration file.
We also have to specify the actual key store location.
So the actual path for this one.
So it's on the class path, luv2code key store. P12.
And remember when using Maven projects,
source main resources,
anything that directory is automatically add it
to the Java class path for your application.
Then we set up the key password. It's a secret.
So that's what we referenced here in our command line
from the previous slide, store, password, secret.
And then the keys store format.
So the key store format is PKCS 12,
and we have that reference also.
So just so it knows which format to use
for reading the giving keys store.
And that's it as far as setting up those properties.
And so this outpatient properties file
has to match information that you use
when you actually generate the key pair.
So that's a common pitfall,
make sure you get that correct in your application.
Okay. So this all looks pretty good.
Let's go ahead and move into our coding video
and let's get started.