In this video we are going to cover
Shopping Cart - List Items.
Alrighty, so we've added items to the cart,
now we'd like to be able to click on the cart icon here
and see the items in the cart.
Okay, so these are the items in our cart.
So, we have each row here for the cart item,
so the product image, product details
and the quantity and the subtotal.
Same thing for the next cart item.
And then finally in the bottom right
we'll have the actual total as far as
the total quantity and also the total price.
And it also accomplishes what actually creates
this new component, this Cart Details Component.
That'll be a table that'll simply list up
all of our cart items for us.
Okay, so let's go and look at the development process.
So, the first step is creating the new component,
Cart Details Component.
Then we'll add a new route for the Cart Details Component.
Next we'll update the link for the Shopping Cart icon.
We'll modify the Cart Details Component
to retrieve the cart items.
And then finally, we'll add the HTML template
for the Cart Details Component.
Okay, step one is creating
the new component for cart details.
So, we simply make use of that Angular command, right?
Ng generate component
and then we give components/cart-details.
And then in step two we'll add a new route
for the Cart Details Component.
So in our app.module.ts file I'll add this new route here.
Cart details and it'll map over
to our Cart Details Component.
Then in step three, we going to update
the link for the Shopping cart icon.
So, this is our cart-status.component.html.
So, we'll make use of our router link for cart details.
So, basically, when the user clicks
the Cart Status Component, then we going to use the new route
that we just created, cart details to view
the Cart Details Component.
Step four of modifying the Cart Details Component
to retrieve the cart items.
So, we'll have this class here, Cart Details Component.
We'll set up some properties
for cart item, total price, total quantity.
We'll inject cart service
and then in our ngOnInit
that we'll call this.listCartDetails.
And then here is the code here for listCartDetails.
We'll go through and we'll get a handle to the cart items.
Then we'll subscribe to the cart total price.
And we'll also subscribe to the cart total quantity.
Now, this code will look very familiar to you,
because we created a similar piece of code
for the Cart Status Component.
Subscribing to information on the cart service.
And then finally here, we'll compute
the cart total price and quantity.
And then finally in step five,
we'll add the HTML template for the Cart Details Component.
So basically we're building an HTML table.
So I'll set up my table headers here
for product image, product detail.
And then I'll simply loop through the cart items.
So that I'll have this temp cart item.
I'll display the image URL
and the also the name and the unit price.
And then we'll display the quantity
for the the cart item and also the subtotal.
And notice here for the subtotal
we're doing some quick math here
where the subtotal is the quantity times the unit price.
And then we have to kind of give
our grand total here at the bottom.
So, the total quantity and the total price.
And so this HTML code here will help us
with that part of it.
And so that's basically it.
So, we'll go ahead and dive into our IDE
and then we'll start writing the code.