In this video, we'll cover
viewing order history.
Let's add a new feature to allow the users
to view their previous order history.
This feature will only be available
to logged in, authenticated users.
Here's a little screenshot.
Notice here on the far right,
there's a new button here called orders.
The user will click that button,
and then it will show them their list of previous orders.
Now looking at the front and back end,
we're going to split up the development
across multiple videos.
We'll start working on the Spring Boot back end,
and then we'll come back and work
on the Angular front end.
Here's the development process
for the Spring Boot back end.
The first thing that we'll do is
we'll create the OrderRepository REST API,
and then we'll update the configs
to make the OrderRepository REST API read only.
Okay, so here's step one of creating
the OrderRepository REST API.
We're going to expose an endpoint
to search for orders by the customer's email address.
We'll have this GET method and the endpoint of
slash order, slash search,
slash find by customer email,
and question mark, email equals,
then we pass in the actual value
for that user's email address
that we want to search by.
Now a bit more here.
Remember that Spring Data REST
and Spring Data JPA supports query methods,
so Spring will actually construct a query
based on method-naming conventions.
In this example here, we have the OrderRepository.
We have this method find by customer email,
and we pass in a param email.
As a quick refresher here,
here's our database diagram that we were working on.
We have the orders table.
Then, for a given order,
it's associated with a given customer,
and so we'll search for orders
based on the customer's email address.
Then as another refresher,
the class diagram for our JPA entity classes.
We have the order class,
and then notice here at the bottom,
there's a customer entry,
so the order's associated with a given customer.
Again, we'll use this JPA entity
to search for orders
based on the customer's email address.
Now moving ahead here,
a bit more details on this OrderRepository.
We have the find by customer email and the param.
Remember, Spring's going to do the work behind the scenes.
Spring will actually execute a query similar to this.
We'll have a select star from orders,
left outer join on customer,
on orders.customer ID equals customer.id,
where customer.email equals the email.
Email is going to the param
that's passed into this actual method,
and it'll actually be passed in via the REST API.
Remember, the nice thing about all of the Spring magic,
we simply write the method name,
and then Spring will actually generate the query
based on the given method name,
so more of that Spring magic for you (laughs).
Then, looking at the rest endpoint,
Spring data REST will actually expose
an endpoint here, find by customer email,
and then you'd pass in the parameter for email.
Here, we simply pass data to the REST API,
in this case, demo@luv2code.com.
Also, as another refresher,
notice here we have page and pageable.
That's for pagination support.
In the event that we had 100 orders or 500 orders,
we could have pagination support.
This functionality is built into the API,
and we can have support for it in the future
if we'd like to use it.
Okay, so that covers that piece of it.
Now, step two of updating the configs
to make the OrderRepository REST API read only.
We've done a lot of this work before.
We're simply going to add
one new line here in our configuration
to disable the methods for the order.class.
Everything else here works out the same,
so we're a-okay.
Alrighty, so this coding looks pretty good.
Let's go ahead and move into the next videos,
and let's start writing some code.