In this video, we're going to integrate
Angular with bootstrap.
So let's make our page beautiful.
So currently, we have an HTML table for our sales team.
But the table is here it works, but it's kind of ugly.
(laughs)
And what I like to do is I like to make it prettier,
I like to make it beautiful.
I'd like to apply bootstrap styles to this given table
to make it look really nice.
And so that's what we're going to do in this video.
All right , so let's go and look at our development process.
So the first thing we're going to do is get the links
for the remote bootstrap files.
And then we'll add the links to our index HTML page.
Next will apply the bootstrap CSS styles
and our component HTML template,
and then will apply the bootstrap CSS styles
and our component HTML table.
And then finally, we'll update our TypeScript component file
to reference the bootstrap HTML template.
Already step one of getting the links
for the remote bootstrap files.
So all we have to do is visit the bootstrap website
at www.getbootstrap.com,
the website has instructions on how to get started
and also how to access the actual links,
they have a nice all template here,
we can copy and paste those links.
So in step two will add the links in our index HTML file.
So in the head section here,
we'll just drop in the link tag,
and then we'll give an H ref to where
those bootstrap files are located.
And then notice here for the version number,
I simply put in a placeholder for that version number,
your version will most likely be different,
just because new versions of bootstrap are released
on a regular basis.
Okay, now in Step three, we're going to apply the CSS
and the component HTML template.
So in our file, app component at HTML
will simply set up a div and set class equals container
that's a bootstrap CSS style.
And also far h1 will use class mt-three, mb-three,
basically margin top, margin bottom,
for our header for sales team.
And then the grey section here at the bottom right,
that's going to be a little placeholder
here for our app sales person list.
And we'll cover that in the next step.
Already in step four, a planet CSS
and our component HTML table.
So here for the file, we're going to have a new file,
so we simply copied over our original file,
and we renamed it with a dash bootstrap.
So we could have used any name for the file,
I simply use the same name
and just gave the dash bootstrap reference to it.
So for our table tag, we apply the bootstrap CSS styles.
Classical's table, table hover,
and for the T-H section,
we say class equals T head dark.
And in this it'll give us a nice, beautiful bootstrap table,
as we see here on the slide.
Okay, then moving to step five,
we need to update our TypeScript component file.
So here's our bootstrap component HTML
that we created in step four.
So I'll kind of slide this over to the right.
And then over on the left hand side,
here's our component.TSR TypeScript file.
So we have this template URL
we're simply going to reference the name of that file
that we just created.
So our dash bootstrap.component at HTML.
So this component will use that given template file.
And this will give us our desired HTML output for our table
using those bootstrap CSS styles.
Alright, this looks great.
So let's go ahead and move into our IDE
and let's write the code.