In this video,
we'll cover secure communication with HTTPS.
So we'd like to have secure communication
for our application
because in the future, we'd like to process credit cards.
And so we'd like to have this data encrypted.
So, between our web browser and our Angular App,
we'd like to have secure communication or encrypted data.
And also between our Angular App and our Spring Boot App,
we'd also like for the data to be encrypted.
And so then we can access our application
by going to https://localhost:4200,
and this will handle all of the secure communication
and encryption for us behind the scenes.
So what exactly is HTTPS?
Well, it's the Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure.
It's the protocol for encrypting data
between a web browser and a server,
and it uses the TLS protocol behind the scenes,
Transport Layer Security.
Now you may have heard of SSL.
Well, TLS is the successor of SSL.
TLS is more secure than SSL.
However, in the industry, people still use these terms
interchangeably, so you'll see blog posts referring to SSL,
you'll see tools and utilities and so forth
referring to SSL.
Using HTTPS, the nice thing about it
is that there's no changes required to your source code.
You simply configure a server to run
using secure keys and certificate.
Then you able to access your site using
HTTPS:// whatever your host name is, localhost:4200.
Make note of the use of HTTPS.
That means that the data is being encrypted
behind the scenes for you automatically
between the web browser and the web server.
Okay, so let's talk about keys and certs.
To run securely, you'll need keys and certificates
for your given application.
This basically provides proof of your server's identity,
meaning your domain name and it's reviewed and signed
by a trusted certificate authority,
such as GoDaddy, Verisign, AWS, et cetera.
Effectively, it's a mutually trusted third party
that can vouch or verify that you are who you say you are
in terms of server identity.
So, if I'm running something for luvtocode.com,
this'll verify that I actually own
the luvtocode domain name,
and I am the Luv To Code company.
A similar thing for Amazon, amazon.com.
It's trusted that that given site is really amazon.com
and not someone trying to fake or pretend
that they're amazon.com.
So that's the whole idea of a security,
basically a stamp of approval
from a trusted certificate authority.
Now in the real world,
you would normally have to pay for a certificate,
but for dev and demo purposes,
we're going to save some money here,
and we'll create what we call self-signed certificates,
and these are really good for dev and demo purposes,
so there's no need for us to buy an actual certificate.
The only caveat here
is that the browser's going to warn about this.
They're going to give you a warning
when you make use of self-signed certificates,
because no one's been able to actually vouch or verify
that you are who you actually say you are
because it's self-signed.
You simply made this up.
But we can safely ignore this for dev/demo purposes.
Here's our development process.
So in the first step,
we're going to generate a key and a self-signed certificate,
and then we're going to run the Angular App
with the key and the self-signed certificate.
And then finally we'll update
our Spring Boot App with the new URL.
And so what we'll do here in this set of videos
is that we'll actually encrypt the data
between the web browser and the Angular App.
Now there's also some additional work
we'd have to do on the backend to encrypt data
between the Angular App and the Spring Boot App.
I'll cover that later in another set of videos.
So for right now,
we're simply focusing on encrypting the data
between the web browser and the Angular Application.
Step one of generating the key
and the self-signed certificate.
We can accomplish this by using
a free utility called openssl.
So here's a sample command here for using openssl.
We give openssl space req for request.
And then we give the name of the output file, localhost.key.
And then we give the name
of the output certificate, localhost.crt.
And then we give some additional configurations.
Now, I'll cover all these configs in a separate document.
So, at luv2code.com/openssl-setup,
I give you all the details and steps
as far as the additional configs,
because it varies depending on the operating system
that you're using: Microsoft Windows, Mac, or Linux.
But I have this document that kind of walks you through
everything step-by-step.
And we'll use this when we get into the coding videos
a little bit later.
In step two, we're going to run our Angular App
with the key and the self-signed certificate.
So now remember, the key and the self-signed cert
were generated in the previous step.
So here we'll simply edit the file, package.json.
We'll move into the script section.
We'll move into the section here for the start command,
and then we'll make use of this ng serve,
and then we enable the ssl mode by saying ssl=true.
And then we give our reference to our ssl key file,
localhost.key, and also give our reference
to the certificate localhost.cert.
Now, one thing that will slightly change
when we actually go through and run our application.
So now instead of doing ng serve by itself,
we can use an npm start.
So that's the new command for starting our Angular App.
The npm start refers to this script update
that we just made here in the package.json.
So when we say npm start,
it's going to do this big, long ng serve
with all the ssl information for the mode,
the key file, and the cert for us,
just so we don't have to re-type that every time.
Now, let's talk about the web browser warning.
So the web browser's going to warn you
when you're using a self-signed certificate.
So here's a screenshot from Firefox.
It'll say, "Warning: Potential Security Risk Ahead".
And a similar thing here for Chrome.
"Your connection is not private".
All right so these are some scary screens here
to try and alert you and make you aware of issues
that could possibly occur.
And if you drill down further to get more details,
it says, "localhost:4200
uses an invalid security certificate".
Ooh, "The certificate is not trusted
because it is self-signed".
And they gave this error code self_signed_cert.
Okay, got it.
So, we understand that we created our own self-signed cert,
and so we're aware of this.
But the browser's saying, hey, it's self-signed.
We don't know who this person is,
and there could be a security risk.
But for dev/demo purposes, we're okay.
We can accept the risk and continue.
Okay, so moving ahead to step three
of updating the Spring Boot App with the new URL.
So in our Spring Boot Application,
in our application.properties for the allowed origins,
this is a list of the actual origins that we can accept
coming into the Spring Boot Application.
So now since we're using HTTPS,
then we have to update this entry here
to HTTPS://localhost:4200,
because our Angular App is going to be running now using HTPPS.
And here's some additional resources for you
because you may have some more questions like,
well, what is HTTPS?
I need to do a deep dive on ssl.
I'm going to do a deep dive on TLS.
Or, more details on keys and certificates.
So, here's some resources that you can use
to get you up to speed with this.
So you can go, there's a site here,
luv2code.com/https-additional-resources,
and I'll redirect you to a link that has additional details
on these topics.
But at this point, we have enough,
we know enough to actually get started
with using this and using it in our full stack application.
Let's go ahead and move to the next video
and let's get started.