In this video,
we'll get started with Angular development.
Already, so just a quick refresher here.
So, Angular is the framework
for building modern single-page applications.
The main website here is www.angular.io.
This website has the official documentation
for the Angular framework,
along with the number of very good tutorials.
So I highly recommend that you access this website
and bookmark it on your web browser,
a lot of valuable information there.
So let's look at the features of Angular.
So it's a component-based framework,
it has clean separation of template coding
and application logic, it also has built-in support
for data-binding and dependency injection,
and it also supports responsive web design
and modern frameworks.
So for example, you can use Bootstrap,
or Google Material Design, or Angular Material, and others.
Looking at the Angular architecture,
as I mentioned, it's a component-based framework,
so you can have parent components and child components.
These components can also make use of view templates.
And you can also make use of directives
to kind of customize the behavior of your view templates.
There's also services you can create as a client-side code
written in typescript.
And also there are modules, basically, a collection
of related components, services, directives, and so on.
Okay, so let's go ahead and look at some of the key terms
here for Angular.
The first one here is the component,
it's the main player in an Angular application.
A component has two parts:
one, a view for the user interface;
and then two, the actual class that implements
the application logic or event handling for the view.
And then, we have the view template which the user
interface for the component.
It has static HTML along with some dynamic elements.
Next, we have directive, basically adds custom
behavior to the HTML elements.
You can use it for looping, conditionals, and so on.
Then, there's the service, basically, a helper class
that provides the desired functionality,
so it can retrieve data from a server,
perform calculation or form validation, and so on.
This service is actually code written in typescript,
it's part of the Angular project, it runs client-side,
but it can remotely connect to any external sources
as needed.
And then finally, as I mentioned earlier,
a module is a collection of related components,
directives, services, and so on.
And we'll see all of these different components
in some of the upcoming videos.
Already, so application UI composition,
so we can take our main application starting
with this main screen and then we can break it down
into smaller pieces, so we can have a header component
and also a footer component.
And then also, along the left hand side,
we can have like a nav bar, maybe some product categories
component, then we can have a main content component
in the center, and we could add a product list component,
to list all of our products.
And then also, we could have a page navigation component.
So this is one example of taking a user-interface
and breaking it down to smaller components.
You have total flexibility, total freedom
on how you want to design your application,
this is simply one example.
Okay, so in terms of application interaction,
so we have our Angular project,
so we have our user-interface,
and our user-interface can make use of services.
These services are Angular components, so this is code
written in typescript, it runs on the client-side,
it runs in the browser.
These services can communicate over the network
to back-end systems so they can make use
of the rest API and call maybe a spring boot back-end
or any type of back-end to get data from a database.
All right, so Angular is the front-end development,
spring boot can be your back-end development,
all of these together makes up of full stack
application architecture.
Okay, so a bit more about the Angular project.
So an Angular project is composed of multiple files,
so you'll have HTML files, you'll have typescript files,
cascading style sheets, configuration files,
images and so on.
So a lot of files, and we'll actually see these
when we create an Angular project.
There's a lot of files that are created,
but we'll break it down and we'll cover the key files.
Already, so now, how do we create an Angular project?
Well, the Angular team provides a command-line tool
to generate a project.
And basically, what this is, it generates the starter files
that helps you bootstrap your project.
The main website for the command-line tool
is at http://cli.angular.io
so CLI is short for Command-Line Interface.
Okay, so let's get started with the Angular CLI
or the Angular Command-Line Interface.
The first thing you do is install it using
the command here npm install -g @angular/cli.
We can always check the version of the tool
by using ng version, and we can also get help
on the tool by using ng help.
Now, here's an example of how to create a new project
with the Angular CLI, so you simply say,
ng new and whatever the project name is.
So here I could say, ng new my-first-angular-project.
So this let's you create a project
create all the initial files that can use to get started.