And this video will cover the checkout form
and we'll save the order to the backend.
We have our shopping cart full of products.
So let's check out, we're going to send the order
to the backend and stored in the database.
We'll have our Angular front-end
send data over using the REST API
to our Spring Boot backend and put it in the database.
Alright, so let's take a look
at our application architecture
and here I'll kind of focus on the backend Spring Boot.
We'll have our checkout controller
that'll make use of a checkout service.
That'll also make use of the spring data JPA repository
and we'll eventually store the information in the database.
And what we'll do is we'll make use of custom coding here
for our checkout controller and also the checkout service.
So a bit more on the custom coding for the architecture
we'll have a custom controller and service.
So we'll have a checkout controller
and also a checkout service.
Now you may be wondering why not use Spring Data REST
because it's really awesome and amazing.
And we've used it so far.
Spring Data REST is great for basic CRUD.
As I mentioned, we're currently using it
for our product catalog, but it's not the best
for processing the order using custom business logic.
So we needed to generate a custom tracking number
and save the order and the database
and also do some other custom business logic.
Spring data REST has a challenge there.
So spring data REST is very limited
in terms of customization
for custom business, logic and processing.
You'll want to create a custom controller and service.
Okay. So that's the reason why I'm using custom coding here
for the controller and the service.
Alright, so let's take a look at our database diagram.
So we'll have our orders basically
for the given order that we're saving in the database.
A customer can have zero to many orders.
A order has a billing address and a shipping address.
That's why we have the two lines there
and also an order item.
That's the actual line item for the order.
And we'll see more of this
as we move into the actual coding for it.
And then as far as the class diagram
we'll create these JPA entities here.
So we'll have a customer that has zero to many orders.
An order has shipping address, billing address.
And also an order has a collection of order items.
We'll also make use of a data transfer object,
basically for transferring data
between the angler front end and the spring boot back in.
So we'll send data over the REST API
and we'll make use of this
data transfer object called purchases.
And this is something that we'll create.
So this purchase will have a reference
to the customer shipping address, billing address order
and a collection of order items.
And he has a description here of the API.
So we'll have a POST
to this end point/API/checkout/purchase.
And the action is that it will create a new purchase order
and stored in the database.
And then here's a look at the sample JSON here
for the purchase.
So we see, we have a section here for the customer
shipping address, billing address
the order and a collection of order items.
Now let's take a look at our development process
and it's for the backend for Spring Boot.
So the first thing we'll do is we'll run a database
script to set up our database.
We'll create some entities.
We'll also create the data transfer objects
next we'll create the repository,
then we'll create the service
and then finally we'll create the controller.
Now I won't go through the coding here in a slideshow
I'll simply swing into our coding video
and it would just cover all the code there
in the coding video
because you've seen a lot of this stuff before.
We're just kind of pulling it all together
for this given example.
Alright, so let's go ahead
and move to the next video and let's write some code.