Now let's go ahead
and look at the Web Storage API.
So the API works the same
for session storage or local storage,
it's based on the concept of key and value,
and key and value are always strings.
So remember the data is scoped to the page origin,
which is the protocol, hostname, plus port.
And remember, only pages from the same origin
can access the data.
To store an item,
we make use of storage.setItem, key, value.
And to retrieve an item,
we make use of storage.getItem, key.
Here's some more details on the API.
So to set an item with key, value,
that'll set the key with the given value.
If it already exists, it'll update the value.
getItem for the key it'll return the key value,
if it doesn't exist, it'll return null.
We can do a removeItem on key.
So to remove the item key,
if that key doesn't exist, it does nothing.
And we can also call clear.
The clear method will empty all the keys out of storage.
So it will empty the keys and their associated data,
this is for this specific origin.
And if you'd to get more details here on the Web Storage API
you can visit the link here on the slide,
and it will redirect you to the official documentation.
All right, so let's kind of pull this together
with our development process.
So in the first step we're going to update our CartService
to read data from session storage,
then we'll add a new method
in CartService called persistCartItems.
And then finally we'll modify
the computeCartTotals method
to call this new method persistCartItems.
Alrighty, step one of updating the CartService
to read data from the session storage.
So in our CartService, we have our cartItems array,
and for storage I'll make use of sessionStorage.
So this is going to be a reference
to the web browser's session storage,
and we get access to this for free.
Now in my constructor, I'm going to read data from storage.
So I'll say, Let data equals
JSON.parse, this.storage.getItem, cartItems.
So cartItems is the key,
and we can actually use any name for the key,
we simply have to stay consistent in our application.
And the JSON.parse remember, it'll read the JSON string
and convert it to an object.
And then I check if data is not equal to no,
then I make an assignment
this.cartItems equals data.
And then I compute the totals
based on the data that's read from storage.
So I called this.computeCartTotals.
And then in step two, we're going to add a new method
in CartService called persistCartItems.
So here's this new method,
here persistCartItems,
I make a call to this.storage.setItem,
cartItems, that's the key.
I'm going to make use of JSON.stringify, this.cartItems.
So I pass in the value and I convert it to a string.
Because remember with the storage API,
everything is a string.
So if I take this object and convert it to a string,
and we do that by making use of that JSON.stringify.
Then in step three we modify the computerCartTotals
to call the new method, persistCartItems.
So here is my computeCartTotals method.
We do all of our normal work
and then the final thing we'll do is this persist cart data.
So I'll make use of this.persistCartItems.
That's a new method that we just created.
And that's basically it here for the coding.
So let's go ahead and move into the next video
and let's start writing some code.