All right, so let's get started
with our development process.
So in this video, we're going to cover step one
of generating the key in the self-signed certificate,
and also updating the application properties
with security configs.
Alrighty, let's go ahead and open up a terminal window.
We need to get to the command line
to do some operations here.
So you can open a terminal window,
or a command prompt window on your operating system,
and simply move to the directory of your
spring boot e-commerce project.
In IntelliJ, they have an option
where you can actually open up the terminal window
in the IDE and other IDE's have similar features too.
Alrighty, so here I am at the command line.
What we need to do is use the key tool command here to
generate the key and certificate.
Now we can manually type this out. However,
I have some online steps that we can make use of.
So let's go ahead and open up a browser and let's visit the
link that I have here on the slide.
So this will take us to a document that has the steps or
instructions for using a key tool for generating this key
and self-signed certificate.
So just kind of moving down here in this document,
it says open up a terminal window, move to the directory.
So make sure you have all that stuff done already.
And then we're going to use this command to generate the key
and certificate. So it's one long command,
copy it and paste it in its entirety.
So you can just select this item here to copy it,
and it will copy this to your clipboard,
and then you can swing back to your terminal window
and you can simply paste it in.
Now, the reason I did this again is
because it's a really long command,
very error prone.
Now I know some people say, hey,
I want to type it in myself, character for character,
simply pause the video here.
And you can type in exactly what I have here on the screen
in your window. It's totally up to you.
All right, so the command ran successfully
and we can go check our directory here,
source main resources,
and so the command that we just executed,
generated this key file, 'luv2code-keystore.p12'.
So that's the new file that was just created.
And remember the key-store is
a collection of keys and certificates,
and we can actually view the contents of our certificates.
So just swinging back to our documentation here,
viewing the contents of your certificate.
We can use this key tool command, simply copy it.
All right, so that's in our clipboard again,
and then we can swing back over
to the IDE and we can paste it in.
And excellent. So it printed out a lot of stuff,
if you kind of scroll up a bit to the top,
you'll see the information for your certificate.
So this is for this alias 'luv2code',
and then it was created on a given date, the owner,
So that's the information that we had earlier,
the issuer, self-signed certificate,
and it's valid from this date
until one year from now, 365 days.
And that's pretty much it. So we know that that part works.
So we know that our key-store has been created
and our self-signed certificate is in that key-store
with the alias of 'luv2code'.
All right, so I'll go ahead and clean up this window here.
And now the next step here is to update the application
properties with security configs.
So we'll set up our configs
based on the previous key tool command.
I'll just open up my 'application.properties' file.
And I'm going to add some new entries here to the end of
this 'application.properties' file.
So I'll swing you back over to
our browser, scroll down down a bit.
So for our application properties,
we're going to add this to the end.
So these are the SSL configs that we'll need.
So I'll simply copy this information
and then I'll paste it here in our 'application.properties'.
So paste it at the end,
so keep all your existing stuff from up top,
and this is the new information.
And so we'll go through and discuss each one of these
configurations here.
So our HPS secure ports going to run on 8443.
We will only accept HTTPS requests,
our alias is 'luv2code', the key-store location is at
this given location, 'classpath:luv2code-keystore.p12',
and remember, anything on source main resources
is automatically on the class path.
We specify our key-store password of 'secret'
and our key-store format of PKCS12.
And again, this is all based on the information
from our previous key tool command.