All right, so let's get started
with our development process.
So in this video, we're going to cover steps one and two,
generating our form service and adding methods
to the form service for months and years.
All right, step one of generating our forms service.
So let's go ahead and open up a new terminal window.
I'll move into my directory
and I'll zoom in here for a second.
Now I'll make use of that ng generate service.
I give services/luv2ShopForm
and then this will generate the supporting classes
for our luv2-shop-form service.
I can swing over here and verify this.
Under App, Services
and so there's my new file here,
luv2-shop-form service.
Before I get into editing here, let me go ahead
and close off this terminal window,
just doing an exit over here.
Now let's open up our luv2-shop-form service.
All right, so this is step two here
of adding methods to the form service for months and years.
I'll add a method here, get credit card months,
they pass in a parameter for start month
and we'll return an observable array,
number square brackets.
And remember, we're using observables here
because our angler components are going to subscribe
to this method to get the results of the async call.
All right, let me kind of just stretch out here
at the bottom so I can have some extra white space
or room to work with.
So we'll simply define our MTRA here.
So I've build an array for the month dropdown list,
I'll start with the current month
and loop until month number 12.
No, I didn't say the number 12 there in the comment
but I'm looping until mark number 12.
So I just set up the four loop here,
I say the month equals start month,
a month less than equal to 12,
the month plus plus,
I'll do a data.push for months,
I'll be adding that items to the array.
And then I do a return of data.
So here we use the of operator from rxjs
so we're going to wrap an object as an observable.
So in this case here, we make use of our data array
and we wrap it as an observable.
Remember, we're using observables here
because our angler component is going to subscribe
to this method to receive the async data.
And then I simply just do a little fix here
on the import for luv
and then we can scroll to the top,
make sure that's all imported properly.
Okay, that looks good.
And remember, all this is
from the Reactive Java Script framework.
All right, so that's the coding there
for getting credit card months.
This looks pretty good.
Now let's go ahead and do a similar thing here for years.
So we'll have get credit card years,
it turns on observable array.
So we'll simply define our MTRA here.
So we'll build an array for the year dropdown list,
we'll start with the current year
and we'll loop for the next 10 years.
So I'll simply set up start year as a number,
new date, get full year.
And so this will give me the current year that we're at.
So if it's 2020, we get the value 2020,
if we're in 2024 it will return us a value of 2024.
And then for the end year,
we simply take the start year plus 10.
So now simply set up a for loop,
the year equals start year,
the year is less than equal to end year, the year plus plus.
And it seems as though I have a small typo somewhere,
where is it?
I see it right here.
The year semicolon,
I get that, semicolon.
Okay, that looks really good, I like it.
And now here, I simply do a data.push the year.
So I'm simply adding that year to the array.
And then we simply repeat the process, right.
So we do a return of data.
We're simply using the of operator from rxjs
to wrap the object as an observable.
Our angular component is going to subscribe
to this method to receive all of this async data.
All right, so I'll just kind of clean up here
and this looks pretty good.
So our Luv2-shop-form service is finished for the moment.
Good job.