In this video, we'll cover
the development process for pagination.
We've built our project so far and we're going to
add this new feature for pagination in the bottom right.
So here's our development process.
The first thing is installing ng-bootstrap,
then we'll refactor the interface for GetResponseProducts.
We'll add pagination support to the product service.
We'll update our product list to handle pagination
and then finally we'll enhance our HTML template
to use the ng-bootstrap pagination component.
Okay, step one of installing ng-bootstrap.
So all of the installation instructions
are at this given website,
we will walk through it here on this slide.
So we'll run the following commands
in our Angular project directory.
We'll use ng add @angular/localize.
This is a dependency for Angular nine and higher.
We'll also do an npm install on ng-bootstrap
that will actually install
the ng-bootstrap component framework.
Also, we need to import the module for pagination,
so we need to edit our app.module.ts file
and add a new entry here for imports
for the Ngb pagination module.
Alright, step two of refactor the interface
for GetResponseProducts.
So we currently use the interface GetResponseProducts
to map the JSON data from the REST API
over to our TypeScript objects.
So here we have underscore embedded,
we map here and in products array we map here.
So we have that coding in place already.
We simply need to kind of enhance this a bit
to support that meta data.
So the Response Meta Data
has valuable information for pagination.
So at the bottom here we have the page,
we have size elements, total pages is a number.
We saw that in one of the previous videos
as far as the data that's returned.
And we need to grab this data and map this over
to our TypeScript code.
So here let's refactor the interface to support,
the pagination meta-data.
So we have our JSON and then there's interface
and we add this new entry into our interface for page.
And then we have those four properties,
size, total elements, total pages and number.
Coz we need to capture that so we can use it
in our Angular application.
Alright, step three of adding pagination supports
to our ProductService.
So on our ProductService,
we're going to add this new method, getProductListPaginate.
We pass in parameters for pagination,
the page and the page size.
And then remember Spring Data REST supports
pagination out of the box.
So we simply have to send over the parameters
for page and size.
And then in step four we need to update our product list
to handle pagination.
So we define some new properties for pagination.
And then in our method handleListProducts,
we call the service and pass in the parameters.
And then notice here thePageNumber - 1,
because, pagination component and Angular,
the pages are 1 based
and Spring Data REST of the pages are 0 based.
So we need to kind of decrement that value accordingly
before sending it over to the backend.
Then we actually processed the result
that came from the backend.
And so when data arrives in a product service,
we set the properties based on that data
and everything on the right hand side of the assignment
is data from the Spring Data REST JSON from the backend.
And so we have to do a small thing
on the page number again, right?
The backend is 0 based,
the pagination component and Angular is 1 based
so we need to kind of add 1 to that value.
Backend 0 based frontend 1 base.
That's why I have to do the little tricky stuff here
with the math.
And that's the coding there for step four.