Okay, so let's get started with our development process.
In this video, we'll cover steps one and two
of generating the key in the self-signed cert,
and running the Angular app with a key and self-signed cert.
And so one thing I'd like for you to do now
is pause the video and follow the steps at
luv2code.com/openssl-setup.
They go through all of those steps that you need for
generating a key and the self-signed cert.
The steps are different depending on the operating system
that you're using.
We have one set of steps for Microsoft Windows,
and we have another set of steps for Mac Linux.
So be sure you walk through those steps
and get everything working in that regards.
And the end product is that you'll have a new key that's
been generated and also a self-signed cert.
Once you finish the steps there,
then you can come back to this video and continue.
Okay, welcome back.
So now you should have two new files that were generated in
this directory called SSL-localhost.
So the openssl steps generated these two files.
Localhost.crt and localhost.key.
And these are all covered in those steps
at luv2code.com/openssl-setup.
So I'm in my terminal window here.
I'm in my Angular e-commerce directory.
And what I want to do now is just kind of
view the certificate just so I can see what's out there.
I can enter this command here,
openssl, x509, no out, text, in,
and give a reference to the actual cert.
Ssl-localhost/localhost.crt.
And then I can see information about my certificate here.
So a couple of things I'll point out.
The issuer,
so I have the country, state, locality,
and it's valid starting at this date and it's valid for
365 days to 2022.
All right, so we're in good shape.
So we know that our certs been created successfully.
So now in step two,
we need to run our Angular app with the key
and the self-signed cert.
And what I need to do here is open up this file
package.json.
And then I move into the script section,
from the start command.
So right now we have our regular "ng" serve.
And I'll give the additional commands here for making
use of ssl.
Alrighty, and I'll just kind of highlight
the new items here.
So we have the part where we enable the ssl mode.
We give a reference to our key file
and we also give a reference to our certificate.
Now I can go ahead and start my application.
So I'll make use of this NPM start.
And so remember this is a new command
for starting our Angular application.
And this refers back to the start command
that we just set up in the script.
So they'll go ahead and start,
behind the scenes that does the ng serve with all the ssl
flags accordingly.
And at this point, your app has compiled successfully
and it's up and running.
And so in the next video,
we'll go ahead and start testing this out.