Alrighty, so let's go ahead
and move into our IDE and let's write some code.
So I'll move in here and the first thing
I'll do is create a new folder.
And I'll call it 05-inheritance.
So let's create a new file, Shape.ts
and so this will be for our Shape class.
So I'll export class Shape.
I'll define some private properties for _x and_y.
So I'll generate the get/set accessors for x
and I'll do a similar thing here for y.
Okay great, so I have these get/set accessors
setup for me automatically.
And I'll just kind of move this private y
and move it up to line four
just so I have my properties defined in the same location
and then my accessors down at the bottom.
And now I'll go ahead and create my constructor.
And I'll actually make use of parameter properties,
so I'll just kind of cut the private _x
and I'll do a similar thing here for private _y.
Again, we're using that little shortcut here
where we make use of the parameter properties
where they'll actually define and assign
at the same time without having to do any boiler plate code
so those are parameter properties there
so that's in good shape.
And then I'll just kind of move down here to the bottom
and I'll write the getInfo method
and I just return the x/y location for this method.
Alrighty, so this looks pretty good.
So right now I don't have a public on the method
but remember in TypeScript everything is public by default.
Okay, so we have our Shape class taken care of.
So let's go ahead and create a new file for Circle.
So I'll have export class Circle extends Shape
'cause we're using inheritance.
And so there's an error message here
so it says it doesn't know about Shape.
Okay, that means we have to import it.
So I'll just manually import it.
There are some quick fixes that you can use
to automatically import it, but I'll cover that later,
so for now we'll just manual import.
All right, so that's taken care of
let's go ahead and define our property for radius
and then we'll generate the get and set accessors.
Then I'll go ahead and define my constructor
and I'll setup the two parameters for x and y.
Those are regular parameters
and then I also do a cut/paste over here
for the parameter property for radius
and do a little cleanup up above.
Okay great, so remember that these are regular parameters,
theX and theY.
And then private _radius, that's a parameter property.
Now there's still a red x here
and so let's kind of hover it
and see exactly what the issue is.
So it says constructors for derived classes
must contain a super call.
Okay, that's fair enough.
So here we'll say super and we'll pass in theX and theY,
so we're making a super class call as required.
All right, now the next thing we want to do here
is actually override the getInfo method
and give our own implementation of that method.
So here I give a return.
I'll call super.getInfo and make a call
to the super class method and then also I'll give
my specific information radius equals and this._radius.
Okay great, so that's the coding here.
We kind of stepped back and this is the main coding here
for our Circle class, good job.