Alrighty, So step two we need
to configure the router based on our routes.
So we configure the router in the application module file.
So that's the AppModule.TS file.
And now notice the new entry here in the import section,
we have RouterModule.forRoot
and then we give the routes.
And so those are the routes that we defined earlier
in our application.
And so now the route is configured
and it knows about the routes that we've set up.
Then in step three, we define the router outlet.
So the router outlet acts as a placeholder.
It renders the desired component based on the route.
So in our previous example,
we have our menu items on the left.
You select the link and then the router outlet
that's a little placeholder, that's the area
of where the actual component will be rendered.
And then remember it only updates a section of your page,
it doesn't reload the entire page, right?
So we have a single page application.
We simply perform partial updates on our given page.
Okay, so to make this work,
then we need to update our app.component.html
to use the router outlet.
So in our app.component.html file
in the main content section here, we say router-outlet.
So again, we're saying,
"Hey, based on the router configuration,
"display the appropriate component here."
And then here's a little snippet of the different routes.
So based on a given path, show component X
at this given location.
So it'll actually create an instance
of the ProductListComponent
and then we'll display the products based
on the given category ID for that given link.
And as part of some refactoring,
we can comment out or delete the reference
to app-product-list.
We no longer need this here, directly.
This information will be updated dynamically based
on our actual router setup.
Alrighty, so in step four, we're going to set up router links
to pass the category id parameter.
So in our HTML page, we're going to set up links
to our route and pass the category id as a param.
So we have that little menu item for luv2shop,
books, coffee mugs, and so on.
We're going to set up links and then based on those links,
we'll actually have the router outlet
display the appropriate component based
on a given category ID.
And we'll pass in that category ID with the link.
So here's our app.component.html
So a little menu sidebar here, we make use
of this anchor routerLink category/1.
So based on the route configuration,
it's going to use the ProductListComponent
and will pass in that given ID.
So remember in our configuration here,
we have a /:id,
So the number one, two, and so on
that's the actual ID parameter that'll be passed in
to this ProductListComponent.
And then once the user clicks the link,
then we can also apply a custom CSS style.
This is optional, not required,
but in this example, I'll say active-links.
So that's the name of a CSS style in my styles.CSS file.
In this case, we simply make the given link bold.
But you can customize this and give it any look
and feel that you'd want.
It's any CSS that you want to apply.
Now, one thing that you may notice,
at the moment we're hard coding the categories.
But don't worry, in upcoming videos
we'll actually make this dynamic
and we'll read the category information
from the REST API that'll get the information
from the database.
So for right now, we'll simply start
with the basics and then we'll make it more advanced,
more complex in the following videos.
So don't worry, I got you covered.
Alrighty, so recall what the router outlet
when the user clicks the link,
the ProductListComponent will appear
in the location of router-outlet.
And that's based on the diagram that we have here.
And remember, it'll only update a section of the page.
It won't reload the entire page.
Now, the next step here is step five
of enhancing the ProductListComponent
to read the category id parameters.
So we need to read that information so we can use it.
So I'll set up a property called CurrentCategoryId
of type number.
And then I make an assignment here.
I say this.route
that's the activated route.snapshot,
the state of the route at this given moment in time,
.paramMap, that's a map of all the route parameters.
And then I'll say, "Hey, read a given parameter name X."
In this case, the parameter that we want to read is ID.
And this is based on the configuration
that we have set up for our routes.
So we have a :id, so that's the parameter,
ID, and that's how we actually access the parameter ID
that's being passed over.
So the parameter values are returned as a string
so we can actually use the plus symbol
to convert the string to a number.
So this is a little typescript trick here
of converting strings to number.
You simply use the plus symbol
at the beginning of that given string
and it'll do the conversion for you in the background.