Alrighty, so now moving ahead to step two,
defining the Getter methods to access the form controls.
So here for get firstName,
we return checkoutForm.get, customer.firstName.
So how did I arrive at this?
So let's break it down a bit.
So we have this.checkoutFormGroup,
so that's how that part matches up.
And then for customer, it's a group, so customer,
and then the form control is firstName.
So that's how we have customer.firstName.
And then we simply repeat the process here for lastName
and then a similar thing here for email.
And we'll actually use these Getter methods
in our HTML template when we access the form controls
to try and get the actual status
and list of errors and so on.
Alrighty, step three of updating the HTML templates
to display the error messages.
So here's the example here for firstName,
the firstName form control.
And so if the validation fails,
then let's display error messages here.
So here we have firstName.invalid.
So hey, did the validations fail
for this given form control?
And there's also some other things
that we need to be aware of here.
So we only want to display validation errors
if the user has interacted with the form.
So when the user changes the field value,
the control is marked as dirty.
When the field loses focus,
the control is marked as touched.
So let's break this down in this example here.
So firstName.dirty, so did the user change the field value?
Or firstName.touched, did the field lose focus?
So in this case we can actually display the error messages.
We need to find out which specific validation failed here.
So I can make use of the errors object.
So the errors object contains a list of validations
that failed for this given form control.
So here, I'm saying firstName.errors.required.
That says, Hey, the required validation failed.
So in that case, I can give my specific error message here
to the user, Hey, First Name is required.
And this error message will show up on the form accordingly.
And then we can do a similar thing here,
firstName.errors.minLength.
So, Hey, did the minimum length validation fail?
If so then I'll say,
Hey, First name must be at least 2 characters long.
And then you can simply repeat the process
for the other fields that you have.
And we'll actually do this here for email address.
So here I have this form control for email
and say email.invalid, so on and so forth.
And then I basically say email.errors.required
or email.errors.pattern, so that pattern.
And so we give the appropriate messages there to the user.
Alrighty, we're almost done.
In step four, I'm going to add the event handler
to check the validation on submit.
So in my onSubmit method, I basically make use
of if this.checkoutFormGroup.invalid,
then in that case, I'll say
checkoutFormGroup.markAllAsTouched.
So by touching all the fields, this will actually trigger
the display of the error messages on the actual screen.
And that's basically it there for the form validation.
So what we'll do is we'll move into the next video,
and we'll start writing this code.
And we'll start adding some validation to our checkout form.
So I'll see you in the next video!