In this video,
we'll cover application security concepts.
So this is the basic introduction to security concepts.
We're going to focus on practical results.
Now the key here,
is that this is not an A to Z reference,
because security is a huge topic.
What we'll do is kind of focus on practical results
for our application.
And we'll cover the following tasks
related to our e-commerce project.
So we'll learn how to do user login, logout with security.
We'll provide access to a special VIP page
only for authenticated customers.
And then we'll also keep track
of order history for registered customers.
And if so, we'll see how to build this in the context
of application security and we'll make use of security
with Angular and also Spring Boot.
All right, so now let's kind of look at the problem
with a given application.
We need to authenticate a user for a given application.
We also would need to know what actions a user
or app is authorized to perform,
and then we may need to delegate permissions
to another application.
So in the modern security world,
there are a couple of key terms or concepts
that you may have heard of already.
So authentication, authorization,
OAuth 2,
OpenID Connect
and JSON Web Tokens.
And we'll discuss these topics in this video.
Okay, so authentication.
This is the process of validating
whether a user or app is who they claim to be.
So normally it works by giving a username
and password for log-ins
or you can give a token or a pin
or you can make use of like fingerprint or retina scan.
And so here, you know, the fingerprint actually works
on, you know, some of the mobile devices,
but, you know, I'm just trying to think of
some other real world examples
of where you can authenticate a given person
to validate who they say they claim to be.
Now, next we have authorization.
So authorization is the process of determining
the actions a user or app can perform.
And so you can commonly think of this as roles.
Like you could have a role for a guest user.
So a guest user can do minimal actions,
maybe just read only work.
You may have an authorized user who can read
and write data in their own user account.
And then you may have an admin user
who has full access to all accounts system-wide.
So this is kind of like authorization,
what can a given user do once they log into the application
or what actions can they perform?