Okay, great, so let's go ahead and
look at our development process.
We'll actually walk through each one of
these steps here in this video.
All righty, so starting step 1 of getting the
links for the remote bootstrap files.
On our web browser we simply go to getbootstrap.com,
and this will bring us to the main bootstrap web page.
They have a link for getting started,
so let's go ahead and select that link.
And this will take us to a nice section
that has information about quick start,
and also some sample template code that we can
simply copy and paste.
I'll move down to this starter template
and I'll grab a couple of pieces of code here.
I'll grab the line here for the meta viewport
and also the line for the link.
And I'll copy those sections or snippets of code.
Okay, great, so here we go.
Step 2 of adding the links to the index.html page.
Just give me 1 second, here I have the page open.
Well, let me expand the window here for a second.
All righty, so let's move in here.
So, right after the line 4,
let's go ahead and do a paste.
All right, so that part looks good.
So there's one thing I want to clean up down on line 13,
there's another meta name=viewport,
I actually want to delete this line 'cause we
already have it up above.
So let's go ahead and delete the line here on line 13.
All right, that looks good,
and so here's the information that we have for adding
references for the bootstrap styles.
So this is pretty good.
So let's go ahead and open up
app component.html file.
And so, that's step 3 applying the bootstrap
CSS files in this template.
Basically, what I want to do here
is actually wrap all of this code inside of a div.
It's inside of a div.
And then for this given div I'm going to set
the class=container, so that's a bootstrap style,
for giving us a proper bootstrap container.
Then also for h1 I'll set the class=mt3 and also mb3,
margin top, margin bottom.
And those are all the changes that we need
here for app component.html file.
Okay, so let's go ahead and zoom in here.
Let's go to this list component.html file
and let's do a copy/paste on this file.
All right, so that's the copy so let's go
ahead and rename this copy and give it a new name.
This copy I'll call it list-bootstrap.component
and I'll remove the copy stuff from the file name.
All right, so list-bootstrap.component.html.
Just make sure that you're in the proper file,
sales person list bootstrap.component.html.
Let me expand the window here.
Now, this is step 4 of applying the bootstrap CSS
styles in the HTML table.
Up top, I'll get rid of the border=1,
and then I'll set class=table and then table-hover.
And then for thead I'll say class=thead-dark,
and so this will give us this desired view
of our HTML table.
This is pretty good it's a nice pretty table
compared to the ugly one that we had earlier.
Thanks to bootstrap.
One more thing we have to do in step 5 is
update our typescript component to reference
the bootstrap HTML template.
We have to open up our component.ts file,
our typescript file.
Up top in this file we need to update the template URL.
Instead of using the original template URL
we're going to use the list-bootstrap component.html.
That's the new file we created, we renamed
and that's the one we have our bootstrap CSS styles
applied in.
Now, when our component is processed and rendered,
it's going to use this new template URL.
All right, so this covers all of our major steps
here for our development process.
Now let's go ahead and open up a new terminal window
and let's test it out.
I just move into my project directory
and I'll start my server.
And it will automatically open up the browser page
and success, yay!
The bootstrap style are applied as desired.
We went from a very ugly HTML page to a very pretty,
beautiful HTML page.
And this is all thanks to bootstrap.
This looks really good.
I'd like to say good job.