Alrighty, so we're on step five
of developing the angular code to subscribe to data.
So we have our class product list component.
We have a field here, our products, our product array.
We have this constructor that also has a dependency
on product service, so that is injected
by making use of the private product service.
This constructor allows us to inject the given component.
And then we'll make use of the ngOnInit()
so this is like a post-constructors is called
once the given component is initialized.
We call this.listProducts().
And then the real work happens here
in this listProducts() method.
So here we say this.productService()
.getProductList().subscribe().
So once we subscribe, that'll actually invoke that method,
and it's going to invoke the method in an asynchronous fashion.
So this method will kind of run in the background.
Once all that data has been retrieved or returned,
then we'll sign that data here to our array of products.
So here I have this.products = data.
So that's the data that came back from that given service
via that rest API.
All right, so now that we have the data,
then we can display the data in an HTML page.
So my page, here I simply make use of the ngFor,
I say "let tempProduct of products",
and then I simply display the product name
and then the product unit price.
I pipe it through my currency pipe to display
the information using the U.S. dollar symbols here.
And so, if everything works out as desired,
then we'll have this given output:
JavaScript, Spring Framework, so on and so forth.
So just a very basic page.
We can make it pretty by putting it into an HTML table,
putting it into a bitweb template,
but right now we're just trying to get
the functionality of having our angular front end code
make a call to the back end Spring Boot code.
So hold your horses here, this code will not work
because there's one more thing we need to do here.
So in Step 7,
we need to add CrossOrigin support to Spring Boot.
Web browsers will not allow script code
to call APIs that are not on the same origin.
This is known as the same-origin policy.
So basically the browser will have a security issue
with any calls that you attempt to make
that are not on the same origin.
So, you may wonder, well, what is the same-origin here?
So, same-origin is composed of
the scheme or protocol, hostname, and port number.
So, even if you're on the same machine
and you have two apps running on different ports,
those are not considered the same origin.
So you have to make some additional configurations here
to allow this communication to go back and forth.
Now this same origin policy only applies
to scripts running in a web browser.
All right, because you're probably wondering, well,
we can access rest APIs, using a browser or using postman,
what's the big deal here?
This is for JavaScript code that's running in a web browser
so that's the restriction, JavaScript in a browser.
But, we can relax this security piece
by adding the Cross-Origin Resource Sharing support,
or CORS.
And so we can make this modification
on our server side application.
We can make this mod on our Spring Boot application.
All right, so let's add CrossOrigin support
to our Spring Booth application.
So in your Spring Boot Application,
you'll add an annotation to your rest API.
So in our case we're using spring data rest,
with spring data JPA,
so here we simply add the sharp product repository.
We say @CrossOrigin,
and we give the origins that are allowed.
Now remember, this is only for Javascript code
that is running in a browser.
Remember, earlier we could access all of this stuff
via a browser or via postman.
This will basically allow JavaScript code
running on local host 4200 to make a call
to our given rest API.
All right, so that's the one example there.
One thing you may wonder, well, I have multiple servers,
how can I do that?
No problem, you can simply say @Cross Origin,
and you simply give a comma-delimited list of origins
where you have JavaScript code running
that needs to call your given application.
And then you may say, well, gosh, this is just too much!
I have a lot of servers, or I really don't care who calls,
like in my rest API.
I'd like for them to be able to use it
in some JavaScript code running in a web browser somewhere.
Easy, no problem!
In that case you simply just give @CrossOrigin,
and that's it!
So by default this is a wild card,
that'll allow access from any website.
All right, so this is all some really good stuff.
We'll move to the IDE
and then we'll walk through this development process,
and we'll start writing the code.
So I'll see you in the next video, yo yo!