Alrighty, so just as a check point
I want to make sure that
you have the tools installed already.
So at this point you should already have
Visual Studio Code installed, node, npm and tsc.
If not, go to the link here on the slide,
follow the install guides and then they'll show you
how to get everything set up on your computer.
Okay, so let me go ahead and move into my files system.
And the one thing I want to do here is create a new folder
where I can place all of my training code
for these set-up videos here.
So I'll create this folder here typescript-training
but you can use any folder name,
you can give any name that you want.
And then I'll start up Visual Studio Code.
So here's the basic IDE, and I just have
all the defaults in place for right now.
And I'll go ahead and open that folder that I just created.
So I'll select my typescript-training folder.
Okay, so there we go.
So we have typescript-training folder that's open,
that looks pretty good.
I'll create a new folder underneath
the typescript-training folder.
I'll call it 01-helloworld.
I'll create a new file.
I'll call it myhelloworld.ts,
and remember the .ts is for TypeScript.
So I'll keep it real simple, I'll simply build
console.log and notice how the whole IntelliSense
code completion helps us out.
So I'll do a log, and then I'll give my message:
"Hello World."
All right, so our very basic Hello World program
using TypeScript.
So let's go ahead and open up a new terminal.
So this terminal basically gives you a shell,
and you can use this to go through
and access your code, compile the code, and run it.
So there's my new terminal.
Just resize here a bit.
So I'll go ahead and move into
this directory here 01-helloworld.
And I'll just check the directory contents here
and I see my file myhelloworld.ts, good.
And now let's compile the code, so we use that tsc command,
so I'll do a tsc on myhelloworld.ts.
And then we simply check the directory here, the output,
and we see that all right, there's the myhelloworld.js.
So remember it generates a .js file.
It's part of that transpiling process;
translating/compiling.
And so now to run the code, I use the node command,
and I give the reference to the generated .js file.
So node myhelloworld.js.
And then there's our output: Hello World.
Cool, good job.
Alrighty let's move into our editor here,
and let's just add some more code to our TypeScript file.
So I'll do a console.log and I'll just play around with
some string concatenation here.
So "Coding Gurus"...
"Time for some fun!"
And then let's go ahead and compile it one more time.
So I'll just clear my terminal window here at the bottom.
And then I will compile it once again.
So tsc myhelloworld.ts.
And then I'll run it using the node command
I run the generated JavaScript file.
And there we go. So that's our new output.
So that's awesome. So this works out just fine for us.
Now one thing I want to give you
a head's up about to be aware of.
So, only edit the TypeScript files the .ts files.
Do not edit the JavaScript file, .js.
Because remember, the .js file is generated
every time by the TypeScript compiler, all right?
So here we're developing code using TypeScript,
so simply write all your code in the TypeScript file.
Okay, that's it.
So we created our first TypeScript file,
and then we'll move into some more fun features
in the next set of videos, so I'll see you there.