Alrighty, let's have a quick discussion on Event Binding.
In our application, in order to search for products,
the user's going to enter the actual search information
in the text field and then they'll hit the search button.
So when the user clicks the search button,
we need to be able to read that text field value
and perform some operations on it.
So for example, we can take that text data and then
pass it over to our rest API for performing the search.
But we need to learn about the Angular techniques
for adding this functionality.
In Angular, you can listen for events with "event binding".
So in other languages, this is
also known as "event handling".
So here's an example, we have a button,
we want to listen for a "click" event.
So when a user clicks something
they'll call our event handler "doMyCustomWork".
So this is basically a method in our Angular component code.
This can actually be any method name that we define.
In our examples, we'll call it "doMyCustomWork".
Let's expand on this example further.
So we have our button, we're listening for the click event.
We'll call a method in our Angular component code.
And so when our Angular code--
There's the method "doMyCustomWork".
So when they click on a button, it'll call argument method.
In this example, we simple do a console.log saying,
"Hey! You pushed my button!".
Don't push my buttons!
Alrighty so looking at Reading User Input.
So we'll have this input text field and then we'll listen
for the enter key so when the user hits enter key,
we want to read that text field and do something with it.
So up top we make use of the hashtag symbol.
That's a template reference variable for "myInput".
This will give us access to the element.
And then in our component,
we'll have our method "doMyCustomWork".
And so "myInput.value", that gives you the actual text
the user typed in so then we can pass that to our
custom method as a string and then we can
display it saying hey, this is your data.
And then we use whatever that given parameter is.
So that's how we can read user input with Angular.
And extending this example, we can add a search button.
So again, we'll simply listen for a "click" event.
And then we'll call our same method here "doMyCustomWork".
And we'll pass in the text that the user typed in info.
So basically our example works if the user hits the enter
key for searching or if the user hits the search button.
So basically both of those events will call the same method.
Now you may wonder about what other events are out there.
Well there's plenty more.
There's a focus event so an element received focus.
Blur: an element has lost focus.
There's also the keyup event so any key is released.
So if you want to handle it for a specific key
like the enter key, then you make use of "keyup.enter".
And we saw an example of that in our previous code.
There's also the keydown event when any key is pressed.
And there's also the double click event
so the mouse is clicked twice on a given element.
And there's more out there so you can
go to the link here on the slide to get a list of
all of the events that you can handle and make use of.
Okay this was a quick discussion on Event Binding.
In the next section we'll actually apply it to our
eCommerce application and see how we can use this for
searching for products by keyword.