Alrighty, so let's go ahead
and get started with our development process.
In this video, we'll cover steps one and two
of creating a component
and adding a new Angular route for product details.
Alrighty, as far as housekeeping,
there's one thing we have to do first
is starting up our Spring Boot backend
if it's not already running.
So I'll just run my SpringBootEcommerceApplication.
And I want to just test some rest end points real quick
on my spring boot backend.
So I'll open up this localhost:8080/api/products/1.
This'll basically allow me
to get the product with the id of one.
Alright this looks great.
So this is actually a built-in feature of Spring Data REST.
There's no additional coding or configuration required.
You get this out of the box with Spring Data REST.
And so our Angular app will use this end point
for retrieving details for a given product.
Alright so let's go ahead swing into Visual Studio code.
And let's go ahead and cover step one of creating
a new component for product details.
Okay, I'll open up a new terminal window.
And gimme one second,
I'll kind of expand the window here for a second.
And I'll zoom in.
Let's go ahead and move into
the correct directory, angular-ecommerce.
And we'll make us of our ng generate component.
And give components/ProductDetails.
Okay great so it created the appropriate files for us.
And then we'll see under our source directory,
app, components, we should have
a new directory here called product-details.
Good, so looks pretty good.
So in step two, I need to add
the new Angular route for product details.
And so I do this in the file app.module.ts.
I'll just expand this window here for a second and zoom in.
I'll do a quick copy paste on one of these routes.
And I'll just update it here.
I'll say, products/:id.
And then the actual component
is gone be the ProductDetailsComponent.
Alright ProductDetailsComponent.
Okay great, that takes care of step two
of adding the route for the product details.