Alrighty, so let's go ahead
and get started with our Development Process.
So we'll go through these four steps here in this video.
Alright, So let's go ahead
and move into MySQL workbench
and we're going to clean up some of our data.
So I'll just tell it which database schema to use.
I'll use full-stack-ecommerce
and then we'll clean up previous database tables.
I disabled the foreign key checks
by setting that value to zero.
And then I make use of this truncate
to remove all rows from a given table.
So I'll do a truncate on the customer
and then I just do this X number of times.
Orders, order item, and also address.
And then I enable the foreign key checks.
So set the value to one.
Alright, so that's good.
We're in pretty good shape here.
And then in step two
I'm going to make the email address unique.
So I do an alter on our customer table.
I say, "Add unique email".
So here we're adding a database constraint such that,
only unique email addresses can be added
to this given table.
If not, the MySQL database will throw an error.
Go ahead and run that.
And everything runs.
We have greens all the way at the bottom.
So, we're ALK and
we're good to go.
Alright. So in step three,
we're going to add the methods
of the customer repository to
find by email.
So I'll swing into intellij.
And I need to move into my dao package,
and open up my customer repository.
So add this new method here,
find by email.
And so behind the scenes, here's what I'm going to do,
I'll select star from customer where,
email equals the email.
And again that's some supreme magic
that happens automatically.
And then remember this method returns null
if not found.
So I move over here to my service package,
and I'll open up this CheckoutServiceImpl.
So just scroll to the top.
Okay. This looks good.
So I'm in CheckoutServiceImpl right now
and I'll move down
to this place order method and I'll make some changes there.
Alright. So right here,
after this customer assignment purchase,
I get customer.
Then, I need to check to see
if this is an existing customer.
And so we do all of this based on the email address.
So I need to get the customer's email address.
And now I need to see
if this customer exists in the database
by using customer repository that
find by email the email.
And so remember that method returns null if not found.
So here I have, if customer
from DB is not equal to null,
then hey, we found them
and let's go ahead and assign them accordingly.
So I have customer equals customer from DB.
So that's my customer from DB.
And then I'm assigning it to the left-hand side customer.
Alrighty. So zooming out,
this is the new code that we just added for this feature.
Alrighty. Looks pretty good. Good job.