All righty,
so looking at our development process.
In this video, we're going to focus on steps one through three
of creating the component, adding the route,
and also updating the link for the Shopping Cart icon.
Okay, let's go ahead and swing into our IDE.
And let's open up a new terminal window.
And so I'll create this component
by saying ng generate component,
and then components/cart-details.
Okay, great, it created some files for us.
We can just verify this over here
in our angular-ecommerce project, source app,
components, cart-details.
Okay, this looks really good.
And let's move to our app.module.ts file
because this is for step two
of adding the new route for the cart details component.
So I'll move down to the routes section here.
And I'll just zoom in, and I'll just do a little copy paste
on one of the previous routes,
and I'll just make some mods to it.
So just a quick copy paste here.
And now this route is going to be called cart-details.
And it'll map over to the component CartDetailsComponent.
And just scroll up to make sure it imported properly
the CartDetailsComponent.
And yes, that's great, looks good.
And now with step three,
we're going to update the link for our Shopping Cart icon.
And so this is in our cart status component.
So I'll move moved to the cart-status.component.html.
Okay, so let's set up a link to our Angular route here,
so we'll make use of routerLink ="/cart-details."
And so now when they click on our Shopping Cart icon,
it'll actually go over to our cart details component.
And I want to do one small change here.
So in our CartDetailsComponent.html,
right now they have the basic generated code
of cart-details works, I'm just going to add
a little styling around here, some divs,
just to help us with running a quick test.
So I'll basically wrap this into a div for main content,
just to help us with placement
of this information on the screen.
And now I think I'm ready to run it or ready to test it.
And before I start the Angular code,
let's just kind of swing over
and make sure we have our Spring Boot application running.
So in our IntelliJ IDEA, the Spring Boot app
should be already running,
if not, go ahead and start it now.
Now I can go and start my Angular application.
All righty, so my app is up and running,
I can access it here in the browser.
And now I want to check the link here for our cart status.
I simply want to click this
and see what I get as far as the output.
And okay, this looks good, cart-details works.
So we know that our basic framework
for our component is in place,
now we'll add some more features to it
in the next set of videos.