Alrighty, so let's go ahead and get started.
So the first thing we'll do
is we'll create the OrderRepository REST API,
and then also go through an update configs
to make the API read only.
So on IntelJ,
we can go ahead and look at some of our backend codes.
So I'll do a quick refresher here.
I'm going to look at the entity class for Order.
So this is the one that will set the API up
based on this order class.
And so order has a reference to the actual customer.
And so we'll use this to search for orders
by customer email address.
And now I'll go ahead and move over to my dao package
and I'll create this new interface for the OrderRepository.
And we'll give the name OrderRepository
make sure it's in Interface.
And I'll give the annotation of top
for the RepositoryRestResource.
Also we'll extend the JpaRepository.
We'll give the entity type comma, the primary key type.
Order, Long.
And be sure to import the order class
from our e-commerce package.
So now, we just go through it
and we create our method name,
findByCustomerEmail, you pass it on Param named email
and we also provide our Params here for pagination support.
And be sure to import Pageable
from the springframework data domain package.
That's all the coding that we need here for this repository.
And so remember behind the scenes Spring will create a query
based on the actual method name.
Moving ahead to step two,
we're going to update the configs
to make the OrderRepository REST API read only.
And so we'll make these updates here in this config package
in this class, MyDataRestConfig.
So, when MyDataRestConfig,
we move down to this method here
configureRepositoryRestConfiguration.
Now we have some code that's already in place.
Let's just go ahead and copy one of those lines
and just paste it here
and then we'll just give Order.class.
So for this OrderRepository disable certain methods.
And we follow this process before
for a lot of our other codes.
So you understand this piece so far.
So we can go ahead and run our application
and we can test it out.
And what I'll do is I'll start up Postman
so I can send some queries to this REST API.
So, I'm really going to hit the Postman
I'll create a new request.
So, it's going to be a GET request
and I simply need to give the URL.
So just use the URL that we have here on the screen
and api/orders/search/findByCustomerEmail.
And then our parameters is email equals
and we need to give an email address
but I'm not sure which email address to use.
So let me go and check my database
and see what customer emails I have in my database.
So, I'll just swing in here to MySQL work bench,
log in, go to my table here and do a search on my customers.
And I see in this example,
I just have one customer emails demo@luv2code.com.
So, your values may be different
depending on what you use for testing.
So just use whatever that email address is
and then we can put it over here in this postman.
So demo@luv2code.com.
So just make sure that this matches
with whatever data you have in your database.
Click Send,
you got a 200 response.
So that's the success.
So this is great.
So looking at the data here, we can see the previous orders
that were processed by this given customer.
And you can always cross check this
by looking at the orders in your actual database tables.
So this looks pretty good.
So we have the REST API in place
for finding orders based on a customer's email.
So, I'd like to say good job, my friend.