Okay, so taking a look
at our development process,
so in this video we're going to cover steps one and two
of creating a new component,
and also adding the HTML template for our component.
All righty, so let's go ahead and swing into our IDE.
And what I'll do here is open up a new terminal window,
stretch out a bit,
and now I'll generate that component
by using ng generate component
and I give components/cart-status.
Okay, great so it created those files
for me accordingly, looks good.
So over here under src, app, components,
we should see cart-status, yep, there we go.
Looks great, love it.
Let me go ahead and close out this terminal window here.
Now in step two we need to add the HTML template
for our cart-status component.
So we'll do some work in the cart-status component HTML,
but actually I'll start here at the app.component.html,
our main page, so app.component.html,
that's where I'm at right now.
And let's scroll down a bit
to the section of HEADER DESKTOP.
So this is where we have our normal search component
that's already there, and also right now,
we have the cart information hard coded.
This will actually move into our cart-status component.
So I actually want to add
this new cart-status component right here
but I need the selector, I need the actual tag
to use at this location.
So I can find that out by looking
at my cart-status.component.ts
and if we looked at annotation @Component,
then there's a selector attribute, app-cart-status.
Let's go ahead and copy this
and we can use it in our app.component.html.
So I'm swinging back to app.component.html
and I'm adding in our new component.
So that's our app-cart-status.
All right, this looks good, I like it.
Now this hard-coded information,
I can go ahead and cut this, remove it,
and I'll put it into my component.
So let's go ahead and cut this code
and let's move over to our cart-status.component.html,
and let's kind of move into this file,
clear our everything that's there,
and then we'll just paste in that hard-coded information.
All right, so this is good right now.
So this is our little HTML snippet here for our cart-status.
I'll do a quick little format on this document,
kind of clean some things up,
expand my window here,
and give me one quick second, I'll do some formatting,
just put things on different lines here, one second.
All right, so there we go.
So we have the basic layout here for our total price.
I'll just change this value real quickly to 36.98,
just making this up.
I'll clean up the white space here
on the span for the quantity.
And so you're probably wondering why I changed that value.
Well, I just added the new total there
just to help us confirm that our
new cart-status component is being used.
So when we run the app,
we should see a different value there,
just so we know that, hey,
it's really getting it from this cart-status
and it's not hard-coded somewhere else in our application.
But again, right now we're just hard-coding it.
We'll actually add code in the future
to update this dynamically,
and we'll cover that in some of the upcoming videos.
All right, this looks pretty good.
I want to test this, just to make sure
my component is actually working.
So we need to swing over to IntelliJ
and run our Spring Boot application
if it's not already running.
So I'm in IntelliJ right now,
I'll go into my Spring Boot app and just get it started.
All righty, so my Boot application is up and running,
swing over to Visual Studio Code,
and I'll just open up a new terminal window
and I'll run my Angular app here.
Okay, great, so my Angular application is up and running.
Let's swing over to our browser,
access our application, and this looks good.
Great, so here's our cart-status component
that has that new value that we just added, $36.98.
So we know that it's actually using our component
and that that part's working out great.
So I feel pretty good about that, I'm happy.
Now one thing that you may have noticed in my video,
and it may happen on yours also, or maybe not,
is that we had some red errors here.
I'm like, hm,
and it says router-outlet and gives you some weird error.
This is an IDE bug.
It normally goes away if you simply restart the IDE.
So you may this, you may not,
depending on the current status of VS Code.
I simply restarted the IDE and pulled it back up
and there're no more errors.
All right, so anyway, small bug,
you may see it, you may not.
All righty, so this looks pretty good so far.
We have the basics of our component in place.
We'll continue on and we'll add some features to it.
So I'll see ya in the next video.