In this video
we'll make use of TypeScript accessors.
So currently we have our customer Class,
we have our properties for firstName and lastName,
and they're private.
And what I'd like to do is figure out,
well how can I access that data?
So since our properties are private,
we need a way to access 'em,
so we can create traditional methods
as in other programming languages.
So we can simply define getter and setter methods.
So here's an example of creating
getter setter methods in TypeScript.
So I simply define a getter method, getFirstName.
So I have the method name,
and I have the return type,
and I return this.firstName.
And then I can do a similar thing for the setter methods.
So setFirstName.
There is the method name.
There's the param type.
And then return type of void.
And we simply assign it internally.
And then I simply create an instance of my class
and then I set the data.
So I say setFirstName Greg,
and then I retrieve firstName by saying
myCustomer.getFirstName.
And a very traditional approach as far as using
getters and setters just like any other programming language
and you can do a similar thing here in TypeScript.
But TypeScript also offers an alternate syntax
that you can use.
This idea of accessors.
So you can define these special get set methods,
known as accessors, with a slightly different syntax.
(laughing)
All righty, so in our Customer class
the first thing I'll do is
I'll change my internal property names.
So for the internal property names
you can give any property name.
Some TypeScript developers use the leading underscore.
But there is nothing special about the leading underscore.
There's no special magic.
It's simply a convention.
You could actually give your internal property names
any name because they're private.
And then I go ahead and set up a get accessor.
So note the special syntax here, get space property.
And then we do a similar thing for creating a set accessor.
So again, note the syntax set space property.
And both of these accessors are public.
So that's what they'll use to access this given data.
And one thing to note about the set accessor,
there's no return type, not even void.
All righty, so these are the accessors,
these are the public accessors that you'll use
to access the given data.
But now you access the data
it's a slightly different syntax here.
All righty, so let's go ahead and use it.
So we create our customer and then I say,
myCustomer.firstName = Susan.
So this actually calls the set accessor
since we're assigning a value.
We're actually setting the given value.
So behind the scenes TypeScript will call this set accessor.
And then a similar thing here when we try
and retrieve the data or read the data,
so myCustomer.firstName.
So we're actually retrieving the data.
So it's going to call the get accessor
since we're actually accessing a value.
So they'll do this behind the scenes.
And in fact, in our Customer class,
we can actually give our internal property any name.
If I wanted to I could have these properties as x and y.
The outside code is not setting
the internal private fields directly.
Only via these public accessors for get and set.
So the public get set accessors
are still called accordingly.
All righty, so let's just go ahead and rename our fields
to the original names from the previous slides.
So just a little bit of refactoring here.
So I put back the _firstName and the _lastName.
And then also I'm going to remove public from the accessors
because if no access modifier is given,
the it's public by default.
So I'm simply just kind of cleaning up my code a bit.
All righty, so regarding compiler flags,
the get set accessor feature
is only supported in ES5 and higher.
You have to manually set a compiler flag
in order to compile the code.
So when you do a tsc you have to give --target ES5.
If you don't provide this information
you'll actually get an error where the compiler will say,
hey, this feature's only available in ES5 or higher.
So you have to explicitly give this compiler flag.
So you may have noticed that
we have a lot of compiler flags.
It's too much stuff to remember,
and it's really easy to forget.
So wouldn't it be great to set this up
in a configuration file?
And the answer's yes and TypeScript has a solution.
They have a config file called tsconfig.json.
So this tsconfigjson file defines compiler options
and project settings.
So you simply place this file
in the root of your project directory.
So here's a very simple tsconfig.json file.
And in this config we're simply
setting some compiler options or compiler flags
so we set the noEmitOnError to true and target for es5.
And so if you don't want to manually create this file,
you can also generate a template for this configuration.
So in your directory and your project
you simply say ts init and it'll generate a default
tsconfig.json file.
And then you simply edit the tsconfig.json file accordingly
for your given project requirements.
And then once your project has a tsconfig.json file,
then you can compile it by simply giving the tsc command.
And there's no need to give the names
of your TypeScript files.
By default it'll compile all *.ts files.
And there's additional configurations
you can set for the tsconfig.json file
you can view the documentation to learn all of the details.
Simply visit the link here www.luv2code.com/tsconfig-docs
and I'll redirect you to the official
tsconfig documentation.
All righty, so just to kind of wrap up here,
so we're making use of accessors, the get sets,
and we have our fields that are private.
We make use of these accessors,
get space firstName, set space firstName.
And then we make the assignments,
and behind the scenes TypeScript will call
the appropriate accessors for getting and setting the data.
All righty, so let's go ahead and move into our IDE
and let's write the code here,
and let's test it out.
So I'll see ya in the next video.