Alrighty, so we're moving right along.
In this video, we'll cover step two
of creating a CheckoutService.
Basically making the REST API call
to the Spring Boot backend.
So the first thing I'll do is I'll generate the service.
I use ng generate service services slash checkout.
And then we can see in this services subdirectory,
it created a checkout service for us.
So the first thing I want to do is set up my purchase URL.
Basically the URL to that Spring Boot backend
REST end point.
And also our class needs to make use of the HTTP client,
so let's go ahead and inject that into the constructor.
Now let's define the method, placeOrder,
that'll pass in a purchase.
We'll make this observable.
Now we'll say any, basically any return type for this one.
Ah, the red squigglies under the observable,
that's because we haven't returned anything yet,
so once we do the return then it'll go away.
So here I'll say return, this dot httpClient dot post,
remember we're going to post to that REST end point.
And so we'll send this to that purchase URL,
and pass over that purchase object.
And that's basically it there for the CheckoutService.