Alrighty, so moving along with our
development process, in this video we'll start work on
step three of adding the router links to
the product-list-grid HTML page.
Alrighty, let's swing into our IDE and let's open up
the file 'product-list-grid.component.HTML'.
Just expand my window here.
All right so moving to the section where we loop
over the collection of products,
I want to add a link on the actual product image
and also the actual product name.
So let's just move in here and let's add a link
on the product image.
So I'll set up my router link.
/products/tempproduct.id
All right so that takes care of that first item
of adding a link on the product image.
And then I just repeat the same for the actual product name.
I'll let you just copy the line with the router link
and then paste it down here.
And then just fix up my ending anchor tag.
Okay great so this covers the work of adding a link
on the product name.
So this looks pretty good.
Alright let's just take a quick look at our product details
component.HTML
So right now it says "product detail works"
but I want to add some divs and styling around it.
Just so it'll show up properly in my application.
So give me one second here, I'll set up two divs
for this example.
So I'll set up a div for the detail section.
And I'll also set up a div for container fluid.
I'll simply more the paragraph inside of the divs
and I'll just do a quick and dirty example
here of setting up some of the CSS styles.
And I'll do it in line but don't worry
this is dirty for right now,
I'm just doing this for a real quick test,
we'll clean it up in some of the later videos.
But for right now, this is mainly for doing a quick test.
So I just have the margin top of 100px.
All right so let's save this and run this application
just to test it out.
Alrighty so lets go ahead and swing to our web browser
and let's access our application running on port 4200.
And then when we click on the link
for one of these products here, yes!
This is good progress.
So we have the links going to our product details component.
Now, there's not much data here (chuckles).
We'll actually add some of the product details
in some of the upcoming videos.
but at least we have our links working
between our master page and our actual details page.
But don't worry, we'll flesh this out
in some of the upcoming videos.
All right, good job.