Okay, so let's go ahead and get started
with our development process.
In this video we'll cover step one
of creating an interceptor.
Okay, so let's go ahead and move
into a terminal window here.
Move into our appropriate directory,
and let's use the Angular CLI for generating the service.
So NG generate service, services slash auth interceptor.
All right, so that's been generated.
We can look into our services directory
and see that there's an auth interceptor service dot CS.
Okay, great.
Okay, so let's go ahead
and implement the interceptor interface.
All right, so that's in place.
Now notice here we have an error on this class.
Kind of just hover over it for a bit,
and it says that it incorrectly implements the interface,
'cause a property's missing of intercept.
All right, so that's the method that we have to implement
for this given interface.
So we just use the IDE to kind of help us out with that.
Now go ahead and add some of my coding here.
I'll say returned from this dot handle access,
and we pass in the request comma next.
So I'll just use some of these IDE tips here.
So I'm going to go ahead and clean up
the params for this handle access.
I'll come back to this in a second.
Let's get this lined up just for a moment.
And I'll set this up as private async.
Async function here or method.
We pass in those parameter types here,
request of HTTP request.
Next HTTP handler.
And this is going to return a promise.
Alrighty, so this looks pretty good.
I still have this error message up top
regarding the request.
Oh yeah, simply have to just use the right parameter name.
There we go, request.
Easy fix.
So now we have the basic stuff in place for this one.
So you can just use this as a checkpoint
for your coding for now.