Alrighty so let's go ahead
and run our application and test it out.
So we have the app running.
Let's go ahead and test this with Postman.
And if you remember, in some of the previous videos
we had some sample JSON
that we would use to test the checkout.
So you may already have the sample request still set
up and Postman, if not
I'll show you how you can download this sample JSON file.
So just swing over to your browser
and go to this link that I have here on the slide.
And this will download a zip file that has
that sample JSON in there for you.
So in a zip file,
there's a file called sample-purchase.json.
So it's just a plain text file.
You can just go ahead and open up with any one
of your text editors and just copy that information.
And then you can paste that
into the body of a given POST request.
So be sure you put
in a body, choose raw and make sure the type is JSON.
So in this example, I'll go through
and change some of the customer information.
So I'll set up a reference here
for John Doe and then his email is john.doe@luv2code.com.
Alrighty, that looks pretty good.
And before I run it, I actually want go through
and just double check some things in my database
just to make sure my database tables are empty.
So I'm moved back over to my SQL work page
and I will go through and check my customer table.
All right.
So that's empty, good.
I do a similar thing here for the orders table.
Okay, great.
So you can check all the others too
but everything's empty right now
because we ran those truncate commands earlier.
So let's go ahead and send this over
and then we get our order tracking number.
All right.
That part looks good.
And then go over to my database
do a query here for customer, right.
That's John Doe fine.
And we should have an order there.
Okay, great.
So that's in place.
That part works.
It's mapped to customer ID of one
and John Doe is customer ID of one.
Okay, cool.
Now let's go through and send that again.
And so hopefully we only have one customer entry here.
Okay. Good success.
So there's only one customer.
We don't have multiple customers
with the same email address.
So we're reusing that existing customer.
All right. That's good.
Now under orders, we should have a new order.
That's tied to this given customer ID and okay good.
Here's our new order tracking number
and tied to customer ID of one.
Excellent. So that's all tied to John Doe.
Good, good.
I'm happy so far.
Do one more send, actually two more sends.
So we should have just one customer here
and should have a total of four orders.
Okay, great.
And then all these orders are tied to customer ID of one.
Okay. Good stuff.
Now let's duplicate this tab
and we'll keep all of the same data
except for we'll change the customer information.
So we'll change the first name,
last name and email address.
So we'll set up susansmith@luv2code.com.
And then we'll send this across.
All right.
So we have this, order tracking number.
Great. Go over here and do a query.
Hey good,
so we have this new customer, Susan Smith ID of two.
That's great.
Check the orders here.
We have this new order that came
in and that's where customer ID of two for Susan Smith.
Okay. So this is looking pretty good.
We can swing back over
and do one more send for John,
customer data
and then orders
and then we see this order,
this is for customer ID of one.
So, all that part is working.
So the data's coming together as desired.
So our feature is up and running
and it looks pretty good.
I like it.
Good job.