Alrighty.
So this looks pretty good.
I'm getting a bit excited here.
Let's go ahead and run our application
and test out our secure connection.
Okay, so I have my application up and running.
Swing over to my web browser,
and I will access the secure version of my application.
So I'll go to HTTPS, colon,
localhost 8443.
That's based on information from our configuration,
our port number, slash api, slash products.
And we pull that up,
and oh, gosh.
We get this scary message again, right?
But, we've seen this before, right?
And so for dev purposes, this is okay.
We're only being flagged
because we're using a self-signed certificate, all right.
So the same thing we saw on the Angular side,
we're seeing over here on the Spring Boot side.
So don't be alarmed.
Everything's okay because we're simply testing
on localhosts with self-signed certs.
Now, I'm going to show you one little trick
that you can use on Chrome.
So, Chrome has a setting to allow self-signed certs
on localhost.
So, you won't get that scary page every time.
Basically, in order to do this, you go into the URL,
you enter Chrome slash flags.
This will bring up all the various flags
that you can set for Chrome.
And then we'll search for this flag called
allow-insecure-localhost,
and we'll actually enable that flag.
So here's the process.
So, in our browser here up top,
we'll enter chrome, colon, slash, slash, flags.
And this is simply a little shortcut
to access special configuration flags for Chrome.
And then to search for flags,
we'll type in allow-insecure-localhost.
As mentioned here, it allows for invalid certificates
or self-signed certificates to work
on localhost without the scary messages.
Simply move over here and select enabled.
And once you've set this,
then you have to relaunch your browser
or restart the browser for those settings to take effect.
Okay so, I've kind of done the restart here.
Now, if we go into the URL,
and if we enter our secure server here,
https,
localhost, 8443,
slash, api, slash products,
then we should be able to access it without
the scary messages.
And success.
Great.
So now, we know that our Spring Boot app is running
on the backend with https.
Now up top left where it says not secure
that's simply because we're using a self-signed cert,
but we are using https in this example.
So, I'd like to say congrats,
my friend.