All righty, so let's go ahead and move in here
looking at our development process.
In the first step, we're going to modify
our Spring Boot application to expose the entity IDs.
Let's go ahead and swing in here.
Let's move into our Java IDE IntelliJ.
And let's scroll down here and move
into our src, main, java directory,
open our SpringBootEcommerceApplication.
I want to first run my application as is
just to take a look at the REST response,
and then we'll make some modifications,
and we'll check the new results.
All righty, so my app is up and running.
I'll swing over to my browser,
and I'll simply look at the product categories.
So I go to localhost:8080/api/product-category.
All righty, so it's up and running here.
And one thing to note here is that there is no entity ID
at the productCategory level.
We simply have the categoryName, but no categoryID.
Let's swing back into our IDE here,
and let's go ahead and modify our MyDataRestConfig file.
Zoom out here, expand my window,
so just as a check point, we're in MyDataRestConfig.
So the first thing we need to do is
autowire our JPA entity manager.
Effectively, I'm injecting the JPA entity manager.
And in this particular example,
the use of Autowired is optional
since we only have one constructor,
but I'll go ahead and leave it there just to be explicit.
All right, so this code here handles
the autowiring of our JPA entity manager.
Then I'll move down
to my configureRepositoryRestConfiguration method.
And I'll call an internal helper method
to help us expose the IDs.
Let's go ahead and scroll down to the exposeIds method.
We're going to get a collection of all entity classes
from the entity manager.
I simply use entityManager.getMetamodel.getEntities.
Next, I'm going to create an array list of those entity types.
This code basically just creates an empty array list.
And we'll populate it in a second.
Then we'll go through,
and we'll get the entity types for the entities.
So I do a for loop, and I loop over those entities.
Then I simply use entityClasses.add,
and I give tempEntityType.getJavaType.
Then finally, I'm going to expose the entity IDs
for the entity/domain types.
I simply take that entityClasses
and simply convert it to an array.
And then I say config.exposeIdsFor,
and then I give it that array of classes
to expose the IDs for, or those given domain types.
That's basically it here for exposing the IDs
for our entities using Spring Data REST.
Swing back over to our application,
just do a reload on this page.
All right, this looks great!
So we have the entity ID at the productCategory level,
so we have the id and the categoryName.
And a similar thing down here for Coffee Mugs.
We have the ID and also the categoryName.
So now our REST API is exposing the entity IDs,
and it gives us easy access to this data.
So I'd like to say, good job so far!