In this video we'll cover TypeScript variables.
So TypeScript has some basic types.
So there's boolean, true/false values.
There's number, supports integer and floating point numbers.
String, for text data.
You can enclose it in a single or double quote.
Any, supports any datatype assignment.
And there are some other more advanced items,
and you can see the details at www.typescriptlang.org.
Alrighty, so how do you define a variable in TypeScript?
So the basic syntax, you use the let keyword,
you get the variablename: type = initial value.
So as an example here I'll say let found: boolean = true;
So here, found is the variablename, boolean is the type,
and then true is the initial value.
And let's look as some other examples of
defining variables here.
So we have let found: boolean = true;
So the values here could be true or false.
Let grade: number = 88.6;
And the values here could be 73, 64.5, 100,
so integer or decimal numbers.
Let firstname: string = "Annup;",
or let lastname: string = 'Kumar;.'
So you can use double quotes for the strings
or single quotes, totally up to you.
Now the TypeScript let keyword.
So we're using the new typescript let keyword
for variable declarations,
as opposed to the traditional JavaScript var keyword.
The JavaScript var keyword had a number of gotchas
and pitfalls, such as scoping issues, capturing,
shadowing, and so on.
So the new Typescript let keyword helps
to eliminate those issues and so in this video series
I'll use the let keyword throughout.
Now, TypeScript is strongly typed.
So here I set up the variables with their given types
and so I can assign it to different values,
as long as it's of that given type, so this would be okay.
So I could say found = false, that's okay.
Grade = 99; firstname = 'Eric'; and lastname = 'Noh';
Right?
So this all kind of matches up with the types
that we've defined earlier.
So this is a-okay, no problems.
But now we could encounter some problems
if we try and assign something with a different type.
All right, so here if I say found = 0; grade = "A";
then it's a type mismatch, because it doesn't match
the given type we initially defined
this variable for.
And firstname = false; and lastname = 2099;
this will also generate compellation errors
because of type mismatch.
And this is actually really good,
it's great that the compiler is finding these errors
at compilation time as opposed to waiting until run time.
So this is a feature about TypeScript that I really like.
Now TypeScript also has the any keyword.
So I could say let mydata: any = 50.0;
so that means we can assign different values of any type.
(laughs) Okay.
So I could have myData = false;
myData = 'Eric';
myData = 19;
And this will all pass the compiler, (laughs) okay.
So this is okay.
But I'd like to say, be careful because you lose type-safety
and you start to lose a lot of the features of TypeScript.
So you may wonder, well when would I use any?
Well you can use any for like generics.
So if you're setting up a list, or an array,
that can have different types of data,
then you can set it up using any.
Alrighty, so as far as displaying output
you can simply use the console.log.
So here is some examples.
So here I have a console.log found; so it will print out
whatever that boolean value is.
It'll say console.log "The grade is " + grade;
so string concatenation here.
And also you can real get fancy
the string concatonation.
console.log "Hi" + firstname + " " + lastname;
So this will give us the output here, true,
the grade is 88.6, and Hi Anup Kumar.
Alrighty, so then as far as running the app,
so we have this file here of sample-types.ts,
I compile the code using tsc, give the name
of the TypeScript file.
So remember this generates a .js file,
so I can run this by saying C:\&gt; node sample-types.js.
And remember we run the .js file,
the generated JavaScript file.
And this will give us the ouput true, the grade is 88.6,
and Hi Anup Kumar.
Alrighty, you can also make use of template strings.
So let's look at the previous example
that we had a little bit earlier.
And so the concatenation could become clunky
for very long strings, and you may have seen
this in other programing languages.
So we can make use of template strings here.
So I could say console.log `Hi + $firstname $lastname;
So notice here the difference, I make use of backticks,
all right, and then I say hi,
and then to reference a variable,
I make use of ${ and I give whatever the value here.
So this is very useful for long strings
with a lot of concatenation.
So instead of doing all the plus, plus, plus stuff
you simply create your template string
and then you reference your variables accordingly.
So, kind of cleans up your code a bit
If you have a very long string with a lot of concatenation.
Okay, so this is all really good stuff.
In the next video we'll move into the IDE
and we'll write some code.
So I'll see you there.