So OAuth 2 is an authorization framework
that enables applications to have limited access
to a resource on behalf of a resource owner, the user,
for example you may have had certain scenarios
where you want it to share images
from your Google Drive to another application.
And you may have used some
of the links within the application,
the browser will prompt you says,
Hey, this given app, and this example here,
Cool Course Uploader wants to view and manage files
in your Google drive and you can give yes or no
if you want to allow them to have permissions to do that.
So behind the scenes OAuth 2 has being used
to provide this type of functionality.
So let's kind of look at this with an example here.
So we have this resource owner with this protected resource,
this client app, and this authorization server,
all of these players here are going to kind of play together.
So the resource owner in the top left, that's the user,
okay, like your user account.
Over on the top right, the protected resource,
that's the Google Drive with your files and so forth.
The client app in the bottom left
that's maybe some application that you're using
to try and integrate with your Google Drive
and then the authorization server in the bottom right,
this is the person who will actually
have information as far as the permissions and roles
and so forth as forth,
as what a user can do for accessing different resources.
So those are the big players here.
Now let's look at a nice sequence diagram
to see how they all play together.
So we have this resource owner
and we have this client application.
So the client app says,
"Hey I need to request authorization.
"So, hey user can I access your Google Drive
"to do X, Y and Z?"
And the resource owner can grant authorization
and then sends it out to the authorization server.
So the authorization server will provide an Auth token,
to the client application.
The client app will use that Auth off token
to also requests a access token.
So this access token will actually have the details
as far as how they can access this given resource
and also we'll have details as far as what they can do.
So then they'll send over the access token
to the protected resource, and then they can go ahead
and use the actual resource and so forth.
At our very high level,
this is how the interaction or interchange works
use of OAuth 2 for authorization.
So now we have OpenID Connect.
So OpenID Connect is an identity layer on top of OAuth 2.
So OAuth 2 really only provide support for authorization,
OpenID Connect will allow you to have authentication.
So basically this allows clients to receive
identity information about authenticated resource owners
or users, and so they'll provide a special ID token
that has information about the user, other details
and anything else that's been published
via the authorization server.
So I've been mentioning a lot about tokens.
Well, there's a standard way of describing a token
and that's using the JSON Web Token or JWT.
And then also just a quick little side note here, JWT,
you may hear some people also refer to this as, JAWT,
J-A-W-T as far as pronouncing it.
So it's up to you if you want to use JAWT or JWT.
It's an open standard that defines
a self-contained way of describing tokens
at a secure and digitally signed to guarantee integrity.
And it's used by OAuth and OpenID Connect.
And so this token is kind of the item that's passed
back and forth, like in that previous example,
I said as far as OAuth tokens, access tokens, ID tokens,
they all make use of the standard way
of describing the tokens using JSON Web Tokens.
So this JSON Web Token,
well-defined way of describing the format of a token.
So we have a header, that basically describes the algorithm
and the type of token that they're using.
The payload, so in this case,
any type of content here, in this case we can have a name
for an identity token, Susan Public.
And then we can have the actual signature.
So these JSON Web Tokens like I mentioned earlier,
they're signed to preserve or guarantee
the integrity of the token.
Alright, so this brings us up to authorization server.
So what exactly is an authorization server?
Well, at a very high level you can say that
an authorization server can generate tokens
and also define security policies.
Now, not all authorization servers are created equal.
Some offer more features than others.
You can actually create some very simple solutions
for authorization servers where you could create
your own simple solution with code
and you can run all the low-level coding for that.
So I normally recommend against doing this because,
you could easily expose,
your code could be vulnerable to some security holes
or flaws or whatever.
So you can do the very basic, you know, hobby project,
we can project with Auth server, but for anything real time,
you need a more enterprise solution.
So regarding real-time enterprise solutions
these are off the shelf solutions
for companies that specialize in security.
So that's all they do every day is security.
They have full-time employees
who simply focus on writing secure code
or providing secure services.
They make use of these services via cloud-based solutions
and also on-premise solutions.
And then we'll take a look at some of these solutions
in the upcoming videos.
Now, as I mentioned earlier,
this security is a huge topic, very broad, very wide.
So if you'd like to get more info on OAuth 2,
you can go to oauth2.net, for OpenID Connect, openid.net
and also JSON Web Tokens at jwt.io.