Alrighty, so let's go ahead and get started.
Let's look at our development process.
So in this video, we're going to start with step one
of specifying the validation rules for the form controls.
Alrighty. So let's go ahead and swing into our IDE
and let me zoom in here.
So I'll move into my source directory
and I'll open up the code for our checkout component.
So I'll open up the code for a checkoutcomponent.ts.
I'll expand my window here.
And what we'll do is we'll move down to our ngOnInit map,
and then this is where we'll do our work.
So primarily here on lines 35 and 37 for first name,
last name, email, we'll add those validation rules.
So I'll start with first name for right now.
And remember we create a new form control.
We give the initial value
and then we also specify our validators.
So the initial value is just an empty string
and then we give an array of validators.
So for this example, we'll have validators.required,
and also validators.minlength.
And we'll have minlength of two.
Alrighty. So that looks pretty good.
And for last name, we want to do a similar thing.
So let's just go ahead and copy this code for first name,
and we'll do a similar thing for last name.
So just a little copy paste here.
All right, so that's good.
So both first name and last name.
Though both of those fields are required
with minimum length of two.
With email, we'll do something similar,
but we'll make some slight changes here.
So again, we create the new form control
and then for email, it's a required field,
but we'll also make use of regular expression patterns.
So I'll kind of drop this down to a separate line because
I've a lot of coding here to type
for the pattern item in particular.
So I'll do validators.pattern,
and I give the actual pattern as a string.
Let me just kind of clean up some of the extra space there.
And I'll put the actual pattern in quotes.
And so now I actually need to put in the real pattern.
So I have it here on the screen.
There's, it's a big long string here
and this pattern for matching on email.
So I'll talk more about this pattern in a second,
but for now, just go ahead and type in what I have here
on the screen.
And I'll give a high level discussion of this in a second.
And if you need to feel free to pause the video now,
to type this text and make sure you get it exactly right,
like I have here on the screen.
Alrighty, so you're probably looking at this
and you're wondering, "Oh my gosh, what is this?"
"It looks like a totally different language."
And it is.
Regular expressions is a separate topic all to itself,
kind of beyond the scope of this course,
but I'll give you a quick overview
as far as how this pattern is used in our example.
So we're using this pattern
to match on valid email address formats.
So for example, anil.public@gmail.com.
So looking at the pattern here,
and I'll kind of break it down at a very high level.
The first section here says, "Hey, match on any combination
"of letters and digits with an optional period."
So we can have like a anil.public.
Then we have the at symbol, okay.
Kind of separating that email address portion.
And then the next section here says matching any combination
of letters and digits with a period.
So gmail. or yahoo. or whatever.
And then for the domain extension basically says,
we can have two to four letters, A to Z,
and that'll be the actual extension.
And that'll kind of give us the basics here,
of matching on like anil.public@gmail.com.
Now regarding the domain extension,
I know there are other high level domain extensions
that are longer than four characters.
So feel free to adjust this regular expression as needed,
if you need a much longer extension there for your example.
But this will cover the basics
for the actual domain extensions,
and also cover the basics here for email addresses.
So this is a very common regular expression pattern
that you'll find for matching on email addresses.
And even if you do a Google search,
you'll find this very pattern exactly like this,
or a very similar pattern.
Now you're probably wondering, "Gosh, I'd like to
"get more details on all this
"regular expression stuff."
So there's a free tutorial available
online at regexstutorials.com.
They kind of walk you through the steps.
They talk about all the special characters here,
like the caret, the square brackets,
the backslash, and so on.
And nice interactive examples to kind of help get you up
to speed with regex.
And also there's some really good tutorials
online at YouTube, if you need to go
and get more details on this.
But for now, we'll kind of take this as is,
and then we'll use this given regex pattern for
matching on email address formats.