In this video,
we're going to cover angler environments, and in particular,
how to add a new environment.
In the previous videos, we saw the use of environment files,
so we saw the source environments directory,
environment dot TS, and environment prod dot TS.
And in environment dot TS, that's the default environment,
we can add our own custom configurations there.
And we also have the dot prod TS.
That's for the production environment.
And here we can add our own custom configurations
for production.
And then we'd actually run our application with the
environment configuration so to run with the default,
we simply give the command NPM start and that'll use
environment dot TS in the background.
And then to run with the production configuration,
we simply did an NPM start and we specify configuration
equals production.
And so in the background,
it'll use environment dot prod dot TS.
Now you may have some questions such as
how does it work behind the scenes?
And how are the filenames mapped to an environment?
And also how can I add a new environment?
And we'll actually answer these questions in this video.
All right, so let's take a look behind the scenes.
The environment configurations are defined
in the the angler dot json file.
The angular CLI tool added entries
for the production configuration in the file initially
when we created the project.
So in his final angler dot json,
there's already an entry here
for configurations for production
and that's the actual configuration name.
And then here, they also specify file replacements.
So let's say replace environment dot TS
with environment dot prod dot TS.
Now during processing for the production configuration,
it'll actually load the file environment prod dot TS.
So we don't really change anything on the file system.
We don't replace files on the file system.
It's simply saying, hey,
when you load the environment file,
load environment dot prod dot TS, okay,
so mainly for loading the given file
or referencing the file.
And then also in the serve section of the angular dot json,
it defines the actual runtime support.
So there's another section here in the file serve,
and we have configurations here and there's also an entry
for the production configuration.
So that's the configuration name.
And this is the actual name that we'll reference
from the command line when we start the application.
So when we say NPM start configuration equals,
that's the production entry that we'll reference here.
And then we have information here for our browser target
and this basically references the configuration defined
on the previous slide.
So on the previous slide here,
we had a configuration entry
and those two configurations there have to match up.