All righty, let's go ahead and get started
with our development process.
So the first thing that we'll do
is we'll install ng-bootstrap.
And actually I want to make a small digression here.
I want to check my REST API Endpoints for Pagination,
just to make sure they're up and running
and just to make sure that they're giving me
the appropriate Response Metadata.
All righty, so let's go and swing into IntelliJ,
let's go ahead and run our Spring Boot application
if it's not already running.
All righty, so our app is up and running.
Let's go ahead and open up a browser
and let's access the endpoint here,
Local host 80 80, API products and then we make use
of those Pagination Parameters for a page and size.
So here I'll start with page equal zero size equals 10.
Okay great, so we're getting our products back
from our REST API, That looks pretty good.
And if we move to the bottom,
we'll see the Response Metadata for Pagination.
So we have page, size, total elements,
total pages and number.
And then I can change the actual size here
so instead of size equals 10, we'll say size equals 500
so just a really large number here.
And again, we get our products and then scrolling
down to the bottom we can see the Response Metadata.
And so here, size of 500 total elements is 100
so there's only one page
and we're currently looking at page zero.
All right, so just the basic idea
of accessing those REST API Endpoints
and seeing those Pagination Response Metadata inaction.
All right, so let's go ahead and swing
over to Visual Studio Code so we can start
with some Angular development.
And so this is kind of the step one here
of installing ng-bootstrap.
And to do this work we'll open up a new terminal window,
and let me expand this window and zoom in a bit.
And so the first thing I'll do
is I'll install the Angular localize,
a new feature required for Angular 9 and a higher.
All right, so that looks good.
Now go through and actually install ng-bootstrap.
All righty, so we have ng-bootstrap installed
I'll close off my terminal window,
and now I'll make this one other modification
of updating my app module ts to do import on the Ngb module.
Let me expand this window here for a second,
so I'll just make an entry here in the import section
and I'll do an import here for Ngb module.
Alrighty. So let me copy this strain Ngb module
and let's move down to our import section and paste it.
So by placing this in the import section,
it makes the export declarations
of the Ngb module available in the current module.
And so that's why you have to place it here for the imports.
All right, I'll just kind of scroll up to the top just
to make sure everything looks okay.
So we have the ng-bootstrap there Okay, that's fine.
And then scrolling down to my ng-module,
making sure that I have Ngb module for ng-bootstrap.
All right, so this looks pretty good, good job so far.