Alrighty, so let's go ahead
and move along with our Development Process.
So in this video, we're going to cover steps 1.2
and 1.3 of handling the reviewCartDetails()
and then we'll also cover step two of updating a CartService
by changing Subject to BehaviorSubject.
All right, so let's go ahead and move
into checkout.component.ts and our ngOnInit() method
we're going to write some codes to call reviewcartDetails().
So this.reviewCartDetails().
Now this is a new method, we haven't declared it yet,
we're simply just putting a reference in for right now.
And so the IDE tells us about the error, Yep, we know,
and then we will allow the IDE to help us
by declaring the method for our reviewCartDetails().
Awesome.
So it just created that method for us.
Let me try and scroll down and find out where it's at.
Let's see, can't find it, silly me.
I'll just go back to the top and I'll say reviewCartDetails
and I'll simply say, Hey, go to the Definition.
I should've did that from the beginning.
All right, great.
So there's the method,
so I buried it somewhere in the middle.
Yikes.
So, it has some placeholder stuff here, I'll remove that
and so basically what we want to do here
in reviewCartDetails() is that we want to subscribe
to the subjects on the cartService.
So I want to subscribe to cartService.totalQuantity
and also subscribed to cartService.totalPrice.
And whatever data's returned
then I'll simply assign it accordingly.
I'll simply say this.totalQuantity equals
the data returned, totalQuantity.
And we've seen this coding before
with some of our other coding for subscribing.
And I'll simply do a similar thing here for totalPrice.
So totalPrice.subscribe().
Alrighty, so this looks pretty good.
So we have the subscriptions set up
for totalQuantity and totalPrice.
Now let's just test our application real quick,
moving to Mouse Pads, I'll add some items here to the cart
and on the Checkout
and move all the way down to my Reviewing Your Order
and, that's strange.
Now, remember, since the checkout component
is instantiated later in the application
it's going to miss out on the previous messages
so we're still going to get these zeros
for total price and total quantity,
so we need to somehow get a replay
or somehow get the last message that we'll send across.
And remember earlier in the videos we said,
BehaviorSubject is the one that we want to use
for this given scenario.
Alright, so Let's swing back into our IDE
and this is step 2.1
of changing Subject to BehaviorSubject.
And so we'll do this work inside of our cart.service.
And it's a very simple change here, right?
So we just replaced Subject with BehaviorSubject,
and then I simply give the initial value of zero.
And then I can simply copy paste this
and do the same thing for totalQuantity.
Alright, so that's in place, that looks pretty good.
So newBehaviorSubject and we specified the initial value
of zero for a price and quantity.
All right, so let's go ahead and swing back
into our browser and test this out.
Let's add some items to the cart, do a Checkout
and we'll scroll down to our Review Your Order section
and success!, alright.
So we're getting the quantity and the price
and the reason we're getting this information now is that
even though the checkout components subscribe late
we're making use of BehaviorSubject,
so they're going to send the most recent or the latest event
or message to this given component.
Alrighty, so I'd like to say "Good job my friend".