All right.
So we have our CheckoutService finished.
Let's go ahead and work on our CheckoutComponent.
So we'll update it, we'll inject the CheckoutService,
and we'll also make use of a router
for helping us with some of our navigation.
So let's move down to our checkout.component.ts.
And let's move down to our constructor,
so we can inject the checkoutService and the router.
So I'll inject the checkoutService,
and also inject the router.
All right.
So let's see checkoutService.
No quick fixes.
Okay, that's interesting.
I may have to do this manually for the import.
So you may have better luck than me,
but I'll just manually do the import here, so...
Here I'll say checkoutService,
and then checkout.service.
Okay, that's great.
That takes care of that issue.
Okay, good.
Now we'll spend the rest of our time
down in the onSubmit method.
So let's scroll down to onSubmit.
So inside of this if statement checking for form validation,
if it's invalid, we do all the mark as touched,
but we also want to just do a return,
meaning, hey, don't execute anything else in this method.
We're done processing.
So be sure to put that return statement there in that if.
Also, I'll clean up all of these console.log statements.
You can keep them if you want.
I'm simply trying to just save screen real estate here.
Now I'll go ahead and write some quick comments to myself
just to keep myself on track.
Alrighty, so that looks pretty good here
as far as all of our comments, as far as populating data.
Now we can make a call to the REST API,
based on all this form data we've collected and populated.
Alrighty, so that's the big game plan
of what we're going to do.
In the next video, we'll start adding the code for it.
Alrighty, I'll see you there.