Alrighty, so that covers how it works behind the scenes,
and also how the filenames are mapped to an environment.
The next question is, well, how can I add a new environment.
So going beyond the default, beyond the dot prod,
how can I add a brand new environment.
So we have our angular application.
We already have the dev default set up.
We already have prod set up.
We see how that part works.
I like to add a new environment here called QA,
and I'm going to run the Spring Boot back in
on a different port in the QA environment.
So those would be on localhost:9898,
so running it on a different port.
So at the bottom here, I'd like to say,
npm start configuration equals qa,
and then that should have the angular app
use the URL for the given QA application,
or the QA environment.
Okay, so here's our development process.
So in step one, we're going to create an environment file
called environment.qa.ts.
And then we'll define a configuration in the angular.json
for the build section.
And we'll also define a configuration in angular.json
for the serve section.
And then finally we'll run our application
with the environment configuration.
Okay, step one of creating the environment file
for environment.qa.ts.
So know that our Spring Boot app
is running on a different port, port 9898.
We'll create this file here, environment.qa.ts.
We'll add our custom environment configurations here.
And so we had this luv2shopApiUrl,
So be sure to use the same name for that entry.
And then we give the value here
that we'll use for the QA environment,
because we know that our Spring Boot app
is running on port 9898, in the QA environment.
And then in step two,
we're going to define the configuration
and the angular.json for the build section.
Now the angular.json file is a really large file
with a lot of nested entries here.
So this is kind of the path on how to
navigate into the angular.json file.
So we'll move to the path projects&gt;angular-ecommerce&gt;
architect&gt;build&gt;, and then configurations.
And that's how we'll add our work here
for this build section.
So here's a snippet here of the angular.json file.
So under configurations,
then we'll add this new entry here for qa.
So that's our configuration name,
and we can actually use any configuration name.
I could call it qa, I could call it beta test,
I could call it west coast.
You can give any name here that you'd like.
And then I'll set up the fileReplacements here.
So I'll say replace environment.ts with environment.qa.ts.
And so remember again,
during processing for the qa configuration,
it's going to load the file environment.qa.ts.
So again, we're not really changing anything on
the file system, we're simply telling angular, hey,
when you load the environment, load environment.qa.ts.
And then you can actually use any file name here,
the best practice is to stay consistent
with the configuration name, or use a name that's similar.
This simply makes it easy for other developers
to understand your process.
If you kind of keep things simple for the developers.
Okay. So moving ahead to step three,
defining the configuration angular.json
for the serve section.
So again, this is this big long angular.json file,
and here's the actual path for it.
We have projects&gt;angular-ecommerce&gt;architects&gt;serve&gt;
configurations, so the serve section.
So here's a little snippet of the angular.json file.
We're in the serve section,
we set up the configurations here,
and I give the actual configuration name of qa.
And this is actually referenced from the command line,
when we start the application.
So when I say npm start configuration equals qa,
that's the configuration name that they're going to use.
And then I set up a browser target,
angular-ecommerce:build:qa, referencing the configuration
defined on the previous slide.
So in that angular.json file that other section there
a qa that has the fileReplacements.
And then that's it as far as mapping the files together,
and setting up the build section,
and also setting up the serve section.
So then step four, we simply run the application
with our environment configuration.
So here I'm going to run with the qa configuration.
So I'll say npm start configuration equals qa.
And then, based on these configs that we just added
to the angular.json file, then it will know,
oh, okay, great, I need to use
the appropriate file replacements.
And here it'll load up environment.qa.ts.
And that'll give us the luv2shopApiUrl.
That'll connect to our Spring Boot backend,
that's listening on port 9898 for the qa environment.