In this video,
we'll cover Add Products a Shopping Cart, part two.
And so, here are our main focus is on CartStatusComponent,
we actually want to update the status,
keeping track of the total price
and the total quantity for the cart.
And we'll cover all this in this set of videos.
Here's our development process,
the first thing we'll do is we'll create a model class
for CartItem, we'll develop a CartService
will modify the ProductListComponents
to call the CartService,
we'll also enhance our CartStatusComponent
to subscribe to the CartService,
and then finally, we'll update
the CartStatusComponent HTML
to display the cart total price and quantity.
All righty, so let's kind of get an overview
of the application interaction
just so you see how all the different pieces work together.
So over on the left-hand side
we'll have this ProductListComponent
that's going to have an Add to Cart button
and over on the right-hand side
we'll have the CartStatusComponent
for displaying the total price and quantity.
And then down in the center we'll have the CartService
basically keeps track of all of the items
that are in our shopping cart.
The way it works here is at the CartStatusComponent
it's going to subscribe for events on the CartService.
Then over on the left-hand side,
when the ProductListComponent,
when the user actually clicks on the Add to Cart button,
the ProductListComponent is going to call the CartService,
the CartService will manually keep track
of all the items in the shopping cart
and then it'll publish the events to all subscribers.
So, one of the subscribers use the CartStatusComponent,
the CartStatusComponent will receive the event
and then update the UI for the total price and quantity.
So this is a very common pattern in Angular developer.
Basically, here we have the CartService
that's an observable and the CartStatusComponent
is an observer.
And we'll see how this actually works out
with the actual coding when we move into it.
So in step one, we'll create a model class called CartItem.
This class simply contains the essential fields of a product
for use in the cart.
And it also has a field for the quantity,
and we can use this for kind of keeping track of everything.
So effectively, we have X number of widgets in our cart.
All righty, so in step two,
we're going to develop our CartService.
So we have this class CartService,
so up top, we have our shopping cart,
it's simply an array of CartItem objects
and we initialize it to an empty array,
so it starts out as empty upfront.
And then we have two entries here for total price
and total quantity.
There's subjects, so you may wonder, what is a subject?
Well, a Subject is a subclass of observable.
And so we can use the Subject to publish
events in our code programmatically
and then these events will be sent
to all of the subscribers.
And so I'll actually show you coding in a second
and how we can actually publish an event using this Subject,
you'll see that in a second.
And so remember our whole application interaction here.
So our CartService is going to publish events for subscribers.
So the CartStatusComponent,
they're going to subscribe for events
and they we'll actually publish events to the subscribers,
and we'll see how this coding pulls together in a second.
So a bit more on the coding here for CartService.
So we'll have this method Add to Cart,
they'll pass on a CartItem.
And so a couple of things here,
we'll check if we already have the item in our cart.
So we simply set up a boolean value here
and also an existing CartItem, initialize it to undefined.
And if the cartItems.length is greater than zero,
so we have some items in our cart.
Let's find the item in the cart based on the item ID.
So we simply loop through all of the CartItems,
then we checked to see if the tip cartItem.id
equals the CartItem ID.
If so we assign it and then we break out of the loop.
Then we check to see if we found it,
so we check to see if the existing CartItem
is not equal to undefined.
If not, we'll assign it true or false.
And we'll use this flag and some of the code coming up.
And here's that little next segment of code.
So if already exists in cart,
we simply increment the quantity.
Else, we simply add the item to the array.
So we say this.cartItems.push the CartItem
that adds it to the array.
And then finally, here we compute the cart quantity
and the cart total.
So we call this method, this.computeCartTotals
and we'll actually write the code for this one
on the next slide.