All right, so let's go ahead
and run this application and test it out.
So let's swing over to IntelliJ
and make sure we have our Spring Boot
backend up and running.
If not, let's go ahead and start it now.
And it will swing back into Visual Studio Code
and we'll get our Angular application up and running.
Go and swing over to our browser and access our application.
And so one thing that we'll notice here is that
we have this new Member button
on our login status component.
And so let's go ahead and select this Member button.
It's going to access this protected route,
so the user is not logged in,
so we're going to send them to the login page first.
Let's now go ahead and login here.
And then success, all right, so now we're logged in,
we can now access the protected route,
so we can see the members-only information.
Good, I like it.
Now this protected route is what we
setup in our configuration, so slash members,
we set up the appropriate configs in at app.module.ts.
So we have the path, the component,
and then can activate or make use of this OktaAuthGuard.
So that's the configuration kind of
pulling everything together.
Now let's go ahead and play around
with this protected route a bit.
So let me go ahead and log out over here.
And let me try to access the protected route directly
while logged out,
Okay, so I'm going to try and backdoor the system
because I know what that URL is,
it's localhost 4200/members.
So let me just try and just manually enter this URL
and see if I can access it.
And then notice here, you're not logged in,
so they're going to send you to the login page.
So the protected route with the route guard
is working as desired.
So even if they tried to backdoor the system
by accessing the URL directly,
Angular will still kick-in
and protect this route accordingly.
Now this Members button here,
we really should only show this button
if the user is logged in.
It's okay to have it here when they're not logged in,
but let's just kind of clean this up a bit
and only show this button if they're logged in.
So let's just kind of move back into that
login status component at HTML.
And we'll put the code back that we had before.
So I told you that we're going to remove it,
but now let's just go ahead and add it back in here.
So we'll only show the button for Members
if the user is logged in.
So I'll just kind of copy this
ngIf isAuthenticated from before,
and just drop it down here.
And so, of course, right,
only show that Member button if they're logged in.
Alrighty, so simply save that swing back into our browser.
That's our app.
And then, of course, this works as desired, right,
we only have the login button,
we don't see anything else until they actually
login to the application.
And then great, so I'm logged in,
and so now I can see the Members button
because I'm logged in,
based on that coding that we setup from before.
And, again, this is all pretty good,
you've seen a lot of the coding
and the logic for this before
as far as showing and hiding buttons accordingly.
So let's go ahead and click on the Member button.
And great, there's our Members page component.
So this is really, really good.
So we were able to kind of setup this VIP member-only page
where they had to be logged in in order to access it,
and we make use of route guards
and also integrated the OktaAuthguard.
So I'd like to say, good job, my friend.