Okay, so moving ahead
with our development process.
In this video we'll cover steps two and three
of defining the Getter methods
and also updating the HTML template.
All right, so let's go ahead and scroll down a bit
in our application.
And let's add a new method here, a Getter method.
Get first name,
and it's going to return the actual first name control.
So use that checkoutformgroup.get
and then we get customer.firstname.
And so this will actually be used by our HTML template
to get access to the form control
and to check the status of the form control,
and so on to see if it's valid, so on and so forth.
And now what'll I do is I'll just kind of clean up
some of the white space here.
And I'll actually put this Getter method all on one line,
cause we're going to have a lot of these Getter methods
in this example.
So I'll just put it all on one line
and then I'll just do a little copy-paste
on this get firstname,
and I'll paste it x number of times
to add support for lastname,
and also do a similar thing here for email.
So get email, customer.email.
All right so just as a check point here
make sure that your code looks like this
and you have the appropriate updates accordingly.
Make sure you don't have any copy-paste errors.
Firstname, lastname, email.
All right so step three, we're going to update
the HTML template to display error messages.
So I'll move over here to my file system.
And I'll open up checkout component.html
So that's our HTML template.
And so I'll move into the section here
for customer first name.
So right after that form control for first name,
then we'll go ahead and add coding here
to display validation error messages.
So I'll make use of this ngIf and I'll say,
if firstname.invalid.
And then also remember we need to add
the additional code here to check to see
if this field is dirty or if this field has been touched.
And then I'll apply the appropriate styles here.
All righty so I just kind of pause here for second.
So that's the coding here, just to check to see
if we have any validation errors:
.invalid, .dirty, .touched.
Now what we can do is, we can move in here
and we can display the specific error message
for a given validation.
And remember we'll make use of that errors object
to check for those specific error messages,
or error validations.
So I check firstname.errors.
Okay, that special object that has a list of errors.
And then .required.
So basically we're saying, hey if the validation
for required failed, then we'll display this message:
first name is required.
And then we'll do a similar thing here for min length.
So I'll just kind of copy this portion and paste it.
And just update the error.
So errors.minlength.
And then I'll give the specific error message here
for min length.
So it must be at least two characters.
All righty so let's kind of just stand back here
and admire our code.
This all looks pretty good.
So that's the coding in our template
for displaying the error messages if they occur.
Good job.