Alrighty, so let's go ahead and get started.
So in this video, we'll cover steps one and two
of keeping track of the user's email address
and also creating new OrderHistory class.
Okay, so let's go ahead
and move into our login-status.component.
All right, so we're in login-status.component.ts.
I'll move down here and I'll add an entry
for the browser storage.
So this gives us a reference
to the web browser sessionStorage.
Now let's move down to this getUserDetails method.
So once the user's authenticated,
then we can get some data from the actual authentication
or response, in particular the email address.
So let's go ahead and do that now.
All right, so now that we have an email address,
let's go ahead and store the email in the browser storage.
So I make use of storage.setItem.
I give the key, userEmail and then the values
are a stringified version of the email.
So that's the new coding here
that we added to kind of keep track
of the user's email address.
We'll make use of this and some other angler components
to retrieve it at a later time,
but at least now we have that person's email.
In step two, we're going to create the OrderHistory class.
So I'll just open up a new terminal window here
and I make use of the angular CLI
for ng generate class common/OrderHistory.
All right, so let's zoom in here
and let's add some fields for this OrderHistory.
So we'll keep track of the ID, the order tracking number,
the total price, the total quantity, and also the date.
Alrighty, so this looks pretty good.
So we can use this information
when we display the list of orders.