All righty, so moving along
with our development process.
In this video, we're going to focus on step four
of modifying the cart details component
to retrieve the cart items.
All right, so let's swing into our IDE
and let's move to our cart-details.component.ts file.
Now let me just move down here to the bottom
and clean up my terminal window
and get rid of it just so I have some extra real estate
for writing all the code right now,
so, okay, good.
So that's out of the way.
All right, so let's zoom in here
and let's get down to business.
So the first thing we're going to do is create some properties,
so we'll set up a property here for cart items
and we'll initialize it to an empty array
and then we'll also set up properties here
for the total price and also the total quantity,
and then, in our ngOnInit method,
we'll call this method this.listCartDetails
and in this method, I will write some quick comments
to myself just to keep myself on track.
All righty, so we'll get a handle to the cart items,
we'll subscribe to the cart totalPrice,
the cart totalQuantity, and we'll also
compute the cart total price and quantity,
and one thing is that I'll need to inject
the cartService here, so I'll move up
to the constructor and perform the injection.
All righty, so scrolling down here
to our listCartDetails method,
we'll go ahead and write the code
for getting a handle to the cart items,
so I'll simply give this.cartItems
equals this.cartService.cartItems,
and then we'll subscribe to the cart totalPrice,
so I simply give this.cartService.totalPrice.subscribe,
and then, when that data arrives,
then we'll assign it to this.totalPrice,
and I'll do a similar thing here for cart totalQuantity,
and then, finally, I'll compute the cart
total price and quantity.
All righty, so this looks pretty good.
This is all the major coding here for this given method.