All righty, so let's go ahead
and move into our IDE and let's zoom in here.
We need to do some housekeeping work.
I simply want to copy, paste one of my previous projects.
So I'm going to copy this 01-class-definition project.
And then I'll move it to 04-classes and paste it here.
'Cause I want it to be a subdirectory of 04-classes.
And now I'll simply rename in this copy.
And I'll call it 02-access-modifiers.
All righty, so now initially the IDE will show errors.
Simply close the previous files,
and that should get rid of any of the errors that you have.
So let's move into the 02-access-modifiers directory
and open Customer.ts.
All righty, so what I like to do is go in here
and make these properties private.
So I use the private access modifier.
And then if I move down I'll see
that there are some compilation errors
or the IDE has noticed some errors here.
It says, hey, the property is private.
It's only accessible within the class Customer.
And it will also see this in the
little problems output here.
They'll even give you the line number, which is pretty good.
So let's go ahead and move to our terminal window.
I want to move to the directory
04-classes/-02-access-modifiers.
All righty, so let's go ahead and compile our code.
And notice here it gives the compilation errors
that says the property is private,
only accessible within the class Customer.
And we kind of expected that.
So if we look at the contents of our directory,
even though there are compilation errors,
the TypeScript compuler still generates a.js file.
Yikes, what's up with that?
(laughing)
It shouldn't do that, okay?
So let's go ahead and just clean this up a bit.
So let's remove the Customer.js file or delete it.
And now we only have the Customer.ts in our file,
and remember we can solve this by using a compiler flag,
-noEmitOnError.
So it says do not generate a .js file
if there's a compilation error.
So now when I add that compiler flag
it goes through and everything works as desired.
So there are compilation errors,
and I simply look at the contents of my directory,
and I see that there's only the .ts file.
So yeah, the .js file was not generated.
So let's go ahead and move back into the code
and let's rename the properties.
So I'm going to rename the property
using the underscore symbol for firstName.
And I'll do a similar thing for lastName.
And notice here it updates everything
in the constructor accordingly.
And so remember, we can give any property name.
Most TypeScript developers use the leading underscore,
but again, there's nothing special about the underscore.
There's no magic, just a convention.
You could call it anything.
You can call it xy, ab, whatever.
And now what I do is I like to go through
and create those special TypeScript accessors.
So I set up the get accessor,
and again, remember that special syntax,
get space the property name.
And then a similar thing here for the set accessor.
The syntax set space property name.
And then also remember, there's no return type,
not even void.
So that's the one item that is very particular.
All right, so we're all set up.
So we have our accessors in place here
for that property firstName.
And that should resolve the issue that we have at the bottom
with those previous compilation errors.
So let's just scroll down for a bit.
So yeah, so this looks great.
So firstName propery is a-okay.
That's not a problem.
So we're good with that.
But there is still an issue for lastName,
so we need to add accessors here for lastName.
So now it's kind of more of the same,
but I'll use a different approach here.
So what I'll do is I'll move up to this line of code,
and I'll actually have the IDE generate
the accessors for me.
So I select the line, I show the fixes,
and I'll say generate get, set accessors.
Ooooh, I like it.
And then there we go.
So we have the get and set last name
that was generated by the IDE.
Cool, I love it, I love it.
So what I want to do is kind of just cut and paste on this
'cause I like for my code to show after the constructors.
So I'll cut those get sets and I'll move them down
to the bottom and place them right here.
But there we go, so we have
our get lastName and our set lastName set up just fine.
So now that takes care of that
one issue that we had earlier.
So that goes away.
So firstName property set
and lastName property set up a-okay, just fine, good job.
So let's move into our terminal window here
and compile the code.
And eww, that's weird.
Ah, okay, it says that accessors are only available
when targeting ECMAScript 5 and higher.
So that means I need to set up another compiler flag.
So I need to set the compiler flat --target ES5.
Okay.
And then now when I go through and compile
everything will compile just fine.
Oooo, good stuff, good stuff.
And now when I run the application it runs as desired
and I'm able to see the given output.
Okay, great.
All righty, so, good example here
of using accessors in our application.