Alrighty, so let's get started
with our Development Process.
So in this video, we'll cover the first two steps
of defining the routes
and also configuring a router based on our routes.
Al righty so let's go ahead
and swing in to Visual Studio Code.
So it's step one of defining our routes.
So we'll open up this file here, app.module.ts.
I'll zoom out a bit and expand my window.
So I just move in here and I'll define my routes.
So it's simply an array of route items.
So I just give a comma-delimited list here,
but first let me go ahead
and perform an import for this routes.
So I'll have routes and router module from
angular/router.
So that should resolve the import issue there.
All righty, so let's go ahead and dig in here,
so I'm going to create a comma-delimited list of route items.
So I specify the path and the component.
So the first item I enter here is for category/:id.
So that's the actual path to match
and then when the path matches
it's going to create a new instance
of our product list component.
And now I just do a little quick copy paste here
x number of times.
So I'll set up a route for just category by itself
and also a route for products by itself.
And both of these will go to ProductListComponent.
Internally we'll set up the default value
for category id.
We'll see that in a bit.
And I'll add two more paths here again,
little copy paste,
and so this will be for the empty paths,
so if they don't give us anything,
they were simply going to redirectTo /products.
And remember this is the one case
where the rule doesn't apply,
so for redirects you can use the forward slash
starting on the routes.
And then we have pathMatch equals full,
so match the full path as opposed to just the prefix.
And now we add our generic wild card,
the star star.
And we'll do a similar thing here,
we'll do a redirectTo /products.
So effectively if they don't give a path,
we'll send it to products
of if they don't match on anything,
we'll send it to products.
Again it's just the generic wild card,
it'll match on anything that didn't match
the above routes.
And then also just as a reminder,
the order of the routes is important.
So the first match wins top down,
so when you define your routes,
you start by defining the most specific to generic.
All righty, now step two,
configure the router based on our routes.
So I moved down here to the import section
and I'll say RouterModule.forRoot.
And I simply get the routes
that we defined a little bit earlier.
So I just add a comma there to the end of it
and that's pretty much it.
So we took care of the first two steps
of defining our routes
and then configuring the router
based on our given routes.