All righty, so let's go ahead
and move into our IDE.
And so this is for the section on making use of variables.
So I'll create a new folder here in my TYPESCRIPT TRAINING.
I'll call it 02-variables.
And I'll also create a new folder in this file here.
I'll call it sample-types.ts.
Okay, so I'll simply go in here
and just define some variables here.
So found boolean = true.
Grade equals 88.6.
firstName Anup.
lastName Kumar.
And so notice here on the strings
you can use double quotes or single quotes,
totally up to you.
And let's go ahead and display some output
using a console.log.
And so I'll simply do a console.log
on each one of these variables that we've defined.
And so for the names here I'll just use
the string concatenation here,
Hi firstName plus lastName.
So let's go ahead and open up a terminal window here.
Just kind of resize it a bit.
And let me just kind of zoom out,
give us some space here.
So let's move into that new directory that we have,
02-variables.
And now I just compile the file using tsc sample-types.ts.
And so now I'll use the node command to run the application.
So here I have node sample-types.js.
And then here we see the output true
the trade is 88.6 and hi Anup Kumar
that looks pretty good, I like it.
So now let's zoom in here and let's try and break it.
Let's see how this compiler thing works.
So here I'll set found equals zero.
So that should generate an error
because a Boolean can't be assigned to zero, good.
So even the IDE tells us this.
I'll set the grade equals to A,
and again, a little error message there,
which is great, good job.
I'll try and make some assignments to firstName.
Okay, great, so I have this and I save it.
Now let's go ahead and compile this.
Tsc sample-types.ts.
And in the compiler, good.
So let's say that final three errors.
And it'll kind of list out those errors.
And these are kind of the same ones that we saw
in the IDE, so that's cool, I'm happy about that.
And also, if you click on this little problems tab here
you'll see those same messages.
So again, good stuff.
They even tell you the line number and so on
so you know exactly where you have to go.
So one thing to note, though,
and this is kind of scary,
by default tsc will still generate a JavaScript file.
What (laughing)?
So to prevent this you need to add a special compiler flag
so noEmitOnError.
Okay great, so let me go ahead and comment that stuff out.
I don't want to break anything right now.
Just get the compiler to pass.
And then we do a tsc sample-types.
Okay, good.
So everything's good to go there.
If we run it then we get our output.
Okay, that's awesome.
I like that part of it.
And then what I'd like to do is kind of
move back into this example,
and I want to make use of the template strings here.
And so remember,
the template strings make use of that back tick.
And so instead of having to do all the concatenation
with the plus symbols I can simply reference the variables
using the dollar sign, curly brace.
So I could say Hi firstName space
and then dollar sign curly brace lastName.
So it'll actually reference those variables.
All right, so I save it.
Compile it.
And then run it.
And we have two messages here for Hi Anup Kumar.
So the first version is with the string concatenation
and the second one is using the template strings.
All righty, so this is a good example.
We kind of went through and played around
with creating variables and also displaying output,
so good job.