Alrighty so let's go ahead and continue
with our development process so we'll focus on step three
of developing a TypeScript class for our product and also
step four of creating the Angular service to call
the REST APIs.
Alrighty so let's go ahead and move in here and develop
the TypeScript class for a product.
So down in my terminal window I'll make use
of the Angular CLI to help me out with this.
Here I'll just type ng generate class common/product.
So it'll place this into the common subdirectory and we'll
have this file product.ts and remember it's a very basic
class nothing's there we need to add our properties
to this class.
So let me just zoom in here and I'll list out all
of the property names here along with their types
and this matches with the actual JSON data that's passed
back from the string boot service.
So I'll just do a little copy paste here on this line
x number of times.
Alrighty so this looks pretty good, so this is our
TypeScript class for our product and again it matches
on the actual properties from the actual JSON data
coming back from that string data rest API.
And now we can move to step four of creating the Angular
service and I'll use the Angular CLI again
to create this service.
So ng generate service and I'll give services/product.
So to place the service in the services directory
and the name of the service is product.service.
So let's go ahead and take a look here, services
product.service.ts.
So there's some actual TypeScript code here for my service.
So before I go any further I need to make some updates
to my application module, so let's move over
to app.module.ts.
In the import section we need to import the module
for http client module.
That's the module that contains the http client.
And also we have to give the appropriate import up top
for this and so we need to manually type this out
because TypeScript won't be able to find that solution.
So this is part of the Angular framework
so @angular/common/http.
And also in the provider section we need to add
a reference to our product service this will allow us
to inject that given service into other parts
of our application.
Alrighty so this takes care of the work for updating
our application module.