All right, so let's remove
that placeholder code and let's start to add our coding.
So we only want to add an access token for secured endpoints.
And so I'll set up this array of secured endpoints.
So this is for my, slash api, slash orders.
And now I simply want to check the URL that's being processed,
see if that matches with one of the secured endpoints
or matches with the secured endpoints that I have here.
And so if it does match,
then we want to get the access token.
So I'll set up this access token equals,
I do the await this dot oktaAuth,
dot,
huh, OktaAuth
oh gosh, okay.
I forgot to inject the OktaAuth.
So I need to move back up here
to my constructor and inject that.
So the OktaAuth is going to come in as an OktaAuthService.
Here we go.
Okay. Excellent, excellent.
So that takes care of that part.
So now I can use this OktaAuth.
Okay, good.
'Cause now it's injected and I can use it.
So OktaAuth dot get access token.
So this is a call to a asynchronous method,
returns a promise.
And so here we make use of this await to say
wait until that processing finishes before proceeding.
Now, we'll go through and clone the request
and add new header with the access token.
So I'll make use of this request dot clone.
And for this entry here, authorization, bearer.
And I give a reference to the access token.
And remember the reason we have to clone
is because the request is immutable,
meaning that you can't change it directly.
So you have to make a copy of it
like cloning it and then setting the headers accordingly.
And so then, at the end of this method,
we say return next dot handle request dot to promise,
basically saying, go ahead
and continue the other interceptors that are in the chain.
If there are no other interceptors,
then I'll just simply make the call to the given rest API.