All righty, so let's go ahead
and get started with our development process.
So we'll focus on step one,
of setting up our database tables.
Let's go ahead and open up a web browser.
And we're going to download some starter files for us,
so go to the website on the screen to download
the e-commerce starter files.
All right, so we have the files downloaded.
I'm just swinging over to my file system
and look at my Downloads directory.
And I'll just do a quick unzip of that file.
And I'll open up a new window.
And what I'll do is I'll create a new folder
here on my file system, I can use any folder name,
but in this example I'll call it ecommerce-project,
this is where I'll place all of my e-commerce project files.
I'll just move into this folder real quick.
And I'll just move these starter files
down to this ecommerce-project folder.
Any starter files are for images, database scripts
and spring boot application properties,
we'll get into all that stuff later.
So let's go ahead and swing over to MySQL Workbench.
And I'll go ahead and connect into my system using root.
And I'll open up one of those SQL scripts.
So in my starter-files directory,
I'll open up create-user.sql.
And so this file basically just creates
the user ecommerceapp with the password ecommerceapp.
You can feel free to change those if you'd like.
All right, let's go ahead and run this script.
All right, so I can go and look at my users
over here on the side in the Management tab.
So if it's not open you can just click
that Management tab there and it will expand it,
click on your Users and Privileges
and there should be a new user here
that we just created, ecommerceapp.
So let's open up one more script here.
And we'll open up the script 02-create-products.sql.
And so at a very high level
this script here will create our schema,
full-stack-ecommerce,
it will create our tables for product and product category
and also load sample data.
All right, let's go ahead and run this script.
And move over to the schemas here
and just do a refresh all and we should see the new schema.
Full-stack-ecommerce, looks good.
And the schema has two tables, product and product category.
And we can run some queries on these tables here real quick,
just to see the data.
So at the moment we only have one category for books
and then we have five products
in our database table.
All right, this looks pretty good so far.