Alright, so here's the code
here for our compute cart totals.
This is very basic, we're simply going to walk through
or loop through all of the cart items
and just compute the totals here.
So for let currentCartItem of this.cartItems
and I have
totalPriceValue += currentCartItems.quantity
*currentCartItem.unitPrice
and then the quantity simply,
+=currentCartItem.quantity
And so now the real word here is publishing the new value,
so all subscribers will receive the new data.
So we will say this.totalprice.next,
and then we pass in total price value,
totalquantity.next, total quantity value.
So again, it publishes the events to all subscribers.
It'll send one event for total price,
one event for total quantity, and this.next method,
that's the method that'll actually publish
or send the event.
That's the code that will actually generate or emit,
or publish this actual event.
So note here, we call the .next method twice.
So we get two separate events.
And again, just remembering our application interaction,
so this card status component, a subscribe,
the cart service, we did some work
and then we publish events to all subscribers.
So the cart status component will now get this event
of this new data that we just sent out
for total price and total quantity.
So now step three of modifying our product list components
have called the cart service.
So here in our product list component, add to cart.
We have our console.log.
And remember earlier I said you know we had some to do,
do the real work.
Well, one thing we do is we create the cart items,
I have the cart item equals new cart item,
I pass in a product.
So remember, the cart item has information
about the product, along with the quantity.
So here I have this cart service, I say, add to cart,
I pass in the cart items, I'm calling that cart service.
So that's kind of the step two there of the product
list component, calling Add To Cart
on the actual cart service.
So now step four of enhancing the cart says components
to subscribe to the cart service.
Alright, so we have to subscribe.
So here's our cart status component.
We set up some values here for total price, total quantity.
For the constructor, we inject our cart service
and our ngOnInit method, we call this.updatecartstatus.
And so on our update card status method will actually
subscribe for events.
So here I say this.cartservice.total price, subscribe,
so I'm going to subscribe
to the cart status total price property.
And so then when new events are received,
we simply make the assignments to update the UI.
So here, whatever data comes back, I say,
this.totalprice = data.
That's data that's being sent from the
actual cart service or published by the cart service.
And I'd do a similar thing here for total quantities.
So data again, that's being sent over, we receive it,
and then we assign it accordingly.
So we can update our user interface.
Alrighty, so we're almost done here,
step five of updating our cart status component,
HTML to display the cart total price and quantity.
So in our HTML page here for our card status,
we simply make reference to total price,
we pipe it through currency, and then for total quantity
we added here, and this will show up
in our actual cart status component dynamically.
So no more hard coded data.
We're actually making use of data from the component.
So now remember our application interaction,
the card service is going to publish
events to all subscribers.
We'll get those events and we'll update
the UI for the total price and quantity.
And so we'll see those new updates right there
in our given status component.
All right, I'm getting excited here.
I'm ready to write some code.
So let's go ahead and dive into our IDE
and let's get started.