Alrighty. So we've done some really
really good work so far, and I'm excited.
I'm ready to test this out and see how this works.
So let's go ahead
and run our Spring Boot e-commerce application.
Okay. So our app is up and running
and I'll test this using Postman.
So let's go ahead and run Postman right now.
Okay. So we're in Postman.
Let me expand real quick.
And we want to make sure that this endpoint is protected.
So it should be protected right now
the slash API slash orders.
So let's go ahead and send over a request for this API
and see what happens
and take a look at the status.
So this is successful.
So the end point is protected.
We get a 401 Unauthorized.
All right.
So basically saying, Hey, this particular person
is not authorized to access this given end point.
So it's secure.
So that's great.
I like it.
But now one thing I'd like to do here is that
notice that the body is empty.
There's nothing there
Will it get a status code?
It'd be nice if we could see a friendly
401 message right here in the response body.
And we can do that by making use
of a little special feature provided
by the Okta Spring Boot Starter.
So I'll kind of swing back here into IntelliJ
and I'll move into my security configuration class.
And what I'll do here is I'll force a non-empty response
about it
for 401's to make the response more friendly.
And I'll use our feature
from the Okta Spring Boot Starter
So I'll say
Okta dot configure resource server 401 response body
I pass in the HTTP.
And again, this is
from the Okta Spring Boot Starter project.
And we've already added the support via the pom.xml.
And what this will do is now when we make a request
and it's a 401
we'll also see this 401 in the body.
So how the normal HTTP status code
but we'll also see this in the actual body just
to make it a bit more friendly for us.
So let's go ahead and run our application again.
And now I'll swing back
into Postman and I'll submit this request again.
So we get the status 401.
The response is more friendly since it has a response body.
So it's just easier to see without having to worry
about just the actual status code itself.
And this is very useful
if you try and access this via a web browser.
So let me just actually copy this endpoint
and then move into a web browser and test it out.
So in this browser, I'll just drop in that endpoint
and then notice here we have 401 Unauthorized.
So that's good.
So we're able to see it right here
in the body of the response.
So this is good for troubleshooting and debugging.
And I like to check some
of my other endpoints that are already out there
just to make sure that they are still available.
So slash API slash products, that's a public API.
There's no protection on it so we can access this
a-okay just fine.
All right.
So that's fine.
It's, it's publicly assessable.
The only thing that we secured
at the moment was simply our slash API slash orders.
So that's the one that's secured
and only can access it if you're logged in.
So just showing you that we can provide very
fine grain security on certain end points
and not apply it to the entire application.
And you can change those rules accordingly
based on your application requirements.
Now, one thing I like to do is actually
run the Angular application right now
and see how the Angular works with this protected backend.
So a spoiler alert here, it's not going to work as desired
but we'll kind of dig through and see, you know, exactly
what's going on because there's more work we'll have to do
to the Angular app,
but let's just kind of see where we're at
at this given moment.
I'm in a terminal window here
starting at my Angular application.
So the Angular app is up and running.
Take a look at my browser.
Visit my app.
and then I'll go ahead and log in.
Okay. So I'm logged into the application a-okay.
It's demo derby.
I can click on orders
and
no orders found.
Well I know I have orders for this account.
Let's go ahead and take a look at our debug console
here in our developer console.
So under developer tools
and Oh, wow.
There's a 401 Error
Hmm, got it.
Got it. Got it.
So
401 unauthorized.
All right.
So now that order's API is secured right now
when you see this area, you're wondering, well
why is it 401 unauthorized because we are logged in.
Well, yes, we're logged in
but we're only logged in on the front end.
We haven't passed our access token to the backend.
So at the moment, the backend doesn't know who we are.
So that's why it's saying unauthorized.
We actually have to update the Angular app to
pass the access token with the HTP requests.
And we'll actually cover these details in the next video.
So we have a lot of good things in store.
So I'll see ya in the next video.