Okay, so we are almost done.
We are on our final step here.
Step five of adding the HTML template
for the CartDetailsComponent. And actually,
(laughing) we are just finishing up because,
we already created some of the HTML table
for this component. We are simply going to add in
the looping code to loop through all of the Cart items,
and we will cover that in this video.
Okay so let's go ahead and move back over to
our cart-details.component.html.
And basically we simply want to loop over
each one of the cart items and display
the product image, product detail, and
information about the quantity.
So I will set up a tr here and I use
my ngFor tempCartItem of cartItems.
And so we'll add code here to display the image.
Next, we will display the name and the unit price.
And then we'll also add code here to display the quantity.
And we'll come back and do subtotal
in the next video. Just for now,
we will simply display the quantity.
So that's the basic piece here for
looping over all the cartItems and displaying information.