Alrighty, so moving along with our development process.
in this video we'll focus on step two of creating this
Spring Boot starter project.
Alrighty so let's go ahead
and move it to our web browser
and let's visit the website start.spring.io.
Alrighty, so I'll go ahead
and move down here
and I'll start adding some project metadata.
So for the actual group name I'll call it com.love2code
and for the artifact ID I'll use spring-boot-ecommerce.
I'll expand the options here.
So I'll simply update the description here for this project.
And I'll also update the project name,
so simply .ecommerce
So com.luv2code.eccomerce
So just a quick check point,
so make sure you have these values here
for your project metadata.
And then for the Java version,
I'm using Java 13,
I'll select that option
but the Java versions change over time
so simply choose the Java version
that works for your system.
And so now we'll add the dependencies here
so I'll enter JPA for Spring Data JPA.
I'll add support for the Rest Repositories.
And I'll also add support for the MySQI database driver.
And then finally, we'll add support for Lombok,
that new modern development project
for minimizing the boilerplate code
for generating all those getters and setters
for you automatically.
All right, so just a check point here
over on the right hand side.
So make sure you have Spring Data JPA, Rest Repositories,
MySQI Driver, and Lombok.
All right, so go ahead and generate this project.
And then that's downloaded to your file system
so let's swing over to our folder here,
let's move into that downloads directory,
there's that spring eCommerce zip file
that was just generated,
let's unzip it.
And then before I move it over,
one thing I want to do in my eCommerce project folder
is I want to create this new folder for the backend.
So I'll create a new folder called 02-backend.
And so I'll move into the folder backend
and I'll simply move our spring boot eCommerce
into the backend folder.
So just stepping back a bit
so you can see the layout of the folders.
Okay, so this looks good so far.