All righty, so let's go ahead and move back
into our RDE and let's kind of do some
behind the scenes work here.
So starting with the launch process,
we mentioned that is going to open up the index.html file.
So I'll go into index.html, zoom over here a bit.
And we see that entry here of app=root,
so basically it's going to replace this tag selector
with a template of the component, like I mentioned earlier.
It's similar to an include.
So let's look at out app module,
just a collection of components here,
and so we see that we have a given
main component for bootstrapping,
that main component is called AppComponent.
All righty so let's go ahead and move to our AppComponent.ts
so this is our TypeScript file.
So we see the AppComponent and we see the selector app-root,
so this matches what we have in the index.html,
like I said earlier, you can use any selector you want,
simply stay consistent between those two files.
Okay, templateUrl points to the location
of our html template file
so that's appcomponent.html
and this is the basic that we have for right now.
And remember, with the {{,
this will actually read the property
of the related component,
so it'll read the property from the appcomponent.ts,
that TypeScript code.
And that's the actually property that it'll read
and include it right there in the template output
as far as rendering.
So I can change this title to say,
"This is My First App"
And then I can move here to the bottom
and start my server using that ng serve.
So remember in the background it compiles the code,
it starts the server and it watches your source files
and it'll reload any of your source files.
I simply swing over to my browser and open up localhost:4200
and there's the output.
This is My First App app is running.
(chuckle) Okay, that doesn't make any sense.
I need to change my code a bit
'cause I have app app twice.
It's all good.
So let's swing back over here
and make that slight change.
So in html, instead of saying app is running,
I'll just remove all of that stuff and just save
and remember it reloads everything for me,
and then there's the new version of it right here.
So, that's a nice little demo here, of the hot reloading
actually working in practice.
(chuckle)
And I don't have to use span here, I can simply use h2,
and save that and swing back over
and now I see new output here in the page.
I'll play around a bit,
kind of experiment here behind the scenes.
I'll set up a horizontal rule,
then I'll say "My name is"
and for right now just kind of leave it as dot, dot, dot.
I see the new output there in the browser,
but I actually want to read this from the component.
So in the component I'll define additional properties here.
So first name of Bill,
last name of Smith.
And now I should be able to access those properties
in my actually template using that {{ syntax.
So first name,
{{,
last name.
Then I'll save that.
And notice here, it automatically
recompiles in the background.
All righty and then swinging over to my web browser
and oh yeah, this looks great, I like it.
So here it says "My name is Bill Smith",
so we're actually reading those properties
from that angular component,
so we're reading the first name property
then also the last name property
and including it right here in our html page.
So this looks good.
I'm happy with this work so far.
Good job.