Alrighty, so moving along
with our development process,
in this video we'll cover steps five and six
of updating our product service
and also updating the HTML page.
Alrighty so, remember earlier I said, "Hey, this getProduct
method doesn't exist yet,
we'll declare it in the next video."
Well, this is the video and we'll actually declare it now.
Alrighty, so lets zoom in here
and we'll make use of the IDE and we'll tell it to
declare the method, getProduct.
So, that takes care of that one issue.
Okay, so now for step five, we're actually going to
update our ProductService to call the URL
on the Spring Boot application.
So I'll move over here into my ProductService
and we see right here at the beginning
they have that method that was just declared,
the getProduct, let me just cut this for a second,
and just move it down to the regular methods are.
Drop it in here.
Alrighty, so there's my getProduct method,
just a template right now or a place holder.
I'll set up the return type of observable product
because we're going to return one product.
And so, the first thing I need to do is
build a URL based on the product id.
So, for example this'll be localhost:8080/api/products/1,
two or whatever that actual product id is.
And remember we get this end-point out of the box
with Spring Data REST, there's no additional coding
or configuration required on the Spring Boot side.
And then we simply call the rest API,
based on its product URL.
And that's the basic coding here
for the getProduct method and the service.
Okay, so lets go ahead and swing back
to our project here, and lets open up the file
product details component.HTML.
And so, this is for step six of updating the HTML page
for the ProductDetailComponent,
to actually display the product details
because right now, we simply have a stock place holder here.
We need to give some real information.
All right, so instead of that hard coded item here,
Product Details Works, we're going to say product name.
So now once we run it, we should see the actual
product name for each product
when we select the actual details.
So let me just get my application up and running again.
Okay back in the browser, select one of my products here
and this is great, that's the product name.
Crash Course in Python, good, good.
And lets try one more, so the beginners guide,
nah, I'll try the JavaScript cookbook.
Excellent, great.
So now we know the actual product name is being
displayed on the product details page.
And this even works with our other categories,
like Coffee Mug for Sweeper.
Okay I'm happy, we're making some really good progress.
Now, we just have to add some details for the page
and we'll cover that in the next video.