All right, so moving along
with our development process.
We're going to cover steps two and three
of creating a new component for search,
and also adding a new angular route for searching.
And just a quick heads up,
I'm going to swap the order of these in the actual video,
so we'll see kind of step three first,
and then we'll see step two next.
But don't worry, we'll cover everything,
and everything will work out in the end,
I got you covered.
All righty, so moving in here,
so the first thing we'll do is
we'll add a new angular route for searching.
So whenever we need to add routes,
we'll open or edit our file app.module.ts.
All right, so here's our app.module.ts.
So I'll move down to my section for routes,
and I'll add a new route here for searching.
So I'll have this route called search,
and then I'll have a parameter called keyword,
so we say :keyword,
and this given route will be handled
by our ProductListComponent.
And remember, we're going to reuse this
because we already have the logic and functionality
for viewing and listing products.
That's how we have this set up in this fashion.
Okay, so that coding looks good.
Let's go ahead and open up a new terminal window,
and I'll zoom in here for a second.
So what we want to do is create a new component for searching.
So I'll make use of that ng generate component,
and this'll be components/search.
It'll go off and create the appropriate files for us.
And if we swing over here,
we can see, under the section for components,
then there's a new search directory,
and it has all the supporting files here
for our new search component that was just generated.