Okay, so let's go ahead and dive in,
and let's get started here.
So in our development process,
we're in cover steps one through three
of update redirect URIs
and our Anglur App Okta Dashboard,
and also set up a Trusted Origins in the dashboard.
Okay, so in our Anglur Application,
we need to update in one of our config files.
So I move down in the source, app,
move down to config,
then I open up this my-app-config.ts.
And I need to update the code here for the redirect URI.
So notice here they're using the regular HTTP.
I need to change that to use HTTPS
because our app is now running using HTTPS.
Okay, so now moving ahead to step two,
we need to update the redirect URIs in the Okta Dashboard.
Let's go ahead and pull up our browser,
and let's go ahead and login to our Okta Dashboard.
Okay, great.
So I'm logged in to the Okta Dashboard.
I go ahead and view my applications,
and then I can go ahead and choose one of the apps here.
So I moved down to my applications,
and in this example,
I'm using this Demo 5.
You can use whatever app that you've created
for your given environment.
So we're looking at a given application
and now let's go ahead and move down to the login section.
This is where you can see the different redirect URIs,
and let's kind of scroll up a bit
and click on the Edit button here.
And then back down to our login section,
and it'll simply update this with HTTPS,
and then we'll Save our changes.
And then just verify that everything is set up accordingly
with the HTTPS for those redirect URIs.
We're almost done.
In step three, we're going to update the API Trusted Origins
in the Okta Dashboard.
So we just move to our dashboard.
We go to Security,
we choose API,
and then in the API screen,
we move over to Trusted Origins.
And then we moved down to our given origin
and we added the origin URL.
And again, we simply make use of the HTTPS
for our application.
Okay, so that looks pretty good.
I like it.
Now we can swing back over through our application,
get our Spring Boot App up and running.
If it's not already running,
then go ahead and start my Angular App.
And remember we make use the new command now, npm start,
that's based on an information from our package.json,
and our app is up and running.
We can go and test it out here on our browser.
So we go to HTTPS localhost 4200,
and this all looks good.
So we've seen this part before.
Now I can go login,
this is one of my accounts
and great.
So we're logged in successfully.
It says, "Hey, welcome back Demo Darby."
So I know that it's pulling that information in accordingly.
That's great.
I can check the members special section,
and also I can check the orders in the background.
So this is really good.
So our app is up and running.
We have it running in a secure fashion using HTTPS.
We'll make use of our self-signed certs,
and we also updated the appropriate configs here
in the Okta Dashboard.
So this was great.
I liked it,
and I'm very happy with what we've accomplished so far.