Okay, so let's go ahead
and move in here and let's start writing the code.
So for setting up our order,
we'll just create a new instance.
And I'll update the values here
for total price and total quantity,
based on the values that we have
for our current checkout component, this.
Now I need to get the cart items from the cart service.
And basically what I want to do is kind of convert
those cart items into order items
and I need to kind of loop through it and make this happen.
I'll show you two ways of doing it.
The first way will be the long way
and then I'll show you a short way.
So the long way is more of the traditional approach,
you know, you create an empty array
and then you simply loop through and you,
you know, create new objects based on the other object.
So we go through the loop
and say order sub-I equals new order item,
pass in the cart item using that constructor
that we created earlier.
So that's kind of one approach of doing it.
So let me show you the short way of doing the same thing.
So we'll set up our order items short,
just giving it a unique name here.
And then I'll say cartItems.map.
And then I pass in new order item, temp card item.
So basically what this will do,
this will loop over the array and it'll return a new array
by applying the function to each element in that array.
So we're going to basically loop over cart items
and then map or convert that to order items.
So that's the short way.
So I'll common out the old code
and I'll simply rename this as just order items.
So anyways, I like keep the old code there
just so you can kind of jog your memory,
so you know exactly what's going on,
but that's the, you know,
the short way using cartItems.map.