Alrighty so now let's go ahead and move back
over to our service now.
Let me simply expand the window here
for this product service.
So I'll go ahead and define the base URL for the service
that we're going to call.
Right now we're hard coding it we'll get into the config
file stuff for it later.
So this is the URL for our spring boot REST API.
And then in our constructor we're going to inject
the HttpClient.
And recall Angular has a dependence injection framework
and HttpClient behind the scenes is injectable
and Angular will inject it for us.
And be careful here on the imports here don't choose
the auto imports, you may want to add it manually because
sometimes Visual Studio code has problems on importing
the correct module.
So be sure to make use of angular common http.
So let me kind of scroll down here a bit.
And we'll write this new method get product list.
Returns an observable of product array.
And this method's basically going to map the JSON data
from the spring data REST service to a product array.
So we use the HttpClient we make a get request to that base
URL the data that's returned we pipet and then we make
use of map to map that data to our given data type.
And so we grab that response._embedded.products and that's
going to be the product array that we're going to make use of.
We'll also add a little supporting interface here
at the bottom to help us with this mapping.
So this interface getresponse will help us unwrap the JSON
data from the spring of data REST API and make use
of that underscore embedded entry that comes back
from the spring data REST API.
And we'll access the array of products.
Now I need to take care of some imports here.
So for observable I can make use of the quick fix.
But for map it may not give you an easy solution here
in Visual Studio code so we can just manually provide
the entry, so I'll just move up top and I'll add the import
here for the map and map is a special operator from the RXJS
module and RXJS is short for reactive JavaScript.
All right so this looks pretty good so this is the coding
here for our product service and I'll make a get request
to that backend base URL, grab the data unwrap it
accordingly and make it available as an array of products.