In step four,
we're going to disable the HTTP PATCH method.
Previously, we configured
the Spring Data REST APIs for read only
and we disabled GET, POST and DELETE.
However, we also need to disable the HTTP PATCH
because someone could still PATCH data to those end points.
And so that's a,
it's an issue that we need to resolve.
Here is our coding here for
MyDataRestConfig.java.
We have those lists of methods in an array.
PUT, POST, DELETE
and we simply add PATCH.
And everything else will work out just fine
because all of those other lines of code
make use of the same array for the unsupported actions.
Okay, with step five
we need to modify the Spring Data REST detection strategy.
So by default, Spring Data REST will expose the REST APIs
for the Spring Data repositories.
This works in general
but you may not want to expose all of your Repositories.
For example, in our case, we have a Customer Repository
but we don't want to expose this as a REST API.
We only want to use it internally
like for checking if a customer email exist or not.
The REST endpoint /api/customers is currently exposed
and we don't want that.
So let's go ahead and fix this ASAP.
All right, so let's talk first
about the Spring Data REST detection strategies.
There are different ones available.
So there is the ALL strategy.
So in this strategy,
Spring Data REST will expose
all Spring Data repositories regardless
of their Java visibility or annotation configuration.
There is also the DEFAULT strategy.
So this strategy exposes
public Spring Data REST repositories
or ones explicitly annotated with
@RepositoryRestResource
and has the exported attribute not set to false.
And you'll see some examples of this.
The VISIBILITY strategy exposes
only public Spring Data REST repositories
regardless of annotation configuration.
So public using the public keyword.
The ANNOTATED strategy
only exposes Spring Data REST repositories,
explicitly annotated with @RepositoryRestResource
and it's exported attribute is not set to false.
So I like the ANNOTATED
because it only exposes the ones
that are explicitly annotated.
And so this is a good approach for our app
and this is what we'll use.
So using the ANNOTATED strategy,
so here we have this state repository.
So we annotate the repository with
@RepositoryRestResource(exported = true).
And in fact, we really don't need the value of true
because the default value of exported is true.
So we don't have to explicitly list it here.
We could simply just give the annotation by itself.
Now we need to configure the detection strategy.
So we need to tell the system,
hey, use the ANNOTATED strategy.
So in our application.properties file
we set up spring-data-rest.detection-strategy
equals ANNOTATED.
Okay, this looks pretty good.
Let's go ahead and move into the videos
and let's start writing some code.