All righty, so we're almost done.
So in step four,
we're going to add the event handler to check
the validation status when the submit button is clicked.
All righty, so we'll move over
to our checkout component.ts file
and we'll move down to this onSubmit method.
So let me just kind of zoom in here onSubmit.
So here I'll check on the checkout form group
to see if it's invalid.
If it is invalid, then we're going to mark all as touched.
And remember, touching all fields triggers the display
of the error messages.
Now, Angular will do a lot of the work in the background
when the form is first displayed,
but also when they actually do the submit,
we want to manually trigger this.
I'm ready so let's go ahead and run our application.
And actually before we run it,
let's just make sure we have our Spring Boot app
up and running.
So I'm just going to swing over there for a second
in IntelliJ.
And my Spring Boot app is already running.
If yours is not running,
be sure to start it now.
Then I just move over here into the correct directory
and get my Angular app up and running.
So I'll just move into my app
and I'll just add a couple of items to my shopping cart.
Then I'll go and view the cart,
just move down to the checkout button.
And now I'm on the checkout form.
So we have first name, last name, email.
Let's just test the validations here,
just move down and hit purchase.
And scroll to the top,
it says, hey, first name is required.
Now, right now it's only displaying the message
for first name because that's the only one that we added
the display messages for.
But we'll go ahead and repeat the process
for the other fields for last name and email.
So I'll move back into the HTML template
and I'll just grab the coding here
for the first name section,
so that div where I have the ngIf,
and I'll just copy that div.
And I'll apply the same thing for the other fields here
so I'll copy that,
move down to last name.
And so the last name section here,
I'll just paste that and now I'll just update this right.
So last name.
So instead of first name,
replace it with last name.
A couple of locations there and also for errors
and also for required and minlength.
And say last name is required.
Last name must be at least two characters.
So just make sure you make the appropriate updates there.
So last name invalid, last name dirty, last name touched.
Now, let's swing back into our application
and let's just move down to the purchase button
and then up top,
success, great.
So now we also have the last name is required
error message showing up.
So that's good.
So now it's just kind of more the same.
We'll do a similar thing here for the email field.
Just our copy paste exercise one more time.
Move down to the email section,
just paste it in here.
And again, we simply go through
and we've replaced last name with email.
And so for the minlength,
email doesn't have a minlength,
email makes use of that regular expression pattern
validation.
So be sure to say email.errors.pattern
Now, I'll just update the appropriate text here
for those messages.
So email is required
and also
email must be a valid email address format.
All righty, so we're back into our application here.
Let's just move down to the bottom and I'll do a purchase.
Okay, good, so this is great.
So email is required, so that's good.
Happy about that.
Now, let's kind of play around with the form a bit
and just add some data here to the form.
And notice Angular will automatically display or hide
the validation messages accordingly based on your input.
So it monitors these fields behind the scenes automatically.
So here I added some information for first name,
added some information for last name.
That's great.
And even email address so it's required.
We gave some data, but it's bad data.
So we have to make sure
that we gave a valid email address format.
Okay, great.
This looks really good.
So I'm happy.
So we have the basic validation in place.
In some of the other videos,
we'll add some more features here for validation.
And we'll also apply the validation rules
to the other fields on our checkout form.
So a lot of good stuff coming up.
So I'll see ya in the next video.