Alrighty, so moving along
in our development process,
in this video we'll cover step two
of updating the app module TS to reference the interceptor.
And actually, before we leave this screen,
we have a problem.
We have a typo,
and there's an extra semi-colon here
that should not be here.
So simply remove this semi-colon to resolve the typo issue.
And so now we can safely move to app module TS
and add a reference to our interceptor.
Alrighty, so we have the file open.
Let's go ahead and move down
to the providers section of the file.
And so here's the one line we're going
to make our modifications on.
So I simply do a comma
and I make use of curly braces here.
So we're setting up providers for HP interceptors.
We use the class that's the name of our interceptor
that we just created, our auth interceptor service.
So that's our class, our code.
And then multi true.
And the reason we have multi-true
is because with interceptors you can have
zero to many interceptors, and so you could
have multiple interceptors here.
Let's go ahead and fix the reference here
for our auth service.
I'll just move up here and do an import.
I have to manually do it.
It may work out better for you on your system,
but mine I have to type it in, but no worries.
So I'll interceptor service from services slash auth
interceptor dot service.
Now moving back down and okay, great, that's resolved.
And that looks pretty good.
So again, just a quick recap here.
That's our token for the HP interceptors,
and then we register our auth interceptor service
as an HP interceptor,
and finally the multi-true informs Angular
the HP interceptors is a token for an injection
of an array of values.