Okay, so, let's go ahead and add the styles
to the angular.json file.
So, this is the main configuration file
for your Angular project.
You can place all types of configuration here.
At this point, we'll simplify focus on adding
some additional styles to our project.
So, let me expand my window here,
give myself some extra space to kind of work with.
All righty, so, let's go ahead and move down here
to the styles section.
So, there's one style sheet that's already referenced,
and we can add additional items here.
So, this is for CSS styles that will be applied globally
to your Angular project.
There's no need to manually reference
these styles in your Angular components.
You simplify configure it here,
and the styles are available globally
throughout your given Angular project.
And so, what I will do here I'll add
some entries here for bootstrap and Font Awesome.
So, I'll give a reference to those style sheets here.
I know they're installed in my node_modules/bootstrap,
and I simply just give the location
for the given CSS style that I want.
So, that's the entry there for bootstrap,
and you can just verify that by looking
at your node modules directory.
And then we'll do a similar thing here for Font Awesome.
But again, remember the spelling here.
So, it's @fortawesome, that's an R,
/font, F-O-N-T,
awesome-free.
All righty, so that looks pretty good.
So, we'll save that, and if your application is already
running, be sure to restart your application,
because it'll need to pick up those new configs
in the angular.json.
Okay, so, at step three we're going to add the local
custom CSS styles to our Angular source/styles.css.
So, if we open source styles.css,
this is a CSS file that comes with all Angular projects.
You can add your global styles into this file.
You can also import other style files,
as I say there in the comment.
(laughs)
And so, what I'll do is I'll actually grab
the styles from our template.
And so, there's a styles.css.
I'll just Copy the styles from here.
And then I'll move over to that styles.css
that's in my Angular project and Paste those items.
All right, so, there we go.
So, now we have our styles.css
that's also part of this given project.
Now, let's go ahead and look at our index.html
that's in our Angular project,
and we can get rid of some stuff.
So, we're not using bootstrap from the CDN
or the web anymore.
We're going to make use of the ones
that we have cloned locally.
So, we can simply delete this code.
There's no need for us to reference anything,
because we get those styles globally
based on those configs that we just set up
in that angular.json.
I'll update my title here for this given project.
And I'll also add a reference here for the favicon.
So, right now the favicon is that Angular icon.
That's fine, we kind of get that out of the box
when we create a new Angular project.
However, I'd like to add my own icon here,
my luv2shop icon.
And so, we actually have that in the starter files
that were provided.
So, we have a favicon, which is our luv2shop icon.
And so, if I open it up, that's kind of what it looks like.
So, okay, great, that'll show up on our browser tab.
So, I'll just Copy this file, or Move this file
into the project and replace the previous one.
So, I just do a Replace there.
All right, great, so that's now part of our project.
So, I need to do a little workaround here.
The web browsers will keep a cache
of the previous favicons.
So, you need to either clear your cache,
or you can do a little URL trick here
to force the browser to get a new version.
And so, one way of doing that here
is when you set up the href, just do a little question mark
and give any unique reference here.
So, I call it v equals two.
That'll kind of avoid the caching issue
by giving a unique query param,
or you can do any value, question mark, A, B, C,
X, Y, Z, one, two, three, anything.
As long as it's unique the browser won't remember it,
and it'll use your new icon.
So, that's one of the workaround,
or you could just have the user
clear their browser cache, either way.
But that's just one little item there.
Okay, good, so, we're in place now.
We have our icon set up and we have CSS styles in place.
So, we're in really good shape so far.