Alrighty. So let's go and move in here.
So the first thing I like to do
is just change my Spring Boot Serve report
to listen on 9898.
So let's go ahead and move into our IntellJ IDE.
And I'll move into my application.properties file.
And let me kind of move down a bit in this file
to the HTPs configuration zoom in for a second
and change my server web ports.
So my server port instead of 8443,
I'll just copy paste that for a second.
And I will comment out the original value.
And for this new one
I'll set this up from our little QA demo,
and this is just kind of a quick and dirty example.
There's some other techniques I could use, but right now,
just keep it simple here.
And I'll say server port equals 9898.
So my spring boot app will be listening on this port.
Now, just go ahead and start my spring boot application.
And then I can zoom in here and kind of
scroll over a bit and I can see that the Tomcat
is started on 9898 using HPS.
Great, so I know that my spring boot app
is really running on 9898 right now.
Let's go ahead and move over to vs code
into our angler application,
and I just want to double check something here for a second,
so under source environments, environment dot CS.
It's currently going to connect to 8443,
so I want to kind of break it on purpose.
I'm going to leave this value as is,
and I'll try and run my application
and just break it on purpose and see what actually happens
when I start up my angular app.
So let's go ahead and open up a new terminal window so we
can start our angler app.
So I'll just use NPM start.
It's just going to use the default configuration here.
Alrighty, let's go ahead and swing over to our web browser
and then we'll visit our angular application,
HTPs local host 4,200.
And so right now it says no products found
so no products and also no categories,
and so the app's broken because of the wrong URL and
actually can't connect to the backend
spring boot application.
But let's go ahead and add some logging messages here,
just so we can see something in the logs.
So I'll go ahead and move into services and then product
service dot Ts.
And I'll move down to this method,
get product list paginated and I'll simply do a console that
log on the search URL.
So here at console dot log and here I'm going to make use of
the back ticks because I'll make use of the template string
here, so back ticks.
And I'll say getting products from,
and then the dollar sign curly brace,
or reference that variable search URL.
So it's important here that you use back ticks here,
as opposed to regular quotes,
allows us to process that such URL
as part of the console log.
Alrighty, let's go ahead and save that.
And then we can swing back over to our web browser.
And then simply do a reload.
So again, the app is still broken,
but we have some logging messages we can go take a look at.
So I can just move down to my developer tools here and then
zoom in and we can see it's getting products from,
and then note here, it's using local hosts, 8443
so it's broken and it's saying, hey,
we can't access that given in point or URL.
We know that it's broken. That's good.
We know that our default environment is using 8443,
but now we need to change this to use a QA environment on
the angler side to use a proper URL.
And we'll do that in the next video.