Okay, so this code looks really good.
I'm getting excited, I'm getting anxious.
(chuckles)
And let's go ahead and run it.
And let's test it out.
So go ahead and start the application.
Swing over to my browser here.
And let's add some items to our cart.
Coffee mug, and let's view our cart.
Yay, awesome, this is great.
So we see that we're looping over each one of our cart items
and displaying information about the image details
and quantity.
Cool, I like it, I like it.
And let's swing back in here.
And let's add some code to display
the subtotal for our cart item.
So just moving into this section
here where we have quantity.
And we'll add a new paragraph right below that div.
So we'll have our subtotal.
And now our subtotal is really a math expression.
So it's really the quantity times the unit price.
So I can actually do math expressions here.
Then I'll pipe it all through the currency.
(mumbles)
Okay, so for each one of our line items or cart items,
the subtotal is the quantity times the unit price.
I'll save this and I'll swing back over and test it out.
So add some items to the cart.
And yes, awesome.
So we have our subtotal for each one of our cart items.
Good.
So that's only one item
as far as quantity let's
increase the quantity here a couple of times.
And now move over and great.
It actually is computing the subtotal so four times x,
and that's our actual subtotal.
Okay, good. I like it.
Now, there's one other thing we have to do here
is actually give the grand total
at the bottom of our ShoppingCart list.
So we'll have the total quantity and also the total price.
So I'll set up a new table row here for this information.
So just add an empty colspan here of two
just to kind of take up those first two columns in the table
and make those empty and then we'll give our
total information or make this information bold.
And then I'll add the code here for total quantity.
So I simply access the Total Quantity property
on our component.
Free Shipping for all of our valued customers.
(chuckles)
And then also we display the total price.
Alright, so this code looks pretty good.
Let's go ahead and save and swing back over
and test it out on our browser.
And okay, good.
So starting out total quantity of zero,
shipping free total price is zero.
That's great because our cart is empty.
Let's go ahead and add some items to our cart.
And swing over and look at our cart details
and okay good, good. Scroll down.
And yes.
Okay great.
So we have a total quantity of six
and total price of 111 dollars and 94 cents.
It should match what we have up top for our
cart status component and yeah, looks good.
Okay, this looks great.
I'm really happy with the work
that we've accomplished so far.
Good job.