All righty,
so we're making some really good progress here.
So in this video we're going to focus on step five
of updating the Angular component
and step six of displaying the data in an HTML page.
All righty, so let's go ahead
and move over to our coding here for our Angular component.
So this is our product-list.component.ts.
And one thing I'd like to do is inject a dependency here.
So we're going to need our ProductService,
so we're going to inject the Product Service
into this productList component.
All righty, so we have that dependency injected here.
And then I'll set up a property here for products.
It's an array of Product.
Once an Angular component is initialized
they'll call the ngOnInIt method.
This is similar to our PostConstruct.
So this is where I'll actually add the hook
to call my listProducts method.
And I haven't defined the listProducts method,
I'll actually define it here.
So instead of my listProducts method I'll make use
of my productService and I'll call getProductList,
and I'll actually subscribe to that data.
And the method is actually invoked once you subscribe.
This method will execute in an asynchronous fashion.
And then when the data's returned
then we can assign it to our own property.
So here I'll simply assign the results to our product array.
And that's basically it
for integrating our service with our Angular component.
Now I need to do one more thing here
in step six of displaying the data in an HTML page.
So let's go ahead and open up product-list.component.html.
And so right now it's very simple,
it just says product-list works.
Let's go ahead and remove all that,
and let's add our own custom code.
So we'd like to just simply
just have a collection of paragraphs
with the actual names of the products.
So right now we're just keeping it very simple.
And we'll get into table stuff later,
but let's just keep it simple for now.
So I'll set a paragraph
and I use ngFor let tempProduct of products.
So we're accessing the products from the component.
And those values were assigned
based on our call to that service.
And now I'll simply display the product name,
and also the product price.
And I'll also send it through that currency pipe
so I can format it.
And now that's basically it here for creating the HTML page.
So this looks good so far.
Okay, so let's go ahead and test our application.
Just move into my terminal window here
and get things up and running.
And then also as a little side note,
make sure you already have
your Spring Boot app up and running too.
All righty, so our app is up and running but, (laughs) what?
Where are the products?
I should see some products here.
That's strange so let me just close
some of these other windows here, do a reload.
Okay, nothing, hmm, strange.
Do a quick little check on the code
so that's our product service calling it endpoint, okay.
And let me just test that endpoint.
Okay, yeah, so my Spring Boot server's up and running
and it's sending back data, that looks good.
Not sure what else is going on here.
And let me investigate a bit further.
And I can use the tools of my browser here.
So More Tools, go to Developer Tools.
And so this'll basically show
any JavaScript or browser errors.
And, ooh, good, look at that, access to the HttpRequest
at localhost:8080/api/products from origin
has been blocked by CORS policy.
No Access-Control-Allow.
Ooh got it, that same origin policy.
Yeah, okay, so that's what's going on.
So this is all a planned exercise
'cause I wanted you to see this
because this is a common pitfall
with building full stack applications.
And so we know how to solve this.
We can solve this by making use
of the @CrossOrign annotation on our Spring Boot app.
But this is just a good exercise
for you to see how you'll get this error message
only if you dig in to it.
On the page itself you won't see this given message,
based on the coding that we've created so far.
But any ways, no problem, no worries,
we can resolve this in the next video.
So I'll see you there.