All righty, so let's go ahead
and get started with our development process.
So in this video, we'll cover steps one and two,
fixing the deprecated method
and also configuring the CORS mapping for Spring Data REST.
All right, so let's move in here
and let's open my MyDataRestConfig.
And you may have noticed here,
there's this one method,
configureRepositoryRestConfiguration.
It's deprecated and we need to change that and clean it up.
So you may wonder,
well, how can I find a good replacement here?
Well, one tip that I use if the IDE can't help me
is I'll simply just copy the method name
and I'll do a search for it online.
So I'll just copy that name, open up my browser.
I'll drop in the method name
and I'll also use the word deprecated
just to see if I can find any hits on this given issue.
And this will take me to the documentation,
which is great because this is the definitive source.
And we see that we have this method here,
configureRepositoryRestConfiguration that's deprecated.
And drill in here and get some details.
And they'll even tell us which method to use.
So we should use this method here.
Same method name.
Simply has a new parameter being passed in.
CoreRegistry.
And this is good because we can actually just copy this
and then move over to our source code and paste it in.
So now the method's no longer deprecated.
Now let's go ahead and use this new parameter
that we just added.
Let's use it.
So this will help us with step two
of configuring CORS mapping for Spring Data REST.
I can just move down here and configure the CORS mapping.
So I'll just do an addMapping here and api/**.
The **'s for recursing for all sub-paths.
And then we also give allowedOrigins
and we give the actual origin that we accept.
In our example, localhost:4200.
And so that's pretty good.
So we're able to use this new parameter
that we gained access to
by uploading this deprecated method.
Pretty good, I like it.
Now we have this here,
we can actually remove the @CrossOrigin from JpaRepositories.
So let's move over to our repository,
so this CountryRepository.
Let's open this and we can remove the @CrossOrigin
because now we have this
in our Spring Data REST configuration.
Our CustomerRepository, there's nothing there.
Our ProductCategory, same thing.
Similar item here for our ProductCategory
and then also a similar thing for StateRepository.