Alrighty, so moving along
with our development process here.
In this video we'll focus on steps four
of integrating the template files into our Angular app
and also adding support for icons and logos.
All right, so let's swing back into Visual Studio code.
And let's move down to our app component.html file.
So at the moment it's very basic, very plane,
we're going to add some information here from our template.
So I'll just take all of this
information and just delete it.
And I'll swing back over to that template html file.
Home.html.
And I'll start with this first section here
of the page wrapper and the menu side bar.
So let's just go ahead and copy that information.
Then I'll swing back into my
Angular component here and paste it.
Expand my window here for a bit,
so I have this div class page wrapper,
the menu side bar, and then let's just add an end div
at the bottom here just to keep ourselves on track.
And now let's also add our section here
for the page container header desktop.
Let's grab this information and copy it.
And then move down here and paste that information in.
So that's the page container header desktop.
And then let's add one more div here to wrap things up.
And now there's the main content section,
but this is where they do the copy/paste
of all the different products, more of the same.
We'll get into that in a bit.
This will actually be handled by our product list component.
So what we'll do is we'll just say main content
and we'll just give a reference
to our product list component.
So let me just copy that item.
Swing back over to Visual Studio code
and I'll paste it right here,
so just main content, just the comment itself.
And then I'll just make use of my app product list.
And that's the same component that we created
a little bit earlier in the course.
And let me grab just a bit more information here.
Let's grab this footer section.
We'll copy that, we'll put it back
also in our Angular component.
I'll just say end page container.
Then paste.
All right, just a little check on here.
Make sure that looks okay.
Don't worry about the pagination stuff,
we'll get to that in some later videos.
But make sure you have those two end divs there on 61, 62.
Or somewhere thereabouts.
And then also I'll just format this thing
to kind of line everything up.
All right, so this looks good so far as
in regards to our main app component.html.
And you can also see that we make reference
to our images/logo.png for our luv2shop image,
so that's our next step here
is adding support for those logos.
So we did the icon stuff a little earlier,
so right now we're really just focusing on the logo.
I'll make this one small change here
on the href, so instead of home.html
we'll just put a pound symbol
or a hash mark symbols for right now.
Or a hashtag.
We'll get into all that stuff a little bit later.
But right now we'll focus on this logo.png.
So remember, in Angular applications
the assets directory's a special directory
for serving up web resources.
Right now we have our placeholder.
Well go ahead and copy in assets/images/logo.pgn.
We can grab that here from that template directory.
I'll just drag and drop it over here and put it into images.
And so we can verify this, so assets.
Images.
And then logo.png.
So that's our luv2shop logo.