In this video, we'll cover step four
of generating new order history component.
Let's go ahead and open up
a new terminal window
and use the angular CLI to generate this new component.
So ng generate component
and then components / OrderHistory.
All right, so let's go ahead and swing over here
to the components directory,
and there should be a new component
in here called order history.
All right, looks good.
And let's go ahead
and open up the order history component.ts file
All right, so the first thing I want to do here
is define a field for OrderHistory lists,
and it's simply an array of OrderHistory items,
and I'll initialize this array to be an empty array.
And let's move over here to this order of history and hmm.
It can't give me the auto fix.
That's interesting.
No quick fixes available, hmm.
I'll just go ahead and manually type it in.
You may encounter this problem.
You may not, your results may be different,
but I'll just manually type it in here.
All right, so that's how we
just manually add the issue
therefore importing our order history class.
And another thing here is that I want
to retrieve a user's email from the browser storage.
So I simply set up a reference here
to the web browser session storage.
And I'll use that a little later in this code.
I move down to my constructor here.
And I inject the OrderHistoryService.
That's the OrderHistoryService
that we just created in a previous video.
And I'm just having such great luck today.
For some reason, the IDE is not helping me
with some of the quick fixes, but again,
I'll just manually enter it.
For your situation it may be much easier, much better.
Alrighty, so on our ngonInit method
we'll simply call a method handleOrderHistory.
And we'll actually define
this method here in this same class.
The first thing I want to do in this method here
is read the user's email from browser storage.
I simply make use of this JSON pause,
storage.getItem,
userEmail, that's the key that will store earlier
by the login status component.
And then we can retrieve this information.
So this is the scenario of our angular components retrieving
this data at a later time.
So this is where we're at.
Okay, great, so I have the user's emails.
So now I can make a call to the history service
to actually retrieve those items for
this given user's email address.
So I use this orderHistoryService.getOrderHistory,
and I pass in the email.
So it returns on observables.
So we do our dot subscribe, of course,
and when the data's return,
then we simply assign the data.
So we have this.orderHistoryList
equals data.embedded.orders.
So this is the data that we've actually retrieved
from the rest API via the service.