In this video,
we'll work on our checkout form
and we'll add a custom validator rule.
Our form currently has a problem with white space.
In the required fields, if we enter only white space,
then it passes.
Yikes.
And let's take a look at this real quick.
So we enter our checkout form.
We have our customer fields here.
And if we simply scroll to the bottom and hit Purchase,
everything's required, that's good.
And now if I simply enter white space here for first name,
notice the validation goes away,
and a similar thing for last name.
Ooh, that's bad.
So white space is okay, as of now, but it's not really okay.
We need to resolve this. We need to fix this.
So we can resolve this issue by creating a custom validator.
We'll call this validator notOnlyWhitespace.
We'll basically check the field value,
if it only has white space,
then we're going to return an error because it failed.
Else will return null meaning that it passed.
Alrighty, so here is our development process.
So the first thing we'll do is
we'll define our custom validator rule.
Then we'll specify the custom validator rule
for the form controls.
And then finally we'll update the HTML template
to display the error messages.
Alrighty, step one of defining a custom validator rule.
We'll simply define a method in a class.
So here I have this class, Luv2ShopValidators,
and we'll add a method here to not allow white spaces
as far as validation.
So I'll create this method here,
static notOnlyWhitespace, passing a FormControl,
that's the actual form control that we're checking on.
And it returns ValidationErrors.
So if the validation check fails,
then we'll return validation errors.
If the validation check passes, then we'll return null.
And this ValidationErrors is a special object here.
It's a map of errors returned from failed validation checks.
And it's part of the Angular forms API.
So here I'll just check
if the string only contains white space.
So I make sure that it's not null
and I check the length by trimming it,
checking it to be zero.
If so, it's invalid.
So we're going to return an error object.
So here is a return ;.
And then else it's valid. I return null.
So a bit more here on this validation error key.
The HTML template will check for this error key
to see if it needs to display the actual error message
and will use this actual key in the template.
Alrighty, step two, specifying the custom validator rule
for form controls.
So here in our checkout.component.ts,
we have our checkout form group,
we have our customer component that we're creating.
We add up the validations for required and minLength,
and now we're going to add our new custom validator,
Luv2ShopValidators.notOnlyWhitespace.
So that's the actual method name that we're going to use.
And we'll see how this maps to our actual class
and the method that we have defined in the previous step.
So that's the connection here
between our custom validator method name
and the reference here in this coding.
Alrighty, in step three we're going to update the HTML template
to display the error messages.
So this is the coding we've seen before.
If validation fails, then display the error messages.
We have a new entry here.
We say, or firstName.errors.notOnlyWhitespace.
So this is a reference to our custom validation error key
from the previous steps.
So if you remember in the coding here, we've said,
"Hey, it's invalid.
We're going to return notOnlyWhitespace : true.
So that's the actual link between the actual reference here
in the template and the actual key.
Now, this key that I'm using here,
it has the same name as the method for this validation.
However, we could use a different key name if we wanted to.
We could use something totally different
than the method name,
but the reason I'm following this approach is because
this is the same convention that's used
by the Angular development team
for all of the built-in Angular validations.
The error key is the same as the method name.
But again, that's not a requirement, just the convention.
Alrighty, this looks really good so far.
So let's go ahead and move to the next video
and let's start writing some code.