Alrighty, so moving in here
with our development process,
we'll cover step one of creating the model class
for our cart item.
Alrighty,
so moving into our IDE,
let's go and moving to our terminal window
and let's go ahead and generate or create that new class.
So I can make use of this ng generate class
and give common/card-item.
And let me just clean up some of these windows here
just to close all just to get rid of those items there.
Close off this terminal window real quick.
And move over here to common,
and there is a new file cart-item.cs.
All right,
just a very basic shell right now.
And now add the fields here for this CartItem.
And remember, we simply hold the essential fields
for our product along with the actual quantity.
So I'll have fields
here for ID,
name,
and image URL
and unit price.
And also that new item here quantity
for this Cart item.
And I'll also create a constructor
where you pass in a product
and then we'll simply make the appropriate assignments here
for these properties.
Alrighty,
so that's the basic coding here
for the Card item.
So we simply just have that constructor,
we assign over the appropriate values
and then we initialize the quantity at one