In this video,
we'll create a new Angular component.
Our goal is to create a new Angular component
to display a table of data,
so we'll have information for our sales team.
So we'll create this custom component
that'll have an HTML table,
and will provide the first name, last name,
email, and sales volume for our given sales team.
Let's look at our development process.
So the first thing we'll do is
we'll create a new project.
Then we'll update the main template page.
Next we'll generate a new component,
and then we'll add the new component selector
to the app template page.
Next we'll generate a salesperson class.
Next, in the SalesPersonListComponent,
we'll create some sample data.
And then finally, in our sales-person-list template file,
we'll build the HTML table by looping over the data.
All righty, so starting here with step one,
creating a new project.
So we simply use the Angular CLI,
we say ng new sales-project.
And then once the project's created
then we simply cd into that directory.
And remember, this generates all of the Angular
starter files for our project
and we saw an overview of those files
in some of the previous videos.
All righty, in step two, we'll update
our main template page.
I'll move into the file and remove
all the Angular placeholder content
that they give us at the start
and just to keep our page simple and clean
for our custom project.
Then in step three, I need to generate a new component.
So I use the Angular CLI again.
So I'll say ng generate component sales-person-list.
It'll go off and create some files for us
and also perform an update on our module file.
And on the next slide, we'll actually
discuss these generated files.
All righty, so more information about
those generated files.
So the sales-person-list.component.ts,
that's the actual component class,
the typescript class,
The .html is the component template HTML file.
The .component.css is the component private CSS
specific for this given component.
And then a .spec.ts, that's the unit test
specifications for this component.
And then we saw the line about update the app.module.ts.
This is where it actually adds the component
to the main application module.
So here's a bit more about that main application module.
So that command here, basically what they did
is they modified the app.module.ts
and they added an import statement here to the module
and also a declaration for the module.
So our new component here, SalesPersonListComponent,
they automatically updated this file.
And this is actually a really nice feature.
In the early days of Angular,
you had to manually add this code to the app module
and it was a common pitfall for new developers,
so I'm really happy now that the Angular team
has incorporated this feature into the Angular CLI.
It makes life much easier for us developers.
Now looking at step four of adding
the new component selector to the app template page,
so on our app.component.html, we'll add a new reference
there for app-sales-person-list.
Now this is the actual name of the selector
from that new component that we just created.
Now we can verify that by looking at the @Component
definition here, selector: 'app-sales-person-list'.
So that's the actual custom tag that we'll use
for this given component here.
And for template URL, that's the location
to our actual component HTML file.
Now later on in our component class,
we'll actually add sample data here.
And then over on our template file,
our component.html, we'll add our HTML table here.
And you'll see how this'll all come together
later in the video.