Alrighty, so,
moving along with our development process.
In step three we need to develop the entities
for the product and the product category.
Alrighty,
now the first thing we need to do
is import the spring boot project.
And we simply navigate over
to our ecommerce project directory,
and our 02 backend.
And there should be a spring boot ecommerce folder,
let's open that one.
And so now we'll simply just go through
the IntelliJ wizard for importing a project,
so make sure you choose the maven project.
And we'll simply check the box here
to help us out in the future
to import maven projects automatically.
We'll keep the defaults here on this screen.
I'm using Java 13,
but whatever version of Java you have installed,
just make sure it's listed there.
And you can keep all the other defaults,
and hit finish.
Alrighty,
I'll just do a little quick scan here of this project.
I'll just move into my source main Java directory.
Our ecommerce package.
And I'll just open up this main application,
the spring boot ecommerce application.
So this is our spring boot app that we get for free.
And then I'll take a look at our resources
and our application.properties,
and it's empty by default.
And what I like to do is copy over
the application.properties file from my starter files.
So let's swing over to our file system.
And our ecommerce project folder,
and our 01 starter files,
we have an application.properties.
Let's copy that file,
and let's paste it here into the resources directory,
and let's hit okay and we overwrite the existing file.
Alrighty, so this is our application.properties
that we copied from our starter files.
And this is all the standard
JDBC spring boot connection work.
So, our driver class name,
our URL,
username,
password,
the dialect,
and the path that we'll use for our rest API slash API.
So this is all standard spring boot stuff.
You should be aware of how this stuff works already.
Alright so now it's step three of developing the entities.
So the first thing I'll do is
I'll create a new package called entity.
And then I'll create a new Java Class called product.
Alrighty so let me expand my window here and zoom in a bit.
So this is going to be our JPA entity.
And then we'll set up our JPA annotation for table
to map this argument table product.
And then I'll make use of this
data annotation from the lombok project.
And so remember,
this will automatically generate
the getter and setter methods for you behind the scenes.
It reduces the boilerplace code.
So, you won't actually see the getter and setter
methods in the code,
but lombok will provide the support for you
behind the scenes automatically.
And now I'll simply go through and define fields here
to map to the given database tables.
So this is kind of straight forward,
more of the same.
I'll be quiet here for a bit
and I'll just crank out this code.
Alrighty, so this looks pretty good.
So we created all of the fields here
for this database table.
We still need to do some more work
as far as mapping it to the actual columns,
but we'll do that in the next video.