All right, so moving along
with our development process.
We're in step four here of
updating our ProductListComponent to handle pagination.
And basically, what we'll do is
we'll make calls to that product service
using that new method that we just created
in the previous video.
All right, so let's go ahead and close this one window,
and let's open up our component,
product-list,
product-list.component.ts.
Zoom out a bit and expand my window.
All right, so just as a checkpoint,
make sure you're in ProductListComponent.
And I'll move in here,
and I'll do some general housekeeping.
I'll just go ahead and initialize some of the properties
to have default values,
just so everything is initialized
and we know what we're working with.
And now I'll go through,
and I'll add some new properties for pagination.
All righty, so I have these new properties here
for page number, the page size, and also the total elements.
So now, let's go ahead and move down
to our handleListProducts method.
And we'll have to do some special work here
regarding the category id.
So we have to check if we have a different category id
than the previous.
Now, note, Angular will reuse a component
if it's currently being viewed.
So Angular may not always create a new component every time.
If the component is currently being viewed in the browser,
then Angular will simply reuse that component,
so we'll have some state from the previous call,
so we need to kind of perform some additional operations here.
And the reason we're adding this code
is mainly for the page number or resetting the page number.
So if we have a different category id than the previous,
then we want to reset the page number back to one.
And that's the rational for adding this code.
So if this.previousCategoryId is not equal to
this category id, then this.PageNumber equals one.
Now, granted, this previousCategoryId, we don't have yet.
Let's go ahead and declare it
and that'll actually create this property for us
up top in this class.
All right, and so if we scroll to the top of this class,
we'll see this new property
that the IDE just created for us.
Okay, great, there it is, previousCategoryId.
Let's go ahead and cut this,
and I'd like to move it up right below currentCategoryId,
just so similar properties are in similar locations
of the actual file.
And then it'll also initialize it to one.
All right, so this looks pretty good right now,
previousCategoryId, great.
Now, let's go ahead and move back
to the handleListProducts method,
and in this method,
I'll actually keep track of that category.
So here I'll have previousCategoryId equals
currentCategoryId,
and I'll also log this information,
just so we can track this in our browser
for debugging purposes.
And I'll also include the page number in the log.
So now, moving down here, as for as getting the products
for the given category id.
Now I simply need to call the service,
make use of that new map that we created,
getProductList paginate.
And then I need to pass in those parameters.
So I need to pass in thePageNumber, thePageSize,
and currentCategoryId.
And let me just clean up the tabbing here,
so things look pretty on the screen.
And then I'll add .subscribe
and I'll call this.processResult.
At the moment, we don't have processResult created yet.
We'll actually create it shortly in this video.
However, I just want to point out again,
as a reminder on thePageNumber.
So here we have thePageNumber minus one.
Again, the reason we're doing this is because
pagination component in Angular,
pages are one based.
However, in Spring Data REST,
the pages are zero based.
So basically, in Angular we have a page,
as we have to decrement it by one
to map to the appropriate page on the backend,
Spring Data REST JSON.
So again, that's why we have to do
the funny math operations here.
All righty, so now let's go ahead and take care of that
processResult method.
So I'll define it here.
And now, basically all we're going to do is
we're simply going to map data from that JSON response
to the actual properties here for this given class.
So on the left-hand side,
we have properties that are defined in this class.
Over on the right-hand side is the result of
the data that came back from the Spring Data REST JSON,
and that's information from our interface,
get response products.
And again, as a reminder here,
we have to say data.page.number plus one,
because Spring Data REST, the pages are zero based.
In Angular, they're one based.
So just make sure you have the appropriate mapping
going back and forth.
And if you miss this (laughs),
your page pagination will not work as desired.
So this is an easy thing to miss.
So just make sure that your code resembles
what I have here on this screen,
because the pagination component is one based,
and Spring Data REST is zero based.
All righty, so this coding looks really good,
and I'm excited for the next step.
So I'll see ya in the next video.