All right, so let's get started
with our development process.
We'll do step one of updating the HTML template
and also updating our checkout component
with the event handler.
All right, so let's go ahead and move in here
and open up our checkoutcomponent.html.
And let's move down to that section
where we have the credit card expiration year.
So there's our component here,
and we're going to add the event bonding here
for the change event.
So let's kind of zoom in, and I'll say change.
And then when that event happens,
I'll call handle months and years.
All right, now the IDE is going to give us an error message,
right, because we haven't really created that method yet.
That's fine.
We'll actually do that in this next section here.
So I'll just copy that method name,
and then I'll use that when I define
that method in my component.ts file.
So let's open up checkoutcomponent.ts.
And so this is for step two of updating
our checkout component and adding that event handler.
So I'll just simply move down to the bottom of this file.
And as the last method here, right after onsubmit,
I'll paste in that method name, handle months and years.
There we go, that looks pretty good.
So the first thing I'll do is
I'll get a handle to the credit card form group,
and then I'll get the current year
by saying new date.getfullyear,
and then I'll also get the selected year from the form.
So whatever the user selected in the UIE on the form,
I'll read that as a selected year.
And so here, we want to check to see
if the current year equals the selected year.
If so, then we're going to start with the current month.
So I'll just set up a variable here for start month,
and then I perform this comparison.
If current year equals selected year,
then we'll start with the current month.
So I say new date.getmonth.
And again, plus one,
because everything's zero-based for months.
Else, I'll have start month equals one.
And then I simply call my form service,
and I say get credit card months,
and I give them the month to start with.
And all of this other coding here is the same,
we do .subscribe.
We get the data back and we assign it
to this.creditcardmonths equals data.
Alrighty, so this coding here looks pretty good, I like it.
Alright, so let's go ahead and test it out.
If your Spring Boot backend is not running,
go ahead and start it now.
Then let's go ahead and start up our Angular app,
swing back into our browser,
let's just add a couple of items to the cart.
And so I'm going to go check out here at the bottom.
And so now we're going to check
to make sure our fields are dependent.
So if we choose a future year,
then we're going to get all of the months, one to 12.
And if we select the current year,
then we only get the months
from the current month into the future.
So when I'm recording this it's June,
and so that's why we see six going down to 12.
But your values may differ based on
when you actually run your application as far as time.
All right, so this looks pretty good.
So we have dependent fields in place, I like it.
Good job, my friend.