So in step five,
we need to integrate the Okta Sign-In Widget
with our application.
So the first thing we need to do is add support
for the Okta sign in CSS styles.
So in our angular.json file, then in the styles section,
we simply reference the Okta sign in CSS.
Next, we need to go through and generate a login component.
So here I make use of the Angular CLI ng generate component,
components/login.
Then I'll open up our login component on HTML,
and I'll basically just set up a container
to inject the Okta Sign-In Widget.
So here I simply set up a div,
and then I give div id equals okta-sign-in-widget.
So this is where it'll actually place
the Okta Sign-In Widget within our application.
So moving into the file login.component.ts,
I have my regular Angular imports.
And then also on the next two lines,
I have imports from the Okta SDK,
and also an import for the Okta Sign-In Widget.
I'll also do an import on myAppConfig.
And so this is from the file
that we created earlier, myAppConfig.
So that's that JSON file
that has configuration information for connecting
to our given Okta application.
So effectively, just think of this JSON here
as like a properties file.
And so we'll do an import here,
so we can access these configs.
So now let's simply go through
and just create a normal component here, LoginComponent.
I'll set up a reference here for Okta sign in.
I'll set up a constructor
while I inject the OktaAuthService.
And inside of this constructor here,
I create this new OktaSignIn,
and here's where I customize the actual logo here
for this Sign-In Widget.
So I say logo is assets/images/logo.png.
So that's our Love2shop logo
that already exists in our application.
So we're simply giving a relative reference here
for that logo.
You can use any logo file here that you like
for actually including it on your Sign-In Widget.
And then I add information here for the base URI,
the clientId and the redirectUri.
This is the same information that we had
from our configuration.
And then I set up the authParams,
so pkce, issuer, scopes.
So we've already discussed issuer and scopes.
You're probably wondering about PKCE,
what exactly does that mean?
So that stands for Proof Key for Code Exchange.
We have this value set to true.
So let's talk a bit about this Proof Key for Code Exchange.
So we'll make use of our authorization code flow with PKCE.
PKCE, again, Proof Key for Code Exchange.
It's the recommended approach for controlling access
between our app and the auth server.
And in particular it protects against
the Authorization Code Interception attacks.
So basically what PKCE does
is that it introduces a concept of dynamic secrets.
So instead of constant secrets, it's dynamic.
So it's actually implemented with the code verifier,
a code challenge, and a method.
Now if you'd like to get more details on PKCE,
visit the link I have here on the screen,
it'll redirect you
to the official Okta documentation for PKCE.
All right so a bit more here
on our login.component.ts file.
So we have the code from before,
and we'll add this new method here for ngOnInIt.
So in the ngOnInIt,
the first thing that we'll do
is we'll say oktaSignIn.remove,
basically remove any previous elements that were there.
And then I'll say oktaSignIn.renderEL.
So EL means render an element,
and we give the actual element id
that we want them to render.
So here I have £okta-sign-in-widget.
So this name should be the same as the div tag
that we used in our login.component.html.
So remember that previous code that we wrote.
We had this div
and we had the id set to okta-sign-in-widget.
So those two items have to match up
because you're telling it, "Hey, render this element."
And you need to give the actual element id
and they have to match.
You can give it any name.
But as long as you stay consistent between the HTML file
and the reference that we have here in our TS file.
When the user submits their credentials, we get a response.
And so if the response.status equals success,
that means that everything's okay.
We'll say oktaAuthService.signInWithRedirect.
If we have an error, then we simply throw an error.
And that's how the Sign-In Widget works.
So again, not much coding.
It encapsulates a lot of the low-level coding
for the backend for communicating
with the actual Okta service.
And it handles the authentication
and the authorization piece for us.
Very nice, I like it.