Alrighty, so there was a bit more work
we have to do here in order item
and that's mainly setting up the relationship
between order and order item.
So, it's really a many-to-one
coming from the side of order item.
So going from orders to order item is one-to-many,
going from order item to order is many-to-one.
And then we simply use the actual join column name here
and the join column is order_ID.
Now our order is also associated with the customer
and then also an order is associated with shipping address
and a billing address.
Then I'll set up the relationship, so an order has
a many-to-one relationship with customer
and the join column is on customer_ID.
Now let's go ahead and look at our customer class here.
So in our customer, we'll set up a collection of orders
and the relationship we'll use here is one-to-many
and this will be mapped by the customer,
that's defined in the given order.
And we'll also set up our cascade type to cascade all.
And I'll simply just initialize this collection here.
And I'll also go through and add a convenience method
for adding new orders for this customer
and again, it's just a convenience method,
we could use it in the future if we'd like.
So we simply pass in an order,
make sure order is not equal to null,
if orders, the collection is null, we create a new one.
We do orders.add the order
and then we also set our reference on the customer
so order.setCustomer(this).
All right, so let's go ahead and move back to order.
And let's set up the relationships here between order
and our shipping address and billing address.
So the shipping address is a one-to-one relationship
and the join column that we're using here
is the shipping address ID that's defined here
in this order table
and then the reference column name is the ID
defined in the actual address table.
So I can just copy this and apply the same
for billing address.
I'll simply make the one small change here on the name,
so that will be billing address ID
and then everything else there stays the same.
Okay, so let's move into address.java
and set up the relationship between the address
and the order.
And this is going to be a one-to-one
and then here we have primary key join column.
So, we'll basically join based on the ID of the order
and also the ID of the address
and so we basically just kind of default
and use the same name for those primary keys
and hibernate or figure out the actual add ID
for each one of these entities.
Okay, great, so this takes care of the relationship
between address and order,
and that applies for our billing address
and shipping address.