All right, so we have orderItems taken care of.
Now let's go ahead and set up our purchase.
So we just create a new instance here.
So we'll start here by pulling in information
for the purchase.shippingAddress.
So the first thing I do here is go through
and use that checkout.FormGroup.controls
for shippingAddress.value.
So it's going to access that form data for me.
And now I need to kind of do a little more massaging here
to grab the data accordingly.
So I want to grab the shippingState.
So I grab that information from purchase.shippingAddress.
And then I'll do a similar thing here for countries.
So just a little copy paste.
So shippingCountry.
Okay, so that takes care of that.
Have those as objects right now.
Now I need to just grab the actual data
for each one of those items.
So I'll say the state equals shippingState.name.
And then I'll say purchase.shippingAddress.country
equals shippingCountry.name.
Okay, so this looks good.
Well, actually, I didn't follow my comments here.
I need to cut this and move it somewhere else.
No, this isn't for customer, this is shippingAddress stuff.
So let's just cut this section
and move it down to the right comment.
Okay, ah, there we go.
I had comments to keep myself on track
and I still got off track.
Oh, gosh!
So let's get back on track,
and let's have a purchase.customer equals,
and then we'll grab the customer from the checkoutFormGroup.
So this is checkoutFormGroup.controls['customer'].value.
Okay, so that's okay, that's in good shape.
And now for the shippingAddress, I can copy this,
and use a similar thing for billing address.
All right, so I simply just need to go through
and update or change our references to shipping to billing.
Alrighty, so I think I have everything covered.
So just double check that
and make sure you have everything aligned up
as I have here on the screen.