All righty, so I'm a little excited here.
Let's go ahead and run the app and see what it looks like.
Let's see how our integration process worked
with the template and the Angular application.
So the one thing we need to do,
is get our back-end up and running,
so start up IntelliJ,
and run the Spring Boot back-end application.
All righty, so our Spring Boot back-end is up and running.
And then we can move over to visual studio code.
And we can run the Angular front-end application.
All right, so that's up and running,
go to our web browser and go to localhost:4200
to access the Angular app, and okay.
Looks okay, it's just a rough cut right now.
That main section is just out HTML table
that we created earlier,
being put into the template
and we'll work on making it a grid a little bit later,
but at least we have the data being displayed,
which is kind of cool.
Over on the left hand side we have the categories,
along the top we have the search bar and so on.
We'll add this functionality over time.
But this is good,
at least we know we have the styles in place
and all the basics in place right now.
All right, let's swing back over to visual studio coding,
you may sit there and wonder, gosh all of the CSS styles,
what are they?
What are they doing and so on.
So if you need to find out about a given CSS style,
simply copy the style name
and then search for it in styles.css.
If it's not in the styles.css,
then you simply copy the style name
and search for it on Google.
Like Bootstrap or whatever.
If the style starts with FA,
then most likely it's something from Fontawesome.
So let's look at a quick little demo of this,
'cus there's a lot of styles here.
Page wrapper, let's go ahead and grab that style,
let's get some more information about it.
So we simply grab the style, we copy it.
And then we move over to our styles.css,
and then we simply search for that style.
So here we see it's one of the styles in our own files,
so overflow, background, padding and so on.
So that's a local CSS style that we're using.
So what about menu side bars,
so let's do a similar thing with that one.
So drop in menu side bar,
and again we can see the reference
on how that given CSS style is defined.
Okay,
so these are all local styles in our given application.
So what about other styles, maybe a Bootstrap style.
So let me go ahead and grab this container fluid,
and copy this style and see if I can find it in styles.css.
Notice here in the top right, it says no results.
Hey, I couldn't find it, it's not in your local CSS file.
All right, so that means we need to go to the web
and then search for it.
So I'll check to see if it's a Bootstrap style.
So I'll just do a search on Bootstrap
and that given style name.
Bingo!
Good, so this is definitely a Bootstrap style.
So we found some tutorials about it,
and we even find the official Bootstrap documentation
about that given style.
If we follow the link here,
search for it over here on their site,
that's a cool feature.
It basically gives you information about that given style.
So it's for setting up containers and flow and so forth.
Basically for setting up a grid system.
That's what we'll use on our product layout.
All right, so that was just a little example there
on researching or investigating the different styles
that are used in this given application.
So now we'll take a look at this app product list.
So this is code we created a little bit earlier,
so this is one of our components.
Our product list components.
So let's go ahead
and look at the product-list-component.ts file.
So that's given selector, that kind of connects everything.
We're going to make use of a different template here,
so we're not going to use the product list template component,
we'll make use of a new one,
but we'll use it as a starting point.
All right, so let's go ahead and copy this component file.
Product list table.component.
Then we'll paste it and now we'll simply rename it,
and give it a new name.
So I will call it product list grid.component,
and I'll remove the copy stuff.
All right, so that's my own file that I can use now.
Make sure that file is open, list grid.
Close the list table,
make sure I'm editing the correct file.
I also need to update the type script file
to make sure it's using the right template.
All right, so I just did a little copy, paste over there.
Comin' out this guy,
and then the template URL is
product list grid.component.html.
Okay, great.
Let's go ahead an open up our product list
grid.coponent.html, expand the window.
This is where we'll do all of our work.