All righty, now step five
of generating a SalesPerson class,
Now, we can use the Angular CLI to generate
a class, so we could say ng generate class
and you give a reference to the class.
This'll create a very basic TypeScript class.
Now, there's no requirement to use this,
you could actually manually create the class yourself,
but here I'm simply going to use the CLI just to help us out.
Now this class that it creates, though,
it's a very basic file, there's nothing here.
But we can actually enhance it by adding
some of our own code here.
So I'll create my own constructor
and I'll make use of parameter properties here.
So the parameter properties for first name, last name,
email, and sales volume.
Now I know these are parameter properties
because they're declared by prefixing
the constructor argument with an access modifier.
So the access modifiers you can use
is public, protected, private, or read only.
So the key here is that if you have a constructor
with arguments and you prefix it with these items,
then it's automatically a parameter property.
Now remember with parameter properties,
it actually declares the properties
and assigns the properties automatically.
It minimizes the boilerplate coding
that you'd have to do for setting up a constructor.
So in the bottom left here's the UML for the SalesPerson.
So we have these four properties here,
first name, last name, email, and sales volume.
Okay, so now about these public properties.
I know you saw that code with the constructor
and I had these parameter properties and I used public
and you probably said, "Oh my gosh, no, no way."
All righty, so in the Angular world,
public properties are very common.
So you'll see the Angular developers
using public properties in their code.
So this is a different approach than what
Java developers are used to.
In the Java world, we primarily use private fields
and have public getter setter methods
to promote encapsulation.
However, in the Angular world,
most Angular developers simply use public properties
and they skip on the getter setter methods or accessors.
So you'll actually see this type of coding
in the official Angular documentation and tutorials.
Also you'll see this coding in blog articles
and on real time projects,
so don't worry about this too much.
Feel free to use public properties
in your Angular coding.
Okay, whoo. I had to get that out of the way.
Now moving ahead to step six,
in our SalesPersonListComponent, we need
to create some sample data, all right.
So here in my code I'm going to import our new class,
SalesPerson and then I'll create an array of objects,
so I have sales-person-list of SalesPerson
with square brackets denotes an array,
equals, and then inside of this array,
I simply create x number of SalesPerson objects here.
So here I have entries for Anup Kumar, John Doe,
Claire Murphy, and Mai Truong.
And then finally to kind of wrap this all together
in step seven, in our sales-person-list template file,
we're going to build the HTML table by looping over the data.
All righty, so we'll go ahead and create
a very basic HTML table.
I'll set up a thead section with out columns
for first name, last name, email, and sales volume.
And so now I move down to the table body.
I'll make use of tr and then I'll use a *ngFor.
So this is a special angular directive
that will loop over the array and it'll
create a table row for each array element.
So here I have *ngFOr equals let tempSalesPerson
of SalesPersonList.
So this will actually access the property,
the find and the component.
So this is the exact name of the property,
SalesPersonList, it matches up, and will simply
loop over that array.
And so for each element in the array,
we'll have this table row and then we'll use table data
to access the actual internals there for that given object.
So I use the curly brace, curly brace,
tempSalesPerson.firstName and then I repeat the process
for .lastName, .email, and .salesVolume.
So this'll give me the HTML table,
populate it with data from the property.
All righty, this looks great so let's go ahead
and move it to our IDE and let's write the code.