Now, there's one thing that I want to talk to you about
or show you that we still have an issue in our application
by making use of this security work.
And primarily when we go through and do a checkout.
Let's go and add a couple of items to our shopping cart.
So right now I have a couple of items.
I'll do a Checkout.
We'll go ahead and fill out our Customer information here.
And now we can go ahead and Purchase or Checkout
and notice that we'll get a Failure.
So the error message says
failure response for /api/checkout/purchase:403.
It says, Okay, but that's not okay.
Let's find out exactly what's going on here
so I can go into my developer Console here.
All right.
So it says Failed to load resource status 403.
Okay.
Swing back over to my application
and take a look at my Security Configuration.
So that's there.
And also let's take a look
at our controller for the purchase, or for the checkout.
So our CheckoutController here
"/api/checkout" PostMapping("/ purchase").
Ah, okay, got it.
Got it.
All right.
So this fails because we're sending the checkout requests
with the HTTP POST.
By default CSRF is enabled.
Remember CSRF is for the Cross Site Request Forgery.
So basically this is a protection
for your given application.
And the way CSF works is that it performs checks
on HTTP requests that can modify the data.
So like a post or put or another feature there.
So in this case was sending over a POST
and they perform this check by making use of cookies.
And our scenario here, we're not using cookies
for session tracking.
So then the CSRF protection says
the request is unauthorized.
We can resolve this by disabling CSRF in our application.
This technique is commonly used for REST APIs
because of state lists.
We're not using making use of session cookies and so forth.
So this is totally okay for this scenario.
Let's go ahead and move into our security code here.
And we're going to disable CSRF
since we're not using Cookies for session tracking.
Okay. So the coding is in place for this.
Let's go ahead and save this and run our application again.
Now we can swing back to our app
and we can kind of just pick up where we left off.
Cause we have all the data set up here
for the form and hit Purchase
and Success.
So the order has been received
and they gave us an Order tracking number.
So this was awesome.
So we were able to resolve that issue
by disabling CSRF primarily here for this scenario
since we're not using session cookies for tracking
and all of our order stuff works.
And we can see that new order that just went in.
We know it's actually saving that order
on the backend and processing it successfully.
All right.
So this is some really good work
and I'd like to say good job, my friend.