Alrighty, so let's dive in here.
So we're on step six.
We need to modify our Spring Boot app.
The REST Repository needs a new method.
For this we need to swing over to IntelliJ
so we can make updates to our Spring Boot application.
Let's zoom in here.
And let's move down to our dao package
and open up our Product Repository,
'cause this is the one we'll actually add our new method.
Expand the window here for a second,
and I'll add one of those new query methods.
Okay, so we have the method here.
Let's go ahead and fix some of the imports.
And I'll actually make use of an IntelliJ feature
or setting to handle auto importing.
So I just move into my IntelliJ Preferences.
I'll select Editor.
I'll move down to General,
and I'll choose Auto Import.
Just to kind of help us out as we go through the course
so we don't have to manually import items every time.
So we'll Add unambiguous imports on the fly,
and also Optimize imports on the fly,
just to keep things a bit tidy and nice for us.
And then we'll simply do an import over here,
because this one is ambiguous and
not sure which one to import.
Be sure to import Pageable
from the org.springframework.data.domain.
So just make sure you have the correct imports
up top here for Page and Pageable.
And just as a refresher here, this is a query method
because it starts with findBy.
We're going to match by category id,
and we'll use this parameter value
based on the id parameter.
And also remember, behind the scenes,
Spring will execute a query similar
to SELECT * FROM product where category_id=
and then plug in that given parameter value.
Again, remember, this is all the Spring magic
that happens in the background.
Spring will parse that method
and execute the appropriate query.
And then also Spring Data REST will automatically expose
the endpoint based on that given method name,
so search/findByCategoryId,
and then here we have the ID,
and that's what we pass over to that given REST API.
Alrighty, so let's go ahead and run this version
of our Spring Boot application and view the results.
So if you have your app running be sure to stop it now,
and then we'll go ahead and start it up.
And then I'll simply open up a web browser
and I'll go to a given endpoint just to test this out
to see how it works.
So I'll go to localhost:8080/api/products/search,
then I give that method name findByCategoryId=
and then I give id= and I pass in whatever the value is,
one, two, three, or four.
So I entered the value of one,
so I'm getting all of the books, all right.
These are all the books that are being passed back, cool.
If I give the id equals two, then I'll get Coffee Mugs.
Okay, Coffee Mug, Coffee Mug.
All right, that's fine.
And a similar thing here for the other CategoryIds
of three and four.
Mouse Pads and Luggage Tags, respectively.
All right, so we know that our REST API is working properly,
and we know that if we pass in a given CategoryId,
it'll give us only products for that given category.