Okay, so we're almost done.
So the final step of our development process
is adding CrossOrigin support
to our Spring Boot application.
So we'll add CrossOrigin support
to get rid of that ugly error message.
So what I'll do is I'll move into my IDE.
So we'll move into our product repository.
We'll add support for the @CrossOrigin annotation
and then we'll specify the origin.
So here we give the actual origin or server
that our Angular application is running on,
or our JavaScript application.
So I'll give http localhost 4200.
And so we can accept calls from web browser scripts
for this origin.
So remember that origin is more than just the hostname.
The origin is the protocol, hostname, and port.
And all of these have to match for it to be the same origin
so note here an example of the same origin.
We have the exact same protocol, hostname, and port.
And notice in the second example here
we have a different origin,
and the reason it's a different origin here
is because the port numbers are different.
All right, so again, origin is more than just the hostname.
All righty, so we have this in place here
for our product repository.
We'll do a similar thing for our product category repository
so let me open that one up.
And I'll also add the annotation here for @CrossOrigin.
All righty, great, so that's in place.
All right, so let's go ahead and run our application
and let's test it out.
All right, so my Spring Boot app is up and running
with the new setup.
And now I can swing back over to my web browser
and I simply do a reload here on the browser
and, yes, success.
So now we have a list of products being displayed
in our Angular application.
So now that we know that we're successful
of having our front end making a call to our back end.
So now we have Full Stack up and running.
I'm excited.
This is working exactly as desired.
So I'd like to say good job, my friend.