Okay, so we've made some progress
but I'd like to clean things up a bit
and I'd like to remove the hard-coded CORS configuration
because right now,
you see we have the /api that's hard coded
and also we have the localhost:4200 that's hard coded.
And so let's clean this up a bit
and make use of some properties files for this.
So I'll move down to my application.properties file.
Zoom in here for a second.
Then I'll add a new property here for allowed.origins
and I'll just move my localhost:4200 right here.
And now just swinging back over to MyDataRestConfig.
And I'll set up a field up top
for the AllowedOrigins.
So this is a String array AllowedOrigins
as they could be multiple.
And I'll make use of the @Value.
And I give my dollar sign, curly brace
and I reference that actual property name,
allowed.origins and so this will actually inject the data
from the app.properties file.
All right, so that part looks pretty good,
so now we can use this new field here
of the allowedOrigins and we can reference it here
in our code.
So remove the hard-coded data, add our variable, our field
and we're A-OK.
Good, I like it.
And then let's do a similar thing here for the path.
So instead of the /api,
we can read this information from our config.
So the config object that's passed into this method
has a method getBasePath
and so it'll access the same information
from the properties file for us.
So that'll give us the actual mapping
for this given path pattern.
All right, so I think we've accomplished our task here
of removing the hard-coded information
from the CORS configuration setup.
All right, so I like to go ahead
and run this application and test it out,
just to see how these CORS mappings work out.
So I have my Boot application up and running.
I'll go ahead and start up my Angular application.
All righty, simply go and visit my application.
And we're able to get categories over here, that's great.
And able to get products, so this looks pretty good.
So those configurations that we set up,
those work out just fine.