Now in step six, we're going to develop
a log-in status component for the log in, log out buttons.
At the top of our application,
we'll have this log-in status component.
So if the user's not logged in,
we'll give them a log-in button.
Once the user logs in successfully,
then we'll welcome them back by name
and then we'll also give them a log out button.
So the buttons will change
depending on the user's logged in state.
Alrighty, so just getting started here,
we use the angular CLI again,
ng generate component, components/LoginStatus.
And then we'll move into our
log-instatus.component.ts file.
We take care of some imports up top,
our normal act component
and our log-in status component.
We'll set up two fields here,
is authenticated and user full name.
We'll use our constructor to inject the Okta auth service.
In our ngon init method,
we'll simply subscribe to the authentication state changes.
So we say oktaauthservice.authenticatestate.subscribe.
We get a result
and we say isauthenticated equals to the result.
And then we also call this.getuserdetails.
Now what about getuserdetails?
Well, it's over here.
So it's a method that we'll define in our class here.
And we check if this stock is authenticated,
then we'll fetch the logged in user details, their claims
and the user full name is exposed as a property name.
So here we'll say this oktaauthservice.getuser.thin,
so once we get a response,
then we'll say this.userfullnames equals
the response.name.
And then also at the bottom here
we'll have a log out method.
So when they actually do log out,
they will make use of the Okta auth service
and sign up a user.
And this removes the tokens that are associated
with this given user.
Okay we also have some work to do on our
loginstatuscomponent.html page.
So we'll set up this div and we'll make use
of this ngif, if they are authenticated
and user full name is set
then we'll say welcome back user full name.
We'll also have another ngif,
if not authenticated,
we'll show them the log-in button
and if they are authenticated,
then we'll show them the log out button.
So here log in, displays the log-in button.
If they're already logged in
or they're authenticated,
then we say welcome back username.
And then we also provide
a log out button for them.
All right so now we need to add our new log-in
status components to the header section of our application.
So right now on our application
and ourappcomponent.html,
we have references to some of our custom components.
So earlier we created an app search component.
So that's in place now.
We also have our app cart status, that's in place.
Now we have this new log-in status component
that we just created.
And so we'll display it right here between the two.
Alrighty. So we're almost done.
We're almost done.
So this is step seven of updating our app module configs
to connect the routes.
So in our appmodule.ts file, we'll do some imports
up top for Okta.
We'll also import our myappconfig.config file that
we created a little bit earlier.
We'll create this Okta config.
So we say Okta.assign on auth required,
we inject the actual router
and then we say router.navigateto/log-in.
This will redirect the user to our custom log-in page.
And we also pass on a reference to my appconfig.oidc.
So that's the JSON configs
that we created earlier in myappconfig.ts file.
And then moving over here, we have a bit more code to write.
So we'll set up our routes here.
So we have a route for log-in/callback
and then also our route for log-in.
So log in, we'll go to the log-in component
that we just created in the previous slides.
So we saw all the code for it,
but you may wonder what's this Okta callback component.
All right so of course it's something from the Okta SDK.
So once the user is authenticated,
they are redirected to our application.
So normally we would have to parse the response
and store the oauth or open ID connect tokens,
but the Okta callback component will do this work for you.
So there's no need for us to do any of the low level coding.
So we simply allow the Okta callback component
to handle this work for us.
We also need to make another update here
to the appmodule.ts in the import section,
we need to import the Okta auth module.
Basically give us access to the different components
to find them in Okta auth module.
And then for providers, we give a reference to Okta config.
This allows us to perform dependency injection
of the Okta auth service into different parts
of our application.
Alrighty, so that's pretty much it.
So if you'd like to get more information
on these Okta components for the Okta sign-in widget,
you can use the link here listed on the slide,
and also the Okta angular SDK referenced here.
And the really nice thing about these links is that
they give a description as far as the features
and functionality that's available.
And also you may be a little curious,
you'd like to say, "Hmm I'd like to see the actual
source code of what's happening in the background
for this given Okta component
or this you know, whatever code."
Well, this is the GitHub repo.
So you can actually see the real source code
behind the scenes, as far as
all of the low-level work that they're using here
for communicating with the Okta platform.
All right, good stuff.