Alrighty, I'm getting really excited because
we're at the final step here!
So step five of the enhancing the HTML template
to use the 'ng-bootstrap pagination component'.
All right, good stuff!
All right, it says go ahead and close that window,
and let's go ahead and open up our template
'product-list-grid-component.html'.
And just moving to the top, this is our main
list grid for listing all of our products
and we want to have our pagination component
at the bottom.
So one thing you want to do here is move down
to the bottom of this file, and you want to
add your new entries just above the third 'div'
All right, so third from the bottom.
So you want to have three 'divs' below you when
you start adding new data and it's really
important because if not what CSS,
if you don't have things at the right location,
your page is all mixed up and CSS is pretty unforgiving.
Okay?
(laughs)
So make sure you have your new entry here above
the third 'div' from the bottom.
All right, now I'll just add some more comments
here to myself to kind of keep myself on track.
So this where I'll add my pagination component area,
in this little footer section here.
Give myself some white space at the bottom to stretch out.
So now add a collection of 'divs' mainly for layout
and alignment of this given pagination component.
All right, so that covers the 'divs'
and styles for the layout.
Now actually getting down to work here with our
'ngb-pagination component',
so getting into the real meat of the actual coding here.
So I'll make use of this 'ngb-pagination' component
and then we'll set some parameters on it,
and remember, this pagination component will
automatically generate the actual controls that
you'll see on the screen.
Again, base on information from those parameters.
So I'll set up parameters here for the 'page',
'PageSize', 'collectionSize',
and the 'pageChange' event.
And remember, on the left-hand side,
these are parameters for the 'ngb-pagination' component.
Over on the right-hand side, those are properties
for the 'ProductListComponent'.
And also, this 'pageChange', this is an event-binding
'pageChange' event.
So when the user clicks a different page,
then they'll call our method list products in our
'ProductListComponent'.
And this will make sure that we show a new page
of data base on this information.
Alrighty, so that's the end of step five.
That's the end of our major development here.
So on the next video, we'll actually run
this application and we'll test it out,
and see our how pagination control works.
Alrighty, I'll see ya in the next video!