In this video, we're going to populate
the Country-State Drop-Down list.
On the form for our shipping address,
we need to populate the drop-down list for countries
and also populate the drop-down list for States.
So what we'll do is we'll populate the countries
and States from the backend REST API,
we'll pull information from the database.
The user will select the country,
and then depending on the country select,
we'll populate the list of States.
Now the term "State" is different for each country.
So in the US we make use of States,
but I know in other parts of the world
or in other countries,
they have other names like Province, Districts,
Regions, Prefecture, so on.
So basically whatever administrative region
is used for your country simply use that name,
but I'll simply use state here just to keep things simple.
All right, so let's go ahead
and look at our development process.
And this is for the backend development.
The first thing that we'll do
is we'll create the database tables
and then we'll develop a JPA Entities for country and state.
Next we'll create the Spring Data Repositories,
and then finally we'll update our Spring Data REST Configs.
All right, step one of creating the database tables.
So here we'll have two tables.
We'll have a country table and a state table.
So for country, we'll have the ID, the code and the name.
For state we'll have the ID, name and the country ID.
So the country ID maps back to the actual country.
So basically many States will belong to one country
and one country has many States.
And the nice thing here is that we can make use
of some of these advanced mappings,
one to many and many to one.
And we'll be able to pull this together
in our eCommerce application.
All right, so here's the SQL for creating those tables.
So we create the table country.
We have the columns ID, code and name.
We specify the ID is the primary key.
And then we also create a table for state,
ID name, country ID.
So country ID is actually a foreign key
and that country ID maps back to the actual ID column
of the country table.
All right, so let's go ahead
and insert data into our database.
So we'll insert some data into the country table.
So we'll insert data for Brazil, Canada, Germany,
India, Turkey, and the United States.
The values here are ID, code and name.
And you may wonder why only six countries,
as you know, there are more countries in the world.
Well, at the moment, these are the six countries
that our fictional company, Love to shop,
can actually ship products to.
Of course, we're just making this up,
but we're a small startup
and hopefully in the future,
our company will expand and we'll be able to ship
to more countries in the future.
Now this is just a little classroom example,
feel free to add more countries to the database.
It's totally up to you.
And we'll do a similar thing here for States.
So when you enter a state,
you're entering the States for a given country
and so the values here are the ID,
common name and the given country ID.
So at the top we have the country ID of one ,
that's for Brazil
and then down here at the bottom,
we have the country ID of four, that's for India.
And once we actually run a real SQL,
you'll see all the data and how everything maps out.
So you'll get access to all of these files.
Now, once everything is populated,
then we can actually do some queries on the data.
So I can do a select star from country,
get all the countries that are available
and then here I could say select star from state,
where country ID equals four.
And so that'll give me a list of all of the States
for India.
Now step two of developing the JPA Entities
for country and state.
So we have our country entity.
This is all fairly straightforward,
you've seen us before.
We define our fields here for ID code and name,
we set up the mappings for the appropriate database columns.
And then we also do a similar thing here for a state,
we make use of the fields and also the columns.
And then notice here at the bottom,
we have our advanced mapping relationships here,
one to many.
So one country has many States.
And then over on the right hand side for State,
many States belong to one country.
All right, so we have the one to many
and the many to one,
for this JPA entity mapping relationship.
And so now in step three,
we're going to create our Spring Data REST Repositories.
So here's our interface,
country repository extends JPA repository.
And remember here we give the actual entity class,
comma, the primary key type.
So here our entities country,
the primary key type is Integer.
And then we make use of this repository risk resource,
we customize it by saying path equals countries.
And so this will expose as slash country's end point
for this given Spring Data REST Repository.
And so now to retrieve all countries,
we'll simply go to local host 8080,
slash API slash countries
and that will give us a list of all the countries
for this given up.
And then also to retrieve country ID equal four,
we go to local host 8080
slash API slash countries, slash four.
All right, so let's look at the JSON output
for these REST APIs.
So here to retrieve all countries.
Then I'll see my JSON here at the bottom.
So for the countries, Brazil and Canada
And then to retrieve a country ID equals four,
then I can see the output here
and this'll give me the actual country for India.
And we'll run examples of this
when we actually get our API up and running.
Now let's do a similar thing here for States.
So we set up our interfaces,
state repository extends JPA repository,
state comma Integer.
This exposes as slash States end point.
And so then I can get a list of all the States
by going to API slash States.
But we'd probably want to kind of customize this a bit
because I don't want all the States,
I only want States for a given country.
So I want to find by country code.
So give me the States for a given country.
So here I have find by country code, Eparam code.
And then I'll pass in Eparam string code.
So this will give me the States
by the given country code that I pass in.
So here's an example.
Here I have slash search,
slash find by country code,
code equals IN that's for India.
And I can do a similar thing here for code equals US,
that's for the United States.
So this only gimme States for that specific country code.
And this will work out great for us in our user Interface
because once the user selects a given country
in the user Interface,
they want to populate drop-down lists
with the States for that given country code.
All right, so here's a quick example
as far as the JSON outputs.
Country code, code is equal IN for India,
then I'll get all the States for India.
A similar thing here,
code is equal US,
I get all the States for the US.
And again, we'll kind of pull this all together
once we get the backend up and running,
then we'll hook it into the front end
for our user Interface that's running in angular.
Then the last step here is
Updating the Spring Data REST Configs.
So we're going to update our coding
for my Data Rest config dot Java.
We're going to make the APIs for slash country and slash state,
make it read only because this is referenced data.
There's no real need to change it via the REST API.
So we'll simply disable the HTTP methods
for our PUT, POST, et cetera.
I want to get into the coding details
of this in the next video.
So it'll be easier for us
to just walk through the code in our IDE.
All right, this is good stuff.
Let's go ahead and move to the next video
and let's start writing some code.