Alrighty so now we can go ahead
and populate the purchase,
using the order and the orderItems.
Now we can get down to the real fun part.
So this is kind of
like the grand finale of calling the REST API
and we'll call it via the checkoutService.
So I'll call this checkoutService.placeOrder,
I'll pass in a purchase object that I just created
and populated with all that good data from the form,
do a .subscribe.
And now one thing I do slightly different here
is I'll add code for calling the REST API
and having the results coming back,
and also I'll set up error handling.
So this is something that's slightly new here.
So we'll have something for next,
and we'll also have an entry here for error.
So next is the success path.
Error is the error path.
Okay just think of next as the happy path,
error is the exception path or error path.
So for the happy path, they'll send back a response,
and now I can use that response and do something with it.
And so we know that that response
has our order tracking number,
so it's going to come back as JSON
and I can give the user a alert message,
and I'll make use of the back ticks.
So notice here I'm using back ticks
because I'll make use of a template string for the output.
So the order tracking number
and then the template string is the dollar sign curly brace,
that I can embed inside of this string,
that has the back ticks on it.
And I'll say response.orderTrackingNumber
so that's the information coming back in the JSON.
And that's from the Spring Boot code
that we created a little bit earlier.
All right so that'll give the user a little pop up,
with their tracking number.
And then also I'll just write
a little comment here to myself
I'll come back to this in a bit
but we want to reset the cart, but give me one second
I'll come back to that.
So if there is an error,
then I want to let the user know about the error.
So a similar approach here, I'll just say alert,
and I'll use the back ticks again
'cause that'll make use of the template string approach
just like we did up above.
So there was an error
and we'll make use of this error.message
so that JSON will have an error message
and we can display it using this code.
And in most online guides you'll see the curly brace
for this up on the previous line.
So I'll kind of clean that up
just so it'll follow what you see in normal online tutorials
and blogs and stuff, as far as coding style.
Once the user places their order
then we want to reset the cart and clear it out,
so we will define this new method here, reset cart
'cause it's not part of our app as of now
but now we have just created it.
I'll remove some of the Boilerplate code.
So we'll reset the cart data,
and we'll also reset the form data,
and finally we'll navigate back to the main products page.
So I simply set the cart items
to an empty array that basically clears it out.
I will make use of those subjects
for totalPrice and totalQuantity.
That next zero basically
send out zero to all subscribers there
so they kind of reset themselves
like the status component and so on.
Just go through and reset the form.
And again, once they've finished with their checkout
we'll send them back to the main page.
So that router, that's what we injected earlier
in our constructor,
we use that router to navigate a URL to /products.
Kind of just scrolling back to the top
so this is called an REST API
so this is kind of the real work here
for this checkout operation.