Okay so moving along with our development process
in step three we're going to create our data transfer objects.
So the first thing we need to do
is create a new package for dto.
And now in that new package we need
to go ahead and create a new class for purchase.
And so remember our purchase basically has a relationship
to our customer, shipping address, billing address,
order and collection of order items.
So we'll make use of the lombok annotation here for a data.
And then we'll add our fields here
for customer, shipping address, billing address,
order, and a collection for order items.
And so for our collection of order items
you will make use of a set.
And then for order make sure you import
the correct class and a luv2code.
And a similar thing here for address.
Alrighty, so that looks pretty good.
Now, one thing that you may notice is
that in the code we use a set for a collection
and in the diagrams a square bracket for array.
But here really it's just a collection
so think of a collection as a generic term.
When we actually pass this over the wire using a REST API
and JSON, JSON'll basically take those collections
and it'll make use of a JSON array, all right.
But we can easily go between the two,
JSON array to a set, a set to a JSON array,
that works with no problem.
And now what we'll do is we'll create a new
Java class PurchaseResponse.
And so we'll use this class to send back
a Java object as JSON.
And so I'll make use of the @ data annotation from lombok.
This class is very simple.
It will simply have the order tracking number
here as a string.
And that's it.
And so once we get into writing the service code
you'll see how we'll use this purchase response.
But for right now, we just have it set
up as a data transfer object for us.
So again, looks pretty good.
Good job.