Okay, so let's continue on
with our Product class here,
and so basically we need to add the JPA mappings here
between the actual fields and columns.
So first I'll set up the coding here for my id column.
And so this maps over to the database column id.
And I'll just copy this @Column annotation
and I'll just paste it X number of times
as I go through the list here.
And most of these are fairly straightforward,
except for the cases for unitPrice where it's unit_price.
And imageUrl is image_url, and so on.
And then we have two fields here for our timestamps.
So one for dateCreated, and also for lastUpdated.
And what I'll do is I'll add two annotations here,
@CreationTimestamp and @UpdateTimestamp.
These are special annotations.
Hibernate will automatically manage the timestamp
so there's no need for the developer
to manually call these methods or set these fields here.
Hibernate will do all of that work for you
in the background.
So stepping back,
our product class is pretty much taken care of
with our annotations accordingly.
All righty, so now let's go ahead
and create another new class for ProductCategory.
And we'll go through a similar process here
of setting up the Entity annotation
and also the Table annotation.
And then one little thing here with Lombok,
there's a known bug when using @Data,
whenever you make use of relationships
like OneToMany and ManyToOne.
So here instead of @Data
we'll make use of @Getter and @Setter.
These are Lombok annotations.
And that will generate those methods accordingly.
But this is just more of a workaround
with this modern framework here.
But don't worry, in the end,
you'll get the similar set of functionality.
You'll get the getters and setters
automatically generated for you by Lombok.
So we'll define our fields here
for id, category, and products.
And then I'll just add my JPA annotations here.
And then for the products, since this is a collection,
this is really a OneToMany.
So I set up the CascadeType to ALL
and it's mappedBy category.
And so over in my Product.java file
let me set up the other side
of the relationship, ManyToOne.
So a given product is associated with a category.
And I use the ManyToOne annotation,
and I specify the JoinColumn.
And the JoinColumn is category_id
and that's a field that's defined in this table.
All righty, so that looks pretty good
as far as our relationship here between the product
and the product category, OneToMany, ManyToOne,
using some of these advanced JPA relationships.
So this is great and I like to say good job!