So our app is up and running,
but one thing I like to do is
I'd like to modify this application,
modify the properties.
I want to try and break it on purpose.
Is it really using this localhost:4200?
What if I gave some bad information here?
Would it read that and apply CORS accordingly?
Huh, let's try it.
So let me just add some bad name here.
Just nowhere:4200.
I'm totally making this up.
You can give it anything
as long as it's not localhost.
And start up my spring boot app again in the background
so it can pick up those new properties.
Go to my angler application.
And now notice here in the angler application
there is no product categories,
and there's no products.
Hmm, interesting.
Let's go look at the actual debugger here.
So on the dev tools
and under console,
and then we can see that we have some errors here.
So it said,
find by category ID, from origin
has been blocked by CORS,
and from origin 4200.
So, it's not allowing anything from 4200
because it's not an allowed origin.
So you'd have to change that value back to local host.
So it is reading our properties information.
Run our spring boot application again.
And then if we go through application,
and everything will work out just fine.
On the back end
we really are reading the application properties
and reading the appropriate data.
So now we see it's back to localhost.
Everything is A-OK,
and we can access our data accordingly.
So our CORS configuration
is working on the back end.
I like that.
Alrighty, let's move ahead to step three
and configure the course mapping for the RestController.
And so remember the configuration for the RestControllers
are different
from the configurations for the Spring Data REST.
All right, so separate configuration shaft to set up here
but we can use some of those same configs.
So in our RestController
we have this CheckoutController,
notice at the top it's a RestController
and we have the @CrossOrigin.
What I'd like to do is use configurations for this.
And so for the CrossOrigin portion
I'd like to remove this or have this configured
via our application and not having to hard-code it
on each one of our RestControllers.
So let's go ahead and delete it here,
remove it from our controller, CheckoutController.
And we'll move into our config package
and we'll create a new configuration.
So creating a new Java class here,
I'll call it MyAppConfig.
And this implements the WebMvcConfigurer.
I'll just expand my window here for a second.
And what I'd like to do is access two of our properties
for allowed origins and also for the base path.
So here I'll set up string array the allowed origins,
and string base path.
And then I'll use my @Value annotation
to inject these property values accordingly.
At theAllowedOrigins.
And then I simply copy that,
paste it,
update the property reference here.
So spring data rest.base-path.
Cause we're using the same slash API
for our RestControllers
and for our spring data RestControllers.
If they were a different thing
you'd make use of different properties accordingly.
Now let's go ahead and overwrite a method.
And I'll overwrite this method, addCorsMapping.
And they'll give me the basic stub here
for this method, addCorsMapping.
So I'll just rename this parameter here to cors.
Just so it follows with the previous code
that we've created.
And I simply do a cors at addMapping.
I give the base path,
and then I do the .allowedOrigins.
And then I pass on our variable, theAllowedOrigins.
There's one more thing that we need to do for this class
and I almost forgot.
We actually need to add the @Configuration annotation
for this class.
This basically allows this given class to be picked up
during component scanning.
And this configuration will be applied accordingly.
So just be sure to add this @Configuration annotation
And then that's it.
So we have the setup in place here for our @RestControllers
for course mappings.
Good job.