Alrighty, so let's move in here.
So one update I'd like to make to the application,
is I'd like to display a list of products in an HTML table.
We have the basic functionality in place,
so let's go ahead and spruce it up a bit
and make it look pretty.
So, I'll swing over to my file system
and do a copy paste on our .html file.
So I copy the product-list-component.html.
And I simply paste it.
So here's the new version here.
Copy and I'll rename it and it give it a better name.
So we'll call it product-list-table.component
and I get rid of the copy stuff.
Alrighty, that looks good.
Let's go ahead and open up
our type script file, our ts file.
Let me zoom out here, for a bit.
And in our type script file, in our component,
We need to change the actual template
that we're going to use.
So in line seven, I'll just do a copy paste here.
I'll comment out our original version.
I'll update line seven
to say product-list-table.component.html
So let's go ahead an move into our
product-list-table.component.html.
We currently have the paragraph code here.
Let's just go ahead and move that to the bottom.
And then up top we'll add our table
and we'll borrow some of that code.
So I set up the table.
Then I set up my thead.
Then my table rows, with th's.
So for the actual headers here for these columns,
I'll have Name, Price and Units in Stock.
And then I'll some coding here for the table body.
So again table row.
And I'm going to just copy some of this ngFor stuff
and I'll put it here for the table row.
Cause this is all the same code, right?
We're just using a different layout thing.
And then I'll add some table data here.
I'll just grab the tempProduct.name.
Paste it up here.
And then I'll just copy paste line 13 x number of times.
And then drop in the price.
And I need to do one more td for the Unit's in Stock.
This is .unitsInStock.
Alright.
So that looks pretty good.
And I can get rid of all the paragraph stuff at the bottom.
Alright, so that's the basic layout for our table.
For looping over our products
and putting them in a nice table format.
Pretty good.
I'm going to swing over to my browser and boom!
Success!
This looks great.
So we have our table layout with our products.
Good job.
I want to make one small little modification
here on the thead.
Add some of those bootstrap styles.
Put in the thead-dark.
Swing back over and there we go.
Okay that looks great.
I like it.
So this is looking really good, so far.