Alrighty so we're making good progress,
in this video we will cover billing address.
So, just swinging back into
our checkout component at HTML.
All right, so let's just add a
little comment here for billing address.
And, for billing address we simply want to copy
everything that we did for shipping address,
so lets go ahead and move up there and,
copy that section starting at that form
group for shipping address and all the way
down to that last div.
Just do a little copy paste there.
And then here's our new version, yep billing address.
We simply change the form group name to billing address,
and billing address, great.
And so everything else should work out just fine for us.
Just swing back over to our browser,
and scroll to the top, customer, shipping and billing.
Good job I like it.
Now, one feature that you may have seen on
some e-commerce sites is that they will do a little
copy paste for you, so if your billing address is
the same thing as your shipping address,
they'll auto fill that, so will actually add a checkbox here
to provide that functionality.
So, will simply copy the shipping address
to the billing address.
So, will add our input type for our checkbox
and will add some event binding here,
so when the checkbox is checked or changed,
then will call this method,
copy shipping address to billing address,
and this is a method that will
define in our component.ts file,
and will pass over the event just to find out what
actually happened if it was checked or unchecked.
And, it will give us a little error message,
but for now don't worry about it will
address it in a second.
And then will just get a text here for our label
billing address same as shipping address.
And so, at least we can go over here and look and see
that okay yes we have our little checkbox here thing,
but it doesn't really do anything,
because we don't have the real coding in place,
but will fix that now.
So, the method here is the method that we need to
add to our component.ts file,
and the IDE even tells us this, that's cool so,
same thing right, just copy that method name,
and will add it to our component.ts.
So moving over to checkout component.ts.
I'll just scroll down and I'll just add this new method.
And they're going to pass in the event.
And then we can make use of that event
to find out what actually happened.
So, if the event target is checked,
that means that hey they actually checked something,
then we basically we want to copy data
from shipping to billing.
So here I basically get the check out from group dot
controls dot billing address,
and I'm going to set the value, so I'm going to set
billing to whatever shipping is.
And so I simply get a handle to shipping and there we go.
So this will basically copy the shipping address value
to billing address value.
And then else if it's not checked that means we simply
just want to reset it, so I'll just blank out,
or clear out the billing address if it's not checked.
So, I'll just grab the billing address here.
Then I say reset, so reset will actually clear out
all of the fields on the actual
billing address form group.
Alrighty, swing over here and lets test it out real quick.
Now, just add some items to my cart swing down, check out.
Just add some data here for my shipping address.
Now, move down here and check the box
here for billing address, and oh nice look it
copied it over there automatically,
so up top we have that, and to reset and it goes away,
and if I hit the check box again it's going to copy
stuff from shipping to billing okay great,
so nice little feature now that's in place,
and it looks really good, I like it.