All righty.
So let's go ahead and dive in here
and let's write the code here
for this computeCartTotals method.
So we'll just set up some variables here
for totalPriceValue and also totalQuantityValue.
And this is really simple.
I simply loop over the cartItems
and just add all these values together.
So for the totalPriceValue,
it's the currentCartItem.quantity
times currentCartItem.unitPrice.
And then a similar thing here for quantity.
And the next thing I need to do is publish the new values
for totalPrice and also totalQuantity.
And remember, all subscribers will receive the new data.
And so here I give totalPrice.next,
I pass in totalPriceValue,
and a similar thing here for totalQuantity.next
pass in totalQuantityValue.
And so this will publish the events to all subscribers.
One event for totalPrice,
one event for totalQuantity.
So this is the part here where the CartService
is actually publishing events.
And remember, the .next method will actually publish
or send the event.
All righty, and then one other thing I'll add here
is I'll just add a method for logging in a cart data
just for debugging purposes,
just so we can kind of keep track of things
as far as what's going on behind the scenes.
So I'll have this method here, logCartData,
I'll pass in the totalPriceValue
and the totalQuantityValue.
Just a little helper method
to help us out here in this class.
So again, this method here=,
we're just logging the contents of the cart.
I'll simply do a loop over the cartItems
and then just log information here.
So I simply log the name, the quantity,
the unitPrice, and also the subTotalPrice.
All right now kind of just scroll over
just so you can see everything.
This is a big long line here.
So name, quantity, unitPrice and subTotalPrice.
That's what we're logging right now.
All righty and so we'll also log the totalPrice
and totalQuantity.
So here I have the totalPriceValue.toFixed of two.
So only show two digits after the decimal.
And you can apply this for other price related items
here and the code as needed.
And then we give totalQuantity, the totalQuantityValue.
And then finally, I'll just give a little line separator
to make things pretty in the logs
when we view everything.
And that's pretty much it here
for this logCartData method.