All ready, so I'll go ahead and run my application,
I'll open up a terminal window,
and I'll run the app using ng serve.
Alright, so the app is up and running,
I'll swing into a browser
and test it out.
Okay, so we have our list of products.
Now let's scroll to the bottom
and see if we can see our pagination control.
And oh, yeah,
this looks pretty good.
Check it out.
So I'll zoom in here.
So our database has 25 books,
the page size is 10.
So we should have three pages of data,
10, 10, and five.
So, this is great.
And if you click on any one of these pages here,
it'll call that list products method
and it will list those products for that given page.
So I'll just move over to page two.
And then yep, so there we go 10 products
four, four, two
and then page three, five products four more.
Great.
So this looks pretty good.
So our pagination is working out
as desired.
But let's go ahead and look behind the scenes
and let's get a bit more info
as far as what's happening with our data
and also what data we have in our given database.
So I'll go ahead and open up my sequel workbench,
I want to run some queries here on my database.
So here we see that we have our products,
and then we do a count star.
This will tell us how many we have so
we have a total of 100 products.
And that's pretty good.
And now remember when we view the products by category,
so we have 25 books, 25 coffee mugs,
mouse pads and luggage tags.
So, 25 each.
That's why we saw just 25 in the previous example,
in the web app,
but we have a total of 100 products out there total.
So here to do a query just on books,
so where category ID equals one,
that's the ID for books.
And I could also just do a select star.
And just highlight that and execute that query only.
And so those are all of the books that we have
in this example.
Okay, good.
And I could do a similar thing for another category ID
of two.
Until that will give me all of the coffee mugs.
So we have 25 coffee mugs.
Then select count star for category ID two.
And that'll give me 25.
So, we have 25 per category
four categories, a total of 100.
Good job.
And so I can simply go through
and just check some of the other categories
and a similar thing here at the bottom with the pagination.
So this is pretty good.
I like how this is working out for us.
Now let's swing over into our IDE
and let's play around a bit
with the actual page size.
Right now we have page size equals 10,
but let's play around with the page size
and change it to five.
Just to verify that the pagination control is being
generated dynamically,
and it's using this information to generate those controls.
Alright, so I have page size equals five,
I save it reloaded,
go to books over here
and scroll down and excellent.
Good job. So notice here,
our pagination control,
so our database has 25 books
page size of five.
So we have five, five and five.
Excellent, excellent.
I love this.
And I can simply choose some of the links here at the bottom
to go through the different pages.
Okay, good job.
And so now I'll swing back
and I'll change the page size to 50.
Okay, I'm just having fun here.
We really only have 25 products per category,
but I'll change it to 50
just to see what happens in our application.
So swinging back into our app,
scrolling down to the bottom,
wow! A lot of products.
That's good.
And our database has 25 books
page size of 50.
So we have one page of data.
(laughs)
And, that's it,
just one page of data, all right,
same for all the other product categories.
Okay, so that's it.
So we had a good time of playing around with page sizes
and seeing how this would affect our pagination control.