Okay, so let's go ahead and update this file
to use the HTML template CSS styles.
So, this is kind of what we had before.
We had our ngFor, we did a loop over those products
and we would display information about the given product.
We'll do a similar thing, but we'll kind of do it
in the context of the actual CSS styles.
So I'll just go ahead and remove all of this information
from this given file and make this file empty.
So I'll go ahead
and use the HTML from the HTML template files.
I could simply just copy-paste it,
but for here, I like to just type it out myself.
All right, so this is just a collection
of CSS styles from our local style sheet
and also some bootstrapped styles
and then I'll add a little comment to myself
just to keep myself on track.
So, in the middle here, this is where I need
to loop over the collection of products
and do some work,
but just for sanity's sake, let me just add
a little string here, just so I can see some
of this on the actual page.
So, I have work to do.
I'll just save this and swing over
to the browser and see what I have, and,
okay, this looks pretty good.
So notice right here it says, "I have work to do."
So this is where that component will show up
on the actual page
and now I'll swing back into Visual Studio Code
and I'll start writing the code.
So, I'll just remove
that little place holder that we had
and then we'll make use of a div
and we'll make use of an ngFor
to loop over our collection of products.
All righty, so we have our ngFor set up for looping.
We'll set up a product box where we'll display information
about the image URL, the actual product name,
and some other details for the product.
All right, this looks good so far.
Let's just test this part out real quick,
the image and the product name.
Swing over to our browser, and, cool,
this looks pretty good.
All right, so we're seeing information being displayed
in a grid fashion, that's nice.
That's based on that bootstrap style
for the container fluid in different rows
and it will simply build and wrap accordingly,
and that's just great, I like it.
And then we'll kind of just do more
of the same here of adding information
about the actual price
and then we'll play
around with some add to car buttons and so on.
And so for our add to cart button, we'll
just set the href equals to just #,
we're not going to do anything with it yet.
We'll add that functionality in some of the later videos
but at least you'll want to have
the button being displayed here.
So that's the main portion here of our given product.
So, for each one of the products that we loop over,
we'll have a product box with that give information.
Now if we save this and swing back to our browser,
and, cool, looks great.
So we have our image place holder,
we have the actual product name, the price,
and a button, add to cart.
So this is starting shape up nicely.
I'm kind of getting excited.
I have a huge smile on my face
and we're making some really good progress
but we have a lot more things to do.
So stay tuned and we'll continue
to add more functionality to this application.
All right, I'll see ya in the next video.