Okay, so moving along
with our development process we're almost done here,
so the last step of creating the REST APIs
with Spring Data JPA Repositories and Spring Data REST.
Okay so let's go ahead and move over here on the side,
in our project structure here, our package structure,
clean up some of the windows,
and the first thing we'll do
is we'll create a new package called DAO.
And now we'll create a new Java interface,
so in IntelliJ you do a new Java class
and you select Interface
but it's going to be for a product repository.
So choose Interface,
and this is for a ProductRepository.
Let me expand the window here
and just kind of zoom in a bit.
And so we'll make use of that Spring Data JPA,
so we extend the JpaRepository,
and then we specify our entity type
and also our primary key type.
So the entity type is product,
and the primary key is long.
And this is all from our product that we just created
in the previous video.
And that's it for the coding for our repository.
Pretty easy, pretty fun.
Let's go ahead and create one more repository
for our product category repository.
So choose Interface, ProductCategoryRepository,
and then we'll follow the same technique as before.
So extends JpaRepository,
the entity is product category,
and the primary key is long.
And I'll add one bit of customization here
for this given repository.
I'll provide the name
for the collection resource relationship.
And also I'll specify the actual path
because I don't want to take the defaults.
The defaults don't work for me,
so I'll specify the given data.
So this will be the name
of the actual JSON entry, product category,
and this will be the actual reference
for the path product-category.
Normally they'll try and make things plural
by simply adding an "s" onto it,
and I don't want that.
I simply will use a simple reference here.
And that's it for creating our repositories.
So we have a product repository,
and also a product category repository.
So this looks really good.
All righty, so we finished our development process.
I'm excited now.
Let's go ahead and run it.
I want to see this thing in action.
Okay, great.
Our Spring Boot application is up and running.
Now we can swing over to our Web browser
and access one of the URLs.
So just for starters I'll access localhost:8080/api.
So this will give me a list of APIs
that are exposed for this given application.
So we can see that we have our product category API
and also a products API.
Let's go ahead and access the products API,
so we do /api/products.
And awesome, this looks great.
So we're getting a list of our products
and this is all coming from our database.
This is awesome, good job.
And so we can also access our product category.
So I'll simply update the URL to reference this
and great, really good.
So notice here we only have one
product category right now, books,
but they basically give us the information
for the various items that are out there.
And we can even see the products for this given category.
So we can select the link here,
and now this basically takes us over
to the previous products that we saw earlier.
So this is great.
So we know we have our REST API
that exposes the actual product categories
and also a list of products.
So I'd like to say good job.