In this video,
we'll add support for the credit card.
And so mainly just laying out the controls
for the credit card.
Alright, so moving into our checkout component at HTML,
let's add a little quick comment here
where we're going to place the credit card info.
So we'll drop it in this section here.
So I'll set up this form group name, credit card.
It's the same group name from our dot TS file.
And now I need to add some controls
in here for credit card.
So I just kind of grabbed some controls
from some of the previous work we did.
So I'll just move up to a billing address,
and I'll just grab everything from billing address down to,
let's see here down to street.
And I'll just copy those controls
and I'll moving to credit card and paste those controls.
Alright, so for our credit card,
we'll update this piece to credit card.
The drop down item here
will actually be the credit card type,
some say card type
and update the form control name, card type.
Again, this matches with the actual code
from our dot TS file.
And then for options, our store
will only support two credit cards.
So we'll support Visa and MasterCard.
We'll put that in there.
And then also, if you're worried about credit cards
and security and TLS SSL,
we'll cover those features in the future
So don't worry gotcha covered,
at the moment here we're just covering
form layout out, but we'll get to that good stuff.
So name on card,
and then form control name, name on card.
So let's just swing over here and okay,
the basics are in place.
So we have our card type, and then name on card.
All right, so this looks good so far.
So now it's just kind of more than same
for those other fields for this card.
So I just grabbed that row here for name on card,
and I'll just copy it.
And just paste it here.
So we have name on card up top,
this one is going to be card number.
And I update the form control name accordingly.
Then just do another paste.
So this will be for security code,
the low three digit code
that you have on the back of your card.
All right, that's good.
Alright, so lets just swing over
and just take a look at what we have in the browser.
All right, name, card number, security code.
Okay, cool, I like it.
Alright, so we have a couple of other things
we need to do here for expiration month and year.
So we'll just kind of grab that row for card type.
And just copy that and we'll use that
for our month and year.
So we just paste,
so we'll call this expiration month.
And then I'll just copy this one more time and paste it.
And then we'll have expiration year.
All right, so let's swing back into our browser
and check things out.
And just moving down to the bottom.
Okay, looks good, right?
Expiration month and year.
All right, I like it.