Okay so in this video we'll focus
on the implementation of the code
for the checkout service example,
in particular this place order method
so it feels like we were just doing a lot of setup stuff
now we actually kind of get down to doing some real coding.
So in this place order,
I know I'm going to do some JPA stuff,
so I'll make use of the @transactional annotation
and now I'll simply write some quick comments to myself,
just to kind of keep myself on track
so I'll just put a return null here,
just to kind of get rid of the red squiggly
but we'll update this in a second.
Alrighty so let's go ahead
and dive in here and let's write the code
to retrieve the order info
from the data transfer object purchase
then we'll generate the tracking number,
and this method generate Order Tracking Number
is not there yet we'll let the IDE generate it for us
or create it for us but give me just one second,
I just want to do order dab set Order Tracking Number
based on this value order Tracking Number,
alright good so I can complete my thought there
now let's go ahead and create this method,
generate Order Tracking Number.
So I basically want to create a unique ID
that's hard to guess and somewhat random,
so I don't want to use the database primary key
that's auto-incremented,
I want to do something slightly different,
so I'll generate a random UUID
so I'm making use of this UUID
but you're probably wondering,
what exactly is a UUID?
Alright no problem
Let's swing over for a second
and let's have a quick discussion about the UUID
and how we're going to use it in our application,
So recall that I want to have a tracking number
that is hard to guess random unique
So we'll make use of this UUID,
the universally unique identifier,
So it's a standardized method for generating unique IDs
It's available in four different versions,
and will make use of version four,
which will generate a random UUID number for us
now if you'd like to get more information on this
I highly recommend that you go
to the Wikipedia and see the entry for it,
so do a quick Google for Wikipedia UUID
or you can use the link that I provided
on the previous code example
but the Google approach is probably
the fastest and the easiest,
and that'll bring you to the Wikipedia page.
And so you may wonder well,
what about the uniqueness of the number
or collisions or duplicates alright,
so the probability of a collision is very low negligible
even in the Wikipedia entry they say
you may not even need to care about it.
Wikipedia has a specific section regarding this,
it's called collisions and here they put all the math
all the statistics and it kind of makes,
your brain melt a bit but the probability of a duplicate,
if you had 103 trillion version UUIDs is one in a billion
alright so a very very very low percentage,
And it has some other nice information
as far as generating every second for the next 85 years
they give you that part there so be sure to check that out,
however you say well one of the billion I can't have that
I need to have absolute 0% of collision,
okay so in that case you could do this instead
so you could generate a random new UUID,
and then you could query a database and see
if that UUID has been used by your application already,
If so so when you have a duplicate
then you simply repeat the previous two steps
until no duplicates are found right
so it's very easy to write the coding
error to check for that so you can go forward,
if you'd like to.