Okay, so we're almost done.
So in this video, we'll cover the last two steps,
steps four of disabling the PATCH method
and also step five of modifying the detection strategy.
Let's go ahead and open up this file, MyDataRESTConfig,
and let's move down here so we have the unsupported action,
so PUT, POST, DELETE.
So I'll just kind of move this down to another line,
so we have a method DELETE
and then I'll do a similar thing here for PATCH.
We are not allowing PATCH, so it's an unsupported action.
So it's in this array and everything else works out fine
because we use the same array
in the following lines of code.
So everything's in place just making this update
in one location.
So as a quick refresher here,
I'm going to put the slide back in just
to kind of jog our memories
cause we've been going for a bit, but in step five,
we need to modify the Spring Data REST detection strategy.
So by default, Spring Data REST
will expose the REST API APIs
for the Spring Data Repositories.
This works in general, but we may not want to expose all.
So in our case, the Customer Repository
we don't want to expose it as a REST API,
we only want to use it internally.
And this last bullet here is that,
currently the /api/customers is currently exposed
and we need to fix this, that's not good.
So let me show you this real quick in the web browser.
If our app is up and running on the back end,
then if we go to localhost:8080/api/customers,
then we actually see the customer data.
eeekkk, yikes, not good!
So let's go ahead and fix this ASAP in our application,
because we didn't want to expose this Spring Data Repository
as a REST endpoint.
So we can move down to our application.properties file
and we can configure the actual detection strategy
for Spring Data RESTs.
So I'll kind of zoom in here
and I'll set up this spring data risk detection strategy
equals annotated, so that's one of the strategies
that we learned about in one of our previous videos.
So now Spring Data REST will only expose a REST end point
if you have the app RepositoryRestResource annotation
and that's based on our configs.
Let's move in here to CountryRepository,
so this has the app repository REST resource,
that's good, so we're okay there, we want to expose that one.
CustomerRepository is not annotated,
hence it will not be exposed as a REST API
based on our configurations.
We have the ProductCategoryRepository,
that's annotated accordingly, that's good.
ProductRepository, oh, no annotation,
so we need to explicitly give the Repository
REST Resource Annotation.
And then over to the StateRepository,
here we have the appropriate annotation, this is AOK,
this looks good.
So now we can go ahead and run our application.
And then swinging back over to a web browser
and to a reload here in this API/customers,
and now we get a 404, so this is good.
So API customers is not exposed,
that's good for us,
we didn't want to expose that given REST end point.
Alright, good job.
And then also we can go through
and just test other parts of our application.
So here we have categories along the side, we have products,
so we know that all of the configurations there,
everything else is still working out just fine as far
as exposing our desired REST end points.
Okay, so this is a good little exercise here,
going back and refactoring some of our code,
cleaning up some of our code,
and so now we're in really good shape.
So I'd like to say good job, my friend.