Alrighty, so moving ahead
with our development process.
In this video we're going to focus on step 6.
Alrighty, so step 6 in our SalesPersonListComponent
we're going to create some sample data.
Okay, so let's go ahead and open up the file
sales-person-list-component.ts.
And then let me expand the window here for a second.
And now basically what I'll do in this file
is that I'll create an array of objects.
I'll create an array of those SalesPerson objects.
So I'll define this property here, salesPersonList.
It's going to be an array of SalesPerson objects.
Take care of the quick fix here to import that SalesPerson.
And so inside of this array,
I'll just create x number SalesPerson objects.
So I'll start off, I'll create one for Anup Kumar.
Then I'll do a similar thing here for John Doe.
Claire Murphy.
And Mai Truong.
Alrighty, so that looks pretty good.
So that's my array of objects, my SalesPerson objects.