Alrighty and so one thing I like to do
is add support for images for our given products.
So if you may have noticed in our database,
if you looked at the products table.
And there's an entry here called image URL
and it has assets, image products,
and right now each one of these products
simply have a placeholder file that it references.
We could always update that later.
But for now we'll just go ahead
and use this placeholder file
and see how this would work out.
So right now, that's simply the name
or the location of the file.
We actually need to add this to our given project.
So in your angular projects under your source directory
there's an assets directory
and so this is a special directory
where you can place your web assets
like images, JavaScript, CSS, PDFs, whatever.
You can also add sub-directories here with any name
and these items will be served up by the given application.
So what I'll do is I'll actually place
our placeholder images here in this assets sub-directory.
So in our file system we actually have some starter files
that you can make use of.
So if you'll look
in the e-commerce project 01-starter-files
there's a directory here called angular-image-assets.
So inside of here there's an images sub-directory
that has products, placeholder.png.
So we'll actually copy that images folder
into our given project.
And I'll show you a nice little technique here,
you can simply drag and drop the images folder
to the assets folder in your angular project.
And there we go, so we have this placeholder.png.
So now we can reference this
in our given angular application.
So let's add a new column here for our image
and it won't have a name or anything.
We'll just give a little empty TD here.
Just so we have a column.
And then what I'll do in the actual TD section,
I'll use the tempProduct.imageurl
and I make use of the image source equals
and I give a reference to that image URL.
And image source is standard HTML work right?
So here we have tempProduct.imageUrl.
And that's pretty much it for that item there.
And so again it's going to serve it out of that
assets/images/products placeholder.png.
So swing over to our browser, and okay, great.
This looks good.
The images are kind of big (laughs)
but at least they're being displayed, and again,
these are just placeholder images.
We could always replace them with real images if we'd like.
But let me go ahead and change some of the sizing here.
So I'll just change the height.
And I'll simply change the height to 50.
And save, and swing back and okay great, this looks good.
So these little thumbnails
basically now of the product images.
And we could always play around with other stuff
but at least we have the basics in place here.
So we have our app kind of up and running
with making use of images.
And one thing here I'll go through
and add some alignment here.
So class equals align middle,
just so everything kind of lines up properly in the table.
And I'll apply this to each one of the elements here.
A little copy paste exercise.
And then swing back over.
And then we'll see how the text is aligned in the middle,
vertically, for this given item.
So this looks great, so our table's in place.
It looks good and we've just added some image support.
So I'd like to say good job my friend.
Yoohoo!