All righty, so we're almost done.
So our final step here is step six
of enhancing our application with product images.
All righty so we currently have those placeholder images.
We want to replace those with some nice, pretty images.
And one item here, be sure to stop your app
since we're adding new images to the assets directory.
And we're going to run a database script
that has new product information.
So go ahead and start up MySQL Workbench.
And then let's go ahead and open up that script.
And this is in that starter-files
for ecommerce-project-release-2.0.
It's in the db-scripts directory,
refresh-database-with-100-products.
So this inserts our different categories
and also products for those different categories,
books, mouse pads, coffee mugs, luggage tags.
Let's go ahead and run that script.
Just do a refresh over here on the side.
And then just do a query on our product table.
And there we go,
so this is all the new information here.
So we have 100 products here.
And then, also, here's the path to the product image.
So assets/images/products,
slash whatever the given product name is.
So then, swinging back to Visual Studio Code,
we need to put these images
in assets/images/products.
Right now, we simply have placeholder.
We want to have some real product images here.
So we can get those from the starter files.
So there's a directory here
called product-image-assets products.
Copy those folders for books, mugs,
mousepads, and luggagetags into our given Angular project.
Your directory structure should look
like the one I have here on the screen.
All right, let's go ahead and start our application.
Just swing back into our browser,
just do a reload over here,
and, oh yeah, this looks great!
So notice here, we have new images for our books,
and they're all unique, and they're all different.
No more placeholder stuff, okay?
But now, Coffee Mugs, Mouse Pads, and Luggage Tags,
those aren't really working,
'cause we haven't implemented the functionality
for those links.
We will do that soon in some upcoming videos.
But at least we're getting so product data right now.
I'm really happy about this.
This is starting to shape up nicely.
Now, by default, Spring Data REST only returns
the first page of 20 items.
So even though we have 100 products in our database,
it's only returning the first 20.
Now, we can do a little quick workaround here
to modify this to tell Spring Data REST to,
"Hey, return X number of items for us."
And we can do that by modifying
our product.service.ts file,
and this is just a quick little short-term thing.
We'll get into pagination later.
But for right now, let's go ahead
and make a quick mod, product.service.ts,
and we'll simply make a small change here
on the base URL.
So by default, the size is 20.
Here we'll say size equals 100.
So we're simply changing the page size to 100 items.
And so this automatically refreshes here
on the Angular side,
and then the pages are refreshed,
and if we start to scroll down a bit,
then we see, oh, more products.
There's some coffee mugs.
Looks good, looks good.
And there's some mouse pads, good.
And there are some luggage tags.
This is great, so 100 products,
so 25 products per category.
That's what we have in our database.
So this looks really good so far.
I like it.
And I'll just swing back into Vis Code,
and I'll remove that modification.
Right now, I'll go ahead and keep the defaults.
We'll actually get into pagination
in some of the upcoming videos,
and so I wanted to kind of take that out
just so we can follow the appropriate approach.
But, anyway, this looks great.
So we kind of went through our whole development process,
we integrated our online shop,
we have icons, we have logos,
we have images, and this looks really, really good.
So I'm excited, doing my happy dance.
I'd like to say good job, my friend.