In this video we'll add a new feature
to our pagination, will allow the user
to select a page size.
Now in the previous video we did some testing
with different page sizes, and we'd modify our source code
to show different page sizes.
But as we went through the process,
I think you were probably wondering, hmm, we should allow
the user to choose the page size,
and allow them to simply select that page size
from a drop-down list.
And so we'll do the exact thing here in this video.
All right, so here's the development process.
So the first thing that we'll do is we'll add
a drop-down list for the page size to the HTML template,
and then we'll update our ProductListComponent
for setting the page size.
Alrighty, step one of adding the drop-down list
for page size to the HTML template.
So here in our component.html we'll simply make use
of a select tag and then we'll have the drop-down options
of five, 10, 20, and 50.
We'll initially display five as the selected one for true.
And then we'll add an event binding for the on change event.
So basically, when the user selects a page,
then we're going to call a method, updatePageSize.
And this method is defined in the component.ts file.
So we'll pass in the value that is selected by the user,
and that's the value of five, 10 , 20, or 50,
depending on whatever they select.
Now in step two we're going to update the ProductListComponent
for setting the page size.
So remember in the previous slide we had a call to a method,
updatePageSize, so this method is actually defined
here in this component.
So this method will take in a parameter, the page size,
and then we'll simply set the page size based
on that parameter value.
Then we'll also reset the page number to one,
and then we simply call listProducts
to list the products again for this given page size.
Alrighty so that's it with our development process,
very simple, very straightforward.
Now let's go ahead and dive into our IDE
and let's write this code.
Okay, so step one of adding the drop-down list for page size
to the HTMl template.
So let's get a quick visual here as far as what we want to do.
So currently we have our app running.
We have pagination in the bottom right,
but we'd like to add a drop-down list for this application.
And we want to add the list right here.
And so the user can go through, select one of these items
for the page size
and then we'll update everything dynamically, on the fly.
Okay so let's go ahead and move into Visual Studio Code,
and let's open up product-list-grid.component.html.
Let me expand my window here, stretch out a bit
so I have some room to work with.
I'll add the drop down list right here
after this div section.
Alrighty, so I'll set up a div.
And give a span here for the text page size,
that's what you'll see on the screen.
And now I'll set up the drop-down list
using the HTML select tag.
So I get the option with the value of five,
and I set selected to true, so that's the item
that'll be selected by default.
And then I give the other entries here for 10, 20, 50.
And that's pretty much it.
This looks good so far.