With our development process,
in this video, we're going to cover step one
of modifying the CartDetailsComponent HTML template
and adding the increment button.
So let's move in here,
and let's open up our cart-details.component.html.
I'll move to the top of the file as a checkpoint
just to get our bearings,
and let's move down to the section near quantity
because we're going to add some new code in this section.
One thing I'll do here is focus in
on the quantity item right now.
I'll set up a div.
I'll apply the appropriate styles here for this div.
I'll create a div here for the increment button.
Then I'll add the code here for the button.
Let me slide over here for a second.
Then I'll add that font awesome icon,
the font awesome plus icon.
Good, so this is the code in place
for giving us the increment button.
And let's set up a div here for the actual quantity.
I'll reference tempCartItem.quantity.
I also want to add the decrement button,
so let me just go ahead and copy the code I have
for the increment button or for plus,
and let's just copy that
and paste it down here at the bottom.
Instead of the fa-plus, I'll say fa-minus.
So just a very small change here
to get the minus or the decrement button.
Then I'll simply add a div here as a spacer
just so things can line up properly
as far as the layout in the actual table row.
So just think of this as a extra spacer here
to tighten things up.
This looks good.
Let's go ahead and test it.
So I'll open up a new terminal window,
and before I start my Angular app,
I just want to do a quick checkpoint here.
Make sure the Spring Boot app is up and running.
If it's not running, go ahead and start it now.
Now I'll go ahead and start up my Angular app.
Then we can swing over into my browser.
I can add some items to my cart
and then view my cart and success.
This is great.
Now notice here we have our increment button
and our decrement button along with our quantity,
so good job.
Now these buttons don't do anything yet, right? (laughs)
Because we haven't added any event handlers
or click handlers on it.
We'll do that in the next video,
but at least we have the layout in place
for the given buttons.