All right, so in this video,
we're going to move ahead and cover step three
of creating our spring data rest repositories.
Okay, so let's swing over to our project here,
and let's move to our DAO package,
that's where we create our repositories
and I'll simply create a new repository,
so I'll say new Java class,
and now I choose interface,
make sure you choose interface here,
even though it says new Java class,
be sure to choose interface
and the name of our interfaces, country repository.
And so there we go
I have a basic shell there for this interface,
expand this window
and now I can go ahead and get down and dirty
and start writing some code here.
So I say extends JPA repository,
and I give country comma integer.
And so remember here country's the entity class
and integers the type of the primary key.
And this is basically our spring data JPA
along with some spring data rest
that we're going to add on here.
So we set up our cross origin annotation.
And we also set up our repository rest resource annotation
for spring data rest,
and we do some small customization here
as far as the actual output and the path,
so here I have path equals countries,
and so by using path equals countries,
and I'll expose the endpoint slash countries.
So let's go ahead and
run this real quick and test it out.
So my Boot app is up and running,
I can swing over to my browser,
and so I can go to localhost 8080 slash API slash countries.
And it'll give me a list of all the countries
from our database, which is good.
So there's Brazil,
and then I have Canada, and so on.
But one thing that you may have noticed
is that we also have states
and we only want countries.
We don't want the states at this moment,
we'll retrieve the states later.
So we need to kind of modify our application
to only retrieve the countries,
not the actual associated states for a given country.
So I can swing back into my IDE,
and I can make one small modification here,
and I can make a modification in my entity class.
So I'll move up to country dot Java.
And what I'll do is
I'll make use of a special Jackson annotation
called @JsonIgnore.
This will ignore the given field
as far as providing a JSON data.
So here, this will actually ignore the states
when it makes the return on the actual data.
So @JsonIgnore, it'll ignore the state
so it'll simply give me the countries
without the actual associated states
and this is a Jackson annotation.
So that's the one little mode here
that we had to make to our given entity
to only give us the countries.
All right, so let's go ahead and run this app one more time
and test it out.
Just go over here and refresh my browser
and success.
So we're only retrieving the countries,
not the actual states.
So I have Brazil, Canada, Germany, India, and so on.
So this looks really good.
I like it.