All right, so we're almost done.
So we're at our final step of our development process,
step number 7.
So in step 7, we basically need to build
the HTML table using this data.
So the one thing I'll do is go ahead
and start up my server so I can kind of monitor my progress
as I'm going through with this development.
And I can swing to my browser real quick.
Right now it says sales person works
but that's the default stuff that was generated.
I need to add my own special information here.
So I'll move back into the IDE
and I'll actually open up this file
sales-person-list-component.html.
And so that's what we saw in the previous screen.
I'll make some updates here in this page.
So I'll do just a quick test.
And what I'll do is I'll actually just print out information
for that first array element, just as a really quick test.
So I'll say SalesPersonList[0].firstName.
So again, we're accessing the property from that component
and then I'll do a copy/paste on this
and I'll also do a similar thing here for last name.
So that first person that's in our array
I'll do display their first name and their last name.
So let me save this and let me swing back over to my browser
and let's see what we have here.
And oh wow, this looks great, Anup Kumar.
Okay, zoom in a bit.
So that's Anup Kumar, so that's the first person
in our array that we created.
So all right, the basics is working out pretty good.
And let's just verify this in our, yep, SalesPerson array,
yep Anup Kumar, cool.
All right, so I really can access that property,
I can access that array in my page.
All right, I feel good now.
So here I simply need to go through and do my HTML work
or my HTML table work.
So let me just get rid of all this stuff
and let's go ahead and setup our HTML table.
I'll setup the head section here
and I'll define the columns for first name,
last name, email and sales volume.
And I'll kind of do a copy/paste here,
first name, paste it x number of times
and just update the column names.
Alrighty, so those column names or headers are in place.
That's pretty good.
I can actually swing over to my browser real quick
and do a quick peak to kind of see where I'm at.
And okay cool, there's our table.
No data, but at least we have the headers in place
which is fine.
Now let's go ahead and add our body.
So let's go ahead and setup our tr
and then we'll make use of that *ngFor
and here I'll let tempSalesPerson of salesPersonList
and the salesPersonList matches with the property name
that's defined in this component.
And then I'll setup table data.
I'll give tempSalesPerson.firstName.
And then I'll save this and again
let me kind of do a quick peak over at my browser
just to see where I'm at.
And this is great, so I'm getting the first name
of each one of those sales persons.
I still have more work to do
but at least I know that I'm actually looping
through the array and accessing the data.
So now, everything else is just more of the same.
So I simply grab that line and just copy/paste it
and then simply do an update.
Save that and now when I swing back over,
oh yeah, success!
So now I'm looping through that array,
getting information about each sales person
and using that to populate the given table.
Alrighty, I'm pretty excited about this.
So we went through the full development process.
We created our own custom Angular component
and then we were able to populate our template
with data from that component and create an HTML table.
This is awesome, good job.