Okay so we have our drop-down list
on our HTML template page.
Let's just do a quick test here
and just view it in the browser
just to see what it looks like,
as far as the placement and location.
Okay, great.
So this looks really good.
So here's our new drop-down list.
It looks great.
But it doesn't do much right now.
It's just a pretty face, it doesn't really do anything.
Because we haven't added any logic
or event handling to it right now.
So this was mainly just for placing it on the page.
But now we have a bit more work to do.
So let's go ahead and do that now.
Okay so now select tag we need to handle
for the change event.
And then call a given method and pass in a value.
Alrighty.
So event binding.
So for the change event, so when the user selects a page,
then we'll call a method, updatePageSize.
And then we pass in the value that is selected by the user.
And remember that's five, 10, 20, or 50,
based on the options from the drop-down list.
And then also the updatePageSize method
is actually defined in the component .ts file.
Alrighty so now in step two,
we need to update our ProductListComponent
for setting the page size.
So let me grab that method name here, updatePageSize,
and just copy it.
And then move over to my ProductListComponent.ts file,
and I'll add this method.
So I'll just move down here and paste that method name,
updatePageSize, it's going to pass in a parameter,
which is a number.
And so remember the link there from our HTML template
to the actual component here.
So updatePageSize, they'll pass in
the actual page size that the user selected.
So here we simply make an assignment.
So I give this.thePageSize equals pageSize,
the parameter being passed in.
And then here I simply reset the page number to one.
Because they've changed their page sizes,
I want to reset it to one.
And then also I called this.listProducts
just to kind of refresh the page view
based on this new information we have for page size,
and page number, and so on.
Alright so that's the code for updating the page size.
And I'll just move up top here
and I'll just set the page size to five
because in our HTML template,
we had the default selected value of five.
So just so it matches up with everything
that we have on our front end.
So just make that one update here.
Alright so we're back in our application,
everything is up and running.
So the default page size is five.
So we see five items here.
And then for the navigation items,
there's five different pages.
So this is a success.
Our page size of five is working!
But let's test it and now choose a different size.
So page size of 10.
Okay great.
So 10 and then we have a total of three pages.
So that works out also.
And then we can play around with some of
the other page sizes here for 20.
We'll scroll down a bit.
That looks good.
And finally page size of 50.
And that looks good.
One page only.
So this looks good.
Our user has the option now to choose their own page size,
and our application will update accordingly,
in terms of pagination.
Alrighty, good job!