Alright so on this video we're going to
cover the step of adding a click handler
for the increment button on the HTML template.
And then also we'll update the cart details component
with the click handler method.
Alright, so let's move in here
into our cart details component dot HTML,
and let's move up to the section
where we have our increment button, the FA plus.
And so on this button here
we're going to add a click handler.
So we'll call the method increment quantity
and we'll pass in the temp cart item.
And of course, the IDE is going to
give us the error message saying,
hey, this method is not defined.
Okay No worries, We'll cover this in step two
of updating our cart details component
with that click handler method.
So I'll just swing over to my cart details component dot ts.
And I'll move down to the bottom of the class
and I'll add the method increment quantity,
That going to pass in a cart item.
And then we simply use this dot cart service dot add to cart
and we pass in the cart item.
Alright this looks pretty good, Let's test it out.
Alright, so it's move in here
and let's add an item to our cart.
So add the coffee mug for cherokee,
go check our cart details,
and looks good,
increment, quantity, Great Love it, Love it.
So it's increment and quantity
for this given cart item.
Great, awesome.
And let's add another item to our cart,
mousepad.
And also do the increment here,
great so this all works as desired,
so our increment button is up and running.