Good, so that was a nice little discussion
about UUID.
Java has a built-in class called UUID.
Create this random UUID
and we get a string version of it
and we can make use of it.
So that's how that piece works out.
So let's move back into our coding here for place order.
Now we'll go through
and we'll populate the order
with the order items.
So I get the order items from
the purchase DTO.
And then do an order items dot for each.
So I'm basically going to loop over
each one of those order items,
and I will add that to the order.
So, really nice coding here.
So I'm making use of Lambdas
and as for each operator
to loop through all of those order items
from that collection
and add them to the order, pretty cool.
Then next we'll simply go through
and populate the order with the billing address
and the shipping address.
Populate the customer with the order.
Then we'll go through
and we'll save it to the database
using our JPA repository
for our customer repository.
And finally we'll return a response
and so we'll make use of that purchase response
and we'll pass in the order tracking number
that we generated.
So do the new purchase response order tracking number.
Okay, well actually not okay.
What's the red stuff.
Let's take a look here.
So new purchase response order tracking expected
zero arguments found one
but we're using Lombok
so it should have the constructor force automatically
since we're using @Data.
Okay.
There, that is order tracking number there.
Okay. I spelled it right.
Okay. That that's fine.
So the spelling is fine.
It's something about that purchase response class
and something about my Lombok,
so let me just go ahead and look at the coding here
for this purchase response
and I'm using @Data.
Oh, okay.
They'll give me a constructor, but I need
they'll only do it for final fields.
Got it.
So I need to say final for that.
Another option is that we could use the @Nonnull annotation
on the field instead of final.
So you can pick either way
but if we wanted to do NonNull just say @NonNull
and private string or the tracking number.
So either way it worked there,
the @Data does a lot of the work for you
as far as creating all the getters
and setters two strings constructors and so on.
And it'll also create the constructors
but you have to make sure that these are for final fields
or they have a number of different rules on that.
If you'd like to get more information
on all these magical Lombok annotations
simply go to the Lombok website
they do a really good job of discussing
what the various annotations are
and also the different scenarios
on when they'll generate the appropriate code.
All right.
So we've kind of resolved that and finished that part of it.
So now if I swing back to my service
then we should be okay on that return statement.
Yep. We're A-OK good job.
All right.
So this looks pretty good.
So we have the coding here for our place order method
in place for saving it to the database.