Okay so we're moving right along here
so in this video we'll cover steps four and five
installing the Okta SDK dependencies
and also integrating the Okta Sign-In Widget.
So let's go ahead
and open up a new terminal window
and then here's the command here
for installing the Okta Sign-In Widget
and now simply do an npm install for the Okta angular SDK
and then finally
I'll just run this npm audit fix
to try and fix some of the vulnerabilities
I mean it's not always successful
but I'll try and fix some of them
but that's just something
that's really beyond our control
it's up to the package maintainers.
But anyway I'll just do the npm audit fix
you'll have different results
than what you see here on my screen.
So anyway we have those dependencies installed
so we're in good shape for that.
And now what I'd like to
just kind of poke around
into the node modules
to see the Okta information that was installed.
So under node modules/Okta
and we'll see here
we have this Okta Sign-In Widget.
We can look in the disk section and the CSS
and we can see here that they have a min CSS.
So this is great
So we'll let you use this CSS
and this upcoming section here.
So what we'll do is we'll add support
for the Okta CSS and our angular.jsonfiles
so this is part of the step five
of integrating the Okta Sign-In Widget.
So I'll move down to this anglular.json
and I'll give a reference
to the CSS for the Okta Sign-In Widget.
So I moved down here to the styles section
where we have the other CSS references here.
And now let's add one more reference here
so styles and then I'll do this node modules
that same path we saw a little earlier here
okta/okta-signin-widget/disc/css
and give her the reference here to that CSS file name
and so be sure you get this correct
exactly like I have here
just so we can find the appropriate styles
for the opt to Sign-In Widget.
You can always go through
and poke through the note modules again just to make sure
that you're on the right track with the reference
and the location there for that main CSS file.
Let me just kind of size this up a bit
so you can see everything on one screen.
Okay, all right there we go great.
So you can kind of just eyeball it
make sure you have the correct path here
for your reference here for that CSS.
All ready this looks pretty good
I like it.