Alrighty, so we're moving right along here.
So in step three, we're going to update the HTML template
to display the error messages.
We've done a lot of this work before,
so we'll do some copy paste here and reuse some code
that we've created earlier.
This is for our shipping address,
so I'll just move down a bit here
to the shipping address section.
There we go, shipping address, awesome.
So, we know we need to add some validation rules
here for this first field, country.
So, let's go ahead and scroll up to last name
and just copy the div here for displaying
validation messages.
I'll just copy this information and I'll move back down
to my shipping address section,
and I'll add this right after the select for country.
So, right inside of this div, after the select,
that drop down list, and I'll just paste it in.
Now I need to simply go through and update the reference,
so instead of last name invalid,
we need to say shippingAddressCountry.invalid.
And then a similar thing here for dirty,
shippingAddressCountry, shippingAddressCountry.touched.
And then also inside here for our last name errors
that should be shippingAddressCountry.errors.
Since this is a dropdown list,
there's no need to worry about no white space,
I'll just clean up some other stuff here at the bottom.
So, shippingAddressCountry,
and also, update the message, Country is required.
All right, let's do a quick checkpoint here on the code,
so, make sure you have a shippingAddressCountry
for invalid, .dirty, .touched and also for the errors.
Make sure you have all that updated accordingly.
All right, so let's go ahead and test this out real quick,
I'll open up a new terminal window,
move into my directory here.
And again, before I run, make sure my Spring Boot app
is up and running, so it's up, that's good.
So now I can go ahead and run my Angular application.
Just move in here and add some items to the cart,
go to the checkout page.
So, here's my shipping address section,
let's check for validation, we added some validation
on the country fields, so hit purchase,
go right to the top, and success, nice, great.
So, they're actually checking to see
if something is selected
and if not, they'll tell us that something's required
and the message goes away accordingly.
So, this is great, I like it, good job.