And one thing I'd like to do,
is make an enhancement.
So at checkout time, I want to pre-populate
the user's email address in the form.
Remember we already have this data saved
in the sessionStorage from the login.
I'll go ahead and grab that and then use it on the form
because we want to keep track of the same email address
because that's how we use it to track the orders
on the back end.
All right, so, an easy way to help things out here
is they'll simply pre-populate that information
for the user during checkout.
And just taking a quick look at our application,
so if we have some items in our shopping cart,
and if we go and do a checkout right now,
user has to enter the same email address
that they're logged in as
but that's kind of error prone, right?
They may not enter the same value.
So let's just go ahead and pre-populate this for them.
So lets go ahead and move into our checkout component.
And I'll open up our checkout.component.ts.
And I'll move down here,
and I add a reference here to the browser session storage.
And then we'll move down to this ngOnInit method,
and we'll actually read the user's email address
from browser's storage.
So we've seen a lot of this coding
before JSON parse to this.storage.getItem,
we give the key of user email
and we simply assign it.
And then when we move down here
and set up our form of control,
our initial value was an empty string.
Now let's use that assignment
that we have the email.
So instead of an empty string,
now we'll actually have whatever value
they have for that user's email.
And that'll be the initial value
that we'll see there on the form.
All right, so I'll go ahead and say this
and let's swing back over and test our application.
Just go back to the checkout form,
and success.
So now the email address is pre-populated on the form.
That's the same email that the user logged in as.
So this looks really good.
I'd like to say good job, my friend.