Alrighty, so let's go ahead
and continue the process here
and now we simply need
to create a Spring Data rest repository
for our state's entity.
So in our DAO package I'll create this new Java class
or we select interface again and
so here we give the name of StateRepository.
Alrighty, so here is our StateRepository.
A similar thing as before,
we say extends JpaRepository
and we give state comma integer
and so for the imports here make sure you import
the correct state from our entity package.
Okay, so this looks great.
So we have our entity class and also our primary key.
And we'll just repeat the process here
of setting up our annotations here
for this given repository
and also remember we're going to create a special finder method
here or query method for finding states by the country code.
So they'll pass in a param code.
That'll be a string param.
So this will allow us to get
the states for a specific country code.
So not all the states only the states for a given country.
For example, code equals IN for India.
And remember this is very useful for our user interface,
where the user will select a country first
and they want to populate the states based
on the user's selected country.
So that's why we have this method in place.
Alrighty, so that's the coding for that.
We're in really good shape.
Let's go ahead and run it and test it out
and then I'll open up a new tab here
and I'll visit localhost:8080/API/states
and here's our data
and it's all looks pretty good.
But this is for all the states.
Let's retrieve states for a given country code.
So I'll do a slash search find
by country code code equals IN
and so this will give me all of the states for India.
I can do a similar thing here for US
and also, I can do a similar thing for Turkey code of TR.
Alrighty, so this is great.
So we have our REST API for retrieving countries
and we also added that query method
for finding by country code so we can get
the states for a specific country code.
So I like it.
This looks really good.