I want to show you two more features
of this pagination component.
This is something just really quick.
I want to show you how to setup the max size for pagination,
and also how to setup boundary links.
So just a really quick video to show you
how these parameters work.
So we have pagination up and working.
And the user can change their page size.
I'd like to make one small change here.
I like to move into my code and add a new page size.
So I'll add a new page size for two.
So this way we can see two products per page.
Then I'll save this and swing back into my application.
And then I move over here, and I choose the page size of two
and ooh, yuck, okay.
We have too many pages, all right.
We'd like to show only a max number of pages.
But right now it's running off the screen.
And imagine if we had a million products right?
Two products per page, this just would not work.
So somehow we need to try and manage this or limit this.
And we can do this by setting a new parameter here
on this NGB pagination component.
I can make use of this new parameter here called max size.
So this will always show a max number of pages,
and I'll set the max size equals to five.
You can actually get more details on this parameter here
at the link shown on the screen.
But we'll see it in action here as far as how it works.
So basically this will show a max number of pages.
So I'll save this and swing back into my application.
I choose the page size of two.
And now notice here, it shows a max of five pages.
Then it does the dot, dot, dot.
And it'll give you the last or first page or whatever.
But the key here is that it's limiting the number of pages.
So even if you had a million products,
it wouldn't show all of those, just that one given max.
And again, you can look at the docs online
to get more details of it.
But this is fairly straightforward here,
as far as how to work this in.
I encourage you to experiment with it on your own.
Alrighty, so one other thing I want to do
is show boundary links.
So boundary links is the little angle bracket,
angle bracket of front and the back.
Basically allows you to jump to the beginning
or the end page quickly and easily,
as opposed to having to scroll through every page.
So I set boundary links equals to true.
Save it, swing back into my application.
And now notice here, we have these boundary links
at the beginning and at the end.
So now I can simply select those boundary links
and it'll take me directly to the front page,
or it'll take me to the last page or the end page.
Basically, the boundary.
Alrighty, so that was it.
We just played around with some of those parameters there.
Again, all the documentation is online.
So you can go there and review some of the other parameters,
and you can experiment with them,
and add 'em to your application.
Alrighty, good job.