In this video,
we'll cover shopping cart decrement and remove item.
So we have our shopping cart details,
so we'll have the button here to decrement,
and also a button here to remove.
Here's our development process.
In the first step, we'll add the click handler
for the decrement button on the HTML template,
then we'll update the CartDetailsComponent
with the click handler method,
then we'll modify the CartService
with the supporting method,
and then finally, we'll repeat the process
for the Remove button.
Okay, step one of modifying
the CartDetailsComponent HTML template.
So we have our quantity section,
we have this FA minus button.
We saw some of the coding for that in the previous video.
Now we'll simply add some event handlers for it.
And for the on click event,
we'll call the method decrementQuantity,
and we'll pass in that tempCartItem.
Okay step two of updating the CartDetailsComponent
with the click handler method.
So here's our method decrementQuantity,
they pass in the CartItem, and then we'll make a call
to this.cartService.decrementQuantity,
and we pass in theCartItem.
So in step three, we need to modify our CartService
with a supporting method.
So in our cart.service.ts, we had this method
decrementQuantity, and then we simply just decrement it
by using minus minus, and then we check the quantity
to see if it's zero.
If it's zero, then we'll actually want to remove it
from the cart.
Else we simply called this.computeCartTotals.
All right, so a bit more on the remove method.
So we'll pass in the cart item.
So we basically want to find out where is this cart item
in the array, and let's remove it.
So the first thing we need to do is get the index
of the item in the array,
we can make use of this.cartItems.findIndex
and then we pass in the actual expression.
So similar to what we did earlier
by using other finder methods, here in this example,
we're simply finding the index.
So we're making use of tempCartItem.id = theCartItem.id.
That'll give us the index and it will return it.
So we have itemIndex, then if found,
let's remove the item from the array at the given index.
So if itemIndex is greater than minus one,
that means it found it, if it didn't find it,
the value would be minus one.
So if itemIndex is greater than minus one,
then we say this.cartItems.splice, the itemIndex comma one.
So we're basically removing the item from the array
at that given index.
The comma one means remove one item from the array.
You can have larger numbers if you wanted to,
but for our scenario, for our use case,
we simply want to remove that one cart item.
And then we go ahead and call this.computeCartTotals.
And that's basically it for the remove.
Now, if you'd like to get more details
on that splice method, go to the link
that I have here on the slide,
we'll simply redirect you to the official documentation,
and you can read all the details there
about the splice method.
All righty, so in step four, we have the Remove button.
So we basically just kind of repeat the process
for the Remove button.
So we have this button here called Remove,
and then we set up our on click handler,
so we call the method remove,
and we pass in tempCartItem.
And a lot of this coding is very similar
to what you've seen before.
And so in our cart-details.component.ts,
we have this method remove,
and it will make a call to this.cartService.remove,
we pass in theCartItem.
And we'll simply reuse that method that we just wrote
in the previous step for the cart service.
So we're pretty much done here
as far as the coding for Remove button.
All righty, I'm getting excited.
So let's go ahead and move into our IDE
and let's get started.