Okay, so I'm really happy now
because we're at the final step,
step six of creating the controller,
oof, almost there, almost there.
Alrighty, so the one thing I want to do here
is create a new package for our controller.
And now in this new package, I'll go ahead
and create a new Java class for our checkout controller.
Alrighty, so here's my checkout controller,
I need to do a couple of things up top,
set up support for the cross origin
and we've been through this drill before
with creating a rest APIs
and then we'll set up our @rest controller annotation
and also set up the base request mapping
for this controller.
And then remember with our application architecture,
we need to make use of our service,
in this case our checkout service.
So I'll go through the normal drill here of injecting that
checkout service using the a constructor injection here.
And then just remember we could put auto wired
but it's not required or it's optional,
and in this case, because we only have one constructor,
so, Spring will automatically auto wire that
service in for us.
Alrighty, let me stretch out a little bit here
at the bottom, give myself some room to work with.
So we know with our API,
we're going to have post-mapping for /purchase.
So this method will return a purchase response.
The JSON will come over in the request body
and so the sign out here to this purchase
data transfer object
that we created a little bit earlier.
And now the coding here is really simple,
all I'm going to do is simply delegate this to my service.
So I'll make use of checkout service.placeorder
and I'll just pass over the purchase.
So that'll return as purchase response
and I simply return that via the rest API,
so it'll take that purchase response,
send it back as JSON and we're all good to go.
And one other thing I would do,
just a little bit of housekeeping stuff here,
I'll upgrade to the current version of Spring Boot,
'cause I'm, I've been using the same version for a while now
and she'll probably just catch up with what they have,
so, of course this all changes with every version, right?
So by the time you watch it,
they'll probably be on a totally different version
of Spring Boot
but I'll just kind of update what I have for right now.
The best way I go about this is just going in
to the spring.io website
and seeing what the current version number is,
so Spring Boot is currently at 2.4
and again, this will totally change
by the time you watch it,
they have a very aggressive and fast release cycle
and I'll use the 2.4 and also to get the right version of
I'll do a little explore here
and note version 2.4.0
so, starting with this version
or maybe even the previous version,
they changed their scheme for our versioning here,
so make sure you use exactly what they have.
The important thing here is that they dropped
the .release with this version and future versions,
so just be aware of that.
So I'll just make use of that little generate feature to
see exactly what the version number is,
and you can drop it in here.
All right, so I have that in, 2.4.0
and then I simply do a Maven update over here
so I can pull down all the latest stuff from the palm.
And if you notice here at the bottom,
it says it's resolving dependencies,
so, the idea is actually loading or downloading
the latest version to our local Maven repository.
Depending on your internet speed, this may take awhile,
but anyways that the final point it's all done.
One thing to be aware of you may still see
the version number in a different color.
You can safely ignore this, the application will still run
and we could still run the e-commerce app
and it'll be up and running with no problem,
so, just move past that.
All right, so this looks pretty good.
So in the next video, we'll actually run this
and see if it works, oh yeah.