In this video we're going to refactor
the cart service.
Currently we have some very basic code
for finding an item in the cart.
So we have this for loop we loop over each item in the cart
and we make some comparisons.
This is the code that we're going to refactor
by using a special method available for arrays.
Okay, so we'll make use of the find method.
This method returns the first element in an array
that passes a given test.
So the find method is an instance method
that's available on all arrays
and basically it'll loop through the array
and it'll check a given test.
So the test that we're using here is we're trying to see
if tempCartItem.id equals theCartItem.id.
And so, it'll execute the test for each element
in the array until the test passes,
so it'll loop through the elements in the background.
If the test passes,
then it's going to return the first element
in the array that passed.
If the test fails for all elements in the array,
then it's going to return undefined.
Basically meaning, hey, I couldn't find that element.
So if you'd like to get more details on this find method,
you can go to the website here on the screen.
We'll redirect you to the official documentation
for the find method.
All righty, so let's look at some coding for this
and now, just a quick heads up,
we'll reference theCartItem.
That's an element that's passed into the method
for addToCart, so that's the actual element
that we're searching for in our shopping cart.
All righty, so up top we have this for loop
and so we have the tempCartItem,
that's the current array element
as we loop through the array
and then we had a Test Conditional here.
We checked to see if tempCartItem.id equals theCartItem.id.
So that's kind of like the existing code,
the basic code that we had before.
Now at the bottom here we'll have this new code
or a replacement or a refactored code,
and so we'll make of this current array element.
So that's the tempCartItem
and then we have this Test Conditional,
tempCartItem.id equals theCartItem.id.
And so it's going to execute the test for each element
in the array until the test passes.
So, it'll do the looping in the background for us.
And so it's going to return the first element
that passes the test, else it returns undefined.
So the coding that we had at the top,
we can basically replace it with the coding
here we have at the bottom.
That's a good way of refactoring our code.
So let's kind of pull it together here
with a before and after.
So on the left hand side we had the before code.
So our basic way of doing a for loop.
And then over on the right we have our after code.
So here we're going to make use of cartItems.find.
So as you can see here, there's some improvement.
We minimized the amount of code that we have to make use of
and we're making use of some of the built in methods
available on arrays.
So I like this.
This is pretty cool.
So, let's go ahead and move into our IDE
and let's refactor our code using this new feature.
All righty, I'll see ya in the next video.