Okay, so taking a look
at our development process,
in this video we're going to cover the first three steps.
We're going to add the click handler for the decrement button,
update the CartDetailsComponent
and also modify the CartService.
Okay, so let's go ahead and move in
and open up our cart-details.component.html.
And let's move down here to our decrement button.
And that's the one here that has fa-minus.
Okay great, so this is our decrement button here.
And I will add a onclick handler.
And I'll call the method decrementQuantity,
and I pass in the tempCartItem.
Just slide over a bit so we can see it all on the screen.
All right, this looks good.
Of course, the IDE is given us that message again.
(laughs)
No problem, we'll go ahead
and update the CartDetailsComponent
with that click handler method.
So I'll just copy that method name, decrementQuantity,
move into the cart-details.component.ts,
and I'll just scroll down to the bottom of this file,
and I'll just paste in that method name.
They'll pass in the param, theCartItem,
and then I simply call a method on the cartService,
so this.cartService.decrementQuantity.
All righty, so this coding looks good.
Now, in step three we need to modify the CartService
with a supporting method,
so we'll let the IDE generate this method for us.
All righty, so they created the method for us.
Let's go ahead and move into CartService
and take a look at things.
So we'll see right near the top of the class,
they have this generated method, decrementQuantity.
Now, let's go ahead and cut this method.
I like to move them down to the bottom near my other code.
So I'll just move all the way down here
and paste it right here.
All righty, good.
All right, so in moving here for this method,
the first thing I want to do is decrement
the quantity by using --.
Next, I'll check theCarItem quantity,
and see if it's equal to zero.
If so, then we'll remove it.
Else, we simply call computeCartTotals.
We'll have the IDE generate the remove method for us.
And I'll just scroll up so I can kind of focus
on the remove method.
I'll write some quick comments here to myself
to kind of keep myself on track.
All right, so let's go ahead and start writing the code.
So I'll set up const itemIndex = this.cartItems.findIndex();
I give it the expression for matching or finding,
and so here I'm comparing tempCarItem.id with theCartItem.id
and we created code like this earlier
in some of the other videos for finding items in an array.
All righty, so that's the coding, looks pretty good.
And remember, if it's not found, the value's -1.
If it did find it, it'll give you the index,
and that'll be greater than -1.
So here I say, if itemIndex is greater than -1,
then we'll give this.cartItem.splice,
starting at that itemIndex comma 1,
so we're simply removing one element,
and this matches our given use case.
And then we also call computeCartTotals.
And that's pretty much it for the remove method.
This looks pretty good, I like it.
And this remove method is used
by our decrementQuantity method,
so we have some good functionality in place right now.