All right so, let's run it.
Ready to run this.
So I just fire it up in my IDE,
start the app, get it up and running.
And then I need to make use of
that sample-purchase.json
that we downloaded a little bit earlier.
So I like to run this with Postman
and test it out.
So let me go ahead and start Postman.
And so I'll zoom in here,
and I'll update my request.
So for the one thing I'll do
is I'll make it a POST method.
And then I'll enter the request URL
that I have here on the screen.
So that's localhost:8080/api/checkout/purchase.
And then I'll select body,
I'll go to raw and choose the type of JSON.
So now, we need to add some JSON here for the body.
So let me kind of swing back over to my file system
to that Downloads directory.
And let's open up that sample-purchase.json,
you just open it up with any one of your text editors,
and just copy-paste that into Postman.
All right, there it is.
It's in Postman now.
And I just do some small little massaging
on the customer names here.
And then also here,
shipping address, billing address,
I'll make sure that those are the same addresses here.
So I'll just kind of copy some of this stuff.
So I'm just going to copy the shipping address content
and put it down here for billing address.
All right. So that looks pretty good.
So let's go ahead and send it across our API.
All right, look at that order tracking number.
And that's that UUID,
that random UUID that was generated.
Oh, yeah.
I'm happy about that.
That's pretty good.
And let's swing over to our database
and see if this is in our database.
So move back to the Orders table
and run this query again.
And oh, yeah,
so that's the same tracking number that we had in Postman.
So I like to say, success.
So we were successful in storing our purchase order
in the database.
We can look at some of the other items here,
we can take a look at customer.
So there's our Susan Smith.
Okay, great.
And so all of our relationships are working out okay.
Address good, Canada.
All right.
Good, good, good.
Order Items.
Okay, we have two items there.
Good, good.
Associated with a given order ID.
Good.
All right. So just kind of standing back
and admiring our work,
looking here at this checkout controller.
Based on architecture,
we had the controller talking to the service
using that Spring Data JPA repository,
and saving information in the database for us.
And we also did some custom work here
by making use of that custom order tracking number
that we generated.
So this looks really good.
I'm happy.
Good job.