In this video,
we're going to learn how to add products to the cart
from the Details view.
So we've already done work of adding products to the cart,
but now on our Details view or our Details page,
we need to add similar support.
So here we have an Add to cart button
on our Details view for adding a given item
to the actual cart.
So here's the development process.
So the first thing we'll do is we'll add the click handler
for the Add to cart button on our ProductDetailsComponent,
and then we'll update our ProductDetailsComponent
with the given click handler method.
And a lot of the functionality will be similar
to what we did before, just with a small change
or a small twist.
So step one of adding a click handler
for the Add to cart button,
so in our product-details.component.html page,
we have a button here, Add to cart,
and that's the item that we'll see on the screen,
and then we'll add this On click event.
So we'll actually call the method, addToCart
when the user clicks on that given button.
Now moving ahead to step two
of updating our ProductDetailsComponent
with the click handler method,
so this is in our file, product-details.component.ts.
So we already have our existing product,
and then we'll just have some comments here,
meaning that behind the scenes,
we do all the code for retrieving the product
from the product from our REST API.
We've written all that code before,
but now we'll simply add this new method here, addToCart,
and we simply log the product name and unit price,
and that's the product that's defined
in this component up top.
Then we simply create a cart item based on this,
and then we'll call cartService.addToCart,
and then we pass in theCartItem.
So as you can see, a lot of this code is similar
to what we did before.
Now, with the application interaction,
the only new code is right here
on the ProductDetailsComponent
where we actually have addToCart
and we call a method on the CartService,
but there are no changes for steps one, three, and four,
so everything over on the right hand side,
that's all the same.
We're simply feeding data to the CartService,
and the CartService is responsible for publishing the events
to all subscribers.
So the really nice thing about this
is that we can leverage a lot of the work that we did before.
We're simply adding on a new piece of code here
for simply calling a method on the CartService
and adding data to it.
Alrighty, so this looks pretty good.
Let's go ahead and move into the IDE,
and let's start writing the code.