Alrighty, so for step three,
we're going to update the HTML template
to display the error messages
for our billingAddress section.
And you all pretty much know the drill, right?
It's just more of kind of copy paste.
So feel free to move ahead and do the work on your own.
Or you can follow along with me here in the video,
totally up to you,
but you've already been through the process once.
It's just more of the same.
So I'll just move up shippingAddress
and I'll just copy this section here
for shippingAddressCountry.
I'm done in the billingAddress section.
I'll add it here for country.
And I'll make the appropriate updates.
And let me just run a quick test on this,
just to make sure
the billingAddressCountry validation works.
So we added it for this one item here.
Just want to check for country right now.
Swing down here to our purchase.
Swing up to my billingAddress section
and country is required, so cool.
So we know that part works.
Now, we're just going to just repeat the process
for all the other fields here for this section.
So I'll just make the appropriate updates here
for billingAddressStreet.
I'll just move down here to City.
Make the appropriate updates for billingAddressCity.
I'll just move down here to Zip Code
and then make the appropriate updates here
for billingAddressZipCode.
And then we're almost done here.
I'll just moved down here to State.
And I'll make the updates here for billingAddressState.
Alrighty, so this coding here looks pretty good.
I'm happy with what we have in place so far.
So good job my friend.