In this video, we'll continue with populating
the Country-State Drop-Down List.
Alrighty, so the back end work for the REST API is done.
Now let's handle the front end development.
So the user is going to select the country,
depending on the country selected,
will populate the list of states.
So here's our shipping address,
the user selects the country,
and then we'll populate the states
for that selected country.
Okay, so here's our development process,
and this is all for the frontend.
The first thing we'll do is we'll create TypeScripts classes
for country and state.
We'll add methods to the form service,
for countries and states.
We'll update the checkout components,
or retrieve the countries from the service.
We'll also update the HTML templates
to populate drop-down lists for countries.
And then we'll add an event handler
for the checkout component.
So we'll read the selected country,
and then we'll retrieve the list of states
based on a selected country.
And then finally, we'll update our HTML template,
to populate the drop-down list for states.
And also here just as a refresher,
we have our backend REST APIs already created,
we can access various endpoints,
and it'll give us a list of all countries.
And also we can find by country code,
and will give us a list of all states,
for that given country.
And that's already up and running.
So getting started here with step one
of creating the typeScript classes for country and state,
allow this class country,
and it'll have properties for id, code and name.
And this will map over to the JSON data that we receive
from the REST API.
And then we'll do a similar thing here for state.
We'll have a state class for id and Name and again,
mapping over to the JSON from the REST API.
Alrighty, so moving ahead to step two
of adding methods to the form service
for countries and states.
So we'll make some updates here to all Luv2shopFormservice,
or statesUrls for countries and states,
and our constructor will Inject the HttpClient.
And then we'll write the code here for Get Country.
So it returns an observable array of countries.
And we simply make the call to httpClient.get,
GetResponseCountries.
Remember, this is going to return an observable,
we're going to map this JSON data from Spring Data REST,
over to our Country array.
And at the bottom, we'll create this interface,
GetResponseCountries, and we use this,
to unwrap the JSON from spring Data REST,
for that underscore embedded entry.
And then here's the JSON here at the top,
and notice here how we map the underscore embedded,
so we can actually get that list of countries,
or get that array of countries,
and then assign it and then send it back
to the calling program.
And this is a common technique.
We've used this before in some of our previous videos.
Alrighty and we kind of just repeat the process for states.
So have this method here,
Get States, pass in the country code,
and then we'll set this searchStatesUrl.
So we basically say findByCountryCode,
and code equals theCountryCode they pass in,
and then we do a similar thing.
So this returns an observable,
we map the JSON data from the spring Data REST,
to a State array.
And then at the bottom, we make use of this interface,
GetResponseStates.
Again, unwrapping the JSON from Spring Data REST,
and we map it to that underscore embedded entry.
So same coding that we've done before.
Alrighty, now in Step three,
we're going to update the checkout components,
or retrieve countries from the service.
So my checkout component class,
I'll set up an array of country objects.
And then here inside of this ngOnInit,
I will do all of our normal initialization work.
Here, we actually want to go out,
and populate the countries or get a list of countries
from that form service.
So I use Luv2ShopFormService,
I get countries that were subscribe, the data is returned,
I simply do a console.log on those retrieve countries.
And then also here, I say this.countries equals data.
So when the form is initially displayed,
we're going to populate the countries.
Now in step four, we actually update the HTML templates,
to populate the drop-down lists for the countries.
So in our HTML here, we have option ngFor,
let country of countries.
And then we simply loop over that,
we say country.name.
So country is an actual array,
that we defined in our actual component,
on the previous slide.
And next, we update our checkout component,
we add an event handler.
So for change event, we're going to call the method geStates.
So when they select a country,
then we want to get the states for that given country.
And so we'll accomplish this inside
of this getStates method.
So a couple of things here.
One is that I'll define two arrays of State objects
for shipping and billing.
We want to keep those separate,
because when a user chooses their different countries,
we simply want to update the appropriate states
for that given section,
for shipping address or billing address.
And then inside of this method getStates,
they'll pass in the formGroup,
so I need to figure out which form I'm using,
if I'm using billing or shipping,
but basically, I read the selected country code,
from the form and retrieve the states,
for the selected country code.
So here I say if formGroup name equals shippingAddress,
then I assign this.shippingAddressStates equals data,
else, this.billingInterestStates equals data.
And then at the bottom here, I select the first item
by default, so I say formGroup.get "state",
setValue data sub zero.
So selecting the first state in that list of states,
so they're retrieved.
And then finally, I want to update the HTML template,
to populate the drop-down lists for states.
So again, a similar thing,
we simply loop over that array
of our shipping address states.
And then we simply give State.name.
And that's the basic coding there for getting this set up.
So let's go ahead and move into the video,
dive and saw it in a missile writing some code.