Alrighty, so let's go ahead and get started
with our development process.
In this video, we'll cover step one
of adding pagination support to the product service.
Alrighty, so let's go ahead and swing into our IDE.
And we'll need to open up the product service class.
So I'll just move over here to source, app, services,
and then product.service.ts.
Just give me one second here to expand my window.
All righty, so we're in product service right now.
And so we want to add a new method
for pagination, for searching.
And so I'll actually copy one of our previous methods,
and make some slight modifications to it.
So I'll actually copy this getProductListPaginate method.
So I'll just highlight that and copy it.
And then I'll move down a bit here,
right after searchProducts, and I'll paste it here.
Okay, so I've pasted the method,
let me update the method name,
I'll call it searchProductsPaginate.
All righty, that looks pretty good searchProductsPaginate.
Let me just kind of line up some of this code here,
format it a bit.
Also just kind of line up my parameters here coming in.
All righty, so searchProductsPaginate,
so this is where we'll pass in the parameters
for performing the search, and using pagination.
So one thing I need to do is remove the category id,
and make use of the keyword, 'cause we're searching here,
based on a given keyword.
And then I also need to make some updates to my URL,
so I'll copy this URL, from up above.
So for my regular searchproducts,
I'll copy that findByNameContaining,
and I'll paste it down here
into this new searchProductsPaginate.
Right, so just a little copy paste exercise here.
All right, so make sure that your search URL,
now has search/findByNameContaining.
I'll also do a quick update here on my comment,
just to kind of keep it in line with the actual source code.
Let's do a slight tabbing over here.
And that's it.
And just remember Spring Data REST supports pagination
out of the box.
So we simply send over the parameters for page and size.
And that's all the coding there for searchProductsPaginate.
So this looks pretty good, I like it.