Alrighty, so let's get started
with our development process.
In this video we're going to cover step one and two
of creating the TypeScript classes for country and state,
and also adding methods
to the form service for countries and states.
Alrighty, swinging into our IDE here.
Let's go ahead and open up a new terminal window.
And we'll move into the appropriate directory
for our project.
And I'll make use of the ng generate command
to create those classes for me.
So I generate the country class,
and then I do a similar command here
for generating the state class.
Okay, this is great,
so I can swing back a bit,
look into my source, app, common directory
and I should see country.ts and state.ts.
Okay, great, so that was successful.
I'll do a quick clean up here on this terminal window,
so I can have some space, some room to work with.
Zoom in here on my country class,
and I'll create three fields here.
I'll have the id, the code and the name.
Alrighty, that looks good.
Let's do a similar thing here for the state class.
So, I'll zoom in here.
And I'll have the state id and the state name.
Alrighty, so that's great, I like that.
Now let's go ahead and move to step two
of adding methods to the form service
for countries and states.
So, I'll swing down here to my service
for our luv2-shop-form service.
And so, I'll start off by simply setting up
the country's URL,
and also the states' URL.
So that's the country's URL.
I'll do a quick, little, copy paste on this,
and then I'll just update for states URL.
And that's /api/states.
And then I'll inject the http client,
because I know I'll need to make some rest calls.
Alrighty, so that looks pretty good so far.
Make sure my imports are correct up top
for the import on that client.
Okay, great.
So, we're in good shape with this coding so far.