Alrighty, so let's go ahead and get started
with step one of adding the click handler
for the add to cart button.
So I'll just zoom in here,
and I'll move down to a source, app, components.
And I'll move into the product details component.
And I'll open up the html page,
product details component.html.
Let's expand this window here,
give us some room to work with,
and I'll move down to where I have the button
for add to cart.
And so this is where I'll do my work right here.
In select before will change href to a button.
And then we'll add the appropriate styles here
for the button.
So I'll make use of button, button primary,
button SM for button small.
And then I'll add code here
for my click handler.
So I'll have click,
and I'll call it add to cart.
Then the IDE will do a good job,
and tell me that I have an error. (laughs)
And yes, Sir, I know
the identifier add to cart is not defined,
and we'll actually do that now.
So here's step to of updating the product details component
with the click handler method.
So I'll actually copy this method name, add to cart,
and then I'll move to the file
product details component.ts.
And what I'll do is I'll move to the bottom of this file,
and I'll just paste in that method name, add to cart,
and I'll just stub it out for now.
But I know that I'll need the cart service,
so let me go ahead and move up to my constructor,
and let's inject the cart service.
Alright, so now I can start using this
here in my actual method, add to cart.
And the first thing I'll do here
is I'll just put a little console.log.
I'll say adding to cart,
and I'll give the product name and the product unit price.
I'll add a semi-colon here.
Notice I have a small syntax error.
And, oh yeah, that's right.
I need to say this.product name and this.unit price.
And now I simply go through and create a cart item
based on this product.
So I say the cart item equals new cart item product.
This.product. (laughs)
Alright, and now I can call my cart service.
I can say this.cart service.add to cart,
and I can pass in the cart item.
And that's the basic coding here
for this add to cart method.
And remember with our application interaction,
that new code,
that's the step two.
That's the new code we're adding
for this product details component.
But, again, we're simply leveraging
all of the existing work
on the right hand side.
So no changes for steps one, three, and four.
All that is still the same.
We're simply adding new data to the cart service
by calling that method.
And, again, we're simply using the product
that's been defined on this product details component,
and, of course, we'll assign it and initialize it
via our handle product details method.
So by the time we add it to the cart,
that product has already been loaded with data.
So, one thing I want to do
is make sure
that our Spring Boot application is up and running.
That's good.
We're running on that side.
And now my Visual Studio Code,
I'll just go ahead and start my Angular application.
Okay, great.
So our application's up and running.
Let's swing over to our browser.
Let's go ahead and open up our Web Developer Console
for debugging.
Now we can access our application,
and we can go to the details view
for a given product.
So, Crash Course in Python.
Hit the add to cart button.
And, yes.
So the shopping cart is updated
with the appropriate data.
So this is great.
So now we can add something from our details view.
Let's try some of our other products here
like our mouse pad.
Hit the add to cart link.
And good, this product has been added to the cart.
We can add multiple
entries of this.
And excellent, this all looks really good.
And we can go around and some other items
to the cart,
but this all works as desired,
so I'm very excited,
and really happy right now.
So I'd like to say good job, my friend.