Alrighty, so we're moving along
with our development process.
So in this video, we'll cover step two
of updating our ProductListComponent
to handle the pagination.
Okay, so let's go ahead
and move over to our product list component file.
And that's product-list.component.ts.
So I'll just start here.
At the top of the file is a little checkpoint,
making sure we're at the right place, the right location.
So we'll add this new property here, previousKeyword,
it's of type string, and I will initialize it to null,
and we'll make use of it later in our code.
Okay, so let's go ahead and move down to our method here,
handle search products,
and we'll do the bulk of our work here in this method.
Let me zoom in a bit.
So I'm going to write some quick comments here.
So basically, if we have a different keyword
than the previous, they want to set the page number to one,
and we did a similar thing here for category IDs,
when we're making use of listing products,
but here we're focusing on keywords.
If this.previousKeyword is not equal to theKeyword
then we'll set this.PageNumber equal one.
Basically just resetting it
if there's a new keyword coming through.
And then we'll also add some code here
to keep track of the keywords,
so I'll say this.previousKeyword equals theKeyword.
And then also just for debugging purposes,
I'll do a console.log and I'll log some information
just so I can see it in the browser console
if I need to come back and debug this application.
So I'll log the keyword and I'll also log the page number.
Alrighty, so that looks good for the basics.
Now we need to update this next section of code here
for searching for products
'cause we're going to call
that new method, searchProductsPaginate.
So I'll just clear out that old code
and I'll make use of searchProductsPaginate.
And I'll pass in those three parameters.
I'll pass in the page number minus one.
I'll also pass in the page size.
And then also pass in the keyword,
what keyword we're searching for.
Okay, and now I'll do the subscribe.
Then I'll make a call here to this.processresults.
So basically process the results of this async call.
And that's the same method that we had previously
in some of the previous videos.
And that's pretty much it as far as calling the service.
Now scroll up a bit and just to, kind of,
get a good snapshot here, so basically,
this is our updated handle search products method.
Alrighty, so this looks pretty good.
I'm getting excited.
I'm ready to run it,
so we'll go ahead and get started and test this out.
The first thing we need to do
is get our Spring Boot application up and running,
so I'll swing over to IntelliJ,
and I'll just run the Spring Boot ecommerce app.
All right, so that's up and running a-okay.
And Visual Studio Code,
I'll simply open up a new terminal window here.
And I'll go ahead
and get my Angular application up and running.
Alrighty, so I'll swing over to my browser,
go to localhost 4200.
And then for the search keyword, I'll just type in python.
So I'm going to have two python items,
and so that works out good with our pagination
at the bottom, only one page.
I'll type in the word introduction.
So we have five products called introduction,
so page size of one, sorry page size of five,
one page, okay that's fine.
I type in the letter A.
And now I get a lot of results.
Basically any product that has the letter A in it,
so there's a lot of products, right,
but this is a really good way to test out our pagination
to see if this is really working for us.
So then I search for Java, I see the results,
change the page size to five.
All righty, this is great.
Our pagination is working for searching by keyword.
This is some really good stuff.
I'm excited and I like to say, good job, my friend.