Okay, so now we'll go ahead
and take a look at doing some layout work for our component
and also adding some CSS support.
So let me move into my login status component.html,
expand my window,
I'll get rid of all the previous stuff that was here.
And basically what I want to do here
is have this new component
where we have a login button.
And then also once they're logged in
we want to have an area where we can display the user's name
and a log out button.
So we'll just set up a div as the main container here.
And what I'll do here is set up an ngIf
I'll check to see if the user's authenticated
and also if their username is set,
if so then I'll actually display a welcome message
to the user.
So we'll say, Hey, welcome back, user full name.
Now we'll display some buttons
depending on their actual authentication status.
So here, if they're not authenticated
then we'll actually show them the login button.
All right, so that's the login button
that'll send them over to this
routerLink/login
and we'll take care of the router links in a bit.
The third item here is ngIf,
and we'll say if is authenticated,
then we'll actually show them the log out button.
And then we'll just change the routerLink portion to be
an actual event binding forward click.
And once you to code the log out method
and then we'll move over here
and we'll give the text for the button to be logged out.
So effectively here, if they're already logged in
then we'll show the log out button.
So this will kind of give us the layout here
for the coding here for a login button
meaning that they're not logged in.
If they are logged in already
then we'll show them a welcome message
along with a log out button.
So that's kind of the basics,
the source of the layout here for our
login status component.
Now there are a couple of CSS styles that I used here
that we haven't really defined yet.
So we actually need to go through the process
of getting that part set up.
And what we'll do is we'll actually
put this information into our
login-status.component.css.
Now in previous videos we never really use the CSSs
for the actual component,
We will kind of put them into the main file
for our styles.css.
But in this video, just to show you a different approach
we'll actually put our local styles
for this component in its own CSS file.
Again, you can do it either way
you can put everything into one big style CSS
or you can put them in smaller specific file
so think about it working on a much larger project
you may want to have separate CSS files per component
just so you can kind of keep track of
which styles belongs to which components.
Again, it can work either way
I'm just showing you an alternative approach.
So what we'll actually do is we'll copy some CSS styles
from styles.css and then we'll rename them
and we'll use them here for the login status component.
And we'll also make some slight maths to them.
So I move it to the style CSS
and I'm going to copy this au-button submit.
So I'm in style CSS right now
and I'll just do a search
for this au-button.
Yeah, the au-button submit that's what I want.
So let's go ahead and select this and copy it,
then I'll swing back over to my login status component CSS
and I'll paste it here.
I'll do the quick rename on it,
let me just fix my comments
so it matches with what I said, okay.
And I'll do a rename, call it security button
and then just a slight math here
I'll just change the border to 10 pixels.
And that's the only real change here for this style.
But we gave it a different name
so if we wanted to make any maths to it
it wouldn't affect the entire application
just the styles here for this given component.
And then we'll move to the next video
and we'll do a similar thing as far as adding
or incorporating more styles for this component.