All right,
So we're still in our login-status.component.CSS.
We're going to copy over some more items,
just to make a quick little comment to myself
to keep myself on track.
So we'll copy another style from styles.CSS.
We'll grab the one call form-header.
Then we'll bring you back over here
and we're going to rename it as login-status-header.
So let's go ahead and find it first.
So we're looking for form-header.
Okay, there it is.
We found it.
Let's go ahead and copy this.
Swing over here to our login-status,
we'll paste it
and then we'll simply rename it as login-status-header.
And again the reason that we're copying
and pasting these items that we may need to
make slight changes to them
or we just want to keep them localized
so in event that we do make any changes,
we don't impact the entire application only just
this login-status.component.
So it just gives us a little bit of flexibility here.
Alrighty, so we just have one more style
to copy and this'll be the last one.
So we're going to copy this .au-input
and then rename it as a login-status-user-info.
And we'll make some changes
to this style by removing solid, font-size and color.
All right, so let's go ahead and find a au-input.
All right, so let's copy that,
swing back over to our login status CSS
we'll paste it
and first off rename it
login status user info.
So we'll remove
lets see the solid
and then we'll also remove the font size and color.
Okay.
So that's it, as far as the modifications here
for our log in status user info.
Alrighty.
So that was a fun exercise copying over those a CSS styles
and making the slight mods and renames.
So we need to do one more thing.
We need to kind of add this
to the main app component .HTML file.
I have app component HTML open.
And let me expand my window here for a second.
So let's move down to that header desktop section.
And so we currently have our search component
and we also have our cart status component.
That's fine.
Now let's go ahead and add our new log-in status component
that we just created.
We're going to add it here to this header section.
So we'll squeeze it in right here
between the search and the cart status.
So now we have some real estate here
for our login status components,
so we can welcome back a user
and have the log out button,
or if they're not logged in,
then we give them the log in button
and we coded all that logic in the previous set of videos.