Alrighty so let's add
validation for credit card,
we'll do things slightly different here
on credit card for the card number,
we only want to have 16 digits as well as the card number.
Now I know that there's some special algorithms
that you can apply to card numbers to check the checksum,
if it's an American express or a visa or MasterCard,
I won't cover that.
For now I'll simply check
if it's only 16 digits
and I'll do that using a regular expression.
If you'd like to get into more advanced algorithms
on the credit card number checks,
feel free to add that in your own time,
and also feel free to share it with the rest of the group.
And also for the security code,
we only want to accept three digits
and then the expiration month and year
they are auto-populated based on our previous coding logic
so, there's no special validation rules
we need to add for the section.
So again just more of the same
as far as our development process
and let's go ahead and dive in.
So move in here to our checkout component.Ts
I'll move down to our credit card section.
So we'll set up our car type to be required.
And then from name on card,
we'll make it required min length 2 ,
not only white space.
And then for card number we'll add Validators.patterns
we're going to make use of a regular expression here
and this regular expression
we'll check to make sure that we only have 16 digits.
We'll also make this field required
and we'll apply very similar validation rules
for security code.
So for security code, only three digits.
And remember we don't need to add anything
for expiration month or year
because those are pre-populated based on the logic
that we created before.
So just moving right along here step two of defining
the Getter method to access these form controls.
I'll just copy some previous code.
So I'll update the method name here.
This is credit card type
and the field name is credit card,
that card type,
and just copy this and paste it X the number of times
and go ahead and make my updates on the method names.
So credit card name on card,
credit card number
and credit card security code,
and then I'll make the appropriate updates
over on the right hand side for the field names.
So this is creditCard.nameOnCard
.cardNumber
.securityCode
Alrighty, so just use this as a checkpoint,
make sure your methods match up directly
with what I have here on the screen.
And this looks pretty good.