All right, so now that we have our constructors set up,
let's go ahead and write the code here
for getting the countries.
So now it's simply make a REST API call,
do HB client dot get.
We get response countries pass the net countries URL.
I pipe map the response.
And I make use of
that response dot embedded underscore countries.
And then in this interface get response countries I make use
of the underscore embedded
in countries as country square brackets.
So for that, all right.
So that'll basically unwrap the JSON from Spring Data REST
for that underscore embedded entry.
And again, we have that little mapping there
between underscore embedded and the actual JSON
that's returned by the REST API.
Okay, good.
I like it.
And we need to make one small modification here inside
of this get countries method.
So that's the main coding there,
but we have a little issue here with this map so we need
to do the appropriate import here for the map.
So be sure you choose our XJS slash operators.
Don't choose the internal, just the regular operators.
And then just scroll up to the top.
Make sure we have the right one pulled in.
So a good online five import map
from our XJS slash operators.
Okay, good job.
Alright, so that's the coding there for get countries
and that's in place.
So I like that so far.
Now let's do a similar thing here for get states.
So we need to make a REST API for getting the states.
But now remember when we get states they're not going to pass
in the country code that they want the states for.
So for example for 'In' for India
or 'Tr' for Turkey or whatever.
And then we'll also return
an observable array of state objects.
And we'll do something similar to what we did
for get countries but a slight modification because we want
to do a search using our search URL.
So that's that special query method
that we defined in our interface to find by country code.
So we'll make use of the base states URL.
Then I say slash, search find by country code.
And then I give the question mark code, equals
and then I make use of the country code that's passed in
to this given method.
Alright, so semi-colon.
Okay, this looks pretty good.
I like it.
Alright, so that part is done.
Now I can make the REST API call
using the search states URL.
So do the client dot get, get response states.
We pass the net search states URL,
and then we simply pipe and map a response.
And then we make use
of response underscore embedded dot states.
And so now let's go ahead and just kind
of copy this get response states, pull down to the bottom
and create a similar interface like we did
for get response countries.
All right, so get response states
and then I'll just kind of copy paste
'cause this is very similar here.
And the field is states and it's an array of state objects.
And I just need to fix the import here so make sure
we have the state imported for the one
that we created for our project.
Alright, so that's the coding there for get states.
This looks pretty good.