Okay, we're finally at our last step here,
oof, we're finally at step seven of updating
our app module configs to connect the routes,
almost there, we're almost there.
So let's go ahead and move over to our app module.tsfile.
And this is kind of like our main configuration
for setting up routes and so forth,
so we'll add some updates here
for the Okta login configuration.
So I'll make some Okta imports here
from the Okta angular SDK.
So we have this Okta config, auth module
and callback component
and we'll use these in some of the upcoming coding.
We also need to do an import here on this my app config
that's that same file that we created earlier.
Basically holding the properties here, the configs
for our client application
and we'll create this new Okta config here.
I'll go ahead and write the code first
then once I have the code written
then I'll come back and talk about it.
So we're basically saying,
"Hey, let's create this new object on auth required."
So when they try and log into our application
and they haven't been authenticated,
then we'll actually route them to the login page.
And so in a second here, we'll connect the routes
for a /login
and also connect the routes for the callback.
And also with this Okta config that we're setting up,
we also want to pass in our open ID connect
JSON configs that we created a little bit earlier.
All right, so let's go ahead and connect the routes.
So we have that login/call back.
And so we'll have a user's component
after callback component
and then for login by itself,
then we'll actually have them make a call to
the log in component that we just created.
Okay, so log in component is the one that we created
in some previous videos, so that's our code
and then there's also this Okta callback component.
So this Okta callback component will be executed
once the user has been authenticated
and they're redirected to our application.
Normally we'd have to write code to parse the response
and store the OAuth and OIDC tokens
but the Okta callback component
will do all of that work for you,
so that's why we're using the Okta callback component
in this scenario.