Alright, so we're making some
really good progress, we're almost done,
we have just a couple more fields to take care of.
So I'll just copy this section here,
I'll move down to the security code section.
Now drop this in, make the appropriate updates
for credit card security code.
And for credit card security code pattern,
the security code must be three digits long.
All right, so that's it for our validation rules so far
so I think we can go ahead and test this out.
So we'll move down to the credit card section here,
we'll kind of keep all of the defaults.
Swing down, hit the purchase button
and move back up and success.
This looks great so we have the validation rules
being applied to these fields here for the credit card.
And we can even test some of the things out here
like for credit card number requires 16 digits,
so make sure you enter 16.
And then also for security code, requires three digits.
So you can also just test those validation rules
out for that one.
So this looks pretty good.
So we added the validation rules here for our checkout form.
This is really good.
There was a lot of work involved,
but I'm happy with what we've accomplished so far.
And we have a lot of other really, really cool things to add
to this application, in particular,
the checkout form as far as form processing and so on
and we'll get into that in the next set of videos.