All right.
So in this lesson we're going to practice getting an email body from a single text file with a known
structure.
I'm going to go ahead and copy this cell right here and then I'm going to paste it down below.
Our goal is modifying the code in the cell.
So we just print out the message body instead of the header and the message body.
Here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to delete this line as well as this line as well as this line.
And I'm going to add some code between opening the file and closing the file.
The first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to create a boolean variable and I'm a call that is on
a school body.
And then when I set that to false to begin with then I'll also create another variable a list called
lines.
So lines is equal to an empty list.
So that has the square bracket notation.
Now what I'm gonna do is I'm going to read all the lines in our file so when I use a loop and I'm going
to loop through our stream so I'll save for line in the stream semicolon and then inside the loop I'm
going to check if I'm inside the email body.
So if is on the school body semicolon lines don't append line with this line of code does is it will
take our list lines and append a single line from our text file to the list if we are inside the email
body.
Now the natural question is how would you know that you're inside the email body.
Well if we look at the structure of this email we know that there is a space between the header and
the body.
There is a new line right after the date information in the e-mail.
So what we're gonna do it's going to check for this blank right here if we hit this blank line.
This new line we're going to change our boolean variable to true.
So else if line is equal to double equals single quotes and then backslash and backslash and is our
new line character.
So this checks for somebody having hit enter on their keyboard essentially.
Then I'll add a semicolon at the end and then inside this else if statement I'm going to set is body
equal to true.
And that's pretty much our loop I can close my file after we've read all the individual lines in our
stream and then all I have to do is maybe print out my email body so my email and the scroll body is
going to be equal to all of my list items maybe joined by a new line.
So I'll take single quotes backslash and don't join parentheses.
Lines and now let's print out our email and a school body and head shift into what we see is that our
loop is working.
We've cut off our hair and we're left with just the email body if you found this line of code confusing
namely joining all the individual entries in the list with a new line character.
Let's take it out and see how this formatting changes.
If we don't have it.
So what I'll do is I'll put a hash tag their comment this out and what I'll also do is comment out this
line right here.
And instead I'm going to print out my list which was lines.
Let's see what this looks like here's what we have.
We've got a new line character.
Then we have the first line in our email.
Dear Mr. Still.
Then another new line character and everything is separated by a comma in this list as the loop.
Read it line by line and appended it to our list.
This is the formatting we would get straight out of our loop and because this is not very readable what
we can do instead is join all the individual entries in the list at the New Line character and then
we get something much much much more readable.
Fantastic.
What we've just done is written the python code to extract an email body from our raw data with this
in hand.
We can apply this to all the messages in our dataset because they all follow the same pattern.
Ahead I'm going to show you how to do just that in the next lesson.
Stay tuned.