In this lesson we're going to talk about Input statements modules and packages in the previous lessons.
We've actually seen and used three different input statements already.
For example we had import pandas as PD we had import mat plot lib dot pie plot as PDT and we also had
from S.K. learned linear model import linear regression.
These are the three import statements that we're going to talk about in detail in this video each of
these import statements imports a Python module that we can then use in our Jupiter notebook if you've
already got some experience in programming perhaps in other languages.
The easiest way to think about Python modules is as frameworks or as libraries.
This is what they're going to be called in other languages.
That said the simplest way to think about a Python module is that every file that ends in dot P Y is
a Python module and by importing a module we get access to the variables and the functions inside the
file that was imported.
In other words importing gives us access to a dot P Y files contents.
Now so far we actually haven't seen any files with a dot P Y extension.
And why should a file end in dot P Y in the first place.
Well a top P Y file is a file that contains Python code and to see how this all works we're gonna create
a file it with a dot P Y extension together.
To do that we're gonna open a text editor in fact every Windows machine comes with a default text editor
print stalled that text that is whose name is notepad and it looks like this.
Now you're probably not going to have the shortcut on your taskbar.
So go to your start menu and then go to find all your programs and search for notepad and you should
also find it hard to remember not Microsoft Word notepad.
That's what we're going with.
If you have a Windows machine then open notepad now.
Now on the other hand if you're on Mac the default text that are that you've got pre installed is called
text edit and you can find this program in your applications folder so open this program now.
And create a new document.
If you're a new document looks like this then go to format and click on make plain text this is what
you want your text editor to look like for the next steps.
Now of course there are lots of other.
And some might say superior text that it has available to my current favorite is actually called atom
and this is made by the team behind the github Web site I've included the link to atom dot Io in the
lesson resources if you want to download it it's available for both Windows and for Mac and once you
start using it you'll never go back to a notepad again I promise.
Now that you've got your text editor open create a variable called the answer and set it equal to the
number 42 then go to file and click save as now and navigate to your desktop.
And instead of saving this file with a dot t t extension what we're gonna do is we're gonna call it
life and then append a dot P Y extension.
This is because we want to save a dot P Y file.
The important thing on Windows is that you have to change the Save As file type from text documents
thought to 60.
Write to this other item in the dropdown.
You want to change it to all files and only then can you click save.
After you've done that check your desktop to make sure that the file that you saved really does read
don't P Y at the end and not something else like dot p y dot t x.
Okay this is what we're looking for life don't P Y now if you're on Mac and you're using text it we're
going do the very same thing as the windows crew.
We're gonna create a variable called the answer and set it equal to 42 and then we're gonna go to save.
You're also gonna go to desktop and then you should be able to name your file life and give it the extension.
Don't P Y.
Now before you click save just double check that it says plain text encoding Unicode down here.
If it says something else like Rich Text you haven't gone to format and made the file plain text so
after you've verified this.
Just click save and then you can quit your text editor and verify that there is indeed a life don't
P Y file on your desktop.
And just like that we've created our first python script file.
Now let's upload this file to our Jupiter notebook.
Go to your email projects folder in Jupiter and click upload then navigate to your desktop where you've
saved your file choose it and click open and then afterwards confirm your upload here.
If you've been successful you should be able to click on this top P Y file and verify it that it says
the answer equals 42 Jupiter notebook will open this in a new tab for you.
The exciting thing is that now that we've uploaded our python script as a doc P Y file to our project
folder we can start using it in our Jupiter notebook.
Check this out back in our Python intro Jupiter notebook.
We can write import life and had shift enter.
If you see no error messages at this point the import was successful.
Now because I have an irrational love of data types let's check out what the type of this thing called
life actually is.
Going to write type and put life between the parentheses and head shift into a ha.
So here we find out that our lifetime P Y file when we import it is called a module.
Now here comes the really cool part.
We're going to access the code inside our life module right.
Life dot the answer and hit shift enter.
Now remember what we see now is the value inside are the answer variable that is shown below the cell.
How cool is that.
I think this is super cool.
It's like our Jupiter notebook has made a new friend.
But let's take a second to think about what this line of code actually means.
It literally means fetch the value of the name.
The answer that lives inside the module called life.
The thing to note here is the python syntax.
We've accessed the variable inside that life dot P Y file using the dot notation with access to the
answer by writing life.
Don't the answer and this notation will come up again and again as we progressed throughout the course.
Okay so now that we've just uploaded our own file and then imported it into our notebook let's draw
a link to the previous lessons now.
You'll probably remember that too.
Import pandas.
We didn't have to upload any dot P Y files we just wrote.
And then it just worked.
How is it that we can actually do that.
See I used to think it was magic but then sadly I discovered that it was not in fact magic.
It turns out that when we installed Anaconda a whole bunch of modules were already included in our installation.
And this is why there was no need to upload any pandas thought P Y file to a project folder.
Notebook already knew about pandas and we could just write import pandas but this should make you suspicious
right.
It begs the question what kind of other stuff does Jupiter already know about.
So let's take a look together at what modules we have access to out of the box from installing Python
Anaconda we can get hold of this information in various places.
The first place that we're going to check is the anaconda navigate.
When you open the anaconda navigator you'll notice that on the left you have this tab called environments.
And when you click on it under route you get a long long list of all the modules that you have access
to we can even filter on installed versus not installed and we can also filter by name.
So if I type in pandas I can see that there's a checkmark next to it.
So pandas is one of the installed modules which means that we can access it easily by writing an import
statement.
Now these filters in the anaconda navigate are actually super handy because we can quickly figure out
if something was installed or not installed but if we look closely at this window you'll notice that
it's not referring to the items in this list as modules instead it's referring to them as packages.
And it says I've got one hundred and ninety five packages available and this this brings me to my next
point.
When we were writing our import statements and we looked at the type of thing that we imported it was
called a module.
However when people talk about pandas or psychic learn they'll use another word they'll use this word
package just like the anaconda navigator even on the anaconda Web site they talk about Anaconda having
1000 plus data science packages since you and I both installed Anaconda on our own computers.
We actually see what these packages actually look like because pandas has to live somewhere on our harddrive
after all right.
I mean don't tell the world wildlife fund but you and I are not gonna go in a hunt for pandas when we
installed Anaconda on our war machine.
It would have created a folder somewhere on a Mac.
That folder will be under your home folder so we can go to go and then get take into our home folder
there will have a folder called Anaconda and then inside the anaconda folder with all the anaconda related
stuff.
We have a folder called P.K. G.S. P.K..
Yes of course stands for packages on windows that Anaconda folder will be hiding elsewhere.
So you'll have to go to your local disk.
This will probably be your C drive and then you'll have to go to users then you'll have to go to your
account.
So mine's called PD and inside there you'll have a folder called Anaconda three once inside your Anaconda
folder.
You're gonna have to venture deeper to find the pandas.
You've got to open your lib folder and then you'll have to open the site packages folder and there you're
going to get the list of all the packages that came with Anaconda once you installed it.
Now this is exactly the same list that you saw in the anaconda navigator and looking at this list you'll
probably realise that even though the anaconda team brags about 1000 plus packages and Anaconda we're
actually super lucky that by default it doesn't install all of them on the machine from the get go.
So now that we've successfully hunted down our pandas folder let's return to the original question why
is pandas referred to as a package.
Well as you can see when we look inside the pandas directory pandas is not a single dot P Y file.
Instead pandas is actually a whole bunch of DOT P Y files that are grouped together into a single bundle.
In other words a package is just a collection of files.
And when we refer to pandas as a package we are referring to this bundle of files that is living on
our computer because after all the sad fact of life is that there just isn't any magic.
And to be honest we don't actually deeply care about what all of these individual files do exactly.
That's all under the hood.
But I wanted to show it to you guys nonetheless at the end of the day all we need is an easy way to
refer to all of this code inside this pandas directory.
And this brings us full circle to the Jupiter notebook because our Python code with that one import
statement allows us to gain access to all the files in that pandas directory with a single line of code
but this story doesn't end here.
The packages that we downloaded as part of Anaconda aren't the only modules that we have access to actually
some modules are built into the python language itself.
And these built in modules include everything on this list.
This list is the so-called standard library.
And there are over 200 modules here.
So it's a pretty massive list scrolling around on here.
We see that there's one module called math.
Let's take a closer look at this math module the math module is something that we can use to do all
sorts of calculations.
And this module actually has information on two things namely the value of pi and the number E.
So as a challenge as an exercise can you import the math module into your Jupiter notebook.
And after you've imported the math module can you write the python code to print out the value of pi
below the cell.
And then after that write some more code to print out the value of e as well.
I'll give you a few seconds to figure this out and pause the video and here's the solution.
And just like we've imported pandas we simply write import math and to show the value of pi below the
cell.
I can write math dot P. I had shift enter and there it is there's the value of pi as per the math module
hand looking at the official Python documentation we can see that we can access the value of E using
this code right here in our Jupiter notebook.
This means that I can simply write math don't e and had shift enter to complete the final part of the
challenge.
So that's pretty cool right.
Using the module and the dot notation we can access any of the variables inside the module through their
name.
This is exactly the same syntax that we used when we uploaded our own dot P Y file and accessed the
answer by writing life dot.
The answer and this goes to show that we can access a lot of code from other modules like the math module
using the same dot notation.
Now let's take another look at this pandas import statement because this import statement that we wrote
with pandas was a little more complex than the one we wrote with import math or import life the pandas
import statement had something a little extra we wrote import pandas as PD and Jupiter is highlighting
the as in green.
So the syntax highlighting is telling us that the as in the line is a python key word.
So what is this.
As PD Pont do.
Why is it in there.
If you remember we actually saw this pattern again with the other import statement that we used further
down import map plot lib dot pi plot as P.L. T.
The answer is is that all this as PD as PDT code is doing is giving an alias to the import.
Why do we need an alias.
Well when you think about it the module math only has four letters.
It's not a lot of typing it's pretty short but this module math plot lib dot pi plot has about 17 characters
and the thing you'll learn pretty quickly about programmers is that programmers are lazy and a programmer
doesn't want to type out 17 characters every time they're referring to their plot.
So instead we wrote import map plot lib dot pi plot as PDT.
This created a variable called PDT which referenced our math.
Plot lib dot pi plot and allowed us to use a short name instead PDT became the alias for.
Plot lib dot pi plot hand.
We didn't have to call it P.L. t by the way we could have called it anything we wanted to.
We could have called it.
Jennifer put a yield pretty quickly discover that there are certain conventions in Python programming
and people people like to stick to convention.
For example pandas is usually given the alias PD.
For some reason don't don't ask me why.
So now that we've talked a little bit about this as keyword to create an alias let's put it into practice
so that it really sinks into memory.
We're gonna use this as keyword with our life module because we can give that module an arbitrary alias
to check this out if we write import life as Hitchhiker's Guide
and hit shift enter.
Then we also have to update the cell below.
And the reason is that we can no longer refer to this module as life because while we've given it an
alias if we were to re-evaluate this entire notebook by going to kernel and going to restart and run
all and scrolling down we see that we can no longer refer to our module by the name of life.
We've given life an alias so we have to use that alias.
We can no longer use the other name meaning we have to replace this with Hitchhiker's Guide.
And if a hit shift entered now this arrow disappears.
The same is true with the cell below.
Because our program crashed these cells were actually never evaluated.
If I hit shift enter here again it would get this name error and we have to replace life dot the answer
with hitchhiker's guide the answer.
Now our Python code will run without crashing so I hope this exercise made it a bit more clear as to
how this as keyword works in practice.
Once we have an alias we have to use the name of the alias to refer to the module.
Now let's take another look at the final import statement from the previous lessons this import statement
read from as learn dot linear model.
Import linear regression and the syntax highlighting here is telling us that this from is also a python
keyword.
So without me showing you this in the video right away can you as a challenge structure R life dot P
Y module to import the answer using the from keyword.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video
and here's the solution.
The pattern is exactly the same we would use from life.
Import the answer and had shift enter now a very very reasonable question that you will probably want
to ask at this point is how is this different from the other import statements.
I mean why are there three ways of importing things.
Can we just keep things simple.
And the answer to that is well yeah.
So the three import statements are all doing very very similar things.
And the reason I'm showing you these three ways of doing things is because people out there in the wild
are using all these three ways of writing their own Python code but there's also a subtle difference
with this from keyword and that difference to the other import statements that we've used so far is
that in this case we're copying out the answer from our lifetime P Y file.
The answer is now its own variable inside our Jupiter notebook because we've just made a copy of it
and this means we can do stuff with it.
For example we can create another variable and set it equal to the answer.
So if I write my favorite number
is equal to the answer and then print out my favorite number
and he'd shift into it prints out 42 but I can also manipulate the answer itself.
So if I write the answer is equal to the answer plus one redshift enter and then print out the value
we can see that this variable now updated to 43 the value by the way inside the P Why file is still
unchanged but the copy that we've made inside this notebook has updated 243 so in summary the from keyword
copies out the answer from our life module and it makes it accessible as a variable inside our current
notebook.
And this is different from the other import statements where this doesn't happen because if I scroll
up and we look at the cell up here we have to access the answer by writing Hitchhiker's Guide not the
answer.
So we have to use this dot notation to get hold of our variable.
Now let's compare this from life.
Import the answer and my favorite number equals the answer.
Let's put this in context of the code that we've written previously.
When we were estimating the movie revenues we had from Ashkelon import linear regression and then we
set rigger to linear regression.
In other words what we did was we copied an object called linear regression over into this notebook
and then because it was too long to type every time we stored linear regression in a variable with a
short name namely rigour.
Now I also want to come full circle.
This is a really good point to connect the dots between the lesson on data types.
The lesson on collections and this lesson on modules.
Remember when we check the data type for our regression intercept and when we read the full name of
the data frame.
Well guess what.
Looking at the full name of the data types you can actually see the module name where this data type
came from.
So for example the data frame came from the pandas module and our NDA array came from a module called
num pi.
In other words num PI was the module where this n d array was defined.
Okay so we're slowly coming to the end of this lesson on modules packages and inputs and we've covered
quite a few important concepts here.
So let's review them before we move on.
For starters we learned that python scripts live inside files ending in dot P Y and we also saw how
we can import existing code as a Python module into our Jupiter notebook projects using these import
statements.
We saw that there's a couple of different ways we can import a module.
The simplest way being just to write import and then the name of the module.
For example import math the next level up was using the as keyword in the import statement.
So in this case we import the module but we create an alias.
We create a new name to give the module and we can use this name to refer to it later on in the code.
This is what we did when we wrote import life as Hitchhiker's Guide.
Every time we wanted to access the code inside one of these modules we had the module name.
Then the dot and then whatever we wanted to access inside the module.
In this case we had Hitchhiker's Guide dot the answer and later on we had math dot pi.
Finally we saw how we can use the from keyword to copy out a specific piece of code from another module.
And this is what we did with from life.
Import the answer and this is also what we did previously with from ASCII loan import linear regression.
So at this point you might be asking yourself why does any of this matter.
Why is this a big deal.
And I suspect that you're probably already starting to see the power of these import statements and
how they're a massive game changer because by importing a module we can use other people's code.
And this saves us the work from having to write the code ourselves.
In the previous lessons we accessed the linear regression capability through a module called psychic
learn.
We didn't actually have to write the code that implements the specifics of linear regression.
All we did was import the functionality and use it.
The people who created site could learn essentially created a reusable software component their linear
regression code can be imported and used by everyone around the world for free.
So hats off to the authors of cyclone.
These guys and girls worked their butts off to create the code that we are using every time we import
cycle learn when we imported our life dot P Y file.
Well we only had a single line of code in it.
In contrast check out the code that we imported when we wrote from SDK learn import linear regression.
This code is actually open source so you can look at it and read it on github dot com or you can actually
open the dot P Y file itself from the socket learn package on your computer.
Now this file alone has about 500 lines of blood sweat and tears and that's just a single dot P Y file
inside the SBA loan package.
In other words there's loads and loads more files just like this that are part of cycle loan I guess
the reason that I've climbed onto the soapbox is that I want to get this idea across that we can do
all this cool stuff so effortlessly because we're standing on the shoulders of giants and on that note
let's set the stage for analyzing the effects of drugs on math test scores and let's import our plunging
module map plot lib and our linear regression to draw our best fit line let's write import map plot
lib dot pie plot as PDT and from SDK learn dot linear underscore model import linear regression and
then head shift enter.
No need to import pandas by the way we've already imported it as part of a previous lesson so I'll see
you in the next tutorial upwards and onwards.