Let's revisit our old friend the scatter plot we saw in the previous lessons.
How important it is to use plots in conjunction with descriptive statistics to spot patterns and outliers
using both of these tools together.
We get a more complete picture of what's actually going on.
So far we've been visualizing our data and looked at the distribution of values of some individual features
like our M for like the average number of rooms or are a D the index of accessibility to highways.
We can dig deeper into the relationships between these feature pairs as well as between the features
and our target value with some scatter plots.
The correlation matrix that we created already hinted at the fact that there are relationships amongst
the features that we can visualize so on that note I'd like to start this lesson off with a challenge.
First I want you to picture what the relationship would look like between the annual X and DHS features.
If you recall an X was a measure of pollution and gas was a measure of distance from employment centers.
Picture a graph in your head hand then write the two lines of Python code to visualize the scatter plot.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video before I show you the solution.
Ready.
Here we go.
So we've created a scatter plot many times before with PDT which is are mapped plot load module dot
scatter and then we have to supply two things the data for the x axis and the data for the y axis.
So on the x axis we're gonna have our data square brackets.
Yes.
So this is going to be our distance which is going to be on the x axis and on the y axis.
We're going to have our pollution measure which is going to be data square brackets and 0 x and then
finally PDT dot show.
So hitting shift into just gave me this error because I've come back to this notebook and I haven't
run the cells above it yet.
So I'm going to go to cell run all and then when I wait a little bit scroll all the way down.
And here we go.
What's this the relationship that you imagined in your head.
A kind of downward sloping line.
Let me add some labels to this graph before I give you my interpretation.
So PDT dot X label it's gonna be the IRS distance from employment and say font size 14 and then for
the Y label copy this line pasted in.
Change it to the Y label.
Change that to read n o x nitric oxide pollution and then my finger size I want to change as well.
So when I make it a bit bigger someone say peel T dot figure parentheses fix size equals parentheses
say maybe nine and six.
And then I'm also going to add a title here and I say PDT dot title parentheses single quotes yes versus
n0 X font size 14 we refresh this graph see what we get.
Okay so this makes the relationship between distance from employment centers and n0 X are nitric oxide
pollution much much more clear what we can see here is that as distance increases as we go more to the
right of this chart here pollution goes down and this makes sense right.
The city center of Boston is going to be an employment center but city centers would also have much
more air pollution than in the suburbs on the outskirts of the city.
Now one thing that might be quite interesting to add to this graph is a little bit of transparency on
these data points as well as the maybe putting down the correlation that we've calculated up here and
including that in our title.
So let's do that now to calculate the correlation.
I'm going to add a new X underscore DHS core variable set that equal to data square brackets and X dot
core parentheses data square brackets the IRS and then when I wanna do is in the title I'm going to
use this variable here and I mean I included in my string and I'm going to use python's f string notation
to accomplish this.
So when I put it f in front of the single quote and then I'm going to modify my string as follows I'm
going to say parentheses correlation and here's the key.
Curly braces n0 X underscore DHS on a score core.
So this is going to grab our variable from up here.
It's gonna grab our correlation between distance and pollution and it's going to inserted into our string.
And that's thanks to the effect that we have.
The curly bracket notation outside of the variable name and this little f in front.
So let me hit shift enter and see what this looks like.
What.
Now we've got a graphical representation of our data and the correlation.
All in one place and the correlation is indeed negative and it's quite high actually with zero point
seven seven now in terms of styling.
You might say to yourself you know what this number is way too precise.
It's difficult to read because it's got too many values after the decimal point.
So why don't we round it and we can do this with the python round function.
So I'm going to do it up here where I've actually calculated the correlation and I'm just going to surround
my correlation calculation with this python function so round comma at the end and then a value for
how many decimal places I want to round it to someone to run it to three decimal places and close my
parentheses at the end.
If a press shift enter now it should refresh and we should get something like this which should get
minus zero point seven six nine.
The other thing I quite like doing with scatter plots is adding a little bit of transparency to the
data points so that we can get a better feel for how dense particular areas of the chart are.
So in my line of code where I'm creating my scatter plot namely this one I'm going to add some other
keyword arguments.
The transparency is set with the alpha keyword and I'm going to set it to a value of zero point six.
It shift into and we can clearly see that there's a lot more data points here than over here.
I think this is a nice touch but we can make this even more explicit by changing the size of our dots
and making them a little bit larger.
So if I choose something like 80 s equals 80 as a keyword argument changing the size then I've got slightly
larger dots for my data points.
Now of course we can continue adding keyword arguments here to style the graph as we see fit famously
color and there's quite a few to choose from.
I'm going to go with indigo and give my scatter plot a purple make over hook.
So I think creating a counterpoint with my plot lib is pretty straightforward.
But now let's do the same thing with the Seabourn module to mix it up a little bit because remember
I said that Seabourn builds upon my plot lib.
Well you're gonna see in a minute how Seabourn really add some nice little touches to these visualizations.
Check this out.
So when it come down here a few more cells and then I'm going to write the following code.
I'm going to say S.A. dot joint plot so has an S being the name for Seabourn module and then joint blunt
being the function to create our scatter plot.
So there's a joint plant X equals data scrap rockets DHS and Y equals data square brackets and X and
then on the next line up with APL T dot show it shift into and what we get is something like this.
Now again I've only specified two parameters in my function call here but you can really see that there
is some sort of histogram on the side and there's some additional data being provided here in this corner.
Now if you can't read this on your screen this is actually the Pearson correlation coefficient down
to two decimal places minus zero point seven seven.
I can make the chart a little larger so that it's a bit more clear by going to the arguments and fighting
the sides argument.
Some of the signs equals seven increase the size a little bit but not too much.
Now you should see the chart appear a little bit larger on your screen but I think these histogram is
and the correlation coefficient and the fact that it adds some labels for the y axis and the x axis
automatically straight out of the box is a really really nice touch in terms of styling.
One thing that you might notice is that that the Jupiter notebook remembers how you've styled charts
previously.
So if you're working in a new cell and you want a new look for the chart you might have to reset the
styling the way to reset the styling for Seabourn is with a function called set.
So S.A. start set parentheses will reset the styling to the default styling.
So now if I press shift enter I get the default parameters for the styling and we kind of get this look
right here.
The set function is a good function to remember if you've ever got like a little bit of a longer notebook
that we've got here and you might have written some code up above.
That changes the styling of these charts and you want to do something different and you and your note
book is behaving a little bit unexpectedly so SNL starts that resets the styling to default and S.A.
dot set and the school style allows us to choose kind of like a template style to use for the chart.
So there's a couple of templates to choose from one of them is called white and then and this template
will make our chart look like so which is kind of what we had before.
But there's another template called white grid which then have these grid lines to the chart like so.
Now of course there's also like dark red and dark and pressing shift tab on this function will actually
show us what some of the options are dark grid dark dark white ticks.
Got a couple to choose from if we want and if you've got some examples on how you would use them.
So for example if you wanted to use ticks you can even provide the tick size as an additional argument.
All right.
So that's a little bit more detail on how you can control the aesthetics of your Seabourn chant in your
notebook.
But the last thing I want to mention is that there is an additional template that you can mix and match
with say white grid or dark grid and these templates are called contexts if you will.
So S.A. dot set underscore context parentheses will allow us to put in a template here for how does
charts gonna be used for example a context might be talk and if I use that then you can see that the
font size is a lot larger and the dots are a little bit more clear.
So this is presumably because you want to present this chart somewhere.
Now there's a couple of other contexts as well.
You can use notebook which will make the chart look like this.
This is a template that's quite good if you're viewing this kind of stuff on a monitor and you're not
having to throw it up on a screen or like a presentation and pressing shift enter on contexts shows
us that there's a couple of other options as well.
So there's paper they're supposed to and there's talk and notebook which we've already looked at.
I'm going to go with talk just to make it a little bit more readable on the video the very last thing
I want to mention on the styling front is how you can get the similar sort of transparency and the color
that we have here on Mac plot lib.
So I want to show you how you can set that by supplying certain arguments the color argument is pretty
straightforward.
So color indigo will give us a purple chart but when it comes to the transparency you have to supply
the argument in a different way because joint plant doesn't take an argument called Alpha that's only
for mad plot lip.
Instead you have to go to the keyword arguments so joint underscore kW us and then equals.
And here you provide a dictionary a Python dictionary so that uses the curly braces notation and then
a key value pair alpha for their key colon and then say zero point five for the value if I press shift
enter now we'll have the transparency applied to our data points.
So I hope you find it useful to see two different ways of generating this chart with different modules.
The first one that plot lib and the second one being seaborne.
Now there's a really cool thing I want to show you next.
And that's to do with the fact that this joint plant method sexually incredibly powerful.
So let me copy to sell and paste it below.
So I have two copies of it now and what I want to do is just for comparison I want to modify how these
data points are represented here.
So I'm going to go with a blue color to set them apart.
So I've got my blue one here purple one here.
And then what I want to do is want to show you this keyword argument that I'm going to change in the
quick documentation so pressing shift enter on joint plant shows us that this keyword argument kind
is set to scatter by default.
But there's other values that this can take for example KDE e r e.g. reserved and hex.
So we've actually got a choice between five different values.
Let me show you what one of them does.
I'm going to go ahead and delete this argument here where we've set our alpha value.
And if I press shift enter you can see that we no longer have any alpha values on our chart.
But if I come in here and I change the kind to hex so writing kind equals and then single quotes hex
and a head shift and we get the following We get a chart that looks like this and what this chart is
doing is that it's aggregating the data points that all fall in a certain area and then it shades them
in depending on how many data points there are in that particular sector so you're aggregating the data
points over like a little 2D area.
And again the shading gives us a very good idea of the density of the data points in that particular
part of the plot.
In other words we're aggregating the data in a hexagonal grid.
And I think this is a quite a beautiful visualization actually.
And it's one that you don't tend to see that often but it does remind me a little bit of a board game
called Settlers of Catan.
But maybe that's just me.