OK so we've talked about the model we're gonna use.
And we've talked about where the term regression actually came from.
Now it's time to write some python code.
One of the habits that I want us to get into when training our algorithms is to split up our dataset
into two parts.
We're going to shuffle all our data and divide our data set into a training data set and a testing dataset
set because we want our algorithm to learn those theta parameters based only on the training data set.
And this means that we can use the other part of our dataset that hasn't been used for testing because
with the testing data set we can see how our algorithm performs out of sample how it performs on a data
set that it hasn't seen yet.
Back in Jupiter notebook I'm going to add a markdown cell with this section heading that reads training
and test data set split go and in the cell below.
I'm going to create two more variables.
The first one is gonna be called prices and when I set that equal to data square brackets single quote
price so prices is going to hold on to our series of price data and then we'll have features which is
gonna be equal to data.
So our entire data frame then adopt a drop and then in the parentheses I'm going to have single quotes
price comma.
Axis equals 1.
What did I just do here.
I took our entire data data frame and I've dropped one column from it namely our target values and to
accomplish this I've used the drop method.
So this method will return a new data frame which I've stored in a variable called features.
But this data frame will not include the price column.
The second argument here access equals one is there to specify that we're looking to drop a column as
opposed to a row for a row you'd have access equals zero for a column.
Use access equals one to split up our dataset in our notebook.
We're going to make use of kids learn capabilities once more but we're going to have to import this
capability.
We're going to have to add an import statement at the very top.
I'm gonna add from SDK learn dot model and a school selection.
Import train under school test under school split.
That's all lower case from S.K. learn dot model on a school selection import train on the school test
on the school split.
Let me shift enter on the cell and then go back to where we left off.
Now this train underscored test on the school split function will actually return to us for values a
training and a testing data set for both our features and our targets.
So we'll have X train x test y train and Y test for values that are going to be returned from this function.
When a function returns multiple values the python syntax will use to store those values is called tuple
unpacking.
So let's create the variables that will hold on to the output from this function.
It's gonna be capital X underscore.
Train comma capital X on a school test comma lowercase y on a school train comma lowercase y on the
school test.
And that's gonna be set equal to train on a school test under school split parentheses so the function
itself.
And now all we have to do is provide some arguments to this function call.
So what arguments does this function need.
Well it has to know which features and which targets to shuffle and to split up.
So the first argument is gonna be are features variable which we've created above.
The second argument is gonna be our prices variable which we've created above.
The third argument is gonna be what kind of split that we want to make we want to make a 50/50 split.
Do we want to make a 60 40 split.
What kind of split do we want this function to make.
I'm gonna go with an 80 20 split so I'm going to say test on a scale size is equal to zero point two.
What this means is that our test data set is going to be 20 percent of the total.
How I could leave this function like this but I want to add one more argument.
And the reason is is that this function will shuffle and split the data.
However this shuffling is random right.
So my shuffle will be different from your shuffle.
If we want to get comparable results then we have to shuffle our data set in exactly the same way and
to ensure that you and I can do that.
Let's supply another argument.
The random state so going to see random underscore state is equal to and then we can pick a number as
long as we pick the same number.
We're gonna be good.
We're gonna get the same shuffling so I'm gonna pick 10 random state is equal to 10.
Let me come over here and hit enter on my keyboard so that my line doesn't get too long and wraps a
bit more nicely like this OK.
So there actually quite a lot going on in this line of code because we are shuffling all our data and
then splitting it up.
The thing about the shuffling is that there is a random number generator which will generate this randomness
and do the shuffling.
The last argument that we supplied here this random underscores state argument basically draws a line
in the sand to kind of set the starting point for the random number generator that does our shuffling
if you and I both have the same starting point.
Then we get the same shuffle.
Now a question you might ask is why shuffle the data.
What's the point.
And the answer to that is that sometimes when you get a fresh data set straight out of the box the data
is actually in a certain order.
Hey good analogy is a deck of playing cards.
Did you ever buy a new deck of playing cards or did you ever watch a magician perform a contract on
stage with a new deck.
When you take off the plastic wrap up on a deck of playing cards and you take the cards out of the box
and you look through them you'll notice that all the cards are in a certain order.
Now obviously this means that before playing a card game with this deck you have to shuffle the cards.
Otherwise you end up with a very very terrible game of poker.
In other words the cards dealt have to be random.
Otherwise it defeats the purpose and the same holds true for this training.
And our test data sets the rows over the data points that are allocated to these data sets have to be
random as well.
There can be a clear pattern in how the data points are allocated.
And that's why it's customary to shuffle any data set as well so customary in fact that our psychic
learns split function does the shuffling off our roads in our data frame automatically and why we use
this random state argument in the function call cool and just like that we've created an 80 20 split
with our data from our data frame.
But you don't have to take my word for it.
You can verify the 80 20 split yourself.
The percent of the training set will be the number of rows in X train divided by the total number of
rows in the data set as a whole.
We can calculate this using the length function so alien parentheses x on school train divided by alien
parentheses features we'll do this calculation and that is equal to zero point seven nine hate four.
So very very close to 80 percent.
If you wanted to calculate the percentage of the test data set.
So percent of test data set.
You could do the same thing.
You could get the number of rows in the test dataset and divide by the number of rows in the feature
data set.
Another way to get the number of rows is to say X underscore test dot shape and grab the first element
in the shape attribute.
That's the number of rows.
So X on a score test dot shape divided by features dot shape square brackets zero.
And that's equal to zero point two brilliant.