Now that we've shuffled and split our data into training and test data sets we can finally run our regression
using psychic learn to do that.
When we scroll back up and import this capability song and see from S.K. learn dumped linear on a school
model import Linear Capital L regression capital are all in one would net shift and turn on the cell
scroll back down where I left off and then I went to create a regression object called rigor set that
equal to linear regression parentheses at the end and then when I use this regression object and call
the fit method on it so rigour don't fit parentheses and now what do I add between these parentheses
Why do I give has an argument to our fit method
the data that we should supply is our training data sets right.
So X on a score train being the training features and y on a school train being the training target
values and hitting shift enter on this will train our model create but we don't see any output on the
theta is that we've just estimated and also we don't even know how well this model fits our data now
before printing out these values before printing out the values of our theta parameters let's make some
predictions on what we expect to see making these predictions is a very important step because it provides
a sense check on what the computer is kind of spit out to us we should never blindly trust the numbers
that we get back that's out silly city mistakes are made.
Besides we've done all this data exploration work up until now and we can use the knowledge that we
gained to make some predictions.
For example we've used seaborne spare plot to run individual regressions against our target prices.
Also we've created this wonderful correlation matrix to show the correlations of the individual features
with our target we know which correlations were positive and which correlations were negative.
So given that this is how our model looks like let's make some predictions on the signs of the coefficients
let's predict what kind of signs we're going to see on these theta parameters.
So get out a piece of paper and write down if you expect the theta parameter for our M to be positive
or negative and then do the same thing for n0 X Piti ratio crime distance and else that did you pause
the video and write this down.
There is actually one more prediction that we said would make.
Remember how a few lessons ago asked you if you thought that being next to the Charles River was a good
thing for property prices or a bad thing.
Well now it's time to also had your prediction to the sign of the chars dummy variable as well.
Okay.
So here's the solution to this challenge.
I want to print out the value of our intercept and it's gonna be regular dot intercept on the school
and then when to print out the values of all the coefficients and to format these values nicely I won't
actually put him in a data frame.
So going to see PD pandas right Dot data frame capital T capital F parentheses and then a first argument
is r data that we're gonna supply.
And these are the coefficients which we can find under regular dot com f underscore.
The second argument that we're going to supply is called index.
So index equals.
And then what.
When a supply as an index R the column names so X on a school train dot columns.
Yeah.
So these are the column names.
That way we can have the names of the coefficients next to the values.
Let me show you what this looks like.
Well I get something like this.
We can our intercept printed here and we get the name and the value of the different coefficients.
Now I'm going to come back up here in to the code where I'm creating our data frame and I'm going to
specify third argument called columns.
Yeah.
And I set that equal to square brackets and then single quotes QF when I hit shift enter now you'll
see this little zero here.
This the lack of a column name changed to the value code.
So columns equals and then a list of 1 value namely the string Clef will add a column name to our data
frame here.
All right.
So we've got our results.
How do they stack up to your predictions.
Remember we're just looking at the side of the coefficients here for now are the actual coefficients
positive or negative according to our model did you predict the right sign for the coefficients.
Because what we see here is that more crime is paid for house prices and also more pollution is bad
for house prices.
More rooms on the other hand is good for house prices.
It's a positive coefficient and more students in class is also a negative factor for the house prices
as is higher values for L stat how looking at this.
I think this is some really really good news because the signs of our coefficients past our first sense
check all these signs that we've just talked about.
Makes sense logically.
So the things that we would have expected to be bad for property prices from a logic point of view indeed
have a negative coefficient associated with them.
Oh a hand.
Do you remember how I asked you to make a prediction if living next to the Charles River was a good
thing or not.
Well now we've got our answer.
Looking at the sign on the chars variable we can see that living next to the Charles River is indeed
desirable and the properties that are on the river are more expensive than those that are are away from
it all else equal in fact we can put a number to it.
Bostonians are willing to pay a premium for a property that is next to the river and that premium is
equal to about two thousand dollars.
Remember Charles only has the values 0 or 1 when chance is equal to 1 then it's next to the river and
1 times approximately 2 is equal to 2 right.
Hence since our target values are property prices are in thousands.
This translates into two thousand dollars.
So what we've just done in Jupiter notebook is calculate all these theta parameters.
Our model now looks like this using our training data.
We've estimated all the values of these theta parameters and the beautiful thing about this linear model
is that all our coefficients have a very clear meaning an increase in the number of rooms by one will
increase the price of the property by three thousand one hundred dollars.
Our model is easy to understand and to interpret is the very opposite of a black box that just spits
out an answer.
And we don't know where it came from.