All right.
Welcome to the last lesson of this module.
In this lesson we're going to publish your Web site and deploy the machine learning model to the real
world.
We've done a lot of hard work and we've come a long way.
We've saved our tens or flow model from Jupiter notebook we've converted our tensor flow model to a
tensor flow J.S. then we styled and built our Web site and then we've pre processed our data from the
drawing canvas.
After that we made predictions using our train model based on what was drawn on the canvas.
And now we're on the final step publishing our Web site and putting it out there into the real world.
At the moment our Web site is still running on our local host.
So nobody other than us can actually access it for somebody other than us to actually see our hard work.
We need to host our Web site on somebody else's computer.
And that means hosting our Web site somewhere other than our local machine but hosting a Web site usually
costs money.
But lucky for us there are a handful of services that provide hosting for free.
One of these services that provides free hosting is.
Get up get up.
Pages in particular.
All we need to do is create a github account and upload our project files.
So what will our workflow look like.
It's gonna be a three step process.
Step one will be creating a repository.
Step two will be uploading our project files.
And step three will be to change the settings on our repository to publish our Web site.
And that's it at this point.
I will assume that you've already gone ahead and created your free account with GetUp GitHub if not
pause this video and sign up right now.
Once you've created your GitHub account you can create new repositories.
So just click on this plus sign and click new repository.
What's the repository.
Think of a repository as just a folder on GitHub computers.
This repository that you're creating right now is where the project files are going to go.
So let's give our repository a name maybe call it your first name hyphen math hyphen garden so this
name will show up in the your realm that you're going to get.
So choose wisely.
Next let's take a look at these options here.
Leave it as public but then tick initialize this repository with a read me.
Just take this little box here and then click Create repository.
Now we're ready to upload our project files and this couldn't be easier.
You can just click on this button here which says upload files and then you just drag and drop your
files over from your computer.
So bring up your windows explorer or your Mac finder.
And then just select all the files and folders in your project folder.
So this is going to be our index HDMI all your math thought J.S. all the files and then simply drag
them over on to get up to Web site and then you should see it upload and when it's done that will progress
Marshall disappear.
So that puts us in a position to actually save our changes.
Saving and updating files on github is a little bit more involved than usual because github is actually
tracking all of these files with the files being tracked every time we save our changes.
We're essentially creating a checkpoint.
And that means in future we can go back and forth between all of these different checkpoints.
In other words we can go back and forth between different versions of our project.
So every time we save our changes we commit our changes and we create a checkpoint.
That's why it's a great idea to add a little descriptive message here say adding initial project files
that way we can take a look at these messages if we ever need to go back to the safe point on the radio
button below leave committed directly to a master branch ticked and then click commit changes after
a few seconds you should see that GetUp has finished processing the files and we can go and change the
settings to actually publish our Web site once all your files are processed.
You should see a page like this.
So now we can go to the settings of this repository of him and then we can scroll down to where it says
getup.
Pages.
This is the toggle where we go and publish our Web site.
So at the moment him we have get a pages is currently disabled in order to publish our Web site.
All we need to do is click here where it currently says none and then select master branch at this point.
The website will update and appear ill say Get up.
Pages source saved and scrolling down what you should now see is a message here that says your site
is ready to be published at.
And then here is your getup username.
And then here's your repository name.
Now publishing a Web site with GitHub pages can take a little while.
So you might just grab a coffee and come back in a few minutes.
But after a few minutes what you should be able to do is you should be able to click on this link and
your Web site will actually load at this point.
It's been published successfully.
And when you refresh this page here with the settings and you scroll down then instead of having that
blue message here you should now see this little tick mark.
And then you should see your Web site is published and then your your URL right here.
Now if you don't like having this your RL here and you want a custom your URL then you can actually
add a custom domain name right here.
However this is not a free service.
This is something you'd have to pay for.
So you'd have to separately go to a domain registrar like GoDaddy or name cheap and actually buy a domain
from them.
And once you've bought the domain from this other company then you can actually enter that here and
you can change the URL of your project and that's all there is to it.
So well done on completing this module.
I know it was quite a challenging module with a lot of moving parts but now you know how you can deploy
a machine learning model and make it do real work in the real world.
I would actually love to see your work by the way.
So if you've completed this project and you've created your GitHub repository and you've published it
then go ahead and share a link in the comments section below this lesson.
Until next time I'll see you on the next module.
Take care.