SO UH SPEAKING OF DATA let's create some data for our example.
A lot a few more cells here so that I'm working more in the middle of the screen and then I'm gonna
add a comment say make sample data and then create two variables here and X underscore five variable
and a Y underscore five variables.
That's our fifth example.
After all our accents go five it's gonna be equal to a num PIRA so end p dot array parentheses and then
square brackets.
And I want to punch in here seven values.
So if you type in something else then we're gonna get different results.
But I want to punch in one point one comma one point to two point four three point two four point one
five point seven and six point five.
So these are gonna be our X values.
Seven of them in total are y values.
So y underscore five.
It's gonna be equal to also an empty array.
Same thing parentheses square brackets and here.
Gonna punch in one point seven comma two point four three point five three point zero six point one
nine point four and eight point two.
So hard to erase and let's print out the shape of these arrays below.
So once a print shape of X underscore five array colon comma it's gonna be X on the score five thought
shape and we're gonna do the same thing for our y array.
When I fix my typo shape and then I'm going to do the same thing for our wiry when it's a print and
then add a string shape of Y on it's got five array colon comma Y underscore five dot shape.
So let's take a look at the shape of these arrays.
So they're both flattened meaning they only have one dimension and they've got seven values.
Brilliant.
So there's our fake sample data and we've added our print statements.
Now let's fit a linear regression to this sample data.
That way we can calculate the intercept and the slope parameter and we can check our work that we're
gonna do against what we know to be correct.
So to scroll to the very very top of the file where you're adding your input statements and then in
the cell add from S.K. learn dot linear on a scale model.
Import linear regression capital L.
Capital r remember to hit shift enter and then scroll back down to where you left off and let's run
a quick regression to get a comment.
Quick linear regression we're gonna run it like so we're gonna see our e.g. our rigger is equal to linear
regression capital L of capital R parentheses at the end and then we're gonna see rigor don't fit then
we're gonna supply two arguments within the parentheses x underscore five and then comma and then Y
on the school five.
So these are two arrays are two pieces of data.
Now let's see what happens.
Because I'm going tell you right now this isn't gonna work just like that when we had shift enter.
We can scroll down and take a look at the arrow what we get is a value arrow found input variables with
inconsistent number of samples one comma seven.
So that's a very cryptic error message but let's take a look at the quick documentation for this fit
method and see what we need.
So.
So our fit method takes an X and Y.
So the X is our training data and the Y are our target values.
Now the interesting thing to note here is that this method requires a two dimensional input.
So at the moment our shape of our x ray and our y array is actually one dimensional it's just got seven
values in it.
But we can see here that this method requires a two dimensional inputs.
It needs to know how many samples and how many features.
Now we've got only one feature right.
We've only got some x values but we still have to pay attention to the kind of array that we're giving.
So even though we've only got one feature namely our Xs we still have to pass in a two dimensional array
and the same is true for our wise.
So even though we're only predicting one value namely the y value we still have to pass in a two dimensional
array.
So let's go back up here and take a look at where we're creating these arrays.
We're going to have to add some additional Python code to reshape or transform our x's and our y array
to meet this requirement from our fit method from our regression.
I'll show you two possible ways we can solve this problem.
Here's the first one for our axis.
If I add another pair of square brackets inside the parentheses and then I put a dot afterwards and
write transpose yeah with parentheses at the end and shift into.
Then you'll see in the print statement that our X array now is two dimensional.
It's got seven rows and one column.
So this is one way you can take a one dimensional array which was just seven values and make it into
two dimensions even though it's only got one column two pairs of square brackets and then calling the
transpose method another way you can accomplish the very very same thing is by using a method called
reshape.
So writing don't reshape and then in the parentheses I'm going to supply how many rows I want seven
comma and then how many columns I want namely 1 7 rows one column.
Let me hit shift enter and update the shape of our y array.
What.
I get exactly the same result.
So two ways you can do it.
Now with that in place I'm going to click into our cell below where we're we're doing our regression
and I'm going to shift into and what are our error goes away.
So we've managed to fit our regression perfectly.
Now what are we actually interested in.
We're interested in the theta values right.
The Intercept and our slow parameter theta zero and theta one.
Let's print this out.
When I put a print statement here and with the string theta zero colon comma record dot intercept under
school square brackets zero.
That's how we got our intercept our theta zero and then I'm going to add another print statement theta
space one colon comma record dot co f c o e f underscore and this was two dimensional remember.
So we had square brackets zero and then another square brackets with a zero.
So first column first row of this two dimensional coefficient array and if I had shift into we can see
what the values are heart intercept is at zero point eight five approximately and our theta one our
slope has the value one point to approximately.
So now that we have the parameters that describe our best fit line let's throw them up on screen because
I'm a very very visual person and I'm sure it'll help you as well.
Someone had a few more cells scroll down and now let's plot this stuff first let's plot our data points
to this.
We can do with a scatter plot so P.L. T dot scatter then in the parentheses we'll have X underscore
five y underscore five and then size for these points maybe at 50.
So that's our scatter plot and now we'll add our best fit line between these points.
So I'll write appeal T dot plot parentheses x underscore 5 x values and then for our y values the predicted
values I'm going to write regular which is our linear regression.
Then don't predict and then then the parentheses are going to supply again the x values.
So I'm going to predict the y values based on the x values.
I make this line orange.
So I'm going to see color is equal to Orange and maybe the line width is equal to three.
Let's add some labels as well.
So appeal T dot X label.
It's gonna be the string x values and peel T dot y label.
It's gonna be the string y values.
Last but not least BLT dot show parentheses.
Now let's take a gander what this looks like.
Well I predict here we can clearly see our data points and the best fit line.
Nothing new so far but I quickly want to mention something quite important and that's to do with a difference
in notation that we're gonna be using in this example than in the previous examples.
You see this isn't the cost function that we're looking at.
This is the best fit line and the data the plots that we've been running previously have been the cost
functions and we're going to be plotting the mean square error shortly.
Now the cost functions plot the relationship between the parameters that we're trying to estimate and
how far off we were from the actual data.
So the cost functions don't plot the actual data itself.
That regression line right here.
This graph that's plotting the data.
It's a function of x and y and not the theta parameters theta zero and theta one that we're gonna be
interested in and looking at for our cost function.
And the reason that I'm mentioning this is that previously we've been using x and y for our cost function
parameters because that's how we tend to learn about mathematics in school and functions.
And it's quite a comfortable sort of notation but when looking at this cost function that's coming up.
It's kind of depend on the theta values and the theta values are not our X's and Y's so just keep that
in mind X and score 5 and Y underscore 5.
In this example have a different purpose than the data that we generated in the previous lesson.