Now that we've defined and formulated our question it's time to gather the data.
So let's have a think about the kind of data that we're looking to gather.
First off we need data on our feature namely the movie budgets in U.S. dollars.
The second thing that we need is data on our target namely the movie revenue in US dollars.
So where would we go about finding this kind of data.
Well lucky for us there exists a Web site called the numbers and their slogan is what data and the movie
business meet.
This sounds perfect for our project.
So let's check it out.
So this is what the website looks like.
If we go to movies budgets and finances then we get the performance records of various films and they've
even got some tables here on some common searches are common questions that people might be interested
in.
For example they've got the biggest budget films right here.
And if we scroll down they've got the movies with the lowest budgets to earn one million dollars at
the U.S. box office.
And I think a notable film here is El Mariachi which apparently only had a production budget of seven
thousand dollars but made about two million in the U.S. box office.
If we click on this link here where it says the complete list then we get the entire table of all the
films in the database right here.
And this table is actually enormous.
It's very very long.
There's quite a few different entries here.
And what I've done is I've selected all of these and I've copy pasted them into a spreadsheet now to
save you this kind of tedious work.
I've made a huge v file available under the lesson resources.
All you have to do is download it and open it in excel or in google sheets.
And once you open this file what you should see is the movies sorted by their rank.
So please Number one we've got Avatar then a Star Wars film then Pirates Of The Caribbean.
All of these films are sorted by their production budget.
So column D and if we scroll down then we can see that there's a lot of entries in this file.
As a matter of fact there's about 5000 entries in this CSP file.
So this completes our data gathering step and we can move on to the next part of the workflow namely
cleaning the data.
So let's take a closer look at what we've actually got.
If I scroll down here then I can see there's a lot of numbers but occasionally we might spot something
a little bit odd.
For example here in columns f we have two big fat zeros scrolling up.
I can see these are the columns for worldwide gross and domestic gross and yet this movie entitled singularity
with a production value of 175 million dollars has zero revenue.
And the reason for this might be found in this column our second column here.
What we have here is the projected release date.
So end of 2020 is when this movie is due to be released according to this dataset.
And what they've done is they've put a place holder of zero into these two columns instead of for moving
this movie entirely.
They've included it in the data set with one hundred and seventy five million dollars production budget
but because it hasn't made any revenue to date they've added some zeros here.
Now this might actually be a little bit of a problem for us because we're looking to make a prediction
for our movie revenue.
And if our dataset is going to be include films that have not been released yet and have big fat zeros
for the revenue it might make our estimates a little bit unreliable.
Right.
So one thing that might actually be worth doing is checking how many films out of the five thousand
three hundred actually have a revenue of zero.
And we can do this by sorting by worldwide gross.
If I select my data here and then open the menu and then go to Data sort range then I can actually sort
by column number E.
And since we don't want to include that first row in the sort I'm just going to tick this box here and
then click sort and what we see here is that there's quite a few films that have a zero entry for worldwide
gross and domestic gross.
Now why might that be.
Well for some of them the release date is in the future but looking at this column we see that not every
film that has a 0 here is due to be released in the future.
So for example this one here Black Water Transit was supposedly released at the end of 2008 and this
film also has a big fat zero in worldwide gross why might that be.
Now one possible answer is looking at the description of the Web site.
So if we go here then we see this line that data to the best of our knowledge is accurate.
But there are gaps and disputed figures.
So some of these zeros might be gaps.
It might just be that the data is incomplete for some films but I've actually looked up this Blackwater
transit film and on Wikipedia I can see that in post-production there were actually quite a few lawsuits
and there was quite a lot of back and forth between the production company and the filmmakers and the
producers and so on.
So this film actually never got released and this release date here of end of 2008 was probably a planned
release date but the movie actually never came out.
Now this might be something that happened to quite a few of these films and there might have a 0 for
various other reasons too.
But this poses a big problem for our analysis if we're looking to predict movie revenue based on the
budget then having these zero entries here is going to be a problem.
So what I would suggest given that some of these films were probably not released other ones the data
might not be available is that we should actually exclude the films that have zero here for worldwide
gross and domestic gross.
We should select all of these entries and delete them from our dataset.
So if I come down here to row 358 and scroll all the way up then I can select all of these rows I can
right click and I can delete the rows.
We're going to exclude these rows from our analysis.
The next thing that we're going to do is we're actually going to have to do some calculations and these
involve the production budget and the worldwide gross.
These other columns we're actually not going to use.
We're not going to use the domestic rows.
We're not going to use the movie title or the rank or the release date.
So what I would suggest is that as part of the data cleaning process we're going to delete these entire
columns.
So going to delete these columns and we're going to delete this column right here.
That way we can trim our spreadsheet to what actually matters for our analysis.
The next thing that we need to do is we need to have a think about these special characters that might
be in the dataset and by special characters I mean anything other than a number.
So we're gonna be doing some calculations with all of this data and those calculations might be troubled
by the fact that there's a dollar sign here or a comma.
This type of formatting could cause problems.
So it's better to remove it and have a pure number in these cells rather than all this extra stuff.
And the way that we can format all these numbers and get rid of these symbols is by selecting the columns
going to format number and then scrolling down which says more formats and going to custom number format.
And here we can pick the second one down which is this decimal number and click apply.
Now we've got no more dollar signs in our columns so we're almost done cleaning our data.
The last thing I'm going to do is I'm going to rename my column headings.
And the only reason I'm doing that is because I'm going to remove spaces and these custom symbols here
the parentheses and the dollar signs from the headings to make our lives a little bit easier on I find
that as soon as I have special symbols or white spaces in my headings I make a lot more typos when I've
referred to particular columns.
So for this one I'm just gonna call this production underscore budget underscore USD and this one here
I'm going to call world wide underscore gross underscore USD with these two names for a headings I've
got very expressive headings and yet there's no whitespace and there's no special characters.
This will make our life a little bit easier to underline.
So in summary for the data cleaning what we've done is we've looked for missing data we've looked for
incomplete data we've looked for in accurate data and we've done some tidying up by checking the formatting
of our data in detail.
And the reason we've done all of this is so that we don't have problems when we provide this data to
our machine learning algorithm down the line.
Now we can move on to the next step which is exploring and visualizing our data.
Mind you if we spot any more problems during this next step we might have to do a little bit more cleaning
as well.
So you'll find that very often in practice you're going to be doing the cleaning and the exploration
side by side.
I'll see you in the next lesson.
Take care.