So now that we've talked a bit about machine learning it's time to tackle a closely related topic and
also a big part of this course.
Data science data science is another one of those terms that gets thrown around a lot.
But what does it actually mean.
At it's hot data science is about turning data into value.
But let's take a look at how it came to be in the 1980s.
IBM came out with the first relational database storing things like customer details or company payroll
data.
And soon after we started thinking about what useful things we can mined from the data and the term
data mining was coined in a paper called from data mining to knowledge discovery in databases published
in 1996.
It defines data mining as the application of specific algorithms for extracting patterns from data let's
think about that extracting patterns from data.
We're going to see a lot more of that in the course.
Up until now a lot of those patterns were being extracted with plain old statistics but we're now in
the 1990s when computer science was progressing at crazy speeds.
So a lot of people were looking into levelling up data mining with computer science and they used the
term data science to refer to this new field as the dot com era exploded.
There were more and more data being generated and these days every click every scroll every time you
open an app.
Huge amounts of data are being generated and collected.
Why business intelligence.
If you were a retailer wouldn't it be cool if you could predict when somebody was pregnant and then
market to them.
The things that you sell to new parents well this is exactly what Target did.
They collected data on people's purchases and then based on what they bought they could use data science
to predict whether somebody was pregnant or maybe you've seen the movie Moneyball the story of how a
poor baseball team used data science to pick undervalued players which changed their fate from a losing
team to win 20 consecutive games the longest in American League's history.
How did they do it.
Data science data science is a broad term so broad that the Journal of data science defines it as almost
everything that has something to do with data.
So most people think of data science as taking huge amounts of data or tapping into big data and performing
machine learning or using A.I. to get important insights.
But data science is actually much more than that.
Just as humans need food and water before they can start thinking about shelter or what is the meaning
of life in the data science Hierarchy of Needs a company first needs to be able to collect and store
their data before they can even start thinking about getting meaning out of it.
And in a large company that's usually done by data engineers.
The role of the data scientist is to then take this data clean it explore it visualize it and then apply
intelligent algorithms to start answering questions with the data in the upcoming modules will be embarking
on projects that traverse all the layers that are the responsibility of the data scientist and the machine
learning expert in every module will try to solve a real world problem by first understanding how to
clean segment and visualize raw data.
We can then learn to apply shallow and deep learning algorithms to extract meaning from the data.
Algorithms like linear regression Bayes classification and deep learning with neural networks.
Also we're going to learn how to use tools like tensor flow Python Charisse panders and num pi to solve
our data problems problems like movie revenue prediction spam classification and image recognition.
There's a lot packed into this course.
So what are you waiting for.
Let's get started.