The first topic that we're going to talk about on the evaluation front is this topic of data transformations.
Let's take another closer look at the values that we're trying to predict.
Our target values the property prices.
Check out this histogram.
This is what we plotted earlier.
Now what we see here is that there are quite a few very very expensive properties on the right hand
side of this graph.
There's a bunch of properties in the right tail of this distribution.
And here's what a normal distribution looks like in comparison the normal distribution has very very
few occurrences in the tails.
And here's the thing.
Having more data points in one of the tails is called a skew our distribution of house prices is skewed
to the right.
Now we can actually put a number to the skew.
We can measure the skew of our target values.
Let's add a markdown cell to the section and combine right.
What we're going to do when I write down data transformations that we go to calculate the skew of our
target values.
All we have to do is grab our price series data square brackets price put a dot after it and call the
SKU method hitting shift enter.
We see that this SKU is one point one.
Now what does that mean and how does that compare to a normal distribution.
Well a normal distribution is completely symmetrical right.
The right tail and the left tail are exactly the same size.
So the skew of a normal distribution is equal to zero and this leads me to think that there's something
that we can try to improve our model.
We can try transforming our price data and then running our regression.
Now what I mean by transforming our data well a transformation would be something like multiplying all
the prices by two or dividing all the prices in half.
A transformation would be applying some sort of calculation to all the prices in the dataset.
However dividing or multiplying our prices isn't the transformation that I have in mind.
I want to do something to our prices that will shift our distribution.
I want to do something that will affect our large house prices in the tail more than the rest.
And to accomplish this I will use a log transformation on our property prices.
And so that means that if one of the target values one of the prices is equal to the value 7 then the
log of this price is equal to one point nine five.
And you can calculate this simply by grabbing a calculator and using the Alan function on that thing.
But here's the interesting part.
If a property price is listed as 50 so some of the highest values that we have in our data set then
the long price of this property would now be equal to three point nine one.
Thus with the log transformation achieves is you get a small change of around five in the small price
of seven but you get a large change of around forty six for the large values in the dataset.
Now a very reasonable question to ask is Why does this matter.
Why why should you care.
Well we have to remember that what we're doing here is we're fitting a linear model to our data.
So say we have some data that's distributed like so distributed like this.
If you were to try to fit a line to this data a straight line you don't tend to get a very good fit.
But if you were to transform this data using the log transformation then those blue dots would line
up like so and then you could fit a linear regression very very easily and you'd get a very very good
fit so in other words based on the skew that I've seen in the distribution I want to try transforming
our data and then fitting the linear regression.
Now one thing I'm noticing is I've actually got a typo here in my notebook title should read multi variable
regression not multivariate regression.
There you go.
OK.
So how do we apply a log transformation to our target values.
Well what we could do is write something like from math import log and use the log function from the
math module.
However this log function from the math module doesn't particularly enjoy being applied to an entire
data series.
Lucky for us number pi actually solve this problem for us.
We can access the log function through number pi so N.P. dot log parentheses data square brackets single
quotes price will transform our entire series of prices into log prices.
I'm going to create another variable called Y underscore log and set that equal to the output of num
PIs log function let's take a look at what y underscore a log actually looks like so y underscore locked
on the head we'll show you the first few values and they look something like this and Y underscore long
tail will show me the last couple of values and they look something like this.
So what we saw here was that this log transformation was applied successfully to the entire data series.
We now have the logs of the property prices stored in a variable called Y on the school log.
Now I can already hear you asking the question well where can we see the benefit of using log prices.
And I think that's a really really good question.
We're going to look at three things.
First off let's look at the skew of the distribution of the log prices.
So why on a school log don't skew parentheses well output minus zero point three three.
So that's nice with the skew of minus zero point three three.
We're a lot closer to zero than with a skew of one point one.
But what does this distribution look like graphically.
Let's pull up our old friend S.A. dumped this plot parentheses y underscore log PDT dot title parentheses
f single quotes log price with SKU curly braces y underscore log dot SKU next line PDT dot show here
we're using C borns this plot function and we're feeding in our log prices we're gonna give this will
chart a title and has an argument we're feeding in an F string I've misspelled price I'm going to fix
that now so our f string will take this part here that's in between the curly braces and actually calculate
the SKU.
So this bit here will show minus zero point three three and then we're showing our chart.
Let me shift enter see what this looks like.
Well now this distribution already looks a lot more symmetrical and with that SKU being a lot closer
to zero it also definitely is a lot more symmetrical we can actually see this difference very very clearly
when we look at these two charts side by side.
Now I see this transformation worked really really well from this point of view.
Now having looked at the SKU a good question as well can we visualize how does transformation makes
our data more linear graphically.
And the answer is yes but it's a little hard to see.
It's a little hard to make out on real data.
You're just not going to get a graph that's clear as day as this kind of hypothetical example.
The biggest difference that you'll actually be able to spot just by inspecting it is on a plot of property
prices versus the else that feature.
So using Seaborne with S.A. and then dot l m plot will give us our scatter plot with a regression line
and this scatter plot is going to have on the x axis.
It's gonna have El stunt the L start feature on the y axis with y equals as the second argument it's
gonna have price.
So we're gonna compare our non log prices and then log prices afterwards as a third argument we're gonna
give our data as a fourth one we're gonna see size equals seven to make that thing a bit larger as the
fifth document I'm going to add some transparency to our data points with scatter underscore kW S equals
and then a dictionary.
Curly braces single quotes Alpha colon zero point six and then I'm gonna add a colored regression line
so that I can do with line underscore score kW US is equal to another dictionary.
Single quotes color colon and I'm gonna go for dark red.
Dark red.
There we go.
I'm gonna spread this over two lines and then I'm going to go with Peel t dark show and head shift into
today.
This here is a larger version of something we've already seen in our plot a little bit earlier and one
thing that you can see is that this regression line doesn't fit the data maybe as well as it could just
by looking at this.
We can see that the relationship between El stat and price might not be a linear one.
But what about our log prices.
Then we take the cell copy it paste it and then I'm going to change the color to cyan and what I'm going
to do now is I'm going to create a new variable in your data frame.
Call it trends formed on the score data and I'm going to set it equal to say features which we've created
up here.
Her features variable was equal to our data frame minus that price column.
So we're gonna reuse that down here and then what we'll do is we're going to add another column to the
transformed underscored data data frame.
And when I call that column single quotes a low g underscore price all caps.
And that's gonna be equal to y on a score log which we've created up here.
So we can reuse this variable as well.
Okay so we've created a new data frame and it has all the features and our lock price and in our elem
plot function we're going to feed in the transformed data
on the y axis.
We're gonna be plotting log on the graph price.
So the log price column from The transformed data data frame so lets it shift enter and see what we
get Tara so here's our log price versus l stand.
And here is our um transformed normal price versus l stand now.
We can see somewhat of an improvement based on this particular scatter plot but trying to spot the differences
visually against all the individual features isn't really all that useful.
What we really want to do is we want to rerun our regression and see the combined effect of using log
prices instead of the standard prices.
The thing to note is that now we've got a different model right.
We're actually going to be changing our regression model.
We're gonna be using log prices instead of normal prices.
So our previous equation looked like this and our new equation will look like this.
And because it's a very different model that we're using all the theta values will in fact change and
the interpretation will also be taking into account that a unit change in say distance or the number
of rooms now reflects the change in the log price.
So that's just something to be aware of.
Let's see this in action.
I'm going to come up here in our notebook where we were splitting our dataset.
A copy this cell and then I'm going to paste it down here the first thing I want to do is going to change
this line of code.
I'm going to say prices is equal to end p dot log parentheses data square brackets price.
So here we're using log prices.
Now when it comes to shuffling and splitting our data set the next thing I want to do is I want to delete
this line of code and I want to come back up here while we're running our regression.
I'm going to copy these cells come down here.
Paste them in delete this comment and then this cell here and change to markdown.
Put two hash tags there and I'll write down regression using log prices.
And now I'm going to hit shift enter here and this is the output that we'll get.
So the question is how do we interpret this.
Let's look at the r squared values.
First the ask what on our training data is zero point seven nine.
This is an increase actually from before before we had zero point seven five.
And we also see an increase on the testing data here.
The value went from zero point six seven to zero point seven four.
So the performance of our model improved on both counts and based on this it makes me think that our
little data transformation experiment was a success reducing the skew in our distribution of target
values allowed us to improve our model and as a result we have a higher r squared and a better fit but
also said that the interpretation of the parameters has changed.
Previously the coefficient for the Charles River dummy variable was around 2 so people were willing
to pay two thousand dollars more to live close to the river.
Now the coefficient on the Charles River a dummy variable is zero point zero eight.
In order to figure out how much more people are willing to pay to be close to the river according to
this model what we have to do is reverse the log transformation because not even mathematicians think
in log prices when they go to the supermarket so let's see what this value translates into using actual
dollar prices.
When a copy of this whole thing and in this sell down here can add a comment.
Charles River property premium.
And in this cell I'm going to reverse the law calculation so we can see what the dollar value is now
as a math refresher.
The way that the log transformation worked was we took the log of our prices.
So if the price was twelve then the lock price would be equal to two point four eight five approximately.
To reverse this transformation we have to raise Oilers number which is approximately two point seven
to the power of two point four eight five.
And then we get back our starting log prices.
So this is how we're going to reverse that calculation.
We need to get hold of this number.
E And we can get hold of this number.
E through num pi and P don't e will give us access to this irrational number and with times times we
can raise e to the power of zero point 0 8 0 4 7 5.
Our coefficient.
Now we can see how to interpret this coefficient and what our new model is telling us is that people
are willing to pay approximately 1000 and eighty four dollars more to live close to the river.
Okay so that was quite a big lesson.
Quite a lot going on through a process of transforming our target values.
We've created a whole new regression and this new and improved regression fits our data set even better
but because we're now working with log prices in our model our interpretation of these coefficients
has also changed in order to get back the changes in the dollar values.
We have to reverse the log transformation when it comes to actually interpreting the meaning of our
coefficients and speaking of coefficients in the next lessons we're gonna be looking at them in more
detail.
We're going to be evaluating our coefficients and looking at their significance their p values.
I'll see you there.