Now it's time to apply the cleaning and tokenization to all the five thousand eight hundred messages.
But before we jump right into that we have to review and practice a few key skills and that involves
slicing data frames and creating subsets.
But not only that we have to find a way to call our clean messages function on all the e-mail bodies
stored in our data frame.
When I change a cell to mark down and quickly commemorate what we're doing we're going to apply cleaning
and token station to all messages but before we dive into cleaning 5800 email bodies It'll be handy
to review these techniques for slicing pandas state of frames and series.
So I'm going to add a little subheading here that reads
slicing data frames and series and creating subsets.
Okay.
So recently we've used the ad attribute to select a particular cell or a scalar from our data frame.
This was a very efficient way of accessing a particular entry in the data frame and the way this ad
attribute worked was that we had to specify both an index name and a column name.
Now I realize the column name has a string and the index name here is a number but that's because we've
given our index a numerical value him.
The important thing to remember is that the act attribute works of names if you'd like to work off a
position say it position one position to position three then there is an alternative attribute that
you can use instead.
Let me show you what I mean.
If we say data don't I at square brackets and then 2 and then 1 we get the entry at position number
2 and column number 1 calling them row 1.
In this case is our messages column calling them 0 was our category column.
Column number 2 is our filing column.
So with that you're working off a name to get a particular entry.
And with I add you're working off a location or a position.
This is very very useful for selecting a single message or a single entry in the data frame especially
if you're working in a loop or your code is iterating over a certain part of your data frame with a
numerical value.
This I add attribute will make your life a lot easier than the ad attribute which works off the names.
Now what if you wanted to select a subset of the data frame instead.
What if you wanted to select more than one value more than one row.
For example in this case you can use the eye ELO See I LOC attribute.
So this is data dot I L O C square brackets 0 and then a colon and then 2.
This code here will select the first two entries in our data frame the first two rows if you will if
I hit shift enter we can see what they are.
We wanted to select the first five rows then we would simply substitute the five for a two and here's
the challenge.
What would you put in between the square brackets if you wanted to select the entries with darker I.D.
5 6 7 8 9 and 10.
Why would just apply here.
In that case you would go for five colon eleven and that's because the first entry is at index 0.
How the nice thing about this I like attribute is.
It works both on data frames as well as series.
So if I had only a single column selected save data dot message I could still use this attribute I ELO
C square brackets and select only the first three entries in this series.
This is very very handy for creating or selecting a subset.
So now that we've covered this let's move on to the next question.
Say we want to try out our clean message function on the first three emails out of the five thousand
eight hundred order emails.
How would we do it.
Well step 1 is selecting these email bodies of course.
And we've done that right here.
Step two is using the pandas.
Apply function.
Now I absolutely love this function.
This is this genius say we store these three entries in a series called it first emails that equal to
data dot message Dot.
I log 0 to 3 and then we can take this series
put a doctorate you use apply parentheses and then supply the name of our function which was clean under
school school message note there is no parentheses after clean on the school message or supplying just
the name of our function to the apply method which we're calling on our series object here.
Let's see what happens what we get back.
It's kind of a list of lists we've got all the woods in a list split out for our first e-mail.
Same thing with our second e-mail.
And again we've cut all the words split out for our third e-mail as well.
If you're curious what kind of type of object we're dealing with here can take a look by just wrapping
this in the type function and you see that you still are working with a series.
So that's good.
That's really really interesting.
Now I'm gonna give this thing a name.
I'm going to call it nested on a school list and I'm going to set it equal to the output from this apply
function.
I'm calling it a nested list because effectively f almost got like a list of lists write each individual
entry in my a series here is a list but here's a question What if I wanted just one list of words what
if I didn't want a list of lists let me hit shift enter on this
in create an empty list here and then just write a for loop write a nested one probably after go over
all the items in the list first so I'll see sub list in nested list that's my first part of my loop
and then my second part of my loop the inner loop I'll say for item in sub list the outer loop goes
over all the lists and the inner loop goes over all the individual words in each sub list put a colander
and then say flat list dot append parentheses item that will pretty much do the job so if I wanted to
check with the length of this flat list is then I can use only n parentheses flat list let's see what
we get three hundred and ninety.
Right so that's three hundred ninety words now in a single list if we wanted to take a peek what it
looks like and it looks like this it's just all the email words in one big list and you know this is
certainly one way of doing it but let me show you an alternative.
Let me show you how this would look like with something called Python list comprehension.
So when a comment all of this out if you select the text like me and then press control forward slash
this is the shortcut for commenting out and tie a block of code if you're on a Mac of course you'll
be command forward slash but for everybody else control forward slash the python list comprehension
syntax for accomplishing exactly the same thing as with these two nested loops looks like this.
So still use flat list as my variable and I'll have square brackets and then I'm basically going to
move my loop inside these two square brackets I'll see item
sub list in nested list for item in sub list.
This year you'll recognize as the outer loop for sub list in nested list.
And this here you'll recognize as the inner loop for item in sub list.
This first bit of code is what appends the item to the list.
Let's see what happens when I've run this again.
I in fact get the exact same result.
So now you've got another application of this python list comprehension syntax.
You can often use it instead of nesting these for loops how you've probably put two and two together
on how to call are clean messages function on all the five thousand eight hundred odd items we're gonna
do something very very similar to what we did a minute ago.
We'll create a nested list and we'll set it equal to data dot message dot apply parentheses clean message
no HMO this here will use apply on all the messages in the data frame now before I hit shift enter and
execute this code I'll use a little bit of Jupiter magic I'll put 2 percent signs here and then use
that keyword time and what this will do is it'll spit out how long this computation will take.
So this is kind of like a little bit of a benchmarking tool for looking at the performance of your python
code.
It'll also help you see just how long it takes for my code to execute on my computer and you can compare
this to your own.
The first thing I'm seeing here is that our beautiful soup package seems to think that we're trying
to open a web site.
Now this is definitely not the case.
So this user warning is a little bit unnecessary.
Our code still working nothing's breaking but this is something that beautiful soup has included in
their code as a suggestion for people who are looking to open Web sites.
The other thing that you can see is that in order to apply this function to a whole might five thousand
eight hundred odd messages is that my computer ran for like a good minute.
It got there in the end but a 10 minute lead did some work.
So let's check out the head of our nested list.
Let's look at the first few lines looks good.
What about the tail.
The last few lines.
Brilliant.
That also looks good.
Nothing unexpected.