So hit our Jupiter notebook.
Let's investigate how wrong and how useful our house price model is and will commemorate this with a
new section heading changes to mark down here.
And put two hash tags there and write residuals and residual lots.
And now what I'm going to do is I'm going to take some of our existing code and just copy it below.
We're going to reuse themselves but modify them a little bit.
So I'm going to take this cell right here.
Copy it scroll down and paste it in and I'm going to add some comments here.
I call this one modified model transformed using log prices and simplified
dropping two features.
Now just because I put that in the comment doesn't mean we've actually done it.
So I'm going to come here and on this line.
We're not just going to drop the price when it put some square brackets around price then a comma and
then we'll drop to other features that we had earlier industry and age.
Now let me come in here and delete this part of the code when I hit shift enter.
And now when I add another comment here that reads using stats model so instead of our psyche learn
we're to continue using stats model here for analyzing our residuals next.
I'm going to come up here take these three lines of code copy them and paste them in here
okay.
So now we're all set up for this lesson.
Now we can start looking at our residuals.
It's when I add a comment here we said the residuals are equal to the difference between our observed
values and our fitted values or our predictions.
So the observed values y where y train and from Y train we can subtract the fitted values we can find
these under results don't fit it values.
Let's take a look at what these residuals actually look like.
So residuals and shift enter will split and shuffle the data.
Train the model and then output our residuals.
And here we go.
These are all 400 and for residuals from our model.
If you're wondering what type of object we're working with here then we can see it is a panda's series.
That's quite nice because if it's a panda series we can call a bunch of methods on it that the series
has like describe.
And if I do that we can see that the mean of the residuals is very very close to zero.
But more on that later.
So let me quickly comment this out hit shift into a hand show you that you don't actually need to do
this calculation manually because our results object from our stats model.
Actually already has an attribute which allows you to fetch the residuals.
So results don't reside is the name of said attribute and heading shift enter.
We get presented with exactly the same thing all right.
Let me count this code out again.
Scroll down a little bit.
Hit shift enter and get to the interesting part namely the part where we are graphing our stuff so I'll
add another comment here that reads graph of actual vs. predicted prices now.
Before I write this code let me explain the rationale of what I'm about to do here.
I want to create a chart that visualizes how good our predictions are.
I want to see how our predictions actually stack up to the actual property prices because seeing this
picture will put the r squared from the regression that we calculated into context if you remember from
our earlier lessons that r squared was kind of a nice one numbers summary for our aggression but it's
definitely not the only thing that we should be looking at.
Now let me ask you this on this chart of the actual versus the predicted prices what would this chart
look like if our model was perfectly accurate.
If it had like perfect predictive capabilities what would you expect to see in that case.
You'd expect that the predicted prices are kind of a really really close match to the actual ones.
In fact you'd get all of these things lining up on a straight line right.
You should have a very very strong correlation between the model's predictions and the actual results.
Let's calculate this correlation and store it in a variable someone say core is equal to y underscore
train dot core parentheses results dot fitted values.
This here calculates the correlation method on our y underscore train object and we provide as an argument
the fitted values from our regression.
Let's put this value here as a core and head shift into the correlation that we see printed out here
is a zero point eight nine approximately.
That's that's quite high actually.
Which is pretty good.
I think one thing I'd like to do though is round this value here so round parentheses and then at the
end here a comma and two somewhere around two decimal places close the parentheses and it shift enter
again.
Nice.
Now let's create a scatter plot using map plot loop which we've stored in our PDT variable.
So let's say party dots scatter parentheses for the x axis.
We're gonna use r y train our actual values for the y axis.
We're gonna use our fitted values.
So this was results dot fitted values.
Now I'm also going to add a color and a transparency to this scatter plot for the color.
C equals.
I'm going to go for maybe navy blue so Navy in single quotes and for the Alpha the transparency.
I'm gonna go for zero point nine maybe six.
Now let me write PDT dot show and take a look at what this looks like.
Here we go.
Now it's a little hard to see what's going on here.
I think we need some labels on our axes and we should also plot a line on this graph that represents
the perfect fit.
So we have a reference point for this scatter plot.
Let me hide this plot by double clicking in here.
And updating our code now and adding our axis labels.
I'm going to show you how you can include scientific notation or latex notation on the labels themselves.
They take notation is something that we've used in our markdown cell but so far we haven't really integrated
into our charts.
So let's do that now.
When I have party X label parentheses and then single quotes actual log prices.
And here's the latest notation.
Dollar Sign Dollar Sign.
And then between the dollar signs when have Y.
And then I want to have like an underscore and then an eye.
Meaning this I will be shown as a subscript and anything between this opening and closing tag will be
treated as later.
Notation let me add a font size as well so comma font size is equal to be 14.
Let's see what this looks like with shift.
Enter.
Here we go has promised we see that why has a subscript that's not the label for the y axis appeal T
dot y label.
And try this one more time.
Say predicted lock prices and for the lay take notation I'm going to say y hat on the score y and I
can do this by having that slash hat for the latest tag and then again I'll have Y underscore I and
also font size equals 14.
Take a look here we can see that the hash tag in the latest notation creates this look Carey symbol
above are y here.
Nice.
Now let's add a title to this chart.
And in the title we'll use both latex notation and we'll use an F string to show our correlation as
well.
So peel T dot title parentheses f single quotes actual verses predicted log prices colon.
Dollar dollar.
And between that all the science y underscore I versus dollar dollar slash had y on the score I and
then outside the dollar sign parentheses core curly braces and then lowercase c o r r which is the name
of our variable here and at the end of course we've got close and curly braces.
The closing parentheses for this one single quotes finish it all off and maybe a font size of say Uh
17.
Let's take a look.
Fatal Exception.
What was the problem.
A typo in the late hash tag.
It should read slash hat.
There we go.
So I think this chant is already starting to look pretty good.
The only thing missing is that line that represents perfect predictions and we can add that up here
with peal T dot plot plotting a single line and that line for the X and the y will be the same.
So in this case it would be y train comma Y train and I'm gonna give it a different color as well so
color is equal to say scion they'll make it stand out quite nicely so check it out.
Here we go.
This side line would represent a perfect prediction.
So it goes through all these great points here two into two and a half in two and a half three and three
and a half right.
And this allows us to see how our predictions stack up to the actual values very very clearly.
The bigger the distance from the sine line the bigger the residual.
In other words in this part of the chart our model is doing really really well.
But for these data points here we have much larger residuals.
Now what if looking at log prices isn't that helpful.
What if you wanted to look at the actual prices the actual dollar values because that's much more intuitive.
All we have to do is reverse our transformation right.
So let's create a second chart below this one.
I'll take this code here.
Copy and paste it below.
And then all I have to do to reverse the transformation is raise our data points to the power of E so
n p dot e times times.
Which raises it to the power and will do the same thing here and p dot e.
Raise it to the power of our residuals.
And of course we have to do the same thing here and be done.
E How times times and p e times times and then actual prices in the label predicted prices in the label
and then for the title will also do that to differentiate the two charts visually.
I'm just gonna go with straightforward blue for this one source kind of plot here.
We'll just be blue shift enter updates what we see and now our axes are transformed and we see our dollar
prices in thousands can even add that to the label.
So actual prices 0 0 0 S. And here predicted prices 0 0 0 s shift into and now our labels are updated.
Now that we've got our charts pretty much where we want them to be we can start to interpret what it
is that we're looking at.
How do you think our predictions are stacking up to the actual values looking at these charts.
I think we're doing actually rather well.
And what we're seeing here pretty much ties out with the expectations that we had.
Looking at the high R squared.
A lot of the predictions in fact are very close to this scion line here.
Mind you this side line is not the best fit line for the scatter plot.
The line here shows where a points would have to be if our predictions were perfect and our residuals
would be equal to zero.
The sideline represents where y hat would be equal to y.
But looking at this chart I do see something that kind of concerns me a little bit.
Take a look at this top right corner here.
There's definitely something kind of strange happening with the properties at the very top price bracket.
These are the properties at the fifty thousand dollar mark here you can see that our residuals are actually
fairly large and our model is performing quite poorly.
If you remember we actually visualized all our target values in our data exploration stage and then
we already spotted that there were quite a few properties at the top end of the price bracket and that
given this histogram these kind of struck us as outliers and we suspected that maybe these might cause
an issue down the line.
What I'm saying is is that yes there's room for improvement in our model obviously.
But overall I think I'm pretty happy with what we've got so far.
After all we're dealing with a real data set so it's nice to see things line up to the extent that they
do.