So now that we've plotted our actual prices versus our predictions and we've generated this chart here
let's move on in our residual analysis to the CIS the chart of this one because in this chart we can't
actually see the residuals explicitly right.
We can see kind of how far the data points are from the sine line here.
But our residuals are actually not on one of the axes.
Let's make this much more explicit and plot our residuals versus the predicted values that come up here.
Add a comment that reads residuals versus predicted values.
To take these lines of code copy them paste them below.
And how I'm going to modify them a little bit.
So want to get rid of this line on the x axis.
I want the label to read predicted lock prices and then slash had y underscore I font size 14 on the
y axis.
I wanted to read just residuals and for the title I wanted to read residuals versus fitted values.
Now let's update the arguments in the scatter plot.
So for the x axis you've already guessed it's gonna be results dot fitted values and for the y axis
it's going to read results.
Dot visit for the color.
I want to go with navy for the Alpha.
I'll leave it at zero point six.
Now let me hit shift enter.
So this is the chart that you can compare to the charts that you've seen in the slides earlier on in
the lesson.
How do we interpret what we're looking at here.
Are you seeing any obvious patterns.
I think it's actually pretty ok the residuals look fairly random for the most part and the residuals
are actually centered around zero.
So looking at the y axis here we can see that a lot of the residuals are centered around zero the residuals
are also fairly symmetric.
They don't seem to be systematically high or systematically low.
So the model is kind of correct on on average.
But in this chart we also see the issue with the high price bracket homes filtering through.
No surprise there.
Can you spot them.
Which data points on this chart correspond to all the fifty thousand dollar homes.
They're actually right here.
You see how this almost traces out a line these data points on this chart correspond to these data points
on this chart that shows fifty thousand dollar properties that were bad at predicting seemed to be lining
up.
Now let's to our next check on the residuals that we talked about.
Let's check for normality.
Let's see if our normality assumption is satisfied or close to satisfied because in the beginning of
the lesson we said well we kind of want these residuals to be normally distributed.
Let's check out if they really are or not.
And the sub below went out a comment and that's going to read distribution of residuals lock prices
hyphen checking for normality a normal distribution if you remember has a mean and a skew of what 0.
Right.
The skew should be zero and the mean should be zero.
How do we print out the mean and the skew.
We'll take our results objects results dot reside get the residuals and then we can change a method
onto this for the mean would use dot mean parentheses me shift into what's printed out here.
Is in scientific notation.
So let's round this let's say round parentheses results dot raise it don't mean comma and then let's
round to three decimal places and have the closing parentheses at the end shift enter and we see here
that the mean of our residuals is indeed very very close to zero.
Mr. This and a variable called reside and a score mean.
And now let's print out the skew so results start reserved don't skew parentheses should be our skew.
See what that is.
Huh.
Okay.
Zero point one two approximately calls around that round to three decimal points.
And I'm also going to store this in a variable visit on the score skews equal to this whole thing.
So fair enough.
The mean is equal to zero.
The skew is not equal to zero but it's not too far off.
Now looking at these two numbers is helpful but it's even better if we complement this with a plot with
a graphic.
So when you born here as an S dot just plot distribution plot parentheses and then as the arguments
will provide our residuals.
So results don't resist.
And for the color we'll go with the Navy again.
I think every plot needs a title so appeal teed up title and then as a title we'll say single quotes
long prize model colon residuals.
Now let's go with L teed up show and see what this looks like.
Here we go.
Here we see the distribution of our residuals using C Bourne's disk plot function.
I can come back up here make this an F string by putting the little f in front and add our residuals
mean and the skew into the title so I'll go with SKU parentheses curly braces wristed underscore SKU
and mean parentheses curly braces Sid on a school mean we didn't calculate the mean in this Q and rounded
for nothing after all let's show it in our chart.
There we go.
So how are we doing.
Well the mean is equal to zero but that's no surprise.
That's actually by design.
That's how the regression models best fit line his calculated.
No matter how bad your regression line the mean is gonna be equal to zero by design but I think the
skew being close to zero is a result of our data transformation and I'm going to prove this to you shortly.
Looking at this histogram and the estimated distribution for the residuals by seaborne what's really
comforting to see is that the residuals are fairly symmetrical right and they have a fairly constant
spread throughout the range.
So I think we're doing pretty ok.
The thing that you do notice however is that this distribution in contrast to a normal distribution
has much longer tails.
So there's more values in the extreme left and the extreme right than what you would see with a normal
distribution.
You've got a bigger peak in the middle and then you've got longer tails on either end.
So this is where the similarity to the normal distribution is much much weaker.
Okay.
So we've looked at three charts of our residuals but I think what we really really need to do is we
need to compare how these charts looked like four different models because if these three charts are
all we've ever seen we don't really have much context right.
And so on that note I'd like to pose a challenge to you.
I want you to generate these three plots right.
So this distribution the residuals versus the fitted values and the fitted values versus the observed
values for the original model that we had.
So this was the model with all the features using normal prices not the transformed log prices.
And after you've generated those charts I want you to analyze and interpret the results that you're
getting back so I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video and give this a shot.
OK ready.
Here's the solution.
Use the lazy man's approach and copy this entire cell when going to then come here and paste it in and
I'm going to modify the code a little bit when I change my comment here.
See original model
normal prices and all features to use normal prices.
I have to not just get rid of this comment but we have to get rid of this and Dot log here and to use
all the features I'm going to delete in this and age from the arguments under the drop method scrolling
down.
Tony this comment anymore.
Don't read these comments anymore and then forward the scatter plot.
I'm gonna go with a different color.
I'm gonna go with uh Indigo for the labels on this chart.
I want to see actual prices thousands predicted prices thousands for the title.
I to see actual versus predicted prices coming down.
I'm going to delete this line of code which we don't need for our second chance.
I'm also gonna go with indigo when I update the labels and now all I have to do is have the distribution
graph.
So that's gonna be a residual distribution chart which I'm going to grab from up here.
I'm going to grab these lines of code here.
Copy them put them down here paste them in again.
Change the color to indigo to set them apart a little bit.
I think my title haven't read residuals and print out the skew and the mean in the title.
And that's pretty much it.
The coding side of this challenge is pretty trivial because we're using a lot of the code.
But let's take a look at what the charts look like and see what the differences are between what we
are doing here and what we did earlier.
First up our actual versus our predicted prices.
Now visually the first graph and this one here actually seem quite similar.
And that's no surprise given that the correlation between the fitted values and the observed values
is around the same.
Yes it's a bit was we know that from the r squared that we calculated and it has a little bit lower
correlation but it's not super dramatic on the differences the predicted and the actual values are actually
fairly close to the sine line as they were with the log prices now coming down on the second chart here.
This one is much more interesting here we're definitely starting to see a little bit of a difference
compared with the log prices.
The cloud of residuals looks almost like it's got a little bit of a parabolic shape to it.
It's kind of subtle and you almost have to kind of squint a little bit.
But what we're seeing here doesn't look entirely random.
This provides further justification that the log transformation for the target values that we did was
indeed appropriate.
Now what about the third chart.
What about the histogram and the distribution of the residuals coming down.
We see that.
Yeah.
The mean is equal to zero.
But what about the skew.
And here we need to see that with a skew of one point five approximately the distribution of the residuals.
It's actually fairly lopsided.
This makes this distribution a lot more dissimilar from a normal distribution because the skew of a
normal distribution is zero.
And we've got one point five approximately a distribution of residuals.
That's not close to a normal distribution makes things much more difficult when it comes to making predictions
and making forecasts which is ultimately what we wanted to do right.
This is t assignment that our Boss gave us in our imaginary real estate office.
So I hope this was a helpful contrast to what we saw earlier and provides a bit more context.
But I want to show you one more example because before we finish this lesson I want to show you the
kind of pattern that you could see in your residuals when you're missing important features or omitting
kind of key variables in your regression.
So let me come back up here copy this paste it and then I'm going to update my comment here.
I'm going to say model
omitting key features using log prices
and now what I'm going to do is start dropping quite a few features from our dataset.
I'm going to drop not just in this day and age but I'm also going to drop else that I want to drop our
am I going to drop an o x and I want to drop crime.
Now we said we'll use log prices.
So I'm going to add and p dot log pack here where we're getting our prices and then just as a review
you don't actually have to stick to the named colors that are in matte plot lib.
You can actually specify any color you want any shade you want.
If you go to a Web site like Flat UI colors dot com you can grab a particular hex code that identifies
a particular shade of a color the hex codes or start with this pound symbol and then there are six letters
or numbers following that.
So I'm going to take a closer in here which I can then paste in here where I've referenced Indigo.
So c is equal to LB e 7 for c 3 C. This is this shade of Algerian that we've copied from the other website
coming down.
I'm also gonna replace the color in our second chant so that way each of our models has a certain theme
going on and I'm also gonna delete this block of code at the bottom.
Finally just gonna update the title here.
So I want that title to read actual versus predicted prices with or Mitt 2D variables hand the very
last thing we have to do on the labeling front is change our X and Y labels.
So these are gonna be back to log prices X label is gonna read actual log prices and r y label is gonna
read print Dick Ted log prices.
Let's take a look at our charts.
There we go.
So this is interesting right.
As before we see this banding here on the top right with a very expensive properties at fifty thousand.
We also see that as expected the correlation between our fitted values and our observed values is much
much lower because we're leaving out a lot of information a lot of explanatory features from our model
but not only that we see this kind of like banding here.
So you've got all these data points lining up here and here and even inside this cloud here scrolling
down we see that this is even more extreme when we look at the residuals versus the fitted values.
Here you can see the banding very very clearly in the residual chart instead of a completely random
distribution of residuals.
What we see in this chart here are clusters.
This is a very very clear pattern and it's telling us that there's some important information that's
missing from our model and this information has somehow found its way into the residuals.
And this kind of brings me to my final thoughts on the banding that we see with the fifty thousand dollar
homes.
My hypothesis as to why we see these properties lining up like this is because there's something maybe
missing from our model maybe there is some feature that these are homes all have in common or there
was something in the way that the data was collected or there is some sort of interaction between a
feature of these homes that we're not capturing in our model.
If I wanted to kind of dig into this further and improve this model that we have further this would
be one of the things I would be looking at.
This would be something I could dig into.
But we have more important things to do.
You and I we're gonna be moving on to bigger and better things.
We're gonna be moving on to making predictions from our regression model.
This is what we ultimately set out to do right.
I'll see you in the next lesson.
Take her.