In this lesson we're going to create our own word cloud.
Also I'll show you how to get hold of entire novels through the NL T.K. resources.
That's at a quick little section heading here with a markdown cell that reads creating a word cloud.
Now whenever you're using an unknown package or a new package that you haven't seen before it's always
a good idea to pull up the documentation of this package.
In our case the package that we're going to be using is called word cloud and it was originally made
by a chap called Andreas Muller.
But since then he's had approximately 33 people contribute and improve and add their work to make this
package better.
As you can see the entire code base is up on github for anybody to look at.
And there's some basic instructions here as well.
But the more detailed API documentation can be found here on this Web site you can see a bit more information
on how to use the word cloud as well as some more examples.
I've added the links to both these sites into the lesson resources.
So without further ado let's get started with a basic example.
Now having downloaded and installed the package in the previous lesson it's time to add it to our notebook
imports.
So here we can say from word cloud import word cloud lets it shift enter and scroll all the way down.
Now we're gonna be using that example email again to generate our first word cloud.
The way to do it is to use Word Cloud parentheses dot and then the Generate method parentheses and then
we just have to supply the piece of text that we'd like to use to generate the word cloud from.
So in our case it was the email body I want to actually save this in a variable called word cloud.
So it's a word on a scale.
Cloud is equal to work hard parentheses don't generate parentheses email body.
This is step one.
Now Matt plot lib is going to come into play so I plot lib was stored inside a variable called BLT.
And here we're going to use the I am show method I am show parentheses and we can supply.
Well you guessed that going to supply our Word Cloud to I am show and let's use peyote don't show and
see what we get we get something like this how I don't know about you but I can see we can make some
improvements on this right away the quality isn't that great the letters look a little bit jagged and
we've got these axes on both sides on the X and the Y these axes are really easy to remove actually
if we use peel T don't axis parentheses and then single quotes with the string off and head shift into
the axes disappear but we still kind of have these jagged edges on some of these letters it doesn't
look that clean.
So what we can do is come up to the I am sure method put in a comma after word cloud and add an additional
argument here.
This one's kind of be called interpolation and we can set that equal to some sort of value.
Right at first we have a default value for interpolation which was none.
There was no interpolation going on but we can do some interpolation to smooth out these edges.
I'm going to go with bi linear and now we have a much cleaner picture of course the only reason I know
to set interpolation to buy linear is because I've had a look at the quick documentation here and I
scrolled down to the interpolation parameter and I've tried out a couple of these.
So there is quite a big number to choose from.
The default is none but I did find that I could get some improvement in the look of my word cloud by
playing around with this and I found that by linear works well for me now I think as a minimalist aesthetic
example This works really really well.
And you'll find something very very similar on the documentation page actually.
So let's take this to the next level.
Let's make this a little bit more interesting to to make our next word clouds a little bit more interesting.
I want to show you how to download entire novel from the natural language tool kit and multi K actually
has a whole bunch of resources that we can use if we go back up to where we were downloading our token
either and our stop words you'll recall both of these were downloaded to the NL T.K. underscored data
folder on our harddrive Hall we need to do is add two additional lines of code here namely and ultra
K Dot download parentheses single quotes Gutenberg and and multi K Dot download parentheses single quotes
Shakespeare if a hit shift enter on the cell it will download some additional core Pora for us that
we can make use of in our word cloud check it out so it got the zip files and it unzipped them.
And here they are in my corporate folder.
I've got Shakespeare right here with a number of his plays including Hamlet Julius Caesar Macbeth and
so on I think Ha and J stands for Romeo and Juliet.
Another classic and Gutenberg has also a whole bunch of books so you can read these for free if you
like.
This one here looks like Alice in Wonderland by Lewis Carroll.
There we go.
Opening them up in my atom text editor can see the whole text of the entire novel nicely formatted the
one we're gonna use is Moby Dick by Herman Melville.
If you actually wanted to read this book you have to scroll down quite a bit past all the acknowledgements
and praises and so on to uh eventually chapter one which is on line 500 with the famous opening sentences
but okay so far so good.
Now we've got access to the text of a whole bunch of novels.
Now it's up to us to put these into a word cloud somewhere insert a few more cells at the bottom of
our notebook and I'm going to get a hold of one of these works the way I'm going to get hold of one
of these is like this I won't have to go and ulti K Dot corpus dot Gutenberg
dot woods.
So in this case I'm getting a hold of one of the text files in the Gutenberg folder the one I'm interested
in it's gonna be Moby Dick so I'll have single quotes in the parentheses and I'll type out the exact
spelling of this text file so it's Melville hyphen Moby underscore Dick dot t x t.
I'm including the file extension the string that I'm passing into my words method here has to match
this file name exactly now I'm going to create a variable called example on a school corpus and that's
where I want to store my Moby Dick novel.
If you're wondering how many words are in this entire novel by the way you can pull it up with the built
in length function alien parentheses.
Example Corpus.
Let's see how much work was put into Moby Dick.
It's not war and peace but two hundred sixty thousand words it's still no slouch.
Now another thing that might be quite interesting actually is to see what type of variable or type of
object we're dealing with.
So in this case our example Corpus is something called a stream backed corpus view.
The reason I'm drawing attention to this is because you might be forgiven for thinking that what you're
getting back here is just a big long string but you're actually dealing with a different kind of object
here.
This thing that we're working with actually has a whole bunch of tokens.
If you wanted to get the list of words you have to kind of join them together.
You have to join all the tokens together.
Let me show you what I mean.
The first thing I'll do is I'm going to create a list called it would on a list and set that equal to
square brackets.
And then inside these square brackets I want to use python's list comprehension to join all the tokens
together.
So I'll be two single quotes then dot join parentheses word.
And yeah you guessed that there's a loop coming for word in example corpus this here will join all of
her words together.
So if you're wondering what this looked like before example corpus shift into looks like so and the
word list that I'm getting after running my list comprehension and joining all the words together will
look like so very similar looking I know but remember we're going from tokens to a list of words which
we can then use to join together into a single string.
So if I say novel on a as on a school string as equal to and in single quotes with the space inside
dot join parentheses would list this year we'll actually take all the words out of the list and put
them into a single string so novel a string will look like.
So now if you're wondering why we're going through this trouble it's because we have to do some pre
processing to feed our text into a word cloud.
Remember this generate function him.
It's kind of expecting a very simple string to build the word cloud from we can't give it a corpus.
Straight out of the NL K toolkit.
And I also don't want to give it a list of tokens or a list of individual words I'm planning to give
my word cloud a simple string so why don't we try it out for now.
I want a copy of this come down here pasted in instead of having email body inside my generate method
I want to have novel as string and see what we get fantastic So that's working we've successfully extracted
all the words from a corpus in the penalty K resources and fed them into our Word Cloud package.
Now all we have to do is make this thing look a bit better and style it.
I'm planning to arrange all these words into the shape of a whale.
Let's see if we can do this.