In the upcoming lessons we're going to talk about how to make predictions using our model.
And believe it or not this gives us a chance to link together several concepts of the past lessons in
our technical section on gradient descent.
We've talked extensively about cost functions and the role of the means squared error cost function
in machine learning.
We've also covered how an algorithm that finds the best fit line minimizes this particular equation.
And we've also talked a lot about metrics like r squared and we touched on how to compare different
models.
And finally we've talked a lot about how to analyze the residuals.
So how does this all tied together.
Let's go back to the equation of the means quit IRA for a little bit y hat in this equation is the value
that is estimated by our model since we're using a multi variable regression with 11 features our equation
for y hat will actually break down into something like this.
We have all the features and then all the features taking it a step further.
We've also encountered the Y minus y hat before Y minus y hat where the residuals the residuals are
the actual values minus the fitted values.
So what does that make the mean square error the mean square error is just the residuals squared and
then summed up and then divided by the number of observations and now do you see the squaring that's
happening here.
We're squaring the differences between the actual and the predicted values we're squaring the residuals.
And this is nice because we're treating the positive and the negative residuals equally which means
we can then add them up in the summation but this mathematical operation of squaring the differences
also has another effect.
Think about this.
What if the difference between the predicted value and the actual value was large.
What if we have a large residual what happens to the mean squared error in this case the squaring of
a big number will increase the mean square error massively.
Right.
In other words the mean square error ways the large differences more heavily and thus it punishes large
residuals the effect of this is is that it makes the means quite a very sensitive to outliers.
So that's one thing to be aware of.
Now let's have a think about how the main square error compares to our squared and to do that we're
going to check out the differences between the two in Jupiter notebook.
In the past lessons we've written some code where we plotted our residuals and calculated them and compared
the residual plots of three different models.
Now let's look at these models are squared and there means quit errors in some of the previous lessons.
The way we've worked with the means quit error was by importing a function from cyclic learn.
So we said from K learned metrics import mean underscore squared on a score error.
And then we use this function to calculate the MSE.
But in this case we're using our stats model module here and it actually makes accessing the means quit
are very very easy because again we just have to use our results object to get hold of it.
Here's how.
Coming down here I'm going to add a comment that reads mean squared error.
And I can access the mean square error from our results objects by typing results dot M S E underscore
resit.
This will give us our means squared error.
And what I'll do is I'll store this in a variable I'm going to call this variable or reduced on a score
log on a score.
M S E and so that equal to the rounded value of this whole thing.
So.
Oh I see round function and have the results start MSE and the score reside inside the parentheses come
after it round rounded to three decimal places and close it all off.
I don't want to do a same thing for the r squared.
So in our comment I'll add R squared.
I'm going to copy this line pasted on here.
Change the variable name to all squared and change the attribute as well.
So results thought r squared rounded to three decimal places will be stored in this variable reduced
on a score log on a score.
R squared is equal to round parenthesis results start r squared comma three closing parentheses will
take this here.
These three lines of code and the comment copy them and I'm going to come down here to model number
two.
The original model using normal prices and all features and what I'll do here.
Going to come down to the very bottom pasted in and changed the variable names.
The first one I'll call full underscore normal and it's quite messy.
And the second one I'm going to call full on the score normal on a score.
Our squared.
Now when I hit shift enter on both of these cells since I've added new code I think I didn't do it on
the first one but I will do it on this one shift enter and then coming up here go ahead shift enter
as well.
This leaves us with our third model the one where we admitted some variables and are still using log
prices.
And I'm going to paste in the three lines the comment reading mean square error and R squared.
And then I want to change the variable names.
Once again I'm going to call this one permitted when I'm double T omitted underscore var underscore
MSE and admitted the score bar at a score of squared shift.
Enter and now that we've added this code calculated all these values we can look at them side by side
which is what I wanted to do in the first place.
So I put him in a data frame PD dot data frame parenthesis curly brackets single quotes r squared colon
and now I want to provide a list a list of all the r squared values.
So the first one was reduced on the score log under school r squared the second one was full underscore
normal underscore Squid and the third one was omitted underscore var underscore our squid.
Those are all the r squared values.
When I put a comma here after the square brackets go down to the next line and add our second key for
our dictionary it's gonna be MSE means quit error colon and again we're gonna be putting in a list of
values so I can probably take this list here.
Copy it pasted in and then change that.
Last thing here in the name too.
MSE this is how I've named all my means quit era variables so that's easy enough.
Let's take a look at what we've got when it shift enter and what we see is two columns one reading MSE
and the other one reading r squared now the roads are still indexed by 0 1 and 2 but we can change that
by adding an additional argument here.
I want to put a come up here and then I'm going to supply the index argument and I'm going to make this
equal to again a list.
So square brackets and when put three values the first one it's gonna be our reduced log model.
The second one is going to be our full normal price model and then the third one is going to be our
admitted
variable model refreshing our output.
We see the names listed here very nicely okay.
So let's interpret what we're looking at.
First off the r squared.
We know that r squared is always between 0 and 1 for every single regression model out there.
But what does this mean.
R squared is a relative measure of fit and r squared does not have any units right.
This means that the r squared doesn't scale with the data it's always between 0 and 1.
And in our table we can see that the simplified model with the log prices has a higher fit than our
full model with the normal prices.
Of course the model where we left out some variables.
This one in fact has the lowest fit of them all.
But what about the mean square error.
In contrast to r squared the main square error actually is an absolute measure of fit.
It's not a relative measure it's an absolute measure and it has units namely the units of the target.
Are Y variable that nineteen point nine that you see here for the full normal price model.
Yeah.
The second one is in the units of the target which in this case is thousands of dollars.
So this means quite error here is actually approximately twenty thousand dollars.
Is this third one better than the second one because it has a lower mean squat error.
And the answer is No.
Right.
Because you can't compare the two because they're in different units the model in the first row and
the model in the third row are using log prices right.
Log prices in thousands.
In other words the scale of the MSE is different depending on the data that you're using.
But of course lower values of MSE indicate a better fit and an MSE of 0 indicates a perfect fit.
So you have to remember that when you're comparing models Okay so now that we've calculated our mean
square error let's talk about how we would go about making a prediction for a house price.
Now I think that before we go ahead and do that we should actually check out how the pros predict house
prices to websites that are very good at this are Zoeller in the UK and Zillow in the US but of course
you can go and hunt around on the Internet to find a equivalent Web site.
That's a bit closer to home depending on where you live hand you can other maybe like paused the video
and try out one of these Web sites to get an estimate for a home.
Or you can watch me go through the process.
One word of warning though uh Zillow thinks they're being very cute or clever and calling their estimate
a XXX estimate.
Mm hmm.
Yeah.
So uh something that so how did that go.
Did you give it a shot.
So yesterday I actually tried using zipline to get a price estimate for Buckingham Palace or the pig
pen but I didn't have much luck providing the postcodes for these lap blocks.
But funny enough there were some properties listed in Windsor Castle of all places including like the
Windsor Castle library.
So yeah I'm really not sure why but.
But I tell you what I did dig around and I want to show you how to get a property price estimate for
this particular home.
Let me show you the brochure.
So this is an old brochure and it's for this house in Kenwood.
And as you can see it's a it's a very very nice house.
I think the agent Knight Frank was looking to sell it hand the story with this house is that it used
to belong to John Lennon from the Beatles.
That's right.
This John Lennon.
Contrary to popular belief he did not live on Abbey Road nor did he live in a yellow submarine.
OK.
So let me show you how to get an estimate for his previous Crip.
Now to get a valuation for this home on Zoom club what I have to do is I have to go to get your home
valued and then I think it's I come down here and I think I have to click on what's my home worth.
So I think the first place they send you is trying to get Agent valuations but I'm actually interested
in the zoo plot estimate so how much zoo hoopla thinks it's worth.
So when I click on this get a zoo play estimate and then I'm going to punch in the postcode.
So this was Katy 13 0 j you looked us up.
So John Lennon used to live on this postcode and hand from that property brochure we know that it's
Kenwood Wood Lane.
So let's click on get estimate now we can supply some additional information about this property the
property type is it's a detached house the property style is that it's a period home and it's a freehold.
I don't know how many floors it has but I did check the brochure and four bedrooms it was six bedrooms
six bathrooms and six receptions.
I think they also had like a big garden and a swimming pool and for the internal area according to the
brochure it's a thousand one hundred and ten square metres.
So absolutely enormous I can press continue and then I'm going to take swimming pool here and leave
these other ones alone.
I can't be bothered but what's very interesting is that Zeppelin knows how much this home sold for previously.
This is actually public knowledge right.
If you're wondering where they're getting this from they're getting it from the UK Government's land
registry.
So the government basically tracks all the property transactions in the UK and you can search for house
prices of the previous transactions.
And if I put in the postcode here.
So Katie 13 0 j you and then say show results then I can see here that for Kenwood Wood Lane in 2007
this home sold for five point eight million pounds.
Yeah.
So this is where Zappala is getting its price data from.
They're getting it directly from the government.
So that's one of the data sources not going to confirm the information above is accurate and I agree
to the terms of use MLC get estimate
and what we see is that Zappala estimates John Lennon's former home to be worth eight point seventy
five million pounds.
So it's sold for five point eight.
Back in 0 7 and today super reckons it's worth about eight point seventy five.
But here's the part I want to draw your attention to.
I want to draw your attention to this value range that they're providing him.
We don't just get a price.
Yeah.
So plays in telling us oh it's worth eight point seventy five million on the nose.
What we also get from them is a range around that price.
We see that super thinks the property is worth between eight point one six and nine point three four
million pounds.
What zoo plus actually telling us is that they are estimating this home to be worth eight point seven
five plus or minus five hundred and ninety thousand pounds.
They're giving us an upper and a lower bound to their estimate.
And this is a key component for making a good prediction.
Why well.
Because it tells us how confident Zoeller is in their estimate.
I mean they're giving us this little bar here confidence level high but we can also infer how confident
they are by how wide this range is in the woods.
If this hoopla says oh it's eight point seven million plus or minus six hundred thousand that's very
very different from saying it was worth eight point seven million plus or minus two million.
Right.
The point I'm trying to make is that when it comes to our predictions our forecasting that we're going
to be doing we're going to have to provide not just a house price but we're also going to have to provide
a range around that price.
And believe it or not this range actually has something to do with the residuals and the mean square
error hand.
That's what we're going to be looking at in the next lesson.
But before you head over there let me uh let me ask you a question.
Have you ever used the Web site like Zillow or Zillow to get an estimate for a property hand.
If so please post the link of the service that you used and the common section for this video.
Hyde actually be quite curious to know for which places on earth we can get estimates like this hand
for which ones we can't at the time of recording.
I tried finding the equivalent of Xu for Austria but no dice.
Yeah.
The property market in Austria is just not as transparent as in the UK.
And this property price transaction data that zoo plus piggy backing off of to make their estimates
you know that they're getting from the land registry is just not publicly available.
Anyhow I'll see you in the next video.
Take care.