As part of the lesson resources that you've downloaded under spam data 01 processing there's a folder
called word cloud resources and there you should see a whale hyphen icon dot PMG file and this is gonna
be our mask that we will project the words from the word cloud onto if you scroll back up in the notebook
to where we find all our constants.
We can add another one here let's add the relative path to this PMG file so we're not a new line and
here will add a constant called while on a school file and set that equal to to what it says in the
previous string.
At first save us some time typing the first two bits will stay the same it will still be spam data 0
1 processing but after that forward slash we have to write word cloud on the school resources forward
slash whale hyphen icon dot P and G this bit here needs to be the relative path that points to our whale
I conduct PMG file has always with these things.
Everything's case sensitive now before we scroll back down.
Let's go up to our notebook imports and import another tool.
This will be some functionality from the pile package.
So from pile all caps import Image L is short for pillow pillow is the name of a package that will help
us with image manipulation and processing.
Pillow can actually do quite a lot of things like pixel manipulation image blurring or smoothing or
adding text we gonna be using it to convert R starting image of the whale to grayscale and then to an
array of RG p values.
And the reason for that is that word cloud has some very specific requirements as to what kinds of images
can and cannot be used as a mask and also it's quite particular.
What kind of format the mask is in and that's why we need to do a little prep.
How so.
I suspect that at one point you want to use your own custom masks with word cloud.
At some point in the future.
So it's a good idea to have seen this workflow of the image preparation once before in fact let's take
a look at word clouds requirements.
If I scroll down here and hit shift tab on my keyboard putting up the quick documentation I can see
that there is a parameter called mask by default.
It has the value none hence scrolling down.
We can take a quick look at a more detailed description and this reads.
If not none gives a binary mask on where to draw words.
So the mask will specify the location of where the words are drawn on the canvas.
Further down it says all white entries will be considered masked out and all the other entries will
be free to draw on and the format that we need to supply this mask in is an NDE array an n dimensional
array like one from num pi.
Now that sounds a little strange right.
Why would we provide an array.
And the reason is is that word cloud actually expects pixel by pixel information on the image in this
array format.
And when I say pixel by pixel information what I really mean is pixel color because what the word cloud
code cares about is if it's dealing with a white pixel or a pixel in another color the way that we will
be providing this pixel color information is in our G.B. format.
RG B stands for red green blue.
We're already acquainted with color hex codes from previous lessons.
So this time we'll use our GP to mix things up a little bit.
The RG format is particularly relevant because it relates very closely to how colors are shown on your
TV or your phone screens.
If you were to take a magnifying glass and go up really close to your phone you will actually see tiny
little red green and blue LCD with RG B.
You essentially supply three values namely how bright each of these little LCD should shine.
The RG B values themselves have a scale between zero and two hundred and fifty five.
If all the numbers are on 255 then we get pure white.
If all the numbers are on zero then we get pure black and with any combination between we get all the
other colors back in our Python code.
We now know that our goal is to get an array of our GP values to our word cloud.
The first step will be opening the image file.
You'll recall that we've added the constant up top that points to the whale hyphen icon dot Pinky file
so we can use pillows image don't open and then supply the relative file path.
Ah well on a scale of file to the open method in fact let's say icon equals image on open whale file.
Step two will be creating a new blank image object from below.
So again we'll use image dot new and then we'll supply three arguments.
The first of which is the mode and this will be our G.B..
The second of which will be the size.
So we're kind of setting the size of our canvas here and I'm gonna set that equal to icon dot size.
So the same size as the whale image and the third thing is I'll set a base colour and then it will be
equal to 2 5 5 comma 2 5 5 comma 2 5 5.
So this is a tuple of three integers and they correspond to the red green and blue values with all of
them set to 2 5.
We get white.
I'll store our blank canvas in a variable called C image underscore school mask.
Now what I'll do I'll take our image mask and put a dot after it and say paste parentheses icon comma
box equals icon.
What this will do is it will paste the picture of our whale onto our blank canvas.
And the reason we're doing this is because now we can easily convert our image mask to an array of our
GP values.
This is why we went through all this trouble so I'll see our GP and a school array is equal to none
pi so end p dot array parentheses image on the school mask.
This is the key.
This converts the image object to an array and with that in hand we can supply the mask argument to
our word cloud.
So we'll see mask as equal to our G.B. array now lets it shift enter and see what we get name and P
is not defined.
Looks like we forgot to import num pi as an P.
Let's go to the very top on our notebook imports and indeed we're missing it.
So this shall not do any self respecting Python notebook needs to import an umpire right.
So let's add import num pi as an P and hit shift enter.
Now we can refresh the cell and see if it runs giving it a little bit of time.
We now see our words superimposed on the whale.
Brilliant.
So this is really cool but I think we can style this a little better and the way we're gonna do that
is going to supply some more arguments to our word cloud here.
In particular I'm interested in changing the background colour here and I'm also interested in changing
the colour of these words and we can do that by supplying something called a colour map.
Also I want to play with this Max words parameter here which is currently set to 200.
Let's see what happens when we change is to say 50 or 400 but the very first thing I'm gonna do is change
the size of this image.
And this is good all my plot libs peel dot figure method that I'm going to call him.
So figure parentheses fixed size square brackets 16 8 I think that will do nicely and make it a little
larger and easier to see what the styling changes are going to look like.
So here's our wheel now let's change the background color to white.
A lot of common here.
Change the background color to single quotes White can hit shift enter.
Now this is starting to look a lot better in my opinion.
But let's play with some of the other parameters as well.
Before we add those though I'm noticing that this line is getting a little long.
So instead of chaining this method call here I'm going to come down here hit enter and see word cloud
don't generate on a separate line of code here.
After background color.
I'll insert a comma.
Hit enter and then change the Max Woods to say 50 and update our graphic.
So that's a very different look.
Right.
On the upside this image was generated a lot faster than the other ones.
But on the downside I can't really tell that this is a whale anymore because a lot of the edges and
so on depend on smaller words being present to flesh out this image.
So what I'll do instead is change this Max words argument to 400 and refresh itself
at this point.
Our code will have taken a little longer but we get a much much more beautiful word cloud with all the
small words on the perimeter of this mask.
But if you recall what's actually determining the location of where these words aren't drawn on the
canvas is this Our GPO Ray.
If we take a closer look at this art GBR Ray and hit shift enter on it.
We see that it looks something like this.
Now that doesn't tell us a whole lot.
Maybe a better way to look at it might be arguably that shape.
And there we see it's 1024 by 2048 by three.
The reason we see those numbers here is because the whale icon itself has a width of 2048 pixels by
1024 pixels.
And the 3 is for the red green and blue are GOP values in other words this array has pixel by pixel
information on the color.
If we take our RG v array we can actually pull up a particular pixel.
So if I say for example 1023 comma two thousand and forty seven then I can see what the RG p values
are for this particular pixel given that this pixel is white.
The word cloud will not drop in this area but let's take the pixel at say 500 and 1000.
Here we see the values 0 0 0 meaning that at this particular location in the image the pixel is black.
So word cloud is free to use this particular pixel to draw an now one of the nice things about matte
plot lib is that we have access to these wonderful color maps and we can play with the styling of our
words by say providing one of these color maps as an argument.
There's quite a few to choose from.
We can go with plasma we could go with blues or greens or oranges.
But one that I found that works particularly well I think for the whale image is a color map called
Ocean refreshing our cell.
Our whale will now start looking something like this and I think thematically this color map seems to
work rather well.
Having worked a little bit now with the analytic resources and our word cloud code I want to throw it
over to you.
I want to propose a challenge.
I'd like you to use the skull image in the lesson resources as a mask to create a word cloud for Shakespeare's
play Hamlet.
The skull image that I've included looks like this.
So have a go at this and have a play with different color maps and different number of maximum words
to make this look good.
And you can find Shakespeare's entire play under Gutenberg and then Shakespeare hyphen Hamlet Dot T
X T.
This is something that we've downloaded as part of the penalty cave resources.
The file is actually in the same folder as Melville's Moby Dick.
If you're particularly brave then you can try and tackle the Hamlet play in the form of example as opposed
to a text file.