To create our Word Cloud for our high messages and our spam messages.
We're gonna use two different masks.
I've got thumbs up for the non spam messages and I've got thumbs down for the spam messages.
These are gonna be our masks for our respective word clouds.
The dataset backing our word clouds will come from some of the previous work we've done so we've got
a flattened list of non spam words and we've got a flattened list of spam words.
This is the data that we're going to feed into our word clouds.
So let's tackle our ham messages first.
I'm going to add a markdown cell here and right word cloud of ham and spam messages.
Next I'm going to add some constants.
I'm going to add the thumbs up and thumbs down files so I'll paste the relative path for the skull file
and just rename these two thumbs the school up file and thumbs on a scroll down file.
Of course the icon names have to change as well.
So this one will call thumbs up dot Pinky thumbs up dot Pinky and this one will call thumbs hyphen down
dot PMG shift enter.
Scroll down.
Now what I'm gonna do is I'm going to copy this code here for our will come down here and paste it in
there's a few modifications that we can make here that will save us a bit of time.
So first off we're gonna change the image to see thumbs up.
Then what we'll have to do is we'll have to generate the text as a string for the word cloud.
Right.
In this case I want store all of this text in a variable called Ham on the score as TR and that will
be equal to single quotes separated by a space dot join parentheses flat list.
So we've got a list of non spam words and we're not joining them all together into a single string before
I run this.
I have to do one last thing I have to change this novel as string to our ham underscore as TR variable.
That way I'm not generating another word cloud for Moby Dick.
Instead I'm generating it for non spam emails.
And here's our output.
We still have the Moby Dick styling but we can change that very easily with a different colour map and
I think otherwise it looks pretty good in terms of colour map.
Let's go for winter and I don't know maybe a bit more granularity on the words
now.
I think this looks pretty good actually but there's probably one thing that you'll notice that might
bother you a little bit.
People for example is spelled without the E at the end.
Change is spelled without the E at the end provide is spelled without the.
We can only guess what this would try.
It's supposed to be the reason for this is is that the data that we fed into our Word Cloud are the
stemmed words.
That's why we're seeing a word cloud presented like this.
Our flattened list of non spam keywords is coming from our nested list of non spam keywords which is
coming from our nested list which we've created up here when we applied our clean message.
No h Tam L. method.
This is where we did this stemming if you recall.
If you wanted to see what this word cloud would look like without the stemmed words then you'd have
to copy this code pasted in use the original word and comment out.
This line right here if you refresh this cell and then go to kernel restart and run all then you'll
run all the cells in the entire notebook and after waiting a little while you can scroll down and look
at the output for the word cloud without the stemmed words.
There we go.
This is starting to look a lot better.
The stem words are going to be very very useful for our bayes classifier but they're actually not so
useful for our Word Cloud.
So if you've changed it like I did then it's important to make a mental note to change this back and
use the stemmed words before we train our model now I've got one final challenge for you on the word
cloud front.
I'd like you to pull up the word cloud documentation and figure out how to use the custom font that
I've included in the lesson resources instead of this default font here and then create a word cloud
of all the words in the spam messages.
I've included two font files.
The open sounds condensed bold font file and I've included the open sends condensed light font file.
If you look at this word cloud here what kind of font you think would work best with it.
What characteristics should a font have in order to make a word cloud look a lot more attractive because
in my humble opinion this default font here doesn't work as well as it should.
What kind of improvement on the font front would you make to this visualization.
I can think of two improvements right off the bat.
First off the words should probably be written in all caps rather than lowercase.
And second the letters of the font should probably be closer together and bold.
These are the first two things that I would try to make this look a lot more convincing.
So I hope you will give this a shot when solving the challenge.
Pause the video and have a go all good.
Here's the solution.
We've already added the relative path to the thumbs down file so we can already use it.
I'm going to copy this code right here.
And pasted in below.
I'll swap up thumbs up for thumbs down this line stays the same as this this one our string of course
will need to change so this will be the spam string and this will come from the flattened spam list
and when it comes to generating the cloud we will use the spam string instead of the hamstring for a
bit of visual differentiation.
I'M GOING TO GO WITH SOMETHING REDDISH from the color map.
In fact I'm going to try this just on the school heat color map that we've got here.
So instead of winter I'll go for just on the school heat and I'll keep some of the other things the
same.
Now when I said check the word cloud documentation what I wanted you to pick up on was the fact that
you could supply a font here as an argument and you can do so by giving the word cloud a font path the
font path is the font that will be used in the word cloud.
And this has to be a O.T. f or a TFSA file and a TEFL file is exactly what we've got going back up.
I'll add my relative path here for my font file so I'll call this one custom on a scope font on the
school file and this will be my Open Sands condensed hyphen bold dot t t f file.
You can try both of these and see which one looks better but I think I prefer the bold one just going
to make sure there's no typos here in this file name them hit shift enter on this scroll back down.
And now I can supply a font and a score path and set that equal to the custom font file.
The other thing that you might have had to have a play with is the maximum font size so getting it to
look the way you wanted to.
There is a mention of a font size parameter in the quick documentation as well despite the rather strange
word wrapping at the moment.
You can see it right here Max font size by default is equal to none but we can give it another value
as well so Max on a school font on a school size equals say I don't know I think 300 worked well last
time I looked at this Harlem hit shift enter and see what this looks like.
My computer is really struggling.
I think I've got too many things open.
Okay.
So here we go.
This is the result.
I think the font looks pretty good but I think we need to up the number of words being displayed in
this image.
Also we're still in lower case so let's change these two things.
Pretty radical and change the maximum number of words to two thousand from five hundred and when it
comes to generating my word cloud I'm going to convert my string to uppercase letters.
So spam on a score SDR dot a poem will convert all of my letters to uppercase now I can refresh and
see if we're happy with the result.
I think the red color definitely worked really well but with these last two changes I think the designer
should really come together.
Okay so that's interesting.
The largest word has randomly been given a white color.
This is probably not what I want someone to refresh this and see if I'm more lucky.
The second time round much better.
Brilliant.
So I quite like the look of this but I'd be quite curious what sort of designs you've come up with.
And speaking of your own designs I could question at this point is where can you find both fonts and
masks for your own projects for your own word clouds when it comes to fonts.
One of my favorite places to go to is Google fonts so Google fonts are free and open source and you
can just browse and download the font files that you like from here.
This is a brilliant resource when it comes to masks and icons.
You've got a lot of choice as well.
One place that you could check out is the icon set on font awesome dot com.
Here you can download various icons that you can then use as masks for your PMG files.
Just remember to double check the licensing on all of these image files that you're interested in using.
In any case font awesome allows you to filter on free icons which is quite handy.
So if we check out this accessible icon here then you can download this icon as an SPG file a vector
which you can then scale as large as you like with some image processing software.
Now with those tools in hand I think you're all set to create something fantastic.
If you do please post it in the comments section below this video.
I'd love to see what you've made in the next lessons.
We're going to generate the vocabulary and the dictionary for a base classifier it's about time I get
some food so I'll see in the next lesson.
Take care.