This lesson is going to be a very very quick exercise.
So Allen sort of marked on sell here.
So the exercise will consist of checking if a word is part of the vocabulary.
So we've got 2500 words in the vocabulary and what I'd like to do is I'd like you to write the code
to check if a particular word is in this vocabulary as a challenge.
Can you write a line of code that checks if a particular word is part of the vocabulary your code should
return true if the word is among the two thousand five hundred words that comprise the vocabulary and
false otherwise.
And I'd like you to check the following words individually.
Machine learning fun learn data science app and Brewery.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video and give this a shot.
Did you have a go.
Well first let me show you the more inefficient way you can use our data frame of vocabulary words and
select the vocab on a school word column and then check if any of these words is equal to the word machine.
So if I hit shift enter on this I'll get a huge huge result.
And because I get a whole series of billions I can't check these all individually.
So what I would do then is wrap this in the any function.
So in this case I can find out.
Yes the word machine is amongst the vocabulary words that are most frequent now there's actually a better
way because we've already learned about sets.
So I'll just add a little comment here and I'll write in efficient the better way of doing this of checking
membership in a collection is to use the python sets I can convert our vocabulary words to a set by
using the set keyword and then feeding in our column vocab don't vocab word.
This converts our vocabulary to a set.
And this is very very efficient at checking membership and what you would do this is using this in keyword.
So if I have the word machine in single quotes followed by the in keyword and then are set here I get
a much much better way of checking for membership.
And this quite frankly is the better way.
Now if you're just executing one line of code you might be like well why is this inefficient right.
Why is using this any and this logical condition here inefficient.
And the thing is yes you wouldn't actually notice in this case right.
Yes.
So very very quick thing to execute.
But if you're running a loop if you're running something that runs thousands and thousands of times
then you will actually see a massive difference in the computer time using sets versus another type
of data structure going back up to our list let's see which words were actually among the 2500.
So a machine is true.
What about learning learning is false.
Right.
So learning is not amongst the words but that could be because of the stemming right.
So if I write learn instead then it is indeed included the word fun is as well the word data is as well
the word science is as well the word app also among the 2500 most common words in our data set and the
word brewery is not.
Yeah.
So this one is not included.
Brewer also not.
And brew also not nobody uses this word.
All right.
So that completes the challenge and the rationale for putting these challenges always into the lessons
is because programming is really like a sport.
Right.
You can't really read about it to get good and you can't just copy code to get good at it.
You actually have to do it and it's kind of similar how nobody really read the book on how to surf and
then jumps on a surfboard and you know surfs around and knows how to surf doesn't work.
Now it seems obvious with the surfing example but with programming you really have to think about it
in the same way.
And that's why I've got another exercise for you.
This one will fall into the realm of data exploration I see in the next lesson.