Okay so previously we've split and shuffled our data and put everything into a data frame.
Now let's create that sparse matrix to do that.
We will use three things we will use our extreme data frame.
We will use our why train penned a series and we will also use our vocabulary words.
Remember those.
They look like this.
Half vocabulary of two thousand five hundred words is stored in a data frame where the index are the
word ideas and the individual strings are in a column called vocab on a school word.
Now if we've got this data frame here and we want to know which word has word idea number three then
we can find that really really easily.
And we've done this before because all you'd have to specify is the index and the column and then you'd
get a string that reads e-mail but see we know the word and you want to know the word I.D..
Now we're asking this question in reverse.
We're asking it the other way around.
For example what is the word I.D. for the string Email.
An easy way to answer this question with some Python code is to create an index from this column here
from the vocab word column and then look up the position of a particular string in the index.
Let me show you what I mean.
I'll add a quick mark down somehow that reads create a sparse matrix for the training data.
Now to turn a particular column of our data frame into an index all we'd have to do is select our data
frame select the column and then wrap that whole thing into some parentheses and put it inside PD dot
index.
This will create an index from a particular column in a data frame that store this in a variable called
word on a score.
Index so word underscore index is equal to PD dot index parentheses vocab dot vocab underscore word.
Now we know we're dealing with a index with a penis index because the type of word on the school index
is pen does not call a dot indexes dot based on index and this index is composed of strings individual
strings like h TTP email get and so on.
The ones we saw earlier and I can verify this if I say pull up the C fourth word at index position number
three and check the type of this would end there you can see that indeed we're dealing with strings
inside our index if I come back up here and take a look at our first email hit hint ha X underscore
train data frame I can see that it's probably the stemmed word for Thursday right THQ now if I wanted
to note the word I d for t h you in r word and X I can simply take our index and use the get underscore
location method with t h you passed in as an argument and I see that this would that position of a three
hundred and ninety five.
So here's what we're gonna do we're going to take our X on unescorted train data frame and we'll take
the information contained therein to create our sparse matrix let's walk through how we would do it
with the first row that I've shown here the document idea for this row is four thousand eight hundred
and forty four we would be able to retrieve this information from our X train using our index since
our document ideas are stored as the index values since four thousand eight hundred forty four is the
very first entry the very first value in the index we would be able to just say give us the value of
the index at position 0 that's what we can use to fill in our document daddy of the sparse matrix now
what about the label what about the category that this email belongs to.
For that we simply look towards the Y on a squad train panda series there at the entry named four thousand
eight hundred and forty four we would either get a 1 or a 0.
So this email actually is a non spam email so it would have the label zero.
Now let's tackle that first stemmed would THQ for Thursday.
Here are word index comes into play.
We can get the word I.D. for this string THQ from our word index using that get location method.
And as we saw earlier Pete is at position number three hundred and ninety five for that last column
in the sparse matrix will simply add a 1.
And that's simply because we've counted one occurrence in fact on our first pass we'll add one for all
the occurrences will combine the occurrences later let's move on to that next would J you L. short for
July the document I.D. and the label of course status same four thousand eight hundred and forty four
and non spam and then we simply again use our word index and get the location for this particular string
and this string has the word I.D. four hundred and ninety four.
And again that cause a single time now because we've actually saved all our word I.D. as a CSB file
we can actually verify the word I.D. and Microsoft Excel or Google Sheets if I double click on this
file and I scroll down to what do we see.
Position four hundred and ninety four.
Then I see my stemmed word right here.
Next up it's that third would rodent.
So let's see what happens when we check whether the word rodent is part of how word index if we do this
word on this call index don't get location parentheses single quotes rodent we will actually get an
error and that's because the word rodent doesn't occur frequently enough to have made it into our vocabulary.
In other words the word rodent will not be added to our sparse matrix.
Instead we move on to the next word.
Our next word is in fact this one right here checking our index we find that the word I.D. is two thousand
three hundred eighty six.
This is essentially the workflow of how we will build up our sparse matrix.
We're going to put all of this work into a loop and then wrap all of that into a function.
So let's get on it.
Here's what our function will look like.
As always we're going to start out with RDF keyword define to create our function we'll call this function.
Make under school sparse on the school matrix a very imaginative name.
But it's very clear and I reckon this function should take three inputs a data frame an index for the
word I.D. So let's call this one indexed on a school Woods.
And then third it should take in the labels namely the y values.
So that'll be our third input.
But a colon at the end.
And now we can add a quick description of what this function should do.
Three double quotes hence a doc string and we'll provide a pretty very quick description right.
Returns sparse matrix as data from our inputs are gonna be as follows.
F is
a data frame with words in the columns
a document I.D. as an index parentheses x train or X on a school test then the indexed underscore words
parameter it's gonna be an index of words ordered by word I.D. the labels should be that category as
a series.
In other words why train or why the school test.
I think that do for doctoring.
Now let's add the body of the function.
Now as you can see from the docs string this function should work regardless of whether we feed in the
X unescorted train data frame or the X underscore test data frame so let's capture the kind of dimensions
of the data frame that is coming in as an input ahead of time.
I'll create a variable called number of rows and I'll be equal to the input.
Def dodge shape square brackets 0 and the number of columns and R underscore calls.
It's gonna be equal to Def dot shape parentheses what so that's that.
Now within the body of this function I know that I'm going to be doing a lot of lookups I'm going to
be checking if the words in the data frame are part of our vocabulary list.
There's a lot of checks they're going gonna be running as part of our loop.
So I want to be working with a data structure called a python set.
As you recall so I'll say word on the score set as equal to set parentheses indexed on a school words.
Here I'm creating a python set from our index that is being fed into this function as an argument.
Now I'm going to add a nested loop and within that loop I'm going to be adding dictionaries to a Python
list.
Let me have the outline of this loop first.
So I create my empty list first I'll call it dict list and have two square brackets and at the very
end of our function I'm going to return a panda's data frame that is going to be created from this list
that we're gonna be creating inside our loop.
Now in between these two lines of code it's gonna go the meat of our code.
There'll be two loops for I in range parentheses number of rows.
It'll be the outer loop and then there'll be an inner loop for J.
In range number of columns.
So we're gonna go through this data frame that we're feeding in row by row and column by column within
this inner loop.
We're gonna be spending a dictionary to our list every time the loop runs.
Here's how it's gonna work.
The very first thing that we're gonna do is we're gonna get hold of a particular string right.
And by a particular string I mean value in a particular cell because we're gonna iterate through this
data frame.
Row by row and column by column to get hold of a particular word we'll say D F dot I and square brackets.
I comma J in other words we'll be retrieving the word in the eighth row and the J column then we'll
check if that word that we picked out of our data frame is in our words set and if it is then we should
fetch the document Daddy.
The word Ida and the category the document I.D. is gonna be equal to the value of the index in the eye
through CPF dot index square brackets.
I the word I.D. is gonna be equal to the indexed words
get location parentheses word word is a string we can feed that into our get location method to retrieve
the position off this word in our index of words and that will be equal to our word.
Now it's time to get the category.
The category is gonna be r y values at well at the document I.D..
Right.
The y values we said we'd feed in as this labels parameter here so we'll see labels dot at square brackets
dock I.D. how we've got the three things that we need.
And from that we can create a little dictionary to put them all into one data structure and I'll call
that item equal to curly brackets single quotes label colon category comma single quotes doc on a school
I.D. colon doc on a school I.D. comma single quotes occurrence colon one comma single quotes word on
the score I.D..
Colon word I.D.
here I've created a dictionary with four entries the first one has the key label and it gets the y value
the category spam or not spam.
The second is our document I.D. which we'll get the document i.e. that we've extracted here the third
occurrence which is always gonna be equal to one because we're kind of doing a first pass on this.
And every time we discover a word that's part of our vocabulary we'll add it to our data frame.
And the last one has the word I.D. which we've retrieved here.
So now that we have a dictionary for a single item what we can do is take our dict underscore list and
append our item.
So appending all our dictionaries that we're creating as this loop runs individually to our list which
initially starts off empty but then gets populated and the data frame that we're returning from this
function gets created using this list.
Fantastic.
So here's the whole function body in its entirety.
Let me press shift enter on this.
And now let's try and run this baby My scroll down here into this next cell and the first thing there
is actually at some micro benchmarking code.
So.
Percent percent time this will time how long this cell will take to run and how I'm going to store the
results of this function call this data frame in a variable called spots on a school train on the school
DLF and I'll set that equal to make sparse matrix and you guessed it I'm going to give it the training
data right.
X on a school train comma would index comma Y on the school train.
And now let me hit shift enter and let's see what happens.
Now this cell can take quite a long time to execute its passing a lot of data and it's going through
another data frame that has thousands of cells and thousands of columns in it and it's going through
it one entry at a time on the machine that I'm currently on.
This cell takes between five to 10 minutes to run actually.
So I typically step away and grab a cross or a coffee or something and come back when it's done.
And I really encourage you to do the same.
There's no point in like waiting around.
This is actually one of those times where you'll see a dramatic performance difference whether or not
you're using a set data structure or not.
This check here in our inner loop runs thousands of times so any minimal difference in time that this
look up this check takes you'll actually see that build up to quite a significant amount of time.
If we go back up to our constants then you will spot another thing that really determines the size of
the dataset that we're working with.
Yes we imported approximately five thousand eight hundred e-mails that were passing and so on but one
of the key inputs one of the key constraints that we set is actually our vocabulary size.
We set this at 2500 and this vocabulary size will actually determine how big of a matrix we end up with
at the end.
The reason I picked 2500 is because it's relatively large it's going to make all computer work quite
hard but it's nowhere near sort of a commercial application spam filter for a youth based model.
If we were on an operating Hotmail or Gmail or something and we had to build this need based classifier
we would typically set our vocabulary size at 10000 to 15000 words and you can imagine how much data
we would have to crunch and how long we would have to run our machines for.
All right pretty chuffed to see that it's all done now.
It's six minutes and 28 seconds.
This means that we can take a look at the results see if they make sense.
Let's take a look at the first five rows here so sparse train underscored the F square brackets.
On 5.
Well give me the first five rows and here I can see my word ideas.
Each of these words occurs only once and all of these words occur in email.
Number four thousand eight hundred forty four which is a non spam email.
Let's take a look at the shape of this data frame now so sparse on this quatrain on a squat f dot shape
shift into shows us that we've got approximately four hundred and fifty thousand rows in this data frame.
That's an absolutely huge amount.
Almost half a million.
This is one of the reasons why this whole thing took a good six minutes to run on my machine the last
five rows of this data frame look like this spots on a squat train on the score D F square brackets
minus five colon closing square brackets.
Here you go.
All of these rows pertain to email number eight hundred and sixty.
Now one of the reasons why they're here.
Four hundred and fifty thousand rows in this data frame is because we've put each and every single word
from X on a squat train into a separate row.
So if in the same email we have the word those they occur twice it has two separate rows in this data
frame.
What we're gonna do now is we're going to combine these occurrences right.
If a word occurs more than one time in the same email we should combine it in the state of frame.
We should have an occurrence of two for this particular word I.D..