The first big Python programming concept that we're going to talk about are variables when you think
about programming and software at a high level.
It's all about manipulating data.
For example if you create a computer game then you'll need to track the Player Score the number of lives
that the player has and what level the player is on.
Of course all this data changes over time as we play the video game and the program runs.
So where do you as the programmer store this data and how do you track it the Python programming language
has a very convenient solution.
You would store the game score in a variable what is a variable.
A variable is just a container for data.
The important thing to understand about Python variables is that they both have a name and a value.
For example if I wanted to track my age inside a program I can simply create a variable called my age.
My age is the name of the variable but because my age is a container for data I can also give it a value
so I can stick the number 32 inside my H in programming lingo.
This is called assigning a value to a variable now as time passes and our program runs.
We might need to update this variable and we can do that simply by updating the value inside my age
with a new value so we can replace the value 32 with the value 33 now the question is what would this
look like in Python syntax inside the python intro notebook that we created.
We're going to create a variable called my age and give it a value just like this.
My age equals 32 this name my age is now how we can refer to the number 32 to display the value inside
the my age variable below the cell.
I'm simply going to write print my age
hitting shift enter on the keyboard we'll evaluate the code in the cell and then display this value
contain inside the my age variable.
Now suppose our program is running and we need to update the value inside this variable.
We can change this value of my age simply by assigning a new value to it say with my age equals 33.
If I write print my age now and hit shift enter we'll see the value 33 print it out.
No surprises there now.
Variables are super handy because you can do calculations with them.
For example if we write print my age divided by three
and had shift enter we'll see eleven point zero printed out below the cell.
Also we can take these two concepts that we just covered and take it up a step in complexity.
Let's say we want to update the value of my age like this.
My age is equal to my age plus 1.
Now if it's your first time learning to program this line of code is going to look very strange but
what's going on is that we're taking the previous value of my age namely the value 33 on the right hand
side of the equals sign and then adding one to it with that equals sign.
Operator we are storing this new value 34 33 plus 1 inside of my age on the left hand side.
In other words we are overwriting the previous value stored inside the.
My age variable if we write to print my age now and he'd shift into we'll see our value update to 34
so let's do a quick exercise on using and manipulating variables in python as a challenge.
Can you create a variable called restaurant bill and set its value equal to thirty six point seventeen.
Then create a variable called service charge and set its value equal to zero point one to five 12 and
a half percent seems to be the standard rate that restaurant suggest as a tip in London these days.
Finally print out the amount of tip below the cell that you would need to add to the bill.
I'll give you a few seconds to figure this out.
So pause the video okay.
So here's the solution for part 1.
Well the right restaurant bill is equal to thirty six point one seven for part two.
Well right.
Service charge is equal to zero point one two five and four part three will right.
Print parentheses.
Restaurant bill.
Times service charge
when I hit shift enter.
I'll see that the value of the tip is four point five two.
Now all that's left to do is asking the waiter if the restaurant is pocketing the money or if the tip
really does go through to the staff.
Now one thing that could happen to you at this point is that you've made a typo in programming.
Everything is case sensitive.
And if our variables names didn't match exactly to how they were defined we're gonna get some unexpected
errors.
For example if this capital B in my print statement instead was a lower case b and we had hit shift
enter we would have gotten the following error name error restaurant bill.
It's not defined and this is because this restaurant bill and this restaurant bill are considered to
be completely different entities.
So you want to make sure that you never have any typos in your variable names.
The same of course is true.
If we miss out a letter.
So for example if we wrote service charge instead of service charge then we would get exactly the same
error our variable is not defined.
In other words Python can't find something that matches this name.
So let's put that our back where it belongs.
Now that we've learned a thing or two about Python programming and variables let's revisit the code
that we wrote when we were estimating our movie revenue since I saved my previous work in a python notebook
and added it to the email projects folder.
I'm just going to open that now
now.
Even though this code is a little bit more complex than what we have written just now.
Can you spot the variables in this piece of code.
Now there's actually quite a few.
And you'll notice that the variables are often to the left hand side of an equal sign.
So for example data is a variable the capital X is a variable the lower case Y is also a variable.
All of these variables are holding on to data but in contrast the variables my age and restaurant bill
these x and y variables are not holding on to a single value they are holding onto lots and lots of
values at the same time.
And I'm going to show you guys how that works and a little bit put before I do that.
Let's talk about another key concept that we need to understand when working with variables namely data
types in machine learning and programming more generally we'll be working with different kinds of data.
We'll be working with text decimal numbers tables of data columns of data images sounds video all sorts
and a programming language like Python will categorize this data.
In other words different kinds of data like text or decimal numbers and whole numbers will have a different
category.
In other words they will have a different data type.
Now you can think of data types like this children's toy where you have to fit the right shape into
the whole.
So for example when you try to put a decimal number somewhere where Python expects to have a string
you'll often find that you have a problem.
And this makes sense when you think about it intuitively.
So you have some Python code that makes a calculation.
So you're adding two things together.
If those two things are numbers then you're good five plus 10 is 15.
But if one of those things is another kind of data like I don't know a home address you have a problem.
Your program will crash or it's going to do something very unexpected.
Trying to evaluate five plus 21 James Street.
It doesn't make any sense now for the most part.
Python will actually take care of the data types behind the scenes so it's not something that's kind
of at the forefront of the programming syntax of the Python code.
But let me show you how you can actually see the data type in Jupiter notebook because we can ask python
what category something belongs to by writing type parentheses and then putting something between those
two parentheses So for example if I write type 33 and had shift into the type of this whole number is
int I I.A. I.A. stands for integer which makes sense.
But there's also quite a few other types with maybe less intuitive names.
So let me introduce a couple of them if we write type thirty three point six and had shift into we get
to see that decimal numbers are classified differently.
Decimal numbers are classified as floats or floating point numbers floating point numbers are the type
that you will usually be working with every time you're dealing with numbers that have a decimal point.
Now let me show you what the type for text is called so can write type and then between the parentheses
I'm going to open the single quotes and add my name when I hit shift enter.
I can see that type for text is called as TR an SDR stands for string the word string is just computer
jargon for a piece of text or a sequence of characters and the way that you can tell that something
is considered to be a string is by the fact that strings are always always surrounded by either single
or double quotes and Jupiter notebook is actually also very helpful with the syntax highlighting so
that the python code that is considered to be a string actually has a different color.
So in this case the string is marked as red.
Let's take another look at the python code that we wrote previously and see if we can spot a string.
Here we can see that when we were writing PD dot read underscore see us v. open parentheses the value
that we specified between these two parentheses was a string.
It was a piece of text marked by the single quotes and the same is true for the column names production
underscore a budget underscore USD and it's also true for the X label on our graph and all the other
parts where the code is highlighted in red.
Okay so far so good.
We've just introduced you to a whole bunch of new programming jargon variables data types I.A. for integers
float for decimal numbers SDR for pieces of text or strings.
But how did data types relate to variables.
What's the connection between the two well if the data has a certain type then so does the variable
containing the data because after all a variable is just a container now for example let's see what
the data type is for the variable my age so I can write type and then between the parentheses I'm going
to supply my age and had shift enter and here we can see that because my age holds on to whole numbers
the data type of the variable is also integer or I.A..
Now let's take a look at the data type for restaurant bill
and I'm sure it's no surprise that because restaurant bill is holding on to a decimal number thirty
six point one seven.
It's a type float if I was to create a new variable called my name and set it equal to the string.
Philip I can write type my name hit shift enter and I can see that the My name variable is a string.
Now let's take another look at the notebook where we ran our regression and let me ask you this what
do you think is the data type of the variables data capital X and lowercase y.
This is the mystery that we're gonna be exploring over the next couple of lessons I'll see you there.