Okay so step one was calculating the basic probabilities it was gathering information on the frequencies
of an event and figuring out the probability of that event happening.
Based on that in step two we're going to talk about a concept called the joint probability.
So you flip a coin twice what are the chances that you get heads both times.
What's the probability that you get heads two times in a row.
The way you see this written in mathematical syntax is with this little upside down use symbol this
symbol stands for.
And also every textbook out there will refer to an event like the result of a coin flip with a letter.
So you'll see this written as what's the probability of A and B A is getting heads on the first flip
and B is getting heads on the second flip.
In our case if probability is a new topic for you then maybe just quickly pause the video and figure
out what the probability is of getting heads two times in a row.
Did you have a go.
If so how did you figure this out.
What was your approach.
One way that you can solve this kind of problem is to draw matrix.
This matrix has all the possible combinations in it and there you can see that there's a total of four
possible outcomes with the coin flipping problem from our little chart here.
We can see that both coins showing heads only happens 1 in 4 times so therefore the probability of getting
heads on two flips in a row is 25 percent.
But you know what.
There's a better way to calculate a joint probability.
All we have to do in our coin flipping example is to multiply the probability of getting heads times
the probability of getting heads since we have a 50/50 chance of getting heads it's zero point five
times zero point five which is zero point to five or 25 percent.
In other words we're multiplying the probability of A times the probability of B.
And that's how we can get the probability of A and B.
Now I think this formula is really really handy when you don't want to draw a huge matrix because say
you want to calculate the probability of getting heads on a coin flip four times in a row.
Well simply by applying this formula you know it's zero point five times zero point five times zero
point five times the 2.5 which is equal to about six point to 5 percent.
So now let's use this technique with a dice pause the video and as a challenge work out the probability
of rolling a 6 on a dice like this three times in a row.
Did you have a go with a six sided die.
You essentially have a 1 in 6 chance to roll any particular number.
So rolling a 6 3 times in a row has a joint probability of 1 6th times 1 6 times 1 6th and that's equal
to approximately zero point for six percent.
So less than one half of a percent.
Very very unlikely.
Now I know these were some very very simple examples just now but I hope you can see how rolling more
and more six years in a row gets less and less likely and the same with flipping coins right.
It would be strange to see somebody get heads after heads after heads after heads on a fair coin that
is now I think personally.
This is like the very friendly and simple side of probability but it's still interesting because let
me ask you a question.
Imagine you and I are hanging out on a Friday night chilling flipping coins and talking about probability
as as we do.
And I've just flipped my coin twice both times.
I got heads.
What's the probability that I could.
Heads on my third Flip as well.
Is it 1 1/2 times 1 1/2 times one half or zero point 1 2 5.
No no no no no.
It is not.
Most definitely not.
And the reason is is that the past coin flips don't affect the next coin flip each coin flip is independent
the probability of me getting heads on that third flip is still 50 percent.
How this might seem obvious to you but intuitively I've seen a lot of people just sort of accept this
idea of independence.
Intelligent people too.
It's like you know people don't want to accept this.
And if you don't believe me you can actually observe this behavior for yourself.
All you need to do is go to a roulette table in a crowded casino and just wait and watch just watch
people.
Now if you've never played roulette or you're not familiar with this game in the casino people spin
this wheel and people win when they've predicted where the ball will land people can bet on a number
of things but they can also bet on the colors right the color that the ball will land on.
So in this game a lot of people love betting on a particular color.
Right.
Red or black.
Will the ball end up on the red or on the black for example.
Now when the ball has been landing on black for a few times in a row you will see that people increasingly
start betting on red because they think it's the more likely outcome for the next spin.
Intuitively many people think it's been black four times in a row on the next spin the ball just has
to land on red.
Right.
But the truth is red is not more likely.
Why.
Because each spin of the roulette wheel is independent.
The wheel itself doesn't have any memory of the previous outcomes.
OK.
So that's a real world example of this concept of independence in action.
And we've actually covered quite a few important concepts in probabilities so far.
Already we've covered basic probability which was very much based on observing the frequency of a particular
event we've covered this idea of independence where two events have nothing to do with one another.
And finally we've also covered this idea of joint probability and what we saw was that for independent
events like rolls of dice and coin tosses the formula for both A and B happening was simply by multiplying
the probability of A times the probability of B.
Now let's take this discussion back to spam classification in order to work out the probability of an
email being spam we should look at something other than the frequency of spam emails out there in the
wild.
Right.
We should look at the contents of each individual email.
This means looking at the message itself which is well where it gets interesting.
Now if you fire up Hotmail or e-mail right now and you look through your e-mail spam folder what kind
of words do you tend to see in the message bodies for these e-mails.
I bet you can kind of spot a pattern.
You can spot certain themes coming up over and over again in your spam emails.
Certain words are just much more likely to come up in spam e-mail than in regular legitimate e-mail.
I'm thinking of words like free access Viagra loan online pharmacy adult great offer winner casino Bitcoin.
What have you like when was the last time a friend of yours send you a legitimate email about an online
pharmacy or free bitcoins for example.
So clearly there's going to be a clue in the message body whether an email is going to be a spam email
or are not just purely based on what the emails about.
So imagine a new email arrives in your inbox.
The e-mail body contains the word VIAGRA.
Should this e-mail be classified as spam.
Let me rephrase that question given that this e-mail contains the word VIAGRA.
What's the probability of this email being spam this question that I just posed.
It's all about conditional probability.
And this is where things are going to start getting pretty wild.
Conditional Probability is in my personal opinion both something unintuitive and difficult and we're
about to get our hands dirty with some of these meaty statistics.
Oh yes.
You see this is really really worthwhile doing actually many of the basic statistical concepts like
probability independence joint probability and conditional probability are used everywhere in machine
learning.
Even if you don't see it right away.
Even our box standard linear regression models come straight out of a statistics textbook.
The nice thing about the naive bayes classifier is that we don't use statistics and probability under
the hood we're gonna use probability explicitly our naive bayes algorithm uses statistics in its raw
and pure format to classify email spam and conditional probability is at the very heart of it conditional
probability measures the probability of some event given that another event has occurred.
The mathematical syntax looks like this.
What we have here reads the probability of a given B for example what's the probability of me getting
heads on my next coin flip given that my last coin flip was heads or we just talked about this the first
coin flip doesn't affect the second coin flip.
Sort of two events are conditionally independent.
The probability of me getting heads on that next flip is still 50 percent.
But but but what if the two events are in fact dependent.
Going back to our email example what's the probability of an email being spam given that it contains
the word VIAGRA in this case the probability of the email being spam actually depends on the probability
that the email contains the word via Gra.
What.
That sounds weird right now.
I don't expect you to accept this at face value.
Let me try and explain this with a different example where the intuition is is less murky.
It's it's much more clear.
Say you look out the window and it's cloudy outside.
What's the probability of it raining today.
In other words given that it is cloudy.
What is the probability of rain now in this picture.
It looks like it's about to rain any minute but why rely on eyesight when you can have a mathematical
formula.
You see like all good things.
Conditional Probability has a mathematical formula associated with it and here it is the probability
of rain.
Given that it is cloudy is equal to the probability of rain and it being cloudy divided by the probability
of it being cloudy hmm.
OK this looks like a very very strange formula indeed but important learning point here is that the
probability of it raining depends on the probability of it being cloudy and that's the bottom part of
the fraction here.
The bottom part of the fraction is the probability of it being cloudy.
If it was cloudy for 250 days a year last year then this part of the fraction is 250 divided by 365.
Now what about the top part of the fraction.
Well guess what.
This is our old friend joint probability.
It's the amount of overlap between the days that were cloudy and the days that it rained so in London.
It rains on approximately 107 days per year.
But you know what two of those rainy days were actually fairly sunny and I saw a rainbow.
So then number of days where it was both raining and cloudy was only one hundred and five.
So the top part of that fraction is going gonna be 105 out of 365 now doing this calculation gives us
a conditional probability of approximately 42 percent the probability of it raining given that it is
cloudy outside is 42 percent according to this formula.
I know this may sound a little bit trivial but the really really cool thing is that what we've just
done is calculate the probability of something knowing something else and that sounds a lot like fundamental
machine learning right.
Knowing the movie budget we can calculate expected movie revenue.
Knowing the number of rooms we can calculate the expected property price.
Think of it being cloudy outside has a feature and think of it raining today as your target your wine.
So I hope this example shows how conceptually conditional probability is actually widely applicable
to machine learning and if you open any statistics textbook out there you'll see that conditional probability
is expressed in very general terms just like this.
The probability of a given B is equal to the probability of A and B over the probability of B what would
this formula look like in our spam example substituting for A and B we get something like this the probability
of an email being spam given that it contains the word by Agora is equal to the probability of an email
being spam and the probability of the email containing the word VIAGRA over the probability of an email
containing the word VIAGRA.
Looking at this formula there's one problem though and that's the top term in this fraction the joint
probability calculating the joint probability was super easy when we were dealing with dice and with
coins because each event was independent.
In that case we could just multiply the probabilities of the events together but with dependent events
like clouds and rain or email and the word by Agora this calculation is no longer so simple and that's
why to calculate the conditional probability and create our spam classifier we have to take it to the
next level.
We have to use Bayes theorem.