In this lesson we're going to play around with our gradient descent algorithm a little bit and we're
gonna see how it is affected by our initial guessed by our starting value also so we're gonna be building
on our Python programming skills by covering some of the more advanced features of functions in Python.
The first thing we're gonna do is we're going to generate a new cost function and kind of go into a
second example.
So I'm going to change the cell at the bottom here again to mark down so that we have a nice clean section
heading and we're going to call it example to
multiple minima vs. initial guess and advanced functions.
The cost function that we're gonna be working with is going to look like this.
It's gonna be two dollars lines G of X is equal to x to the power of four minus four X squared plus
five.
And then to Dollar Signs at the end.
So again we're gonna be using LaTeX markdown to write our function in mathematical notation.
So as we've talked about before remember that latex uses tags to mark text for special formatting and
there's two tags here.
Right.
There's an opening tag of two dollar signs and there is a closing tag of two dollar signs.
Now let's get stuck into the python code.
So the first thing we're gonna do is we're going to make some data and when to create a variable called
X underscore too since this is gonna be our second example.
And again we're gonna be using num PIs Lynn space to generate our values.
So I'm gonna have value starting at minus 2 going to 2 and I'm going to space them out with about 1000
values.
Now as a challenge can you write the G effects function and the derivative the DG of X function in Python.
So remember you gonna be writing two functions with the.
Def keyword and applying that power rule that we covered in the previous lesson.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video and write these two functions
ready here's the solution.
It s d f key word G F X colon return x two time symbols power of four minus four times x two times symbols
two plus five.
So that's our first function but the derivative of this function applying the power rule it's gonna
be div f DG of X colon and then it's return 4 times X to the power of three minus eight times X so four
gets multiplied by two becomes eight and the constant drops out.
And that's it.
And head shift into and if you get this error that I've gotten you've got to scroll all the way up to
where you're importing num pi and just hit shift enter on the cell again because N.P. was not recognized
by Python because I haven't come back to this notebook in a while now I can click back into the cell
and hit shift into the run just fine.
Now it's time to plot the cost function for this example.
I'm going to scroll back up for a second here and I'm going to grab this cell here and I'm going to
copy it because we're gonna be reusing some of this code to copy this cell and I'm going to come here
and go to edit paste cell above but when I have to make a couple of changes here.
So first off I'm going to change the x axis to go from negative two to two and the y axis to go from
zero point five to 5.5 and then I'm going to change the label here on the y axis as well to g effects
and of course on my plot I'm going to take X and the score two and geophysics and the score two and
similarly for my derivative the Y label is gonna be DG of X and for my x axis I'm going to go from negative
2 to 2 as well and for my y axis I'm going to go from negative 6 to 8 and when it comes to plotting
a plot x underscore 2 and DG of X underscore 2 minute shift enter.
See what I get what are so these two plots.
Help us visualize our second examples cost function.
So what can we observe here.
What can we see.
Well there's a couple of things that are of note right.
So if we look at the chart on the left we can see that there are two minima.
There are two places where the cost is very low.
One here and the other one here also looking at the right hand chart we see that the derivative intersects
the x axis on three points right.
One here one here at x equals zero and one here so there are three points when the slope is equal to
zero.
And those three points correspond to this minimum this minimum but also this maximum here.
Now it's gonna be very interesting how this affects are gradient descent algorithm but before we start
playing around with the starting values we're going to make some modifications to our Python code because
this is a really really good time to talk about some of the advanced features of functions in Python
programming.
Now we've written our code already for the gradient descent algorithm but we're gonna do is we're in
a scroll up
and we're gonna take this cell and copy it
and then we're gonna insert that cell above and we're in a good position to start modifying this little
bit of code.
I really can't wait to show you some more advanced Python programming features when it comes to functions
because Python functions are actually incredibly powerful and versatile things.
And in this lesson we're going to cover how to pass a function as an argument how to make an argument
optional by specifying a default value and also how to have a function return multiple values.
I'm going to show you all these things by turning our gradient descent algorithm into our very own function.
In fact let's add some markdown to show this in our Python notebook.
So I'm want to move this cell this one here at the bottom and across that up arrow here when I move
this cell up and then I'm going to convert this cell to markdown and then I want to use two hashtags
and just put down gradient descent as a python function.
There we go.
OK let's get started.
The first thing we're gonna do is write our function header as always.
So it's gonna be D F and then we're to give our function the name let's call it gradient descent.
Yeah.
Followed by two parentheses and a colon.
Now our gradient descent function is gonna be taking for arguments the derivative function itself a
value for an initial guess the learning rate and the precision.
So let's put these in as parameters between these two parentheses.
So the first we said was the derivative function I'm going to call this derivative underscore func then
the initial guess
comma then a multiplier or learning rate and then the precision if you're looking at this then you're
going to be maybe wondering about my intentions here.
What do I mean by putting this derivative function as a parameter here.
See the thing about Python is that a function is actually a full blown object.
Yeah.
So functions are stored in a piece of the computer's memory all on their own.
Just like other objects are.
And this means that you can stake a function in a variable and pass functions around our program.
So in our gradient descent function this derivative underscore func parameter will be our place holder
for the actual derivative function and you'll see this when we call this function.
So now let's fill in our function Bonnie in order to make all of these lines part of our function body.
We have to invent them because the indentation is how Python knows that these lines should be part of
our function.
Now to indent a whole group of lines what you can do is you can select them and then use a keyboard
shortcut.
So on windows you can press control and then and then this key here to invent the whole group.
And then on Mac instead of control you simply press command and the square bracket key.
Let me show you something I select all of these up to the break statement here and then I get a press
control and then the square bracket key and they all move over by 1.
So now they're all part of our function body.
That's pretty neat.
Right now I'm going to modify these lines so our new X will be equal to to the initial guess that we're
making here.
Yeah.
So the initial guess is our place holder.
And when our function gets called we're gonna supply an initial guess and we're going to set new X equal
to that initial guess.
I don't need this line anymore.
And I also don't need this line anymore and I don't need this line anymore as well because these variables
will get their value when the function is being called and I'm going to keep these around but I won't
have to make a modification hit our derivative function here isn't gonna be called DFA anymore right.
It's gonna have the name of our place holder.
Right.
It's gonna be called derivative underscore func and the same.
Yeah it's gonna be the case down here.
This is the other occurrence where we're referring to our derivative function.
So this is gonna be also called derivative on the school func to delete this comment here.
Don't need this anymore.
And then when it comes to graphing there's another reference here to our previous example.
But now I'm going to replace this again with derivative on the scroll func.
I'm also going to take away this print statement.
Don't need this anymore as well.
And then I'm also gonna delete these print statements here.
We don't need these anymore as well.
But there's one additional thing that I do want to add.
I'm just gonna delete a couple of these lines here to tidied up a little bit better so we can actually
tell what's going on and now I can add that last thing to our gradient descent function that I wanted
to add.
I'm going to add my return statement.
So this is the keyword return followed by whatever the function spits out.
Now what do we want this function to return.
What are the important things that we want out of our gradient descent function.
We want three separate things three separate values that we're interested in.
So we want the new x value we want the list of x values and we want our list of slopes that we calculated
because our list of x values and our list of slope values is what we're going to be using for graphing.
And obviously our minimum is going to be that new x value that we spit out.
So one of the easiest ways of having a function return more than one value is simply by having our return
values separated by a comma.
So new X comma X list comma slope on a score list will return three values so let's press shift enter
now and see if we get any errors.
Okay so far so good.
Now it's time to call this function.
This is where the rubber meets the road as they say right.
Test since we have multiple return values we can store these return values in three separate variables.
Someone to call these variables local on the score Min karma list on the score X karma derive on the
score list.
Yeah.
So my function is gonna be returning three values and these are gonna be stored in this order in three
variables.
Okay so time to call this function gradient on the score descent.
Open parentheses.
Now it's time to supply those for arguments.
So the question is what are those gonna be.
So let's apply these arguments by their position.
The first thing that will pass into our function is going to be well another function it's gonna be
another function we're going to pass in our derivative function which is kind of crazy right.
Like we're passing in a function to another function like it's no big deal.
So I already mentioned that functions are just objects in python just like pretty much anything else.
So our derivative function is an object and it's got the name DG That's it.
So if we want to get technical what's in fact happening here is that we're giving our gradient descent
function a pointer to our DG function that we've defined in the cell above.
Now if you've got a programming background then you might be interested to know that what we're doing
here is we're not copying our DG object we're simply pointing to our DG object how that supplier other
three variables let's have our starting position be zero point five let's have our learning rate be
zero point zero two and let's have our precision to be zero point zero zero one and let's add some print
statements for good measure.
Yeah print local Min occurs at Como local on the score minus print out that first value and let's also
print out the number of steps yes or the number of steps is gonna be.
Well it's gonna be the length of our list so I can have alien o the length function of our list list
on the score X so this will include the initial guess plus the number of times that the loop ran that's
gonna be the number of values that are gonna be stored in this list right here and how as a challenge
can you figure out what the problem is if I tried to run this as it is and also what I would have to
fix in order for our function to run properly because there's something that I've missed in our gradient
descent function that I have not taken into account yet and here's the solution so this variable here
step multiplier exists locally within our function so it only exists within the function itself but
the problem is is that it hasn't been defined anywhere.
This means that Python actually does not know what this name refers to hence short we've got to be consistent
with our naming here.
So multiplier is the name of the parameter which we actually want to use we cannot use the name step
multiplier which we've defined earlier and that's the fix.
So let me press shift enter to rerun the cell.
Now I can press shift enter again to run the cell below and here's our answer our local minimum occurs
at one point four and the number of steps it took to get there was twenty three.
So our function is working now looking at how we're calling this function here.
Gradient underscore to send parentheses DG 0 5 zero point zero to zero point zero zero one is is not
very readable.
Yeah this is something I really really dislike when writing code because these numbers just appear like
magic numbers.
Looking at this we we don't know what they mean.
Right.
We'd have to actually know what the function definition is.
It's much nicer to add keywords to these arguments and we can do that by modifying our function call.
So I'm going to take this code here.
Copy it paste the done here for reference and then I can fill in the names of these arguments.
So this was our derivative on the score funk can be equal to DG our initial underscore guess it's gonna
be equal to.
I'm going to say uh zero point five and then I can uh I can actually hit enter here and go to a new
line.
This won't affect the function call at all but at least that's gonna make our code a lot more readable.
So this was our multiplier
and this was our precision let's see what happens when our initial guess has a starting value of negative
zero point five.
Let's run it now so we can already see a difference here.
So the first time the local minimum occurs at one point four and the second time round the local minimum
occurs at negative one point four.
But uh before we investigate this let's talk a little bit more about arguments.
We already know that arguments are how a function gets its inputs.
Arguments are how objects are sent to a function as an input.
And I promise to show you how we can give our arguments a default value and also make some of these
arguments optional and to do that we're gonna have to modify that header in our gradient descent function
because this is where we can specify our default values so let's specify a default value for this multiplier
here.
We can do that by setting it equal to zero point zero two and to specify a default value for the position.
We also can just simply set it equal to zero point zero zero one.
And now our gradient descent function has two required arguments.
The derivative function and the initial guess and two optional arguments they're optional because they
have default values.
So let's call this function again this time we're only gonna specify the required arguments.
Now copy this code here pasted here and I'm going to delete
this part of my function call so I'm only going to specify the derivative function and the initial guess.
Now I'm going to change this guest to minus zero point one and let's see where we end up.
If you're getting this error.
Yeah.
If you're getting gradient descent is missing to require positional arguments.
Despite having added this code it's because you haven't rerun the cell.
So remember to press shift enter on the cell to rerun this code and make sure that our Jupiter notebook
is updated and then come down here and run this one and you should see that we end up at the same minimum
as before but this time it takes us thirty four steps instead of twenty three.
Now one thing that you might try is you might want to rerun this cell here.
Question is will this still work.
And the answer is yes it will.
Even though we don't have to specify a value for the multiplier and the precision we can do.
So I can add an extra zero here to the precision and make our step size even smaller by changing it
from point zero to two point zero one and I can overwrite the default values that this function usually
has and we can see that having made the step size smaller and our cut off point even more precise now
the number of steps increases to 56.
So this is really really cool right.
We've got really powerful capabilities with functions.
We've got a very descriptive way we can call them.
We've got multiple outputs that we can store in variables just separated by commas and we can have optional
arguments so we can give default values to some of our parameters in the function when we create it.
But all this stuff with arguments and optional arguments it's kind of hidden from view.
Right.
I mean how would you know what the arguments are for a function that you've never seen before.
Wouldn't it be nice to be able to pull up this information really quickly and really easily inside Jupiter
notebook without having to guess.
Well I got you covered.
Let me show you a neat little trick in Jupiter notebook.
So if I put my cursor over my function here gradient descent and then I hit shift and tab on my keyboard.
So I'm holding on to shift key and then pressing tab then to put a notebook will pull up a little bit
of documentation a little bit of information on this function so I can see here.
I need four arguments I can see what the arguments are called derivative func initial guess multiplier
precision and I can even see what the default values are for my other two arguments.
Isn't this really really cool to put a notebook is actually smart enough to give us some information
on our function right there and then.
And it doesn't just work with our own function.
So a scroll up and pick out map plot lib scatter function in this notebook and give this a try shift
and then tab on your keyboard.
Go on.
And when I wait for you right here
did you did you try to in a couple of places you might have noticed something.
Sometimes it's really really informative.
And other times it's not.
So let me show you what I mean.
So I've got my Python code here from our previous example.
If I go to scatter and press shift tab then I get a wonderful description here with very very detailed
information on the signature
I can click this little plus sign to even take a look at all this information here and all this documentation
for four hours kind of function.
And similarly when I go up here to PDT dot figure and I press shift tab again I get a wonderful description
here a wonderful signature.
These are all the things in the header and clicked a little plus sign and I get really really cryptic
information right face color the background color if not provided.
Defaults to our si figure face color.
Fair enough right.
Cool.
Let's go to this plot functionality here.
Right.
If I press shift tab on this all I get is PDT.
Dot plot and then args and KW args so this isn't really informative and I do have to kind of go to the
documentation here and really really figure out what it is but it's not all that readable right.
So I mean you can be scrolling around here for a long time trying to make sense of all this.
So at this point you're probably much better off going to the website of the official documentation
where you can actually read up on this in a much nicer format and you can search on this page etc..
In other words if you want to know how something like plant or a subplot works you're probably still
better off in pulling up the documentation for these things in your browser.
But speaking of plots it's time to chart our gradient descent.
So let me copy the cell that generates these charts here.
Edit Copy cells scroll all the way down and then paste the cells above.
This is our chance to play around with the starting values and our algorithm.
So I made a comment here.
Calling gradient descent function and I'm going to edit this comment here.
Plotting function and derivative and scatter plot.
Side by side then I'm going to take this one here and copy it and I'm going to paste it here.
I am going to change our initial guess from minus zero point one to positive zero point one.
How.
Let's add a couple of lines of code to have that scatter plot on here as well.
This is gonna be PDT.
Dot scatter.
And here we had our list of x values and then our cost function.
G parentheses list underscore X but we can't leave it like that because we're doing some calculations.
Remember and the power function doesn't play nice with a list type.
So when we convert it to and p dot array and then I'm going to have it inside our G function.
So this is going to be the input I'm nesting two functions here.
Instead of splitting it out and then we're not a color gonna say color is red the size of the dots will
be one hundred as before and we gonna give it some transparency as well.
Alpha equals zero point six and then a closing parentheses for the scatter plot.
Now transparency looks pretty good on the other one as well.
Someone at alpha equals zero point eight on our cost function chart as well.
And let's do something similar for our derivative chart below.
So it's also gonna be a set kind of plot peel T dot scatter and it's gonna be a list of x values again
for the x axis.
And then what was previously our slope list we've stored in a variable called the Riv underscore list.
We're gonna go again with the red color for the chart.
We're gonna go with size one hundred and alpha zero point five.
And this sky blue line is also gonna get some transparency with alpha equals zero point six.
Now let's run the cell.
See what happens and walla.
This is what we get.
We get our initial starting value up here at zero point 1 and we're descending to the minimum here.
And on our derivative it looks like this.
We're gonna go down down down down down down down until our slope is equal to zero.
Okay so let's try out a couple of different starting values for our gradient descent function in this
example.
So here we've started at zero point one and we've converged to this minimum here.
This right hand minimum here.
Let's see what happens when we start out with the value too.
So I'm going to say my initial guess up here is gonna be the value to and I'm going to hit shift into
in this case our gradient descent algorithm goes down here and we end up at the very very same minimum.
And if we start out somewhere else say like negative one point eight
then we end up at this minimum.
Instead we end up in the left hand minimum and we'll end up in this left hand minimum as well.
If we start out at minus zero point one so if we start at minus zero point one we end up here as well
we end up in the left hand minimum.
So what we can learn from this what we can see from this example is that our algorithm isn't perfect
it's got some weaknesses because conceptually it's a little bit disturbing.
Right.
That we end up at completely different minima when we start out at positive zero point one and negative
zero point one.
So if we're unlucky in our choice of initial starting position we can actually end up in very very different
places.
So we can see in this example that the path of the descent can be very very much influenced by that
initial guess in certain situations.
Now would you like to venture a guess what happens when we have an initial starting value of zero doesn't
think about what would happen with our gradient descent if we feed in the value zero into our initial
guess before you run the algorithm let's try it out.
So I'm gonna say instead of zero point one I want to start a zero and press shift into what ends up
happening is that we don't descend to any of the two minima here.
Instead we end up sitting right here on the maximum.
And that's because the slope at this very very point is also equal to zero.
And we can see this here on the right hand function here on the slope of the cost function.
Remember a gradient descent algorithm stops running once the slope is equal to zero.
So this problem is also related to this sensitivity to the starting position.
Right.
The sensitivity of the path of the gradient descent algorithm to that initial guess.
Now in this case both of the two minima have the same cost.
Right the cost is equal at both of these two minima but we can also imagine a very different situation
if our cost function look something like this then we would have to minima one of which has a much lower
cost than the other one.
One of these is a global minimum.
And the other one is a local minimum.
So the local minimum actually has a higher cost than the global minimum.
But our gradient descent would not discover the global minimum if the initial starting point was on
the right hand side of that local maximum of that small hump right there in the middle of the chart.
Okay.
So we've outlined the problem.
What's the solution.
Right how do we get around this weakness.
Well the easiest thing to do would be to simply try out multiple different starting values and see if
they end up in the same place.
Think of this as like injecting a little bit of randomness into our gradient descent so we could do
this by choosing a whole host of like random starting values and then running our gradient descent over
and over again to see where it ends up.
And this might be an approach you could take if you actually don't know what the cost function looks
like right.
If you don't know where the minimum is.
This might be something that you want to try.
Another thing we could do is to try a completely different algorithm to find the minimum.
Right.
Because let's face it this particular version of gradient descent isn't our only option.
Similar to how we can try a bunch of different random starting points other algorithms have randomness
baked into them.
One of the versions of gradient descent that has more randomness baked in is called Stochastic gradient
descent.
And this is in contrast what we're currently doing which is called Batch gradient descent but the thing
to note about any of these approaches is that none of them are perfect right.
You'll find that no matter which approach you choose it has certain strengths and it has certain weaknesses
and it's important to understand what the pros and cons are of of each approach.
So on that note we're not done yet examining this particular algorithm.
Our Batch gradient descent algorithm might actually face another problem and this is what we're gonna
be looking at next how I'll see you in the next lesson.
Take care.