Now that we've covered the theory behind the naive bayes classifier in detail it's time to get our hands
dirty and write some python code in this lesson.
We've got a big and important topic coming up namely how do you get your code to talk to your computer's
operating system.
How do you read a file.
Now a lot of this knowledge is going to be transferable to whatever programming language you're working
in on whatever project you're working in.
But with Python and machine learning you're gonna be working with a lot of data and that data is gonna
be stored somewhere.
Most likely that's going to be stored locally on your computer or it's gonna be stored on a server for
many of our projects our Python code is going to need to interact with our own computer's operating
system and actually be able to read the files from the disk.
So while we're on this topic about learning how to read files we're also going to cover quite a few
other topics as well namely file paths File Locations file extensions.
We're also going to see how our email data is actually structured and we're also going to see how we
can extract a message body from a raw email.
But first things first.
Whenever you're referencing a file in your python code you're going to need to specify exactly where
that file is and what that file is called.
And this means you have to specify two things namely the file path and the file name in the lesson resources
that you've downloaded and added to your projects folder.
I included a practice email.
So taking a peek inside the spam data folder and then opening 0 1 processing you should see a file called
practice on a school email Dot T X T.
Now the file name for this file should be pretty obvious because we're looking right at it.
It's practice on a score email that t t that t x part is called the file extension and this signals
what kind of file this is a text file.
It's just a boring old text file but the thing is these file extensions are key to the computer or you
or me understanding what kind of file it is that we're working with.
The extension tells us something about a files format.
So for example Microsoft Word documents have the extension DLC or DLC ex and PDA FS have the extension
dot PD f windows executable files on the other hand have the very dangerous extension dot e XY.
So if you ever receive an email that has an attachment with a dot EMC extension don't open the attachment.
This was always the classic way that people installed viruses on their computers back in the day.
I was going through my spam directory recently and one thing I noticed actually was that more and more
folks are sending out their malicious code with the DOT J.S. or JavaScript extension instead of DOT
EMC.
So yeah it's always good to pay close attention to these file extensions now that we've talked about
the file name and the file extension.
What about this other thing that I've mentioned.
What about the path the path or the file path is the location of the file.
Let me quickly show you how you can actually view the file path on Mac.
And afterwards I'll show you how to see it on Windows.
If you're using a Mac then you can open finder and you can go to this practice.
E-mail that text file in finder and then you can go to file get info or command.
I and what you can see right here is the location of this file.
It's on my hard drive under my username inside my projects folder.
Then spam data and then zero one on the score processing.
This here is the location of the practice on a score email the text file.
This right here is my file path if you're running Windows on the other hand you can always see the file
path and the location in this address bar right up here.
So right now this is the project folder.
Double clicking on spam data will open my folder and you can see now that the location here has updated.
If I open processing then I can clearly see the full file path to this practice email right here in
my address ball if I click inside the ad respawn then we can see the names of the folders and the sub
folders separated by a backslash.
In other words my processing folder is inside spam data which is inside my projects folder which is
inside my username folder under users and then on my C drive.
This long piece of text that we're looking at right here is the full path and this brings me to the
two different kind of paths that you'll be encountering.
The first one is actually called an absolute path think of the absolute path as the long form.
This is the full path to the file or folder on Windows.
You often see the absolute path starting with C and then going to your particular user profile and then
down to a particular folder on Mac.
The absolute path to the practice email would look something more like this.
All right.
I think that's easy enough but while the absolute path is the long form there is also a shorthand you
see you don't always have to work with an absolute path.
Instead you can work with what's called a relative path a relative path uses your current location as
the starting location and then points to a file or folder from there.
So suppose I'm in my MLK projects folder and finder then the relative path to the practice email would
be spammed data 0 1 processing.
And there it is.
There is my practice on a school email the text file has such the relative path from my email projects
folder to my practice on a school email or text file would look something like this.
What you're looking at here is actually the formatting for windows on a Mac.
You'd have a relative path that would look more like this notice.
The only difference are the slashes Mac uses the forward slash and Windows uses the backslash in front
of the file and folder names.
Now this might be a small thing to point out but the direction of the slashes actually matters when
you're writing your python code.
So even though in windows you see backslash is used in the path on the end respawn.
It's actually a little problematic to try and just copy paste what's in here and the reason is is that
in Python you actually want to use a forward slash because the backslash has a special purpose in the
Python programming language.
Let's fire up a new Python notebook and I'll show you exactly what I mean and why we want to use forward
slashes in Jupiter navigate to your email projects folder and then click new.
Python 3 notebook Let's rename this notebook to 0 6 Baz classifier and click rename say we print align
what is up and had shift enter.
Then we see this text printed below.
But what if we wanted to write what's up.
So I wanted to write what's up with an apostrophe.
You can see that I now have three single quotes in this string and that means that my string starts
here ends here and this part onwards here is considered Python code and then it starts another string
here.
In other words Python needs to know that it should ignore this single quote and for that we use the
backslash the backslash escapes the character that follows it.
So by using the backslash this single quote here is treated as part of the string.
And if I had shift enter I can get that apostrophe to show up in my output.
And that's also why when you're providing a path as a string you want to make sure use forward slashes
instead of backslash is that you get from copy and pasting from the windows address bar okay.
So so much for the theory behind relative paths filings file extensions and absolute paths in the next
lesson.
I'll show you how to read that practice email into Jupiter notebook.
I'm gonna go ahead and get some coffee but I hope I'll see you on the next lesson.