Hello and welcome to part three of the blockade course very exciting part.
We're going to talk about development finally we're going to talk about development and what changed.
And we've got quite a massive journey ahead of us so let's look at the plan of attack how are we going
to tackle all of these tutorials.
So in this section we will learn the following.
Number one what is a theorem.
A quick overview of what the whole general concept behind Ethereal is very exciting it's very powerful
and changing the world already as we speak.
They don't talk about what is a smart contract and we'll find out how they are used in blockades and
what exactly they mean for developers.
Then we'll talk about decentralized applications on watching how applications can just exist on a block
chain rather than a centralized server.
And what that means again in the terms of development of these applications and programming them will
talk about in theory virtual machine and gas.
So how this infrastructure always theme actually works and what what's the purpose of ether at the end
of the day.
And you know that it's not just a cryptocurrency is not actually intended to be a cryptocurrency.
How this how these programs that we can write on block change how these applications that we can develop
are actually what the economy is behind it how they can run.
And at the same time not overload the network and be efficient and things like that.
They don't talk about decentralized autonomous organizations and that's an interesting tutorial about
how organizations might run in the future in a completely decentralized manner in fact in a completely
autonomous manner where they're just running there's no not no or not many humans operating organizations
and we'll see how that is possible but with the help of blotching In theory I'm not talking about the
Dow attack.
Interesting episode that happened in the life or the theorem when there was a massive hack and lots
of millions of dollars were stolen.
We'll talk about that and what implications that had on the network and how they recovered from that.
They will talk about soft and hard fork's what that means for a block chain network in general.
Look at some examples of that.
Will be two parts as a toil to this topic.
The second is quite advanced so feel free to skip it it's a long tutorial.
Things over all were 15 minutes long and it is quite advanced.
Feel free to skip it.
That's just the actual theory behind soft and hard force and how they work.
But even the first part of that tutorial is sufficient to understand in a general sense what how those
things work.
They will talk about initial coding offering so slowly we are getting into the more financial aspects
of watching projects which are also important to consider and keep in mind when you are developing something
in the world of watching or where you're working on an application because this is kind of like the
end game or what you're aiming for and also we'll have a look at some examples.
So we'll talk about initial court offerings and how they work and how they're different to IPO or initial
public offerings.
Then we'll talk we'll have an IPO case study a hypothetical case study to show us even better how an
ICAO would work and what benefits it would bring and what kind of economy it would create for the project.
Then we'll talk about blocking startups will have a look at a couple of UPS we'll have a look at least
three examples of start ups in the space of bushing that I personally find interesting the ideas behind
them and in in one of these tutorials we're talking about investment advice financial advice.
This is more for educational purposes and for understanding where to get ideas from how to find those
good projects that are using blotching in a way that makes sense and will specifically talk about white
papers and porters and white papers where to find them and what they mean for blocking projects and
what they mean for you as a as a developer or as a professional that is going to be using Guangcheng
in the future.
And finally we'll talk about.
We'll conclude by talking about washing and where three point old what role block chain will most likely
play in Web 3.0 or is is slated to play in the Web 2.0 that's coming our way in the next couple of years.
So there we go that's our plan for the section as you can see quite a lot of details to tackle.
So we're going to be fun and lots of different information and very very excited to jump straight into
it.
So hard for you.
Let's dive into your and I would call you on next tutorial Until then introductions.