Hello and welcome back to the course on blog.
How did you go of the procedural with the transactions and UTX shows.
I really hope you had a chance to kind of rethink the things that we talked about and maybe even practice
a couple of times.
And today we'll talk about where transactions fees come from.
We'll definitely continue practicing what we learned previously to solidify that knowledge but really
build on top of that a little bit and we'll see where the fees come from.
So let's get started.
All right so so far I've bought two bicycles with my bitcoins.
And as we remember i have that one unspent transaction output left from a transaction that works and
to me of one BTC has been hanging in there for quite a while now.
All right so let's say in the meantime in between the tutorials a couple of more people have sent me
transactions and the blocks have been mines and these transactions are in the system.
And so here they are so are certain to be zero point one BTC Adlon sent me 0.4 BTC.
Ebay sent me a reply through BTC Maybe I sold something there and eidolon sent me Agins 0.3 BTC.
All right so those are our current UTX sales.
Let's see what I want to buy now.
And today I want to go and buy a third bicycle for 0.9 BDC and an apple for zero point zero to PDC.
So I was walking home and I saw an apple and I decided to buy it because I wanted to eat it.
And so let's construct the transactions that are going to make this happen or the transaction one transaction
is going to make this happen and we already know that we can put we can have multiple inputs and multiple
outputs and so all of this you know like in banking you'd have to send you know to one transaction or
the bike shop and watch the action of the fruit shop in watching you just do one transaction and you
get everything done right away.
All right so our inputs.
How much do we need in total Let's calculate that we need 0.9 to BTC.
So what can what you take so can we take to combine them into 0.22.
So if we take let's have a good start.
So input will take this report from Adlon because that's the first one and then we'll take the 0.3 from
E-bay.
We'll take the other 0.3 BTC from Adlon and interesting to note here that you know I said the money
twice but that doesn't get accelerated into one UTX So that's separate transactions that happen.
They need to continue they need to feed into another transaction in this case we're letting them feed
into this transaction.
And so in total that gives us 0.4 plus or 3 0 3 at one point in total and that's more than we need which
is good.
And so that's going to be our input and output is going to be well naturally 0.9 BDC to the bike shop
to get the bike zero point zero to BTC to the future for the apple and the rest.
The change as we can see that's less than our input though the changes we know because just the time
that we need to send it back to ourselves.
So zero point 0 6 BTC to myself I know what you're thinking.
We'll get to it in a second.
So what happens from where we were learned that this because these transactions this transaction has
fit into here now it no longer is a UTI.
So there is no output that is left on just hanging it's already taken up by this transaction this transaction
same thing this transaction same thing.
So we could just get rid of them out of all of you take those.
So this Amman's will grow it will become a takes over the bike shop this Amman's will become another
you are not should say for each of you takes over the.
And this will be a you take so for me so I'll go into here.
And so the question you're probably wondering is this doesn't add up here all this adds up to zero point
nine eight BTC total.
This adds up to one BTC.
So where did that difference go to.
Didn't you say that the change has you have to account for the changes to go back.
Well the way it works is that anything that you don't account for becomes the feed becomes the fee for
this transaction to be included in a block in the blotching.
We know that we've already spoken about fees.
We know that they're quite important and even though the auction theoretically is should be can be free.
You don't have to pay fees.
Nobody's making you pay fees at the same time.
There is a competition going on miners are putting these blogs in and there's a lot of transactions
that are waiting in the pool.
So if you want a transaction to actually be accepted you need to put a fee to kind of volunteer a fee
and or bid if you're a guest.
And so the higher the fee the more likely the question will be I said accept that sooner.
And so the way you specify the fees you don't actually there's no field to say the fee is going to be
this the fees calculate automatically what they do is they just take the total output that you have
with the total input minus the total output.
And whatever the difference is it is assumed that you want that to be the fee.
And that's where the fee comes from.
And so that's where the fee originates.
Very very simple like that.
And plus we had another example another section.
So now we update our utech sales.
So that's huge.
So for the minor but now we're going to update this UJA.
So here
are some I know.
Oh.
And again of course can I forget and again the bicycle from my mom and I get an apple and now we update
this as we can see we those who takes us to get removed and now we have the money to me that should
be 0.06 no doubt here you take us out there we got.
So there we go.
That's how fees work.
And now let's have a look at some real life transactions that apply our knowledge in the real world.
All right so I have the luxury dot.com upset here and if we go into data and then we pick and you block
block and we go down you'll see here the transactions.
And so the person's action we haven't spoken much about this but it's very easy it's always the Coinbase
transaction it's the action that pays the minor the reward for Mining's block which is 12 and a half.
Bitcoins currently.
And it also includes as you can see it's a bit more because it includes the fee that the miner gets
fuzzbox all the fees for the transactions that were paid in this block they get aggregated here as well.
And that's the total amount.
OK.
So that's the first one and then these are the transactions we can have a look at.
You can see just as we described these are you the checks those coming from somewhere else from previous
transactions.
And there you go.
So this is our new transaction over here and they're going into new new places somebody is like buy
something moving around and because it's old crypt to topographically hashed out tell who's buying what.
Where money's going.
But you can tell them months you can tell what amount is going where that you've got some 0.1 1:03 or
you can tell where it's going but you can say see that these are monster movie.
What else.
So you can click on the transaction.
So this one and you can see how it's happening over here.
So another thing this amount is what's what blog.
Shane call mobilization that infer what they estimate the actual spend is because if you send your money
back to yourself you for instance one of these transaction is money going back to yourself.
The change then it won't be included in this amount.
So that's what their estimate.
Oh no she's sorry that that's the total this amount estimated BTC transacted.
So that's the total.
So they can that you can see there that they are estimating that the payment was actually 0.1 1 3 and
then this is probably the amount that went back to the person themselves.
That's that's what they estimate.
And then an interesting thing here is you can go to the tree chart and you can see that the money came
from somewhere and then you can see how it's further purchase of the because it's the new transactions
and you block.
You can really see here so we need to go to like an older block to see that trees.
It's pretty interesting.
So let's pick a block and here always or go here to see the transactions.
And then just pick any transaction with this one.
Let's see if this will be worth something.
Yewtree chart there so you can see this one kept going so then it like what we discussed.
You take so I went to this one transaction.
This went into this transaction and then into this one so mauritians action adds it to that and then
it kept going.
So for now these are you check right now sitting there waiting to be spent.
So this one this one that you say like they added up to a whole Bitcoin and then it's moving on.
And now then that transaction 270 Bitcoins look we started with zero point two and one small example
and then this production which has been something bigger bigger bigger and then it went into a of 270
Bitcoin transaction.
Wow.
And then 130 Bitcoin.
So 270 Bitcoins that's like what is that going to give us 270.
There's like two million dollars.
That's a $2 million total because if Bitcoin is about those right now.
So that gives us 200 times.
So to have 2.7 million dollar transaction and then three Bitcoins here and then it split out like that.
So this is pretty cool isn't it.
So you can explore and at any point in time you can create.
You probably would need to.
You could probably look up this transaction somehow I guess
maybe we can try put it in here.
No.
All right.
So that didn't work like that.
Well I actually thought you could look them up here.
All right.
Well how can I look up a transaction see like that's supposed to work like that.
OK well no no worries.
So you can see how powerful that is that.
And you can see the whole concept in action.
So just feel free to go here and pick any blog.
If you take a look at all the blog you will see like a deeper blog you'll see there's more potential
to go through it.
And once again you just go into the blog you pick your transaction.
Look at that.
That's huge.
But this is not her not her recent book but anyway.
All right.
So you just pick a blog you pick your transaction on the header and then you click the chart and you
can have a look around and see how it was you know how it developed from there.
Once again if you take a deeper look then there will be more more to the tree.
All right so hope you enjoyed today's tutorial.
It is quite fun.
Now we know with that trend which is actually how transactions work what you take so are were fees come
from.
And in the next term we'll take that a step further and I look for it see you there.
Until then Jibla chance.