Hello and welcome back to the course of blogging today we'll find out what a blog is at a high level.
So bludgeons Where did they come from.
Well the concept initially came from these two people.
They didn't necessarily coined or introduced the term block change that came much later after the original
paper by Cistercian or Comodo but these two gentlemen over here stood a habor and called Stern Netzer
in 1991 published a paper called How to time stamp a digital document.
And if you look through the paper you read through it you'll find that the concepts of what now we call
it a block chain and all or most of the features and ideas behind the notion actually are present in
that paper.
And the way we keep pedia identifies a block chain is a book that is continuously growing list of records
called blocks which are linked and secured using crypto cryptography.
So this is a very general definition.
There's much more to abortion as we'll see.
But this is already some place for us to start.
So let's have a look at one of these records are so-called blocks what constitutes a block Well a block
because it's a record.
We'll obviously have a data inside it.
For instance it might have just a string of words hello world.
Then it will have a value which is called a previous hash and we'll get to this in a second and then
we'll have a value which is its own hash.
And what the hash is is it's like a fingerprint of this block.
It's like taking the first two elements the data and the previous hash and finding the like a number
which represents that data.
So a shortened version of that data specifically 64 characters long.
I will talk about hash more in the future.
But basically right now the best way to think about it is a hash a digital hash is like a fingerprint
of some amount of data.
And that makes its much clearer or makes it clearer now what's going on.
So the block here has its own hash and then the previous hash which is contained within the block as
a reference is actually the hash of the block that came before it.
So let's have a look at that in action.
So here we've got block number one.
It's also called the Genesis block in a box in the first block and it's called jazzes block because
after the block chain is initialized that block will always stay blocking them on forever and ever and
ever for eternity it will never change.
That's no other block will become the once.
This block is always going to be the first one.
That's where it all originate.
You might have some data in it.
We're not going to go into detail what kind of data is in there but assuming there's some data it doesn't
have a previous hash inside this block because this is the jettisons block is the only block that will
have a previous hash.
So we're just going to present them all zeros and then it will have its own hash again.
For now let's think of hash as a fingerprint.
We'll find out more about how these hashes are derived in coming to Torro And then there is block number
two and a book on Mattoo also has some data.
This time it does have a previous hash and it has its own hash again.
And as you can see the block is the previous hash of block number two is exactly identical or is exactly
block number ones hash and that is where the link comes.
That is why abortion is called a chain or a block chain because the blocks are cryptographically linked
with each other through these hashes.
And again more of that not to come.
But this is conceptually hard works every brought block has its own fingerprint and it also references
the fingerprints of the previous block.
So if anything were to change and block number one it's fingerprint would change.
So if anything were to change here
anything would that change in the data.
So somebody were to tamper with the data.
This fingerprint would change and it would no longer match this fingerprint.
So this block would know or we would know by looking at this block that somebody tampered with this
block.
And then again looking at the three data it's got the previous hash it's got its own hash and it's linked
to the so on and so on.
So again Conceptually we can see that if anybody were to tamper with any block this one and this one
then the fingerprints would no longer match up and the chain would be invalid the chain would show that
there's something wrong.
And that's why Bloch's That's why we say that blocks are cryptographically linked together.
All right so that is a blockade at a very very high level to get us started.
There are many more concepts to blockades and things like mining distributed peer to peer network consensus
protocol immutable ledger and hash cryptography.
So right now many of these bytes are very alien or very confusing at the moment.
And that's totally fine because we're going to go through them one by one in the coming tutorials and
debunk all miffs and understand exactly how everything works and we're going to start in the next tutorial
with hash cryptography.
But for now if you'd like to learn a little bit more about boxes from the original source where the
idea first came up I highly recommend checking out the paper called How to time stamp a digital document
by habor and stern as the links here and also the link is going to be in the course notes and you'll
be able to just click it there and go head to the paper if you like to check it out.
And on that note I look forward to the next tutorial.
And until then in your actions.