From the types of Spring Boot dependencies we added to our POM file,
it correctly assumed that we wanted a web application with OAuth2 login,
and the way it configured everything is via these auto‑configured dependency,
which has a number of auto‑configured classes in it.
Now, in the webmin folder, there is a spring.factories properties file,
which lists all the auto‑configuration classes that
would be bootstrapped on Startup.
Here is the one that takes care of OAuth2 clients,
the OAuth2ClientAutoConfiguration.
Now, let's take a look inside and see the magic.
This class will activate if the following conditional annotations are satisfied.
So these two classes need to be in the class path,
which they will be because we added the oauth2‑client boot dependency.
The application is a web app as we also have the
spring‑boot‑starter‑web dependency, so conditions are met,
hence the triggering of the import of the
OAuth2ClientRegistrationRepositoryConfiguration and the OAuth2WebSecurityConfiguration
classes.
The ClientRegistrationRepositoryConfiguration creates an
InMemoryClientRegistrationRepository.
Now, by merging the client info we put in our application.yml file,
so Facebook and Google, with the properties in the CommonOAuth2Provider enum.
If we look at the OAuth2WebSecurityConfiguration class,
it highlights the opinionated nature of Spring Boot.
Using the ConditionalOnMissingBean annotation,
Spring Boot detects that if we have not configured the essential services,
such as the OAuth2AuthorizationClientService and ClientRepository,
then it will do that for us.
If you have used Spring Security in the past,
you'll be very familiar with the WebSecurityConfigurationAdapter.
Don't worry if you haven't.
By the end of this course, you will be.
Now, here, the OAuth2 configuration class creates one for us,
annotates it with Configuration so that it gets added
to the Spring application context, and overrides the configure method,
the HTTP security builder, which by default,
would have secured our application with form and basic authentication.
But in this case,
it will require all requests to be authenticated using oauth2login.
Okay, I hope that makes things slightly clearer,
but don't worry if it doesn't because it will by the end of the course,
I promise.
Next, let's get back to the main focus of this module.
How can we complement an existing form of authentication with the option of OAuth2 social sign‑in?