Let's log into the Keycloak admin console and create a new role.
You can create roles for different namespaces,
so realm based or even client based.
Now I'm going to go for realm based,
so that this role is available to all clients in this role.
Currently, though, I just have one client.
Let's name the new role ADMIN.
Now, I'm going to assign this role to Victoria.
Let's put a breakpoint in the OpenID Connect User service,
so that we can actually see this access token created by Keycloak.
As you can see,
Victoria's access token now has the role ADMIN for CryptoPortfolio realm.
This is nested,
so I am going to map this into a claim named roles to make things a bit easier.
So in Clients, crypto‑portfolio client, select Mappers,
and the type will be User Realm Roles.
And I want this under roles claim.
Now Keycloak gives me the option to include this new claim in the ID token,
the access token or the userinfo endpoint.
Now, this is an important concept to understand about OAuth 2.0.
ID tokens, according to the OpenID Connect spec,
are JWT tokens,
so they will have claims about the user and the authentication on them.
In fact, it has certain mandatory claims that need to be there.
ID tokens are actually meant for the client to be
used for authentication purposes.
Now, when it comes to access tokens, according to the OAuth 2.0 spec,
there is no standard for what the access token should be.
It doesn't actually have to be a by value token.
It could be a by reference token, meaning opaque.
And the userinfo endpoint is where the client should
be getting the user claims from.
Now, for convenience,
you will find that most authorization servers will issue access
tokens that are by value and in JWT format,
and by default Keycloak does that, but according to the OAuth 2.0 spec,
access tokens are actually meant for the resource server,
and not to be read by the client.
So the client should be simply forwarding on to the resource
server to access the userinfo endpoint,
where they can then retrieve those claims from.
There is also a limit on the size of an access token that you
can actually fit in the header of a request,
so you tend to find that the userinfo endpoint actually returns more claims
back than what could be on the access token or the ID token.
These are known as thin tokens.
Okay, save this for now.
If I log out and log back in, you can now see Victoria has a new claim of roles,
with the ADMIN role inside.
Now we need to map these roles claims into the
GrantedAuthorities collection on the authentication token.
For this, we need a GrantedAuthoritiesMapper.
It's basically a class that implements the GrantedAuthoritiesMapper interface,
overrides the mapAuthorities method.
You just need to add it to your Spring ApplicationContext,
and Spring will plug it into the OAuth 2.0 login authentication provider.
In the authorities collection,
there will be an OpenID Connect userAuthority object,
and via this object you have access to the ID token and the UserInfo endpoint.
Notice that there is no access token.
Again, Spring is following the convention.
The access token is not meant for the client,
it's meant to be used against the resource server
to access the UserInfo endpoint.
Now, using the UserInfo endpoint,
we can get the roles claim and add the value into
the GrantedAuthorities collection.
Note that because these are roles you need to
prefix them with the capital ROLE_.
Now Spring, by default, maps scopes to GrantedAuthorities.
Since we're returning a new collection, let's also add them as well.
Okay, in our SecurityConfiguration adapter,
we can restrict access to the /support/admin path
to use this with the role ADMIN.
All other requests will still just need to be authenticated.
One thing to know is you can also use the
hasAuthority with the value of ROLE_ADMIN.
It's the same thing.
The prefix is like a namespace for roles,
as, if you recall, they're just maintained in the same collection as authorities,
nice and simple. Next, let's look at scope‑based authorization.