Being a public client means the code is,
well, public,
and hence there is no way to securely store the client ID and secret.
In the past, to get around this,
the implicit flow was created where rather than returning the
authorization code via the front channel,
the access token was instead returned to the client.
This is now deprecated and no longer recommended to be used by the OAuth 2
working group as now there is really no limitations or excuses as most
browsers now support cross‑origin requests so calling the authorization
server via back channel is possible.
Also, sending the access token via the front channel,
effectively, the user's browser's address bar,
is a bad idea.
Firstly, it is exposed to any malicious browser plug‑in extensions,
it can be logged while it's in transit to your
application at a gateway or a proxy somewhere,
if you're using Google Chrome, your browser history is synced with Google,
so that would include any access tokens sent in the URL,
and I could go on.
So yeah, just don't use this flow.
What you need to use is the Authorization Code Grant
flow with proof of key exchange.
The way this works is the client generates a random code
verifier and stores it in the client session.
It then hashes the verifier to create a code challenge.
The code challenge is then included along with the
method in the authorization request.
When a client receives the authorization code from the authorization server,
it includes the code verifier when making the POST back
channel request to the authorization server.
The authorization server will then verify that the code matches.
This way, if the authorization code is intercepted,
it is useless without the code verifier,
and the authorization code can only be exchanged once,
so it's less likely that an attacker would beat the client to it.
In fact,
unless you're using OpenID Connect with the nonce parameter and
your client is verifying that nonce parameter,
you should be using proof of key exchange for all flows
regardless if it's public or a confidential client.
This is to prevent an authorization code injection attack.
In our demo application,
because we are using OpenID Connect and Spring is including the nonce in
the authorization request and then also checking that it matches the nonce
returned in the ID token means our application is protected against the
authorization code injection attack.
The next issue you need to address is that the request to
exchange the authorization code for the access token to the
authorization server is cross‑origin,
hence you need to configure your authorization server to
include the CORS headers for your domain.
In Keycloak, on the client, this would be under Web Origins.
Once your public client gets the access token,
the next issue you're going to face is safely handling and storing it
and including it in all requests to the back end.
Unlike cookies, there is no real safe way of storing them.
Your options include via in the cookie where your back end
needs to run on the same domain and the token is at risk of
cross‑site request forgery,
local storage where the token will live forever unless the
user or application specifically remove it,
and session storage, which lives as long as your browser session,
basically, as long as the tab in your browser is open.
Additionally, it's not shareable between tabs,
so it's slightly more secure than local storage; however,
with both local and session, your token is at risk of cross‑site scripting.
Ideally, you would only expose your public client to an opaque token,
though sensitive data cannot be extracted from the token.
Again, in the end, it's still really depends on your requirements,
and the front‑end framework you're using,
and the level of security you require; however,
if you do things correctly with robust content policies,
then Authorization Code Grant flow with proof of key
exchange is still a viable option,
and many organizations are securely handling OAuth 2 in browsers this way. Next, let's wrap up.