Our demo app has come a long way.
Users now have the option of social login,
which improves the user's experience,
which should result in more people using the application.
The key takeaways here, always prefer OpenID Connect over
OAuth2 implementations as it's more secure,
cleaner, and simpler to code.
Spring Security is very customizable. If you need to change any
part of the authentication code flow, there is an endpoint in
Spring that represents that state,
such as the redirect token or userinfo endpoint. Now,
combining form and OAuth2 authentication in your application
can work, but there is a more scalable, secure,
cleaner, and simpler way of adding authentication to your application by
outsourcing it completely to an authorization server. Let's look at that, next.