Hello and welcome back to the Course also to sticks.
Today we're going to have a very sick tutorial we're going to be exploring the issue of misuse and overuse
of p values.
So let's have a look at what's going on here.
So it all kind of started for me with this video.
I was doing some research about p values for this course and I read like I stumbled on this video.
It's by seeker by the way Seeker is a great great channel.
You can find lots of really interesting videos about science and stuff like that.
But this one talks about how scientists manipulate research with p value and it talks about that you
know all these things that we've discussed in the course.
You've probably noticed like very mechanical very straightforward and it's just mathematics is just
basically basic calculations that you need to perform in order to reject a hypothesis and come up and
therefore prove some kind of theory or something.
We're afraid a five point ninety five percent degree of confidence or 5 percent or 99 percent degree
of confidence is something that.
And that's that can be a problem that sometimes people will take that's those those mathematics and
actually you know do research and just just rely on the P-value and then therefore prove that their
research is statistically significant and just basically to push that research out and get it published
as quickly as possible.
And because in the science community unfortunately it's really about the publications like the more
publications you have the more kind of credibility you have and the very a reputation in the community.
It's about publication.
Most of the time.
And so that can be a problem and the thing is that P-value doesn't actually tell you everything it's
not the end game for research but that's how research is taking.
And that's what we're going to be talking about a little bit today.
So check out this video.
If you just search for how scientists manipulate research with P-value will give you a quick overview
of the problem.
Then there's this article published in Nature.
I think it's Yechiel 14 Birgeneau news on Izzo.
I'm not sure how to pronounce it correctly but it basically talks about the same thing that there are
so many papers going out about P-value like which used P-value.
And we'll we'll come back in a second.
I just wanted to point out like what an impact this article had is a few of these articles but what
an impact it had is it was sighted it was I quote tweeted nine thousand eight hundred twenty five times
it's called mention and tonight blogs on turn to pay Facebook pages.
Hundred and Fifty three Google plus users.
And so this is this exact article by Regina news.
So it's huge.
It made a huge impact.
And in fact it's not this one.
In fact here you'll see that American I think is American Statistical statistics Association.
They actually published a paper kind of not directly in response to that article but if you search news
here you'll see that it's actually here that that they mention that this article was published and had
a huge impact.
And so this this is a comment from the American statistics Association about how indeed is this is a
problem that scientists are using.
P-value to manipulate research but kind of to get the results that they want to sometimes even manipulate
research and I just wanted to go through this so this is kind of the overview of that is is a thing.
This is a real thing.
And now I'm going to we're going to go through like what exactly does it mean that why why can we just
use P-value as we've discussed in the scores.
Why don't we just like isn't P-value like it sounds from what we've discussed sounds like P-value is
the real thing it's it's pretty it's pretty solid it's just math and so on.
And that that would have been kind of like the case but I just wanted to find this here somewhere.
So let's just read this part of this decision as I've pointed out put it to a number of measures that
might help us avoid the trap of thinking of our results as a significant or not significant for example
coming things that researchers should always report effect sizes and confidence intervals.
These convey what a P-value does not the magnitude and the relative importance of an effect.
And so that's kind of like the key to the thing that P-value is they don't actually look at the magnitude
of an effect.
And relative importance but this kind of like focus on the magnets.
What that means is that in as if you've seen we we can prove for instance that if P-value that something
has increased or something has decreased but we don't actually say by how much.
How much has it increased or how much has decreased we just say oh yes the number of households in five
has has increased or has decreased and that's pretty that's great.
But what we need to be doing is we need to be actually see I need to be checking.
All right.
So is it something that's valuable to us to know that it's increased What is it what are we taking that
is increased compared to is it we just checking that has increased to some arbitrary value that is not
going to be valuable to or in our case in this case like research into the population of the world.
But in our case to make the business objective that we were trying to fulfill so if that has increased.
Is that sufficient or do we need to actually see the effect do we need to be comparing to the previous
value or do it just sound like a set of sort of benchmark and compare to that and things like that.
We need to actually see.
All right what is going on.
And here's an example.
They have a look on line.
So here a great article by the way.
Definitely read it but I'm just going to look at a few like comments here.
So prime example is their tendency to deflect attention from the actual size of the effect.
Last year for example a study of more than 19000 people showed that.
Who those who meet their spouses on line are less likely to divorce.
So the P-value there was less than Point 2 percent and more likely to have marital satisfaction P-value
is less than Point 1 percent than than those who meet off line.
And so there's the link to the article that might have sounded impressive but the effects were actually
tiny effects were tiny.
The meeting online the divorce from right from Point 67 percent to down to five point ninety six percent
and barely budged.
Happiness from five point forty eight to five point sixty four and seven point scale.
So that's kind of like that's the issue here that you know it sounds pretty cool.
19000.
That's huge sample and it sounds you know like the P-value sound pretty significant but as it says here
basically there go so that deflects that deflects these these formulas.
I think the was Pompeius like these mega statements they deflect attention from what's actually going
on there or like let's say one of those things that we talked about like a drug that increases attention
span like you might say oh yes it increases attention.
Is this clinically proven.
You might find on a bottle is clinically proven that this drug increase increases attention span.
Well you know from 99 and the confidence in the level that we used was ninety nine percent confidence
level.
So that's pretty cool.
But how much does it increase their attention span.
Does it increase it by $0.00 1 percent.
Well in that case I'm not spending $20 on your natural medicine that's going to help me increase my
attention span by 0.7 percent or 1 percent.
So that's kind of the underlying issue of magnitude.
And in a business sense we always have to think about.
OK.
Yes.
Maybe the amount of money that customers are spending in our store has increased.
We can prove that but by how much has it increased by how can we actually see that that is the case.
And one final thing that I wanted to mention is they talk in this article about frequentist frequences
frequentist statistics which were just what we've been talking about all along which were created by.
Well if you want to look at an alternative and they also mentioned so if you look for these.
So they talk about Bayesian inference and Bayesian statistics versus frequence of official statistics.
And if you'd like to learn more about Bayesian statistics and Bayesian inference and have some real
world examples about about this issue in even a bit more detail and you're looking for a good book to
read I just wanted to recommend a book called Signal and the noise why so many predictions fail by Nate
Silver.
And this talks a lot about Bayesian inference and how it is different to frequences statistics.
The thing is that Bayesian inference as you'll see from the article it's requires kind of some subjective
input at the start it's like what is our starting point and is it subjective whereas what we've been
discussing is is our objective.
And if you use it right I believe that if you use p values and hypothesis test scores and all these
things T-test Elissa's when discussing if you use them correctly then like you are less likely to fall
into a trap like this but Bayesian inference is just a whole different story.
So if you want to learn more about that just maybe read this article and find out you can check out
that book single and always great book on data science as well.
And the other thing I wanted to mention to kind of like finish off to this tutorial is that so here
they mention that Cumming's coming things that researchers should always report effect sizes and confidence
intervals.
These convey values.
You know that's what people always do NOT Magnuson and relative importance and effect.
So the good news is that in this course in the next section pretty much we're going to be talking about
confidence intervals and there's some additional tool for you to be able to not only understand it if
there is an effect but also understand what kind of magnet should this effect potentially has.
And yes it will cover that off in the next section and hopefully you got some kind of insights about
potential warnings of values that is lost to discuss here is.
Lots of debate as you can see it's a big thing in the community.
All these researchers are using pure values all over like in all these universities and all these publications
at the same time they are growing concern about their overuse of values and you might find articles
about that you know that huge percentage of all published research is actually false simply because
you know the issues that are underlying here.
So it's just something to know it's of course we're not researchers and we're not going to be just running
toward to get our publications done.
And again I'm not saying that all research has to do that but it's not it's not even a even a concern
for us.
We just want to do business analytics and we want to make sure our results is significant.
So be aware of these problems that potentially exist.
And again if you read this article you will find to just search for scientific method statistical errors
and go find it and you'll find that there's actually there's some estimates of you know what.
What if you value 1 percent means like what are the percent.
What is the likelihood of things that that actually went wrong there and 5 percent is on.
But if you always keep in mind the cause and effect like a good example is if you use you can actually
I think there's some example of that some of you linked the behavior of drugs and earthquakes that you
know that frogs can actually predict earthquakes and that research has proven P-value as as as you'd
expect.
And you know it's kind of ridiculous unless and this is like some some weird connection between frogs
and earthquakes.
Otherwise it sounds like ridiculous things.
If as long as you don't try to prove ridiculous things as long as there's a cause and effect is actual
causality and you're always keeping the magnitude of the effect in mind as well.
I think these are a great tool to use and this whole hypothesis testing statistical significance which
we've been doing is great because people understand it and because it gives you that backing and even
this article says that P-value as they were they weren't just designed they weren't designed to prove
the research all the time all the way but they were indeed designed to check to do some initial checks
to understand OK which way should we start thinking in which direction.
So in terms of our purpose I think it's it's a good tool to have.
Good to know.
And again because people now know it and understand it it's definitely an important tool to have in
your arsenal and apply it so that you can rely on the results that you're finding.
And the business can also rely on those results.
So we hope hopefully enjoyed this little excursion into the world of warnings about values and so forth.
So then I'd be analyzing.