Hello and welcome back to the course in statistics.
And finally after all we've been through of the Central Limit Theorem.
Finally we're at the stage where we're going to look at the real life business challenge which we will
solve with the Central Limit theory.
I've got a very exciting challenge prepared for you.
You're going to be working as a business analyst for FedEx.
How cool is that.
Well a quick disclaimer.
This course has no affiliation with FedEx whatsoever.
This is an education example for illustrative purposes only.
So it is all made up.
But nevertheless it is very very real life and illustrates the power of central in a theory and how
you could apply it to really boost your career.
All right so you're a business analyst working for FedEx and you've been challenged to tell the executives
very quickly whether or not they can do a certain delivery.
And this has to be done quite fast.
Analytics has to be done very fast.
So here you've got a map of somewhere in the U.S. somewhere in the center towards towards the west I
think.
So they have Denver and you have Salt Lake City says so then we're on the right Salt Lake City on the
left and a client a business client of FedEx wants to deliver some cargo from Denver to Salt Lake City
and they need and they needed done very quickly there.
They just want to find out if you can do it or not.
So let's go through the details of this case study.
So you're a business analyst working for Fedex a business client has requested a large Frade to be transported
urgently from Denver to Salt Lake City.
When asked about the wait when you asked them about the way or your boss asked him or the weight of
the cargo they could not supply the exact weight.
However they have specified that there are a total of 36 boxes.
And from your prior experience with this client you know that this type of cargo follows a distribution
with a mean of 72 pounds or thirty two point sixty six kilos and a standard deviation of three pounds
or one point thirty six kills.
So this could totally be the case when they've very loaded the boxes onto the onto the truck which is
supposed to go to the airport.
They didn't weigh them up but the they know that these are you know approximately the boxes that they
usually supply you and you know that what their boxes usually look like and usually they're about £72
on average of a standard deviation of three pounds and that's from your prior knowledge.
We're working with this client.
And so the question is can you deliver these boxes.
Why is a question like that.
Well because right now the only plane you currently have in Denver is a Cessna open right riding that
right Cessna 208 the Grand Caravan.
That's the plane you actually saw in the very start at that image in that image.
Exactly a plane with a max cargo weight of two thousand six hundred three pounds or 1193 kilo's.
And so based on this information what is the probability that all of the cargo can be safely loaded
onto the plane and transport it.
So as you can imagine very urgent question very important for your boss to manage it to be able to answer
the to tell the client whether or not they should go ahead or they should look for another way to transport
the cargo it might be something that is perishable they might need an answer very soon.
And moreover how bad would it be if they come to your airport and then it turns out that once they load
the plane the pilot says no this is too much we cannot takeoff.
And it's it's a plane ride it's it's not like you can do something about it.
If a plane cannot take off it can take off and that's it.
And then they have to turn around and go somewhere else.
So there we go.
That's the challenge and we're going to solve it together so don't worry about.
You can definitely do it on your own but don't worry if you don't feel that you have enough practice.
Because we haven't had any practice yet on how to use the Central Limit theory in real life scenarios
like this one.
We will definitely have a homework exercise.
Will there'll be a summer exercise at the end of the section which you can do on your own after we've
done this one together.
So it's totally fine if we just proceed and do this one go step by step and you will see how to think
about using the Central them at the rim and the power Leveraging is power.
So are you ready.
Hope you're excited.
Let's get started.
So what's our plan.
We're going to walk through the plan first because that will help us understand the intuition behind
things and then we'll do the calculations so we're now going to just dive straight into the calques.
We want to understand exactly what we're doing.
So there's our population of possibly all the boxes that could ever come from this client.
That's our population and we know that this population from all from everything that we've seen so far
with with this client for many many years we can see that it has a an average or mean of 72 pounds.
And the standard deviation of all three pounds and you know that's a pretty accurate estimate of course
we don't know.
We're not the client we don't know all of all boxers but because we've worked them with them so for
so many years we've seen so many phrase from them we can confidently say that that's the situation that's
going on.
So there we go.
But at the same time we don't know what the distribution looks like for this.
We we we've seen the boxes we've seen you know we've measured the the mean and standard deviation we
know them but we don't know what the underlying distribution is.
There they're small boxes bigger boxes.
What does it exactly look like we don't know and moreover it's most likely not a normal distribution.
So what we could do is we to solve our problem our challenge we could potentially imagine taking a sample
of what we actually can we can take a sample.
We know that this is six boxes and they're going to send us a sample of 36 boxes so what we're going
to get for this plane ride is 36 boxes which is a sample of the total population.
But they're going to be picking this sample.
We don't know the sample we and moreover we can pick this sample because we don't know the distribution.
We don't know what the distribution line looks like.
When do we all we know is what we know is I mean and the standard deviation but we don't know the distribution.
We don't know this part and therefore we will even if we wanted to we can't pick a sample from that
distribution just because we don't have enough information.
And at the same time and even if we did even if we could pick a sample from that distribution what use
is that sample to us even if somehow by the means of a sample over a magic wand we could pick a sample
from this from their distribution somehow what's the point they're just going to send us a sample.
It's going to be a different sample most likely because samples.
Well we're going to pick a random sample they have a specific sample of boxes that they need shipped.
So what's the point of picking a sample.
So this is an example of where you can see that just picking a sample doesn't work doesn't work because
we can't and doesn't work because even if we could it there's no point in doing that.
And this is where most other business analysts are and you would get stuck.
They would probably just calculate the average and say OK yes you can probably do the flight or no you
can fly but the question is what is the probability.
And this is where people who don't know the central limit theorem would be stuck and you'd be at a huge
advantage because what you would do is you would take a sampling distribution you take maybe you.
Well again you can take these many samples but you just think in this way you'd think.
OK so if I had a sampling distribution of this population what it would look.
What would it look like.
This is just the thought process for now it will make a lot of sense when what what calques we're doing
as it is and of course we can pick these lots of sambuca.
We can pick one sample of copeck lots but let's just think about this.
Let's say we had a sampling distribution what would it look like.
Well we know that a sampling distribution of the sample mean would look like a normal That would be
a normal distribution.
And we know two more additional things about it.
We know first of all that's the mean of this sampling distribution of the sample mean would be exactly
the same as the mean.
So the mean here would be exactly the same as the mean of this population distribution which we don't
even know but we know the mean from Oprah experience so therefore we now know oh well we now know the
meaning of this sampling distribution.
How convenient is that.
And also we know that the standard deviation of we know something about the sand third powerful thing
about the central limit there.
Remember this 3 the the form that it's normal the mean that it's exactly the same and the standard deviation
that the standard deviation of the sampling distribution is equal to the standard deviation of the population
distribution divided by the square roots of the sample size.
And as we know the standard deviation of the population.
And guess what the sample size is going to be 36 because they're sending us 36 boxes.
We don't.
The point is we're going to be looking at sampling distributions of sample means where every single
sample similar single mean comes from a sample of 36 and make a bit more sense.
Now just now but you can see that already and analysts that is doing this you know it's stuck you on
the other hand you bypass this part by using a central limit theorem or what we're doing we're bypassing
this part and we're saying OK.
So if we don't take a sample we take many samples.
Hypothetically then they're sampling distribution would be a normal distribution.
That's really good.
We know it's mean.
There it is.
That's really good.
And we know it's sanitation that's that divide by the square root of 36 that's recalls not what can
we do with that.
Let's have a look.
So there's our original vision there's our sampling distribution of and 36.
So let's let's plot the things that we have already so there's our mue that's our mean for urgent discussion.
Now we know that the myu of the sampling distibution is going to be exactly the same.
So right away we can put her a spot on the right there and then the standard deviation.
Same thing we well not exactly the same thing but we know how to calculate it so we're going to know
that as well so hypothetically if we're dealing with a hypothetical sampling distribution which again
we cannot create from scratch but at the same time if we imagine in our mind we know all these things
about it we know that if we were to create and there's only one right and for four if you take some
samples of 36 from this population take millions and millions of samples of 36 from the population this
is all you're always going to get this sampling distribution.
So the only one sampling distribution for an equal 36 for this group for this original population exists
in the US so only one sampling does Russian exist in the world for this program or 3:6 and we already
know so much about it.
We know that it's got that mean that's on deviation.
So what can we do with that.
Well there we go.
Let's just write that down so mue x is equal to mucosal £72 Sigma x is equal to Sigma or the salvation
we had here.
Divide by square root of 36 and that is three because that's our standard deviation the original population
which we know from prior experience to have a sort of 3 6 which is 6 and is equals to Mazower 0.5.
Now we know that the plane capacity and this is the part where we are getting to the actual critical
thinking.
We know that's the plane capacity is 2600 40 pounds.
So what is the critical mass for a given box at which point I'd like if we go beyond we will not be
able to.
The plane won't be able to lift off.
So let's think about we have thirty six boxes and two in total.
They can only way.
Two thousand six hundred forty pounds maximum.
If there were more than that then we have a problem.
So the critical mass of a box or oven like on an average if we do if we divide the total mass of the
boxes the maximal mass that we can have for the boxes which is this by 36 then we'll get the critical
mass per box.
Right.
It doesn't matter.
The boxes can all have different weights but we know there's 36 of them so we know that on average the
bore the mean or the average weight of a box cannot exceed this value on this vast galley 73 points
point six point zero six pounds per box.
So if the average weight of a box in the sample that they send us doesn't matter again the the boxes
can be from one pound to two more to 50 pounds or 2 to 100 pounds.
Doesn't matter for us but if we take the saw the total value the total mass total weight of those boxes
we added up and then we divide by the number of boxes it cannot exceed 73 point 06.
And so this is where our sampling distribution comes into play because the sampling distribution one
is in a sampling distribution of is a sampling distribution of the sample mean so every time when you
build this distribution or the way it what it represents is you take a sample from your point population
and then you in that sample of 36 items you calculate the mean you plotted.
Then again you take another sample you Calcott the mean you plotted can take the sample you calculate
the mean you plotted and you do that many many times and then you get the sampling distribution.
So now we can plot this value.
It's relevant to this chart we can upload it here.
And that's going to be our next critical.
So it's somewhere on this chart.
So we know that this is £72 the mean here and X critical is somewhere on the chart as well.
So it's 73 0.06 is to the right so that's where we're putting it here.
And so now because X critical care is derived exactly the same way as any other value in the sampling
distribution in the sampling distribution you take a sample you it the mean you plotted is critical
is you take the sample which you actually have which you're going to have 36 boxes and you take the
mean and you plot it.
There it is.
So the question is now.
Now it kind of starts making sense right now.
Now this is this is where the score is going to come in.
So the question is how far away is critical from our mean.
In fact what we want to know is what is the probability of us ending up in this part.
What is the probability this sampling description describes all of the possible samples of 36 boxes
that they could have ever sent us and they would ever send us if they study six boxes.
We know that there's six boxes so we know that the sample they're going to send us is definitely going
to come from this distribution is going to be one of the values here.
The question is what is the probability that this value is going to be beyond extra tickle that.
Oh that's the sample they send us is going to exact is is going to have a value that lies over here
and that means that plane the plane won't be able to.
Well now we just use ours as score.
Now it's it's all mechanical from here.
Now we just calculate Zed which is X critical minus myu That's distance divided by the Sigma X which
we've CALKIN over here so we know how far away in terms of standard deviations we are from the center
so there's a center that's how far away we are and it calculate seventy point 0 6.
There it is divide by 72.
Divide by 0.5 two point twelfth standard deviation so one two point twelve standard deviations we are
way from the center.
And so what's the next step.
Next step is we bring our table.
Voila.
And so we just want to find two point twelve in our table.
Let's have a look.
So Zed 2.0 12 to do 2.1 2.1 to.
There it is.
Zero Point 9 8 3 0.
Let's put that back so there we go.
That's that's pretty much the result.
So the probability of X being less than X for Dickel which is a question that was asked.
Will translate that into question.
So the ability of X and X less and X reticle is 0.9 A3 0 which is nine eight point three percent so
the probability that the sample they send us is going to be here is ninety eight point three percent.
So the probability that the plane can safely take off is ninety eight point three percent.
Why is that.
Well because the possibility that inside the sample they send us the average mass of a box is going
to be less than seventy three point six pounds is eight ninety eight point three percent.
And we've established that that is our critical mass which beyond which a plane cannot take off but
underneath which the plane can take off.
So there's an eight point three percent chance that this plane will take off or is if you do one minus
that you'll get like a one point seven percent chance that it cannot take off.
So the answer to that question is yes.
Most likely you will be able to take off of a ninety eight point three percent chance as the Bazawule
is just doing this as you could see it took us like 15 minutes.
And if if you learn how to do a lot of these like you kind of learn how to apply the central limit theorem
and think in these terms you can do it much quicker.
And this is because we're going through intuition and the steps.
But basically you just go back to imagine say hey OK so there's nine eight point three percent chance
that the plane can take off and then the mat is up to the manager to make the call there.
What do they do they would just say to the client Yes come along and take that to take that risk of
1.7 percent of of it not going ahead or maybe there's an approach of telling the client Hey look from
what we know because he didn't weigh up the boxes from what we know about your previous boxes were done
the calculations.
And there's a ninety eight point three percent chance of you of this plane taking off.
Do you want to take that risk as a manager.
If I were the manager I'd probably do that.
It's a safer bet.
And and more importantly is backed by statistics right.
So if if the plane if it happens so that the plane can take off you will always be able to go back to
the client and say look we warned you.
We told you there's a 1.7 percent chance you took that risk and these are calculations we can prove
it.
You know you can you can prove to the client that you did do your Ju-Ju Julians you didn't just come
up with a number randomly.
So there we go that is the power of the central limit theorem I hope this was a very like Vout valuable
example for you that you were able to see how you can use this to your advantage how you can get ahead
of the game.
So is there's lots of situations where the central limit theory can be applied and you can learn from
now because you know all of this you can look out for this in your career and always remember that you
have this super powerful tool in your arsenal and of course they'll be homework.
I wish you best of luck with that in this section and I hope you enjoyed learning about the central
theorem and I look forward see you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.