Our homework time.
I know we have a few traitors among our students and you guys are going to love this today we're going
to Wall Street New York you're going to be working as a quant which is sort of a quantitative analyst
at one of the investment funds.
Very interesting challenge ahead.
But before we proceed I have to read out a disclaimer because there is like a hint that as if we are
working on a financial market even all the all of this is made up just to make sure that everybody is
safe.
I just want to make sure that don't go running and applying this in finances and investments this is
just for educational purposes so here we go.
Any information in this tutorial is for educational purposes only and does not constitute personal or
investment advice.
We will not accept liability for any loss or damage including without limitation to any loss of profit
which may arise directly or indirectly from the use of or reliance on such information.
You should seek independent financial advice prior to acquiring a financial product.
All securities and financial products or instruments transactions involve risks.
Please remember that past performance results are not necessarily indicative of future results and with
that in mind we can proceed with the tutorial.
OK so the challenge you are a quant or quantitative analyst working for a Wall Street investment fund
the team of traders under your supervision pre-high position.
If you are a team of traders under supervision earns profits which can be approximated zoophile law
plus distribution profits have a means of $95 and 70 cents and a whopping standard deviation of 1247
dollars.
Your team makes about 100 trades every week.
Questions.
Question 8.
What is the possibility of your team making a loss.
In any given week question be what is the probability of your team making over $20000 profit in any
given week.
An example of a law plus distribution can be found on the following page.
This is what a description looks like and that's it.
Off we go.
The challenge is set going to reveal some hints or one hint just now.
But if you think you're ready if you're prepared to take on this challenge then feel free to proceed.
And then compare to the solution which you can find at the end of the course.
All right.
Good luck with that.
And now we're going to move onto the hint so we only have one hint today and it's very trivial because
we know everything we need to know apart from this one thing even this one thing we do know as well.
Does it matter what distribution the profits follow.
Question mark answer.
No it doesn't.
They'll applause distribution is there just to scare you.
It doesn't matter.
We know the central in that theory.
So we don't really care what distribution the profits follow we can just apply the central limit here
and there we go.
That was the only hint and I'm sure you knew that already.
So good luck with the challenge and I'll see you in the solution.
And until then happy analyzing.