Well hello there, Mark Wilkins checking in.
How are you today?
We're going to look at Securing Access to Edge Locations.
Well what's an edge location you may say?
Well,
it's a piece of technology or a service that is on the
edge of Amazon's internal services, like DNS,
load balancing, web application, firewall protection,
those sorts of things.
So I'm glad you're here.
You may have some questions though on security, why the focus on security?
Well, everything in cloud is focused on security.
People talk about it's cheaper, it's available,
I can get going really quickly, and then security rears its head,
so we have to focus on security and ensure that what we're
hosting/implementing in the Amazon cloud is secure.
Now the portion of security that we can control,
because after all it is a partnership,
and this is also a course that will get you ready for
some of the Amazon certifications, such as sysops,
administration, and security itself.
And as I like to say, security is 25/7 in the cloud.
It's always something we have to monitor and manage.
In searching for sayings to start off each of these modules,
looking for something to do with security,
well William Cowper was in the 1700s,
and I don't think he saw any of the clouds that we saw,
but the saying still kind of makes sense.
We are never more in danger than when we think ourselves most secure.
Isn't that the case?
We have a network, nobody's broken in, nobody's done something,
so we feel that we're secure until somebody breaks in,
and then, oh my goodness, we've got to fix something.
And then, of course, the last part of the saying,
nor in reality more secure than when we seem to be most in danger.
And that kind of applies to that definition of security.
Are you secure?
Last time I checked.
Never-ending story, isn't it?
This course is going to help you with edge location security,
the components that are on the edge of the AWS services,
and a working knowledge of AWS, hey it's always a bonus,
it's not essential for this class.
So what are our topics?
Well we're starting off with elastic load balancing,
and then we'll look at the traffic through the balancer,
how we could encrypt it.
Then we'll take a look at the policies for the elastic load balancers.
There is 2 elastic load balancers, the standard TCP/IP up to level 4,
and then we have the application load balancer.
Then we'll look at DNS services and Route 53.
DNS,
kind of essential for everything that we do on the cloud across the internet,
pretty well everywhere.
Then we'll look at the AWS Web Application Firewall and the AWS Shield Service.
And then we'll end up with some best practices for securing access.
So there's our topics. Let's get going.