In this clip we're going to take a look at the term the Amazon Machine instance.
I know the title says instances, but there are Linux and Windows instances.
So when I'm looking at the choices to build my virtual machines,
I have a couple of things to consider.
Instances nowadays typically run on 64-bit virtual Intel processors.
And as such,
we get into a few other distinctions when we are building our instances.
The hardware virtual machine, as it's defined,
with paravirtualization support, now there's a mouthful,
and paravirtualization used to be the way,
I'd say 5-6 years ago it was pretty well the predominant way of
running virtualization when we're looking at running Xen as the
hypervisor in the open source world.
Typically nowadays,
the paravirtualization provides pretty amazing support to attach to
the network and storage through drivers that are really baked into
this copy of the hardware virtual machine.
Because of updated drivers, faster processors at the physical layer,
I would start with an HMV and it will come down to
choice as to what is readily available.
The typical market nowadays, the hardware is getting better,
this is typically the defacto choice.
Now when we're talking about paravirtualization,
we really were talking about Linux.
Windows hasn't opened up their operating system for anybody.
For Windows systems, since we have the HVM with the paravirtualization support,
Windows can take advantage of the support for faster
networking and storage than they could in the past.
So when it comes to choosing our instances,
we have a few choices, the first is general purpose,
and as you may expect, general purpose means just that.
There's a balance for compute, memory, network resources,
and they have a couple of flavors that based on what
customers ask for as a starting point, they provide it.
The next instance choice we can look at is the optimized instance for memory.
So if you have needs for a high performance database,
maybe you're dealing with heavy duty analysis,
maybe you're building some enterprise application that needs a
ton of RAM or maybe it's compute optimized.
Now the compute optimized instances are,
as you may expect, high performance, and so again,
you might be doing scientific analysis, engineering,
gaming, encoding video, or it might be storage optimized.
Maybe you have something like a very large NoSQL database,
maybe you've got transactions going on, data warehousing,
big data, Hadoop, then you can start with storage optimized.
You need something that is defined as accelerated computing where
you're using the graphics processing units,
so the GPU instances.
Maybe it's something that's designed for that specific GPU power.
Now that we have a bit of background on the instance choices,
let's take a look at the storage options for our instances.
So we start off with ephemeral storage.
This storage is on physical drives that are on the bare metal server,
so in this example we have a couple of instances that have
some volumes that are defined as ephemeral,
and they live and die as your virtual machine lives or dies.
So you can reboot the box, the drive is still there,
you turn off the system, your drive goes away.
So we can't rely on this instant storage for anything that's valuable,
but it might be perfect for a web server or app server.
If you think about it, you have a perfect image for your web server,
you launch it, there's no data on that web server.
Why wouldn't I use ephemeral storage?
It's fast, it's probably the fastest thing you're going to have,
it's on an SSD drive.
So lots of ways to look at ephemeral storage, expect it's not permanent.
To recap, the disks are physically attached to the host,
they're attached only during launch, which means that you shut them down,
they're gone.
The data is scrubbed when the instance is terminated,
we've heard that before,
and if I wanted to I could encrypt using third-party tools.
So one of the caveats about this type of storage is that these volumes
can't be detached and attached to a different instance,
just can't do that.
There is lots of customers out there that use third-party tools to make copies
of this information and store it on Elastic Block Storage. So there is a number of possibilities if you want to take a bit of risk.