In this clip,
we're going to take a look at the elastic load balancer
operation and some of its features.
So probably the most popular use case for using this load
balancer is internet-facing load balancer,
where it's deployed in the public subnet,
you're balancing traffic to the private subnet.
So, let's look at a picture.
We've got our VPC, we have a private subnet with our workload,
we order the load balancer, it gets placed in the public subnet,
and my workload remaining in the private subnet,
how do I get to it?
Well, a DNS name with public IP address of the load balancer,
the VIP, and we have that communication.
The other option, internal, where it's an intranet location,
and we're hosted in the VPC, yet again,
so we have a private subnet and a private subnet.
We still have separation.
In one of the private subnets goes my load balancer,
in the other private subnet, my workload.
DNS name with the private IP address of the load balancer
versus the internet facing with the DNS name of the public
IP address of the load balancer,
so a little bit of a difference in the placement into what we're doing
with our workload and the load balancing that we need.
So we've eluded to some of the features of the load balancer.
Let's go over some of the kind of classic features that
apply to both of the load balancers.
So, health checks,
the ability of saying that instance has not responded three
times within a particular period of time,
so I'm not going to send any more traffic to that instance.
When it comes to security features,
managed by security groups and NACLs when it's hosted in a VPC.
Why would we say when it's hosted?
Well remember, we had classic networking from the past.
Nowadays it's going to be in a VPC.
It supports end-to-end traffic encryption,
HTTPS/TLS, SSL offloading to take the workload off the web servers,
so we have SSL termination support for the load balancer,
and we can also have sticky sessions.
So you've got a session and you're buying coffee with a particular server,
and you want to ensure that you keep talking to the same server,
you don't want to be directed to another server that
doesn't know anything about your order.
So sticky sessions are really kind of a commonality with load balancing,
associating the session with usually cookies.
So we have a session in that communication channel,
how long that communication channel is going to be open,
the client has authenticated to the load balancer,
the client is known, we have the SSL offload,
so hopefully you can see the benefit of using load
balancing for our web servers.
Now the advantage of the load balancer is that the work of encryption and
decryption and authentication is taken over by the load balancer,
so we end up with a single point of contact for managing
the encryption and decryption process of all traffic that's
being sent to all instances, and we're using HTTPS/TLS,
a pretty standard way of dealing the end-to-end traffic encryption.
Now, if I'm using TLS,
the server certificate will be used to terminate the client connections.
And that can be managed on the load balancer,
and this helps out because it separates the job of
authentication from the instance to the load balancer.
The SSL offload allows me to have the HTTP-encrypted session
between the client to the load balancer,
and to the back-end instances.
And in order to carry out this negotiation process,
you're going to need a security policy.
So these security policies require an SSL certificate to
be installed on the load balancer, kind of makes sense,
doesn't it,
that the load balancer will work based on a set of rules that are
defined by the level of security and at that certificate.
So you can use the predefined policies, or you can have a custom security policy,
maybe you want your own certificates to be on the load balancer,
you don't want to use the ones provided by Amazon.
So, the custom security policies can certainly be used for more security.
So when the client authenticates, looks at that custom certificate,
the load balancer terminates the connections at the load balancer,
decrypts the request, sends it to the back-end instance.
So there's a look at some of the features and some of the security options and some general rules of how the load balancing works at AWS.