In this clip we're going to take a look at storage options as well as key pairs.
And we'll take a look at our host server,
which has a couple of instance for a couple of customers,
color coded, you can see in blue those instances are using ephemeral storage,
where in orange the instances, they're not doing exactly the same thing.
So Elastic Block Storage can be access, in this case,
by both of the instances for the blue and the orange customer.
So these Elastic Block Storage volumes, they are block storage,
but they're formatted based on the operating system that you're
attaching them to and what you can do with the block storage is
indicate when the instance shuts down, I want to keep my storage.
Now it can also create a snapshot, which gets stored over an S3, i.
e.
in a bucket,
so the number one advantage of Elastic Block Storage is taking those snapshots
and placing them in a bucket and then optionally I could take those snapshots
and manually copy them to a different region.
I also have the ability of using the Elastic File System,
this is more of a NAS solution where multiple servers can attach
to the volumes on the Elastic File System.
So we have a few storage choices, EBS, we know about S3,
we know about ephemeral, and now we know a little bit about EFS.
We'll do a little more work on EBS and S3 throughout these classes.
For now we're looking at the choices, when I spin up an instance - what can I do?
Lastly, Amazon EC2 key pairs, if I want to authenticate to my instance,
I have to use the key pairs and this is through public key
cryptography and I use this to decrypt and encrypt the
pertinent logon information, so before I log in to my instance,
I have to create a valid key pair.
If I don't have the key pair that I've assigned to an instance,
I'm not getting in, I have to start over.
So the name of the key pair must be linked to your instance at boot.
Linux, we'll use the key pair to log on via SSH.
Windows they'll use the key pair to decrypt the
administrator password and log on via RDP.
Now if you lose the private key for an instance store-backed instance,
you can't access the instance ever.
You have to start over.
EC2 keys are 2048-bit SSH-2 RSA keys. So there's a fair bit of security involved in that public/private key pair.