Some of the additional features for ELB security is the
order preference from the server,
so the load balancer will choose the order for the
SSL/TLS cyphers and protocols.
What's happening here is that the cyphers are based on the priority from
the server's point of view instead of the client's.
Now by default, you've got that client wanting to connect with the load balancer,
and they have a list of cyphers and protocols that
they each talk in and support,
and the default is that the first cipher on the client's list that
matches any one of the load balancer's ciphers,
that's selected for the SSL connection.
Well you might say, well I don't want to do that,
I want the load balancer to say, this is the security I'm talking,
you don't want to comply, see you later.
So we have a pretty handy way to ensure that there's a high level of security,
rather than the client dragging the load balancer
down to a lower level of security.
Another feature is perfect forward secrecy.
It prevents the decoding of the captured data,
so there's no compromise of that session key because it's
not going to be stored in a partition, it's going to be stored in RAM,
so it's ephemeral storage, it's gone if the system shuts down,
so no luck.
So as we know, we can use the predefined,
or we can have our own custom,
so just a little more work on the security policies for the load balancer.
It supports ciphers and protocols that are used through that negotiation,
either SSL or TLS.
There is a predefined security policy provided by AWS,
created and updated according to the best AWS security practices at the time.
Now these practices include TLS 1.
1 and 1.
2, setting the server order preference,
and the end result is to have a high-secure cipher that
matches with the bulk of Amazon customers.
However, you can use a custom security policy defined by your needs, the customer needs, and matches your compliance standards.