In this clip IAM Users and Security Controls,
we're going to delve a little bit further into the concept of IAM
and what it's performing and then in upcoming clips we're going
to get into creating the policies, applying them,
so and so forth.
So defining access, that's what I want to do with IAM,
other than being the root user, and I'm accessing data,
that's the most important, and if I'm a user,
well do I really want to give users direct access to data or
do I want the user instead to query the application server
and the application server says, well I've got to check,
can I do and it sees if there's a policy applied to the server.
Now these policies are JSON format and so every time a request
is carried out where our policy is involved,
you're going to get an answer back that hey thumbs up,
you can do that, or no you can't.
And the best practice is don't do this by user,
add that user to a group to define the access in that way.
So identity and access management, giving me a flow for accessing users,
groups, and more.
So after that initial root user has been created,
in order to get additional users you're using IAM.
It's controlling the authentication and the authorized
access to the resources in your account.
It's also providing central management of user accounts and user
access to resources based on users and groups,
roles, i.
e.
what is the server doing, is it an application server,
is it a database server, the policies which some provided by AWS,
a managed policy, i.
e.
a policy you can manage, an inline policy,
inline with a role, a computer system, an application server,
or an custom policies that you want to create.
So you have questions, we have answers.
Access to the management console?
Assign a password.
Access AWS resources via a script or automation?
Create an access key or maybe you're using an existing access key, i.
e.
a secret access key that might be enabled for the account.
Controlling access to the resources at AWS?
Attaching a policy to the user?
Let's attach the user to an IAM group,
that's the best practice and I know I keep hammering that point,
but really important.
Extra security?
Add multi-factor authentication to either the root account or the IAM user.
So looking at IAM at work for access points,
maybe I want to control access to the S3 bucket.
I've got specific needs and requirements for some content.
Maybe it's an EC2 instance and the access to database records.
Maybe it's specific access to a folder in S3, not the whole bucket.
Maybe it's access through Cognito for a single sign on.
Maybe it's database access when the username matches the actual IAM policy.
There could be a lot of scenarios where you want to set
up access using a policy through IAM.
So you could look at this as administrative setup for access,
what about the end user access?
For IAM @ Work for Users at the very least you get to
change your own password on a schedule,
perhaps you set up IAM to define group membership,
somebody managing the members of a group.
That's all they can do, that's what you want them to do.
Maybe you want somebody to manage other IAM users,
that's as far as you want them to go.
Maybe it's for setting the actual account policy, the default account policy.
Maybe all you need to do is create security reports.
Again, we can get very granular and define the jobs for the end user,
the jobs for people using the resources,
what they can and can't do.
When we have an IAM policy it's checked every time
access is requested via from that user, that group or that role.
There's a policy attached, let's review it, every time.
Did I mention Every.
Time.
It's not like you get a DHCP lease for 7 days,
we're checking it every single time. We don't want any holes.