In this clip we'll take a look at controlling access to resources.
Now some of the access resource will be specifically IAM controlled,
other access is going to be more of the big picture as
to where the access can come from.
So if we start off with the access to resources,
the most common way to access something at AWS is through the
management console and we know we can use IAM to control access to
everything except for the root account.
We also have the command line interface and we now know that the command line
interface involves those access keys linked to an account.
Both of these I would consider administrative
methodologies of accessing resources.
The next thing we can do is access via HTTPS using APIs, using credentials.
We can access using software development kits to actually
create something that's quite custom and this would be
considered from the programmer point of view.
And lastly we have managed services, an example AWS config.
And I would define these resources as preconfigured.
They're set up, you have to define how far you want to go.
The managed services, the access to those resources,
involves obviously credentials.
A little different from the level where the programmer is and a
little different from pure administration.
Now resources outside of IAM that we have to control at AWS,
what about an EC2 logon?
So I've got a user, an administrator,
and they have to access and authenticate to one of the
instances running Linux or Windows,
that's a logon which is not controlled by IAM,
that's at the operating system level, at the application level.
Same thing could be said for something that you build yourself,
let's say you build a database server and you're logging
on to that relational database server.
Administrator authenticating to the database outside of IAM.
Now there also could be managed services,
which are completely controlled by IAM,
but there also are these authentication methods that you have to manage as well.
A couple of other ones, protection of my instances,
if I've got them in a security group,
that's a different form of security outside of IAM,
although you could say, well couldn't you control who sets up the security group?
Yeah that's true,
but just trying to make a distinction between some of the
security levels that we have at AWS.
And finally, RDS protection,
if I have something that I build myself or something
that is provided for me from Amazon,
I can set up security groups to protect that instance and that RDS database
could be within a VPC where we know we can use security groups,
or it might be standalone.
So a couple of ways of accessing resources where the control isn't always IAM.
These access methods, not part of IAM.
So are you up for a little bit of a challenge?
Well let's compare the root user, IAM user, the IAM roles.
If I start with who has a password?
The root user, yeah they've got to have a password.
The IAM user?
Yep.
The role?
No.
Remember you've got a computer system asking for permission from the IAM policy,
so it's not setting a password, it's not a human.
Access key?
The root user?
Yes.
Remember we can get rid of that if we don't want that
automation through the secret key for the root user.
IAM user?
Yes access key.
Again, we can control the access.
IAM role?
No.
Belonging to a group?
Root User?
Self contain.
IAM user?
Absolutely.
IAM role?
No.
The IAM role could be controlling a group.
Finally, association with the EC2 instance?
Root user?
No.
IAM user?
We don't want to.
The role?
Yeah, we want to do it that way, again,
the inline policy for that instance saying what is the job that
that instance is allowed to carry out for us?
Control by IAM.
Okay did you pass?
Well that was a no pressure test. So that's a look at access to resource outside of IAM at AWS.