In this demo we're going to take a look at EBS volumes and the security
that we can attach to the EBS volumes and their snapshots.
So from the console let's go into EBS.
Don't see it.
Now the reason you don't see it, it's kind of interesting,
it's not in the new menu, we have to go into EC2,
that's where the volumes are attached.
So on the right we can go down and there is Elastic Block Store.
So let's go into Volumes and we can see there is a number of volumes.
Some are in use and some are available.
Now what does it mean in use?
Well you can bet if they're in use they're probably attached to an instance,
so let's go back up to the dashboard.
There's one running instance, but I'll bet you there's three.
And each of these will have a volume.
Now if we go back down to volumes and let's select the one that is
in use at the top and let's change our view,
now we can see this is a volume for the web server,
it's attached, it's a general purpose, it's a certain size,
and there is a snapshot associated with this particular EBS volume,
it's not encrypted.
And there's no option here where I can encrypt it and we'll
look at that as we go through this demo.
Now along with every volume there are status checks.
If I look at Monitoring, there are 9 CloudWatch metrics I could use.
So I can take a look at the read, the write, throughput, the queue.
Now if I was concerned about some of my volumes,
if I was worried about how the volume was participating,
and there has been some of this at Wired Brain Coffee as they scale up in size,
so one of the recommendations from Globomantics is that they create some alarms.
So I could go through and create the alarm,
send a notification to a topic, I don't see a topic there that's useful to us,
so let's go through and create a topic, pick some name that will make sense,
we can send it to a particular account whenever the average of
throughput percentage is greater than say 65%.
We want to see what's happening with this box.
And we can create this alarm.
I could also define tags, so we could give a name of web server.
So there's a review of the volumes, let's go and create a volume.
So if I want to create a volume, I then have the definition of General Purpose,
Provisioned IOPS, if I want a certain speed,
and we're not worried yet about the IOPS,
but we could come in and create a volume and say we are
interested in IOPS and set our speed.
Now notice at the bottom, regardless of whether I pick provisioned IOPS or not,
I can go through and encrypt this volume.
Let's go back to General Purpose and we'll create this volume
and once it's created we can give it a name,
log files.
Now what if I want to encrypt this volume?
Well I missed my chance.
Now there's ways that I can end up with an encrypted volume,
but I can't do it here,
I have to make that decision at the time of volume creation.
So let's create another volume and we'll make it General Purpose as well,
but we'll encrypt this volume.
And when I encrypt this volume, I've got some choices,
do I want a default master key provided by Amazon or
do I want to bring my own keys?
So we'll accept the defaults, but before we click Create,
look at the Snapshot ID.
So I can actually go through and decide that I want to
create a volume from an existing snapshot,
and you can see that there's a number of snapshots that are there.
So we'll create this.
So let's name this volume, this is going to be encrypted volume.
Let's look at the properties of this drive, and we can see now it is encrypted.
We've got the KMS Key ID and we've got that core information
as to where it's actually being encrypted,
in US East.
Next, let's take this encrypted drive and create a snapshot.
Name is going to be encrypted data snapshot, it's encrypted.
Why is it encrypted?
Well the volume's already encrypted, it's going to remain encrypted.
Let's click Create.
The process has started.
So if we go over to our snapshots, it's completed, and there is our drive.
It's encrypted.
What I could do with this is also copy this volume and notice if I'm copying it,
it's defining it as it's encrypted, once it's encrypted it's staying encrypted.
Now I also could take a look at, so let's look at the root drive,
and we can see that this is not encrypted.
There's a Permissions tab, it's a private snapshot.
I could go through and change that,
maybe I would like to share that with another account.
If I wanted to do that, I could add in the account number,
so in this case I could add in another account that's linked to
Wired Brain and say okay I've now got permissions assigned from
this snapshot to multiple accounts.
Now it's the GUI so things are running in the background and taking time,
so let's speed this up,
let's go back to Modify Permissions and we can see right now it's private,
but it's linked between the account that I'm logged in as and another account.
I'm linking them together,
and I could change this from private to public if I wanted to.
So I've got the control, I think I want to keep this private,
after all it is for my web server.
So let's go back to Snapshots, change our view,
and take another snapshot and from Actions say Create a Volume.
Now notice the volume is not encrypted,
so I can't change this here because it wasn't started as an encrypted volume,
so when the volume was snapshotted, the rules were in effect.
But what if I go through and say I would like to copy?
Now I can copy the snapshot to a new snapshot,
it's going to be in US East and I can encrypt it.
So the dance between our volumes is like this.
I start with a volume, I can choose to encrypt it or not,
if I don't encrypt it, then the cycle from creating the volume,
snapshotting the volume, means it remains unencrypted.
However,
if I go to the snapshots of a volume that is not encrypted and decide
to copy this snapshot I can encrypt this snapshot.
So let's do this, and once this process finishes,
you can see it's pending as far as the status,
we can see our copied snapshot and from this snapshot we can
then go through and create a new volume,
which is encrypted because when I copied it,
I encrypted it.
So creating the volume, I have an encrypted volume,
so going over to Volumes, I've got my volume at the top.
I can attach this to an instance, but it has to support EBS encryption.
But I don't have an instance that supports encryption, why?
Because I've created very small inexpensive 3-tier images in these
demos and so it doesn't match up with encryption.
I would have to create an instance that supports encryption and then I
could attach the volume and it would be encrypted.
So there's a look at EBS security and some of the ways it's being carried out at Wired Brain Coffee and some other options.