Probably the most important consideration when we're dealing
with security is knowing your network, it's signed off,
it's secure, and that starts with VPC architecture.
Now the VPC architecture, the Virtual Private Cloud,
cloud providers do it different ways,
but they're all pretty well doing pretty much the same thing.
You have some software defined networking saying this is
your space to setup as you see fit.
So a virtual network for your account, isolated within the AWS cloud,
we had a classic network, you may still be on a classic network,
that's more of a flat infrastructure, nowadays you sign up for Amazon,
you're starting with a VPC.
Now the IP address range is chosen by you,
the customer, and the VPC can span multiple availability zones,
i.
e.
data centers, however each subnet must reside within each availability zone.
If you think about it,
pretty hard to have a subnet spanning 2 separate buildings 3 to 5 miles apart,
but the VPC can span the availability zones.
So you have failover, number one thing Amazon wants you to know,
please design your infrastructure for failover.
Best practice, I'm repeating myself, but it's important,
use 2 subnets in different availability zones for each network layer.
What are you building?
2 tier, 3 tier, set them up for failover.
So we've done some work on subnets, now let's take a look at the type of subnet.
We're talking about public and private subnets,
so here's an example, we have a VPC and there is a public subnet.
That should say to you that the design of this is for public access to
those systems at the very least in that public subnet,
maybe a load balancer in that public subnet,
but the thought process is public,
I'm wanting public access for something on that subnet.
Now let's add some other pieces.
If I add a NAT device,
that won't be that useful for the systems that are already in the
public subnet because they'll have public access,
so the NAT device or the NAT service could be useful for my private subnet
with instances that want to talk privately among themselves,
but they may need updates and they may need some way to be wired to
the outside world through a NAT service or a device.
Let's add in a couple more subnets, so we've got subnets,
so we know we have public and private subnets,
within the VPC we have routing for all instances,
we also have NICs on each instance that can be turned on or off
for public access or private access only.
What else do we need?
Well we need some way of getting outside,
so we need some sort of gateway, internet gateway service,
linked to the VPC,
wired to the route tables to ensure that the public subnets know how to get out
or how to accept traffic from outside across the internet.
So when a subnet's traffic is routed to the internet gateway,
then it's deemed a public subnet, that is the differentiator,
having the internet gateway turns a subnet into a public subnet.
Now if the subnet doesn't have a route to the internet gateway,
it's deemed as a private subnet.
Now we could have other things on the diagram,
we could define elastic IP addresses.
We could do a lot of detail,
but we're just building this piece by piece saying public/private subnets,
what's the reasoning for these subnets.
Is it for web access on the public subnet?
Is it for load balancing?
They're both possible answers.
Private subnets, could be database, could be application servers,
could be resources that don't need public access at all.
So all public subnets will need a routing table entry
that points to the internet gateway.
The private subnets,
they'll have a routing table entry potentially to a proxy/NAT instance or NAT
service for the outside access for those specific instances,
being able to go out and because that instance went out the
traffic the response can come back in,
potentially maybe totally protected subnets,
for example, PCI workloads,
that there is no access to the internet deemed
necessary for this potential workload.
The communication tool between the subnets,
between the outside world, between the different subnets in your VPC,
the route tables are making those decisions.
Now one way to define a route table is that those rules, i.
e.
routes, they define where the network traffic, where the packets can go.
So in this example we've got a VPC defined as a 10.
0.
0/16 subnet and the main route table says got it,
local traffic, I'll allow that.
So each route table has a set of rules that determine the network traffic flow.
That initial route starts with a single rule for local traffic within the VPC,
when you create the VPC and you define your subnet.
All instances, therefore,
launched into that VPC are going to be bound by their IP address,
the subnet and the route table relationship.
So if you mess it up, it's not working at all.
So how many possibilities could you have why an instance
isn't working the way you thought?
Yeah, the wrong VPC, the wrong IP address scheme,
the wrong route table, the wrong subnet,
could be a lot of different reasons.
And each route table, now some rules,
every subnet has to be associated with a route table,
otherwise how could it route traffic?
There's got to be some linkage with the routing.
Best practice,
for best security create your custom route tables so you
know where your traffic is exactly going.
Don't get caught using the default VPC,
which automatically assigns you outside access via an internet gateway.
It may be what you want,
but I'll bet you the range of addresses over time that were assigned
automatically might not be what you want long term.
So what happens when we have a situation where we have multiple VPCs
and we decide that we'd like to link them together?
Well we can do that and we can do that through a
cool feature called VPC peering.
Now VPC peering allows me connections between two VPCs.
The peering connection isn't relying on a single piece of hardware,
this is a service provided by Amazon that you sign up for in effect.
These are the two VPCs, here's my security,
I want to have communication,
private IP addresses must be used to route the traffic,
and you can also set up communication with VPCs in other accounts.
Now all the VPCs must be within a single region and this is where
your networking might come back and haunt you.
We can't have any overlapping of network addresses allowed.
So maybe over time the separate VPCs had exactly the same IP address range,
you tried to link them together, how are they going to communicate?
Transitive peering is not allowed.
What this means is that we can't go through and say well I've got one VPC
peering with another VPC and if I add in a third VPC,
they aren't automatically having communication established,
it's got to be direct between each VPC.
So in this case if I have three VPCs,
I've got three arrangements between the VPCs and I have to have those direct
arrangements in order for the VPCs to talk to each other.
So I could have generic corporate services hosted in one VPC and the other VPC,
say dev and production,
would utilize those core services held in the generic VPC for the corporation. So that's a look at VPC architecture and some of the main components.