In this continuation clip of VPC security,
we're going to look at security groups, NACLs,
and connectivity options.
We ended off our last clip taking a look at the multi-tier security
groups and some examples of how we could setup security.
So let's look at an example.
Let's take an example of Wired Brain Coffee,
the coffee growers in Australia, a three tier architecture,
and the recommendations from Globomantics as to what they
should consider for security groups.
So starting off with availability zones.
Availability Aone A and B over in Australia, that makes sense.
They have a public subnet and what they're going to put in
that public subnet is load balancing.
The load balancing is exposed, not the web servers, important concept.
Now we need a security group for this public subnet and it's going to be
for the web tier elastic load balancer and we're going to take inbound
rules from port 443 from anywhere in the world.
Next, private subnets.
On the private subnets we're starting off with instances for the web tier,
the security group required, inbound rule through port 80.
Now once they get authenticated,
the web tiers can happily communicate with port 80.
The source, the web tier elastic load balancer.
So notice the protection.
What's next?
Well, another set of load balancers for the app tier.
Now the app tier needs a security group,
inbound rule from specific port 8082, the source: the web tier.
Notice, again, the protection.
Next, the app tier.
The app tier inbound rule from port 8082,
the source: the app tier elastic load balancer.
And finally, I guess we need some data,
so we've got the database tier and the inbound rules from port 3030,
source: app tier.
So we don't have any over-extension of any tier needing to
go further than they absolutely have to.
So an example of security groups in a three tier architecture.
Now let's look at some examples of network access control lists.
So for network access control lists, stateless subnet firewalls,
that's really what they are.
They work at the subnet level, they're optional.
They control the inbound and the outbound rules.
But these are separate inbound and outbound rules.
So they perform a separate allow and deny of traffic flow.
The rules are processed in order and the default NACL
allows all traffic to flow both ways, in and out.
Best practice: Number your rules by 10's.
Now what do I mean by that?
Well let's look at a specific example.
So for this custom NACL, we've got inbound rules and outbound rules.
Note the rules are numbered 120, 130, showing you a subset of all the rules.
If we take a look at 120, from anywhere the protocol port 443 will allow that.
Is there a matching rule on the outbound rules?
Yes there is.
120 TCP 443, allow.
In that specific example the packets can go in through the
subnet up towards the instance and back out.
What else can we do?
From the source IP of 172.
30.
1.
10/16 we allow port 3389, must be doing RDP, must be doing administration.
Note the asterisk rule, source address anywhere in the world,
you're not identifying yourself, any protocol,
any port, don't want to talk to you, deny.
Going down on the outbound rules, we've looked at 120, what's 130?
From anywhere, TCP specific ports, so outbound servicing of maybe web pages,
we're allowing that.
And we're denying anything from anywhere, again the 0 rule.
So highly recommended as a starting point for setting up a custom NACL,
overruling your default NACL, which says you can do whatever you want.
Now onto gateway devices connecting from on-prem into Amazon and
ultimately connecting to a virtual private cloud.
We have some external choices that are pretty common.
We can attach an Internet Gateway.
We can attach a Virtual Private Gateway,
so two distinct differences here,
either access for public or access from corporation.
Hey I want it private.
I want an IPsec VPN.
So the internet gateway allows you to connect instances
located in the VPC to the internet.
Now we kind of know that by now.
It's added as a target to the route table for the
routable traffic for the internet.
The virtual private gateway,
well this allows you to connect your VPC to your on-premise data center.
So you get a hybrid design, all the range in cloud these days.
So the virtual private gateway gives you private connectivity between the
Amazon VPC of your choice and your on-premise network.
Now I've got a couple of examples for VPC access.
We can, of course, have ingress and egress internet access subject to the rules,
subnet rules, NACLs, rules and regulations of the VPC.
We've got the Amazon side of the secure VPN connection.
We've got the customer side of the secure VPN connection.
We can also have dedicated and isolated bandwidth to AWS,
such as the direct connect where I could have up to a 10 GB private connection.
I have to have an on-premise device, either hardware or software,
in order to access AWS across the internet.
And we also know we have VPC access where we can enable VPC peering,
direct peering.
So there's a number of examples.
The connectivity to Amazon is very well documented and so take a look at the
docs and you'll be able to get some great step by step,
depending on the devices, hardware and software,
that you're using on-prem.
For this course, getting the big picture of how do I get access to the VPC?
One example though to end off with,
VPCs with multiple subnets and hardware VPN access.
So let's review, we've got availability zones, that's good.
We've got public subnets and we've got private subnets,
we've got workloads, we've got NAT so the private subnets can get out.
Obviously we need an internet gateway to help with those public subnets,
we've got routing in the bottom left to our on-prem
resources and we also need some routing,
which we have as standard default routing within the VPC,
giving us routing across the availability zones.
So using the same pieces, the new component,
the router from the on-prem to the Amazon VPC. So there's a look at VPC security and connectivity with AWS.