In this clip we're going to take a look at delegation and federation to AWS.
So federating external users, users that might need access to the backend of AWS,
or they need access to resources, but they don't have IAM accounts,
they don't have any permanent identities.
Well users that already authenticate to a corporate network,
well they can be linked to AWS resources through a process called federation.
You're existing user identity can be linked or federate into AWS.
The most common example is Active Directory Domain Services.
So this can be quite useful when users have corporate credentials.
AWS Directory Service allows you to establish a trust between the
corporate network and the AWS account holding the resources.
So that's one example and the common scenario would be
that somebody is using Active Directory,
they want access to a resource,
we've talked about roles in the past and we'll talk about them in this clip,
we're going to have to create a role that contains the
resources that you want to allow access to.
So the persons authenticates and once they authenticate,
there's a level of trust and that level of trust will
define who's allowed to assume the role,
policy will then define the actions and the resources that
the principle is allowed access to use.
Now we've talked about the principle being an AWS account or a service,
but it now can be, for example, a SAML provider or identity provider,
an external user.
So in that case the user could have an internet identity such as
a mobile app and the backend is in Amazon.
And so they can be identified using an identity provider such as Facebook,
Google or OpenID.
So we're overviewing this here so you get an idea of the
authentication chain when they're an external user.
So with an IAM role, I'm defining access to Resource 1,
in this case, or Resource 2, and a federate user,
they won't have a permanent identity in AWS the way the IAM users actually do,
so we have to actually create a role providing temporary
access through delegation to the AWS resource.
So permissions are defined using IAM roles,
the permissions are attached to the role,
but not to an IAM user or group.
We're going to use the authentication,
the external authentication and that has to be vetted and approved first.
So when the role gets assumed,
what's different is that there are temporary security credentials
provided for access to the requested AWS resource.
So you don't have any long term security credentials that are
stored with access keys and secret access keys,
this is how we access resources at Amazon as an external user.
So when I'm creating an IAM role, I'm going to have to be pretty precise,
pretty careful, because after all it's an external user to my Amazon resources,
and I'll have to define what's the resource that I need external access to?
Then I'll define a trust policy.
What are the actions and resources that the principal will be allowed to?
Once I make that decision, who can assume the role?
Then, how are they accessing it?
We've talked about the AWS account accessing the role,
but in this case we're talking about a SAML provider or an identity
provider needing access to something at Amazon.
Maybe you have a third party orchestration tool that needs
access to your resources to manage those resources and so you
have to give credentials for that access when they have to
carry out their administration.
Once we get these tasks done, we'll define the permission policy,
save it, and put it in place.
Now when we're using identity federation,
we're using some sort of external provider to provide identity,
i.
e.
using an identity provider and this provides that
permission to the external user identity,
but they don't need the IAM user account with credentials.
Now the overall management of those external identities is
carried out using your selected identity provider,
where the user is first authenticating to.
The common corporate example, Active Directory Domain Services,
most companies have this.
And well known identity providers include Google, Facebook, and Amazon Cognito.
So creating that entity, that IAM identity provider,
establishes trust between what you have in your account and
the external identity provider where the authentication for
the end user is first taking place.
SAML 2.
0, security association markup language, OpenID Connect, SAML 2.
0 supported by Active Directory as well,
and lots of third party identity providers.
Now identity federation using the AWS Directory Services,
this is a managed service,
there's two other options that you could also use to connect your AWS resources.
The first one,
use your existing on-prem Active Directory Domain Services and create
a standalone directory service in AWS and then you would have to sync
it with something like Azure Connect.
The managed service, which I don't have to install,
I can just use, provides all the patches,
all the backups and all the upgrades.
In addition, the managed directory service infrastructure,
that's replicated across multiple availability zones within your region.
So you have a couple of choices.
The behind scenes technology that's providing the
authentication is the Security Token Service,
STS,
this provides the temporary security credentials when you're
performing federation with a federated user.
Now STS by default is a global service with a single endpoint.
You can choose to send your requests to a specific region
endpoint if you want to cut down the latency or for additional
redundancy in your overall design.
Now these temp credentials use a short-lived access key,
a secret access key, and a session token.
Customers can also specify how long the credentials are valid for.
Now by default credentials expire after an hour when using SAML.
The minimum duration credentials is 15 minutes.
If I'm using a federated token or a session token,
the minimum is, again, 15 minutes, the maximum could be 36 hours,
and the default is 1 hour.
So some of the features of using STS is we have secure
access without requiring an AWS identity,
therefore I don't have to distribute the security credentials,
I can do it through STS.
It supports the process of single sign on and also
supports multi-factor authentication,
and all calls are going to be logged in CloudTrail. So that's a look at federation and delegation at AWS.