Well we've come to the end of a long module.
Let's wrap it up with some best practices for planning our access control.
So when we're creating individual users, we must use IAM.
This way we get unique credentials per user,
credential rotation per user, and we have individual unique permissions,
and always start by granting least privilege.
Make sure we manage permissions through groups.
It's much easier to assign the same permission to multiple users.
So it's kind of obvious isn't it?
Easier to reassign to permissions as the responsibilities of your users change,
and one change updates multiple users.
Now in conditions there was one example condition we were
looking at when we were dealing with resources,
using an IP address range to be able to connect to some resource at AWS.
Consider those sorts of conditions when you're trying to be absolutely granular.
Restrict access from a specific IP address,
as mentioned, restrict a database creation using a specific engine.
Again,
trying to narrow down where you can solve potential future security
problems when you didn't lock something down,
when you could have.
Or maybe you want to set conditions that the user can
create only specific EC2 instances.
So again, that granular control.
On to auditing.
Get visibility into your users activity.
How do I do that?
Oh yeah, I enable CloudTrail to get the logs of the API calls,
so I could log the calls to an S3 Bucket in my account
and then I can see what's going on.
Create strong passwords.
Ensure you, your users, and your data is protected.
So that strong password policy, there's a number of components to consider,
password expiration, password strength, the reuse policy.
You may find that your corporate policy is a good
baseline to consider using in AWS.
Remember, the password policy does not apply to the root user.
Credential rotation.
Ideally rotating those credentials on a schedule.
We can find out the information on our users and the
credentials that are active or the ones that should be
rotated or deleted using credential reports.
The IAM console will also display when the password was last used.
So we have some tools and we can grant IAM user permission
so a user can rotate their credentials.
Now you and I know most users aren't going to do that,
so you probably want to look at how you can automate that task.
Lastly, if you're defining roles for EC2 instances,
hey they rotate their credentials automatically.
Multi-factor authentication, enable that for all privileged users, all users.
Require a one-time code during authentication.
And so we have choices, the virtual MFA, hardware devices, or an SMS feature.
What about sharing?
Well only use IAM roles to share access.
There is no need to share security credentials,
there's no need to store long term credentials.
We want to analyze and implement these based on your use case.
Cross account access potentially, account delegation, or federation.
When looking at the IAM roles,
we want to consider using those roles for EC2 instances.
Again, the example, my instance needs to access a bucket on my behalf,
let the instance carry out that request on my behalf.
Access keys are stored on the instances.
We have automatic key rotation.
We get the automatic assigning of least privilege to the
application if we manage IAM roles for our instances.
And if you're a developer,
it's fully integrated with the software development kits offered by AWS,
and if you're an administrator,
you can do this all at the command line interface.
And oh yeah, the root account.
Reduce or restrict the root account.
We looked at certain ways of doing that,
such as a random password that we don't save,
locking up the email address of the root account.
We have to do this.
We want to remove the potential for misuse or these administrative credentials,
they can do anything.
Alright time for a wrap up.
We looked at identity and access management.
We looked at IAM users and groups.
We looked at controlling access to resources.
We took a look at understanding the role and purpose of access keys.
We then created some IAM policies,
we looked at the aspect of delegation and federation.
And then we ended off with some best practices when planning access control.
So thanks for hanging in, I know it's a long module, lots of information.
Hopefully it's great benefit to you.
Up next, securing core infrastructure. Hope you to see you in that module.