Hagos,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss in of the technique for filtering dates using combo boxes or using
data validation lists.
And we're basically gonna have some date ranges so you can select a starting month and you
can select unending month.
And the data in your table is going to react to your selection.
So you're gonna have the data appearing for the sales between these two months.
The March 14 for example,
on October 14 here.
This is one way to do it.
Using combo box is the other way,
which performs the same function as well.
You can do it using data validation lists.
So we're going to see how both ways are constructed.
And I want to grab your attention as well to the fact that the sales here are sorted in
descending order.
Okay,
so here,
because Canada has the highest sales,
it's at the top.
And then us a having second place and so on and so forth.
And this is the case on both tables as well.
So we're going to discuss this ah,
date range dashboard,
and we're going to see what is behind all that.
That is feeding these tables.
OK,
so we're going to go to our data validation dates worksheet here,
and we're going to discuss actually the list of months.
The are feeding the combo boxes and the data validation lists.
So actually,
this list of months I have two ways for creating it.
The first way is to create a pivot table,
OK,
And this pivot tables sources actually the road data and have created a month column here
and this month column is created using the date function,
just as they explained on the previous video.
And basically,
I've created pivot table from that road.
It is sat and just put the month on the rose here.
And this will create this pivot table that you see here and to basically guarantee that the
months are sorted in ascending order.
You just click here and click on sort oldest to newest.
And every time this pivot table is refreshed,
the months are always gonna be sorted in ascending order and then you can have a dynamic
range on that table covering that table,
and this dynamic range will cover the list and then you assign that dynamic range to the
combo boxes or the date of elevation lists,
and we've learned how to do that Previously,
you could also do it in another way,
which is to basically write the list of months in a column here,
which is cold months.
And you just write the list of months by just writing,
for example,
January 14 year and just drag this handle like that.
And Excel will understand that you're trying to do a no to fill for months,
and it will just fill the months on.
Then you create a four minute here that checks if there are dates between this state,
which is here the first of January 2014.
But because of custom number formatting,
it looks like January forcing like that.
But the values the first of January.
And,
um,
this formula actually checks if there are dates between the this state and the end of month
for this state.
Israel.
The end of month for the States.
The under month function actually returns the last day of the month,
so it's going to check if there dates between the 1st January 14 and the 31st January 14
here in this row,
data on the order date column,
actually,
and if there are dates than this,
sell here is gonna be returned.
So basically,
it's going to check if there are dates between first junior 14 and 31st of January.
And if there are dates that it's going to return this cell,
If not,
then it is just going to give you a blank cell.
This is account ifs formula.
We've learned how to use the Countess formula previously.
So I'd recommend you check this formula on the simple workbook here to be able to
understand it and implemented as well.
And this is done for each and every month.
And if they're month exists,
or if there are dates,
that or between the first of the month and the end of the month,
then the months then the month is gonna be displayed here.
If not,
then it's gonna be blank.
As you can see here,
the formula is extended,
but only if there are dates than the month will appear.
If not,
then the month will just not appear.
It will be just a blank.
I personally prefer this method because it's easier to implement because you just create a
pivot table and make sure you sort it.
But the drawback to this method here,
the pivot table method for creating the months list is that you need to make sure to
refresh your pivot tables whenever you update your data.
OK,
so to hit this refresh button here refers All.
I've created this shortcut on my Excel,
but you can go to data top and click on Refresh old here.
But remembering to refresh my pivot tables is not a problem for me,
because I always refresh them.
It's just second nature to me whenever I update my road eight.
I just refresh my pivot tables so it's not a problem for me,
but it could pose a problem for other people.
This one is harder to implement,
however,
it actually updates the months lists without needing to refresh the pivot tables.
The months will be just updated instantaneously when you add some new months to your
rotator,
but it requires writing a formula,
so you're the judge.
Okay,
now let's go to our analysis formula stab,
and this worksheet contains some analysis form.
It is that we would use to control the sorting on this stable and also for the combo boxes
because we know that combo boxes would need some cells that actually,
they would output the index number for the selection in right,
because there is a combo box index number.
So,
actually,
this is the combo box index number four,
the date from combo box.
And this is the combo box index number for the date to combo box.
And after the combo box outputs the index number here for the selection in this cell,
there is actually an index formula that extracts the month using the index number,
the combo box index number.
It extracts the month from the months list.
But here,
actually,
we extract the month from the months list.
But we actually used the end of months formula to get the last day of the month,
and I'm going to tell you why just in a second,
Okay,
so we use the under month function to extract the last day because this is actually the
ending date that you need your filtration to extend to.
Okay,
so we need your filtration to extend between the first of March 14 and 31st of October 14
and here we've actually got some some If formula that axity sums up the sales between this
date and this date,
which this state is actually the 31st of October.
So if you check here on the home time on the ribbon,
their states,
if we just change its for it,
it's going to show us 31st of October.
This state is actually the 31st of October 2014.
So this summer's form it out actually sums up the sales between these two dates and have
learned about the summits formative previously.
So please make sure to go back to that lesson if you struggle with that formula and this is
done for all the countries,
and then the grand old is simply the summation off the sales for all the countries.
The same thing is done for data validation lists.
OK,
so we're basically doing a some ish formula and then a some function here for the grand
total.
To sum up.
All the sales were older countries were also using a rank for media the ranked out e que
formula which is equivalent to the rank function in Excel 2007.
So this rank function basically assigns a rank for each country in a descending order.
So actually,
the country with the high sales will have the highest rank and then the lowest sales is
gonna have the lowest rank.
So here,
actually Canada is having the highest sales was having ranked number two because actually,
this formula is applied to the grand total as well.
And the grand total is having ranked number one.
Because,
of course,
it's gonna be higher than any country,
right,
because the summation off sales for all the countries.
So actually the highest country is gonna have number two and then the second highest three
and so on and so forth.
And then there is actually a sorting table.
And this is the stable actually feeding our tables here on the day train stash board.
So our tables air basically having an informant s.
So if a cell contains a value,
then give me the value.
If not,
then give me a blank.
And then there is a formula here that says that if the value is blank and give me a blank
else,
give me the value of the cell and this is applied for both e stables.
This stable is copying its values from this stable and this stable is taking its values
from this stable,
basically.
And here,
actually,
to make sure that we get the correct rank for the countries we have actually written a view
look of formula with and,
ah,
if our if there is an error than give me a blank value,
basically.
And here you can see her that the look of value is basically the rose function.
And we've learned about the roads function before,
and we're generating the number to basically to look up the highest country because we're
gonna use this stable for the look up,
okay?
And we're gonna look up using the rank.
So we're actually going to look up the country's name using its rang.
And here the Rose,
for example,
Rose F A to F nine is gonna open it to OK,
so too is gonna be our look of value in this stable.
And we're gonna get actually the second column,
which contains the country.
So here this look of formula is going to generate our country's list,
and then our grand total is written actually manually here,
and there is also the total sales is generated as well using you could either do it using
the rank,
or you could do it actually using the country.
So here,
this one is looking up the country,
and this one is looking at the sales using the country from this stable as well.
Okay,
so be sure to check these formulas,
and that's it.
Basically,
this is how you generate the sorting table,
and then this dashboard is basically getting its value from the sorting tables.
And this is how you make sure that the country's sales are actually sorted in descending
order.
Okay,
So this technique here for the ranking table and the sorting table actually has a drawback
,
which is,
if you add a new country in your row data,
you need to make sure to add it to these two tables.
Okay,
but what I'm going to show you is actually a checkpoint the I have created,
which enables us to check for any missing countries on the fly really quickly so as to make
sure that we have data integrity and that we're not missing any countries on our data.
I'm gonna actually introduce two ways that you're able to do it,
and you could actually figure out your own way as well.
So here I've written a V look of formula,
and this formula looks up the country from the pivot table in this table here and returns
it.
But it there isn't if condition as well that says that if the cell in the pivot table is
blanked and give me a blank value else look up the country from the pivot table in this
table and return it basically returned the country itself and have actually put this if the
value is blanked and give me a blank.
So that will be able to extend the formula beyond the pivot tables as to allow for the
expansion off the pivot table so that if we add more countries,
pivot table is gonna expand,
they're gonna be more roast.
Two shows of the pivot table is gonna be longer.
And this if allows for the expansion.
So basically,
this actually looks up the country from the pivot table in this table and returns it.
And if the country is not returned and we get a hash and a value than the country does not
exist,
and we need to add it to the table There is also another way that you could do it here.
This formula basically generates true or false values and have added some conditional
formatting to as well.
So if it's true,
it's going to be green.
If it's fools,
then it's gonna be read.
And I'm gonna have a demonstration here for you by adding another country.
So,
for example,
if I take any row here,
just,
ah,
duplicated and just add a different country here.
Russia,
for example.
We don't have this country on our data on I refresh here my table and go back to the
checkpoint.
You can see here that Russia is reflected here as having a hash and a value on this column
and having a false value on this column.
Okay,
By the way,
you don't have to create both these columns.
It's just here two ways of doing the same thing.
OK,
so here you're If you check this checkpoint whenever you update your data,
you know,
I'm trying to introduce the concept of having checkpoints on your reports or dashboards so
that whenever you update the data here on the road data,
you look at the checkpoint.
You just have a quick lines of the checkpoint to make sure that you have data integrity,
that everything is adding up properly and that you don't have any gaps in your numbers.
Basically,
that all your numbers add up to each other.
Because if you're having problems with your data than the total sales on all the countries
,
air not gonna add up to the grand total,
for example.
So basically,
when we see this,
when we have a glance at our checkpoint and we see this,
we know that Russia does not exist.
So we're basically going to insert in euro here and right Russia here,
for example,
and right Russia here is well and just drag this formula and direct this formula as well
and dragged this rank formula as well.
Okay,
and everything is gonna be fine.
So as you can see here,
the checkpoint clears again.
And you know that you have accounted for all the countries on your road data.
Okay,
guys,
So that's it for this technique.
I hope that I have introduced some good ideas for you that you can implement as is,
or you can add your own as well.
And I hope I have simulated your minds to come up with some great looking and professional
dashboards.
I'd recommend that you would check all the formulas in this sample workbook thoroughly so
as to be able to understand this lesson better.
Thank you very much for watching this video and I'll see on the next one.