tega is welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss another dash boarding technique which on that technique,
we're gonna use,
Ah,
a table and a pivot table and a slicer and the choose function.
Okay,
so the objective is to create different aggregation methods for the user to choose from.
Okay.
So as you can see her on the slicer,
I can choose to get the average off the order amount.
And you can see here that the average appears in cell G two or can choose to get the
maximum of the order amount,
and it appears here and sell G two or can choose to get the minimum,
Or I can choose to get the total.
So that's for your user who doesn't want to fiddle with the formulas and stuff.
They just want to see average,
maximum,
minimum and total.
Okay.
And you can apply other aggravations as well so you can expand the options on this slicers
or just giving you Ah,
an example.
Now,
I've got here some raw data okay for sales on the left,
and we're actually gonna work on the column for the order amounts.
This is what we're aggregating as you've seen when I was selecting the different selections
year on my slicer.
Okay,
now,
to apply this technique or to ah,
to do what I've done here with the slicer I had to create a table,
a mini table here.
As you can see,
that has two columns,
the aggregation and a number column that just assigns a reference number.
Ah,
a counter or so Ah,
just a key to the aggregation type that you want to apply.
So average have given it number one maximum,
giving it number two minimum.
I've given him number three and total.
I've given a number four.
OK,
it's just a reference number,
okay?
And I have created another pivot table here at the bottom that is based on the table at the
top.
OK,
so I just ah created a pivot table that is based on the table at the top.
And by the way,
if you're ah having any questions regarding tables or if you're not familiar with tables
are drink a mint that you watch the lost two lessons here on the course.
Ah,
that explain tables.
They are extra lessons bullet bonus lessons that explain the tables eso the explaining cell
tables in detail.
Okay,
Now,
after I've created this pivot table here that is based on the table at the top,
I've removed the grand total row from that pivot table.
Okay,
so I've done that by go by selecting my pivot table,
going to the design time on the ribbon and then going to grand totals,
clicking on F on off for rows and columns.
Okay,
so I've removed the grand total row,
okay?
And I have created a shoes function here in cell G two.
Okay,
So this choose function is on its first argument the index number argument or the index
number input.
It's referencing cell K 13 here.
That's got,
um,
estimation off the number,
because,
ah,
the discuss the submission of the number,
or actually the number Because the number here has only,
um,
every record has only ah,
every number has only one record here on the table,
at the top,
on the mini table at the top.
So the summation is gonna be the same as the number itself.
So the first argument here is referencing this cell here containing ah,
the summation.
Okay,
are actually the reference number on the pivot table.
And then the choices that I've put are the average of the order amount.
This is the first choice on A Put it as the first choice because the average here is having
the number one A referent,
the reference number one here on this table at the top.
Okay,
And then I've got the maximum as having the being the second option.
Because it's got number two here,
and I've got minimum as having as being the third option,
because it's got number three and some as being the fourth option.
Because total is number four here for here on the table at the top.
OK,
and what happens is that when I choose the type of aggregation that I want to apply self a
choose average.
Okay,
this gets put here in the pivot table,
okay?
And I get here the reference number off the aggregation type that I want to apply on.
Then the choose function reads that reference number.
Okay,
So que 13 is going to be one,
and so the chills function is going to choose to apply.
The first option here on the first option is the average.
This is the aggregation type that's going to be applied.
Okay,
on if I choose maximum,
I will get number two here,
okay?
And the second aggregation type will be applied,
which is maximum.
Okay,
so got the maximum order amounts put put here and sell G two.
And this is gonna be the same story with minimum and with some.
Okay,
so basically,
the truce function will refer Ah,
to this or reference,
this cell here will get its choice Ah,
number or the reference number of his choice from this cell here from self k 13.
And then it will apply that aggregation function.
Ah,
Teoh.
And get that the result And actually the aggregation functions are being applied to the
column for the order amounts here on the table.
And this is a structured reference for the table.
And if you're having any problem or you don't understand what a structured references I'd
recommend you watch the lost two lessons.
Ah,
on the course which are bonus lessons about tables about excel tables,
you'll be able to understand what a structured references,
okay.
And I have no problem understanding that.
Okay?
So,
basically,
whenever you choose what you choose here on the slicer.
The aggregation gets applied here in cell G two,
and then we've got some sort of an interactive text here.
So actually,
I'm aggregating.
What's Unseld J 13 here.
Okay.
With the word order amount.
But put a space beside before it so that there would be a space between the aggregation
type and the word.
The two words order amount.
Okay,
this is just,
um,
the text labour leader economic texts label that I've created to just ah,
have something that that would change dynamically as I change my choice Year is a choose
something different on the slicer.
Okay,
so Ah,
this is how the technique works,
guys.
Um,
so someone would ask,
What if I don't choose here?
A Ah,
I make two choices on the slicer.
Actually,
Excel will just ah,
do the first choice.
Or actually,
you will got the result off the first choice because we're referring to the first cell on
the pivot table here.
The first row under the sum of number.
Um,
call him,
and then he just changed the ah,
the header of that column to make a reference number something.
Okay,
of course,
Normally you be hiding this,
um,
pivot table from the user so the user wouldn't see that you'd be putting It may be in
another sheet.
And you be hiding that many table as well.
Okay.
And,
uh,
that's it.
You could maybe,
um,
have like,
a cell here that would say,
um,
that would have a formula.
Okay,
that would count These cells here,
give you the count of these cells.
And remember,
guys that comes function,
it counts.
Only the cells having numbers.
Okay.
So,
um,
you could maybe put an EF four minute here if count of this is greater than one,
then,
um,
please choose one aggregation type.
Okay,
I'm gonna show you why I have done that.
Else,
give me a blank cell.
It's on.
I'm doing that so that if the user chooses to aggregation types,
you had got this cell here saying,
Please choose one aggregation type,
and you could maybe give this warning,
sell some conditional formatting,
so maybe you can go to conditional formatting highlights.
So rules and then text that contains,
please.
Shoes.
One aggregation type.
Okay.
Now,
so that if ah,
the user makes more than one choice,
this cell here would have a red color and some sort of a warning that says,
please choose one aggregation type,
and then the user would,
ah,
just choose one aggregation type on.
This warning would disappear.
Okay,
so you can do that.
Ah,
so that you'd give the user some sort of warning if they choose to arm or aggregation types
.
Zero shows in three works was three.
And it works with,
you know,
four aggregation types.
If you want to choose for it works with four aggregation types as well,
and it selected a same time.
Eso the user will get a warning.
You know,
when they select more than one aggregation type,
but it's just the select.
Just one.
Um,
the the warning disappears here.
Okay,
So I hope that was informative for you guys.
Thank you very much for watching this video and please follow me on to the next video.