Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss another a technique that involves putting our slices selection into
formula.
So as you can see,
I've got a slicer.
And as I'm changing my selection to date on the chart changes this chart actually gets its
data from this table here,
and this slicer is actually linked to this pivot table.
This pivot table is a very simple pivot table that has the model field put in the row
section here.
And this pivot table is based on the actual sales road eater and the actual sales raw data
is one of two row data sets that we've got would get the actual sales and the forecast
sales.
So this stable axity just references the model name from our slicer selection.
So we've got a summits formula that calculates the sales,
the actual and the forecast from the respective data sets based on our slices selection and
that particular month also,
we have actually put this value here in cell p five,
which is our slicer selection.
We've made it a name drain so created a very simple name,
drains a scold slices election.
We've just made it equal to that cell just to be able to refer to that cell as slicer
selection.
It's not necessary,
but it just makes things easier.
As you can see here,
this is a chart title text.
This cell here contains the chart title text,
and this cell has a formula that tests if the cell under our slicer selection cell is empty
or not.
So if is blank,
so test if.
Is this blank or not?
Because if it is not blank than we've selected multiple models,
so he's sincere.
If I select multiple models,
it's not gonna be blank.
So two or more is gonna make cell P six not blank.
And this is something that we don't want to do because we don't want the user to select
multiple models because then the summers formulas were not work properly because they can
only reference one model.
So this is why,
in case the user selects multiple models,
he will get a warning messages.
This please choose one model on Lee.
So this is actually a test that we do in order to make sure that the user selects one model
on Lee and this title boxier just references this cell so as to make the title dynamic.
And basically the title says the slice of selection actual versus focus sales.
So that particular model that we selected actual versus forecast sales.
So that's it.
This is a very simple technique to involve your slicer selection into a formula.
So thank you very much,
guys,
for watching this video and I'll see on the next one.