Hello welcome to the course on testing and optimization.
I'm super excited that you decided to join in this course.
You will learn a lot and you will have heaps of fun along the way.
And this story is designed to give you a quick overview of the structure of the course.
You can navigate it better.
All right so let's jump straight into it.
So here at the top we've got the promotional video that's the one you saw when you were enrolling in
the course.
And then right away we've got the introduction section which is the section we're in right now so here
we've got the overview tutorial which is this one we've got the disclaimer so very important to check
out the disclaimer so you understand what this course does show you and what it DOESN'T SHOW YOU SO
DIFFERENT check out the disclaimer How To Get In fact don't proceed with the Congress unless you agree
to the disclaimer.
Next how to get the most out of the scores.
A quick to tutorial on how to get the most value or discourse and choosing a broker so saw just threw
in a quick tutorial to text Tauriel on how to select your for expert.
Basically what who my preferred mortgage broker is because I'm sure you're curious about that.
The next section is Section 2.
Theorie So here we've got a couple of tutorials so this is some theory that we have to go through in
order to prepare ourselves for the rest of the course so we're on the same page.
So here we talk about first of all I'll show you how installment a traitor for then we've got how to
navigate the strategy should test so we took a back test forward test optimization so all of those things
are theoretical side of everything.
And then we got a quiz so make sure to do the quizzes in this course.
They are very useful.
They will help you assess your knowledge and also some of the questions are just trick questions so
they'll definitely help you or they will allow you to have a lot of fun along the way.
Those quizzes are quite interesting sometimes.
All right.
Preparation So this section is after we know the theory.
Now we have to get everything set up.
So here you've got the simple system training system so I actually share with you here you can download
a share if you are a robot that I develop but bear in mind this robot is specifically developed for
training purposes.
In my 4 x courses so do not use this training robot on a real live account.
This is only for you to practice the concepts that we talking about in this course.
So make sure to keep that in mind.
And I will mention that once again once when we get to the simple system and you will also see that
on the disclaimer on the page we can download.
So you get the simple system trading system here.
Then I go through some additional modifications that I've made since very early to launch the Course
students have.
You know we're always interested to see how to work for trailing stop loss or you know what five digits
is four digits.
So we've made some modifications there.
So we've got a couple of trolls and.
Then I show you how to download and important daughter and him editor for that we're going to the quiz
.
And then finally we get to the fun stuff.
So Section 4 is where we start our optimization a demo and real testing so here we'll show you how to
run back testing and optimization so we'll be using a simple system as an example of a robot that we
will be optimizing.
But basically all these concepts and this is the whole point of the course so that you learn these concepts
and then you're able to apply them in a similar fashion to any other expert Yser out there that you
are evaluating.
So we talk about backtesting authorization precise optimization forward.
So we're actually doing the practical side of things we're running all these optimizations and tests
.
Then I show you how to enable automated trading.
And then we do live demo.
So the live demo tests are going to run for four weeks.
I'll be checking every single week to show you how the results are going.
And you're welcome to also run your own live demo tests on your demo account and there at the end we
will evaluate which expert advisers have succeeded through the demo tests which have not.
Then I will move onto the real test so this is the part where we kind of split because I will be running
real tests on my account.
I will show you how I will be running a small real test on real accounts but with small funds so because
these are tests after all at this stage you will be able to just observe how I'm doing real tests and
learn how to what the differences are between demo tests and real test so basically I'll be using my
live real account as a guinea pig to show you how a real tests can compare to demo tests and then we'll
wrap up the tests and then we're going to the quiz.
And finally at the end of the Course I've thrown in some additional bonus lectures on optimization tips
and tricks so these are some tips and tricks and hacks that I use to make my optimizations more efficient
and more effective.
And here you will learn quite a lot of them so we'll talk about the recovery factor export results into
Excel.
The genetic algorithms there.
We've also got a very interesting tutorial.
So one I added recently is called that could quadruple genetic algorithm walk through and it's got a
live example there so make sure to check that one out.
He's got a very detailed and intuitive in my view a very intuitive explanation of the genetic algorithm
.
There was talk about rerolling optimization.
So another quiz here.
And finally the course conclusion where we will sum up everything that we learned and I'll wish you
well on your way.
So as you can see it's a quite a large course a lots of lectures a lot of fun in these lectures as well
.
A lot of practical applications and I can't wait to see on the first tutorial.
Let's dive straight into it.
And until then happy trading