Hello this is Kirill from forexboat dot com.
And welcome back to the course on testing and optimization and meditated for in this section of the
course we will talk more about optimization and you will learn things like setting limitations two dimensional
surface analysis exploring optimization results into Excel and further analysis there.
The genetic algorithm and a few more very interesting and insightful topics.
However before we proceed I'd like to ask a favor.
Now I know I've already mentioned this previously in the course and if you have already left review
then thank you very much.
But if you haven't left review yet then and you do like what you've seen so far in the course I would
like to ask you to maybe leave me some feedback.
And even if you just clicked the number of stars you feel that the course deserves.
That would be very helpful.
It would not only help me out but it will also assist other students who haven't yet signed up for a
course in deciding for themselves whether this course is worth their time.
So I would really appreciate if you could leave a review.
And once again thank you for those of you who have already done that.
And now let's go back to today's topic.
So today we'll be talking about the mutations.
I've got the strategy tester when window open in front of me and I've already chosen simple system version
5.0.
Set the currency pair the period and the model as we remember we're going to be using open prices model
and know what we're going to do.
We're going to go into expert properties and to make it a bit more interesting.
We will choose for expert properties we will choose one of the sets that we know perform quite well
in our demo test.
As you remember that it was the fourth set.
The one that was at the bottom or bottom right corner.
So let's go ahead and find that set.
I save it in this folder here and out of the four sets this one set number four where our was eight
.
So we get to select that and it automatically populates the values of the set here.
And so we'll just go ahead and run there just to see that the result is what we were looking for.
As you can see that's the set over here.
So and this is still on the same period where we ran out back test plus forward test.
So those four months between May and September going back to the graph.
So that's that's our share.
Now what we want to do is go to exper properties and we want to optimize who we want to run like an
optimization and maybe we'll see if we want it we can improve the said.
But much more for the sake of just practice.
We want to run an optimization so we'll uncheck that start all we really know that we're happy with
this hour we know that out of the ones that we've chosen.
This was perhaps the best hour that it's worth starting your trays that many people limit will also
take that for now and a filter and a period will SANTICH that will be just optimizing and take profit
and the stop loss and we will also leave the optimization parameters here so we'll start with 10 value
of 10 will move step of 10 and will stop at 100.
That's not particularly important right now so just click OK just to say that it will go back into expert
properties and how to find the limitations we need to go into the optimization tab.
So these limitations will allow you to kind of restrict the optimization results to certain criteria
such undescended better I'll just go ahead and run the observation of any limitations at this stage
.
So just going to click optimization here and run it as it gets it as a 100 results which is fair because
we had 10 steps that take profit intends to have full stop loss.
They're all ordered by profit right now.
So we can order them by pass if we like and here it will go from just make is bigger here we'll go from
1 to 100 and is basically just gone through all different combinations.
And here you see other parameters so you see the drawdown percentage drawdown expected payoff, profit
factor total trades and profit and so on.
So drawdown is a good example because you can set limitations on that.
And let's just talk about that for a second.
So what you can do in limitations is you can and this is something that we touched on during our test
of our simple system in the previous section.
You can limit the results that you see here and excludes results of say a certain drawback say you don't
like this drawdown of 12 percent.
You say that is about your level of tolerance and you don't want to include such results in your analysis
or just basically wasting your time and taking up space.
So you can set through limitations you can set this optimization process to exclude results.
We have a drawdown of over 12 percent.
So for example you wouldn't see these results from nineteen point eighty five you still see these ones
of 11 or seven or 10 percent but you wouldn't see anything above 12.
So how would we go and do that just to.
So we have an illustration of how limitations work.
So I'm going into X reappropriate I'm going into optimization and then I'm looking at maximal drawdown
.
Well first you thing you have to do is you have to take this box next you have to say changes value
And here it's very tricky so if I just click over here somewhere else then the value returns to its
previous whatever the number was in there.
So you have to set your value and click enter and that's something a lot of traders often forget.
If you don't click entery just click OK then the value won't be set and just make sure that the box
checked.
So once that's done that means that any result of maximal drawdown above troops that will be excluded
.
So let's click OK and let's run optimization now.
As you can see all 100 have been run.
If we go into optimization you will notice that there is much less results.
It's only got 31 results here.
And as you can see for all of them the drawdown is below 12 percent.
So it has literally excluded any results above so you can even see them here.
And if you take any one of them and said as input parameters you will see that the drawdown here never
goes above 12 percent of the deposit that it was at that at the start.
Well on the drawdown started.
So that's how you basically use limitation.
So now let's go into a bit more detail which limitations are available.
The motivations that you can select from are the minimum balance so you can say set the minimum balance
to 9000 For example if your starting balance is 10000.
Then you can to 9000 and you'll know that BAC tests that you're presented with Will Never.
It has never been below that value profit maximums the maximum number amount of profit reached.
And you might want to use that one in special cases when you're just checking some money management
technique that you're trying out a minimal margin level.
Find me a point of concern for some people maximal drawdown consecutive loss in value how much you can
expect or you're prepared to lose in one in a series of Lost trades.
So these one leads to a quite useful consecutive loss trades if you don't want to see your expert advisor
level losing more than 10 times in a row or say two times in a row you can specify that here consecutive
win trades if you don't want to see expert why is a winning more than 30 times in.
Maybe because that's too suspicious too or you have other reasons to set that limitation mind you want
to do that.
But I find the most powerful one out of them is the maximal drawdown and I do use that quite often.
It helps me significantly reduce the amount of time I spend on analyzing my optimization results.
All right so I think that's enough for today.
Have a play around with that and see how you go.
Also let me know if you have any questions using the comments section.
And next time we'll be talking about two dimensional surface analysis and I look forward to seeing you
on that tutorial.
Until then Happy training