Hello there's a kernel from forexboat dot com.
And welcome back to the course on testing and optimization in megatrend for it has been one week since
we launched our real test of simple system version 5.0.
And let's check into see how it's going.
So first of all as Bring on the calendar and here you'll see that there's a 20 it's off September 2014
.
We launched the real test on Monday the 22nd Tembo of 2014.
So the real test has been running for one full working week.
Now going back let's look at the results.
If I'd like to ask you to add the comments call them over here.
And so in order to do that I'll just take it out.
All you have to do is right click anywhere in the account history tab and choose comments and you'll
see that simple system version 5.0 is quite smart.
It actually puts in a common saying which of the simple system expert advisors set this order so you
have multiple them running like I do on this terminal you'll be able to understand which one belongs
to which order.
So that's that's quite handy.
However in our case we will be also using the size of the lot to differentiate between them and I'll
just show you how to do that in a minute.
So so far you can see that after the first week our balance initial balance of 500 has gone up very
likely only up to 500 point fifty.
So you can't even consider that as an increase.
What we're more interested though is in the individual trades to understand what was happening.
So as you can see here you've got we've got quite a few take profits quite a few stop losses and there
are quite a few trades here and that's because we had three versions of expert advisors running with
three different sets as you can recall what how we could analyze is we could look through these.
And right away could look at the stop loss we can see that it's 0.02 to zero point zero to lots so the
hour was 10 hours 10 and the last one.
Our sense of the stop losses were incurred by the same set.
And that's the set that has our turn here but it had our 9 back in the demo.
So that's that said over there on the top our right there we were running the one that is currently
quite unstable.
So instead of analyzing these trades one by one what I like doing is I just like storing the
historical trades by size and that is a very handy thing you can do especially if you've allocated different
lots to the different versions of your expert adviser or the different expert advisors are testing.
And that quickly allows you to differentiate between them.
So right away I can see here that the first trades are here.
The point one belong to the simple system where our was five.
So in the one test that's the one we're always for and that's the one on the left or bottom left that's
the one that was really good in the demo test and it has been so far.
But as you recall we put it we gave it a lot because we weren't sure that the demo test results would
be the same as the real test results.
And then the point to laut is the one that's quite unstable and a demo test and we didn't know that
at the time of launching them a real test so we thought that maybe we'll get Point to Point Zero two
a lot because it's got some potential.
And Point 3 of a lot is a there or three of a lot.
Is the test that said that had no lost trades on the demo test.
And as you can see here is got one last trade but which wasn't a stop loss which was a time out.
So let's analyze them separately.
So this first on over here as you can see the results are quite good too if we take these top trades
there's a loss but then it's covered by the profits so in total this try this said was profitable on
the real test.
The next set are here it was unprofitable so only one good trade and three bad ones.
And that doesn't balance out.
So so far this hasn't been doing well.
And finally the point 0 3 of a lot has been very good.
So for this time down trade and that's that's a good example of a discrepancy so we can see this trade
here it created a loss on that count but there wasn't one in the demo test and the that DeMatteis all
of them are profitable.
So that some that's once again a good example of how a demo test can be different to a real test even
when you run them in parallel at the same time.
So first thing that comes into mind is that you'd want to take this set off your test and like exclude
this set from the further test and your real account because it's doing so badly.
But I just wanted to use this tutorial as an example of one how you handle these kind of psychological
dilemmas because in reality what we're testing here is we're not trying to get all of them together
to work really well and create a profit on our account.
What we are doing is we're using this account of 500 dollars to run a real test of each one of these
expert advisors and we want to analyze them separately.
So instead of trying to get a community of good outcome what we want to do right now is we want to give
them some time and see how they'll go individually.
So maybe at the end of next week when we've got all of we've got like five more days of are dotted and
analyzed We'll look at this expert advice and will say oh OK so in two weeks this guy that's where this
set this training with 0.02 lots where our stand has overall had a very bad run.
So then we'll say OK no we won't put him on our actual real account where we don't test things or we
actually try.
And so we'll analyze them separately anyway.
And you have to kind of withstand the urge to make alterations to a test because once you've launched
them you should give them some time to have enough momentum build up enough momentum so that you can
actually analyze the results were from quite quite a good level of certainty.
And another thing that might come into mind is to change a lot say this one's done really well let's
put up its Laud's this one is doing better than we thought.
Let's put up its lots and let's put down the LOTS of this one we can do that but I won't in this case
because it's very convenient to sort by last like this and analyze them.
And if we changed a lot then they'll be jumbled around and it will be hard to find them.
And what we will have to do is then will have to copy all of this history ex-porn and check sell and
then use this comment section to sort our trades and find the right ones.
So we'll just stick to the easier option we'll keep the lots different and that's primarily why we've
said what's different so that we can now we can sort them and find the right traits for our analysis
and we'll just keep the lots the same for one more week and see how it goes at the end of next week
and then analyze the results then.
So that's how our real test is going so far.
I hope you're finding it really interesting because personally I'm very excited about all of this and
it's been a great demo Plus real test combination.
Let's wait and see what happens next week and I look forward to seeing the next tutorial.
Until then have training