Hello this is Kirill from forexboat dot com.
And welcome back to the course on testing and optimization in Medicare for now that we have made a trader
for successfully installed and we have a demo account up and running today we can focus on the strategy
tester window and the navigation controls that operated.
So here in front of you you can see the trailer for platform and at the bottom here we have the Terminal
window.
And this is what your platform will look like if you've opened it for the first time.
And you can see your demo account name and number over here on the left.
If we click around in the terminal tab in the terminal tabs you will notice that there isn't a tab for
the strategy tester and that is because the strategy Tester has its own separate window which we can
open by pressing this button over here which is called the strategy tester.
So just go ahead and do that.
As you can see a new window has popped up at the bottom here which is called the tester window.
Now we want to close the terminal window because we don't have any active trades that we need to monitor
and we don't really need the terminal window at this stage.
We can do that either by clicking the terminal button over here or alternatively we can just click the
button or we're here on the top left.
So it will go ahead and do that.
And now the first thing that it will do we'll just pull this navigate a bar tab to the right so that
we can see a bit more of these two windows.
Now at the bottom we have the tester window and I already have a expert advisor and symbol selected
.
Yours are probably blank at this stage but we'll fix that shortly.
So there are quite a few controls here and let's go through them one by one to understand what they
do.
The first control allows you to select an expert advisor and basically that means you have to specify
which forex robot you want to test.
And as you can see these expert advisors here present the same ones which you can see in your expert
advisers folder in the Navigator.
And basically that means that you can select any one of the expert advisers that's installed in your
platform currently.
And at this stage it's just the two prepackaged expert advisors that come with marriage for.
So we'll go ahead and select the moving average and go we'll move on to the next control the next control
is the symbol here.
You can choose from a variety of different financial instruments on which you would like to test your
expert buys.
And these are the same financial instruments as you have here in the market.
Watch next is the period and the periods in the right here are currently selected the hourly period
is selected.
You can select any other period on which you want to test your most expert advisor.
And the reason for this control is because med trader 4 has historically been developed in a very specific
way and there are ways that if you launch an expert advisor on on a chart you're not only launching
it on that financial instrument but you're also launching it on that specific timeframe of the chart
.
So let's let's look an example if I open a Eurodollar here and I choose for hourly chart then launching
an expert advisor on the hourly chart will be different.
We're launching an expert advise on the four hours each hour and that is applicable to all expert advisors
except for the cases when they're specifically coded in a way that disregards the period on which they're
launched which is quite rare usually.
Expert advisors use the bars of the period they're launched on or the chart that launched on them for
the period has a significant influence that feature of traitor for is different for example to the Duke
is called PJ for its platform where if you want an expert advisor or for X robot you launch it on a
financial instrument and then within the expert adviser itself the code has to decide which periods
it will work with in military or for it's not like that imagery for the period which are launching the
expert advisor on has significant influence on the outcomes and performance of the 4 x robot.
So that's why you should always remember to choose the correct period for your expert adviser.
Now let's move on to the next control which is the model.
We'll talk about these three different types of models separately in another tutorial in the scores
.
But for now it's sufficient for us to understand that open prices is the least precise model for testing
but it is the fastest one for testing control points is the average and every tick is the most precise
model.
But it takes the longest to run tests on the small.
Next we're going to move on to the date controls.
So here you can specify a date where within which you want to test the expert advice.
So for example if you want to test it from the start of this year then you just put in first of January
and then you can add up to today or you can test it up to us.
Any other date in the past visual mode will specify whether you want to see how the test is progressing
on the chart over here or if you just want to get the results if you take this you'll just get the result
for the test before it actually seen when the trades were open.
So obviously we'll find the visual motets Foster with visual Moji you get to see when the trades are
occurring.
Skip to allows you to skip to a certain date during a visual mode test so if you set the date like say
a second of June and you start from the start of the year you can watch it at the start of the year
and then click skip to and skip to a certain date.
Next the spread parameter here is quite new.
I think it was introduced in one of the recent builds and if you're using me as a traitor for above
build 600 then you definitely should have it.
And this allows you to specify which spread you want to test your expert advice.
It's a very convenient function as you can see here the spade right now is to Pip's I might want to
test my expert was with five pips in there you can choose and you can also enter any other value you
want in here you don't have to select one of the dropdown.
The optimization button will talk about that later.
But basically it allows you to optimize your expert was also there's a few controls in the right here
modify expert Darell going to kill for to change the code for the expert visor open chart.
I never use that bottom myself but basically I guess it just opens the chart symbol properties.
Also we'll talk about that separately and expert property bring expert properties brings up the parameters
of the expert advisors.
So we'll talk about this more in the coming to Tyrol's.
I look forward to seeing you there if you're watching and you do subscribe to the channel to be notified
when I post next.
Bridget Tauriel and until then Happy training