What I'm going to do is basically deploy our TodoMVC
application to a production environment,
and there's going to be some kind of bumps along the way
because I'm going to actually manually configure a few things
after the application has been deployed.
But if you have an AWS account already,
you can feel free to follow along because these will be the same
steps that you'll need to reproduce after as we're trying to get
the application deployed yourself.
So, does everybody here --- does everybody have the,
excuse me, an Amazon account, like at least an Amazon developer account?
So we did go as far to sign up there.
So that next thing that you'll want to do,
and I'll drop this in the chat,
is the Elastic Beanstalk Command Line Interface is
something that you'll need to install.
It's a Python utility; it can be installed on any platform.
I'm looking at the docs right now, but let me drop it in the chat.
(Working) And if you have Homebrew, it's actually fairly easy to get installed.
There's actually a brew package that will do it right up for you.
If you also have Python installed, you can install it with pip as well.
So, let me go ahead and drop that in.
So if you want to go through the process of starting to get that installed,
I will sort of slowly go into the Amazon console and give you a
little chance to get that installed as we go.
Because the first stop is going to be --- like once
you sign in to your Amazon account, which I am right now,
you'll probably see a dashboard that looks something like this.
I'll deploy to a region that I haven't deployed to yet maybe,
or I guess could go US East.
Doesn't really matter.
Alright, so I'm going to be creating resources within the US East region,
but first I need to start by creating an API user for myself.
So from the dashboard, I'm going to go down to Identity & Access Management,
and these users are actually shared across your account,
so it doesn't matter which region your in for this particular one.
So, the first thing that you're going to want to do is go down here to Users,
and Create a New User, and you can give them a username of some kind.
So like I'll go through and actually create one,
although I actually have done this numerous times,
so I already had one created.
So once you create a user,
you'll have the opportunity here in the browser to
see their security credentials,
which is going to be their secret key and like a user ID.
So you're going to want download those credentials and keep those in a
safe location because it's not possible to retrieve them.
If you lose them,
you're going to have to regenerate credentials for
the user for security reasons.
So once you create a user, download your credentials.
Store those in a safe location.
It looks like Bohdan is saying that he always gets scared in the AWS console,
and that is wise, as well you should.
It's kind of a scary place.
But hopefully we'll leave today with it being a little bit less scary.
So once we have that user created,
we're going to want to add that user to a group.
And this is different from the security groups that
we'll be talking about later,
but it's essentially a user group which gives them certain
permissions within the AWS infrastructure.
So in may case, I only have group defined,
which is Admins,
which kind of gives GodMode access to a user for all
of the resources in my AWS account.
As practical matter,
most organizations you'll work in that use Amazon will have
security groups with much more granular restrictions,
but if we look at that briefly just to give you an idea of what it is,
let's see, so we can see the users that are in a group,
and its permissions.
And Amazon has essentially like a language,
a DSL for determining like what resources a given
group or a given user has access to, and the administrator access policy,
it's JSON based obviously,
and for the administrators basically says that you can allow like
all kinds of actions on every kind of resource.
So it's the most permissive one,
but you can make these very tightly scoped to specific products,
to specific instances of services as granular as you feel
like you need those services to be.
So, once you have created, excuse me, a user,
added them to a group which has sufficient permission to --- yes,
question?
Some people are asking you like how you're going through this.
Do you just want them to watch for now and then they're
going to go through it themselves?
Some people are behind, but … Yeah,
I mean I think that if you want to follow along,
that is totally fine.
The first page of the documentation that I put in the chat
will also take you through the same process.
So, if you want to --- for me personally,
I like to see it and then do it,
but if you --- I would recommend that you probably watch at
this time and then try to recreate it.
Because if we all try to do it together,
like it's not going to --- like I don't think it'll work.
So we'll go through the process, I'll show you the steps,
and then I'll help each of you get through it with the rest
of the time we have here this afternoon.
Alright, so we create a user, we download our credentials,
we add that user to a group or give that user permissions to access the resources that it's going to need.