What we're going to finish up with is a topic which
is near and dear to my heart,
which might be kind of strange considering I'm a developer by trade,
but understanding what's going on in your application from a user's
perspective is something I try to get better at every day and make part of
my decision-making process as much as I possibly can.
And the primary tool that we use to do that is Google Analytics.
There are actually some other paid tools that you can use that are very cool.
My new favorite toy is Heap analytics where you can retroactively create
behavior statistics by essentially creating CSS selectors for elements on
your page and attaching events to those.
And you don't need to instrument those events ahead of time,
you can actually retroactively pull those events out.
So there's that.
There's Optimizely, which is useful for AB testing.
But the core of it all is definitely the data that
we get out of Google Analytics.
So what we'll do in this section is we'll learn a little bit about what
kind of intelligence we can glean from Google Analytics,
I'll hop into the UI and point out a couple of the key
features that you might want to check out in your quest
to find data about your users,
and then we'll also take our last code break of the day to
actually implement universal analytics on our TodoMVC
application using a handy node module.
So, why do you care about analytics in the first place?
Mostly because you don't know everything.
You have a strong hypothesis about what a user might need,
about places they might go on your site,
but all it is without data is your opinion.
So,
using Google Analytics as a part of your decision-making
process as a developer for what you spend your time on ends
up being a useful skill to acquire.
Once you realize that you want to be working as smartly as you can
and not just shipping code with your head down,
Google Analytics can help you make the best decisions possible
for what you're going to be focusing on.
And when you look at some of the data coming from your application,
you'll be able to serve your users better.
You'll understand what they find useful,
what they're searching for,
and you can help them find it a little bit more easily.
So are parts of Google Analytics free or is it all free or is it
a --- You can sign up for Google Analytics.
Yeah, it's free so you can integrate it on your site.
There is a premium offering for Google Analytics, but it is --- what is it like?
Like, it's in the six figures annually.
I forget what the actual price tag is, but it is quite expensive.
And you can get closer to real-time data and some more granular information.
But the core of the offering is definitely free.
Now, who in here is in Google Analytics regularly?
So we've got James, we got Mark, a couple folks looking around.
That's okay.
As developers, it's not something that we necessarily do every day, but it can make all of us better at our jobs if we're developing for the web.