Now we're ready to start adding in the Socket.
IO pieces.
So, on the server, we're going to create the Socket.
IO object that's going to allow us to manage incoming WebSocket connections.
So, we're going to create this IO object by requiring Socket.
IO.
And then to that, we're going to pass in the HTTP server that we just created,
and that's going to allow Socket.
IO to serve up the client-side JavaScript that we'll be using here
in a second in addition to a few other bits.
And, next, with that IO object,
we're going to be listening for a connection event.
So, whenever a new WebSocket connects,
this function is going to be called with that socket.
So, for now I'll just console.
log socket connected.
And,
we'll start doing some more interesting stuff with that socket here in a minute.
So that is the server-side component.
Now on the client-side because --- one of the things Socket.
IO provides us is like a dynamic script tag.
So this route that I'm about to type in the source here is
actually going to be generated by Socket.
IO because this isn't a route that we created.
So it's just going to be socket.
io/socket.
io.
js.
So that's going to load up a Socket.
IO JavaScript object for us to start working with on the client-side.
And then in my script tag here,
this is where we'll write all the logic for our chat application,
I'm just going to create a new instance of Socket.
IO here on the client as well.
We'll just call that socket,
and then we'll use the window-scoped IO object to initialize it,
which is what we get when we include that script tag.
So I'll save that up.
And I'll kill my server.
And I'll actually run the script with nodemon so we
don't have to restart it every time.
And if we refresh the page, go back out here,
we should have our message that the socket was connected.
So now we have a connection between the client and the server.
And now we can start doing some interesting stuff with it.
So, the first bit that I think we'll do, we'll start off on the client-side.
We can use the client-side socket connection to emit
events that will be received on the server.
So I'm going to say socket.
emit message.
And in addition to Socket.
IO, maybe I'll just, for good measure,
grab a version of jQuery to help me grab some stuff out of the DOM.
So for that message,
I'm going to actually grab the current value of the form field.
So,
I'm going to emit the message and then the second --- so the
message is kind of the event that other sockets can listen for
and the server can listen for,
and the second argument is essentially the data value
that you want to send along with it.
So, for the input of the chat object,
I'm just going to grab the current value of that.
And that's going to be enough logic to emit the current value of that.
We also want to wrap that in an event handler,
so we have that send button, so on click.
That's when we want to grab the current value of that.
And we'll emit that value back to the server.
And then we'll also reset the value of like our local chat box back to null.
So, that'll be kind of the send part of the equation here.
Then back on the server to actually listen for that incoming event,
we're going to listen for an event on that socket object that
we get when somebody connects to the server.
So, when that socket receives a message event,
we are going to execute this logic on the server.
And for now,
we'll just acknowledge that we got it by writing that out to the console.
And again, if everything went according to plan,
we'll send some messages, and hopefully out here --- oh,
no!
Missing handler.
Console is not a function.
Oops, oh yeah, console.
log.
That would be a more effective thing to try.
So we'll send that.
And then here we go,
we have some messages being emitted in real-time from the client to the server.
Now we've implemented one half of this,
but what we haven't done is send this out to any other connected client.
So,
what we can do when we want to send a message to every other socket
that's currently connected is use the IO object,
this guy that we created here,
and use a method called emit to fire off a message on that
object that will be received by every client.
So, it's very similar, actually,
to what we did on the client-side emitting that event.
So we're going to emit a message event,
and then we'll just relay that message that we just got.
Alright, so, now after we emit that to every connected socket,
up here on the client, we're going to have another event handler here,
so on that message event.
This is going to be fired every time a message event is emitted from the server.
And what we want to do is on that unordered list that we had,
just append a list item to it.
So for that, what do we call that?
Messages.
We'll actually start by creating a li, oops,
li =, create a li item,
and we'll set the text of that to be the message
that we got back from the server.
And then, we'll append that list item to the messages.
So now what should be happening is we'll emit a message from the client,
it will be received on the server,
and then the server will emit that message back to every other connected client.
So, let's reload and see if that is indeed what we experience.
So it looks like we have a very crappy real-time chat
application running in the browser.
And now,
one other tool that is a constant companion for me and for many other
developers that work with webhooks or have to expose their local development
machines to the internet is a little tool called ngrok.
And ngrok basically allows my laptop to get a
publically addressable URL on the internet.
So, this will allow all of your to test my application along with me.
So this tool I'll call ngrok http, and we'll want to expose port 3000.
And then I'll reserve the subdomain of frontendmasters.
So now, if you go to frontendmasters.
ngrok.
io, we should see that interface that we just saw.
And I'll start sending some messages.
And hopefully,
some of you out there will start sending some messages back to us as well.
Try to keep it PG-13, this is a family show.
Alright, so we got some folks coming in here.
So, there we have, again, the magic of Socket.
IO for all to see.
Certainly something that I'm sure folks have seen before,
but in just a tiny amount of code, a few lines in the client,
a few lines on the server, we were able to create this real-time interface for our application.