So the first thing that I want to do before we get started
is to ensure everybody is at a good place with their local
development environments.
So that GitHub repository that I sent out before contains what
should be at this point a fully functional Node.
js web application that you can run locally.
So, if you head out, if you haven't gone there already,
it's actually up on my GitHub repository,
guthub.
com/kwhinnery/todomvc-plusplus,
and thanks to some great QA from here in the room earlier I believe
that README should take you all the way through actually getting
this thing set up locally on your laptop,
and I think that is the first step that we need to accomplish
before we get on to some of the other things.
So we'll take as much time as we need, hopefully not to much time,
just to make sure that we get everybody with a functioning local
development environment so they can start playing along at home.
So, let's go ahead and do that.
And I'll be coming around to help folks as they might need help.
The one potential tripping point for a local development environment may
or may not be getting like Postgres up and running.
Postgres can be kind of a bear to configure for local development,
so if you want to take sort of a shortcut,
there is a service out there you can sign up for called ElephantSQL,
and you can actually provision a shared Postgres database for free,
and we can drop that database configuration directly into your application.
So, I would invite you to go through the README,
start taking those steps if you haven't already,
and while you're doing that,
I'll very briefly kind of go through the structure of the
application project as it exists today so you have a sense
of where to look for what.
So, I'll browse it out here on GitHub,
and the bits that I'll draw your attention to right away are this bit,
the Gruntfile, which we'll dive into a little bit later,
and that's sort of the nexus for most of the administrative
commands that we'll run for this application.
Grunt is a general purpose task runner, again,
that we'll dive into in more depth later.
We have a package.
json, which contains all of our project's dependencies that you'll be installing,
and then we have a bin directory,
which contains the JavaScript file which actually launches the HTTP server,
which powers our application.
And then we also have --- right now we just have one custom
Grunt task located in this directory as well,
but anything having to do with any custom code we're going to
write for the command line lives in there.
The config directory, this is how we use it.
It's kind of --- it's sort of loosely based on Django configuration,
but we have a this index.
js, which has soft of the global defaults for the application's configuration,
and then we have a configuration files with overrides for the
development production and test environments.
So you can dig through that if you like.
But we also have this file, user.
save.
js, which doesn't have anything in it right now, but if you create a user.
js for local development,
you can override any of the configuration settings there,
such as a custom database URL perhaps,
if you go the route of spinning up an ElphantSQL
database rather than having a local one.
So, configuration lives there.
We have this db directory,
and the primary bit that you'll be interested in is this
is where we've configured our ORM to place the migration
files for this application.
We are using a relational database for this application,
so as we modify the database,
we'll have to create migrations to move the database from one state to another.
If you've used frameworks like Rails or maybe Hibernate before,
you're kind of familiar with this concept.
The src directory is where most of the fun stuff lives.
The browser directory has all of the front-end JavaScript code and SCSS files.
The static directory contains things that will be copied over
verbatim into the web route of your application.
The server directory contains our Express web app,
our Mocha tests for our back-end code.
It also contains the model directory,
which configures our database connection and defines the
model objects for our application.
We have controllers, which have the routes for our application,
and this todos controller,
which contains --- which actually powers all of the routes in the application.
If you don't know what these things are, don't worry.
We'll kind of dive into more of them as we go.
And then we also have the views directory,
which actually has the HTML which will server the
front end for this application.
And there is a tiny bit of shared code.
In my experience,
the opportunity for code reuse on client and server is
not maybe as great as you would hope.
The bigger win is the ability to write the same kind of
code on both client and the server,
but there is a tiny bit of affordance for shared code across platforms.
And if you have any questions about other stuff as we go along,
I'd be happy to go specifically into any decisions or the other bits there,
but many of them we'll go over as we go through the course.
So, at this point,
what I would like to do is ensure that everybody gets the
application going locally to the point where they can run Grunt
in the top-level application directory,
which will fire up a couple of neat tools,
which will monitor your application project for changes and then execute
compilation steps or relaunching the application based on changes.
So what you should be able to do with a running Postgres database and a
valid database connection is have a persistent set of todos that will stick
with you across page refreshes because in this instance they're actually
being stored in a Postgres database.
So this is the step that I would like to get everybody to,
so we'll spend a little bit of time doing that before we dive into
some of the code that drives the web server.
Alright,
so I re-mic'd myself because I was talking about the option of using
ElphantSQL rather than a local Postgres database.
It looks like my configuration might not be totally sound as yet because I
haven't run the migrations because I changed my database URL,
but I didn't run the migrations.
So, I'm going run sequalize db:migrate,
and that should go across the network and update my ElephantSQL database.
Show us where you changed the config to.
And again, where I changed that config was I created a file called user.
js in the config directory, and I didn't override for this databaseUrl property.
And you can actually copy the configuration,
like say from the test environment and just bring that over,
and then you can paste in that Postgres URL you get from ElephantSQL.
And now when I refresh, I get an empty list of todos, which is okay.
And if I go back to the UI,
I should start being able to pop in some todo list items.
So the steps there would be to update the
configuration to your ElephantSQL databaseUrl,
to go out to the terminal and execute sequalize db:migrate,
and then you can rerun your development server with Grunt,
and you should be off to the races from there.
What is the get path to ElephantSQL?
It is --- if you go to elephantsql.
com, you can sign up for an account, and then you can create your own.
What are the limitations on ElephantSQL as far use?
The free database is only 20MB, so that would be the big one right there,
but you can create multiple free databases if you would like.
Sharding across frees.
(Laughing) Yes, maybe it has some other fun features as well,
but use this a couple times in workshops just for something quick and dirty.
Alright,
so we have a couple folks online reporting an issue that was
--- if you loaded up the README earlier,
we actually discovered some bugs in it, I apologize,
here in the room earlier this morning.
If you're loading up the page and you don't see --- and
the style sheets aren't being loaded, run grunt collect_static,
and collect_static has and underscore between the collect and static.
The README on GitHub has been updated to reflect this,
but that'll copy over the static CSS files that you
need to be in that public directory.
So, the README has been updated to reflect that.
What I'll show one more time is the fastest path to success with Postgres,
which I think is where most people are tripping up.
If you're on the repo and following the README,
we'll start kind of right from the beginning.
You're still going to want to do this.
After you download the code, if you haven't already,
you'll want to do npm install in the directory in which you downloaded the code.
You'll want to do npm install -g grunt-cli sequelize-cli,
and that'll put two new commands on your system path.
One is called Grunt, and that's the task runner that we're going to be using,
and another is called Sequelize,
and that will control the database migrations and the
other stuff that you'll need to do later.
And then for setting up the database,
if you don't want to go the route or were not successful going the route of
getting a local Postgres database going with these instructions,
simply forego these instructions and create a database using ElephantSQL,
which you can sign up for a free account at elephantsql.
com.
Then, once you have signed up for one,
the first thing you're going to see is a URL for your database info,
and you can use this connection string in lieu of a local Postgres database.
So to connect to this database rather than one that's running locally,
inside your application folder here,
and this is the code that you downloaded from GitHub or
you cloned when you got the repository, you'll create a file called user.
js, and you can initialize the contents of that file with what's in the test.
js file or similar,
and then you will copy in your ElephantSQL database string into this file,
and then the application will connect to that ElephantSQL
database rather than one that's running locally.
After you do that,
then you can continue along with rest of the instructions in the README.
So you will then do sequelize db:migrate,
and then you will do grunt collect_static,
and then at that point you should be able to run the application
locally just by running the grunt command.
So, we'll make sure that we get everybody to that step,
but again,
I think the fastest path to success is signing up for --- if
you're struggling with Postgres locally,
sign up for an account here on ElephantSQL and just go ahead and use that.
It'll be totally fine for our local development purposes.
Alright, so we will come around, make sure if anybody still needs help after,
and when we get into the next exercise,
we'll make sure everybody starts by getting the local development environment ready to go.