The exercise that we were just working on was to integrate Rollbar
into our error handling process for our application.
Now, I did sort of a quick and dirty solution so I can show you what happens.
But, Rollbar does provide a Node.
js module that you can include in your application so you npm install rollbar.
And, if you're doing an application based on Express,
they have a connect middleware that you can plug in after the
rest of your routes have been defined and it will pass off all
the data that it can glean from the request off to Rollbar
whenever an exception is thrown.
So, I have my errorHandler here and my disposable account ID,
which I'll terminate shortly.
But I also have introduced a route in the application
which I intend to throw an exception.
So, when I open up my browser and hit error,
in development,
Express will actually show me the stack trace here in the browser.
In production mode it won't do that.
But I've generated an error, I got a stack trace,
and I need to know what's going on.
So, I'm going to head over to Rollbar and look in my Dashboard.
And I've just signed up for this account so I have a lot of todo items.
I can invite more people to my team, set up deploy tracking,
which is actually super useful.
When you do a deploy,
you can possibly correlate errors to a particular deployment.
There's lots of different stuff you can do.
But on the Dashboard,
I can see what errors have occurred from my application over the last 24 hours.
So I can see I sent like the Hello World message
during the onboarding experience, and now I'm starting to get an actual error.
So if I click on that, I can see the status of that issue.
It's actually possible to have your team resolve issues through Rollbar.
We don't actually use Rollbar for that.
We use PagerDuty to actually track down who is
responsible for closing out an issue,
but there are some workflow possibilities there.
And if we scroll down,
we get the entire trace back from our application showing us
the error happened on line 37 of webapp.
js.
So it helps us to understand where the error occurred.
It'll tell us when all the occurrences have been so we get a timestamp,
the browser that generated it, the operating system if available,
the route, which of our servers it came from,
so if we're running the application on multiple servers,
we can help track down the precise box that it came from,
and we can glean a couple other bits from this.
If we had a logged in user,
we could configure our Rollbar integration to actually send
the account information or some kind of account identifier
for our user to Rollbar as well.
So we could say,
account 1234 just experienced this error in the production environment,
like maybe we need to follow up.
We can see some graphs about like the browser and OS.
If you have deployments configured, you can see those deployments.
You can see what the potentially suspicious deployment
would be and other similar errors.
Now, when one of these things happens,
where the value of this comes in is the notification scheme
because if an error happens and nobody is listening,
then it doesn't really matter how effectively you log it.
So, on a personal and on a project level,
you can configure different notification channels.
The only one that's active by default is email,
but you can notify yourself of errors in many,
many different ways as you can see.
Again, the one we like to use is PagerDuty because PagerDuty has,
itself, some very robust notification capabilities,
and it can alert an entire chain of command essentially and escalate at
each level if one person doesn't answer the page.
So we usually have Rollbar pass through to PagerDuty when necessary.
Any questions on Rollbar?
A very simple integration.
There's more data that you can send to help diagnose your errors,
but very easy to get set up.
Definitely recommend it if you're looking for a service like this one.
It lets you know when bad stuff is happening.
It's just one part of a notification scheme.
The other things that you'll want to look at configuring are maybe a
Pingdom configuration that'll check your servers from the outside
world to ensure that they remain accessible.
You can check the HTML that's coming back to ensure it's doing what you expect.
And then with Elastic Beanstalk if you're running Beanstalk,
there are some configurations around notifications as well.
You can set up such that when certain events happen on your instances,
you can see that happen.
As you can see, since the load has died down,
the other two instances that got spun up have been terminated,
so I'm back down to my single instance.
But here in Monitoring, you can dig into the data coming out of your instances,
and then with the alarms, you can see any alarm configuration you have.
So for like CPU utilization, let's see, if I click on this little alarm,
we can send out a notification for if the CPU goes over a certain level,
and we can specify an email address that gets that.
There are also other services Amazon provides that are more robust,
like CloudWatch,
that can do more notifications about happenings going on inside your AWS account.