When we sent you off on this Vue.
js journey,
we had you try to change the application to take advantage of the
API that we just put in place last time around to actually save the
completed status of the todo list items.
And so we actually do have, looking through,
we have one pull request,
which is great and definitely implements this in a way
very similar to what I would recommend.
So let's actually take a look and blow that up.
So, what we have here in this pull request are a couple of changes.
For the first is to our existing store utility class,
or utility object, I guess.
So,
we had some logic before that would actually save every todo in the list if
it was flagged with a Boolean property called modified.
And this was just kind of a byproduct of the way TodoMVC was
originally implemented where like the only way todo items were
saved were as an entire list all at once.
So, that's still the way that it works.
So what we've done here is updated those Ajax requests to in
addition to sending the title to the server,
also sending the completed status of a todo item to the server as well.
We also have that down here in the updates.
So, both in the create and the update steps,
we've just also started tracking the completion status of the todo.
So that was step one that we had to do.
Next,
we had to modify the user interface to actually like save that property as a
part of the interface when something was actually completed.
So, what we did here, this is the actual Vue component,
we added another instance function here.
Actually, I might just open this file up so we can see what we did.
So,
there is a section of functions within a Vue component called methods which are
callable as a part of event handling and other scenarios.
So we had before an addTodo, a removeTodo, edit, doneEdit.
And what we added here was a new method called complete
which takes a todo that was completed.
And the actual property completed of the todo is already being updated
because it was bound to a property of the checkbox object.
And maybe it would be easier to look at that here in the source for index.
ejs.
So, here is the for loop in which we're rendering all the individual list items.
And inside each list item there is a div that
contained the contents of the button,
but also this checkbox toggle which was bound to the
completed property of the todo model.
So anytime that checkbox is updated,
it's actually going to be updating the Boolean property
completed on the underlying todo list item.
So that property is already being updated.
So what we did in this change set here is we take the completed todo,
we flag it has having been modified,
which is necessary to actually persist the save to the server,
and then we called that same storage method that we had before,
passing in the current list of todos.
And because this todo was marked as modified,
we're going to persist that change to the server.
So that was the only thing we needed to change on
the actual Vue instance itself.
And then the third change in the pull request was also necessary.
So we updated our service, which hits the back-end.
We updated our controller, or our component logic,
and we also updated our HTML here for the actual Vue.
And it was reformatted a little bit, which is also good,
get it closer to under 80 columns, which I appreciate.
The primary change here was adding a new event listener on this object.
So whenever the change event happens on this checkbox,
we're going to call this complete function on the component,
passing in the current todo that was updated.
And there are a few ways you could have gone about this.
Listening for the change event is great and probably maybe the cleanest.
Another way would have been to attach a click handler to this input as well.
So, here's our input checkbox.
Listening for the change event and calling our function is a great solution.
Another thing that you might have done is add a click handler function here,
and then you could have called that complete function,
passing in the current todo for this item.
So, that would've been a response to the actual click,
but listening for the change of the property is
probably the best way to approach that.
So, excellent work on that piece.
That is precisely what I would've done in this situation so good work.
And you did it much better than I would have done had
I live coded it in front of you.
So, I'm going to go ahead and apply a plus one to that.
And since it's a bigger change,
I'll pull it down locally and make sure that it's
working properly before I merge it in, but it looks absolutely perfect at this point.