So that was the fix that we had submitted for completing that particular issue.
And that was awesome.
It looks like we might have some other ones here.
So we have a slightly different one here.
It looks like this was maybe not the theme piece,
so we can actually do that together right now since I don't think we have
a pull request for the theme challenge specifically.
So,
the other issue that we had open was the ability to change the
current CSS class of the component --- let's see here,
based on like some kind of selector, or radio button,
or something that would indicate that we want to change
like the current theme of the object.
So, let's go ahead and implement that here together.
So, at the end of the day what we want to do --- here is the todoapp section,
which is the container for the entire interface.
And if we look at our todo controller here,
the element that we are binding to is this todoapp,
which I'm sure many of you already figured out.
Here, let me back out the changes here because I haven't done that.
So,
what we want to do is conditionally add a class to this section that kind of
contains all of our component based on the property of a Vue model that will
update through some kind of user interface component.
So the way that Vue provides to do this is a couple of things.
One thing you could do is you could have a mustache template here,
which will put the value of a Vue model property directly
into the class list of the element here.
So I could have a themeClass like Vue model property and I
could drop it directly in the class list there.
The other thing I can do is I can use a bind directive,
which is a little bit more flexible if you have to do complex things with the
classes that you're adding based on the state of the model.
So one of the ways that we have to do that is with this v-bind directive.
We can bind the class of that object to be the result of an array of
properties or of an object with properties that we can toggle true or false
indicating whether or not that class should be selected.
So in this case, I'll just pass in an array of potential model properties.
In this case, I'll just call it dark because by default,
we'll assume that the light theme is essentially the default and
just add some additional styles for the dark theme.
So, what we're going to --- excuse me, we'll just call that theme.
So, we'll be setting that property based on the Vue model.
So now I think that's pretty much all we're going to
have to do here in the markup.
If we go into the actual Vue, we're going to add another property called theme,
and this is actually where we'll set the default.
So, the CSS theme for light will be the value by default,
or we could actually not have a light theme class
at all and just leave it empty.
But we'll have a light theme class just in case we decide we
want to add some properties for that later.
So, now we need to do --- actually, I lied.
We do need to go back to the markup a little bit.
So, down at the bottom here at the section that has the filters,
we'll do something just quick and dirty.
There are a few ways you could do this.
You could do like an input radio button,
which maybe I will do right,
input radio with a name of theme and a value of say light.
And, we'll default that to checked.
And, in addition,
we're going to bind that to that theme property that we just created.
So that's going to be like our radio option for the light theme.
And then we're going to do something similar for the dark theme,
although this time it's not going to be checked and
the value is going to be dark.
So, we've updated our Vue model to track this new property called theme.
We have a little bit of user interface here to allow people to select
a radio button based on their current preference.
It's going to start updating the model,
which should start toggling this class up here at the top.
So, let's fire that up, make sure that that worked.
And again, because I was spamming my database,
we're going to have a long way to scroll down to the bottom,
but there is our light theme and our dark theme,
which doesn't seem to be updating the way I'd thought.
Let's see here, name, theme, value, dark.
Actually, you know what?
This is going to change that to be a Boolean rather than a string.
So that's not exactly what I want in this instance.
Alright.
What did I goof up there?
Let's see.
Yeah, I'm not sure.
That kind of matches my note over there so I'm going to have to dig into that.
Does it need to be checkbox instead of radio?
No,
I think the radio is what I want because I only want like one
of these to be selected at any given time.
What is weirding me out a little bit is the fact that I can't update it.
It could be some like z-indexing stuff.
I'll just, as a Hail Mary,
try this and then I will leave you alone to debug this.
I do want to show you how this works though so I'll do this over the break.
Alright.
So there I think it might have been like a z-indexing issue in
the CSS because I am able to click it now.
So, now if everything worked according to plan,
like if I inspect this component, open up the body,
there is the current class and --- that's not exactly
doing what I thought it would do.
Let's see, value dark.
Alright.
So that binding isn't working exactly the way I wanted here.
I thought that --- I'm going to have to figure out why that is.
Man!
That is a bummer.
But the idea is we are going to be toggling this property,
it's going to be updating the class on that DOM element,
and then we can add CSS styles to make that work.
So, during the next break I'll debug that.
I'll check my gist that I had set up for that and
figure out why that's not working, and we'll cover that when we come back.
But the next piece that we are going to tackle was starting to dig into Socket.
IO a little bit.
Yes, question.
A quick question about --- this was a little bit a while ago,
but what about the allDone input?
They're just asking what about the allDone input.
Yeah, so --- I can ask them to clarify if --- Yeah, what is the allDone?
What do we mean by the allDone input?
I'll ask them.
Okay.
The main section right above the todos header is bound to an allDone v-model.
Line 25, I think.
I think maybe like is that the completed stuff?
V-model allDone.
Oh, toggle-all.
I think it's if you want to mark all of them isn't it?
Yeah,
so that is essentially --- I think that's going to be like a Boolean toggle.
Let's take a look at that.
And he's just saying it's not saving it to the database.
The allDone is not saving to the database.
That's a good question.
I'm not sure off the DOM what that's supposed to do because the allDone ---
this is code that I took from the TodoMVC implementation,
is not actually a model object.
Oh, you know what it is?
I think it's probably a computed property.
So, allDone is this computed property here, which has a getter and a setter.
So it can be treated as if it is a property of the Vue
model associated with the component.
And then when it's called in the Vue like it is over here,
the get function is called.
So this checkbox is toggled based on whether or not all of
the current todo items have been completed.
So that's where that's coming from.
It's one of these computed properties.
So if you did want to save all of them after doing that
you would just update this forEach callback to mark that
it's modified and all saved?
Yes, yes, that's what we would do.
So you would, in addition to completed for each of them,
you would also mark them as modified and it would all go to the
server based on the current implementation.
So the setter is what happens on change.
So like if I were to click this checkbox, then that's when the setter logic gets executed.