Now we should be able to start using the model with this new property.
So the first thing I might try is to run my tests,
npm test, and it does actually successfully create a TODO item,
but I might sort of modify that to also add in a completed flag.
So, in addition to creating a todo with the title Text,
I think I actually want completed there,
right?
Right!
I'm going to create a todo with both the title and the completed,
and I'll add another assertion there that says todo.
completed should equal false.
And there's a bunch of ways to do that assertion, but that one works okay.
But this is one way for me to just quick verify that the table has been sort
of updated and the model is kind of doing what I expect.
These are fairly shallow tests again, but it's the first step.
Now what I need to do is update my REST API endpoints to actually
update these properties on the models as well.
So for that I'm going to open up my Todo routes,
and for both the update and the create operation I'm going to have to
accept another parameter for the completed flag essentially.
So for an update, we'll do this first.
I'm going to look for a request body.
Or excuse me, I'm actually going to do that after my 404 check.
So,
I'm going to set the completed property of my model to be
equal to the result of a Boolean check.
So if request.
body.
completed equals the string true,
that's going to set completed to be true for all other values of that component
that is going to be --- that's going to evaluate to false.
There's other ways to do this.
This is a fairly quick and dirty implementation,
but it's one way to make that piece happen.
And then in my create I'm going to do something similar.
So, in this case, oops,
I'm going to set that completed property again based on
the result of that Boolean comparison, whether or not it's true,
and then it should be updated in my database accordingly.
So those are the two like REST API endpoints I need to update.
Now I'm going to run my application and make sure that my
REST API is doing what I feel it should do.
So I'll start up the dev server,
and now you can verify this using cURL or whatever HTTP client you want.
Like I said, I'm kind of a fan of Postman, so I'm going to do it that way.
So if I start off by sending a GET to my input,
I can see that I have all of my todos in the database,
but for most of them the completed attribute is set to null.
So let's create a new one with that attribute in place.
So, in addition to the body, the title, excuse me,
I'm going to pass in a completed string,
and I'll initially set it to false.
And I created that value in the database, so completed is set to false.
I could create another one set to true, send that in,
and then, again, if it's anything but the string true,
it's going to default to false.
So now if I list those items in the database,
the most recently created ones are there with their proper values.
And I can test the update by changing the --- by using the PUT.
PUT is the operation that I'm using to update the models.
And in this case, the title is going to be whatever I want that to be,
and completed is going to be true.
I can send that, and once again I can see like id 11 has been updated,
but that had one already, so let's do like maybe id #2.
(Working) And hit Send, and then that's been updated as well.
Alright, so I've --- once again, the steps were creating a migration,
handling, adding,
and removing the column whether or not we're migrating the database up or down.
After we did that,
we updated our actual Todo model to have the
property that we added to the database.
We updated our test,
and then we updated our Express controller logic to take advantage
of that new property which wasn't there before.
Cool!
Any questions on any of that code?
It is --- there were a number of steps there that you had to discover,
so not surprised that a good chunk of people --- yeah,
there was definitely a lot to grok there if you haven't done it before.
Anybody in the chat?
Maybe we'll give them a chance to --- Okay,
if you have any other questions on the Sequelize side of things,
I'd be happy to answer them.
Sequelize is a fairly full featured ORM.
It can do complex relationships and can use database-specific
features like JSON fields and Postgres.
So if you're interested in digging deeper,
it's definitely going to be your best bet for an ORM if you're not going to go with the driver, a driver directly.