Now, we get to what I hope will be the fun part,
one of the fun parts of the day, one of many,
hopefully, where we spend a lot of time actually hacking on this application.
Now,
unfortunately you guys have already found a few bugs that I
did not intend to put in the application,
specifically around the README and the setup experience.
However,
there are actually a lot of things in this application
that leaves something to be desired.
In fact, you could say that I have issues,
in fact, many of them, seven at the moment that I could use your help on.
So what I would like to do over the next,
we'll see how long it takes, it may be 20 minutes to a half hour,
maybe more, we can kind of play it by ear,
I have three GitHub issues here labeled exercise1,
and those are GitHub --- those issues are around features or problems with the
application that I would like for us to collectively add.
So,
what I would like for you to do is to pick one of these issues or
get through all of them if you're feeling particularly industrious
and try to add the feature or correct the problem that is described
in one of these GitHub issues.
So, for example, issue #7 is for a feature addition.
So at Twilio,
all of our HTTP APIs will return a header called X-Shenanigans-None because
one of our core values as a company is no shenanigans,
so we return this header with every response from the API.
But sadly, this API for todos does not return the X-Shenanigans header.
So we should look at expanding the implementation we have with Express to add
that header to every request that serves our todos API.
So we could send it back with every request,
but I've scoped it here to say like only do this for the todos route,
see if we can for those API requests return back this X-Shenanigans header.
So that's one of the things you can tackle.
Another thing you might want to tackle is this piece,
which is not sending a Powered By Express header with every response.
So, if you were to look here at this application,
which is already running in the Network tab in Web Inspector,
where is this going to be?
Where's my?
There we go.
I just have to click on the resource there.
So if you look at the headers that are sent back with the response,
there's a X-Powered-By: Express header that gets returned
by default in an Express application.
And it's innocuous enough,
but when you're taking an Express application to production,
usually you don't want to include that extra information because
it's possible that an evildoer could launch a targeted attack on
your application with the knowledge of what web framework you're
using on the back end.
So, it's not the hugest deal in the world,
but if --- it's a good thing not to do in a production Node application.
So removing or disabling that header is a good thing to do.
The other piece that you might take a look at is the
logging middleware for Express.
So right now we don't use very much middleware in the application,
and one of the things that would be nice to do would be to actually to log
the HTTP traffic that's coming into the application.
So there's lots of modules out there that do this.
I've linked to one called morgan,
which is very popular to use with Express applications.
So adding some HTTP request logging middleware would be
a nice feature to take on as well.
So, if you would like to take one of these on,
you can just hack on it locally,
and if you are comfortable with the Git workflow,
you can actually send a pull request to this repository with the
implementation of the feature that you implemented.
And if we have in 20 to 30 minutes time a few pull
requests that show how to do this, I'll go head and merge them in; otherwise,
I will cheat, and I will show you how it is to implement,
like we actually implement each of these bits.
But I would vastly prefer to merge a pull request from one of you,
so if you would like to take on one of three of these
issues in the next 20 to 30 minutes,
we'll say 30 minutes because there are still a few folks
that are getting their environments set up,
but we'll play it by ear.
No sooner than 30 minutes will we reconvene and talk about some of the solutions.