Any questions on Google Analytics before we wrap it up?
There was somebody who was asking if you've used
load balancing for the Postgres?
Yeah, so there isn't a load balancer in front of Postgres.
If you use RDS,
thy do have a master slave setup and there's a fair degree of
resilience that's just built into that as a service.
But there isn't a load balancer on top of Postgres mostly because like
it's not exactly the same as like an HTTP request.
We actually have a number of open TCP connections between our
EC2 instances and our Postgres instance.
It can handle quite a few concurrent open connections,
but it doesn't sort of handle traffic in that same way.
So there isn't like a load balancer in front of Postgres per se.
Cool!
So, that's kind of all we're going to cover.
Obviously,
we haven't covered the entire universe of what's going to be
necessary to get your application into production,
but the hope is that the application that we've presented and worked on
together over the last couple of days gives you the starting point for
getting your application out the door.
We've integrated in this application a lot of tools and
technologies that you will bring to bear if you're going to
actually operate this application in production,
the build tooling, the technology stack,
the monitoring,
the ability to understand the performance implications of
your application after it's been deployed,
and infrastructure that with some tuning can be made to handle a whole
bunch of load for a reasonably sized web application.
So,
what I hope you'll walk away from is a starting point
to start building your own stack.
But if you start from this one and just build on top of it,
I think you'll ultimately be pretty happy.
And if you have any questions as you go, my email address is kw@twilio.
com.
I'd be happy to answer any questions that you might
have to the very best of my ability.
I'm on the Twitters @kevinwhinnery,
so you can follow me there as well where I mostly talk about nerd stuff.
And I'm really grateful for having had the chance to spend this
time with you over the last couple of days.
And I'll hang out today.
I know a couple of you are still trying to get stuff running,
so I'm happy to stay here until everybody is up and running
with as much of the stack as they would like.
So, thank you very much. I appreciate it.