You all have risen to the challenge very effectively here.
Good job team.
I knew you could do it.
I had nothing but the utmost confidence.
I perused the pull request that came in for these specific issues,
and we have great solutions for all three issues.
So we have two that are clearly winners,
like they're what I was looking for,
and then we have one that is correct and one that is more correct,
so we'll look at both the correct one and the more correct one.
So #1 we got from juan267 who I imagine is hanging out on the live stream.
So what's up buddy?
Good job.
This is the most minimal edition of the morgan logger that we could've added.
So what he did was he npm installed that module
using probably the --save command, or he might've added manually.
That also is a possibility.
But when you know that you want to add another module
to your project's dependencies, you can execute this command,
npm install, and then --save will actually write the dependency to your package.
json so that the next time another developer npm installs your
project they will get that dependency as well.
So,
it's always a best practice when you add a dependency to add it to the package.
json as well,
and npm install --save is usually the best way to do that and
lock in the current version of the module.
So probably what we had here was an npm install --save morgan,
which would add that dependency to our package.
json as we have here.
And then we require the morgan module,
and by the default behavior of morgan is to log HTTP requests to standard out,
and he's mounted that middleware there in front of
just about everything else here.
So, we will get that HTTP logging output on every request to the server.
So, I'm going to go ahead and +1 that, so +1 for me,
and I'm going to merge that down, so good work.
And we'll pull that down here in just a little bit.
Alright,
so the other one we did was to take a look at
removing that X-Powered-By --- actually,
we'll do that last because that has the two answers.
The other one was adding and X-Shenanigans-None header to the response.
So we have a couple of submissions there,
so we'll go to this one from James that fixes #7,
and this is probably the lightest weight way of doing it.
In the webapp.
js he added a new middleware, just declared it in line, which is probably fine.
You could've created another file, probably would've been overkill here.
He sets the X-Shenanigans header on the response using response.
set, which is a method available on an Express decorated HTTP response object,
and then he calls next to move onto the next piece of middleware.
And that's all we need to do to add that header to the todos routes.
So I'm going to +1 that, great work, and I'm going to merge it down.
Awesome!
So now for the removing the Powered-By Express issue,
we had a couple approaches, both of which are --- both of which work,
one of which is slightly more correct, so let's see if I can find the one.
Okay.
So this is the version which is correct but not as correct as it could be.
So here we've defined a global middleware,
which is going to be executed on every request that will remove that
header X-Powered-By from every response that we send back.
And that will have the desired effect,
but it will also execute on every single request.
So, it's a little bit insufficient.
We don't necessarily need to take that header off on
every single request to the server.
So probably what we want to do is actually disable that option in Express.
So I think we have a pull request here which does just that,
so within the configuration options for Express.
So Express has this app.
--- on an Express app has a set and a get function,
and those will set configuration properties and
also get configuration properties.
In this case, he is setting a configuration property,
this x-powered-by header to false so Express will never send it at all.
Yes, question.
Is there any meaningful difference between doing this method of.
set for the header to false and doing.
disable of the entire header?
App.
disable x-powered-by specifically.
This one's not a header.
It's a config value.
Okay.
So this one's on app whereas the other one was on response.
Right, but you can also do, at least according to the Interwebs, you can do app.
disable x-powered-by in the same area in webapp.
js in the rest of the middleware.
Yeah,
I believe there's also a signature there for disable for Boolean properties.
So like this is expressly just setting a property to false.
Disable, I believe, toggles a Boolean property like x-powered-by to false,
so they're equivalent in this case.
So the correctest might've been app.
disable x-powered-by,
and it would've saved us a couple characters there if we wanted to go that way.
So, go back out here.
I've got some +1s.
James added some docs.
Look at you.
Good work.
I'm going to add my own +1, and we're going to merge it down.
Super job!
So now, if we go back out here, we've got some add logging middleware.
I thought we would've closed this out, and so.
I think we just didn't mention it in the commit message, which is fine.
I'm going to go ahead and close this out.
So,
30 minutes later we just knocked out two or three GitHub issues on our project,
so great work.
We're going to do that again a couple more times here today,
and then I've got a fresh batch that I'm going to load in there
tomorrow for you guys to go crazy on as well.
So, knocked this first one out of the park. Very nicely done.