Hello everyone and welcome to the section on installing spark and Python on an AWOS E.S. to.
So this lecture and the following lectures in this section will walk you through how to set up Python
spark in a Jupiter notebook system on an Amazon Web Services easy to instance.
However before we begin I want to discuss a few things to keep in mind.
This is by far the most tedious setup option out of the four.
It's the one of the most steps and you have to make sure you get everything right.
Also while everything we show is within the free one year tier for Amazon Web Services you still need
a credit card to set up an account and follow through with everything we show.
So if you create an easy to instance using different parameters than what is shown here you may also
be liable for charges.
So keep that in mind.
Everything we show in this video lecture series is going to fall under the free tier if you're signing
up for Amazon be less to give you a one year free tier of services for these little micro instances
if you choose more powerful parameters more memory more storage etc. then you may be liable for charges.
So keep that in mind.
Also you're going to have to make sure to follow the direction shown in this video exactly.
Otherwise you'll probably have to repeat the process all over again.
So leave yourself plenty of time to go through this process.
If you ever feel uncomfortable with any of this you can just go straight to the virtual box installation
lectures.
There's a whole section on that.
Those are local they're simpler and they're for sure 100 percent free OK.
Over on that trying to dissuade you.
I just want you to know the CC to process isn't too bad.
But again keep in mind if you get an error during this process it's because you made a mistake somewhere
not following along with the video lectures and it's going to be hard for me to help you out in the
Q&amp;A forums debugging because really there's only a few commands that you have to follow along.
So you'll probably have to just go back and start over.
All right let's get started walking through the process of setting all of this up.
So the very first thing you have to do is set up an Amazon Web Services account.
So go to HTP s AWOS the Amazon Dot com slash free or you can just go to amazon.com or just google search
AWOS then what you're going to do is click on Create a free account.
You'll sign up with an email address and then fill out the profile information.
Basically just follow along with the prompts.
Once you've done that the profile information will require your contact information billing information
ID verification and then you're going to choose the free support plan in the next lecture.
We're going to do explore it ws and create an easy to instance.
So right now your assignment.
Just create that AWOS profile and choose all the free settings.
I'll see you in the next lecture where we actually begin to walk through using AWOS and Creedon that
easy to instance.