Hello everyone and welcome to the Amazon Web Services elastic map reduce set up lecture if you ever
want to quickly set up a cluster of a notebook interface Amazon Web Services elastic map reader service
is actually a really good choice.
But please know where we're going to be showing in this lecture does not fall under the free trial of
a.
You will be charged and depending on what kind of instance you do how large a cluster is the price varies
so definitely check out Amazon's own official documentation for pricing to get the latest pricing and
how much this would actually cost you.
And this particular lecture we're going to walk through is setting up the zipline notebook on AWOS EMR
and we're also going to discuss some security options and I highly recommend you watch to E.S. to instance
lecture's first before watching this particular lecture to learn more about S-sh in case of something
you see yourself doing in the future.
Now the zipline notebook is a fairly new environment that mimics a lot of the cheaper Jupiter notebooks
capabilities but it was created specifically of big data in mind things like Sparc and Hadoop where
we were going to do as quickly explore with zipline up looks like on their official documentation page
and then go through the process of setting up our own on AWOS EMR and creating a cluster and AWOS earmark
can take a while to initialize.
So while initializing the master node in the slave nodes we're going to show you how to set up the security.
So take some time with this.
The actual cluster creation process is really fast but AWOS on there and setting up servers Sometimes
it takes a little while and there we're also going to talk about security settings as we set up the
zipline notebook running on EMR.
I really want to stress here that make sure to read through the resource documentation to choose the
best security settings for you or your organization.
The way we're doing it here may not be secure enough for your needs OK.
Let's get started and jump into the documentation.
I'm going to go up on that Apache the org.
And afterwards we're going to log into our AWOS consul AWOS to Amazon.com and show you how you can go
to the EMR OK.
Here I am at Zeppelin that Apache or.
This is the official documentation page and this is basically almost like a Jupiter notebook except
like I said it's really designed to support a lot of different big data Bacchantes things like sequel
Scalia's spark Hadoop those kind of things hive etc. and the current version is 0.7 at this point in
time and they've added a couple new things things like multi-user support.
A lot of improvements in Python which is good for us.
And then they integrate them at Port lib into some of that Python stuff.
Plus they now support SPARC 2.1 which at this point in filming is the latest version of SPARC Now if
you just want a general idea of what is Apache's upline is a multipurpose notebook for data discovery
data analytics and also has some visualization capabilities built into it.
And more importantly it supports lots of language Balcones so you can see here it supports things that
Cassandra are hive.
Flink a classic search Python HFS etc..
So lots and lots of stuff that Zeppelin can support a lot more than just the Jupiter note book itself
and really what's its main key point is that especially Apache's Zeppelin provides built in SPARC integration
so it's really designed with SPARC in mind and everything else is kind of built on top of that plus
has data visualizations and dynamic forms and really strong support for Sparc sequel.
So you can always just check out the documentation here by clicking on this.
And then if you go to 0.7 point one he'll talk a lot more about some of the QuickStart capabilities
so configuring it tutorials dynamic forums etc. and I encourage you to explore as documentation if you
think zipline up is something you're going to be using in the future.
But what I'm going to do now is basically walk through the process of setting everything up.
So let's jump over to our AWOS console.
All right.
Once you log in to AWOS thought Amazon.com you should be able to search for AWOS services or you can
always just click here and look at the various services.
But what we're going to be using is EMR.
So if you either search for EMR or the classic map reduce it should be some manage the framework.
So click on that and then you have these options of creating clusters.
You can see here already had a cluster that's been terminated.
So click here and create cluster.
This is your first line you're probably the have one yet and then you'll be taken to this page and what
you want to do is give the cluster a name so we can say like you cluster or whatever you want you can
link it up to three folder if you want to do that.
And more importantly down here on the software configuration what we're going to be choosing is all
the way here at the bottom where it says Sparc and Zeppelin.
And that's what you want to make sure is included.
So maybe these applications will show in a different order for you but definitely make sure that it
shows spark and I can zoom in here to make it a little clearer and zipline up look.
That's what we need.
And then as far as hardware configuration This is where based off your needs if you want more power
or more storage or faster computing.
You can choose different types of instances and you basically choose one master and then however many
core nodes you want and you can set the instance type and the number of instances here.
I'm going to stick to the default so large.
But if you want to make it a little cheaper you can come over here and go to like medium of the previous
generation.
It's really up to you.
We can even just stick to medium.
Then finally you have the security and access options.
The most basic option is just to proceed to thought and easy to keep there.
That's kind of a lower security option that means if someone doesn't have that key pair they can still
access your instance as long as they know the actual address to locate it at.
If you're thinking of just going through this one time and you just kind of want to get the feel of
creating the cluster and you're immediately going to shut it down then go ahead and proceed to an easy
to key pair.
It's really easy you don't really need it.
But let me briefly explain in case you didn't watch the E.C two lectures how you can create an easy
to keep here all you have to do is click over here on learn how to create nice to keep there and you
just come over here follow these instructions to actually create an easy to keep there.
It's pretty straightforward.
Just come here to the Amazon easy to con..
Go to click key peers create a keep pair click create and save the resulting T.M. file in a safe location
and then you're going to need to modify your pen file.
If you are on a Windows or Mac so there's instructions here on how to do this on Windows.
And if you click here on this tab there's instructions on how to do it on a Mac.
Since you may or may not have done this before I'm going to briefly create a new key pair that you can
actually see how this works I'm willing to open my Amazon easy to con..
In a new window and click on key pairs in the navigation pane.
So I come here to my console and going to see key pairs here.
I've already created some but let's just make another one point click here on create key pair and typing
you create keep your name.
So for instance we'll call this my sparkie click on Create once you created that new key pair it should
automatically have downloaded that p e m file.
It's really important that you remember where this PTM file is.
You basically don't get another chance to download another one.
So make sure you know the location of this PTM file you just created and downloaded.
All right so once you have that file make sure you save it to a location that you remember going back
here to our set up keep there once you have that pgm or pen file in a safe location.
You're probably going to need to modify a file in order to S-sh or securely connect to your cluster.
Now modifying the pimp files a little different depending on whether you're on a Mac or Linux or Windows
computer.
Amazon Web Services actually has really nice instructions for either version.
But basically if you're on a Mac or Linux you're just going to open up your terminal and type this command
you're going to say S.H. maade space O.G. dash R W X.
And then Mikey Peridot PM or whatever you're called your key pair.
Now remember you have to be at the same directory directory location where you saved your dot file.
Now if you're on Windows it's going to be a little more involved.
You have to download Agent X to your computer.
There's a link right here to download it.
You're going to launch the puttee then click load.
Select the PM file you created earlier click open then click OK on the page and notice telling you your
key was successfully imported.
Enter a passphrase in the key passphrase field.
Click Save private key save it in a PPK format that's the format Windows needs for S-sh into a cluster
and then you're going to name your petty private key such as my key Peridot PPK click save and then
exit the PATTI-JANE application.
OK so go ahead and do that whether you're on a Windows or Mac.
Take care of this PTM file.
I'm going know Windows.
I'll be using this putty generate now.
Windows is a little more involved.
But again Amazon Web Services is really good documentation on this.
If you ever get stuck you can either just look at these steps.
Pretty straightforward or just google search AWOS S-sh easy to keep.
Or something similar.
And Amazon EMR has a whole management guide on how to do this step by step.
So I'm going to close this.
Again the instructions are always here for you.
Just how to create an easy to keep there.
I'm going to choose the one you see to keep.
I just made which was my Sparke key and then I'm going to come down here and click on Create cluster
and that's going to be creating your cluster right now.
Now it usually takes a couple of minutes to actually fully create the cluster.
So you may need to just wait a little while it's going to say starting for a little bit but it's actually
creating a cluster right now and it has the Miss spark key for security and access.
OK what you're waiting for your cluster to actually initialize what you want to do is make sure that
you're going to be able to s s h into your Zeppelin notebook.
And for that you may need to change the security settings so what are you going to do.
Under security and access.
Come here and click on security groups for Master now I'll take you to this link on security groups.
All right.
Once you're on this security group page where you're going to do is select the map reduce M..
Click here and you should see the security groups.
And if you click on inbound tab where you want to do is click here on it.
And we're going to open up some ports here.
So click on it.
And then click here where it says add rule and you'll get a new little rule pop up.
And we want to select S-sh and then make sure that the port is 22 and over here on Kustom we can either
select any where or my IP.
Now if you select my IP that means you can only connect to this cluster from your actual IP address
location.
That's probably the most secure way of going about this.
If you want to click anywhere.
That means anyone will be able to connect to this cluster which could be dangerous or for the most secure
thing just click on my IP and then we want to do is open up one more rule so say our rule and then have
this be a custom TCAP rule and then what I want to do is open up the poor 8 8 9 0 and I going I'm just
going to say my IP.
So if those two things selected click save.
All right so now that we have our security groups for it to go where we needed to just wait for the
actual cluster to start.
So come back here to the AWOS cluster in probably still waiting right now may take a couple of minutes.
But basically we have everything set up.
OK.
Coming back to the Amazon AWOS counsel for your cluster What do you see the masters running in the core
is running.
You should see something like waiting here and that means your customers waiting for you to actually
do something with it which is good to know what we can do here is you have basically two options depending
on how strict you want your security settings to be.
You could S-sh and that has to do all the stuff I was talking about earlier using that dot PM your key
or yours.
PPK if you're on Windows and setting up the actual S-sh connection but if you did the security settings
that I showed you here you can actually access your zipline notebook directly through this public link.
Now keep in mind this is a pretty open way of accessing a cluster.
So this may not be the right setting for you or your organization the pending on how important security
is for you.
But I can just copy and paste this public DNS into my browser and then write Colan 8 8 9 0.
Remember that was the port we left open for Zetlin enter and you should see something that looks like
this these aplan notebook page.
And you can import notebooks or create new notebooks and if you click here on this zipline tutorial
file or folder you'll see it has an example notebook but this is essentially just that big data version
of the Joop or notebook.
So let's create a new note and then we'll give it a you note names we like my first notebook and there's
different default interpreters you can use like spark M.D angular SH Python.
If we want to use Python with Sparke what has worked best for me in the past is choosing Sparc and then
saying you want to use the Paice park interpreter in the notebook.
So select Sparke create note and here let me zoom in so you can see this.
You can end up typing Python of Sparke code.
But the first thing you do in the cell is how a percent sign and say Paice park and then everything
else in the cell can then be Python code.
If you don't do that expects Skala because SPARC has written in Scala so it's sort of a really simple
example say something like for x in the list.
One two three colon if I enter and you see that default indentation that means it's working which is
good.
And then we're going to say print's X do shift enter to run this.
And we see one two three it's looking good.
And you can notice that it continues on with the Paice bark in the next cell kind of expect you to continue
with Paice park and luckily the zipline notebook actually creates a sequel context ready for you.
So if you just type SE and do shift enter that is the spark context object and that's what you can use
to call different things off of it.
Now usually throughout the course we're going to be using Spark's sessions not spark contacts because
spark session is what the newer Sparke data Freyne that 2.0 version runs off.
And instead of typing as c the default for that isn't going to be just Sparke.
So SPARC is already defined as an object of the current SPARC session when we run things locally or
maybe even on an easy to instance that you've seen in the past.
Or maybe you can check out those other lectures.
You'll definitely be seeing me define Sparke all the time.
But here in the Zeppelin notebooks and that knows that you're going to be working with SPARC.
It's already set up that variable.
So don't ever overwrite spark that special variables already set up as a spark session and then off
of this you can do things like read that cxxviii and then usually if you're dealing with the zipline
notebook you're in a situation where you're dealing with data that's hosted on S-3 of Amazon.
So in order to grab that data you would have to do something like this.
I'm sure you you would pass in a string you would say something like as 3 then call and forward slash
forward slash and then you have to pass in your keys that like to connect to your as three buckets and
that would look something like you know whatever your access key is then colon and then your secret
key and then after that you can specify what Buckett you're looking for.
So usually a bucket's in those S3 storage instances and that would be indicated with an at symbol.
And then you would say whatever the name of your bucket is.
And after that you can then start looking for the actual file so essentially here you can just look
through directories or you know if it's saved directly under that S3 bucket just say something like
my file see a city.
And obviously this won't find anything so I won't run this.
But that's basically what this would look like.
If you have a super large dataset that tribut it on S3 Spahr can read it from that just by saying spark
that read that see it's free and then you can also do other options that we show later in the course.
Things like header or infer schema IX cetera.
But the basic idea behind getting's run up and running of the Zeppelin notebook of Python is that in
each cell you got to make sure you have this pie Sparke percent command.
And then if you want to use a spark contex you use se if you want to call a spark session you just call
spark.
So those are key words that are already registered for you.
OK.
I hope that was useful to you.
And remember to terminate this instance when you're done with it.
Otherwise you're going to keep getting charged.
So again this is not free.
This doesn't fall under the free limits of Amazon Web Services.
OK I'll see you at the next lecture.