Welcome to the spark data France project exercise section of the Course.
This section of the Course is essentially just two lectures this lecture where we go over the exercise
and the next lecture where we actually code through the solutions.
The overall goal of this section is to review everything you learn about Sparke data frame basics those
operations group by order by filtering etc.
So let's get started by going over the notebook which contains the exercise questions.
All right here I have the notebook open.
The spark data France project exercise and what this is going to do is like to get some quick practice
for new Sparke data frame skills and we'll again be looking at historical stock market data.
In this case we'll look at Wal-Mart stock data from the year 2012 to 2017.
And this exercise is basically going to be just a series of questions and tasks so you start a simple
Sparke session low the CSP file that asks you what are the column names etc. and you can see here that
there is an empty cell free to fill out the actual code.
And right below it is the expected output.
So luckily you can see before you actually run the so you actually expect the output to look like.
So you just continue on and you'll notice kind of in the middle here there's a bonus question.
So over here when you actually display the output of that data frame there's a lot of decimal points.
So as a bonus question to you I want you to check out see how to actually reduce that number of decimal
places.
And there's a little link here for a hint that takes you to the actual documentation page for the function
need to use.
So if you get stuck on that little thing don't worry about it just be the solutions.
But continuing on that should look something like this.
That's kind of a solution to that bonus question that I want to create a new data frame with the column
called H V ratio and that is the ratio of the high price versus the volume of stock traded for a day.
So the ratio is just one divided by the other and you should get some pretty small numbers here.
So it should look something like that.
And then we also ask questions like what they had the peak high end price.
What does that mean of the close column the max and min the volume column.
How many days the close lower than $60.
What percentage of the time was the hike greater than $80 and basically what I mean by that is what
are the number of days that the high was greater than $80 divided by the total number of days in the
data set.
And then I also asked you something that we didn't exactly cover but there is a hint here for you which
is what does the Pearson correlation between high end volume.
So you basically have to figure out what kind of function you need to use here.
And there's also a big hint as far as the column name there then what does the max high per year.
We actually kind of showed this when we talked about dates and time stamps.
So if you get stuck on this one and make sure to review that lecture towards the end.
All right we'll ask you what is the average close for each color of the month.
And in other words across all the years Carlists if it's in 2012 2013 et cetera what does the average
close price for all those Januarys all those Februarys et cetera.
So it should look something like that.
And those are basically all the questions at the end hopefully did a great job.
If you get stuck on anything don't worry about it.
You can either post to the coupée forums for a hint or just go to the next lecture where we're going
to go over all the solutions.
Thanks everyone and best of luck on the exercise.
I'll see you at the next lecture where we go through solutions.