Welcome to spark in Python for big data with PI spark my name is Jose Portsea and I'll be your instructor
for this course and one of the most popular Python instructors here on you to me where he teach over
a hundred and seventy five thousand students on various topics including python data science machine
learning and more.
I also conduct in-person training on these topics for some of the world's largest companies.
In this course we teach you how to harness the simplicity of the Python programming language with the
power of Apache's spark for working with big data.
So why learn Python and spark spark has been reported to be one of the most valuable tech skills to
learn by in the dot com with the man for sparking big data skills exploding in recent years as one of
the latest technologies in the big data space.
SPARC is quickly becoming one of the most powerful tools for analyzing big data with the ability to
run programs up to a hundred times faster than Hadoop map reduce.
In this course you'll be learning the latest SPARC 2.0 methods including the latest updates the spark's
M-L live library for machine learning and working with SPARK and data frames will also cover additional
Sparke topics such as Sparts streaming.
Let's get a quick overview of the course curriculum.
We'll start off with full set of installation guides that reflect a realistic deployment setting including
local installation guides of Linux and virtual box using Amazon Web Services elastic map readers utilizing
Amazon and easy to instances and even the data Brick's notebooks service will be free to choose whichever
one best suits you or your company's needs.
Or you can try them all out.
We'll continue on a crash course in Python programming.
In case you're coming in from another programming language or you feel a bit rusty on your Python and
want a quick review then we'll move on to learn about the latest shift SPARC syntax working the spark
2.0 style data Frings then we'll continue by learning how to use Spark's and lib library for machine
learning utilizing the latest data Frain API then will also cover some advanced topics such as gradient
boost to trees and Spark's stream all of this content is presented in clear video format as well as
carefully detailed notebooks that include explanatory text and code.
You'll get chances to test your knowledge all along the way with exercise.
We've also included maake consulting projects based on real data sets and real world companies.
She can get experience solving real problems not only do you get fantastic technical content with this
course you will also get access to her online question and answer forums where fellow students I myself
are happy to help you out and answer any questions you may have.
Once you complete the course you will receive a certificate of completion that you can post on your
LinkedIn profile to show off your new skills to colleagues or potential employers.
All of this content comes with a 30 day money back guarantee.
So what are you waiting for.
Jump to the world of big data and enroll today.
I'll see you inside the course.