Welcome to the section on Sparke data frame's in this course the main way we will be working in Python
and Sparke is through the data frame syntax.
If you've worked with panderers in Python the our programming language sequel or even just basic Excel
a data frame will feel very familiar.
And this data frame syntax is the main way we can work with Sparke with SPARC 2.0 or higher SPARC data
frames hold data in a column and row format where each column represents some feature or variable and
each row corresponds and represents an individual data point.
And we're going to be seeing tons of examples of data frames throughout the entire course spark in its
early days began with something known as the already decent tax which was a little ugly and a bit tricky
to learn.
Fortunately now SPARC 2.0 and higher has shifted towards a data frame syntax which is much cleaner and
easier to work with and this data from syntax looks really similar across all the API which is nice
meaning if you've already done a course in something like Scala and spark learning Python and Sparke
data frame's is really easy.
A lot of that stuff looks extremely similar now Sparke data France are able to input output data from
a wide variety of sources and we can use the state of frame's to apply various transformations on the
data.
At the end of those transformation calls we can either show that data or collect the results so you
need to display them or collect them for some sort of final processing.
And in this section We'll cover all the main features of working of data frames that you need to know
once you have a solid understanding of Sparke data frames.
We can move on to utilizing the data from M-L lib API or machine learning library for machine learning.
And that's the machine learning library that comes with SPARC after this section.
We're going to have another section called the data frame project and this project will be an analysis
of some historical stock data information that uses all the spark data for knowledge from this particular
section of the course.
It's going to serve as just a quick exercise review to test all the skills learned in this section.
So as you continue throughout this section Don't worry if you feel a little fuzzy on it in the very
next section with this project exercise we're going to test all your skills so you can review everything
that you learn in this particular section.
All right let's get started with learning the very basics of Sparke data frame's.