Hello everyone and welcome to the documentation example lecture for the logistic regression section.
We're going to do is quickly walk through the documentation logistic regression example.
In reviewing this lecture as well as the previous lectures you should begin to pick up on Spark's general
pattern and workflow for using machine learning with sparks and Python's M-L lib library.
Regardless if you're doing a classification task or a regression task the general workflow for this
lecture should become clear to you.
But we're also going to do is introduce the concept of evaluators evaluators behaves similar to machine
learning algorithm objects that are designed to take any evaluation data frames that is data frames
that are produced when we run things like model thought evaluate on some test data set that produces
an evaluation data frame that has that prediction column and this evaluator object is going to be able
to take in that object and that what we can call metrics off of it and we'll explain that when we actually
see the coded example as a quick note.
If you read the documentation evaluators are still technically labeled as experimental.
So you should use caution when using them for production code.
However they have been around and part of SPARC since version 1.4 and at this time in filming the latest
version of Sparke is 2.1.
So you can assume they have some stability to them.
However you definitely use caution there label experimental for a reason.
So keep that in mind.
The files we're going to be using for this lecture are a logistic regression example the IPY and be
for the notebook and sample it SVM underscored data that text or the actual data look under the logistic
regression folder under the machine learning folder her access to these files and all inks we show can
be found inside that notebook OK.
Let's get started in a brand new notebook and also have some links open and new types.
We're going to visit throughout this lecture.
All right here we have the logistic regression folder open under sparker machine learning and you can
see here we have the logistic regression code along that's going to be the next lecture.
The consulting project the consulting project solutions and the example which is exactly the notebook
we're using right now.
So if you click on that you should see an output that looks like this.
This is all the codes and all the links as well as some explanatory text for everything that we're going
to be doing in this lecture.
And then we have also as well the sample SVM data text that you're going to need for this lecture as
well.
I've created an you know book it's called Untitled right now it's a blank notebook so we can do is just
get started in what you need to do is say from Paice park sequel and begin a spark session in order
to create a data frame Hopefully by now this is second nature to you.
But we can just say spark session builder give or app a name we'll call it.
I don't know my log Reg firm I looked just regression and I'm going to get or creates and the next thing
I want to do is say from Paice spark thought and well and since logistic regression is a classification
task.
The family it falls under is classification and then it can say import and if a hit tab here.
I can see the various things that are available to me.
A lot of these aren't models or just general things but I'm looking for logistic regression.
So let's run that and then let's grab our training data so I'll say my data and I will say Sparke read
formats and this is a live SVM format remember because it's the documentation example and I'm going
to load sample SVM they get that text.
So let's see what that data looks like.
By saying that show and I can see here it's already nicely formatted for me we have labels which are
either 0 or 1 is binary classification and they have features as well.
So that vector of features.
So we'll scroll down here and continue on.
Next I'm going to just go straight ahead and actually create my logistic regression model so I'll say
it my log read model maybe call it something shorter and then we'll say it's an instance of a logistic
regression model.
And as always in this logistic regression model you can specify the features the label column in the
prediction column will keep everything with the default right now that should be enough for us.
And what we're going to do next is call log Regg model lips is equal to.
And we'll just say something like my log.
Well let's call this fitted.
So fitted Greg Zucco to my luck Rick model fit and I'm going to fit it on that training data which I
called my data so will say my data and run that.
So now what I've done is I went ahead and fitted this logistic regression to this data.
I didn't bother to train test Blitt will see that later on.
Oftentimes the documentation doesn't do that.
Now that model has been fitted to the data what it can do is get a summary off of it so I can say results
is equal to.
Well it's called this something like log summary is equal to that fitted log model.
And I'm going to call the summary off of it.
So I've called that summary which means I can grab my log summary and graphs something the predictions
date of frame.
So if I just shift enter here it says that data frame and we can check out the columns Ahaz I could
just print scheme and check out what has it has the label the features the raw prediction the probability
and then the prediction.
So in order to do this we're going to need data which we already knew the labels for in this case we
already knew the labels for data.
So basically what this is saying is here's the actual correct label.
Here were the features.
Here's the raw prediction value which do a logistic regression.
Here's the probability for that prediction value.
And then here is what the model predicted.
So we really want to compare at least the most straightforward way is does this label match our actual
prediction for it.
So let's show this results hopefully we're not too zoomed in here.
OK.
Let me zoom out one more time and then show this again so we can see this nicely formatted.
Well basically this is actually even nice reformat it because I can see label.
And then I can see prediction.
They're kind of stacked right on top of each other which is actually pretty convenient.
So you can see here my labels are Point Zero and my prediction was are appointer as well.
And then 1 1 etc. If you keep going down it looks like we're doing a pretty darn good job of predicting
the labels correctly.
So we can end up doing is checking how we can evaluate this now that we've seen the basic way to perform
a logistic regression.
Let's expand on this documentation example a little bit and introduce the concept of evaluators in order
to really show that we're going to end up doing is grabbing my data and splitting it into a training
set and a test set and then running evaluate on that and then passing in that evaluate data frame into
the evaluator itself.
So we're going to scroll down here and we're actually on a run and you sell.
And in this new cell what I'm going to do is use random split on that all data.
So I'll say all data Let's double check that it was called my data.
OK.
So say my data ran them split and I'll do a 70 30 split and then we'll say well our train religious
aggression.
And then our test set that equal to that and then we're going to do is retrain just on the training
data and then evaluate our test.
So if we come back up here we're basically going to follow these exact same things except we're only
going to fit on the training data instead of all the data.
So we'll come back up here.
Couldn't you model for this so I'll say final model is equal to a logistic regression object.
And then we'll say final model fits on L.R. train and then we'll call this fit final.
So now I have that final model it's fitted to that logistic regression training data.
So I want the actual prediction and results.
So what I'm going to do is say prediction and labels is equal to fit final and then I evaluates on that
test set.
So you've seen a really similar process back in the regression lectures but hopefully these four cells
basically show everything you need to know.
You take all your data.
Once it's formatted Well then you randomly split it into whatever ratio you want.
Pre-training data and you test data you create a logistic regression model if any parameters you want
then you fit that model onto your training data and set that as your fitted model and then using that
fit in model you can evaluate on the test set.
And this is everything shown in separate steps.
But sometimes people like to combine these steps so they'll call a method on a method.
So I have this prediction labels data frame that I'm about to create.
And if we take a look at it I have a prediction it labels and then I can call various things off of
this.
But what I wanted to call is predictions and then show the results here.
So I can see here I have my label the features the raw prediction value probability and then prediction
again.
So essentially this is the exact same thing.
I had a peer with the log summary.
But what I did is I called evaluate on this test data.
So that means is I'm on the test data so I may not get perfect label and prediction matching up.
Right now it looks like it's doing pretty well especially because it's kind of just the documentation's
own data.
It may be a perfect fit but we're about to explore that.
So what I want to do is actually explore the valuation of this prediction and labels data frame is do
an evaluator object or an evaluation object.
So we'll scroll down here and we're going to do say from Paice spark thought M-L the evaluation import
and then we're going to be discussing both multiclass cation and binary classification.
So the ones that may interest you I'm just sitting tab's autocomplete there is binary classification
evaluator.
And let me put on a new line so you can see it.
Multiclass classification evaluator sort of have these multiple lines what we can do is just wrap them
in parentheses.
Now that we've imported both of these evaluator objects I want to quickly hop over to the documentation
so we can dive a little more into the details about binary classification evaluator and multiclass classification
evaluator.
Let's start with binary classification.
So if you come over here and you see M-L that evaluation we have this binary classification evaluator
that takes in the raw prediction column and by default it expects it to be called prediction a label
column that expects to be called label and then some sort of metric name.
In this case it expects area under our O.S. by default.
So that's that receiver operator characteristic curve.
And you can see here that actually has an example where it creates a frame for you to kind of play around
with.
So this is essentially just the basic evaluator for binary classification.
And the raw prediction column can actually be of type 0 or 1 for prediction or probability of label
1 or some sort of type of vectors so that length to vector prediction scores are able probabilities
and we actually had all of those we hopped back to our notebook and scroll up.
We had some of those we had both for our prediction and we had the label and prediction.
So we have this prediction column which is just a zero or once who could use that as well.
And coming down here we want to explore the metric name so the actual metric name if we scroll down
here we basically have two options and that's going to be all the way under metric name right here.
So the metric name it expects is either the area under the receiver operator characteristic curve or
the area under the precision recall curve.
So those are the only two metrics it can return to you since it's the binary classification evaluator.
It's a little more difficult to actually grab things like precision or recall directly from this specific
evaluator.
Now speaking of grabbing things like accuracy precision or recall directly we could use the multiclass
classification evaluator for that.
So what I am going to do is hop over to the next tab I have open which is multiclass classification
evaluator.
You know this multiclass classification evaluator.
I have the prediction column expected which can no longer just take raw prediction and it needs the
actual prediction column which is going to be those zeros those ones and since this is multiclass also
toos and you can see it's basically building one for you with just the strict prediction and the actual
label and the label call them which is the true label as well as the metric name.
So multiclass classification evaluator if you begin to scroll down here you'll eventually get to the
metric name and it can return back the F-1 a weighted precision score a weighted recall score or even
an accuracy score.
So those are all your options for dealing with multiclass classification evaluators.
Now they're a little complicated so don't worry if you totally don't get the idea right now.
We're really going to focus in on these evaluator objects a lot more when we discuss pipeline objects
because that's where they're really going to come into play.
But right now what we can do is go ahead and just show you a very basic example of using one.
So we'll come back to Untitled.
We have prediction and labels predictions that show.
So I'll come down here and use this binary classification evaluator so I'll create my evaluator object
so I'll say my evil is equal to a binary classification evaluator and we'll just keep the actual defaults
since I have a label column and I have a prediction column.
So we'll keep those the faults here and then when I'm going to do is run this and then the next thing
I want to do is actually say my evil and I want to evaluate and I want to go away on this predictions
data frame.
So that was predictions and labels that predictions will pass that N and we'll call this my final Aros
see results or whatever you want to call it.
We'll run that.
And that may take a little bit of time.
The pinning on your actual computer.
And then what we can do is check this out.
So we say my final Orosi Well that happens to be one.
So what does that actually mean.
Well it means the area under the curve of the Orosi was 1.0.
Meaning this essentially was a perfect fit and it predicted everything accurately.
So is that realistic.
Probably not unless you have a lot of faith that everything was highly separable in this case.
This data was highly separable and you can even see a hint of that we were getting predictions that
match the labels perfectly even with the train test blip.
So this wasn't a super good example for what the my final Orosi would look like but this is an indication
that we filled up the Aros seeker and we basically matched our prediction to every single level perfectly.
But what I really want you to get out of this is how to generally use evaluation or evaluate or objects
you'll say from Paice sparked the M-L that evaluation called binary classification evaluator or multiclass
classification evaluator.
And then you can get back for binary class know the area under the Orosi curve or the area under the
precision recall curve.
Her multiclass classification you can get back accuracy the precision and recall etc..
All right I hope you found that useful.
This was not a super realistic example since we got everything perfect.
So let's head up next and see a realistic example using a custom coatl on.
Thanks and I'll see at the next lecture.