Hello everyone and welcome to part two.
The spark in Python was virtual box installation guide in part 2 where we're going to be doing is installing
Python Sparc and the Jupiter notebook system onto our Ubuntu machine.
Ubuntu is already our local operating system.
He's skipped the previous lecture in part 1 and came directly to this video.
If you don't have Ubuntu either as a local OS or on a virtual machine please go back to the previous
lecture apol the guy there before starting with this one as a quick note.
The current version of SPARC at the time of filming this video lecture is sparked 2.1 and that particular
version is incompatible.
The latest version of Python which is 3.6.
This will be fixed when SPARC 2.2 is released.
In the meantime we're going to stick to Python 3.5 to avoid any issues.
Now let's hop over to the actual Ubuntu desktop and show you how to set up everything all right.
Here I am at my Ubuntu desktop instead of my virtual box.
Now the first thing I want to do is confirm that Python 3.5 is already on Ubuntu now it should have
been on Ubuntu sorgen select terminal and if you just type in Python you'll notice you get Python 2.7
out.
But I'm going to quit this and then I'm going to type python 3 so that's all one word.
And then I get Python 3.5 which is the version I'm looking for.
So it already comes Ubuntu we're going to quit and that step is done pretty simple because it came with
it already.
We're going to do now is install the Jupiter notebook system so to do that all you have to do is say
Pip three install Jupiter.
Then enter.
And if it says Pip's 3 is currently not installed.
We're going to do say sudo apt install Python 3 bash pit and then put in your test password and it's
going to install that for you.
It's going to ask if you want to continue.
Select y free s and then I'm going to jump forward in time to this finished downloading and installation.
It should be relatively quick and alright once Pip 3 is done installing and the previous command again
which was picked 3 install Jupiter.
Hit enter and it's going to click then install Jupiter which is going to allow CS to Jupiter notebook
system.
So once that's downloaded and installed will test it out by typing out Jubran output at the command
line.
I'm going to hop Cordone time for this to finish installing and downloading all right once that is done.
You may get a warning about using a older PYT version.
Don't worry about that.
Just type in Jupiter space notebook.
Hit enter once you type that in.
You'll notice that Jupiter notebook's system automatically opens the Mozilla Firefox browser and is
ready to go.
But you'll notice if you come back to the command line it says copy and paste it into your browser when
you connect for the first time to log in with a token.
So if you want we're going to copy this come toward your L and then paste that it will say paste and
go and then we're ready to go.
So we're going to use this is home and I always recommend that you do that.
If you get that warning of a first time copy and paste it and then here I'm going to zoom in a little
bit.
Zoom in and then once we're zoomed in I'm going to hit new note book Python 3 and then just type something
like one plus one new shift enter and then you get some sort of output.
If you are able to get this far.
That means that Jupiter notebook is working correctly on your system and what I also want you to check
is do one divided by two.
That's a forward slash do shift enter and if you're getting zero point and five out then that means
you're correct.
You're running Python 3 not Python 2.
So so far we are all good on our Jupiter notebook and our Python.
All we have to do let is download Sparc and make sure that we connect SPARC with Python.
So let's go ahead and do that.
What I'm going to do now is come over here to the virtual box do Control-C to shut down and then hit
why might you bring an opaque server that's going to shut down.
You'll notice something like connection failed.
Totally ok makes sense to just everything down and I will close that close those mokel tabs leave the
page.
Now what I'm going to do is I need to install Java.
So what I'm going to do is say sudo X gets updates and it's going to update the apt get mechanism which
I'm then going to use to install Java that's it all finished relatively quickly and then once you've
done that we'll go ahead and install it Java with pseudo apps bash gets install default dash.
J R E.
Enter the Laski if you want to continue.
Say yes and then it's going to Dalat install Java for us.
So I will jump forward in time until this is a finished installation.
Quite so after a few minutes you want to check if that all works.
After it's done and you can type Java bash version and if you get something looks like this one point
eight.
Or maybe something a little newer than your good to go.
So once you've installed Java that means we can install Skala so we all say sudo app gets install Skala
enter and then select quite Contini that operation.
And this should be a little quicker than installing Java.
It's about a third of the size I'm willing to jump forward in time until Skala is uninstalling.
Now we're going to check that it installed correctly using the exact same thing we did for Java which
was just Java dash version and that will do Skala dash version.
So let me hop forward in time for Skoll it could be done installing all right now let's check on that
by saying Skala dash version enter.
He should see something like two point eleven point something.
Maybe a little more recent but that means it's good to go we have Skala installed.
The next thing we have to do is install a library called pi for J which connects Java and Skala with
Python.
All you have to do is say Pipp 3 install.
Pi the number 4 and then the letter J.
Enter they'll collect it and then install it.
It's quite a small package so should be done pretty quickly.
Then once you've done that the last thing I do is install Sparc and Hadoop itself.
So in order to do this there's various ways we come to Mozilla Firefox again.
We can search for Apache Sparke.
Make sure you spell it right.
Patchi spark enter and then come over to spark that Apache the short and then select download and it
will get a spark release.
So at this point in time the latest release is 2.1.
So that's what we're going to be using.
And if you want to follow along everything in this course and make sure everything works exactly the
same as me then I would also suggest you do 2.1 and then we'll choose the package type mix we choose
pre-built for Hadoop 2.7 and later.
Then if it says download type you can do.
Download or select Apache.
So we'll just download and then we're going to be downloading SPARC 2.0 1.0 been Hadoop 2.7 thought
DGC and once you have that just click on it and it should begin the download and will select Save file
will hit OK.
And it's going to be quite a large file.
So here it's taking about 8 minutes.
Depends on your internet speed.
It's about 187 megabytes.
But I mean that's a spark.
We're going to need it.
So I will hop 40 in in time until it's finished install or downloading and then we'll show you how to
install it with ubuntu all right.
Once that's done finished in downloading we want to install it but I want to make sure it's in the correct
location.
So click here on the little file explorer and then I'll go over to downloads.
Double click on that and I'm going to move this.
So let's cut this.
We just downloaded sparking Hadoop and then bring it over to our home folder.
So then we will paste it here and that's exactly where I want it.
So then I can just come over to my command line and them the type is sudo tar
z x the X and then start typing the word spark and then hit tab to auto complete this.
So basically this is going to unzip this for us and then you'll be prompted for a password.
Put it in and then that's going to unzip that and create the hole that we need.
Perfect.
So what we want to do is tell Python where it's actually fine spark.
So you can copy and paste this from the resource lecture notes or just type it along with me.
I only say export Sparke underscore home is equal to home slash wound to slash Sparke and then let me
make sure I get the file path right.
It's going to be cash to point one point zero that's been cash Dhoop 2.7.
Basically the folder or file that we just made directory so export that to spark home and you're going
to type export pass equal to dollar sign spark and this is in all caps here underscore home Kolin dollar
sign.
And then in all caps again Pat which is basically going to tell the path of where to find Sparke home
and set the path.
And they're going to say export Python pass is equal to dollar sign Sparke underscore home slash Python
Colan dollar sign.
And then in all caps Python path then hit enter and we have a few more things to do before we can actually
get up and running with Sparke running in the notebook.
But we're going to do is say export pie Sparke underscore driver underscore Python is equal to double
quote Jupiter double quote enter and you'll also say export in all caps here.
Weissberg underscore driver underscore Python underscore o pete t s o p TS is equal to and then in double
quotes.
Notebook close that all enter and finally to link it up with Python 3 you want to say export Paice spark
underscore Python is equal to and it will say without quotes.
Python 3.
Enter in order to fix any possible permission errors.
You may get when using the Jupiter notebook under the spark folder.
You see here in home there's a little icon saying it's kind of locked here.
If I double click on this folder eventually I can see under Python that I do have pi SPARC ready to
go but what I need to do is set the permissions so I can access it.
So what we will do here is inside the terminal the command I'm going to use is S.H. maade and then I'm
going to write 777 and then the file name which in this case is Sparke 2.1 etc..
So hit enter and it says change permissions blah blah is not permitted so we're going to do a pseudo
S.H. maade 777 and spark enter is going to ask you for your password when I type in my test password.
Enter again.
And now that should work.
So I'm going to see the into Sparke CD into Python there and then if I just type in Python 3 I should
be able to then say something like import.
Spark and it will import it just fine.
So what I want to do is check if this actually works now that Jupiter notebook.
So I won't say quit in once we've changed the permission of Sparke we can come back here to home and
see that no longer has that icon.
But if you click on this you still see that Python has that permission icons are going to come back
to terminal CD into Sparc and then we're going to do the same thing.
Sudo S.H. maade on Python.
Whoops forgot to add code which basically is me read write and execute permissions on that folder.
Hit enter and now we can see if.
Come back here.
That's unlocked and it should be ready to go except we have Paice Birk So one more left.
We're going to then CD into Python and then say sudo changed bar so it 7:7 on py Sparke.
Hit enter and now in this python folder Let's go ahead and type in Jupiter notebook
and inside of this we'll create a new notebook.
Python 3 and inside of this note but I'm going to type in import PI spark shift enter and there it goes.
So once we have that you are ready to go and you have spark running on your computer.
Any time you want to come and start a new notebook and work with Paice SPARC all you have to do is CD
into SPARC 2.7 into Python and make sure you change those permissions as we just showed.
Otherwise you'll get errors saying something like.
Permission denied on untitled.
I wipe or IPY in B file.
All right.
Thanks everybody and I will see you at the next lecture if you have any questions on this process.
I know it's a bit complicated.
Feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums and makes you check up the resource in this lecture which has a written
guide of everything we covered.