Hello everyone and welcome to the sparks streaming example code along lecture because we're really using
spark streaming and the structures streaming that's still experimental in an Alpha at SPARC 2.1 0.1.
What we need to do is use some older ardy the syntax because we're going to be using a spark context
instead of a spark session.
So we're going to be building a very simple application that connects to a local stream of data just
to open terminal through a socket connection.
It will then count the words for each line that we type in the terminal.
Now the steps for creating the actual streaming connection is going to be the following.
Well first create a smart contex.
It's very similar to the way we've been treating SPARC sessions.
Then using that SPARC context we create a streaming context and then using that streaming context we
create a socket text stream essentially connecting via a socket.
Our Jupiter notebook or your PI file to the actual terminal.
Then we're going to read in the lines as a stream worried data stream.
Then once you actually have that data stream the steps were working the data are the following.
First we'll take that input line Remember we're just reading this in batches so we'll have these inputs
of lines which are essentially just a long string.
We want to split that into a list of words just using a normal not split method.
Then we're going to map each of those words to a tuple that looks like this a word comma one where it's
always going to be one as the second parameter in that tuple.
Then we're going to group or reduce the tuples by the word which is the key.
And this is just a way of saying a reduced by key then we're going to sum up the second argument which
is always the number one.
And that allows us to essentially reduce all those tuples which is going to the words comma 1 and actually
get a word count.
So you can imagine if I had type then hello hello we would end up splitting hello hello into a list
of those two strings.
Hello comma Hello.
Then would a map each word to a tuple hello come a one in one tuple and again hello come a one in another
tuple and then we group or reduce the tuples by the word which is the key.
In this case it's the hello and we actually sum up the second argument which is the number one.
So at the end we will get something that looks like a tuple except they would say hello comma two and
that will then provide us with a word count in the form like I just said hello comma three or comma
to cetera for each line.
Then as a quick note the ardy the syntax relies heavily on lambda expressions which are just quick anonymous
functions.
And luckily the land expressions we use here are really quite simple and basic so I don't think you
have any problem understanding them.
OK let's get started with a simple example I'm going to open up my virtual box and we'll open up two
terminals and the in a notebook.
Let's get started OK here I am at my Ubuntu desktop inside my virtual box.
Going to come over here and I will open a terminal and then I'm actually going to open a terminal twice.
So we'll have two terminals and in the first terminal that will be used for Jupiter notebook in the
second terminal.
I will actually use for the streaming socket connection.
So let's start a Jupiter notebook.
Enter and then eventually my Mozilla Firefox.
Or google chrome whatever you're using should pop up and we'll create a new notebook and then I'm going
to save you toggle header you toggle toolbar.
And since I'm running this on a virtual box also I'm going to say import fine spark and then the next
step after import find spark is just find spark in it and then the file location for our spark.
So I'm going to copy and paste this sentence I just say find spark in it and then wherever spark happens
to be installed in my virtual box machine then I'm going to run that.
And now we should be ready to go.
OK.
So the first thing you have to do is begin the streaming.
So I'll say from Paice spark import a spark context so you can run that and then I will also say from
Paice spark not streaming import a streaming context then we can also use tab autocomplete that as well.
Then we will say actually create these.
So I'll say S-C is equal to a smart context and we're going to be working with two working threads.
So the actual syntax for that is local and in square brackets and the number two are two local threads
and then whatever you want the application to be called.
So we'll call this network word count.
And you can actually check out all the details in the instructions both in the notes provided but as
well as the documentation.
This is the example from the documentation.
And then once you've created that smart contex I'm going to say s s c for streaming context is equal
to a streaming context and then I'm going to pass in the Smart context.
And then one so the number one just means the interval is 1 second.
So whatever type of streaming context I end up using it's always going to be taking it in batches of
one second at a time.
So we can run that and then I will say lines is equal to offer this streaming context object.
I will create a Bub's a socket text stream and this is going to create that stream or data stream will
connect to a hostname and it's going to connect to a local port.
So here I will say local host and then pass a port number that I'm pretty sure is not being used.
So if you have a firewall it may be blocked.
It shouldn't really matter here because we're running on a virtual box.
There's no default firewall like a Windows firewall here just running Ubuntu.
So we're going say nine nine nine nine as our local hosts port connection and we can specify that when
we actually go back to the terminal.
So there are lines remember that's the actual string of data we're going to be typing in.
Now I want to grab that string that single line and turn it into a list of words which means I'm going
to say words point to get that lines object and then I'm going to say flat map.
And this allows me to map something to those lines.
And we're going to use the land expression where we've taken each line and then we split that line based
off whitespace.
So just to make that clear I'll actually specify the argument into that split.
OK so now that we have that list of words I want to create my pairs which are those tuples I was talking
about earlier we're going to take my words and then I'm going to map each word to the tuple just consisting
of the word comma one.
Now my peers.
I want to actually get my word counts so we'll say word counts as equal to those pairs.
And then I'm going to reduce by key and you can essentially almost think of this as a group by mechanism
where reduce by key takes in a tuple and automatically reduces by the first argument in the tuple and
then you can do an operation with the rest of the second arguments.
So we say pairs that reduce by key lambda and we're going to take an x y.
So I'll actually type in Word number and then I'm going to say actually this is probably not a good
choice we'll say number one.
Number two say number one plus number two.
Now this is just a little weird because it's not very intuitive.
What's going on here when you say reduce specky.
And because of this kind of non intuitiveness it's actually Weissberg streaming is moving towards structure
streaming in Weissberg context.
The syntax is moving towards data frames in general just because this sort of stuff is kind of a little
weird to get your head wrapped around.
But basically what's happening here is a lot of times when you're working.
ARDE these eventually get things and map stuff to be in tuple pairs where you have a tuple and you have
some sort of key as the first argument and a tuple occurs item in a tuple and then as a second item
or element in the tuple.
You have a number or a word etc..
And then once you have those tuple pairs you say reduce by key.
And what's interesting about this is using the ardy the syntax is reduced by key automatically knows
that it's going to grab the first item in the tuples and use that as its key to reduce by group grouped
by and then the land expression or the function you pass in that takes in two arguments.
It's not just going to apply that to just two tuples that happen to match the same word.
It's going to keep reducing over and over until you just get one single instance of the word tuple itself
on that key.
So that's a little bit strange to wrap your head around the very first time you see it but I think after
we see some examples of the terminal it will make more sense.
But keep in mind this kind of weird non-intuitive syntax is basically the whole reason people are start
to move towards data frames.
Just gonna take a little longer for Sparke streaming to get there because streaming in itself is a little
more complicated to convert.
But hopefully by the time SPARC 2.2 comes around SPARC structure streaming will be maybe out of Alfon
into a beta phase and then by 2.3 it's you know a little more stable.
Right now it's pretty experimental and I really wouldn't suggest using it in a production environment.
OK.
So we have our word counts the very last thing I want to do is off this are the the when I say word
counts and then we can call the prince.
Kind of like a pretty print.
It's basically just the printing everything with a nice format is word counts themselves.
OK.
So then we're going to do is type in S S C that starts close parentheses and I won't actually run this
quite yet.
So we're going to do is come back to our terminal and in the terminal in an array and see space that's
L.K. space and then that port number 9 9 9 9 and going to enter and then and then start typing.
But before you start typing I'll come back to the Jupiter note book and actually start my streaming
context.
So let's run this.
OK.
So my streaming contex has started and you can already see it's beginning to print every second.
So let's start typing something.
Say hello enter and we'll say hello hello hello and then we can write.
This is a line with multiple words.
Ok so since I'm using the Jupiter note book in order to kind of kill this I either need to say as a
seed that await termination which is going to wait for the computation to terminate.
You can actually put limits on it but since this is just running in one cell it's going to keep running
for a really long time.
So what I will do is say kernel appear and then and when to just interrupt it to force it to stop.
All right.
So if I come all the way down here I should stop seeing the print outs.
And if you come back up here since it was taken every second we can see here that our word count was
in fact actually working this multiple line is a words with etc..
And then if we come back up here we can see those counts.
Hello three.
And the very first one was Helot one etc. and those are the very basics of working with Sparke streaming
and also working with kind of the older Spart context RTD syntax.
Now if you want some more details on that definitely check out the documentation page.
This same example is on the documentation page and we have a little more details on every step for you
as well as different links for more help.
OK.
Coming up next we're going to set up everything we need are the actual Twitter example and then the
lecture after that we will go through it.
Thanks everyone.
And if you have any questions feel free to post the uniforms.
I'll see you at the next lecture.