Welcome back in this lecture We'll discuss the basics of working with Sparke data frames.
Let's jump to Jupiter notebook and get started.
So in order to actually work with Sparke data frames we first need to start a spark session to do that.
I can say from Paice spark that sequel in poor sparks session and note the capitalization here.
You can always just use tab to complete this.
So I'm going to run that and then we need to actually start the spark session by applying it.
So annoying create a variable by default or convention I should say you call it spark and then we'll
say spark session dots builder.
App name and let's give this app name something like basics and then I will call get or create and notice
capitalization there and then do shift enter to run this.
Now most likely if you just open up the notebook and you're running this command for the first time
it's going to take maybe a minute or two.
I already ran this previously so that's why it's working so fast right now.
So maybe if you're working on a W-S elastic map reduce it's also going to run really fast.
Something like a local virtual box or SETI might take a little while that very first time.
So don't worry if it takes a little bit of time just give it one or two minutes.
All right.
The next thing I want to do is actually read a data set we'll talk a lot more about various data inputs
and outputs.
But for right now we're going to be using the people that chase on a file that's included with the course
notes so we'll say the F is equal to spark and then we'll call the read method and then from that will
say dot and then if I hit tab here.
Luckily Jupiter notebook can show me all the various ways I can read stuff but also keep it simple for
now and just say thought Jason and then I'm going to read.
And people thought Jason.
Now I recommend that you start this Jupiter note book in the same directory where this file is located.
So you don't need to worry about providing the full file path name.
If this notebook is in a different directory than this data then in that case you do need to post the
whole file pathname as a string here.
And keep in mind sometimes Sparke can be a little tricky when working the file paths to have spaces
in them.
Sometimes it doesn't like that so you may need to put underscores or get rid of those spaces so keep
that in mind as you work with Sparke.
So I will run this and then I have my data frame.
So let's actually show some of this data in order to show the data and show it data frame you just call
the DOT show and it's a method so we call a closed parentheses there.
And now it's actually missing some data.
But SPARC can handle it.
So we have an age column and a name column and we have a null value for this age.
Spark has no problem dealing that it automatically replaces missing data with null and we'll have a
whole another lecture on working of missing data with SPARK data frames.
But right now notice how it's missing and how it still works.
If you want to know the schema of a data frame you can use the DFT print schema method and then just
using tabs to autocomplete there close parentheses because this is a method to run it.
And here I get the roots and then the name of the column age and name and the data type.
So long is just kind of another way of saying a certain numeric integer data type.
If you haven't encountered it forward don't worry too much about it.
And then we have this string data type.
So luckily SPARC was able to infer that we had age as some sort of numeric long integer data type because
of 30 and 19 even that missing data and really stop it there.
And it was able to clarify that name is some sort of string data type.
Now sometimes depending on your data source it may just default everything to a string and we'll talk
about that in just a little bit.
But I want to show you two more methods one of them is actually an attribute.
If you just want the column names you can use DFT columns and this is an attribute meaning you don't
need to actually have those close parentheses there.
And luckily it just returns back a python list of all the column names and then we can call this scribe
to get a statistical summary of the data frame.
And if you called the described by itself can just run this you get back a data frame.
So what does it actually mean.
Well it says hey I returned that data frame with a column called summary which has some strings in it
and a column called age which also has some strings in it.
If you actually want to see the state of frame then we need a call that show and then actually the data
framed that was the description data frame.
So what does the scribe actually do.
It's just a statistical summary of the numeric columns in your data frame.
So the only numeric column we had was the age column.
So it gives you a count.
There was two values in there.
Note that we just had a scroll back up 13:19 it won't count that null value there.
It gives you the average some standard deviation and then the min and max.
Now later on we'll also talk about how you can edit the output so you don't see so many significant
figures.
But for right now just know that that describe and that show are way to quickly see a statistical summary
of the numeric columns.
Now I want to take a little break and discuss schema.
Luckily we're dealing for pretty small data set and the schema was inferred correctly some sort of long
integer value and then a string.
Often if you're not dealing with data that's really nice.
Or maybe from a particular source you need to actually clarify what the schema is.
So in order to do certain operations the schema has to be correct there has to know what columns are
strings or columns are integers etc..
So let's walk you through how to actually do this SPARC has all the tools you need but it just requires
kind of a very specific structure.
So the documentation actually isn't so great on showing this so I want to walk you through it myself.
The first thing to do is actually import these type tools.
So we'll say from Paice spark the sequel dot types is important.
And you can actually use tabs help auto complete some of this.
So I'm going to import a struct field which is the search field and then I can import a string type
and I'm also going to import integer type and then if I hit tab here I can just see wups Let's hit tab
over here so I can see the list of everything that's available for me here.
It's a lot.
So we'll just kind of stick with the ones we need.
And I also want structure type so you can always refer to the notes if you want to just copy and paste
this but we imported structure field string type integer type and struct type in as a quick no.
If you're ever importing stuff and you don't want everything just in one long line like this I'm a little
zoomed in.
So you can do is have a princes here and then break it up into two lines and just wrap all the imports
in these print princes and all still work.
So I imported these four types and basically Next we need to actually create a list of structure fields
and the structure fields takes in kind of these three parameters takes in the name the data type and
some sort of nullable.
So let me walk through that kind of explain it all create a variable called data schema.
And this is going to be a list here and the list is going to take in structure field.
And I want to pass in the column which is going to be age and I want to pass in an instance of integer
type close parentheses and then I want to specify true.
So what does this actually mean.
Are you going to pass in name into this field.
So that just means hey the column that this relates to is called age.
Then you pass in some sort of class instance.
In this case integer type meaning I want age to be integer type.
So I'm actually going to be changing from long to straight integer and then the third parameter is a
boolean.
So whether or not the field can be NULL if you don't type in true here if you have a missing value they'll
show an error.
So right now I have true here saying hey it's OK that it's null and that's one structure field anoints
create one more.
So it's actually kind of start this on a new line.
So I'll create one more structure field all in the same list just the new line and then this clarifies
that the Name column or name field should be a string type.
Which kind of matches with exactly what spark inferred on its own.
And then I'll say true that it can be null even though we didn't actually have any.
So that's my data schema.
That's how you set up the schema that you're expecting.
And then I'm going to set up a variable called Final struck for final structure and you pass in that
data schema into the struct type.
So structure type.
And this takes in this Field's argument which is just this data schema.
So you're going to say Fields is equal to data schema so we're going to run that.
And now I'm actually going to read in that case on file but I'm going to clarify that I want the schema
to be my final structure.
So no what happens here when say the F is equal to spark.
Read that Jason same file people that Jason.
Except I'm going to add in schema as a parameter argument and pass in my final stroke.
So let's run this and see what happens when we show the schema.
So let's actually say DFA print schema.
And now I can see that it's clarified age to be an integer instead of a long.
So if you ever have issues with your own particular file formats where everything's being read into
as a string you can use this methodology to actually clarify your particular schema type.
So for esoteric data types this is kind of an issue sometimes.
Luckily it's getting less and less of an issue and SPARC is getting better and better at inferring schema
types so I want to show this here.
But as a quick note we'll never have to do this for the course all the course materials are in C S ves
and SPARC has no problem inferring the schema types but I do want you to be aware that this does exist
for you as a tool.
And honestly just frankly speaking right now that documentation I don't think does a very good job of
showing this process but hopefully with this notebook and this video you now have a clear idea of what
you would need to do in case she ever need it to define your own schema.
That's all I wanted discuss for the first part of day to frame basics in the second part of day to frame
basics.
Kind of get a little more with the nitty gritty and the stuff that you'll actually be doing on a day
to day basis things like grabbing the data creating new columns and even possibly using sequel with
your data frames.
So coming up next we're going to see some more realistic use cases for actually interacting with your
data frame.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.