Welcome back everybody.
In this lecture we're going to go through the documentation example for the various tree methods.
So now that we have the intuitive understanding of how these algorithms work we're going to do is dive
into the documentation examples we'll work through decision tree random forest and gradient boosted
trees and you'll see that it's actually very easy to swap almost any machine learning algorithm out
for another.
The way pi Sparc and M-L lib have been constructed.
We will also expand a little more from the documentation example and show some useful evaluation features
as well as how you can use multiclass evaluators on a binary classification.
So let's open up a new Jupiter notebook and get started or I started in new Jupiter notebook and as
a quick note all the data that you need is available under the spark for machine learning under the
tree methods folder.
There's all the data and all the notebooks for this lecture as well as all the other lecturers in the
section.
I started a spark session I've called it my treats are ready to get started.
Most are going to do a couple of more imports.
I'm going to import from Paice sparked the M-L.
I'm going to import pipeline and then I will also import classification models from Paice sparked thought
m-L.
So I will say from Paice park the M-L classification import.
And then the ones we want I want a random forest classifier.
I also want the gradient boosted GBC classifier So they kind of shorten it there and then I also want
the decision tree classifier and let me put this more on a couple of lines here so we can see them all
so ran the first classifier PBT classifier and Decision Tree classifier.
Now as a quick note all these various tree methods depending on how you actually apply them can be used
for regression as well.
So if you ever regression problem that you're interested in applying ran the forced on you could say
from Paice spark the M-L regression and then import and they can click tab here and see what models
are available for you.
You can see you're here you have a decision tree repressor a general or a gradient to tree or aggressor.
And if you start writing.
Are you also heavy rain the forest regressors you can use all these models for regression tasks as well.
And remember for a classification if you have an ensemble of trees basically what we're doing is we're
taking votes to see what class the actual road should belong to.
For regression what they end up doing is the average all the guesses for that continuous variable.
So we're going to the classification for the tree method just because it's a little easier to evaluate
things like root mean squared error or sometimes a little hard to tell or understand intuitively things
like accuracy or area under the curve are a little easier.
So let's continue on a classification and what we're going to do is read in the actual data.
So I will say data is equal to spark read.
And this is the documentation data.
So it's in that kind of esoteric live SVM format.
And then it will say load.
And it's the sample live SVM data that text that's already available for you in the tree methods folder.
So run that we have the data.
And let's just show off that data what it looks like and because it's documentation data it's already
conveniently shown as the label and features column so we don't actually need to do much with this.
So we'll keep scrolling down.
We're going to do just split this into a training set and a test set.
So we'll say something like train data and test data is equal to data.
The random split.
And then let's do a 70 30 split here.
OK.
So now what we can do is create various models.
Let's start off with the most basic one.
A decision tree classifier and then set that equal to this entry classifier we want to specify the label
column as label in the features column is features.
But right now if you look those are already the default.
So we don't really need to specify these the parameter that may be interesting to specify feel like
that shift plus tab are things like the maximum depth for the tree the max on bins and things like minimum
information gain.
I encourage you to play around with those values and if you're confused on how they may affect your
actual decision tree what you should do is do the reading an introduction to statistical learning to
learn a little bit more about the mathematical background behind those parameters.
If you want to mess around beyond the defaults leave everything default right now.
And besides a decision tree classifier I'm also going to make a RAFC or random forest classifier and
have also make a great and boosted tree classifier So it's called PBT so GBG classifier so have these
three classifier objects are all use and the default parameters something like random forest.
And if you do shift tab here not only do you have things like Max def and Max bin's but you also have
a really important one which if you expand on this is the number of trees to use now 20 by default maybe
pretty low especially if a really large dataset.
So we can do here is say something like number of trees equal to 100.
And there's no right or wrong answer for how many trees you should use at a certain point if you start
using too many trees.
You're not going to gain any more accuracy for the additional trees an additional computation.
So sometimes what people do is they run multiple instances of different tree amounts.
Testor accuracy and kind of see where that cutoff point is where they're not gaining any more accuracy
or whatever they're trying to actually evaluate on whatever metric for adding more treason.
So the more trees you add the more computation time and at a certain point you don't get anything back.
Freezing more trees.
OK.
So it will trees to 100.
It's also fine if you just use the default.
It shouldn't really make a difference given that we're kind of working with meaningless data here because
it's just that random live SVM file.
Now that we have these various classifiers what you can do is actually fit them.
So we will see the TC model is equal to the PC and I will fit this to my training data and will do this
for all three of them.
So let's create those three models and then say RAFC for this first one or the second one I should say
and then G-B t for the third one.
So once you run that this may take a little bit of time because you're just fitting three models in
a row.
Once those models have been fitted we can use them and transform the test data to get predictions.
So I can say DTC spreads is equal to my DTC model thought transform and then grabbed my test data and
I'm going to do that for all three of them again.
So let's copy and paste this and we will say R.F. spreads is equal to the RAFC model on that evaluation
or prediction or transformation I should say.
And then she Beati and G-B here.
So basically doing the exact same thing for all three models and then we kind of compare them at the
end.
So now if we take a look at just one of these I'll say DTIC breads and then show them.
So I'm going to let's just say show.
I have the label.
The original features and then RAW prediction the probability and then the prediction itself for the
label.
Now if you look at all of these for example RAFC this also looks really similar has that raw prediction
column but CBT will not have that raw prediction column.
So if you're Renji t it only has prediction itself.
It doesn't have that raw prediction value.
So when you're using something like a multiclass classification evaluator or a binary class classification
evaluator sometimes it has raw prediction as its default input column.
You'll have to change that to prediction for CBT and we show that in the very next lecture so keep that
in mind.
But now that we've done this let's show you how you can use an evaluator on this.
So what I'm going to do is say from Paice park dot evaluation import.
Now even though this is a binary classification dataset if I only do a binary classification evaluator
here I'm only going to be able to do stuff like the precision recall curve and the area under the Orosi
curve but luckily with the multiclass classification evaluator this will still work even though it's
a binary class.
And with this multiclass classification evaluator I can do direct metrics such as precision recall or
accuracy.
And you can check the documentation as we've shown in the past for those actual metric names.
But let's create a multiclass classification evaluator that works for accuracy.
So I will say A.S.C. evil is equal to a multiclass classification evaluator where the if you do shift
tab here expects a prediction column called prediction and a label column called label.
Well we just saw all these threads.
These data frames those are all have it.
And then the metric name the default is EF 1.
But you can do is say metric name to be accuracy.
And again check the documentation for all the various metric names available to you.
But once you have that well we can do is just evaluate.
So I can say A.S.C. evil and I'm going to evaluate the predictions so the predictions I have right now
let's just do the decision tree breads and I'm going to print something.
So this is labeled so DTC we'll say accuracy.
So if I run this we should see the actual accuracy.
So accuracy is 100 percent for decision tree classifier.
That should definitely raise some eyebrows but you should also note that this data over here is really
easily fit.
So it's highly separable meaning even if a decision tree a single decision tree has 100 percent accuracy
it's not a good sign.
As far as how hard the data was to separate.
So keep that in mind in the next lecture we're going to do a much more realistic data set.
And these numbers will be more meaningful but the methods themselves won't change.
So let's check out random forest classifier accuracy RAFC spreads will get 100 percent on accuracy for
around a first class fire.
And finally check reading boosted tree.
Now remember Green was a tree we were just using the default parameters.
So we also get a hundred percent accuracy.
Not very helpful I know.
But the actual methods are the same.
So again in the next lecture on our own custom code example we're going to see something much more realistic.
And these numbers won't be so perfect.
OK.
One final note that I want to show you is the ability to grab feature importance.
So let's grab our model that's fitted.
For example our Random forest model going to copy this.
Paste this here.
And if you hit dot tab you'll notice that one of the things you can grab off of this is feature importances.
So this is not a very good example to show this but it hit shift enter on this.
Essentially what you get is the feature itself and then how important it was so the higher the number
the more important it was.
Now this is kind of a weird example to show because the vector was sparse and it had a lot of features
in it.
So I'm going to leave this just for now kind of hanging in the air.
The reason for that is this is a really big part of your consulting project in this section.
So I kind of want to just leave it out there.
And I want you to explore the documentation on how this feature importance actually works as an attribute
off the model because you're going to be using it for your consulting project.
So consider this just a really heavy hints for the consulting project and I'm going to leave it at that.
This is something you can explore on your own.
If after viewing the consulting project solutions you saw questions on this feel free to post them to
the Kewney forums.
But again this particular dataset is kind of strange to call feature importances on it wasn't very clear
what was going on for the next coatl long project and the consulting project it will be a lot more clear
to you so I won't mention this again until we get to the consulting project.
But keep in mind it's going to be really useful for that particular project.
OK.
Overall I hope you understand now how you can actually call Decision Tree classifier ran the forest
classifier ingredient boost tree classifier.
And again if you wanted to this could all be used as regression models.
Main things to get out of this is basically you should have a full understanding of how to use almost
any model with Sparke.
Essentially you just import it.
You could use a defaults or set up your own parameters then you fit the training data.
Transform any test data.
Or if you have test data or some data that doesn't have the labels already you would just evaluate it
then you get your predictions out and then you can call your evaluation.
Now you can only call these evaluation metrics if you have test data.
If you have data where you only had for example the features you don't have the actual label so you're
kind of about that deployment stage you're not going to be able to call the evaluator.
Instead you're just going to do the evaluation and show your predictions.
As we've shown in the past before and the second thing I want to put out is that you can cut.
You can use this multiclass classification evaluator even on a binary metric or binary data set.
And you can use metric names such as accuracy.
This particular data set not very fun because it's essentially perfect but the next data set that we'll
see in the next lecture they'll become a lot more clear.
All right.
Do you have any questions feel free to the Kewney forums.
But hopefully by now most of this is clear to you.
I'll see in the next lecture.