Welcome back to part two of the spark to frame basic's lectures.
We're going to jump right back that you put a note book from the previous lecture and continue on here's
a book from the previous lecture where we discussed how to start a spark session read in a data frame
from a jay sun file a couple of methods and attributes from that data frame such as print in the schema
describing it showing the columns and then we have a discussion of how to manually set the data frame
schema.
Now this is what our current data frame looks like.
Has the H column in the name column.
Let's discuss how to actually grab data from this.
There's a couple of different ways we can go about this but I want to discuss what happens when you
select vs just grab data if I want to get a column.
You might be tempted just to say something like an index call off a dictionary def and then passing
the string age.
If I run this I get back a column object meaning if I actually check the type of this by passing this
in through the type function I get back Paice sparked the sequel doc column column.
So that's a column object.
If I actually want to get a data frame with that singular column that way I can see the results.
I use the Select method and that's really all we're going to be doing quite a bit in this course.
You say DFI dot select and then if I just an age here I can see I have a data frame with the singular
column H.
Which means I can then call the show off of this and see that singular column.
So the main differences between these two methods is the fact that one of them the first one is returning
back a column while the second one is returning a data frame that contains a single column.
You get a lot more flexibility with a data frame of a single column versus just a column.
So a lot of times will defer back to select instead of just grabbing that column object.
So again this command using select File Type in type and pass it in it's returning back a data frame.
So and a lot more methods and attributes we can call off of that.
So if you want to check the row objects themselves.
For instance let's say you want to check the first two rows in a data frame.
You can call DFT ahead and then pass in the number of rows you want.
This grabs the top two rows and you can see here.
I gave a list of row objects so that means I can index this list so called 0 off of that and I get back.
This row objects which tells me the age is equal to none and name is equal to Michael so if I scroll
back up that was this row right here and again I can check the type of this to confirm that its sequel
types row.
So keep that in mind that there is actually a row object in that data frame.
And the reason there are so many specialized objects such as a column object or a row object is because
Spark's ability to read from a distributed data source and then map that out to distributed computing
so that's why there are so many specialized types here instead of just something like some sort of series
or list objects for everything.
If you want to select multiple columns that's pretty easy to do as well.
You just passing DMF select and then a list of columns so I can say instead of just aging and passen
names to note the difference here.
I'm saying select but I'm passing and a list of columns of square brackets.
So this returns a data frame of two columns and I can just say that show off the data frame to actually
see the results.
In this case the entire data frame let's discuss creating new columns so you can add a new column with
a simple with column method so we can say F and then we call with column and there is also if column
renamed will you're going to see later on and with column basically returns a new data frame by adding
in a column or replacing an existing column.
So the first thing he pasan is the name of your new column so it will say something like New-Age.
It's just a string here and then you pasan a column.
So in this case we do need to say DFA square brackets age so I actually want to pass in the actual column
itself.
Remember that this doc column doc column data type here.
So I say the name of my new column D.
Age and then I can actually show this just so we can see the results and we see age name new age.
So that's just essentially a copy of New-Age.
If I actually want to perform some operations I can do something like DFI age and something that says
times too.
So let's make this more obvious by saying double age and I'm going to run this and I can see age name
age.
But notice here I'm saying grab this numeric data type.
Multiply it by two.
And here we see 36 the 1938.
So we won't actually be doing this a whole lot but I do want to show that it's possible here especially
with numeric columns.
Now something to keep in mind is these changes aren't permanent on our original data frame.
If I just say the show that it says age name.
So notice what happened here.
This was not an in-place operation.
You would have to save this to a new variable now a really common operation is just renaming a column.
So if you have a column that you just want to simply rename that's actually quite easy.
That was the with column renamed.
So instead of passing in a column all you have to do is pass in the old column name.
So for example age and then as a string the new column name.
So I'll say my new age and I always put in underscores there to make sure I don't get any errors.
They shouldn't be necessary but just keep that in mind and let's show the results of that so I can see
Ivery named age to my new age.
So the difference between with column and with column rename is with Camarena just for two strings the
old column name and the new column name.
So as I mentioned you can do operations.
So here we have the age but you can do a lot of stuff with this.
So I'll put in new stuff and then I could do something like even divide by two.
And that has no problem.
You can do something like plus 2.
Again has no problem running.
So keep that in mind there's a lot of flexibility there and we're going to discuss much more complicated
operations later on.
The very last thing I want to discuss is using pure sequel that's the query language to directly deal
and interact with the data frame.
So in order to do that we're going to scroll all the way down here.
And if you have no idea what sequel is you've never used it before.
Don't worry you can basically finish this lecture off.
But I imagine that if you're a data analyst you probably have a little bit of experience of sequel.
So this is a really cool feature and it's actually why it's called spark that sequel is because it can
interact directly with sequel queries.
So in order to actually do all of this you want to register that data frame as a sequel temporary view.
So I will say DFI dot and then I can start typing creates and I want to say create or replace tenth
view.
That way if I XLE already created this view ill replace it.
And then we pass the string of what we want to call.
Essentially this table.
So we'll call this people.
So I run this and now essentially I've registered this as a sequel temporary view which means I can
do the following or create a variable called results and say spark that sequel.
And as a string here I can pass and direct sequel queries meaning I can do something like this.
Select Asterix from people we're a people.
Is that registered temporary view that I did up here.
So let's run this and then check the results.
So I will show the results here.
And no I get everything back.
So let's actually show a more complicated example.
So I'll say new results are equal to spark thought sequel and I'm going to say select Asterix from people
where age is equal to 30.
So the say direct sequel query analysis shows new results and I get back Andy because his age was 30.
So what's the real positive here.
What's really awesome is if you already have a lot of sequel knowledge you can leverage that with Sparke
sequel and you can do complicated operations really quickly in case you happen to forget some of the
more basic Sparke different operations.
Now keep in mind we won't really be focusing on using direct sequel queery syntax for this course.
In general we're going to be focusing more on the Python and PI spark specific methods of interacting
with a data frame.
But I want you to realize that if you already have that sequel knowledge that's a huge thing you can
leverage with the power of Spark's sequel and that's essentially why we've been importing everything
from sparked up sequel or pi sparked a sequel.
And that's also why when you're looking through the documentation online you see a lot of references
to sequel because of the power that you can say a direct sequel query and grab results from this data
frame.
So that's really awesome.
If you had no idea what I was talking about when I did a sequel and you have no idea what Asterix and
from and where is actually doing.
Don't worry about it because we don't really approach this in the course at all.
There's going to be a little question on the exercises almost like an optional question but as far as
this course is concerned I want you to be aware of it but we're going to be dealing with the pie Sparke
way of interacting for data frame.
Okay that's it for Sparke basics.
Coming up next we're gonna talk about basic operations of Sparke kind of expand what we've been discussing
for these past two lectures.
The next lecture.