Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture on sitting at Paice park.
So this is just an extra lecture based off the press to lectures and if you noticed Right now we can
only use Paice park if we're in the correct Sparke directory folder.
And this lecture will show you a quick way that allows you to import Paice Park from any directories
so don't have to worry about changing directories that SPARC home directory.
Let's jump back to our terminal and show you how to install that fine SPARC library and then use it
to go over to my virtual desktop.
Now OK here I am at the virtual desktop.
Personally I want to do is open up the terminal and see already have it here.
So I'll open up my terminal and the next thing I want to do is show you how right now.
Hi Sparke is working.
So I call Python 3 I hit enter.
Notice that if I ask to import Paice first here I'll get back an error it says No module names Paice
spark.
However if I quit out of this if I move over to spark and then CD into all we can list everything C.D
then it's a python.
And then if I list this and call iPhone 3 here and then say import Paice SPARC.
Now I get no errors.
So the main thing I want to do is instead of having to change directory every time I use this fine SPARC
library that we're going to install to actually do this sort of connection process for me there are
other ways of doing this.
You could just export the paths to your bash RC file but this way is a little more clear and it's a
little easier.
So that's what we're going to do here.
If you're familiar with aboon two systems you can probably just set up an expert pass yourself.
I'm going to quit this so I'm just directly at my terminal and then I'm also going to hit CD.
So I go directly home and I'm going to install this fine SPARC library.
So let me hit clear here so I can clear everything and then I will say Pipp 3 install find SPARC enter
and then it says collecting fine spark and it's going to install it for you.
So now the idea is to actually use to find Sparke to do that connection for us.
So what we need is the actual path to that SPARC home directory.
So let's get it going to list this which shows sparks are going to see into Sparc and then going to
type WD which is going to print my working directory.
So here I have it under home Jose and then Sparke etc. Hadoop.
That's the actual path I want.
So I will copy this.
I'm going to highlight that and then right click and copy now to explore.
How do we can actually use find Sparke.
So I'm going to hit CD again.
So I'm back in my home directory and then I will type python 3.
So right now since I'm at home if I try to import PI SPARC you'll give me an error says no module named
PI spark.
So let's use find the spark to actually make this all work.
I will import fine spark enter and then I'm going to call find spark got in it and then I'm going to
paste my actual stream here of the file paths so I'll put a little quote there for the string say that
it looks like I instantly set this over.
So if hit paste I accidently hit enter there.
So let me try this again find spark got in it.
Quote The actual path and so close parentheses enter.
And now I told find Sparke where it can actually find Sparke for me.
So once I've done that I can hit import.
Spark.
And now it's working even though and that my working directory.
So that's all you have to do and I can use Paice bark from any directory.
So let's go over those key steps again especially because I messed up a little bit here.
All you had to do was check first the import price Sparke work.
If it doesn't if it gives back no module named PI spark then call import.
Spark and then we have to do is pasan this directory appear where your actual Sparke home is.
So if you copy and paste and then hit enter.
You might accidentally get this error which just means you accidently ran that code a little too soon.
Well you have to do is copy and paste it as a string inside of this init call and then say import Paice
part and then everything should be working for you.
So that's it.
I'm going to do this one more time to the Jupiter notebook.
You can feel free to just continue and skip to the next lecture if you're done with this.
But I just want to walk through one more time.
How this would look.
Using the Jupiter notebook system.
So I'm going to quit python here.
And then I'll start my Jupiter note book again I'm starting this directly from the home directory.
And then if this is your first time running Jubran notebook remember you have to copy and paste this
token.
By now this should not be your first time.
So we're going to say new iPhone 3 notebook and then right now if I say import Paice SPARC I should
expect an error.
So I get that error.
Now to use find SPARC to fix it so I will say import fine spark shift enter and then say find spark
in it.
And then I'm going to copy and paste that path to my actual SPARC home shift center and now for import
Paice Fark.
I don't get any issues.
All right that's it.
Make sure you do that.
If you're ever dealing with the lectures and you have this module named PI spark issue you can just
use find Sparke pass in your home directory where spark is located and it should easily fix that.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.