Hello everyone and welcome to the natural language processing code along lecture.
Well we're going to do is work through building a spam detection filter using Python and spark in our
dataset consist of volunteers text messages from a study in Singapore and some spam text messages from
a UK reporting site and we're going to combine these into a data set consisting of these two types of
messages mixed up and then see if we can actually build some sort of filter that can detect a spam message
versus what's known as a ham or good message.
So let's get started.
I'm going to jump over to a new chapter notebook now.
Here I am at a new Jupiter note book and all the data and the actual code that goes along with this
can be found under the natural language processing folder under the spark from machine learning folder.
Well we're going to do is after you start a spark session is import the data will say data is equal
to spark.
Read that C S V and this dataset it's under a folder called S-M as spam collection.
And then under that folder if you start typing with a capital S. there's a spam S-M SS spam collection
and there's actually no that see a city on this the schist that actual file name and all say in first
schema to be true.
And then the lesson you have to do is if you know the data it's actually separated by tabs not by commas.
So you can indicate this with a backslash T.
So we will run this.
Now that we've read in the data if we take a look at what it actually looks like data that show we have
this no header essentially the default is c 0 for column 0 and then underscore C-1 for column 1.
You can see here the actual label is whether it was a ham message or a spam message and then some sort
of sentencing stream.
So let's actually relabel these two columns we'll call one of them a class and the other one text and
we can do that.
It's just grabbing our data and setting it equal to data with column renames just using tab autocomplete
there.
And I'm going to rename the first column underscore the 0 to class and then do with column rename again
on the same object.
To do kind of twice in a row and then we'll say underscore C-1 to be labeled text.
So we'll run that.
And now we show our data we can see here it's called class and text for the actual columns.
All right.
So now we have to do is actually clean and prepare a data using everything that we learned about with
the tools that SPARC comes with.
So we'll start with from Paice spark thought school functions.
Earlier we showed you how you can create a user defined function for length but there's actually already
one included a spark and it's just a length.
So we will say that the data is equal to data and we're going to create a new column will say with column
and we'll call this length and then we'll just apply the length function we just imported the data text
column.
There we go.
And now when we show this we can see here that we have the actual length of this text column.
So it might be interesting to know is to see if there's any major difference between the length of a
ham column versus a spam column and we can actually do that for group by.
So if I come over here and say data and then I group by and I grouped by the class column and then check
the average and then say show what it's going to end up doing is it will average any numerical columns
in this case the length column and it will separate them or group them by class.
So the average length of a ham text message is seventy one point four.
The average length of a spam message is much longer 1:38 so it can already see that there's some sort
of clear difference between the averages in length of a ham column versus spam column.
Meaning this may be a useful feature and this is essentially feature engineering you take a text which
is your raw feature and you feature engineer some other column feature.
In this case the actual length of that text.
So now let's focus more on things that are specific to natural language processing such as tokenization
removing Stoppard's and then the count vectorize or the inverse document frequency and then string indexer.
So a lot of stuff to import here will save from Sparke the M-L feature and I'm going to import tokenizer
also import stopwatches remover count vector Isar and then let's start this on a new line.
Next one's going to do is inversed document frequency and then the string indexer.
OK so we'll run that lips and this is on multiple lines any day princes there.
There we go.
And then let's set it all up.
So we'll have our tokenizer object equal to tokenizer it will have an impact column.
Be text and the output column is going to just be token text.
So we have a tokenizer and then we'll create our stop or remove and that's going to people to a stop
words remover and that's going to take the tokens so that input column here is the token text and hopefully
you can begin to see the pattern here that we're kind of doing this in steps.
And then the output column will call these stop tokens.
So this first tokenizer is going to take that sentence and make it into what is essentially a list of
tokens or words than the stop words or move or is going to take that list of tokens and remove the really
common words that are going to be useful for our analysis.
Then the next thing to do is some sort of count vectorization.
So we will say count vec is equal to count vectorize.
And we'll say input column is equal to the stop tokens.
Or stop token I should say.
And then the output column we'll call this see underscore VEC for Count vectorization.
OK.
After this what we probably want to do is some sort of inverse document frequency so we'll say IDF is
equal to an idea of where that impot column is that C underscore VAK and then that output column is
going to be term frequency inverse document frequency.
OK.
And then we'll say some ham spam to Numeric is equal to a string indexer and it's going to take the
input column of class and then it's going to output column label.
So this very last one the Hamps spam to Gnumeric what this does is it actually focuses on this class
column spark and M-L live in general can't have classes that are labeled as strings.
Other programming languages and other libraries can.
But in this case we need Python and Sparke to basically convert these into numbers so zeros and ones.
And that's exactly what the spam spam tumeric does.
So I'm going to run this and then one going to say from PI sparked by M-L that feature import this vector
assembler.
So I'll run that and then let's clean this all up.
So we'll have Clean-Up be a lips a vector assembler that takes in the input columns of T.F. underscore
IDF and the length column and then finally the output column is just gonna be called features OK.
So essentially are these two features one of them uses all those tools.
The other one which is kind of a simple length test and would be interesting to see if whether or not
we did link that that actually improves our model performance.
So now it's actually time to build the model.
Now it's actually really common for natural language processing when you're doing a classification model
to use something called a naive base model.
And this is where I really want you to feel around to play with this choice of what classification algorithm
to use.
We've learned a lot about different classification algorithms so jump to documentation grab some examples
of different classifications and then import them here and then play around and see what works best
with this dataset.
So essentially we can just do it say from Paice park M-L thought classification import.
And then it hit tab here.
You should be able to see various different classifications some of these are not classification models.
They're just different functions that exist within classification.
You can see here even have a multilayer perception classifier that's almost like a neural net.
So to be interesting and then I'm going to use naive ways that's kind of the classic model to its natural
language processing.
And then I'm going to use all the defaults for it.
So I'll say because these old defaults.
OK.
Now since I have so many steps and all these feature vectors I'm going to use a pipeline and we can
do this by saying from Paice sparked the M-L import pipeline.
Then I'll say data preparation pipe is equal to this pipeline and the first thing I'm going to do is
I'll do this.
Ham spam to Gnumeric so I'll take care of that class called first.
All say the various stages is going to be ham spam to Gnumeric then I need to tokenize the words so
that's my tokenizer then I need to call stop or move then I need to call the count vectorize raiser
then I into the inversed talking a frequency or idea.
And then I need to do my cleanup remember that cleanup is just taking the input columns T.F. idea and
length and outputting features it's all come back down here and let's run that.
So we have our data prep pipeline.
So we're going to do is say cleaner is equal to my data prep pipe and then I'm going to fit it to my
actual data set.
Let that run a little bit and then I'll finally have clean data when I transform it.
And if you want you can do that that fit on the data and that transform on one line.
I like doing it this way because especially when you're teaching it shows kind of the different steps
here.
So all say clear that transform data and then that should be my clean data.
And now it's time for the actual training and evaluation.
So I'll say clean data if I actually show the columns here.
I still have a bunch of columns.
I basically have a column for all those steps.
So what I'm going to do is set it equal to the only columns I want.
So it's a little more organized.
So I will say select the label and you can pass this as a list if you want to if you get errors not
passing as a list.
So have the label in the features and now actually show my data what's clean data show the results.
I can see here I have my label and my features were not my label is zero on one.
OK.
So let's get to splitting this up into a training set and test set.
So we say training test is equal to that new clean data and I'm going to call a random split on this.
Now we can do 17:30 that classic split and then I will finally say my spam detector is equal to my naive
base model that I imported earlier.
Scroll down and fit that to the training data.
And if we actually check out what the data looks like remember our original data pre-print the schema
they had the class the text and the length.
So now let's create some test results.
And set it equal to spam underscore detector and then I'm going to transform my test data run that.
And now we can do is show the results or say test results and show them and I can see here I'm a little
zoomed in but I have the label the features the raw prediction the probability.
And then my prediction.
So I don't really want to compare my label versus the prediction.
So let's do that by using some sort of evaluation metrics and I'll use the multiclass classification
evaluator from PI sparked by MLR evaluation in poor multiclass classification evaluator.
And then let's do an accuracy evaluation will say accuracy.
Val multiclass classification evaluator.
So it's an instance of that.
And then when is going to do is say my accuracy is equal to accuracy evaluation.
And I'm going to evaluate the test results.
Run that and we'll print the results so I'll say accuracy of naive base model and then Prince A.S.C.
run that and it looks like we're getting 91 92 percent accuracy.
Now that's really not bad considering that we're just taking raw tex applying some feature patients
to it and then we actually get a model that can attempt to predict with 92 percent accuracy whether
or not something is spam or him.
So what I really want you to do in lieu of a consulting project is to come back up to this step where
we actually import our classification model.
So right here from Paice sparked the MLA classification of Mornay Baise.
I want you to switch this for other models such as random force or logistic regression or any of the
other classification algorithms that we learn in this course or some of them that we haven't even covered
you can jump straight into the documentation.
Check out the different classification models that are available to play around some of those parameters
and see if we can get even better performance than what we've done here with around 92 percent accuracy.
Now remember accuracy is not the only measure of a modest performance or things like precision recall.
You could also do area under the curve for an Orosi curve etc..
OK.
Hope you enjoy this.
This is kind of a classic example the state of really common for building some sort of spam detection
filter.
But personally I haven't seen online an example using a spark in Python.
So I hope you enjoyed this project.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.