Hello everyone and welcome to part two of the Twitter project for Sparke streaming our next task is
to write a script that will connect to Twitter for streaming and this will be a lifestyle that we're
going to call later on in the Jupiter notebook.
So let's get started.
I'm going to write this all a Jupiter note book but then I will save as a thought PI file.
Ok I can open up a Jupiter note book now.
All right so here I am at a Jupiter note book that's running inside Ubuntu running on a virtual box
and I'm going to write everything into a Jupiter note book but I will download this as a PI file script
that we're going to run later on.
So start off I'm going to import tweet pire tweet pee and then say from tweet prior to the import and
the first one is off händler and I'm choosing tabbed autocomplete and then the next one is just stream.
So we will run that and then actually I also want to import from twe pie streaming in poor stream listener.
And then I also want to import our socket and import Jason.
So those will be imports.
And then I want to also set up my credentials.
So we'll set up some variables consumer key is equal to.
And then we'll leave that as an empty string.
And then consumer underscore secret and that's an empty string and then access underscore token equal
to an empty string.
And then finally access secret to an empty string.
All right.
Now keep in mind you are actually going to have to fill in those strings with your own credential values.
Right now I'm leaving them blank but later on past the video lecture I will actually fill in those.
And so make sure you fill in your consumer key or consumer secret the X token and the access secret
key from the previous lecture.
So I will run that.
Leave them playing for now.
So let's continue on the next thing we're going to do is create a class that will listen to the tweets
themselves and then we'll create one function that actually sends the data through a socket school say
class and we're going to call this class tweet listener and it's going to inherit from streamlets inner
and then we're going to say the F created in it's and say self and it's going to take an A C socket
and then we're saying self taught it will say the client's socket sequel to socket.
Let's make sure I spell that right.
C socket.
There we go.
And the next cigarillos you say the F and create a method called on data that takes in self and data
as a parameter and then we're going to do a bit of a try.
Commands let me scroll down a little bit we see more room and then I'm going to try to do the following.
I'm going to try to create a message that's going to come from Jason load's data so I'm going to load
in the Jaisalmer file and then I'm actually going to print out the message itself.
So the message is under the text and then I'm also going to encode this with UTF 8.
That way if I get emojis and stuff they'll at least show up as blanks instead of causing an error and
then I'm going to say self clients.
Sockets we can just have autocomplete that I'm going to call send and I'm going to send that message
over animals so again going to uncoated with UTF 8 so we could also just make that a variable.
So I wanted to try to do that.
And then if that all worked I'm going to return true if for some reason it didn't work.
I'm going to have some accept call sort of say except that I'm going to say base exception and I'll
call that as E and then I'll print air comma e.
So I was going to print whatever that base exception was in filing to return true here.
OK.
And then that's on data.
If there actually isn't Aircel say on an air and it takes self and status in it's just going to print
the current status and then it's going to return true.
OK so now we're going to let me just run that cell since that's all we need in it.
So now we're going to create one last function and then finally we'll create some code that will actually
run the entire script so we'll create a function called send data.
That takes in a client socket.
So I'll say C underscore socket and we'll set up.
This is basically when I set up our connection so I'll say oh off handler takes in our consumer key.
Whoops takes in our consumer key and takes in our consumer secret
and then we're going to call a method called Access tokens.
X-ists underscore token and that takes in our access token and also takes in our access secret and the
next thing you're going to set up Twitter underscore stream is equal to a stream object with her authorization
and then we'll call an instance of Thweatt listener and Whoops looks like I have a D in there.
So let me fix that up here.
Tweet listener.
I'm going to run that again.
OK.
So tweet listener.
And then we're going to pass in that client socket inside this.
Make sure that princes are balanced.
And then finally we'll call Twitter stream again and I'm going to filter based off a track and you're
going past this is a list of a single string and this is basically the topic.
You can pick.
So essentially we're doing is send data we are connected to Twitter and this Twitter stream we're going
to filter everything by a certain string so whatever string we put in here has to be in the tweet in
order for us to get it.
So you should probably try to pick something that's going to be relatively popular that we are not waiting
forever for the tweets to come in.
Now relatively popular can be super wide said since for so many users on Twitter.
So I will say something like soccer or guitar that's relatively popular.
Try to avoid really hot topics Otherwise you'll get a flood of stuff.
So we have Deif send data and then finally and on to say if name is equal to underscore Maine is essentially
a way you can make files run on say s is equal to SACA socket close Prince he's going to set my host
to be the local host so 6:59 point zero point zero point one.
So it's my local machine learning to open up a port will open up port 5 5 5 5 basically just reserving
a port for a connection service.
I'm going to say estop bind and I'm going to pass on a tuple of the host and the ports and the princes
there how there's two of them.
Then I'm going to print a statement letting it know that it's running.
So I'll say listening on port and I already know my ports $555 person by 5:5 they're.
And then let's put a G in there.
Just when I was running so listening on port 5:55 and then we'll say s listen and we're going to wait
a couple seconds so in this argument you can pass and how many seconds you want to listen.
So say five and then we'll say a little tuple unpacking.
See a DDR at our is equal to estop accepts.
So that will establish connection with the client and then we will finally say send data and then person
C and then run that and we are good to go.
OK.
So upon running this your connection will actually try to attempt to do our thing.
So what we're gonna do is sit kernel interrupts and then going to keyboard interrupt that's that's not
a big issue.
And then I'm also going to clear that up or say cell all output clear.
All right.
So we have everything cleared and they're in Jupiter note book format.
So let's save this into a PI file and then we'll kind of do a quick review through that dot PI file
itself.
I will say file download as pie.
Select it then it's going ask me how do I want to do it to open.
And I say save.
And right now it's called Untitled 9.
Let me actually change that cells at cancell.
Let me view my header and I'm going to call this something like tweet read so I'll a tweet read it.
OK.
Now let me down with this.
The file download as the pie to read that pie that looks good to me I'll select Save file.
OK.
Now it's going to save that file.
So if I head over here now I have this python file.
So let me put that somewhere I can find it.
Actually it fits in the Downloads folder it should be fine.
So Downloads folder.
I'll just remember that it's there is totally fine print desktop wherever.
Just make sure you are able to find that once you're at your terminal.
So you'll see that their tweet read that pie an organ to do is double click this and open it.
And now I can see what it actually looks like.
So notice here because I was using the Juber notebook I have some commented in and out cells but that's
totally OK.
Everything that's here is what we want.
So let's zoom in and explain line by line what's actually happening here.
And I'm going to go back to the Juber notebook to do that.
OK.
So the very first couple of cells we're just importing stuff that we need.
Then when you're ready to go you're going to need to fill out your consumer key consumer secret access
token and access secret key.
So this technically isn't ready yet.
You have to fill it in with your information.
Then we have the tweet Lisner which is essentially going to listen.
So once we actually get a connection with our client data we're going to do is use the Jaison library
to load in that data and we're going to grab that text message and then send it through the socket.
And if there's an exception or some sort of error we're going to print it out and on air you know we're
going to print that particular status of the error then with this send data.
What this is doing is it's using our actual consumer secret keys or access tokens.
It's connecting everything and actually launching the Twitter stream and filtering out those tweets
for whatever keep track you're looking for in this case.
I'm going to look for tweets that have guitars.
Then what I'm going to do is actually run everything with this so we set up the socket.
The host is ready to go.
We have our power locally.
So in my you Pernod pick that I'm going to run later on I can connect to this port 555 and do everything
locally and then is going to send the data to the client socket.
All right.
So I know this kind of a bit overwhelming especially given that this course wasn't technically on Python
in general so a lot of this stuff may be new to you if this was your first Python course ever.
What I would suggest you do is check out the different examples in streaming documentation.
If you want a little more background on this they also have some more documentation on the tweet PI
site for how to actually connect with Twitter.
So if this is something you find yourself are going to be doing a lot.
You can check out a tweet by in fact tweet pi as you can see has a lot of streaming functionality built
into it.
So honestly if you're really interested in streaming from Twitter I would suggest you check out tweet
pie's documentation Web site if you are not doing a whole lot of data from Twitter.
You may be able to kind of skip Sparke completely and just use twe PI and streamlets an hour by itself
and I have to connect that spark in the next lecture or going to do a set up but you brought a notebook
that will be able to connect to tweet live streaming capabilities but it's going to be using SPARC in
order to actually do all the final connection and data evaluation.
All right thanks everyone.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums but I will see you at the next lecture we're
going to set up a we really want the actual chip or notebook that has all the sparks stuff in it.
If you don't really want to type all this out and make sure you got the right one.
Check out the notes.
This is all save this tweet read that pi.
Just as we've done here a tweet read out pi.
I would actually suggest that you kind of follow along here of the video but use the downloaded version
of the dot PI file just to make sure that it accidently make any mistakes.
Remember you have to fill out your own consumer and access keys.
All right thanks everyone and I will see you at the next lecture where we finally create our little
mini dashboard.