Welcome to the overview of Sparke lecture before we begin the set up and coding of python and spark.
Discuss what spark is in the context of big data will begin of a general explanation of what big data
is and then the related technologies.
So again the general things are going to be covering and this lecture is the answer to the question
What does Big Data give an explanation of Hadoop map reduce spark talk about local versus distributed
systems an overview of the Hadoop ecosystem and get an overview of Sparke now on this course when we're
actually coding we'll be working with the spark Python API which comes in the form of a library called
Paice park.
But in order to really understand why you would need to use that and what the purpose of SPARC is and
what problem is trying to solve you need to understand Hadoop and map reduce and the entire big data
ecosystem which is why we're going to talk about that here.
So first off what is Big Data.
Well let's say you have some data that can fit on a local computer somewhere in the scale of 0 to 32
gigabytes maybe even 64 gigabytes depending on how much RAM you have that kind of scale of data is not
big data even if you have somewhere between like 30 and 60 gigabytes.
It's still large enough that conceivably you could buy enough RAM to just fit it all in your random
access memory that's memory that is used when you open up something like an Excel file.
You know everything is stored on RAM and you have quick access to it.
But what do you do if you end up having a larger set of data than what you can hold on to ram.
Well they have a couple of options.
You can try using a sequel database to move storage onto a hard drive instead of RAM.
Or you can use a distributed system something that distributes the data to multiple machines and computers.
And this is where SPARC is going to come into play if you're using SPARC you're at a point where it
no longer makes sense to fit all your data on RAM and it no longer makes sense to fit all your data
into a single machine.
So what is a local system versus a distributed system.
Well a local system is probably what you're used to.
It's just a single machine a single computer.
It all shares the same ram the same hard drive a the Strip it system looks something like what we see
on the right.
You have one main computer some sort of master node and you also have data and calculations distributed
onto the other computers.
And what you can do in a local system versus a distributed system is your local system you'll be limited
to however many cores are on your local system.
That is how much processing power or how much storage you have locally.
But in a distributed system what you can do is leverage the power of a bunch of weaker machines to eventually
have more corps and more capabilities than even a strong local single machine.
So we can see here on the local machine we have four cores but what we can do if distributed machines
is get a bunch of weaker servers or weaker machines with less power but distribute either the data and
the calculations across all them as machines to take advantage of a distributed system which is kind
of at the crux of what SPARC is trying to do.
So a local process will use the computation resources of a single machine widely distributed process
has access to the computational resources across a number of machines connected through some sort of
a network.
And after a certain point it's much easier to scale out to many lower CPQ machines in the distributed
system than try to scale up to a single machine with a high CPQ and distributed machines also have the
advantage of easily scaling.
All you have to do is just add more machines versus a single computer no matter how nice it is there
there's going to be a limit on how much RAM or how much storage you can add to a single machine.
So if distributed machines you can just keep adding systems to the network and just get more power that
way.
And they also include fault tolerance which is really important when you're talking about large data
sets.
If one machine fails the whole network can still go on which you can't do on a local machine if your
local machine crashes due to some error in the calculation that well that's it you just lost all your
calculations all your data and fault tolerance is a fundamental idea where you're going to be replicating
your data across multiple machines so even if one goes down your calculations and your data still persists
and goes on.
Now let's discuss the typical form of a distributed architecture that uses something like Hadoop so
Hadoop is a way to distribute very large files across multiple machines.
The issue of taking one large file and storing it onto one machine isn't really that complicated of
a task was quite trivial.
But the idea of grabbing a really really large file that no longer sits on one machine and distributing
it in a way that makes sense across multiple Sheens was quite a complicated issue back in the day and
that's what led to the creation of Hadoop which uses the Hadoop distributed file system or HFS and you
may have seen that term HD effect when you've read stuff on big data and HD FS allows a user to work
with really large data sets across a distributed system.
What's also super important about HFS it duplicate blocks of data for fault tolerance which is the idea
if one machine goes down in your system your data is duplicated on some other machine.
So it still continues.
It also uses what's known as map reduce and map reduce allows computations on that distributed data.
So it can have two fundamental ideas here Hadoop sheeted file system which is the way that we get a
really large dataset distributed across multiple machines and then we have the idea of map reduce which
allows computations across the distributed data set.
So for distributed storage you have something that looks like this.
Again you have some sort of master node or a named node has its own C-p its own RAM and that basically
controls the process of either distributing the storage or the calculations to these other something
known as slave nodes.
These other data nodes are their own super and own RAM.
So what the effect does is it uses blocks of data with a size of 128 megabytes by default.
And each of these blocks is replicated three times and the blocks are distributed in a way support fault
tolerance.
So a machine can go down but your data will go on so smaller blocks provide more paralyzation during
processing and multiple copies of a block prevent loss of data due to the failure of a node and a map
reduce is a way of splitting computational tasks to a distributed set of files such as Hadoop distributed
file system and it consists of a jog tracker and multiple task trackers.
And this idea of trackers is also going to go on with Sparke.
So in the context of map reduce the job tracker sends code to run on the task trackers and then the
task trackers allocate the CPI in memory for the tasks and monitor the tasks on these worker nodes.
So what we cover can be thought of in two distinct parts using the first distribute large datasets and
then using map reduce to distribute a computational task to a distributed dataset.
And next we're going to do is learn about the latest technology in this space.
That second half of it known as SPARK and spark improves on the concepts of using distribution so we're
going to continue talking this lecture just an abstract overview of spark spark versus map reduce what
sparked already these are and then spark data frames spark is one of the latest technologies being used
to quickly and easily handle big data.
It is an open source project on Apache So you have access to all the source code and it was first released
in February 2013 and has exploded in popularity due to its ease of use and its speed.
And it was created at the app lab at UC Berkeley.
And you can think of Sparke as a flexible alternative to map reduce.
So don't think of it in the concepts of Hadoop versus SPARC but instead of map reduce versus spark and
spark and use data stored in a variety of formats including things that are stored on Sandra AWOS S3
storage Hadoop distributed file system and more.
Now let's take a little bit of time to discuss the idea of SPARC versus map reduce this does dive in
a little bit into semantics because sometimes people phrase things in a way that's a little bit confusing.
But I want you to get the idea that it's SPARC versus map reduce not SPARC versus do.
So a lot of times you'll hear that discussion of Hadoop map reduce versus Sparc and then people kind
of shorten that to Hadoop versus Spart but that's not really a good analogy or comparison.
But let me explain why sometimes people say Hadoop map reduce and then just shorten it to Hadoop.
The reason is map reduce remember that's the half that actually distributes the calculation.
It requires files to be stored in Hadoop distributed file system.
So because of that people tend to put Hadoop in map reduce together as kind of a single phrase.
And then when they discuss SPARC they'll say Hadoop versus SPARC but really it's map reduce that you're
comparing with SPARK.
Spark can use Hadoop striated file system which is why it doesn't really make sense to say SPARC versus
Hadoop by itself because SPARC can actually work with the Hadoop disputer file system but SPARC can
also work with a wide variety of data formats.
Which is why we kind of always hook up Hadoop with map reduce.
But SPARC can work with not just Hadoop distributed file system but quite a wide variety of file formats.
But more importantly spark can also perform operations up to 100 times faster than map reduce.
And that's one of the big selling points of spark and that's what you hear a lot of times when you're
reading about Sparke online.
So the question is how does it actually achieve the speed 100 times faster.
Is a huge increase in performance.
Well map reduce writes Most data to disk after each map and reduce operation Sparke will keep most of
that data in memory.
That is something like Ramm after each transformation and spark can spill over to disk if the memory
is filled so if you don't have enough RAM on that single local machine it can spill over to the hard
drive.
But the main idea here is that as computers and ram have gotten cheaper it makes sense to just put everything
on to ram instead of writing and reading to the hard drive.
And that's one of the main differences between spark and map reduce as kind of an high level overview
now stuck about just SPARC in particular at the core of SPARC is the idea of an already very resilient
distributed data set and really at the stream that data set or our DD has four main features a distributed
collection of data fault tolerance parallel operation the ability to be partitioned and the ability
to use many data sources not just be limited to something like Hadoop subunit file system.
So what does it actually look like.
Well usually you have something that looks actually really similar to the map reduce framework that
we talked about earlier.
You have some sort of driver program in a spark context or even a spark session.
When we talk about SPARC 2.0 and you have some sort of cluster manager and then you're working nodes
that distributed system.
Now what does this actually look like.
Physically we'll have something that looks like this a bunch of servers somewhere or maybe AWOS is your
provider of them.
You just link to them online.
You have this master node and sending back tasks and the slaves sent back results.
And on those worker nodes are sometimes called Slave nodes.
They have the data cache to ram slash disk so these are immutable lazily evaluated and cashable and
there's basically two types of SPARC operations.
There's transformations and actions transformations are basically a recipe to follow and then actions
actually perform what the recipe says to do and then return something back and this behavior of transformations
versus actions also carries over to the syntax when coding a lot of times when you write a method a
call off of a data frame which are going to be working with Paice SPARC you won't see anything as a
result until you call in action something like show.
And this makes sense because if you're working with a really large data set you don't want to constantly
be calculating all the transformations maybe transformation can be something like take the average or
take the count of particular data or show me where column x is greater than the number 2 x that are
like that.
But you don't want to actually calculate that every time until you're sure you want to perform it because
it's such a huge dataset.
It's quite a task to calculate everything every time you type something.
So that's why everything is separated between transformations and then those calls to action.
And we'll see this more when we actually begin coding of Pi Spahr and Sparke data frame's Now there's
one last point of confusion that arises that I want to clear up right now when discussing the spark
syntax that is what you're actually going to be coding the syntax of the code you type into a keyboard.
You will often see our DD syntax versus data frame Syntec show up.
Now with the release of SPARC 2.0 SPARC is moving towards what's known as a data frame based syntax.
So if you work with something like pandas or R or maybe even like an Excel spreadsheet those are more
like data frame you have columns and rows.
But keep in mind that the way the files are being distributed physically can still be thought of as
an RFID.
The resilient distributed data set your data is still being stored in a resilient distributed manner.
So art is still the way it's happening physically.
Just the syntax of what you're working with is now called data.
So it's just the type that syntax that is changing.
All right so we covered a lot but I don't want you to worry if you didn't memorize all these details
or if a lot of this went over your head and left you maybe a little confused.
We're going to cover a lot of this again and again as we learn more about how to actually code of Python
how to code a spark and utilize all these ideas.
They should just give you kind of a very high level understanding of what a distributed system looks
like.
Why we actually phrase things as SPARC versus map reduce and maybe how SPARC works of art these really
sort of very high level.
But again don't worry if you don't memorize all this will going to cover this a lot more as we continue
coding throughout the course.
Okay.
So a quick now on Sparke data frames which is what we're going to really focus here in the course Sparke
data frames are now the standard way of using Spark's machine learning capabilities and Sparke data
from documentation is still pretty new and can be a little sparse.
I think it's actually getting better so we'll take a brief tour of the documentation just to show you
what you can expect and how we're going to cover this course and it kind of blend in the documentation.
So you have the skills to reference that documentation because it could be a little mysterious at first.
So I'm going to jump over to spark that especially the org in my browser and you can just Google Sparke
or Apache and it'll probably take you there and we're going explore the documentation together for just
a little bit.
All right here I am at Sparks that a patch that you can already see here.
They tell you that it can run programs up to 100 times faster.
And note here it says Hadoop map reduce not just Hadoop and it runs even 10 times faster on disk.
That's when it goes to the harddrive and it's also ease of use so we can write applications in not just
Java or Skala but we can also do it in Python and our.
And as I mentioned we're going to be working with Python in this course and then also a generality so
it can combine sequel streaming in complex analytics etc. but it's going to scroll up here and talk
about where we're going to be working with.
This course is a work with SPARC 2.1.
And if you click here on the latest release documentation it'll take you to link a spark overview.
And this work kind of describes downloading many examples in the show launching on a cluster where to
go from here QuickStart etc..
And as we explore Sparke more and more are eventually going to run into what's known as data frame's
data sets and sequel.
This is going to be one of the first things we cover and this is essentially the way you can work with
Sparke with dataset so basic data analysis cleaning up your data manging data were going to be working
with Sparke sequel Ensberg data frames and essentially spurts sequel.
Is this platform where we build on top of ticket data sets and data frames.
And the reason it's called Sparke sequel is because it has the ability to execute sequel queries so
if you already know sequel you're going be able to use that sequel knowledge to filter out your data
base off a sequel query and we'll cover that later on in this course.
And as you continue on through the documentation you know there's these nice little tabs that show you
the Skala Java Python and equivalent our code.
Now not every operation is available in every language.
Now something that we haven't really discussed yet is that SPARC itself is not a programming language
it's just a framework for dealing with large data and distributing it and doing those calculations across
a distributor network SPARC itself is written in a programming language known as Skala.
So the Skala API for Sparc is the one that gets the latest features which makes sense because SPARC
has literally written in Scala.
It's going to get the latest features.
Now Skala is actually written in Java so Java a lot of times also gets a lot of the latest features.
The API has for Python and are are usually a little bit behind all the latest stuff.
So keep that in mind.
A lot of the more advanced things are the latest technologies with SPARC.
Sometimes it takes maybe one generation or one more release cycle to get to Python and then maybe inexorably
cycle to get to our creating data frames all this stuff and kind of see here it looks like a table we're
going to be covering this an entire section talking about data frames.
The last programming I do want to show you is this Madlib guide and if you click on that you basically
see the machine learning library right.
And this is something we're going to be referencing a lot throughout the course especially in that second
half on machine learning.
But you will also notice it has this RTT based API guide and this is kind of what I was referencing
when I talked about ardy the syntax versus data frame syntax.
And there's this big announcement with SPARC 2.0 are already on 2.1.
The data frame based API is the primary API which is why we're going to be focusing exclusively on the
data base the API.
And honestly it's a lot easier to work with that makes a lot more sense than the ARDE based API so it's
a welcome change and you can see here you can click on the main guide or check out particular topics
maybe you're interested in clustering So you click on clustering or it's in and k means click here.
It gives you some information about Kamins and Shoji examples for Escala Java Python and are.
So that's definitely stuff we're all going to be talking about and focusing on a lot more in the second
half of the course when we talk about machine learning.
But I do want you to know that the documentation is all here for you.
It's pretty good for Emelin.
Maybe you're a student collaborative filtering say come over here.
Scroll down.
They show you a full example but they also have the API documentation.
So click here on Python.
This will take you to the API docs.
So come over here Sparke sequel functions.
That's something we're going to be using a lot and then it tells you basically the pure API as close
as it can to the actual source code without clicking here where it says source if you click on that
then we'll actually take you to the source code itself for further explanation.
Now usually we'll just re ref referencing the documentation not the actual API docs.
This is more of a heavy duty especially if you're hitting the source code button but this is about as
far as we're going to get if you ever have questions or want to dive deeper into what certain functions
do.
You can check with the API docs.
All right.
So I know there was a lot but hopefully that kind of clears up some misunderstandings of spark and where
we're going to be using it.
What's its purpose.
Cetera.
I will see you in the next lecture will probably discuss how to actually install setup and get everything
running on your computer.
I'll see you there.