Welcome to the solutions lecture for the K means clustering consulting project.
Let's open a new Jupiter notebook and get started.
All right.
I have the consulting project notebook open here and I'm going to scroll down and create a new cell
and get started.
First we want to do is say from Paice park import sparked session and then we're going to create a spark
session just as we've done before in the past.
So our main idea is to try to figure out whether it was two hackers or three hackers based off of this
key piece of evidence where they alternate hack Scofield's 100 total hacks and there's two hackers should
be 50 hacks 100 total hacks there's three hackers there should be thirty three hacks and hopefully Kamins
clustering can help us with that.
So let's create our cluster and then envoy's they get or create.
OK so what I'm going to do is load up our data set in our data set.
Isn't there a spark read C S V and it's the hack underscored data set.
So hack underscore data that CXXVIII.
And we're going to say header's true and that in first schema is also true.
It can put that on any line.
OK so now that we have our data set we can see an example row from it.
So we'll say data set our head.
See the following.
So we have the session connection time that bytes transferred whether or not Kelly trace was used.
Servers corrupted and these are all Americal except for the location.
But remember the location.
The forensic engineer said that it was probably useless because we're using a VPN.
So will actually be able to drop that and ignore it.
So let's begin by importing what we need from Paice Parker m-L.
So I'll say from Paice park M-L thought clustering
import Kamins and then we're also going to do is import vector assembler from PI SPARC M-L feature import
vector assembler.
And now let's actually grab the data set columns for our similar object within the past and we want
all of these except location because unsupervised learning.
There's no label here and I'm going to pass this in I'll say feature columns is equal to and then just
grab these paste them here and then I'm going to remove location.
So I'll run that and then I'm going to create an assembler object called assembler.
And it's a vector assembler and it takes the input column.
And then I'm just going to type in feature calls and then the output column is going to just be called
features.
So I'll run that and then I'm going to transform my data.
So I get a final dataset.
So my final data is equal to this assembler object transforming my actual dataset so we're run that.
And if we take a look at my final data it can print it schema and I should be able to see the final
features column.
OK so there's my features column and it's a vector.
So it's ready to go.
And just to be safe let's practice scaling everything.
Although we probably don't need to do it for this particular dataset.
So it is a good idea to get some practice in.
So I'll say from page sparked the MLA feature import standard scaler and then I'll create a scalar object
called scaler.
So that my standard scaler there and the input column expected is features and then the output column
expected is going to be called skilled features.
So we're run that and now we want to do is scale the actual data.
So I'll say my scaler model is equal to that scalar object and I'm going to fit it to my final data
and then what I'm also going to then do is take that and say cluster final data is equal to that scalar
model.
Transform on that final data.
So let's run this.
Make sure it works.
And there we go.
So now if I see my cluster final data and print the schema I have all the way down at the bottom.
My scaled features which is what I'm going to be using for the actual training and if I wanted to I
could just select those.
Or I could just passen everything and my actual algorithms will only be looking for skilled features.
OK.
So our main task is to figure out was it two hackers or three hackers.
And hopefully that gives you a hint that you should be creating two Kamins models one for cables two
and one for Keiko's three.
So let's do that say k means two is equal to k means and make sure we've imported this came in India
and we're going to pass in the feature columns expected to be scaled features and they will specify
that cosmical the two here are going to copy this and paste this but change the K value to be 3 so Kamins
to Kamins 3.
And then we're going to do is create the model so model K-2 is equal to k means 2.
And then we will fit it to that final cluster data base or cluster final data.
And I'm going to copy this and paste this.
Now we're going to do the exact same thing here except this will now be for Keiko's 3 so will run that.
All right.
Now comes for the trickiest part trying to figure out if it was two hackers or three hackers.
And the key to this entire thing is a specific hint.
If you come back up here it was that they should have roughly the same amount of tax.
Which means if we were clustering these into three groups and two groups we could check against the
predictions grouped them by their actual prediction values and then just do a count to see if there
was three even groups or two even groups.
So will scroll all the way back down and check this out.
So we'll do is say model K3 will transform that cluster final data.
So if I take a look at this I just do that then I have a data frame and then I can say for example selects
the actual prediction column
and then show this and then we have predictions.
So the first ones are all zeros but you get the idea.
So what I'm going to end up doing is saying cluster final data group by that prediction column and I'm
going to zoom out just a little bit so we can see this whole command.
So model K3 transform cluster final data group by prediction.
And then what I'm going to end up doing is a count on this.
And then let's show the result.
So this may take a little bit of time but there you have it.
OK so we have three groups here.
Hacker one hacker two and then hackers zero.
And you can see the counts 88 79 167 counts may have differed a little bit but overall you can see that
these are not even looks like hackers 0.
If it's grouped this way has an uneven amount of hacking meaning as far as the behavior goes it's not
an even split.
So let's try this exact same thing except we're going to do is call it with K-2.
So we will run this.
And now we get the actual truth which is here we have an exact even split 167 between 1 and 0.
And you can kind of tell what happened when you went from cake was to teacake was three and you can
basically see what happened here.
It grabbed one of the hackers at two and then if you push the cake three it split it into another two
hacking sessions which essentially kind of dictates that it should have been just two hackers because
we have the even counts here of 0 and 1 versus three hackers where there are uneven counts.
OK.
Hopefully that makes sense if you have any questions on this.
Feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
I know this was a bit of a stretch from what we'd done before even with consulting projects in the past
but I hope you enjoy this specific challenge because you have to think about how you could actually
grab the predictions and then do the group buying counts in order to clarify whether the groups were
even or not.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next section.