Welcome back to three of the Python crash course.
We're going to end things here by talking about functions and some special methods you can use off of
Python objects.
Let's jump back to that Jupiter notebook and finish up.
All right let's start off by talking about functions and how you can create your own custom functions.
The key word in creating a function is DPF and then whatever you want to call the function.
So I'll say my underscore for you and see for func and it's going to be a really simple function it's
not going to take any parameters.
We have a colon there and then whatever you want to have happen when you call the functions of for example
Prince hello and then make sure to run this.
So now the function has been defined I can see here the cells been run and then I can actually call
my phunk and I see hello back.
Now a common point of confusion sometimes is you'll just type my phunk run this in a Will report back
what the function actually is so they'll say oh my funk that well that's a function.
So then the main file thought my phunk.
Do you actually want to do it if you want to execute the function how does open and close parentheses
there.
If you would like to add parameters to a function.
For example let's give a parameter a name then it will take for example Hello and a simple way can pass
that in is plus name.
So now I'm going to run this redefine it and then say my func and passen Jose Ferrer and this says Hello
Jose.
So it's stewing is concatenating strings together so that's a little special method you can use for
strings and I can add a space in there run these two again.
Now I see.
Hello Jose.
If I don't actually provide one here I will get an error.
They'll say type error intellectually say hey I'm missing one required positional argument called name.
If you want to have a default parameter or argument value you can just say names equal to and we'll
say for example No-Name and then I'm going to run this.
And now if I just pass this in a Jose it will still work.
Say Hello Jose.
But if I for some reason forget it's going to go to the default value so I can run this and I'll say
hello No-Name.
And that's the basics of functions and a real quickly if you want to have a docstring in your function
you can do it with a set of triple quotes.
These can be either double or single.
And this is where you can describe what the function does so I can say something like this.
Print outs the username and then I'm going to shift enter to run that.
And now with my own function I can do shift tab and they'll say the signature of the function and then
the docstring.
This prints out the username so I can see here that it actually looks for the documentation for this
function.
Whenever I call shift tab which is kind of a nice feature.
All right so let's actually show you one last function that will kind of show a more realistic example
so I'll say the square and it takes in some value X and then it's going to return x.
So what's the difference between Prince and return.
So print just displays the actual value return allows you to save the actual object or whatever the
function happens to do and save it to a variable.
So my little function here Square is going to take some sort of number x and then it's going to return
the square of it.
So I'm going to say result is equal to square of two.
And then if I check on my results I notice that it's four.
So if the return keyword I can actually save this as a variable if I just printed this.
So if I just said Prince and put that there then what would have happened was I would get none back
so if I rerun these I get back nothing.
As a result.
So no says result is equal to square 2.
And when I run this it prints it out.
But then when I ask for what result was it's actually none.
And if it's check the type of result they'll say it's a non type.
The reason for that being is that they only printed out the value for it didn't actually return it.
And the only way I can save is if I return it.
So the only way I can do the assignment to a new variable is by using that keyword return then rerunning
all this.
Notice how I run this again.
I don't actually see the printout result because I was returning it in order to save it to this variable
result which means I have four.
And if I check the type of result now I get this integer type OK.
Now let's discuss lambda expressions lambda expressions.
It's just the way you can quickly type an anonymous function.
That's also another name for it.
Essentially if you only plan on using a function one time maybe you don't want to rewrite the entire
function.
Give it a formal name if you want something kind of quick and easy.
So the way you can do that is for example if I had the ref will call this times 2 it takes in some variable.
They are.
And then it's going to return the r times to.
So for example I can say times 2 and notice I use tabbed out of complete that so it's a little faster.
So it says times 2 and it returns 20 for me.
Notice that it's returning it not printing it out.
So I have that a little out next that cell.
The way I can use the land expression to rewrite this is the following.
Use the land the key word the input colon and then you want what you want the output to be.
So for example V-A are times two.
And now this will behave really similar to the function.
For now it's not really clear how to use these when they use these along another outside function.
So we'll talk about this later on the course when it shows up but I just want you to be aware of what
the land expression is essentially an anonymous function.
So it's a different way of rewriting this whole thing in just one go.
But the issue here is I can only call this one time I don't have a name assigned to it.
So what's the actual relationship between this and this.
Well I can of convert this function to show you first thing I need to do is take away the name take
away this the key word replace it with lambda take away these print seize take away the return keyword
and then put it all in one line and that's never a function to the lambda expression.
And later on throughout the course if we ever use the land expression I'll touch a little more detail
and how we actually use this.
I just want you to see it for now.
All right.
Moving along I want to talk about a few methods that are going to be useful to you throughout the course.
So methods on strings when you create a string called Esty and it's going to say hello my name is Sam
with a capital S..
Do you ever want a lower case.
Everything in a string and just say estopped lower close parentheses here and it returns back everything
lower cased in that string.
So notice here s on Sam has been lower case we've seen upper before it's exact same thing.
The upper case is everything.
A really useful method is split which is going to splits by default on whitespace and return a list.
So it splits that string into a list based off the whitespace.
If you actually want to split on a particular string value you can clarify that as well.
For example I'm going to create a tweet here.
And later I will see how we can do Sparke streaming for tweets but I'm going to say hello.
Hash tag sports run that and then I'm going to if I just say splits by default it splits on whitespace
so it splits.
Hello.
And the hash tag sports but maybe I actually want to split on hash tags so I want to analyze Twitter
somehow.
Well I can just pasan hash tag there and then it's going to split on the hash tag.
And notice how the hash tag is no longer in this list because that is what was split on and then if
I want to grab the actual item from this that was in the hash tag.
Assuming that the hash tag is all the way at the end I could just say something like negative one and
then that returns a string sports.
Obviously not every case will have a hash tag although at the end of the string.
But this kind of just show you a little more realistic example of how you can actually use split OK.
A couple of more things I want to show you is how you can grab the keys and items of a dictionary.
So just quickly now if I create a dictionary with K-1 the one so key one value one and then maybe K
to the two.
If I don't grab all the keys in the dictionary I can just say that keys and I get this dictionary keys
where I see K-1 K-2 followed to grab all the items I can just grab these kind of tuple item pairs so
K-2 V-2 K-1 of one note that the order here is not retained.
Again dictionaries not retain any order.
We won't actually see these.
Basically all throughout the course but just something to be aware of in case why are you using a stack
overflow or something you kind of run into these on your own.
Finally I want to show how you can pop something off of the list or check if something is inside of
a list.
I'll say my list is to 1 2 3 if I want to grab and remove the last item in a list I can say a new variable
last is equal to my list and then say Pop close princes and if I check my list it's missing that last
item that number three and I've saved it to this variable last so that you can remove an item from a
list.
At least the last item if you want to remove an item at a specific index you can just pass that into
pop.
So for example it's redefined my list again as 1 to 3.
So if I check my list I have all three numbers there.
And then I want to pop off the first element a pop and then pass in the index zero to indicate that
I want to pop off the first element and I'm going to save that as now first run this I can check my
list just have two and three and then I can check first and it's one if I don't I check if an item is
inside of a list.
I can just use the in operator so I can say X in 1 to 3 that returns false.
If I ask for one in the list one to three that returns true.
So I could also say something like two in my list that I defined earlier and that also returns true
because my list is now 2 and 3.
Coming up next we have a really quick review exercise notebook that's optional in case you just want
to clarify and make sure that you really understood everything we're talking about here are totally
optional you have to do it but it would be a quick review just to confirm that you understood everything
and you're ready to go to.
Talking about Sparc and Python and data frames and all that cool stuff.
Thanks everybody and I'll see you at the next lecture.