Hello everyone and welcome to this example solution lecture for the linear regression consulting project.
Well we're going to be doing is walking through and coding along an example solution for the linear
regression consulting project.
If you do it another way that's totally fine.
This is just a example of one possible solution.
Let's hop over.
Create a new notebook and get started.
OK.
So the first thing you have to do regardless of whatever approach we take is start a spark session and
get the data.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We'll say from Paice spark that sequel import a spark session and then we'll say spark is equal to spark
session builder app name and then we'll call this app crews and we'll say it gets or creates and the
next thing we're going to do is actually read in the data.
So hopefully you recognize that it's a C S V file.
So all I have to do is say sparked thought read that yesterday and we should also infer schema to be
true as well as header to be true.
So we're run that analysis and then we want to do is print out schema that just to get a taste of things
here so we can see we have the ship name as a string.
The cruise line it belongs to is also a string.
The age is an integer.
We have the tonnage the passenger's length cabinets passenger density and crew.
So we see that we have all these numerical concepts here and we have two strings.
The ship name and the cruise line.
So we take a look at some of the first entries so let's say the head of 5 and let's actually say for
ship in the head of 5 we will print ship and then print a new line.
This is just so it looks a little nicer for us here.
So let's run that.
OK.
So I can see that ships have various names.
Journey Quest celebration etc. but the cruise lines sometimes are shared.
So we have one cruise line here with multiple ships.
The Carnival Cruise Line has the ship's celebration the ship conquest etc. and when we note it here
is that the cruise line may have an effect on how many crew members we need.
So maybe certain cruise lines try to increase the number of crew members or certain cruise lines compared
to others have fewer crew members.
So that's something we want to explore.
But since it's a string argument or a categorical data point we're going to need to use the indexer
to convert it.
If you weren't able to figure that out on your own no problem there's still plenty of information here.
That's totally numerical and lines up with the examples we worked through earlier.
We can see here the age of the ship how large the ship is and tonnage how many passengers can hold the
length of the ship.
Number of cabins.
Passenger density.
Those are all things that intuitively would relate to the actual number of crewmembers needed.
So if you have more passengers or your ship is larger or there's more density of passengers on the ship
you're going to need more crew members.
And likewise if you have less of that stuff you probably need less crew members.
But let's convert this cruise line feature into some sort of numerical value that our algorithm can
understand because the algorithm cannot understand directly something like carnival or Asmara whatever
etc..
So let's come down here and we're going to do is work with dealing with that cruise line categorical
variable.
So let's just see how many cruise lines we have in general and what I can do is say group by that cruise
line and it's Cruise underscore line column.
And I just want to counts and then show the results there.
So what this is going to do is it's going to group by the cruise line and then show the count and I
can even order this if I wanted to.
But I can see here that it looks like there's quite a few cruise lines and what I can also see is that
certain cruise lines have a lot of ships and certain cruise lines have way less ships.
That's something we may want to explore later on but it's worth it especially because that client Hyundai
heavy industries indicated that this may be an important feature which is why we're going to explore
it further.
So what we can do is you stream indexer to try to convert these various cruise line names into just
number groups so 0 1 2 3 etc..
So let's try to do that.
Well we're going to do is say from Paice sparked the M-L feature import string indexer and then I'm
going to create an object called indexer and this is essentially going to look really similar to a vector
assembler object so we're going to say input column is cruise line and loops and then say output column
output call is will say Crewe's underscore cat.
So cruise category and then what I will say is indexed is the indexer.
And then you fit the indexer to the data frame and then you can also then transform this.
So I'm doing this all in one step but you could separate the two lines.
So if you wanted to you could take this object and then on another line do the transformation.
I'm just doing it here on one line.
These two steps.
So then we're going to do here say well show indexed at 5 rows of show ones.
We'll need to see one in here I can see the ship name journey cruise line.
And then if I come all the way over here I can see this particular cruise category is now assigned that
number 16.
If I see something like cruise at 3 we continue down we can see again this same cruise line.
It's category 16 But if you're on Carnival Cruise Line your cruise category number one.
So now that's a numerical value that the algorithm can use versus just this string value.
Now there's definitely different ways to deal if string categorical information.
Beyond this you can separate this out into what's known as dummy variables.
So when you have a single column indicating yes or no for every cruise line but we're going to keep
things kind of loose and just set it as some numerical category here.
This is not the most optimal way to deal with this but it should be enough for our particular use case
especially since we have so much more numerical data here.
All right.
So continuing on don't worry if you were able to figure that out.
We'll discuss working categorical data much more in future lectures.
But we're going to do now is move on to working with the vector assembler and just getting our linear
regression working.
So I will say from Paice barked the M-L Lin owls import vectors and then from PI sparked the M-L that
feature in your vector assembler so that's what we've seen earlier.
And then if I look at the indexed columns.
So that's my new data frame that now has this cruise category.
I can see the actual columns that I want to include.
So what I will end up doing is creating an assembler object and Goines said equal to the vector assembler.
And I want to define my impact columns.
So what I always like to do is copy and paste these.
So I don't want the cruise line and I want the ship name the ship name is just some arbitrary string.
The cruise line have already converted to this cruise category and I don't want the crew column.
So I'm going to do is copy all of this and then make sure to get rid of crew because crews what I'm
trying to predict it's not a feature.
And now I'm good to go.
So notice that age column tonnage passenger's length cabins pastorate density and then a cruise category.
Those are my input feature columns.
And then my output call is going to be just features.
So let's run that and let's make sure we wrote that right by saying output is equal to that assembler
object and transform indexed into that.
OK.
The reason we have to do index and not data is because remember index is the one with the cruise categories.
So we can do now is check it out and make sure we're good to go.
So when you say output select features and then crew and show the results here so I can see how my various
features and then my label column which is just crew great and we can also see that certain ships that
are basically exact same make and model have a certain number of crew.
So that's good to know here as we explore this data further.
So continuing along let's create our final data which is going to be equal to output select and all
I care about is that features column and that crew call them and here that I'm not passing it in as
a list that shouldn't be necessary but in case you're getting errors for certain versions of SPARC you
may need to do a list like this.
OK.
So moving along and the train data split are trained to split I should say and we'll grab our final
data and do a random split on it am I going to split it into a 70 30 mix and let's explore that train
data.
So I'm going to ask it to be described and then show it.
So it may training data have 103 ships.
That's not so bad.
And then in my test data we're going to describe this show the results and then I have 55 ships that
are going to be using for testing.
So we're going to do now is finally build our our linear regression model from Paice sparked the M-L
regression.
I want to import a linear regression object and let's create a linear regression model object.
So I will call this ship L R and I will set it equal to linear regression.
But I also need to specify that my column my label column at least is going to be crew come back up
here remember that we have features but we also have crew instead of label.
So we need it select that so I'll come over here say Larry Gration label column's crew run that and
then offer this ship.
LR I'm going to say let's say trained ship model is going to be equal to ship.
How are men going to fit this to my training data.
So that that's fit to my training data I can check out my training ship model train ship model and now
I can evaluate my test data and then do this ship results run that and let's check out our ship results
so I can just check out things like the root mean squared air.
And I can see them I mean square error here is zero point six seven.
Now remember the units here if I take a look at my actual data.
So for example my training data and let's say the scribe show.
So we can actually the crew count the crew count is in counts of 100 of the mean value being around
seven point seven.
So as always this root mean squared error is meaningless unless you compare it to the actual crew values
so crew values were in those units.
I believe it was in hundreds and you can see here that the mine was seven point seven standard deviation
3.6 five men beings are 0.5 9 Max being 21.
So the roomie's squirter is actually looking pretty good.
Now let's go ahead and check out some other metrics we can call ship results.
And check out our R-squared values to see how much of the variance explained.
And in this case we're explaining quite a bit of the variance.
Is there a point 9:5 now pending on how your random split occurred you may be explaining a little less
or a little more.
I would suspect that given whatever random split you did you should have achieved at least 0.8 R-squared
of value in the actual solutions note book when I was running this the first time I achieved around
0 8 6 because there is a random split here if we come up here.
So because of this random split on 0.7 and 0.3 depending on two things one.
Actual random splits you end up doing.
And to what values you choose here your results may differ than mine.
So if you have less training data you're going to be a little less accurate.
But keep in mind your results won't be exactly as shown in the solutions.
No but Or in this video because of this random split.
So coming back down we've got a really good R-squared value and a pretty darn good root mean squared
error and we can continue to analyze different things about this.
For example who wanted the mean square error that could grab the ship results and then call mean square
error.
There's also an absolute error that we can check out so say mean absolute error and that's 0.5 3.
Now as I mentioned in the previous CO-2 long lecture if you're getting really good results on things
like root mean squared error and you're getting a really high R-squared value it's always a good idea
to kind of do a reality check on your results.
Does it make sense to you getting this good of a model now in this case.
This data is actually real it's not artificially created.
This is real data on real ships gotten from the U.S. machine learning repository that's UC Irvine machine
learning repository online.
So what we can do to kind of do a reality check on these results is see if the two columns are any two
columns are really highly correlated.
So things I can do is check is the number of crew highly correlated with the number of passengers on
board or as a number of crew highly correlated with the number of cabins on board.
If those things are true then it makes sense that my model performed really well because there's two
columns that are really highly correlated with the thing I'm trying to predict.
So let's do that.
I will say from pi pi spark dot sequel dot functions in poor c o r r and that stands for the Pearson
correlation which is basically just a way of saying how related are these two columns.
And what I'm going to do is if I take a look at my original data frame.
So let's make sure it did save it under DMF.
OK so I did.
So I want to check if in my original data is this crew column really related to things like the cabins.
So we'll see if select and then I'll pass on the correlation and I'll pass in the crew column as well
as the passengers column.
And let me show the results here.
So I can see here based off these results that these two columns are highly correlated with one being
perfect correlation so 0.9 one does signify high correlation which makes sense just intuitively if there's
more passengers on board you need more crew or likewise that there's less passengers onboard you'll
need less crew.
So it makes sense that these are highly correlated.
And if I chicken against another column such as cabin's that I get an even higher correlation 0.9 5
so more cabin's more crew members which means that just a lot of these features of the ship itself have
a really good indication of exactly how many crewmembers we need.
So all of that makes a lot of sense both intuitively just from thinking about more passengers more crew
members and mathematically based on these correlations as well as the results of how well our model
performed.
Okay.
So hopefully you got the basic idea of how to test out the model and create a model trying to predict
the number of crewmembers.
If you were able to figure out string indexer don't worry that's no problem we're going to need to be
covering categorical data in a lot more detail for future models and future projects.
Hopefully however you were able to create some base linear regression model that had good results or
at least fair result in trying to predict how many crewmembers were needed for new ships.
Thanks.
I hope you enjoyed that and I'll see you at the next section of the course.