Welcome back often data sources are incomplete which means you will have missing data.
You have three basic options for filling in missing data.
Either keep the missing data points as just Noll's drop the missing data points including the entire
row or fill them in with some other value.
We're grooming to cover how to actually execute these various methods using Python and Sparke.
Let's hop over to a Jupiter notebook and get started.
In this Jupiter note book I've already started a spark session and I've called that just miss you can
feel free to call it whatever you want and we're going to create a data frame by saying Sparke read
C S V and we'll use the contains no thought see as we file include two of the notes and I'll say the
header is true as well as in for schema is equal to true.
But it's one equal sign.
Let's put that on another line that way it's a little more readable.
So there's our data frame let's showed it looks like and we can see here we have three columns in employee
ID column where there are no missing values and name column we have two missing values null and NULL
in the middle.
And then we have a sales column at the end with the first two being nulls.
So if we actually look at it at a row basis we have one row where we're missing both a name and a sales
and then two rows were missing either a name or a sales value.
And the very last row has all the information we need.
Let's talk about just dropping the missing data.
So for any data frame you can use the dot and án methods either to drop fill or do something with that
missing data.
We're going to show you what that looks like.
I can say DFA N.A. and if I hit tab here I can see the various options I have and I'll start with just
dropping.
So you can use the any functions to drop missing data in if I just call that drop and then show the
results here.
This is going to drop any row that contains any amount of missing data.
However you can also specify a threshold and if you specify threshold argument.
So if I come back here to drop and specify what's known as thresh.
So it's not the whole world.
Word is just thresh.
And if you specify this it drops rows that have less than this certain number of non-null values.
So for example I can type in for two as my threshold and then show the result.
So what does sexy mean.
This means that the road needs to have at least two non-nil values in order to pass the threshold of
being dropped.
So I can see here all these rows have at least two non-null values and 1 John employee 3 3 4 5.
And then this one has all of it.
So if we come back here to the original dataset we can see that this row only had one non-null value
and didn't meet the threshold so it got dropped.
OK.
There is another argument you put in here and set a threshold and that is the parameter how.
So by default the parameter How is set on any.
And that just means if you have any null values we'll just drop that row.
However you can also specify all which means only dropped a row if all the values are no values.
And if you do that in our case not there's not a single row that has everything all all of them have
at least the ID column.
So nothing actually gets dropped there.
So you have the threshold and the how parameters that you can play around with.
You can also play around with the subset parameter and the subset parameter just gives you an optional
list of column names to consider.
So if you only want to consider a certain column as far as missing data you can clarify that with the
subset.
So I can say something like subset is equal to and you pass it in as a list and we'll say sales.
So now I'm going to run that and now it considered any on subset sales.
So I can see here that it doesn't matter if your name is missing.
All that matters is if your sales are missing.
So we see three four five four five six here.
Looking back at the original data it dropped anything that had no value on the sales call and that's
how you can use the subset argument.
Now let's say we don't want to actually drop the missing values.
You want to fill in the missing values.
Well luckily DFA N.A. also has a Phil method we can call off of it.
Coming back here also at the FBI N.A. and I will fill and I'll just show you what happens because it's
actually really interesting.
SPARC is actually smart enough to fill in and match up data types.
So let's imagine that I put in.
Well before I actually do this I want to print out the schema just so we can see what's going on here.
So if we look at the schema I have a string a string and a double.
So then if I say DFT and a thought fill and let's pasan a string so we'll say fill value.
Something really obvious and then show the results here.
Know what happens it fills in this value to any column that's a string column.
In this case name had two missing values so said Phil value fill value.
Great.
Now let's imagine that I put in a number.
So for example I just put in zero and then I say show.
Now it knows that this is a numeric type.
So it only fills in numeric values so sales since it was double it was numeric.
So if filled in zeros they're actually smart enough to not fill in the zero for the string or fill in
the string for the sales which is kind of interesting.
Usually however you should probably specify what columns you want to fill.
You wouldn't just depend on Spark to be smart enough to get it for you.
So we end up doing something like this.
You would pass in the value you want to fill.
So we'll say no name and then using a subset parameter.
Again we'll just pass in a list of the actual column we want to target in this case will say name.
So now let's run this.
And here I can see No-Name has been filled.
If I didn't clarify this subset it would have also worked as we saw earlier but you should actually
declare the subset always because it's just it's nicer that way and you make sure that you know what
you're doing.
So if someone comes back and reviews your work it's really obvious what you are trying to do.
So let's finally go over a really common practice and that is to fill valleys with the mean value for
the column.
So for example I want to fill in any missing values for sales with the average sale value to do that.
I need to import some functions from Paice park.
So we'll say from PI spark thought sequel that functions import mean.
And then I'll say my mean value is equal to DNF select the mean of of sales and I'm going to collect
this to actually get the object back instead of just showing it.
Now if you actually look at what mean value is.
It's this list real object which is a little weird.
We actually just want to grab the single number which means what I'm going to do is say zero here and
then I have row.
And I want to grab the first item in that row object.
And luckily I can actually index this.
We also saw earlier how we could translate this into a dictionary but I can use indexing to grab that
as well.
So let's say means sales is equal to mean value 0 0.
So that actual number there then what I can do is say if any fill and then I'll say fill in that means
sales value and I want to subset sales.
Note here that I'm not actually passing in the parameter names but I'm passing them in the right order
so it actually works.
And I when I run this I can see the FDA that fill me in sales and I have that mean value there.
Now let me show you quickly how you could do this all with one line that's going to be a little ugly
but you may see this in the real world the finding on who your coworkers are.
But we'll see.
The FDA does fill all select that mean from DFA sales and then make up this to collect that value zero.
Those index calls and then at the end of this I want to say the subset was on sales.
Whoops.
Let's make sure that's correct and then show the result.
So let me zoom out a bit so we can see this whole thing.
Run this and I get the same results.
This is everything we just did in one line.
Pretty ugly.
Not very readable so I wouldn't suggest you do it this way.
But if you find yourself needing to do it it's definitely possible.
All right.
That's really all we need to know.
Basically the personal decision of whether you should feel something or drop something is going to have
to be evaluated on a case by case basis.
There's no general rules on when it's good to fill or when it's good to just drop.
It really depends on what algorithm you're using or what's the general objective of the data analysis
so keep that in mind whenever you're working with data that has missing data.
OK.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.