Welcome back to the Python crash course exercises lecture in this lecture.
We're going to get a brief overview of the actual notebook that corresponds to the exercises in the
next lecture.
I'll be coding through the solutions to the exercises.
Let's hop over to the No.
So the notebook file you need to open is called Python crash course exercises and this is just an optional
exercise to test your understanding of Python.
The questions start are pretty simple and honestly most of them are just pretty simple questions especially
if you already have a lot of experience of Python.
But you just come down here you check up the first question or all the questions it's going to have
an empty cell free to play around with.
And then right below that cell is the expected answer.
But keep in mind that once I run something in this cell it will delete that expected answer.
So it wants to ask what is 7:2 the power for.
How can you figure that out with Python.
Hopefully you remember that and then you just continue on it keeps asking you questions and expected
answers below.
If you go all the way down eventually you have a final problem.
This one's a little different.
It basically has a little word problem to solve.
It wants you to fill out a function and then it gives you two examples of how it should work.
So go ahead and read that for the final problem.
OK.
Coming up next I'm going to be personally coding you through the solutions and then explaining the tricky
parts that you may have encountered.
Thanks and I'll see at the next lecture.