Welcome back everybody.
And and this lecture will be going through the solutions to the Python crash course exercises.
Let's hop over to the exercise notebook.
All right let's get started with the crash course exercise questions solutions.
So the very first one was hopefully pretty simple for you.
It's what is seven to the power four to do that.
We just need to set seven asterisks Asterix to the power of four and then we get that split the string.
So we have a sequel to hi there Samms I can actually just copy and paste this.
Run that.
And then the new cell we can say split close print sees shift enter and then we see Hi there Sam.
Next it was given the variables planet and diameter use that format to print this following.
So I'm going to run the cells to make sure those parameters are those variable names are saved and then
the first one you want to do is say print and then I will say the the ammeter of Earth is and it's 12
7 4 2 and you say can and then are called up format and then I want to replace planets and diameter
here.
So we'll say Earth and put curly braces there and then diameter.
I'm going to put curly braces there and delete those and then say that format planets and then the emitter.
So that's just kind of to show you the logic that I am using for actually inserting these variables
into a string and if I run this I can see here the diameter is however many kilometers.
So hopefully that made sense we're just kind of interpolating these variables into the strings here
using curly braces.
Next it was given this nested list use indexing to grab the word Hello.
So this is a little complicated but let's break it down into steps.
First thing I want to do is grab that third or fourth item in the list to index three.
So remember I'm looking for hello here.
So we'll go 0 1 2 and then here's three so let's see what that looks like.
So first thing to run this.
There we go.
And then the next thing I want to do is actually grab index one from that list so it keep just breaking
this down.
And then from here it starts getting more obvious.
So I'll say in next to that brings back.
And sometimes people stop here.
But you actually just want to string up the list itself you know grab one more 0 and this returns the
string itself.
OK.
Then the next one up was given this dictionary grabbed the word Hello.
I said prepared this is annoying slash tricky and I'm a little zoomed in here so he can't see the whole
thing but I'm going to walk through it.
So first thing let's actually run this so we have it in memory.
Then I'm going to grab for the first key so dk one that I can see here kind of print out this list.
So the next thing I want to do is grab a 0 1 2 and then this dictionary.
So I will say let's index three and I get this kind of tricky dictionary and I want this value key tricky
to begin trying to grab Hello here.
So let's put that in.
Tricky.
Run this and then it says oh man and ception target etc..
So I actually want this target.
So what I'm going to do is say 0 1 2 3.
So pass and 3 again and then get Target and then I just want.
Hello.
So that's the fourth item in the list index three and there's Hello.
So again pretty tricky.
Don't worry about this kind of just the practice indexing and key calls.
But if this was really tricky for you we're not going to do anything nearly this crazy as far as that
fact will never have really the dictionary throughout the course.
This is kind of more just fun for you to practice.
Now what is the main difference between a tuple and a list.
Well a tuple is immutable doing.
If you want to create a function that grabs the email Web site domain from a string in the form some
user domain name dot com.
So let's go ahead and create a function that can do this all say the f domain gets takes in an email
and then it's going to return that e-mail and I'm going to call splits the at symbol and then just like
we did for that tweet.
I want to say negative one and then I'm going to run this.
And let me fix that casing in there.
And there it is.
I mean that comes so what are we doing here we're just splitting on the at symbol and then grabbing
the last word.
So if I actually want to see what this looks like so I go say let's say this that splits on at I can
see that I get this list so by saying negative what I'm describing that last item in the list.
Next you wanted to create a basic function that returns true if the word dog is contained in the input
string.
And don't worry about edge cases like punctuation being attached to dog but do account for capitalization.
So this one was a little tricky because we're going to do something that we didn't exactly show you
their rectally but hopefully you're able to figure it out.
So I'll say fine dog takes in some string and then it's going to return dog in I'm going to take that
string lower case it and then I can split it to get a list out and then if I call find dog here so let's
fix that casing it returns true.
Now something I don't actually have to do.
I don't actually need to split this in function.
Also works for strings directly.
So for example I can say something like as in super and that also works now in the lecture I only showed
you this.
An operator for a list which is why you may have wanted to do this split and why I have that in solution
but it's not actually necessary.
Up next you want to create a function that counts the number of times the word dog occurs in a string.
And again ignore some edge cases.
So I will say the F count.
Doug as t takes in some string I want to set count equal to zero and I'll say for word in s t lower.
Now we can go ahead and split this if the word is equal to dog then I'm going to do is add 1 to the
counts say counts plus equal to 1.
And in this case you really do need to split this otherwise we would be iterating for every single letter
in the string.
We didn't actually split and then after that's all done I'm just going to return the count.
So let's run that and let's confirm that this works by saying count dog.
And there it is two counts of dog in this string.
OK.
Finally this final problem hopefully you read it.
If not you can just take the time to read it.
But essentially we need to check if we've been caught speeding or not using some logic.
Let's go around with this function.
So I'm going to say if it is my birthday then I will take the speeding value.
So I'm going to create speeding is equal to speed minus five else.
Speeding is equal to speed.
So essentially what I'm doing is if you read this I'm going to be adjusting for the birthday
and then I'm going to say if speeding is greater than 80 mph.
So now I'm using speeding not just speed.
So I already accounted for whether it was not my birthday.
I'm going to return big ticket and then whoops I make sure I line up correctly and then if so if speeding
or else if I should say was greater than 60 then I got a small ticket.
And then finally else I didn't get a ticket at all.
So it went speeding and I said what I end up doing here was adjusting for that birthday right here and
then having the additional statements to check whether I'm going above 80 or above 60 so as to shift
and run this and make sure that I actually get the same results here.
So 81 in true should be a small ticket.
Let's run it let's see if we got small ticket 81 and falsely big ticket.
Run it and I got big ticket.
OK.
That's it for the solutions.
Hopefully most of these were pretty straightforward.
If this was extremely challenging to you then I would suggest actually taking another course in the
meantime to maybe review and try to beef up on some of these more basic Python commands.
If this was just kind of OK then that should be fine to continue on with the rest of the course.
A lot of the stuff we're kind of going to see behind the scenes will be dealing mainly of the data frame
syntax and spark in which case you won't be doing crazy things like doing so many false statements or
creating your own functions.
Those kind of things will actually do them that much because a lot of the data from syntax has taken
care of that for us already.
All right thanks everybody and I'll see you at the next section of the course.