This video we'll take a high level look at how all of this works.
If you're completely new to programming then many of these terms will probably be new to you.
The most important thing to remember is that the computer isn't smart at all.
It simply does exactly what it's told to do by the programmer and the programmer in this case is you.
A computer program is like a recipe. If you want to bake a cake,
there were a series of tasks that you must execute in a specific order.
Otherwise the final product won't be a cake.
Suppose that one of the tasks is to put four eggs in a bowl and mix.  A human might assume that the number
of eggs to be cracked and only the egg whites should be used.
But that's not necessarily true.
They might assume something else.
See that's the problem.
A computer would probably put the eggs, shells and all into a bowl and mix them.
So, when we write programs we will need to be very very explicit about what we want the computer to do.
Otherwise our result will probably be incorrect. In order to write programs.
we use programming languages.
There are many, many programming languages out there and this class we'll be using C++.
The code we write is called source code.
Source code is generally higher level than computer code since it needs to be understandable by humans.
And humans aren't very good at reading long streams of zeros and ones. We write our programs using programming
editors.
These editors are like word processors specifically designed to write these recipes in a specific programming
language. C++ programs have an extension like .cpp,
.h, .CC,
.hpp, and there are several others.  In this course we will use .cpp and .h as the extensions for
the code we write. Just that humans aren't very good at reading computer code,
computers aren't very good at reading source code.
We need to translate the source code to a form that's understandable by the computer.
This form is called object code and the compiler is the translator. The C++ compiler is a program that
takes as input C++ source code and produces object code as output.
If the source code has errors then no object code is produced.
Since our code might depend on code that other programmers wrote,  this is actually a very likely scenario
because we want to reuse as much existing code that's out there as possible.
This makes it easier for us to solve our problems.
So a program called the linker takes our object code and the object code that exists out there in the
form of libraries and links it all together to form an executable program.
That is a program that we can now run that follows the recipe we told the computer to do using C++.
Now that our program is complete we test it to find as many errors as possible
and we debug it to eliminate those errors.
As you can see there's a lot going on in understanding what's going on at this high level is important.
The integrated development environments are programs that allow you to do everything I just mentioned
from a common interface.
Sometimes they make the process seem like magic since all you need to do is click a button and the entire
build process happens.
Let's go over this build process one more time in a visual manner.
First we use an editor to enter our C++ code or to edit existing C++ code. Note that we can have many
C++ source files.  In this course we'll be using a single main cpp file until our programs get larger
then we'll need several C++ source files to better organize our program. Production C++ programs can
have hundreds and even thousands of source files and millions of lines of code.
Then we need to compile the C++ code using a C++ compiler.
If the code contains no syntax errors then the compile will generate an object code file for each C++
source file. On Windows.
the object files have .obj extensions and on Unix and Mac they will have .o extensions.
Finally the object files and any libraries that our program requires must be linked together.
This final step creates an executive file that can run. On Windows the file extension will be .exe and
on Unix and Mac they typically don't have any extensions.
But remember we're not done yet.
You must test your program to find any logic errors and debug it to eliminate those errors.
Let's wrap up this video by looking at some of the available IDEs that can help us with this process.
As mentioned previously IDEs are programs that provide an editor, a way to compile, link, and execute your
source code.
They also often have debuggers that can help you understand your code and fix errors.
Most beginning C++ courses don't cover integrated debuggers at all.
I think this is a mistake and I plan to cover the debugger once we have the basics of C++ behind us.
IDEs also help us keep our files in sync and provide hooks to version control system such as Git and
Subversion.
There are many IDEs available.
I've used all the ones listed here and others.
The selection of an idea for this course was not an easy one.
I wanted an IDE that was free, cross-platform, and had a relatively small hardware requirement to run.
In this course will use CodeLite as the IDE since it meets all of these criteria.
However,  there is no perfect IDE.  As a professional developer
many times you use whatever IDE is used by the team you're working with.  As a consultant,
you should learn as many IDEs as you can and always have an editor command line preference available
as well. As you gain experience in C++, I encourage you to experiment with the various IDEs and
find one that works for you.
Let me talk briefly about the ones that are listed here.
CodeLite as I mentioned is the IDE we're going to use in this course.
It's free, it's cross-platform,
it's fast, and the memory requirements are minimal.
Code::Blocks is also a nice cross-platform IDE.
However the Mac version is pretty buggy and it kept crashing on me all the time.
NetBeans is the Oracle IDE.
It's used mainly to develop Java code but they've got a plug in for C++ and it's actually very good.
It's a great cross-platform IDE.
The problem is that it requires Java JRE install and the memory requirements can be pretty significant.
Same thing with Eclipse. It supports many different languages,
it's cross-platform, but it's got pretty good memory requirements.
CLion is an IDE by JetBrains.
This is a company that's created Kotlin, IntelliJ, and  Android studio.
This is an awesome IDE.
This is my IDE of choice, but it's not free.
It's actually quite expensive but there's a download available that gives you a 30 day trial.
Try it out and see if you like it.
Dev-C++ is a C++  Windows only environment.
It's small, it's fast, and it's a nice IDE, but again it's Windows only.
KDevelop is a cross-platform, multiple language IDE.
However, there is no Mac binary available.
If you want to use it on Mac, you have to build it from the source.  Finally, Visual Studio and Xcode are
Microsoft's and Apple's development environments, respectively.
Visual Studio is a great development environment.
It runs on Windows only in the C++ version.
They have a Mac version of Visual Studio now, but it doesn't support C++ and Xcode is Mac only.
Again it's a great development environment,  if you're a Mac developer you're probably already using it
for iOS development,
Mac OS X development, Swift development,  and so forth.
But as I as I mentioned it's Mac only but it's a great development environment.
There are many more IDEs available. If you find one you like and you think others in the course should
know about it,
please post that information about the IDE in the course forum.
Well that wraps up this video.
I hope you have a better understanding of the build process in C++ and how to IDEs can help make programmers
more productive.