Now that code light is installed we need to run it configure it and then run a little test program to
make sure our configuration is correct.
So the first thing we want to do is we want to find code like.
And you could just type code in the search and you'll find code light and DoubleClick.
Now the first time it runs you make it a small window like this and it's probably a good idea just to
make it a little larger.
OK now sometimes when you run it the first time you'll get a setup wizard that runs.
Sometimes you don't.
We'd like to run the setup wizard so if it doesn't show up you can go to help run the setup wizard and
select that and you get a window that pops up.
So I'll select next now here.
Code like supports ph and node and a few other technologies.
We really don't want all that clutter on our ID.
We want to strictly concentrate on C++.
So I would suggest that we clear all the plug ins and then turn on only the C++ plug ins.
So you can see now that not everything is checked.
Only the plus plus plugins are checked and will select next.
Now we'll scan our computer for any installed compilers so we'll scan the computer and it's found GCC
across GCC.
I'm going to select GCC.
Gcc stands for the new compiler collection which includes C C++ Fortran ADA and a few others.
Select next as far as the editor theme.
This is really a preference for you.
This dark monocoque theme is really easy on the eyes but it doesn't show up too well on video so I'm
going to select the classic eclipse look for the videos you can choose whatever your preferences not
pressed next.
I'll leave these defaults as is and press finish.
OK now sometimes it opens up to Windows like you see here so I want to save an exit and I want to shut
down all the versions that I've got going.
I don't know why it does this but does it a few times and I'll save and exit again.
All right so now let's.
Now we're back to normal Let's try that again.
So run code like
and it's make this full screen again.
Perfect.
OK.
So now what we need to do is we need to create a workspace.
A workspace is an area where we can have our C++ projects so we can have many C++ projects in one workspace.
We can do that by selecting this button here called new workspace or we can go up to file new new workspace
either place some of us like this button here and it's going to ask for the workspace name.
This could be any name you like.
I'm going to say BPP workspace and I'm going to put this on my desktop.
You can store it anywhere you like as long as you remember where it's at.
So going to put this on my desktop
I want to create the workspace under a separate directory that help me organize my files better and
press OK.
That's it.
Now we've got a workspace which you can see here on the left side.
I can right click on that now and create a new project.
Again I can also go up file new project.
So I'll do that.
Now we've got some options here as to which template to use to create the project.
We're going to stick to the console template which is just basically a terminal window and we want a
G plus plus that's the C++ compiler.
It's called C++ because it's the new C++ compiler I'll select next.
What's my project name.
It could be anything you like.
Don't use spaces for any of these project name so I'll just say test one.
And again I want to create a project in a separate directory under the workspace so I select next.
Now I was going to ask you which compiler do you want to use.
You may have a lot of different compilers on your system.
Just select the one that you used in the setup wizard and you'll be fine.
And these defaults are perfectly fine.
Select finish and that creates a test project under the C.P. workspace and you can see it's called it's
created a source directory and in there it's kind of main CGP file.
That's our C plus plus source code and we'll get to that in a second.
We need to do a couple of bits of configuration before we do anything else.
Let's go to our project test one in this case and we'll right click and we'll go down to the bottom
where it settings will select that and then we'll get to where it says compiler options.
And notice I mean the global settings that's pretty important I mean the global settings compiler options
and then I'll select these three little dots here on the button and I want to make sure that w all is
selected that way we always get warnings and I want to make sure that the C++ standard C plus plus 14
is selected.
That's the latest standard for C++.
That'll make sure that we're using the modern C++ compiler at that point.
You can click OK apply.
OK good.
Now we can go to our workspace and right click on that and come down to workspace settings and you'll
see environment and code completion.
Go to the code completion and select enable C++ 14 standard code completion is a tool that the integrated
development environment uses that tries to figure out what I'm typing and what I want to type when it
helps predict what I want to do so it can help me so I don't have to type so much and it can do some
checking as it goes.
In this case I'm just telling you to use the modern C++ compiler.
I'll select OK and that's it.
Now I can run a simple test program will double click the main CGP file and this is actually C-code
not see post post code so we'll delete this in a minute but that aunt is a little small so in my case
since I'm doing this on video I'm going to get a settings colors and fonts and I'm just going to set
that to about 16
and see
that's much better.
You should see that much better.
OK so let's delete all of this and we'll write a really simple C++ program as we go through the course.
I'll talk about the anatomy of a C plus plus program and will go into detail as to what everything I'm
going to be typing here means.
But for now just type along and let's get a clean run so that we know our environments are set up.
So the first thing we want to write is we want to write.
LB include and I O stream inside angle brackets and we'll press Enter then we'll say int main and open
and close friends that will create them will typeless left curly and the Integrated Development Environment
will automatically close that for me and here want to do a say as T.D. to Colon's and seek out the insertion
operator which is two less than signs with no space in between.
And just some strange saying hello testin or anything else you like that has to be in double quotes.
And then finally we'll put a semi-colon on the end of that to terminate.
And then finally the last statement will be returned zero.
That means that the program terminated correctly.
That's it.
That's our first really simple C++ program.
And like I said in the beginning of the course I go through what all of this means and we'll go through
the anatomy of a C++ program and in great detail I'll save this.
Another option you may like is if you come up here to the menu you say view and say toggle minimal view
and you can see it's putting a bunch of buttons up here if you like this.
This is great because you know you can run and compile and do all kinds of things just by clicking on
a button.
I'm not going to use that because I find that pretty distracting to the video.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to shut that off on my end.
But feel free to use it.
I'm going to use command keys and I'll also just come up here and say you know build in that with very
explicit what I'm doing rather than just clicking on a button.
So that's it.
So let's run this.
Now what we'll do is I say build.
First thing I want to do is I want to clean this project that way there's no remnants of anything left
over.
It'll put it into a stable state that's good to go.
So I clean the project all the messages will show up down here then I'll say build and I'll just say
run and it's going to ask me do I just want to run it or do I want to build it and run it.
Well in this case I have to build it and run it because I haven't built it yet.
So I select to build and execute.
And if all goes well we'll get a window that pops up that says Hello.
Testing exactly what we typed here.
Press any key to continue Osaki press enter to continue which I'm going to press now.
The window goes away and we're done.
Now several things could go wrong here.
You may have an error in your program you might have forgotten to type this exactly right.
So you may have forgotten the semi-colon in which case when you go to build and run.
You'll see this red line here that's a compiler error.
You'll also see a red arrow over here telling you there's something wrong here.
And the compiler is telling you that it's expecting a semi-colon before the return.
So put it in there.
Just be really careful.
Talk about debugging and fixing syntax errors throughout the entire course.
But at this point save it make sure it's right.
Again be very careful you may have extra quote marks and the compiler won't like it.
You might only have a single less than sign here and it's not going to like it.
So just be sure it's exactly like this.
Once you've got it set up build run build and execute.
There's a clean run and there's my terminal.
OK.
So that's it we're all set to learn C++.