In this section we'll look at how we can create build and execute C++ programs using only a simple editor
and the command line.
All we need on our system is a simple text editor.
It's important to note that word processors such as Microsoft Word and Apple pages are not usually used
to enter program code.
Instead we use basic text editors or programmers text editors these types of editors are much simpler
than integrated development environments.
We also need an installed C++ compiler like GCC or Ms.
GW on Windows and Apple's command line compilers on Mac.
That's it.
At this point we can create the C++ program using the text editor and compile and run it by typing commands
into the command line.
This may sound intimidating at first but it's actually quite easy and efficient.
That said this is a workflow that's more commonly seen with experienced developers.
However you may wish to consider this approach if you find the ideas too complex or too difficult to
understand.
You might also consider this approach if your computer hardware resources are insufficient to run an
idea.
In any case this is another option that you may use in the next several videos.
I'll show you how to edit build and execute C++ programs using only the command line and a simple editor.
There will be separate videos for Windows Macs and Ubuntu Linux for your reference.