In this video we'll take a look at the main elements of the code light idea or integrated development
environment now integrated development environments are really nice because they allow you to build
and compile and edit and debug and do everything from a common interface but they can be pretty complicated
as well.
Now the code like ID is a fairly simple idea as far as ideas go.
If you use Microsoft Visual Studio or if you use X code and Eclipse and others they're much more complicated
and they've got a lot more bells and whistles but code like is a great idea for C++ especially when
we're learning.
So let me go over some of the main elements here.
When you first start code like you have an interface that looks like this.
This is the main default interface or perspective as it's called in in code like over here on the left
you have the workspace pain which is this little rectangular area right here.
Here we this large area we've got our editing pane.
This is we're going to be editing and typing our source code.
Then we've got an output pane down at the bottom and you can see that each one of these has a lot of
little tabs in there and I'll break that up so you can see it a little better.
So here we've got a workspace tab and explorer tab and so forth.
And I'll go over what those do in just a moment.
Now at the moment there is no workspace at all.
So we need to create a workspace and then we need to add projects to that workspace.
So let's do that let's create a new workspace and we can do it right here.
We like you workspace right on the main menu here.
Or we could go up to workspace new workspace or we could get a file new new workspace you can choose
whichever one you like I'll choose this one right here.
I don't get the workspace name.
In this case I'm going to call it Section 4 because this is a video in Section 4 and that where we can
create our section for projects right within this workspace.
The path for the workspace you need to provide.
I'm going to select my CPE examples folder which is on my desktop.
Select that this will create that workspace within that folder and I'll select OK.
Now you can see that we've got a workspace here called Section 4 and a couple of other things have popped
up here you can see there's a de-bug down and book Atwal that is just a bit.
So at this point we need to create some projects.
Notice that there is nothing to edit here in those window.
It's empty because there are no C++ files ready for editing yet.
So let's create a project.
This is going to be very similar to the way we created the projects in the installation videos of the
previous sections.
Some would have right click on section for workspace.
I'm going to say new project at this point I'm going to select that default project template that we
created in this case I called it Frank default posts plus project summary select that press next.
And I want to get this project today and I'm just simply going to call it Project 1
select next 0.
Except these defaults which is my compiler debugger and also like to finish.
Now you can see I've got a project named Project 1 under my section for workspace.
And you can see there's the main CPV file.
If I double clicked that it will open up in the editor and it's just going to say hello world.
What gets a building and running this in the next video.
But for now let's create another project because remember we can have multiple projects in our workspace
someone to go back up to my workspace right click again.
New project I'll use the same template and I'll just call this project to and press next and finish.
So now you can see that we've got two projects within the work space also noticed that project one is
italicized and it's bold.
This tells you that this is the current project or the active project.
Now I can select the main C.P. and project 2 and you can see here we've got two C plus plus files one
for each project.
Now you'll notice that when I select these tabs you'll let us select this tab and this highlights right
here.
So this tells you that this is the main C-p for Project 1.
When I select this tab here on the right this means GPP lights up for project 2.
If you're not getting that behavior then this little link right here is probably not selected.
If that's unselective then you'll click on these and this won't change at all on the left side here
in the workspace for you.
So you want to make sure that that's selected that way at least the editor to the workspace files so
there you go.
We can switch between them very easily.
So let's change the source code I'm going to select this file right here and I'm just going to say hello
project one.
And I'm going to save it with control as your commands and I want to select this guy right here and
I'm going to say hello project to that we will be able to see the difference when we run them.
And I I'm saying that we could also do file save.
That's it.
Now suppose I want to change between projects.
So here.
Notice that project 1 is the active project.
You can select the active project just by choosing it here from the download list.
You can see when I when I hover over it as select the active project.
So that's as simple as that.
You can also double click on the project name.
So if I double click on project to project to is now the active project project one is now the active
project that was active project mean.
Well when I build a project let's say I come up to my build and I say build something run something
clean something and get to all this in the next video.
It's going to apply it to the currently active project.
It's real important because suppose that now you're here and you're modifying the source code here and
then you build and you see nothing's changed.
Well that's because this project too is not active.
Project 1 is the active project.
So when you build and run it's going to run project 1.
It may seem like this is pretty hard to keep track of but it's really not it's really easy to keep track
of what project is active and using this little link editor.
You can obviously see which file you're working on so it's pretty easy to do.
There's a couple of other things that I want to talk about here in the editor window here.
You can see that we've got line numbers selected and so the idea is displaying line numbers for us.
This is handy because the compiler errors will give you line numbers and will also throw you a little
error right here.
I'll show you some red a little mark that says hey the error is here which is kind of nice.
I'm going to keep the line numbers on for me.
You can choose to not use them if it distracts you.
But in the course I'll refer to a line number 7 line number 5.
That way it's much easier for you to follow along if you want to get rid of those line numbers.
You could just go up to settings preferences and read an editor you could say show line numbers in the
margin and you could just uncheck that.
It's a whole bunch of other options.
Yeah the thing you might notice is you'll notice right here to the left of the end there's a little
triangle that's called the code folding triangle.
So if I select that you can see what happens is notice I've got active right now lines three four.
Well I've got all my lines right from 1 to 8 when I select that.
It hides lines 4 5 and 6 and you get this horizontal line showing you that yeah there is stuff in here.
I'm just hiding it right now.
This is called code folding.
It basically just hides that code.
This is real handy when you've got hundreds and hundreds of lines of code in your file and you're scrolling
through trying to find things.
It's really really nice to be able to just fold some stuff up.
In other words I'm working on this function right now.
I don't need to see all the other ones I just fold them out of the way.
We'll get to use these features later on as our programs get bigger.
But if you find yourself in the position where you've clicked on that by accident you see this line
and you're thinking well my goodness where did my source code go.
Don't worry the source code is still there.
Again if you see that horizontal line just click on that little triangle or show it for you also notice
that the editor uses color coding to display certain things.
So for example you could see that INT and return are a purple color and you can also see that halo project
to here is in this dark blue color.
We've also got things in dark green light green and so forth.
Also notice that the integer 0 is red.
So there's rules that the idea is using behind the scenes to make it easier for you to figure out what's
going on.
So one of the rules that is saying hey you know what if you're seeing a reserve word or one of the keywords
in C++ make it purple.
You can tweak all of this by going to settings colors and fonts select C++ here on the left and you
can customize the font that you want to use for your keywords and so forth.
I recommend you just leave this alone unless you have a real problem with some of the colors that are
there.
OK.
So that makes it really easy to figure out what's going on.
So for example let's say I forgot this quote right here.
You could see that that entire thing is now dark blue that you something is not right.
So we can always use that coloring to help us out.
It's the idea trying to make life easier for you.
The output pane down at the bottom this is where our compiler messages will be displayed when we build
code it will tell us what we're building the status of the build and so forth.
It'll also be handy for doing global search and replaces both at the workspace level and at the project
level.
Sometimes we want to change a name from hello to hello there and it's really easy to do a global search
and replace.
There's a bunch of other tabs here.
These tabs we're not going to use most of them.
I'm basically just going to leave them alone.
But if they bother you you want to get rid of them.
You can click on these three horizontal dots right here these three vertical dots rather right here
and you could select to hide certain things.
So let's say we don't want to see the build queue tab just select build queue and it hides.
You can always bring it back if you like.
Like I said I'm just going to leave him alone.
But if your if your screen real estate is small or your monitor or small you're having trouble fitting
all this stuff in.
This is a really easy way to do it.
We're going to use the most are build and output and obviously search and replace or can come in very
handy.
Ok now in the workspace view we've also got some tabs.
Now here I spread this you could see it a little bit.
The only ones we're really going to use here are workspace Explorer and tabs.
These last three tabbed groups see make help and W X craftier we're not really going to use them.
So what we can do is we can hide those.
So I get I'll select the three dots and hide W X craftier hide C make and hide tab groups.
That's it.
That makes it a little less cluttered and it's kind of nice too to see it all there.
This little drop down arrow here.
If I'm in tabs and I select download I can go to work space.
If you only have three tabs it's not really a big deal but if you've got a lot of tabs and it's really
nice to be able to do that especially when they're hidden and you can't see them in situations like
this so the last thing I want to do is I want to show you that you can actually move these pains around.
Now this is the default perspective that you get out of the can.
Some people don't like the workspace view on the left.
They prefer it on the right.
So you could just grab the workspace view tab right here just move it over drag it to the right and
you'll see it light up.
You can see here if I wanted to put it down here it lights up the area that it's going to be in lights
up again at the top.
You could choose to put it wherever you like.
Let's say you like it over here on the right.
And some people like this workflow a little better.
So now you've got your workspace here on the right and your editor on the left you can do the same thing
with this output view.
I mean suppose I want to put my output view right under my workspace for you.
I could do that and I've got a really large editing area.
It's totally up to you.
The perspective that you use this is a real personal decision.
I've worked on teams where everybody on the team teams have hundreds everybody's got their own way of
doing things.
So everybody tweaks the environment their way.
The nice thing about this is that if you download some project and it's got this perspective saved you
can always come up to perspective and click on default laya.
That'll bring it right back to the default.
So I could just select that and here I am back to back to scratch just like you came out of the can.
If you prefer your layout to be a specific way let's say I like it like this and I want to move this
over just a little bit here.
And these guys appear like that again however you want to do it.
You can come up to perspective and then save current layout as.
So let's just say I want to call this Frank Dodd lay out
and I can save it so I can switch between the default layout and if I want to go back to my own laya
I can go back to Frank lay out really really easy to do.
There's two lay outs that come already pre-configured.
One is the default layout which is the one I've shown you before and the other one is a debug play out.
This is the layout that's used when you're doing debugging.
So if I select debug layout you can see that I've got an output view pane on the left and a debugger
pane on the right and code like will switch to this automatically when you go into debug mode.
Again if you have a better way of doing it that works for you you can tweak this and save that perspective.
So I switched back to the default perspective and we can also use the view options to hide or view different
page.
So for example if I don't want to see the output pane or the workspace pane I can certainly hide them
and view them.
I can also do that here by closing up with that little X right there to close up the workspace view.
I can also make the workspace really large by clicking this icon right here.
So you've got all these options you encourage you to play around with the environment and set it up
to a place where you feel comfortable working.
Recall we talked about this in one of the installation videos that we can show a toolbar so we can build
and run and save and have all kinds of options by just clicking on these toolbar icons.
I'm not going to use that since it really clutters things up for me and I want to be able to explain
exactly what I'm doing.
So for example that icon right there says run active project that one says start or continue debugger
so they can be confusing at first.
I'm not going to use those.
I'm simply going to come up here and tell you exactly what I'm doing.
So I'm going to close the toolbar down.
But again feel free to use it.
And that wraps up this quick tour of the code like ID.
We are certainly going to use more features as decors progresses in the next video we'll create our
first C++ program that goes a little bit beyond the hello world program and we'll use that program to
understand how the build process works within the code like I-T.