It this video will learn how to declare and initialize variables.
Then we'll head over to code like and declare and initialize some variables in life code.
The syntax for a variable declaration in C++ is very simple.
First you tell the compiler what the type of the variable is.
Then you tell the compiler what the name of the variable is.
And finally you terminate the Declaration with a semi-colon later in this section.
I'll go over some of the basic C++ types but here are a few is a preview.
Intice an integer or a whole number.
A double is a floating point number and a string is a sequence of characters that you would see in my
name.
Frank also noticed that we can declare variables of non-C plus plus built in types.
One of the very powerful features of C++ is object oriented programming which allows us to create our
own types so we can create variables that represent an account or a person using the same syntax as
we used for integers and doubles.
This is great since it makes our program so much more readable in the next slide.
We'll talk about some of the rules that you must follow when you named variables.
Remember in C++ we must declare our variables before we use them.
So let's take a look at some of the variable naming rules the rules for naming C++ variables are very
very simple C++.
Variable names can contain letters numbers and underscores.
However the first letter of the name cannot be a number.
It can be an underscore or letter as discussed previously C++.
Keywords are also reserve words so you can't use those names.
You can't use it you can't use double as your own names.
Also you cannot declare a variable name that's already been declared in the same scope.
So if you declared x to be an integer you can't do that again.
Remember C++ is case sensitive so the name age in uppercase is considered different from the name age
in lowercase.
Let's take a look at a few examples.
In the left column of the table you can see some legal C plus plus variable names.
Since C++ is case sensitive age beginning with an uppercase A is considered a different name from age
beginning with a lower case.
We can begin our variable names with underscores or letters and we can also have underscores and numbers
within the variable name.
The right column has some examples of a legal variable names.
The first example is lowercase and this is not allowed since lowercase.
It is a reserve word in C++.
We cannot have special characters like the dollar sign or mathematical characters but the plus sign.
Also notice that variable names cannot have spaces in them.
Now let's talk about C out see out is a little different.
C out is a legal name because it conforms to the variable naming rules.
However if you include IO stream in your program then C out it's already defined somewhere else it's
defined by the standard library so it no longer becomes a valid name since it's been defined somewhere
you cannot redeclare it yourself.
So the rules that the C++ compiler enforces for variable names are pretty simple as you can see.
Now let's take a look at variable naming style and best practices.
The most important thing you can do is to be consistent with whatever naming convention you choose to
use.
There are many style guides and naming conventions out there.
In many cases you'll be working for a company and they have a specific style of naming convention that
you have to use.
This has nothing to do with the C++ compiler but it's still very important.
For example Google has a published C++ style guide as do many other companies one of the first decisions
you make with regard to variable naming is whether you want to use camel case or underscores two separate
words.
Both styles make the text more readable by avoiding long streams of lower case letters which are harder
to read camel case.
Capitalize the first letter of every word in your name and does it use underscores the other style is
to use underscores to separate words either style is fine.
The important thing is to be consistent in this course.
I'll use the underscore style please use meaningful names don't use obscure abbreviations for example
instead of using the variable name.
M o e to represent the mass of the earth.
Just use the real name mass of earth with underscores or camel case.
Either way.
Sure it's a little bit more typing but your program becomes so much more readable and maintainable.
Never use variable names before initializing them uninitialized variables can cause all kinds of unexpected
results in C++.
I'll show you an example of this when we head over to the ID.
Finally it's best practice to declare your variables as close to when you need them as possible.
In other words if your program uses 10 variables don't declare all 10 of them at the top of the file
and then use them later.
Instead declare them right before you use them.
There are many many more programming best practices and we'll discuss them throughout the course.
So let's talk about initializing variables.
Notice the first line of code in this example.
It age this is a variable declaration that's uninitialized.
You have no idea what the value of h is.
And that's the problem.
If you try to display age or perhaps use in some calculation you'll run into problems because it was
never initialized so its value could be anything uninitialized variables or a very common source of
programming errors.
C++ provides three ways to initialize variables.
All three are equivalent and they're related to the way that C++ has evolved over the years.
The first is to use an assignment operator.
That's the equal sign.
This will assign 21 to age right when it's created so it will be immediately initialized.
The second uses parentheses around the value in this case 21.
This is a constructor style initialization.
We'll talk about constructors when we talk about object oriented programming.
The final initialization statement is the C++ 11 initialization syntax.
This style of initialization is consistent across different types in C++ and has some benefits that
we'll discuss later in this course.
I encourage you to use this style of initialization.
Now let's head over to code and see some of these examples in life code.
Ok so now I'm in code light and let's write a real simple program that calculates the area of a room
and square feet.
So the idea is to use or for the length of the room and the width of the room and then we'll multiply
those two together to calculate the square footage of the room the area of the room.
OK.
Now obviously we need to Varians But before we do that let me show you one of the issues with uninitialized
variables as we talked about in the previous slides.
Let's create a real simple variable here called age just like we did before and I'm not going to initialize
it on purpose.
And what I want to do is just output that value to see out.
Let's build this and I'll execute it.
And you can see the printing out here you can see there is h I'm outputting age and that's the value
that's in H right now not what we expected for sure.
The problem is that we never initialize the variable age so the value that's in that variable could
be anything and in this case it is anything.
OK so let me show you how that works.
So let's go back to our conceptual model.
Here's our memory.
I've got a memory location let's say that that's maybe location 2000 that could be anything.
And age is associated with that location now in there there are a series of zeros and ones that's how
we store values in computers whatever value happens to be in there is the value that will be displayed
on the console.
Remember when I output age the compiler is going to grab whatever this value is in here and replace
it right in there.
In this case we've got that we've got that really strange very large number.
The idea is we really want to initialize this guy to something even zero before we use it.
So you can see here I'm using it before I initialize it.
That's not a good idea.
OK so let me clear this.
And if we now initialize this to let's say 0 or 21 or whatever we like I use 21 here now a build and
run
you can see now it's printing out 21.
OK so that gives you an idea and also when we did not initialize it the compiler did give us a warning
just right click here and compile notice the warning that the compiler is giving be done here it's saying
warning.
Age is used uninitialized in this function.
That's occlude don't ignore those warnings.
The computer is telling you be careful you're using something that you never initialized.
OK.
So that gives you an idea of what's going on with uninitialized variables.
All right so let me race this and let's write our program.
So what we need here is we need to ask the user for the length of the room and the width of the room.
We'll grab those two values from C in them or multiply them together and we'll display the square footage
of the room.
Really really simple program but let's get started.
So what we'll do is we'll say see out and remember I don't have to use standard scope resolution operator
here because I'm using namespace.
So I say enter the width of the room and assume this is in feet.
Or put a semi-colon at the end of that line to terminate it.
Now we need to read something into a variable right.
So we need to do in into something.
What we need to declare that variable Let's declare it right appear.
We could call it with and it's going to be in integers that say Remember we've got to say the type followed
by the name of the variable followed by a semi-colon.
This is perfectly fine with is probably not a great name something like room with is better provides
much more information to whoever's going to come later and modify this code.
So now we've got the room with and I'm going to enter the room with and I'm going to read it into room
with.
Right now we've got our variable.
Now notice a couple of things.
One is we never initialized room with in this case it's probably OK because I'm going to read something
into it before I use it.
But best practice is let's initialize that.
We'll set it to zero.
Now we need another variable right.
We need the length of the room so I'll just cut and paste this to save a little time here and I'm going
to say and the length of the room and we're going to read that into another variable called Room length
and we will initialize that to zero.
In this case 0 is fine you could initialize it to anything that makes sense in your application.
All right so now I will read that went into room length so I'll just change this variable name right
here.
So look at what's going on here.
We've initialized two variables.
Room with en route length.
They're both integers.
Again notice the syntax the type name as integer followed by the name of the variable.
And in this case where initializing it.
I'm prompting the use of trencher the width of the room and I'm reading that integer into room with
then I'm prompting the user to enter the length of the room and I'm reading that integer into room length.
All I have left to do now is just say see out and I'll say the area of the room is.
And we'll do the calculation here right in line.
It's going to be room with times room length.
And we may as well say square feet.
That's it.
We'll complete this with an end line
and clean a little bit of space up just to make it a little bit more readable.
That's it for returns zero at the end.
Now let's build and run this.
We get a clean compile and it says enter the width of the room that said the with is 10 feet and for
the length of the room let's say it's five feet.
Always remember we know what to expect.
Expect a 50 percenter.
It says the area of the room is 50 square feet.
So we get back what we expected.
Always think about what you're going to get back before you do this otherwise you may have errors that
you didn't think about or press any key to continue.
That's it.
That's a pretty straightforward solution.
You can see how we use variables how we can initialize variables how you can read into variables.
Now a best practice would be rather than declare these two variables.
Up here what we could do is we could declare them closer to where we're using them.
So in this case this is the first use of room with.
So I could modify this by taking this line here and I'll just cut it and I'll paste it right in here
and I'll do the same with room length.
I'll cut it from here and I'll paste it right in here.
And I just cleaned up the code a little bit get rid of some of this extra white space.
Now now you can see what's happening.
I'm prompting the user declaring that variable I'm reading into it prompting the user for the length
I'm declaring the variable I'm reading into.
So this is basically what we talked about in the previous slides.
You could see this is a really simple example.
Try it out.
Play around with it.
There'll be a challenge exercise at the end of this section that's going to extend this a little bit.
So that's the end of this video.
This shows you how to initialize variables use the variables in the next video.
We'll talk a little bit about scope and global variables.