All right.
So let's get ready for the challenge.
This is a pretty simple challenge that's based on what are the problems that we solved in this section.
If you recall we had a problem for crank's carpet cleaning service where Frank charge so much per room.
While this is a little bit different in this case Frank has two charges one for small rooms and one
for large rooms.
So as you can see here he charges $25 for small rooms and $35 for larger rooms.
The sales tax rate is still 6 percent.
And estimates are still valid for 30 days.
So what you need to do here is prompt the user both for how many small rooms they want cleated how many
large rooms they want cleaned and then provide an estimate that looks something like this number of
small rooms.
For example 3 number of large rooms one price per small room $25 price per large room $35.
Calculate the cost calculate the tax and then come up with the total estimate and tell them that the
estimate is valid for 30 days.
Okay.
So hopefully that makes a lot of sense.
And here's a sample run that you can see.
So here.
Hello welcome to Frank's carpet cleaning service how many small rooms would you like clean.
Let's say I want three small rooms cleaned and one large room clean.
And you could see here the estimate is number of small rooms three number of large rooms one that's
what I just typed in the price per small rooms is 25 their price per large room is 35.
And the cost is 110.
If you do the math you can see that three times 25 is 75 plus 35 is 110.
Six percent of that is $6 is 60 cents if you add it all together you get $116 to 60 cents and then you
display this estimate is valid for 30 days.
All right.
So give it a shot.
Take your time.
I'm sure you'll do it just fine.
If you want to see the solution in the next video I'll present my solution to this problem.