Welcome back.
I hope you had fun trying to solve the problem.
I'm sure you did great as you noticed in the work space that created the challenge which has created
an empty shell for the problem.
And I've also got the challenge solution which has my solution to the problem.
OK so let's start looking at the code here we know we had to solve.
So let's look at some of these really simple statements first and I'll mark this up just so easy for
you to follow.
So in this case I'm simply putting welcome that I've defined a variable here which is going to hold
small rooms and I've initialized to zero that's the best practice I'm prompting the user and I'm asking
them to put in the number of small rooms they want and I'm doing exactly the same thing here except
we're doing large rooms and now we've got to define two declared constants right.
We're going to declare one is the price for a small room and one is the price for a large room 25 and
35 respectively.
We've got our sales tax declared constant here and we've got our estimate expert constant.
So so far so good.
It's exactly the same as we did before.
The only thing is I'm adding the barge rooms.
Okay.
So let me clear this and I'll scroll up just a little bit and take a look at some of the calculations
here are some of the outputs statements and you can see here I'm asked about putting the number of small
rooms which is just whatever the user typed in and the number of larger rooms which is whatever they
typed in the price per small room and the price per barge room right here those are our declared constants
which I'm outputting.
Now the cost the calculation is really simple it's the cost of the small rooms plus the costs of the
large rooms and we calculate each one by price per small room times the number of small rooms.
Plus there's a plus sign.
Or you can split these across lines so you can line up the insertion operators like that and make some
nice and easy to read.
So in this case I'm just calculating the cost for the small rooms and I'm adding the cost of the large
rooms to it.
Same thing with tax I'm calculating the cost again and I'm multiplying the whole thing by sales tax.
Notice that I've got those parentheses here because what I want to do is I want to calculate the whole
cost and then multiply that by the sales tax.
Otherwise I won't get the correct answer.
Make sure the whole thing is here.
So this becomes all the small costs plus all the large costs.
Okay.
Then finally the total estimate just takes the cost and adds the sales tax to it.
That's it.
The estimate is valid for 30 days.
And there's my program so you can see that my formatting is going to be a little bit different from
your formatting and mine might be a little bit more readable because you may not have split things across
lines like I did.
It's good practice to split these across lines that we can really see what's going on and it's much
much easier to follow.
OK.
Well I hope you enjoyed the challenge and I hope you did well.
Remember there's a lot of duplicated code here that we're going to clean up as the course progresses.
And this program will actually modify this program a little bit later on when we use functions.
OK.
So that's it for the challenge.