In this section of the Course will learn about our first compound data type compound type has a type
that's made up of other types.
First we'll learn about arrays what they are and why we use them.
We'll go over the syntax for declaring and initializing arrays and we'll learn how to access the individual
elements of an array.
Then we'll talk about multi dimensional arrays.
These can be two dimensional or three dimensional arrays or they can be as many dimensions as you need
they can be very useful for modeling grids boards and much more complex data types.
Then we'll learn about vectors.
Vectors are better than arrays in so many ways and we'll discuss their advantages.
In fact in modern C++ we rarely use raw arrays.
Instead we use vectors.
So why cover arrays at all.
I think it's important to understand arrays since there's so much legacy C++ code out there and conceptually
they're easy to understand and they'll add to your overall knowledge of C++.
OK so let's get started learning about our first compound data type arrays.