In this video we'll learn about a raise and their characteristics will also see the typical use case
for an array an array is a compound data type or a structured data type.
This means that it's a data type that's made up of other data types.
For example a collection of test scores were.
Each test scores an integer is considered a compound data type made up of integers.
We say that this is an array of integers.
It's important to understand that all elements of an array must be of the same type and each element
can be accessed directly.
We'll see some other array characteristics shortly but first let's see why we use arrays and why they're
so useful.
Suppose we need to model my test scores in a class that's pretty easy.
We've already seen how to use variables and this would be a perfect use of variables.
So suppose to have three test scores that I need to track and they're all graded as integers out of
100.
I can simply declare three variables as integers give them meaningful names initialize them to zero
or whatever values I wish.
But what if I need to model more than just a few test scores suppose I'm a school administrator and
I need to model the test scores for 100 students so that I could do some statistics on them modeling
each one of them as its own variable with its own name can quickly get out of control.
Now I have to keep track of 100 variable names.
You could still do it but it becomes tedious and error prone.
What if I had 10000 test scores to model.
You get the idea.
This is a typical use case for an array and that's when they're really really useful arrays allow you
to tell the compiler to give you a collection of as many elements as you want and give the entire collection
a single name.
So you no longer have to name each individual element.
Let's go over some of the characteristics or properties of arrays.
Arrays are fixed in size.
Once you create an array of a specific size the size cannot change.
So if you create an array of 100 test scores then you need space for more than that.
You'd have to go back to your source code.
Change the max size and recompile the size of the array is fixed arrays will not grow or shrink on their
own while the program is running.
As mentioned earlier all the elements of an array must be of the same type.
So we can have arrays of integers arrays of doubles race of persons arrays of accounts and so forth.
A race is stored continuously in memory.
So if you tell the compiler that you need an array of 100 integers the compiler will generate code that
allocates exactly 100 integers did are contiguous in memory.
That means that the memory will be allocated as one chunk.
Array elements are individually accessible so I can access any test score that I wish you could do that
using the position or index of that array element.
So I could tell the compiler to give me the second element in the array or the 1308 element in the array.
Be aware that array indexes start at zero.
This means that the first element in an array is a position zero not a position one and the last element
is a position size minus one.
You can see an example in the figure on the right.
Here we have an array of 10 test scores.
The array is named test scores and it's indexed from 0 to 9.
Many many programming languages have compound data types like arrays and the majority of them start
their array indexes in zero.
I know that most of us start counting at 1 with arrays.
You must started 0.
This is a common cause of errors and programs especially with beginning programmers.
It's also important to understand that C++ arrays are not bounds checked.
That means that there is no check to make sure that when you access the individual array element that
it's between zero and size minus one.
It's the programmer's responsibility to be sure that you don't go over bounds.
If you go over bounds your program may have strange behavior and you could even crash finally in a few
sections.
We'll talk about iteration or looping.
As you can imagine looping is used all the time with arrays since we often need to loop through the
arrays and process every element just like variables always initialize the raise or they'll contain
unknown values.
Arrays are extremely efficient in C++ since they are bare bones raw arrays.
Later in this section we'll talk about C++ vectors which are super powerful dynamic and safer to use
in a race in the next video.
We'll see how to declare arrays.