In this video we'll look at the syntax for accessing individual array elements.
The syntax is probably very much like what you expected.
We use the name of the array followed by square brackets with the index of the array element we want
inside the square brackets.
This is called the array subscripting for example test score one refers to the element at index 1 in
the test scores array in the code example at the bottom.
You can see that we've declared the test scores array of five integers and initialize those integers.
Then we have 5 output statements that each displays one of those array elements.
Remember that arrays subscripting or indexing starts at zero.
So the first element of an array is at index 0.
We use the same syntax for storing values and arrangements in this example.
We're getting input from the user via the console and updating the individual array elements from index
0 to 4.
We could then display them as we did in the previous slide.
We'll talk about assignment statements in an upcoming section but here you can see that I'm assigning
90 to the first element of the test scores array.
Notice that the syntax is the same.
That pretty much covers the basics of a race but you might be wondering how this works behind the scenes.
Let's see in C++ the name of the array represents the location or address in memory of the first element
in the array that is Yellam with index zero where we access an array element using the subscript operator
and provide an index in the square brackets.
The compiler knows that you want the element that is at that offset from the beginning of the array.
So all the compiler has to do is a pretty simple calculation.
For example if you want the element an index to all the compiler has to do is go to integers away from
the beginning of the array and there it is.
Or two doubles or two whatevers.
The compiler uses the size of operator to determine where the element will be.
This is one reason why raw raised and C++ are so efficient.
But remember there is no bounds checking so be careful if you have an array of 5 integers and you asked
the compiler for the integer at the tenth index it will gladly do the calculation and give you whatever
happens to be at that location.
It's your responsibility to be sure that you're within the bounds of the array.
Now let's head over to code right and use what we learned and write some code with a race.
OK so now I mean code light and I mean the section 7 workspace and the arrays project.
And here's my main CBP file what I've done is I've created some examples where I am declaring and initializing
some arrays I'm accessing array elements I'm reading from them storing values in them and so forth.
And that way you can go through this step by step so you can really understand what's going on.
I've also commented a bunch of this out and what I'll do is uncomment as I go and we'll build on this
little by little.
So the first thing we're doing here is I'm creating an array right here named vowels that's that a.m.-I
array follows.
You'll notice that right in those square brackets I'm not providing any information.
So what I'm telling the compiler is hey you figure out how big this is based on the initializer.
OK so in this case I've got five characters that I'm initialising this to.
So the array will be size 5 so was going to happen is I have an array of 5 characters and I'm initializing
them to a T.
Oh and you write the name of this array is vowels.
So I can treat it as such and it's indexed from 0 to 4.
Remember there is no 5 here.
So don't let that confuse you.
Fine.
Now in this case I'm saying the first vow is and I'm using an output statement and grabbing vowels Sub-Zero
that's right there.
That's the little AA.
So I expect this to print out a little AA in this case I'm using vowels for which is the little you
right here.
Lowercase U.
All right so let's run this and see what we get.
So what I'm going to do is I'm pressing control 5 to build and run and the output is the first Vout
is a and I'll move this over here is you could see the first is lowercase say the last five was a lowercase
you exactly what we expect.
Now what would happen be clear this real quick what would happen if I tried to read from the console
and I want to store whatever character I read into vowels 5 recall.
There is no vowel so 5 right it goes 0 1 2 3 4.
What happens here really depends on a lot of things.
Obviously I'm going to read a character and stored in a location that's not part of the array so there
could be something important there.
And I just blew it away.
My program will likely crash depending on what operating system you're on and what you're running your
crash may look different from mine.
So let me run this and hopefully it'll crash it may not.
You never really know this.
OK there's first vowel is little AA second bell is lowercase you know I'm going to read someone to type
in that say capital A.
And when I press Enter that's my crash.
Hopefully you can see that this is a phrase that he has stopped working PLO's program depending on again
what operating system you're working on it may look different.
But in this case this is a good thing my program crashed.
I'm able to fix it.
And obviously what happened here was and I'll comment this out and I'll leave it coming.
It won't keep crashing hoops on me.
Do that again.
And I'll write something like know out of bounds that way when you download the example you'll know
what's going on and I'll say don't do this or be very careful with that.
OK so that gives you an idea of what happens it could be a pretty serious problem.
And the real problem is that it may not happen every time you may clobber some information that's just
not even important but you may Klepper some information that's real important.
OK.
So let's move on in this example here.
I mean uncomment this code and I'll walk you through this example here I'm doing something very similar
I'm creating an array called high temps and you can see that the name of the arrays right there high
temps.
Again I'm not providing the size of the array because I'm letting the compiler figure it out based on
my initializer list.
There are one two three four initializers.
So I going to create an array of four doubles.
The first one being ninety point one that second when being eighty nine point eight and so forth here
I'm saying pre-adult high temps Sub-Zero right.
Remember this would be 0 1 2 and 3.
So in this case this will predestine ninety point one.
Now I'm saying high temps Sub-Zero is one hundred point seven.
So what I just did was I just changed the ninety point one to 100 point seven.
This is an assignment statement we're going to talk a lot about assignments statements in an upcoming
section but they're really really straightforward when you see them like this.
All it says is move this guy into that guy.
OK so that's what we're doing.
We're just overriding that ninety eight point one.
Two hundred point seven.
And then when I display it it's going to display a hundred point seven now.
So what I expect here is the first time I put that guy it's going to give me ninety point one.
Now I'm going to get 100 point seven.
So let's try this out and see if that's exactly what we get.
We build and run the first high temperature is ninety point one.
The first high temperature is now one hundred point seven.
So here you could see some examples of declaring initialising and accessing array elements.
Now here's another example here.
I'm like come at this out as well.
In this case right here what I've done is I've asked the compiler again to give me an array of five
integers and call it test scores.
What's happening here is I'm getting an array of five integers.
Just like that it's called test scores
again they're indexed from 0 1 2 3 and 4.
However I never initialize them.
So what you have in here is junk or garbage memory whatever happens to be in there whatever bit pattern
happens to be in there is still in there.
So with this code right here is doing is it's displaying each one of those array elements.
It's starting the development at index 0 going all the way through the element index for this is what
we'll do later on with looping.
We can do all this in one statement with looping and we'll learn how to do it a little bit later.
Now when I do this I'm expecting junk.
I have no idea what's in those cells so I don't know what's going to print out.
So let's try it and see.
And you can see that chunk right here 41 9 9 1 3 6 and so forth because there's zero in there.
The point is you cannot rely on those values you really don't know what's in there.
So what do we do.
Well we can just put a couple of curly braces there and initialize that will initialize everything to
zero.
So if I run this again I expect to see all zeros.
I do.
That's exactly what I want always initialized to a race.
Never assume that they've got any value in there until you put the value in yourself.
I could also put a hardcoded zero in there and I'll have the same effect.
But what if I had to 100.
This is this piece confuses beginning programmers sometimes you may think that it's going to put 100
or all of those elements but that's not the case.
Let me run it and you'll see what happens.
You see that it put a 100 in the first element and then the rest are zeroed out.
That's the behavior you can get put in less initializers than you have so much.
Now if I put a 90 here then what's going to happen is it's going to set this element right here.
It's going to set this element right here to 100 this element to 90 and then 0 0 0.
So that's the behavior when you provide less than the size of the array.
As far as initializers are concerned.
So again I'll run this real quick.
And what you'll see is 190 000.
Let me clear the screen real quick.
In this case what I'm doing here is I'm reading integers from the console and storing them into those
array elements from 0 to 4.
So whatever was in here before is going to be removed now so I'm going to initialize this to 100.
It just goes straight down by 10 70 and 60.
So 198 1760s how initialising this too.
I have a 5 here I don't really need that 5.
There I think just get rid of it like that.
I did it before so you can see how it initializes zeros.
So I'll just get rid of that five right there.
It's still going to create an array of five integers and initialize them to 190 80 1760.
Now what I'm going to do is I'm just going to enter different numbers and then we'll display those new
numbers right here with this code which is the same code as we used before.
OK so let's do that real quick.
Well built and run.
So there is our original array one hundred ninety 1876.
So suppose I want to go now 10 20 30 40 and 50 and I print them out.
Now you can see that array Sub-Zero is 10 and the next one is 20 30 40 and 50 as you can see that those
values are read from the console and stored in the array.
The last thing we'll do is this may give you a little bit of a different effect than you thought.
Suppose that I want to output just the name of the array.
You'll notice test scores right here.
I'm not saying test scores Sub-Zero or test scores 1.
I'm just saying test scores.
Let's run this and then I'll show you exactly what's going on when we come back.
So I'm going to run this.
And again let's just enter those scores again
and notice what happens here says.
Notice what the value of the array name is.
And you get some hexadecimal number that number is actually the memory address the storage location
where the array is located.
This is the way that C++ works or the race the name of the array is the location of the array.
Now that's a strange number to write so I'll just use a thousand for it that way we can make it a little
bit easier to explain.
So let's take a look at how this works.
I've created that array right test scores and test scores is five integers just like we saw before.
Again indexed 0 1 2 3 and 4.
This is called test scores.
Now when I say test scores what's it going to do.
Well it's going to take the address of that variable that variable is an address so let's say that the
address is a thousand and then this address is a thousand for assuming that we have 4 byte integers
and this is 0 0 0 0 8.
This is a thousand 12 and so forth.
What prints out here will be 1000.
And the calculation that C++ is doing that we mentioned in the slides.
So for example when I say test scores one is I'm saying here what is going to do is it's going to take
test scores which is a thousand and it's going to add one integer to it.
Or in other words go one integer away from it and it's Jer's 4 bytes.
There you go.
That's the address.
That's the calculation it's doing.
This is why when test scores of five is referenced it's going to do the calculation and come up with
that number right there and it's going to try to put to work with this guy.
Well this is not part of the array right.
The array ends here but just no real boundaries around there it's not like protected or anything.
So in this case something is going to change and it may be a bad thing you might crash your program.
OK so hopefully this example helps you understand a little bit about the syntax of a raise how to initialize
them how to use them in a little bit more about how they're laid out in memory and some of the issues
that you can have with them.