In this video we'll go over the C++ equality operators these operators compare the values of two expressions
and evaluate to a boolean.
That's a true false value.
The operators are the equals which is represented by two equal signs and the not equal operator which
is represented by the exclamation point or Bang's symbol followed immediately by an equal symbol be
extra careful when you're starting.
It's super common for beginning C++ programmers to use a single equal sign.
That's assignment not comparison these simple operators along with the operators would learn about in
the next several videos give us so much power in programming we use these operators all the time and
control flow statements that we'll learn shortly.
So suppose we want to do something when x is equal to 100.
We can do that.
We can also test for two expressions not being equal.
So if my password doesn't match the password on file then you want to do something specific the following
code snippets only show the equality expressions they're always used within statements.
The first example evaluate to TRUE if the value of expression 1 is equal to the value of expression
to these two expressions could be very complex or very simple.
The second example will evaluate to TRUE if the value of expression 1 is not equal to the value expression
to the 30 sample will always evaluate to false since 100 will never equal 200.
We don't usually write expressions like these but it serves to illustrate how this operator works.
The final example evaluates to true if number one is not equal to number two.
Let's go over a few more examples that you statements.
First we're declaring a variable named result that's of type Boolean and we're initializing it to False.
Then we compare one hundred and fifty plus 50 for equality.
This will result in a boolean that's a true false value which we assign to result in the next example
we compare number 1 and number two.
And if they're not equal we store true end result.
Otherwise false.
Notice how we can use boolean expressions in output statements in the first output statement we're comparing
number one and number two and we're displaying one if they're equal or 0 if they're not equal.
Sometimes it's handy to display the words true and false rather than 1 and 0 in the output statements.
We can do that using the bool Alpha stream manipulator Alpha and noble Alpha are located in the standard
named space.
Once you use them all boolean output to the stream will result in the words true and false being displayed.
That can be pretty handy if you want to go back to the default of 0 and 1 just use noble Alpha.
Let's head over to code light and see some examples.
So I mean code like I am in the section 8 workspace the equality operators project let's run over a
few examples of using these equality operators.
These are going to be really really straightforward examples I don't think you'll have any issues understanding
this but you may see a couple of surprises so stay tuned for that.
So here we go we've got and we've got a boolean called equal result which I'm initialising to faults
and another building called not equal result which I'm also initialising to faults and I've got two
integers here.
Number one and number two.
And we'll just play around with this a little bit.
I've got my C out bu alpha here commented out uncomment that out in a moment moments you can see the
difference between the behavior.
When you do that.
So here I'm prompting the user to enter two integers separated by space.
I'm reading in those two integers on line 15 I'm comparing those two integers for equality right here
on line 16.
So I'm saying is no one equal to number two that result is going to be stored in equal results so it's
either going to be true if they're equal or not true if they're not equal then I'm going to compare
the same two numbers using the not equal operator.
So is number one not equal to number two in this case if they are not equal then I'm going to store
true into the not equal result otherwise false.
OK.
And then I'm just going to print out those two results so let's run this piece of the code right now
and you'll see what happens.
Let's enter two integers in this case let's enter two integers that are equal to one another.
So I'll type in 10 and 10 and Precentor and you can see here the comparison result for equals is 1 which
is true.
And for not equals zero because they are obviously are equal.
OK.
Now notice I have a one in a 0 being I put it here when I uncomment down the alpha stream manipulator
and recompile and run.
Now I can say that say 20 20 and instead of 0 1 we see true fault so that's pretty handy.
So in this case they are True's to the equals will be true and the articles will be false.
Let's use an example whether they are not equal.
And let's say we're trying to do 10 and 20 this time.
So.
Equals is false and not equals is true.
Just like what we would expect.
OK.
So I said that's pretty straightforward.
I'm going to comment out this piece of code right here and now we'll do the same thing except we'll
do it with characters remember we can do this with any type of pair any type.
So in this case I've declared two characters char one and Tartu and initialize them both to empty to
zero.
And I'm asking the user to enter two characters separated by space.
I'm reading and the characters then doing exactly the same thing I'm comparing them for equality and
I'm comparing them to see if they're not equal.
So let's run this.
And the first test will do is say lower case and upper case A.
There are different characters or Precentor or they equals.
No that's false.
Are they not equal.
True that's true.
That's exactly what we expect.
And let's test it one more time with let's say a capital Z and another capital Z in this case they are
equal.
So that's true and they're not equals is false.
Ok so you can understand the logic that's going on here.
Comment that out and I will uncomment the next section which is dealing with doubles.
So again exactly the same thing except I'm using doubles.
I run this and will type in say two doubles that are the same twelve point one and twelve point one.
The comparison result is they are equal.
Exactly what would expect again.
And let's do an example where they are not equal So let's say twelve point five and thirteen point two
the equals is false because they're not equals and they're not equals is true because they are not equals.
OK.
Now this is the example that I want to run to show you something that may not be real obvious.
Let's say we want to enter two doubles separated by a space and then type in twelve point zero and eleven
point a lot of nines.
Now to us those are not the same number but remember the way the computer stores floating point numbers
it stores approximations.
So that might be surprising as far as the computer is concerned.
Those numbers are equal because the representation that it's using to store them behind the scenes is
equal.
OK so it's important to understand that if you're dealing with applications that need this kind of precision
you know scientific application medical applications many many safety critical type applications you
would not use these built in doubles we would use specific specialized libraries that really help us
deal with this so that 12.0 is not equal to eleven point nine nine nine.
OK.
So it's important to understand that but the way that it stores it is an approximation.
So as far as the computer is concerned these are the same.
So let's do one more and I'll leave that double declaration there and I'll uncomment this last piece
of code here and here I'm just grabbing an integer and a double.
So we're doing some mixed mode comparison here.
Run it and it says give me an integer and a double separated by a space.
In this case I could say 10 and ten point zero.
You remember what happens it's using an operator to compare two different types.
It doesn't want to do that.
This types have to be the same.
So the 10 will be promoted to a ten point zero.
And then the comparison happens.
That's the mixed mode expressions.
So what we're doing here is we're eventually comparing 10.0 and 10.0.
So we expect this to be true and it is right there and you get the same sort of issue here if I say
10 and nine point ninety nine a whole bunch of nines.
What's going to happen again is the 10 will be promoted to ten point zero ten point zero nine point
a bunch of nines as far as the internal representation is concerned are equal.
So there's your True.
OK so that it finishes off this video and that's it I'll see in the next video.