In this video we'll learn about C++ is switch statement as you've already seen.
It's very common to have to execute specific sections of code depending on the value of a constant for
this particular use case the switch statement comes in very useful.
Well learn the switch case break and default keywords the syntax for the switch date is a little more
involved than the if statement but it's not too bad once you understand what it's doing.
First we have the switch keyword which is followed by the control expression inside parentheses.
This control expression must evaluate to an integral type or an enumeration type.
Then you have a series of case statements enclosed in curly braces.
The value of the control expression will be compared to the values following the case keywords.
These case statements must also evaluate to an integral or enumeration type and must be known at compile
time.
That means there must be constants or literals when the value of the control expression matches the
case expression.
Then the code after the colon is executed until you hit a break statement.
The break statements are optional.
But best practice is to include break statements for every case statement.
Unless you've got a really good reason not to.
In the next several slides will go through the behavior of a switch statement with and without break
statements.
Finally a switch statement can have a default case at dnd that will execute when none of the cases is
true.
This is similar to that catch all else at the bottom of an IF statement.
The break statement is not needed in the default case.
Let's see some examples of the various forms of the switch statement.
In this example selection is a character type.
Which of course is also an integral type.
We assumed that the user has entered a character at the keyboard and it's been assigned to selection.
We can write IF ELSE IF statements to execute code depending on the character entered.
But in this case we can use a switch statement since the control expression is an integral type and
the case statement contains character literals to match.
So suppose the user enters the character to the switch will start at the first case statement and compare
the two to the literal expression.
Following the case keyword.
So the two will first be compared to the one.
Since this is not true we proceed and check the next case statement.
In this case we have a match so all the code following the colon will be executed.
Notice that we can have multiple statements here without the need for a block.
However if you need to declare variables in this section then you need to put the curly braces in for
a block so we displayed two selected.
Then we execute the break statement which completes the switch statement.
No further cases will be checked when we continue with the rest of the program.
Notice that in the case of 3 and 4 we display 3 or 4 has been selected and then we're done with this
switch.
This is handy since we can write logic that's equivalent to an OR statement as we see in this case.
Finally the switch has a default case.
If none of the previous case statements match then we execute the default.
Which in this case displays 1 2 3 4 not selected.
No break is needed in the default statement.
Also the default statement is optional but it's best practice to include one.
Let's look at an example where we don't have some break statements.
This is an example of the fall through behavior of the switch statement.
Notice that there are no break statement in cases 1 2 and 3.
Case 4 is the only case that has a break statement.
Suppose a user enters the character one and it was assigned to selection.
We checked the first case statement and it matches.
So we execute the code following the colon.
In this case we display one selected.
Now we continue executing code going straight down the switch statement until we hit a break statement.
So in this case we also display two selected and three selected and four selected.
Finally we hit a break statement in case 4 and we're done with the switch.
Remember once a match is made all the code in the switch cases including And following that match will
be executed until we hit a break statement.
No other conditions will be checked.
This sort of logic can be handy in some cases when you want to execute a subset of statements depending
on various conditions.
However this should not be the way you normally code a switch statement.
Best practice is to include a break statement in every case statement.
If you need logic that falls through.
Please document the code and be very clear in the documentation that the follow through behavior is
what you intended.
If another programmer sees the code and needs to modify it they'll understand this and be very careful
when adding or removing new conditions or statements.
Let's see an example of using a switch statement with an enumeration.
In this example we see an example of using a switch statement with an enumeration type.
We have an enumeration type called color with three enumeration constants red green and blue.
We also have a variable name screen color which we initialize to green but it can hold any of the three
enumeration constants using this enumeration variable in the switch statement is a very common use case
and a great way to execute code depending on its value.
In this case we switch off the screen color which can only be red green or blue and we execute the appropriate
code when we match the specific value.
Also notice that in this case we're supplying a default case but this should never execute unless we
add another enumeration constant to our enumeration and forget to include a case for it.
So let's review what we learned about the switch statement.
The control expression must evaluate to an integral type.
The switch statement is commonly used with enumeration types.
The case expressions must be known at compile time so only constants are literals can be used.
No variables once a match occurs.
All code in the following case statements is executed until a break statement is reached.
Finally best practice is to always include break statements for each case and also provide a default
case.
Let's head over to the ID and see some switch statements in action.
I'm in the ID in the section 9 workspace in the switch project and what we're going to do we're going
to do a little program here that uses a switch statement.
We're going to ask the user what grade they expect on an exam that will be a character a b c d f and
we'll tell them what they need to score to get it.
OK so I made a start here where we have a letter grade a character and that's what the user is going
to enter.
We prompt the user to enter the letter grade they expect on the exam and we read that into letter grade.
OK so now what we want to do is we want to switch off of letter grade.
It's a character so that's definitely an integral type.
So we'll say switch
and we want to switch off letter grade.
Well put in the syntax I need which is the open and Curley's for my switch statement.
Now what we have in here is we need to provide the cases now in this case we can provide upper and lower
case for each character so we could say case lowercase a and case upper case a.
I want the same behavior because the user could certainly type of a lower case.
So if they type a lowercase or an upper case they almost say is C out.
Let's say you need a 90 or above and we'll tell them to study hard.
OK.
So that will be the statement for that specific case.
We need a break.
Otherwise word will fall through I don't want to fall through in this example and let's do the be case
again lower case and upper case.
And also remember them using single quote marks here because these are characters.
So in the case of a B.
That's what they want most.
Say something like you need 80 to 89 for a b and we'll say Go study
and I'll use that line here.
And again I want to break
that to our c case.
So there are a couple left.
So there's my lowercase c is my uppercase C and in this case I'll just say up put a.
Something like you need 70 to 79
for an average grade that say
and roll and line.
Here again a break will do the DKs
and here will say something like I don't know Hmm
actually you should strive for a better grade.
I was just saying all you need is 60 to 69 or something like that
and will put an end line here as well.
Of course the break is required here because I don't want to fall through.
And then in the case of F again lowercase f or uppercase f
hear what just you see out is just put a little placeholder here to test ourselves because we want to
add a little bit of code here once we finished this example OK and we'll break out of here.
Our default he's going to say something like Sorry that's not a valid grade.
And I think we're pretty much done here.
OK and we clean that up just a little bit.
So let's look through this right before we run it.
We're grabbing the letter from the letter grade from the user was switching off of it.
We're checking for lower case upper case a we've got a message to be the c to d the f.
And sorry not a valid grade and we'll get back to the effort a little bit we'll write some code in there.
So let's execute this
actually the letter grade you expect.
I want to say you need 90 or above.
Study hard.
OK let's do the beat.
I'll do a lower case b this time.
You did 80 89 for a Bigos study and let's do the F
and then there's my axis.
OK.
So what we want to do now is in this case right here in the F case let's ask them Are you sure you really
want an F.
Neither did you type this incorrectly.
So what we want to do is we want to read a little if else if statement here and I'm going to declare
a variable in here so I want to be sure that I'm using a block and I want to use the block right in
here like this OK.
So I want to get rid of this guy.
You know I want to put the break inside this block.
Sometimes the ideas don't put those Curley's in the right places and think it's ok now.
OK so this is the logic I want here.
So I want to have another character and I want to actually confirm because I want to confirm that they
really want an F and will initialize it to going to zero.
And then we'll say see out.
Are you sure.
Or something like that.
Say yes.
No
OK so they'll they'll enter a yes or no and I'll read in to confirm again so they're going to type in
a character either yes or no hopefully.
So what do we do.
Well let's say if they type in a yes uppercase or lowercase we'll give them a message.
If they type in a no we'll give them another message and we've got to make sure that they types a yes
or no if they're typed anything else we'll give them a little message that says I have no idea what
you're saying.
OK.
So let's do that.
They say if the on the Confirm character is equal to a lowercase y for the confirmed character is equal
to an upper case why Remember don't forget to do the double equal signs here because we're comparing.
So if that's the case and I'm not going to use any in the block statements here I don't need to just
say out OK.
I guess you didn't study
because you don't want to study right.
You know you've been in line here Els let's check to see if they actually type.
No it could be anything else now right.
All we know is that it's not a yes.
So in this case we'll say else if confirm is a little lower case and or again confirm is an upper case
and
then we'll just simply say something like see out good go study.
So now here we need that catch all else right at this point.
They typed something in.
Other than a yes or no.
So what do we do.
Here we tell them boy you really do want that airfreight we'll just say out illegal choice or something
or something more clever if you like.
Ok that should do it now.
Because I'm creating and declaring that character right here.
I need those Curley's inside the block.
Otherwise if I was not declaring a variable here I don't need to put the Curley's but once I have to
declare a variable I need those Curley's.
So let's execute this and see what's going on.
OK so what's the letter grade the only one I really changed was the F so let's type the F and now it
says are you sure I'll say yes OK I guess you didn't study exactly what we expect.
Let me read it again with the f..
Are you sure.
No good.
Go study.
And then we'll just give it another character and we'll go F and let's say are you sure Q illegal choice.
There you go.
So here you can see some logic using the switch statement with a character which is an interval type.
A bunch of literals here with the lowercase A's and so forth.
And in the case f we've got some if else if logic going on as well.
So you could see that the logic for this is pretty straightforward.
The case switch statement makes it nice to do it's kind of long.
The code is pretty wordy but it's very very easy to see very easy to understand.
And when you read this I mean it can't get much clearer than that right you switching off a letter grade
if it's an error and a or a B or A B.
Really really clear indentation again and style really really important if everything here was at the
same level all the way on the left hand side.
It would be really really hard to read and figure out what goes where.
OK so that takes care of the switch statement in this context.
Next we'll do the switch statement using an enumeration and we'll do that one really quickly.
OK so I've switched to the switch in room project and I've started it already so let's go over it here
what I've done here as I've created an enumeration type called direction.
And you could see it right here between lines 10 and 12 and the numeration constants are left right
up and down.
So it's pretty straightforward.
Remember when you declare an enumeration you're creating a new type.
So we can create variables of that type so heading is of type direction just like we could have said
I's in int and we're initializing it to left which is one of those enumeration constants.
OK so now what we want to do is we want to switch off of that heading heading.
Is an enumeration.
So basically it's an integral type.
Enumerations are.
So here I'm going to type and switch and I want to switch off heading in this case.
Our cases are left right up and down right.
They have to be they can't be anything else.
I mean get rid of that extra curly here so we can say case
case left and then at this point we could just say something like C out say going left just something
really simple so that we know we hit the right case and we'll put an end line here.
And of course I want to break
OK.
Most say case right and we'll do the same thing.
I just copy and paste these two lines to save a little time.
And now I'm going to compile this and you'll see the issue that we see right away.
And let me just clean this up just a little bit.
OK.
So let's compile this.
I get us and I get to run this is going left just like I expect.
Right.
But look I'm here and you've got some warnings.
The warnings are saying warning enumeration value up not handled right.
Warning enumeration value down not handle these.
This is telling you that the compiler understands that there are four enumeration constants here.
You're using an enumeration variable in your switch but you're only handling two of those cases.
Well C++ gives you the warning a lot of other programming languages now won't compile this.
This will be an error.
They force you to handle all the types.
So you could create two more types for up and down.
Or you can use a default that's going to catch everything else.
And I would just say OK here
and now no warnings.
All good.
And we're going left.
OK.
So that's really what I wanted to show you with the enumeration types when you use them with switch
statements.
I mean there's a reason you create an enumeration type right you've got these enumeration constant so
that variable Hedding could be any one of those four.
So you really should be handling all four cases in your switch or using a default to handle the fall
through in case one of them doesn't match.
OK so that finishes up this video with the switch statement.