In this video will learn about C++ as conditional operator.
This is a really neat and very useful operator.
The operator is represented by the question mark and the colon symbols.
But they aren't used next to one another.
The conditional operator is a ternary operator which means that it operates on three operands.
The first operand is the conditional expression which is usually in parentheses.
The conditional expression is evaluated first and it must evaluate to a boolean or true false value.
Then we follow the conditional expression with the question mark.
Part of the conditional operator followed by expression 1 then the colon part followed by expression
2.
This may sound complicated but it's really super simple.
The conditional expression is evaluated if it's true then the expression returns the value of expression
1.
If it's false then the expression returns the value of expression 2.
You can see it's like an if else construct in a single expression.
While this operator is very handy It's also easy to abuse.
Best practice is to never nested conditional operator expression within another one.
This leads to if else if logic that quickly becomes unreadable and difficult to manage.
Let's see some examples of the conditional operator in this example.
We have variables A and B initialized to 10 and 20 respectively.
We also have score initialized to 92 and result initialized to zero.
The first assignment statement uses the conditional operator on the right hand side.
First we evaluate a greater than B if A is greater than B then the value of A is assigned to the result.
If it is not greater than B then we assigned the value of beach a result.
That set you see is very straightforward.
You can see this works exactly like an if statement but it's more concise.
The second example evaluates if a is less than B.
If this is true then the value of B minus a is assigned to result.
Otherwise the value of a minus B is assigned to result in 13.
But we're using the conditional operator to avoid a divide by zero error.
First we check if B is not equal to zero.
If this is true then we divide a by B and assign the result back to result.
Otherwise we simply assign zero to the result.
Notice how we're avoiding a divide by zero error by making sure that B is not equal to zero before we
divide.
Finally we often see the conditional operator used in output statements.
In this case we check if score is greater than 90 and if it is we display excellent.
Otherwise we display good.
You can see the conditional operator can be very handy and easy to read and understand when it's used
this way.
Let's head over to the ID and see it in live code.
Ok so no I'm in code like.
I'm in the section 9 workspace in the conditional operator project and what I'd like to do is just go
over a couple of real simple examples of using the conditional operator.
First of all write it using regular if else statement then move right.
Using the conditional operator OK so let's get started.
Let's create a variable here call it number and this is what the user is going to turn into.
Into.
We're going to save it in to here will prompt the user to enter an integer
and will read that integer into Gnome.
OK simple as that.
Now what we want to know is we want to know whether the integer they typed in is even or odd.
So let's use a simple if else statement will say if the number they entered mod 2 is equal to zero.
OK in this case we're dividing by two and we're looking at the remainder so obviously if it's an even
number the remainder will be 0.
That's what we're testing.
So in this case we'll just see C out.
Let's say numb
is even
in the else case.
Obviously it has to be odd.
OK so that's real simple logic here.
Let's test this out.
For d l and the end line.
OK so an even integer let's say we want to type in 6 6 is even.
That's correct.
More one more time with seven.
Seven is odd.
Simple as that.
Now let's rewrite this if else statement.
Just using a simple conditional operator that's inside the output statement.
So will say C out and will say something dumb.
Now here's we'll put the conditional operator numb is and right here is where I will put the conditional
operator OK.
So in this case we need to wrap this up and put the conditional operator right in here so we're going
to test to see if numb mod 2 is equal to zero.
If that is the case then I've got my question marks which gives me the true side and I'll just say even.
And the colon.
Odd.
That's it.
And we'll end this with a new line as well.
Let's run this to see what it looks like.
So put into it we can see both of those statements fire.
Because we've got the regular if statement going.
And let's try to run it again with three.
There we go.
Now let's see what's really going on here.
In this case again we are testing to see if the number is even if this is true then this piece is the
one that's going to be able to get an output operator here and one insertion operator.
So this is going to be replace this whole thing right here will be replaced with even the string even
if it's false.
It will be replaced with odd.
So we've got the same thing going on here right now is even numbers odd except that it's all in one
statement like that.
Dismay.
You may be wondering why in the world would you do this.
Well a lot of times it's really handy to not have this sort of logic here but rather put something right
in a print statement.
So suppose we've got some sort about put statement and we've got a looping thing going on and every
tenth time I need to do something I need to print something different.
It's real handy to use this operator in that context because it makes your code a lot cleaner and if
you use it properly like this it's really easy to understand.
OK let's do another example and I'll comment this out here.
And let's just do a real simple example is going to compare two integers.
And so we need those two integers here.
MCCOLLUM number one and them to
and look tell the user to enter two integers separated by a space
OK.
And we'll read into those two integers.
Number one and number two.
All right.
So in this case I want to display the largest in the smallest of those two integers.
But I want to do it using the conditional operator.
So the first thing we need to do is we need to see if the integers are the same right.
If they are the same then we'll just say they're the same.
There is no largest or smallest.
So let's do that logic first.
So we say if someone is not equal to number two in this case we want to say OK one is bigger than the
other which is biggest which is smallest right.
The Else case means that they're the same.
So let's handle that case first.
So I'll just say see out and we'll just say something like the numbers are the same.
And I put a new line at the end.
OK.
Now this is the logic we need to figure out now we need to figure out what's the largest And what's
the smallest I could write an IF fell statement in here a couple of times right.
But in this case I'm just going to do it right in line with an output statement.
So let's do the first one we'll say see out and what I want to do here as I just said the largest because
that's what we get to look for first.
And now we'll use the conditional operator.
So again I put the Prendes in there and put in and mine at the end might as well do it now.
Now the logic in here says OK let's test to see if someone is greater than number two.
Right.
If it is used the conditional operator and display number 1 if it's not I display number two.
That's it.
Simple as that.
It Over here will say seek out
smallest
and the same sort of logic that come right into the Perrin's right in here.
And what we'll do is we'll test in this case number one less than two.
And if it is one otherwise I'm to OK that's it let's run this
he says that should have been number one
and tried to introduce separated by space do the equal case first.
The numbers are the same.
That's good.
Let's do a five in the 10 largest is 10 smallest is five.
And let's do a 10 or five
largest ten smallest is still 5 so we're good.
So here's a real simple example of using the conditional operator will use the conditional operator
in a couple places as the course progresses.
And typically it's going to be inside a loop as we're looping and we want to do something every fifth
time tenth time.
You know that say every fifth time you want to print a new line or something like that.
Then this makes a lot of sense to do it inside right inside an output statement like this.