In this video we'll learn about the C++ while loop the while loop as an example of a pretest loop because
the test is done at the beginning of the loop.
So it's possible that if the test fails immediately then the loop body will never execute the syntax
for the while loop is the key word while followed by an expression in parentheses.
This expression has to evaluate to a boolean value.
This is followed by the statement or statement block to execute if the expression evaluates to true.
In this slide we can see a simple while loop that simply counting.
We have a looping variable named I and we initialize it to 1.
The loop condition is I less than or equal to 5.
So as long as I is less Center equal to 5 we continue executing the loop body in the body of the loop.
We display the variable by and then increment it by one.
Eventually I become six and the loop condition fails and the loop terminates.
It's important that we increment it in the body of the loop.
If we don't then the loop will never terminate.
Since I will always be one which is less than or equal to 5 This is called an infinite loop and it's
not usually what we want.
I'll talk about an infinite loops in a later video in this section because sometimes they can be useful.
Let's see another example let's write a while loop that displays the even numbers between 1 and 10 just
as we did with the for loop.
In this case we declare and initialize it to 1.
Since this is where we want to start looping then in the loop condition we'll check to see if it is
less than or equal to 10.
So in other words we will loop while I as less Center equal to 10.
And then at each iteration we execute the body of the loop.
In this case we have an if statement that uses the module operator to see if it's an even number if
it is then we display it.
Then we increment it.
Note that we increment i regardless of whether it's even or not.
Eventually becomes 11 and the loop terminates.
Let's see another example of using a while loop with an array.
In this example we're using a while loop to iterate over an array.
The array is named scores and it's an array of three integers.
We set the integer to zero since array indexes begin at zero and we loop while I's less than three as
we've done an other array code in the loop body we display scores.
So by then increment i when i becomes 3 the condition fails and the loop terminates.
Loops are commonly used in programming to provide input validation.
In this example we want to use her to enter an integer less than 100.
If they don't.
We want to ask them again and again and again until they enter a valid integer.
So we declare a variable named number and initialize it to 0.
Notice now how we prompt the user for the integer and read it from the console before the loop begins.
Now we have the value they entered in number.
The loop condition is now evaluated.
And if the user's number is not greater than or equal to 100 then we have a valid number and we never
go into the loop.
We simply print the thanks message at the end.
However if the user enters an integer that is greater than or equal to 100 we go into the loop and ask
for another integer.
Read it in and then we test again.
This will continue until the user enters a number less than 100.
Notice that we have some duplicated code here.
We have the same output and input statements outside the loop and inside the loop.
This is usually a clue that the code could be better.
We'll make this code better in the next video when we discuss the do while loop.
But this kind of code is commonly seen.
Let's see another example in this example we asked the user to enter a number between 1 and 5.
Notice the code is very similar to our previous example with the exception of the condition in the loop.
In this case we're testing both ends.
So if the number is less than or equal to one it's not valid.
We also test number greater than equal to 5 which is also invalid.
If either of these conditions is true then the number is invalid.
So that's why we use the logical or here in this example we use a boolean flag to control our while
loop.
First we declare a boolean variable named done and we set it initially to false.
The idea is that when this variable becomes true then the user entered a valid number.
So the loop test while not done not done will be true since we set it to false so we enter the loop
in the body of the loop.
We prompt the user for a number and read it.
If the number is not valid we display an error message and loop again since done is still false.
If the number is valid we display thanks and said the done flag to true.
Now the loop condition will fail and we exit the loop.
There are many ways to write logic and to achieve the same outcome.
Always remind yourself of the KISS principle.
Keep it simple stupid or keep it short and simple or keep it simple and straightforward.
However you want to think of it.
Basically don't be too clever.
Keep your code as simple as possible.
Let's head over to the ID see some other examples of the wild.
I'm in the section 9 workspace in the wild loop project.
What I want to do is write a couple of wild loops some day count down when that counts up in a couple
of more and more complicated ones.
In this case I've already written one that counts down.
So the idea is we ask the user to enter positive integer to start the count down and then we start the
countdown and we blast off when we get to 1.
So if they type in 5 we'll say five four three two one blastoff.
OK so let's walk through this code so you can understand it.
First thing we're doing is we're defining that name right up here that's where the use is going to enter
the number into and let's say they entered a three.
So they're going to enter the three and we're going to store it in.
So I've gotten over here and it's value is three right now.
Now we checked this condition is three greater than zero.
Well that's true.
So we execute the output statement which says just displayed Nahm and I'll do that over here on the
display of three.
And then I decremented Um remember when it's all alone on a line like this the predicament in a post
that means exactly the same thing.
So I just changed from a three to a two.
I go back up and test the condition again is to greater than zero.
It is I output the number which is 2 and then I decremented to 1.
I'll check the condition again is one greater than zero it is so display the one then I decrement this
to a zero and I check the condition one final time in this case zero greater than zero is not true.
So I stop and I end up executing that line right after the loop blastoff.
So what we end up with is three two one blastoff.
OK.
So that's a good way to walk through it.
And what we'll do is we'll run this and let's do it with a 10.
And then you can see the code going ten nine eight seven six five four three two one blastoff.
OK so now let's write a while loop that counts up soil comment this coda right here and I'll paste some
code that I've already written to save a little time.
And let's walk through this code.
In this case notice that I'm defining again declaring and defining this same variable name to be an
integer.
I asked the user to enter a positive integer to count up to.
So in this case I want to count from 1 to whatever they typed in.
And I'm reading that.
So again suppose they typed in a three.
So now I've gotten some and it's value here is three.
I can't do what I did up here with just a single variable because I don't want to change numb.
Numb is my target as to where I'm going to stop.
So I need another counting variable or looping variable in this case.
I want to use I.
So I've got I over here and I'm initialising I one because that's where I want to start counting at.
So I becomes one.
All right.
Now we do the loop we test the condition is none greater than the equal to I.
So is three greater than or equal to 1 in this case.
This is true.
So what we do is we display I and I'll do the display over here will display I which is 1 and then we
increment I.
So now it is 2.
We do the loop condition again is numb which is three greater than or equal to two.
It is we execute the body of the loop so we print out which is now 2 k.
Hope you guys are with me.
I increment I I now becomes three.
Then I go back up and I test the loop again.
Is numb which is always going to be three is number greater than or equal to three.
It is right.
Three is equal to three.
I want to output I again I use three and then I increment I now becomes four will test one more time
is for greater than
or sorry is three greater than or equal to
it is not.
So it fails at this point.
Now we come down here and whatever statement would be here we would execute.
OK.
So you can see that walking through these examples is pretty easy to do it's kind of time consuming
but once you get used to the logic you can pretty much do a lot of it in your head.
OK so let's do another one now and clear this up and I'll comment this all out again.
So in this case what we want to do is we want to do some input validation.
And I've written the code again let me paste it in and let me indent all this.
I don't know why it puts all flush left.
There we go.
OK so we've got an integer here called number that we've declared and we've initialized it to zero and
we're asking the user to enter an integer less than 100.
And we're reading that into that variable number.
Right now we want to loop.
Remember we want an integer less than 100.
So we want to loop while that number they entered is not less than 100 so we could say not less than
100 or greater than or equal to 100.
Either case will work here.
So in other words if the number they entered is greater than or equal to 100 it's not valid.
So in that case we'll just ask them to enter an integer less than 100 again or prompting them to enter
it and we're reading it and then we're just checking that while statement over and over and over.
When this condition fails that's when we have a valid number.
OK.
So let's run this and we'll print out.
Thanks when we have a valid number at the end.
So let's run this and see what it looks like.
Let's see I want to injure less than 100 let's let's do it correctly.
We'll type in 50 and we get a thanks but if we run it and type in a number that's not less than 100
or so we typed in 120.
It prompts me again I'm in the loop now so say 100 15 thousand.
It'll just keep going forever until I type in a valid number.
And basically this is the basics of input validation.
So ninety nine that's valid.
Thanks.
OK.
So there you go you can walk through this the same way that I walk through the other one.
Notice that you can write this condition in here.
A lot of different ways because greater than or equal to 100 or not less than 100.
So there's different ways that you can write that condition and you'll see it all kinds of ways out
there.
All right.
So the last example I want to do is one using a flag a boolean flag to do input validation.
So let me come at this out and copy that code in real quick.
OK so there's the code and I will walk through this real slow and in detail so you can see what's going
on.
This is a common use case and this is a kind of code you see out there a lot.
So in this case we've got a flag called done and we're initializing it to faults.
Faults means that we're not done right.
We still need to get more input from the user for whatever reason either we haven't started yet or they've
entered something illegal or out of range.
And I've got this variable right here that I've declared here called number that's the integer.
That's what we're going to read into.
Now it's important that we set that flag to false to begin because that's how we're getting into this
loop.
The first time.
So don't just leave that to true or just don't leave it at nothing and take a chance that it is false.
Explicitly said it's a false because that's going to get us in that loop the first time.
So the first time we're going to say while not done well it isn't done right it's false.
So we're in here and we ask to use to enter an integer between 1 and 5 and they type the number right
there.
We're going to store it in the variable number.
Now we do a check if the number is less than or equal to one.
Remember we want numbers.
There's the one Here's the five.
So we want numbers between there.
Right.
So we want 2 3 or 4 1 and 5 are not valid in this case.
So if the number is less than or equal to 1 in other words the number is over here somewhere.
Or the number is greater than or equal to 5.
So the numbers over here somewhere then it's out of range.
So we simply display out of range.
Try again.
Notice how we didn't change the Dunn flag.
Dunn is still fault's right.
So at this point we just executed that statement.
We don't do the else part and we loop right back up to here.
Right.
Dunn is still false so we're going to go right back into the loop and output again and try an integer
between 1 and 5.
Grab the integer and so forth.
Now when you do type an integer that's in range.
Suppose we typed in a three then this if statement fails here and we go to the else and all we're doing
here is saying thanks and then we set that flag to true.
This is like super super important here don't forget to do that.
That means we are done.
So when we loop back up again here that condition fails and we're out of the loop.
OK.
So hopefully you can walk through this and just take it a step at a time and really understand it.
The challenge exercise at the end of this section is pretty tricky and hard challenge but it uses this
kind of logic to ensure that you know you've got input validation and you're going to prompt the user
every time that they are not in range.
Right so let me clear this and let's run this example.
So we're going to enter an integer between 1 and 5.
Let's say we type 1 1 is not valid.
We want it to be between 1 and 5 again to 3 or 4.
So that's no good.
Five is no good.
70 is no good.
Right.
Negative 12 is no good.
So let's give it something good just give it a three something that's right in the middle.
Thanks.
So you can see that and using this kind of logic is better than using this sort of logic where you've
got a statement repeated here and then the same statement over here and you've got duplicated code.
We don't have that here.
And the reason we don't have that here is because we're using that flag to really decide whether we're
in the loop or not.
Now in the next video we'll talk about a do while loop where we're doing the condition at the end and
that makes this kind of code even nicer.
OK so that's the end of this video.
Please try these examples yourself come up with your own versions of them and walk through them so that
you really understand the logic and what's going on.