In this video you'll like it to continue and break statements in C++ that continue and break statements
can be used within all of C++ loop constructs to provide more explicit control over the looping behavior.
Their behavior is really easy to understand when a continued statement is executed in the loop.
No further statements in the body of the loop are executed and control immediately goes directly to
the beginning of the loop for the next iteration.
So you can think of this as Skip processing and the rest of this iteration and go to the beginning of
the loop.
In the case of the while loop and the for loop the condition will immediately be tested again.
When the break statement is executed in the loop no further statements in the body are executed in the
loop is terminated.
So control is transfer to the statement immediately following the loop.
Let's see an example that uses both the continue and break statements.
In this example we have a vector of integers.
Let's assume that this data comes from some sort of device and occasionally we get noise in the data.
The noise is represented by the minus one.
We really don't want to process the noise we want to ignore it.
We also need to stop processing when we get to stop signal which is represented by minus 99.
In this case we can use the range based for loops.
Iterate over all the vector elements at each iteration we can check if the value is minus 99 in which
case we are done.
We could set a flag to done and handle that done boolean in the loop condition as we've done before.
Or we can simply break out of the loop.
In this case we're using the break statement to break out of the loop completely in the else statement.
We know we haven't seen a negative ninety nine so we can check from minus 1 that represents noise if
we see it we can continue.
This stops the iteration and control goes back to the beginning of the loop and a new iteration begins.
Finally if we hit the L statement we know we don't have a minus 99 and we know we don't have a minus
one.
So we process that data.
In this case we just display it in this example we display 1 to 3 continue and break statements are
very very easy to use.
However don't overuse them.
I'm obviously exaggerating here but if you have a loop that has 10 breaks and 12 continues in its body
that's a very complex piece of code to try to understand the less ways that you can come into a loop
and out of the loop the better we can understand and debug it we'll see the breaks didn't.
But again when we talk about infinite loops in the next video.