In this video we'll learn about infinite loops an infinite loop is often called an endless loop an infinite
loop is a loop whose control expression always evaluates to true.
So it iterates over and over usually infinite loops or mistakes by the programmer.
If you have an infinite loop it's pretty easy to know since the program does something or does nothing.
Over and over again.
So we find and fix the problem.
However sometimes infinite loops are written as infinite loops on purpose and programmers use break
statements and strategic places to eventually break out of the loop.
There are cases where this makes sense and could be justified.
However writing an infinite loop and using break statements to terminate the loop is usually bad practice
and should be rewritten so the loop condition expression is descriptive of what the loop is doing.
Here are a couple of examples of infinite loops that are appropriate and in fact necessary Infinity
event loops are commonly used and event driven programs such as those you find on mobile devices and
embedded systems in these programs the program loops forever listening for mouse clicks mouse movements
touches and so forth and reacting to them.
This continues as long as the program is running.
Another example of an endless loop is an operating system an operating system is constantly looping
handling input output handling resources and so forth.
It only shuts down when you shut down your computer.
Let's see a few examples of infinite loops in C++.
First let's look at an infinite for loop.
Remember that all three expressions in the for loop are optional.
So if you omit all three you get just two semi-colons.
By definition in C++ that's an infinite loop.
The output statement will be displayed as long as the program is running.
Let's look at a while loop.
Here's an example of an infinite while loop.
It's probably exactly what you were thinking of.
While true will always be true and the output statement will execute over and over again.
Of course we don't have to use the true keyword.
We can use an expression that's always true.
So if we say while 10 is less than 12 since 10 is always less than 12 it a loop forever.
You get the idea.
Finally let's look at an infinite do while loop again.
The loop condition will always be true.
So the output statement repeats forever.
OK so what.
Why would I ever do this.
Well you might write an event loop like this but more often you see code that looks more like the following.
Note that in this example we have an infinite loop since while true will always be true.
However we have a strategically placed break statement that terminates the loop.
Let's walk through the example inside the loop.
We declare a character variable named again.
We asked the user if they want to loop again and read their response as a character into the variable
again.
If again is uppercase and or lowercase and then we break and terminate the loop if they enter anything
else we loop again.
This is an example of an endless loop that might be ok.
However best practice suggests that the loop condition be more informative of when the loop iterates.
If I was doing the code review of this code I would refactor it to do just that.
However you do see code like this out there and now you know how it works.
That completes this video in the next video.
We'll see how we can nest loops one within the other.