In this video we'll go over using nested loops just like we nested if statements one inside the other.
The same technique can be used to nested loops we can nest loops as many levels deep as we need.
I'll be using just two levels and the examples I'll show you.
That is one loop inside another nested loops have many uses but they're especially useful for multi
dimensional structures like 2D 3D arrays in 2D and 3D vectors.
When we talk about nested loops it's common to refer to the loops as the outer loop and the inner loop.
Let's see some examples.
Here's a pretty generic example of a nested loop.
In this case we have a for loop with another for loop within it.
The outer loop is incrementing outer value from 1 to 2 by 1 the inner loop is incrementing interval
from 1 to 3 by 1 noticed the output the integer to the left of the comma is the outer vowel and the
integer to the right of the comma is the interval.
Notice how interval increments from 1 to 3 while outer vowel remains at one then outer Valot increments
to two.
And we do it all over again.
You can think of this as the outer loop iterating two times and each time the inner loop iterates three
times.
That's why we say that the inner loop loops faster than the outer loop.
But see another example in this example we can take advantage of a nested loop to display the multiplication
table from 1 to 10.
A nested loop is perfect since we want 1 times 1 1 times 2 1 times 3.
All the way to 1 times 10.
Then we want to do two times 1 2 times 2 and so forth.
So we want an outer loop iterating from 1 to 10 and an inner loop also iterating from 1 to 10 and the
body of the inner loop simply multiplies the outer loops variables times the inner loops variable.
Notice the output statement after the inner loop that displays a line of dashes.
This executes each time the inner loop completes will execute this loop in the idea in a minute so you
can see it work.
Let's see an example of a nested loop using a to array.
In this example we have a two dimensional array of integers named grid grid has five rows and three
columns.
Suppose we want to assign 1000 to each element in the grid.
We can do this easily with nested for loops.
The outer loop iterates four rows 0 to 4 inclusive and the inner loop iterates the columns for each
from 1 to 2 inclusive.
Then in the body of the loop we simply assign 1000 to grids Sobero same column.
Notice I'm using block statements for the body of these loops.
I didn't have to here but it's good practice to do so since it makes adding code later much easier.
Now that we've initialized the grid values to a thousand we can use a similar nested loops to display
the values in this example we're assuming the grid has been initialized as in the previous slide at
each iteration of the inner loop.
We display the element at grid Cerebro sum column followed by space.
So we're displaying these elements across the screen.
When we complete the inner loop we print a new line and then execute the outer loop again.
You can see the pattern is the same as with initialization.
This is a very common pattern for working with multi dimensional structures.
Let's see how we can use nested loops with vectors in this final example.
We declare a vector of vector of integer.
So we have a vector whose elements are vectors of integers.
Very similar to a 2D array of integers with the advantage of vectors with a vector of vectors we can
allow each vector within the vector to D to be of different size.
In this case we have three vectors of vectors and each of those vectors is a vector of integers.
I know it sounds complicated but if you look at the example it should be pretty clear.
The first vector has three integers 1 2 3.
The second vector has 4 integers 10 20 30 40.
The third vector has 5 integers 100 200 300 400 and 500.
If we wanted to display the contents of vector to d we could do it easily with nested range based for
loops and if we use the auto keyword to allow the compiler to deduce the type of each loop element it
makes it dead simple.
Notice the outer loop in this case the compiler deduces VEC to be a vector of integers and in the inner
loop it reduces vow to be an integer in the body of the inner loop.
We simply display the value followed by space as we did in the previous example would display a new
line after we're done displaying the inner vector values.
You can see how little code and how simple the code is.
You can see the output from this loop at the right on the screen.
In these examples I've used for loops within four loops but you can use any combination of loops within
any other loop to achieve your desired behavior.
Let's head over to code light and see some of these examples live.
OK so I mean the code like ID.
I mean these still in the section 9 workspace and I mean the multiplication table project.
This is the piece of code that executes and displays a multiplication table for up to 10 by 10.
So let's go over this really carefully.
This is a classic example of a nested loop.
Notice we've got the two four loops one within the other and the outer loop is looping on the number
one variable.
The inner loop is looping on the two variable.
So we're going to start the outer loop and we're going to assign right here we're going to number 1
to 1 and then we check.
Is no one less than or equal to 10.
It is.
So we go into the body of the loop while the body of this loop is another loop.
And in this case we're initialising number two to one right here.
And we check his number two less than or equal to 10.
It is.
So we execute the body of the inner loop which is this output statement right here.
So what we do here is we display number one which is one we display the asterisk string right there.
We displayed them too which is one we display that equal sign right here.
And then we multiply number one number two.
That gives us 1 and we display the value.
That's it.
We display a new line and we loop again.
So we come back up to the loop we do the increment.
So now number two is to we check is number two.
Less than or equal to 10.
It is execute the body of the loop again this time through we've gotten some one is still one right
here.
Number two is now to and we display yapper and so forth so we're going to do this until we get to 1
times 10 equals 10.
And someone will still be one.
At this point number two is 10.
Now we're going to incrementing up to 11.
We come over here and we check is number two.
Less than or equal to 10.
It's not so we fail.
Now we terminate the inner loop.
We execute this statement right here.
What's going to display a bunch of dashed lines here and then we remember we're still inside the outer
loops we have to go back out to the outer loop.
And do the increment.
So now number one becomes to is to Enrico to attend Yes we go back into the inner loop again.
So think of this says Here's your outer loop and it's looping.
And each time it loops you're going to do the inner loop 10 times that you're going to go back out outer
loop.
You're going to do the inner loop again 10 times.
OK.
My art is not pretty but hopefully it and you'll understand what I'm talking about.
All right so that's what's really going on here.
Let me clear this and run it so you can see this in action.
So there's the output.
Let me scroll up so you could see here 1 times 1 is 1 1 times 2 is two and so forth.
Notice in this case I mean move this just over here so you can see the variables over here.
This left one is number one and then you can see that number two is looping faster.
That's why we say the inner loop loops faster than the hour loop.
We go through all 10 of them then we display the dashed line then we go back out to the outer loop.
Now number one is two and then three and then all the way to the bottom where we ended up with the tens
and we end up with 10 times 10.
At this point the outer loop fails and we're done.
OK.
So hopefully that makes sense and what we'll do next is we'll do an example.
That's a little bit more complicated we'll actually grab some user input.
We'll grab some numbers put them in a vector and display a histogram based on those numbers.
OK so I'll close this and I will open up the histogram project a double click on that to make it the
active project.
Right now there's not much in here it's just a really really simple basic main that does nothing just
prints a new line.
So what do we want to do here.
We want to ask the user how many data items they have that say they type 6.
Then we ask them for each one of those data items which is just an integer.
And then when we're finished with that we'll output all that information using a histogram.
So that's pretty straightforward.
We need to ask the user how many items they've got so let's create an integer variable are called number
items and we'll just initialize that to 0 and then we'll ask them how many items you have listed data
items
OK and will read that integer into items.
So now we know how many data items they have.
What we want to do next is loop that many times if I've got five data items.
Well I want you to ask me five times to enter those data.
So it really makes sense to use a for loop here because we know exactly how many times we want to iterate.
We also need to store this information somewhere right so all that information they type in We'd like
to store it somewhere since we really don't know what number they're going to type in an array would
not be a good idea here because you don't know how big to make it.
You'd have to make it really big just to be sure that everything will fit.
So we use a vector.
First thing we'll do is we'll include vector here.
So we're going to go there and let's declare the vector right now we'll call it vector of integers in
this case.
And this is called a data because that's what it is and initialized the vector it's empty.
All right member of vectors that dynamic data structures so we'll be able to read data from the user
and put it into that vector using its push back method.
So let's loop How many times are we going to loop.
We're going to loop from 1 to that number they entered.
Right so if they enter 10 we're going to go from 1 to 10 and we're going to grab 10 data items.
So let's do that right now for it.
Pi will use I will initialize I to 1 because we want to start here at 1 and I want to loop while I.
Is less than or equal to the number of items that they want to enter into the vector will increment
by 1 each time.
I'm going to use a block statement here.
Now what do you think is going on in here.
Well I need to ask them for the data right.
I would have to say I typed in 10 items.
This is going to look 10 times.
So we need somewhere to read the data into.
That sounds like an integer means also a data item will initialize that to zero and then we'll just
say seek out no enter data item and we may as well tell them which one it is because we know it right.
I would do something like that would put a colon so it looks nice for them.
So this will say enter data item 1 and 2 Date.
Item 2 all the way up to whatever they decided they wanted.
What we do now is we read that integer that they type in into that data item variable we just created.
So we've got the data.
What do we know.
We need to put it into that vector.
Now remember how to do that.
The vectors name is data.
So we say data push back and we put that data item in there.
So it's going to put the data item in the back of the vector.
That's it.
That's pretty straightforward.
So at this point now what we've got is a vector that contains whatever data they typed hence of the
typed in five integers that vector has five images in there.
So what we want to do now.
Well we want to display the histogram But before we do that let's just display the data make sure we
have it right.
Always good to test as you go.
So let's do that.
We'll say for we'll use a range based for loop here.
Otto Vau that's the value and the collection is data
OK.
So for each element in that data collection let's just put it.
Now just to test
OK.
That's it.
Let's run this.
How many data items do you have.
Well I have five data items enter data item 1 10 to 20.
Let's just put them in tens that way we know what we're getting.
30 40 should ask me one more time.
Fifty.
Now it should be done and I'm displaying the data items.
So everything's looking good.
Let's run it again with three data items.
Let's put a thousand in here let's put a 10 in there and let's put a hundred in here 1010 twelve hundred
perfect.
So that's exactly what's going on right now.
We want to be how many items do you have and entry data for each one of those values.
So it's always a good idea to test as you go because it just makes life much much easier to test as
you go rather than try to test this big monolithic thing at the end.
All right so let me just do a quick statement here and I'll put a line in the end just to give a little
space.
I'm just going to say displaying histogram
Now what we need to do is pretty much what we did here right except we don't want to display the value.
We want to display a dash for each one of those values so for example if the values 10 we want to display
10 dashes if the values 100 will display 100 dashes.
That's what Mr. Graham looks like.
So how do I do that.
Well I need to have another loop in here and I'm just going to get rid of that right now.
So we still have this loop right here just looping through the collection.
So what do I do here.
Well I know how many times I need to loop round be to loop Vau time so a for loop is good.
We can use any loop we want really but let's use a for loop because it's really simple.
So we're going to save for it and let's use I again.
And we're going to start at one and we're going to loop while I is less Center equal to that.
That's the number we just read
OK.
Now what.
Well the increment is by 1.
We need to increment by 1.
So that's my inner loop.
What do I want to do in here.
I want to do just type hyper dash and will use dashes for a reason you could use an asterisk but I want
to use an asterisk in a second.
That's it.
So if the me fix that typo if the user typed in five integers in the first one is 6 then Vau is going
to be 6.
And we're going to loop six times displaying six dashes.
The next one is 12 are going to display 12 dashes after you were done displaying those dashes we need
to display a new line.
Otherwise everything's just going to go right across the screen.
So I'm just going to say and line right here.
And we need to close off this.
Let's do that for loop right here in a block as well.
Since we're probably going to add a little bit more code.
OK so that's where we're at now.
Actually pretty straightforward.
Let's run this and I forgot a semi-colon right there.
I put that in there
OK.
How many items do you have.
This is start simple three items.
What's the first data item.
Five 10 15.
What I expect now is three rows one with five dashes one with 10 dashes and one with 15 dashes.
Awesome that's what we've got.
Displaying histogram.
One two three four five dashes 10 dashes 15 dashes.
You see that it was pretty simple and it's pretty powerful because we've got dynamic data structure
that's growing as we need it.
Let's run this one more time with a little bit more data.
You say I have 10 data items and I've got a 10 34 and I'm just going to put some really any numbers
in here 7.
I don't want to do a 90.
Let's do a 30 let's do 50 and let's do a 1 and a to have at the bottom.
So there we go.
There's my histogram.
You can see the last two should be one in two and they are right here one and two and you could count
them if you like but I think they're correct.
Obviously you would want to count them if you were going to test them to be sure that everything is
correct.
So there is my histogram.
Pretty straightforward.
This is kind of hard to see though.
I mean how many dashes are here.
I can't really tell.
So why don't we say that every fifth dash let's display an asterisk instead.
That will make it easier to see.
OK.
So how do we do that.
We're right in here.
So we could do is we can modify this code slightly we could say if that specific county variable mod
5 is equal to zero.
So that means I'm on the fifth number right.
In this case I want to display an asterisk
otherwise so anyone else here.
I just want to display the dash and I'm in debt Dennis correctly.
There we go.
So notice the indentation here.
It's really important.
If you look at that piece of code right there you can see that I have a for loop and I've got another
four nested within it.
And that for loop has an if else statements every time that loop executes I'm executing that if statement.
OK.
So you can see the structure of the code by just looking at the code.
You don't have to try to figure it out if everything here was indented to the left.
Flush here.
Be really hard to see the structure.
So let's run this and see.
OK let's say I've got 10 data items and I've got 34 32 24 5 10.
And just some other numbers that I can put in.
And let's do two and one to get it in.
There we go.
So now you can see that every fifth number is being displayed with an asterisk.
In this case it's really easy until that's 10.
I can tell that's 19.
I think tell that's five 10 15 20 25 34 and so forth.
So it makes it much easier to interpret the data.
Here's a really easy simple example of using a nested loop.
In this case the 4:4 makes sense because we know how far we're going but we could easily rewrite this
with Wiles or do wells or anything we like.
Remember at the end of the day a loop is a loop is a loop right.
So they all do the same thing they all iterate.
It's just a matter of trying to choose the right one for the application.
So hope that helps these kinds of examples is going to be really useful in the challenge exercise which
is next.