In this section we'll talk about characters and strings.
As we've already seen the character type can hold values that represent characters.
These values are basically integers that map to a character set like the ASCII character set.
And we've also seen that strings or sequences of characters C++ supports two types of strings C-style
strings and C++ strings.
So will first look at the CC type library.
This is a library of very simple but very useful functions that work with characters.
For example we can test characters to see if they're uppercase or lowercase numeric alphanumeric punctuation
and more.
We can also convert characters between lower and upper case after we learn about the CC type functions.
We'll talk about strings.
As I said earlier you can think of strings as a sequence of characters.
So far we've only use string literals which were represented as a sequence of characters inside double
quotes.
I'll discuss both C-style strings and C++ strings in this section and give you the basics of using each.
However you should be using C++ strings in modern C plus plus I think you'll understand why at the end
of this section first we'll see what C-style strings are and how they are represented in memory.
Then we'll see how to work with C-style strings using some of the string functions available in the
C string and C standard lib libraries.
Then we'll learn about C++ strings C++ strings or objects just like our vectors were and their use using
an object oriented style of programming.
In this section we learn how to declare initialize assign compare and use some of the other C++ string
methods methods or functions that work with objects.
So let's look at C-style strings first in the next video.