In this video I'd like to go over using the C++ string class and some examples there.
So I'm in the section 10 workspace in the strings project.
Now remember the String class is a class when we create strings in this case.
Here you see him creating eight strings from zero to 7 on lines nine to 16.
These are objects.
We'll talk about exactly what objects are in the world of object oriented programming in a future video.
But we are using object oriented programming here to work with the C++ String objects.
OK.
It's important that you include the string library.
Otherwise you'll get a lot of compiler errors and I'm using the standard namespace.
First thing is let's declare and initialize some of these string objects.
Here I'm declaring as 0 through 7 you can see as 0.
I'm just saying string a 0.
It's important to understand that with classes and objects in this case 0 is an object.
I am getting an initialized object is not going to be any garbage in there and will display that in
a second.
Just so you can see what that looks like then I'm declaring other string objects here so as one is being
initialized to Apple as to the banana as three to Kiwi As for the apple and so forth.
S-5 is being initialized to us one well as one is Apple.
So a copy of that string is going to be put into S-5 so S-5 is going to be its own version of Apple.
So if I change this one it's not going to affect us five.
There's also a couple of other initializers there's a bunch of initializers and constructor style initializers
a whole bunch of examples that you can use.
But I'm just sticking to the commonly used ones in modern C++.
In this case Essex is as one of initializing it from s one which is Apple but I'm only using a part
of it.
I'm starting at index 0 and I want three characters.
So it's only going to be initialized to the string a P-P and then in this case as 7 I'm initializing
that string to 10 x characters.
Notice the Xs in single quotes here.
So that's a character.
And also notice that I'm using parentheses here and not Curley's.
This is a constructor style initialization and that's the one that works with this example.
Before we look at the initialization of values let's look at this right here.
Notice that I declared that string object is zero.
If this had been what we the example that we saw using C-style strings and we never initialized it.
You remember we saw that garbage.
You're not going to get that here.
So if I display zero you won't see anything because it's empty.
And if I ask as 0 What's your length.
This is a method.
This is an object and this is what Object-Oriented Programming is all about.
I'm asking the as zero object.
In other words this string right here.
Hey what's your length.
And it's going to return to its length.
In this case I expect back to zero because it's an empty string.
So let me run this and you can see that nothing printed out because the string is empty and I get back
as 0 which says that the string has no length that's empty.
So you can see that it is being initialized.
That's really important to other objects.
OK I'm going to comment that out and then let's look at some of these initialization examples.
I've just initialized those objects right up here where I declared them.
Now I'm just going to display them and you can see that we're getting exactly what we expected.
Here we scroll up just a little bit.
So as one is as to his banana then I've got Kiwi apple with a lowercase a apple.
An app that's that three the initialiser where we only wanted the first three characters and then I've
got 10 x's because you can see really powerful really easy way to initialize these string objects.
So now it's come at this out again and work with some of the operators and methods of the string class.
In this case I'm comparing If you recall using C-style strings we had to use the RCMP or the string
compare function pass into strings and get back either zero or a positive value or negative value and
then we'd have to check things like that.
Well here we can just use the operators that we're used to.
And I'm using the bool Alpha IO manipulator just so it displays the words true and false.
And you can see I've got a whole bunch of examples that it's actually easier to run it than to read
on that code.
But you can see here that I'm comparing apple with Apple and I get that true.
I'm comparing apple with banana.
I get back false then I'm asking.
Is Apple not equal to banana.
That's true because they're not equal.
Is Apple less than banana.
True because the capital A comes before the capital B in the ASCII table.
What about banana greater than Apple.
Yes.
Again I just flip the sign and flip the strings.
What about Apple with a lowercase.
Is that less than Apple with an upper case.
A It is not because the uppercase characters come before the lowercase characters in the ASCII table.
And then the last one I'm using is right here where I'm actually comparing an object as one with a C-style
string literal Apple.
And that works perfectly fine because what happens is this string literal right here gets converted
to an object and then we're doing Object object comparison.
So that's true.
Remember it's doing character by character comparison.
OK so real familiar real intuitive very easy to use.
Let me come at that out and let's do assignment if again if you recall with the seesaw strings we had
to do as TR RCP Y or string copy using C++ String objects we just use the assignment operator just like
we're used to.
So they feel like they're really part of the language just like you would with integers and doubles
and characters and so forth.
So in this case I'm assigning watermelon to S1 whatever was in S1 before is now gone.
I've overwritten it with watermelon and then I'm out putting as one is now and then obviously I expect
back watermelon when I say a sign as one as one is watermelon to two as two.
I'm going to get a copy of that watermelon object right.
So I'm not going to that they're not pointing to the same watermelon.
I'm going to get two copies that are individual so if I change this one it won't affect us too and vice
versa.
And if I displace two I also expect watermelon here.
Here I'm saying as three is Frank some assigning the string Frank to us three and that should also display
Frank.
Now once I've assigned these strings I can manipulate them.
So in this case I can say change to zero with character in as three while that's the F in frank right
here.
Change that to a capital C and notice single quotes because I'm changing character.
So I'm saying assign the capital C to the first element of that string right to one at the zero index.
So this would change it to a crank which will print out C R and K.
I can also use the at method.
Again this is the whole idea of Object-Oriented Programming him saying hey S-3 change the character
at position 0 to a capital P.
So when I display that it should display prank.
Let's run that and double check.
So you can see here that one is watermelon as two as watermelon as three is Frank.
And then I'm changing the first letter of Frank to crank to see Saryan displaying crank and then I'm
changing it to a P and displaying prank.
All right I'll comment this out and let's look at concatenation.
Again I'll compare this to the C-style string where we had to use the string cat function as TR C.A.T.
to concatenate two strings.
Here we could just simply use the plus operator and in this case I'm saying assign watermelon to us
3.
OK that's easy.
But now I'm saying s three equals as 5.
Well as 5 is Apple and as too is banana and juice some concatenating these one two three four strings
together by simply using the plus operator the plus operator is it's considered overloaded that means
it works with integers it works with doubles.
And in this case it works with string objects.
So what we're going to do here is we're going to say apple and banana juice and assign that to S3.
So in this case watermelon is gone.
We're overwriting that.
And then when we display history it should say apple and banana juice.
Right so let me run that quickly and there you go.
Three is now apple and banana juice just like we expect.
If you try something like this you're going to get a compiler error.
The problem here is that we've got a C style string literal and another C-style string literal and the
plus operator C-style strings don't work with the plus operator if you wanted to do something like this
you would have to use your cat and concatenate them together.
In this case you're going to get a compiler error saying something about I don't know what to do with
these two character arrays in this binary operator so keep that in mind if you're trying to use the
plus operator you've got to use it on at least one of the objects.
Notice over here we're using an object and a string literal.
That's OK because it'll convert but when you've got to C-style string literals like this it doesn't
know what to do.
Let's move on and talk about looping.
In this case we're going to use a for loop to loop through a string and remember a string is simply
a collection right a bunch of characters.
So we can easily loop through them and we'll loop through them two different ways.
First we'll use a regular for loop and then we'll use the range based loop.
In this case I'm assigning Apple to S1 just so we have something to start with right here and I'm initializing
to zero.
Notice that the type of II is size t.
This is really the proper way to do this.
It's always going to be a non-negative number right because we're looping through a string.
Now if you've got looping variables that need to go negative you don't want to use size t you just want
to use irregular integers or something that's signed.
But in these kinds of examples size is the proper type to use.
So I'm initializing to zero and I'm going to loop while I is less than the strings the length.
Remember we're going from zero to the length minus 1.
So in this case I'm asking the S1 object What's your length and it's returning 5 because it's Apple.
So I'm going to loop 0 1 2 3 4 and then I'm going to stop.
And as you see I'm incrementing one each time.
So every time through the loop all I'm doing is just simply outputting that character at the IFE location.
So see out as one dot at.
I could use array subscript syntax.
They both work.
The method does bounds checking the subscript method does not.
So when I run this I should see Apple print out across the screen.
And there it is just displaying one letter at a time.
I can also do this using the range based for loop in which case I'm just saying for every character
c in S one put it right so it's going to go a p p l E-stop.
So in this case I showed up a Schappell twice.
Now it was for the for loop and once for the range based loop you can see some of these are very very
intuitive and easy to use.
There's a couple left.
Let's talk about substring here.
This one again is very intuitive.
Suppose S One is this is a test I've just assigned that string to S1 and I want the substring that starts
at 0 and it's four long so it's going to go t h i s right the t the capital T is index 0.
So that's going to return the word this string.
This in the second substring example I'm starting at index 5 which is 0 1 2 3 4 5 so it's starting at
the high end is.
And I want two characters.
So it's grabbing.
This is right there and that's what it's returning.
And then the last one I'm starting it.
Index 10 which is lowercase T and test and I just want four back and it's giving me test.
So you can see it's very very easy.
And of course all these you can see here it's explained this is a test.
All of these are hard coded but you can certainly use very variables for these integers and loop through
and loops and grab pieces of substrings and you can do a lot of really cool stuff.
We can erase characters in this example I'm saying as one again I'm assigning this is a test to it.
And I'm erasing from S1 again.
Notice the Object-Oriented style.
Think of this almost as you're asking the one object right.
Because notice it's as one dot.
So you're saying the erase method is going to execute on that object as one because we could have asked
to doddy race as a study race anything to race right.
But in this case it's happening on esp one which is this is a test right here.
So what I'm saying here is the race starting at zero.
Any race of characters.
So it's going to be a race the capital T H the I s and the space when I display that this one is now
just the is a test part.
I got rid of this and the space from the beginning.
All right.
Let's do a couple of more.
The getline is a little bit different from the get line that we saw with C strings if you remember we
see strings we said C in getline and we had a length.
Well we're not worried about a length here because the C plus plus string class handles likes for us.
So it looks a little different but it's the same basic effect.
Here I've got a new string that I'm declaring called full name and initializing it to empty.
I'm asking the user to enter their full name and then I'm using the getline function here and I'm passing
in where I want to get the input from in this case the keyboard or C in and where I want to store the
result fullname.
This will get an entire line up until I press enter.
So and then I just display the name.
So in this case if I run this and type my name
notice full name is Frank Metropolis my entire name it doesn't stop at the space the same way that the
extraction operator does.
The last thing we'll do is look at the find method which is a real handy method.
So in this case here's the secret word the secret word is boo.
That's the string and I've got a word variable here which is a string object.
I'm asking the user to enter the war to find the idea is they're going to type one of these words in
here right.
And I'm going to tell them where that word is in the string what position it begins at.
So if I typed in the I'm saying hey s want again the as one object find that word within you.
So it's going to find the word though within it and it's going to return 0 because it starts at the
zero index right there.
That's the t again.
I'm using a size t for the type because it's always going to be right zero or greater or an error.
And we'll talk about the error in a second.
So at this point I'm looking for that word in the string and position holds its position whether it
was found or not.
How do I know whether it was found or not.
I need to see if the position returned was that value right string and position no position.
So in this case if the position I got back is not equal to that then I found it.
So I'm simply going to dispel any found word at position whatever.
Otherwise it wasn't found.
So let's run this.
And remember the string is the secret word is blue.
So I'm going to run this and search for Boo.
And it says I found it a position 19.
Read it again and we used the word secret.
This time it founded it.
Position 4.
And you could see there it is right there position 4.
And we could try to find something that's not there like hello.
And it says hello.
Now found.
OK so the wrap up this video now you have all the elements you need for the challenge.
It's coming up next.
You could certainly try the challenge using C-style strings and then C++ strings.
But I'm just going to do it using C++ strings because we really should be using C++ strings going forward.
All right so head off to the challenge.