Welcome back.
I hope you enjoyed the Sipher challenge and I hope you were successful with it and I hope you extended
it even further if you did post it on the forum.
Share what you did.
It's pretty fun stuff.
OK so what do we need.
First thing we need to do is ask the user to enter a secret message.
Right.
So let's do that first.
It's not that out before we even start writing any other code so we need a String object and we can
call that string object secret message and we'll initialize it.
That's what the user is going to type in.
So I'm going to say see out her secret message
Campbell.
Leave it just like that and let me fix that typo.
And you know what I mean just put me as proper English here and to your secret message.
Now the user's going to enter their message and we need to read it.
It's potentially more than one word.
So we can't just use C in an extraction operator.
We're going to use getline and I want to get a line of text from C in and I want to store it in secret
message OK.
So now at this point secret message that string object will contain wherever the user typed in.
Perfect.
So we want to encrypt that string.
Well I need to store the encrypted message somewhere right.
So let's create another string object and we'll call it encrypted message and we'll initialize that
as well.
That's going to hold the encrypted message once we finish encrypting it.
But at this point it's just simply empty.
So we'll do a little output statement here just so we can see some processing and we'll say something
like encrypting message
and would put an end line at the end.
All right so now we start to process what do we need to do.
Well there's a lot of different ways to do this.
Is this the easy way the harder way.
Let's talk about the harder way first.
Suppose that the message is Frank.
That's the secret message.
Well I need to iterate through that string.
Obviously I need to look at the FDR the way the I've got to do that no matter what because I've got
to look at every single character.
Well what I could do is I could read the first character.
That's the F then I can loop through this array here looking for that f and when I find it I need to
know what position it's in.
So I could have a counter that's counting up right so that when I started 0 and then I go the next one
next one eventually it's going to find it and I've got a position.
That's the hard way.
That's not the way I want to do it.
Remember the String class has a method in it called find.
So if I want to find that character f it's going to return the position of f or it's going to return
no position.
That's really all I care about.
OK.
So that's the way I'm going to solve this problem.
Less code is better.
So let's solve this.
So right here we're about to encrypt the message.
Now we need to iterate through the secret message one character at a time.
So I'm going to use a range based for loop here.
It's perfect for this.
So I'm going to say for every character C in my secret message.
So now in the loop I have access to see which represents the current character I'm looking at.
In my secret message.
Right.
So I'm going to call the find method in the alphabet string.
And when asked the alphabet string to find C writes C is f it's going to find that lowercase f and return
its position.
Now that positions type is size t is that we've mentioned before.
That's an unsigned integer that's where the dependent platform this would work everywhere we'll call
it position.
And I'm going to ask the alphabet string or the alphabet object to find that character in itself if
it finds it we're good.
We're going to substitute it with the equivalent character at the same position and he doesn't find
it then we're just going to process that character as is.
It's not one of these.
So I'm not going to substitute it.
I'm just going to use it.
All right so what do we need.
We didn't state and we're going to say if the position
is not equal to no position what does that mean.
That means we found it right.
Let's do the else and I'll just use a block else in case we need to add some code later.
Now if we didn't find it in here we were not going to substitute we're just going to use the character
as is right.
Someone to say encrypted message plus equals C just add the character as is to the encrypted message.
We're not going to substitute it now.
What if we do need to substitute it.
Let's go back here again.
We need a new character.
Right we need the character in the key.
So let's create a variable called new character and we can initialize this variable to the very the
the character in the string at that position.
The key string.
Right.
So we have position already so we can ask again we can ask the key stream to give us the variable at
that position.
And we can initialize it to that.
So now we've got the new character that we want to substitute.
And what do we do.
We simply say encrypted message plus equals new character.
That's it.
That should be all the code we need.
Now let's just output the encrypted message
so the encrypted message would be encrypted message.
Right so let's run this this is the first half.
This is just the encryption side but you can see the code is really easy to understand very straightforward.
So let's run it and let's say this is a test.
And that's the encrypted message right there.
And let's get this to a simple test case we know that we're going to replace the lower case a see it
right here with me is my pen real quick.
You can see that we're going to replace the lower case a with an uppercase X and it's obviously the
capital Z with an R.
So a good test case would be a z z z that we expect back x x x.
R r r right.
That's the encrypted so let's try that out.
So with the three lowercase A's and three uppercase Z's
a z z z and as I said what we expect back is X X X lowercase three R's.
That's exactly what we want.
OK so it looks like we're in the we're in the ballpark.
Obviously you would have to test a lot better than this but that's a good example of a simple test case
that tells you you're definitely on track.
I'll erase this and let's try a couple more.
Let's try.
Meet me at Bill's house.
Now in this case you see we have an apostrophe.
We're not going to handle that apostrophe right.
We're not substituting So we're just going to print it out as it is so I expect to see that apostrophe
in the encrypted string in the same position.
So you can see here.
There it is right there.
So that's correct.
All right.
So that's the encrypted message.
Now let's decrypt the message.
Same idea right we're just going the other way.
We need a string object for the decrypted message.
And it will initialize that to an empty string as well.
We'll say see outness to another new line here and we'll say decrypting
message.
All right so now let's do the code again.
What are we doing this time well this time we're looping through the encrypted message right.
Grabbing those characters finding them in the key and substituting them back in the alphabet.
All right.
So let's do it it's the same exact idea except we're going backwards here.
So for every character says call it C in the encrypted message this time
for every character in there we're doing exactly the same thing the position
is we're going to ask the key this time to find that character and then if the position is not equal
to no position
then we found it in the else part means just handle it as is so let's handle that part really easy.
So this time we're going to say this to the decrypted message right.
So decrypted message plus equals C.
In this case we did find it.
So we want to get a new character again just you said before.
There's my new character and I want to initialize it to this time not the key but the alphabets at position.
So give me the character at the same position but in the alphabet string and I'll initialize it to that.
Then here we'll just say decrypted message plus the calls new char.
Awesome.
That's it.
Our screen should be decrypted at this point.
And what would you Heeres will just say seek out
put another new line here in front
decrypted message and I'll fix that typo in a second.
In this case it would be decrypted message followed by a new line.
OK let's try this out.
Hopefully we get back what we started with right.
So enter your secret message.
This is a test.
I'm decrypt I'm encrypting first.
That's the encrypted message right here.
I'm decrypting and I'm getting back.
This is a test.
Perfect.
Let's try a couple more.
Meet me at Bill's house at MIT say 12:30 P. M..
OK this is a good test case because maybe Nil's house not Bill's house.
Meet me at Nil's house.
You see we have an apostrophe.
We have the one the two the colon and the three in the zero were not handling those since they're not
letters.
So we should see those characters as is in the encrypted string.
So let's try that.
There you go.
There's the apostrophe there's the 12 the colon the third is just as we expected.
And then when we decrypt the message we get back.
Meet me at Neil's house at 12:30 p.m..
OK now suppose we wanted to make this a little better not a lot better but a little better.
Let's deal with those spaces right now.
I want I want to fill up those spaces with something.
So what we could do is we could come up here to my alphabet and I can insert a space right at the beginning.
That's a space character.
Now what am I going to replace the space character with anything I want that's already in here.
Let's say one of those characters left bracket.
That's fine.
But now we've got to deal with the left bracket right.
So let's put the left bracket up here and we're going to replace that with a space because we've got
to go both ways.
We're not going to work.
And so now we're going to handle spaces at least we'll fill up all that void space so let's try to run
it and we'll do something like this is a test and you can see now that sticking those square brackets
in there so it makes it look a little more jumbled up at least.
Obviously this is so easy to break and then the decrypted message is still correct.
This is a test.
There's a lot of things you can do here.
There's you know there's some real famous ciphers that are substitution ciphers like the key word cipher
in the Caesar cipher that you can play around with.
You can use random numbers we'll talk about generating random numbers so that maybe be the first time
you see a space you replace it with something the second time you replace it with something else that
would just make a little bit more more interesting and hard to break.
But there you go.
This is an example of using C++ is string class.
Very easy I mean there's no counting there's no checking to make sure that things fit.
It's handily everything for me.
All right so hopefully your solution is similar.
If it's not you can learn from this one and if you've got a great solution you can share it with the
rest of the class.
I'll see you in the next video.