In this section of the Course will learn about C++ functions functions allow us to divide our programs
into modular units of executive code and call and reuse these units as we wish.
Functions are very powerful abstraction mechanism.
You've already seen functions defined the main function that we've been using in every program and you've
also used some functions such as getline and the C-style string function string copy string length and
others in this section will understand what functions are and why they're so useful.
Then we'll look at functions in detail.
First we'll see how to define functions and create function prototypes that make our functions useful
anywhere in our code.
As we've already seen when we call a function we usually send information to the function.
This information is sent in the form of function parameters.
We'll see how to define these parameters and exactly how they work functions.
Also usually return some kind of information to us when they're done processing.
For example if we have a function that calculates the square root of a number well that function expects
the number and it will return to us the square root of the number which we can use however we wish.
Functions can also take many parameters and in some cases we want to default the value of some of those
parameters so we don't have to provide them every time we learn how to set these default values per
parameters to make our code easier to write them we'll learn how to pass arrays to functions and how
to work with them inside the function.
I'll discuss references in the next section but we'll look at how we can pass information to a function
efficiently by avoiding copying.
We'll also see how we can change past information as well as protect it from change.
Then we'll discuss inline functions inline functions are functions that the compiler optimizes to avoid
the overhead involved when we call functions.
Remember when we use the auto keyword to allow the compiler to deduce the type of a variable.
Well we can also use the auto keyword to allow the compiler to deduce the type of the function return
value.
This is pretty cool and it can save us from writing a lot of unnecessarily complex code.
Finally we'll learn about recursive functions.
These are functions that call themselves.
You might be wondering why would a function call itself.
You'll see it's pretty cool and it can help solve a class of problems that would be more complex to
solve without recursion.
At the end of this section we'll do a challenge project and we'll be well on our way to starting to
learn object oriented programming.
Let's get started.