This video we'll learn how to return a pointer from a function in C++ that functions can return pointers
which is a super powerful feature in order to do this we need to provide the type of the pointer in
the function definition and in the function prototype.
All this means is that the function will return an address of whatever type we specified in the function
declaration.
Let's see an example in this function where returning a pointer to an integer.
In this case it will be the value of the parameter that points to the largest integer.
It's OK to return a pointer to data that's being passed into a function.
Since we know that data exists.
So in this case we compare the two integers that the two pointers are pointing to and return the pointer
that points to the largest integer.
Notice that we're not comparing the pointers themselves.
We're comparing what they're pointing to by dereferencing them.
Pretty straightforward.
But how do you call this function.
I'll show you in the next slide.
Here we have a simple main that calls the largest function that we just wrote.
I have two integers A and B B is the largest with 200 I call largest.
In passing the addresses of A and B.
This is correct since it expects pointers to integers.
The function returns a pointer which I assign to a variable named barges pointer which is declared as
a pointer to an integer.
So now that variable largest pointer points to either A or B depending on which one was largest in this
case it's B.
So we dereference a pointer and it displays 200.
Let's see an example where we allocate memory dynamically inside a function and return the address of
that memory.
Returning dynamically allocated memory from a function is a very common use case for returning a pointer
from a function.
In this example we created a function called create array and it expects an unsigned integer that contains
the size of the array to create in a default parameter called init value.
And that's the value we can to initialize all the array elements to the function returns a pointer to
an integer.
Now this represents the address of that first integer that we dynamically created.
You can see the code is pretty standard after we create the storage.
We use a for loop and initialize all the array elements to add value.
Notice that I'm using pointer offset notation within the loop but I could have used pointers subscript
notation.
Finally we return new storage which is the address of that first integer in the newly created array.
So how do we use this function.
I'll show you in the next slide.
In the sample code we call create array and we pass in 120.
That means I want 100 integers allocated dynamically on the heap and I want to initialize all of them
to 20.
So this function allocates the space dynamically on the heap for those hundred integers.
Initialize them all to 20 and returns the address of that first integer which I assign to my array.
Now I can use my array.
However I like.
But remember since the storage is on the heap you need to release it so you have to remember to use
delete with the square brackets on that pointer variable.
Now let's see what NOT to do when returning pointers from a function.
Here I have two functions.
The first function is called Don't do this.
Now the second function is called.
Or this.
They both return pointers to integers.
The first function returns the address of size.
This is a real problem.
Size is a local variable to the function.
This will compile just fine since the address of size is the address of an integer and that's what the
function returns.
But what's the problem.
Well you can see it's a huge problem we're returning the address of a local variable in the function.
The variables on the stack and the function just terminated so this variable is now past its lifetime.
The next time the function is called or any function is called the stack area will be reused in the
pointer when I'll be pointing into that new functions activation record.
If you overwrite the data it's pointing to you could trash the stack pointer static links all kinds
of important information on the activation record.
Hopefully the program crashes or you get a really strange error that you can fix.
But if the program changes data that isn't currently being used then the program may appear to work
correctly for a while.
These types of errors or bugs are very difficult to find.
The second function has the same problem except that it's assigned a pointer to size variable and returns
it in both cases the address that's being returned is a stack variable or a function local variable.
Very bad idea OK that completes this video.
You'll get a chance to work with functions that return pointers to dynamically allocated storage in
the challenge exercise at the end of the section.
But first let's head over to the ID and we'll go over some of these functions in live code.
Ok so I mean the idea and the section 12 workspace in the returned pointer project and I'd like to walk
through this example when we created that create a re function that dynamically allocates some storage
on the heap.
So let's walk through this example right here we're in Maine.
Notice that Maine is activated when the program begins and we've got three local variables in Maine.
We've got Mirei which currently is just no doubt we have size which contains garbage right now when
we have a value which is zeroed out at the moment.
OK.
So what do we do.
We ask the user how many integers would you like to allocate and we read that into size.
Let's say that they want to allocate 10 integers.
So we'll put a 10 in here and then what value would you like to initialize to.
How about we initialize them all to number two.
So now we've got those variables and what we do now is we we call create array and we pass in the size
and the initial value.
So we're here now.
Here's the function create array noticed create array has one to three local variables right.
It's got size and let me call create array here some calling create array with the size which is 10
and the initial value is which is 2.
If I didn't supply an initial value would you 0 there's the default initializer here.
But in this case size is 10 initial value.
And notice again I'm using the same variable names.
I'm doing that on purpose don't let that confuse you too.
And then we've got new storage right here.
Which is a pointer to an integer.
That's where we're going to allocate the memory from when we call you right here on the next line.
And right now that's No.
OK so now new storage equals new size.
How many integers do I want to allocate dynamically however many integers were passed in in this case
10 so 10 integers will be allocated dynamically on the heap not on the stack.
This is to stack the heap is a different part of memory.
It's way up here let's say and we're going to allocate 10 integers 0 through 9 on the heap.
Let's say that this is addressed 5000.
That's the address of that very first integer right here.
What's being returned and assigned to storage is that first integers address or putting a 5000 in here.
There's our pointer.
Now this is really important.
We've got a pointer on this stack that's pointing just George on the heap.
This is exactly what we want.
We've got to be careful not to lose that pointer if we lose that pointer we've got a memory leak.
OK.
Great.
So now we have that memory allocated and we want to initialize it remember right now that all that is
garbage data right in here.
So what do we do.
We just use a simple for loop we're going from zero less than size by 1 and we're initializing every
element in this array to whatever was being passed in an initial value right here in this case we passed
in A2.
So we're going to store to everywhere and here I'm using pointer offset notation.
I could have just said new storage sub I and used pointer array notation or a pointer subscript notation.
Either one is fine.
So in this case we're putting a two in all of these guys.
All 10 of them will have twos in them and now this is the piece that's really important we return you
storage.
But what's new storage.
It's 5000.
We returned that value 5 0 0 0 0 0.
And notice in Maine we're assigning it to Mirei.
So we're putting 5000 in here.
So now this pointer is pointing to the same place.
That's really important because this function is almost done.
So when this function gets popped off the stack we're going to lose this pointer right here and we don't
want to lose that pointer.
So that's why we assign it to my race and we've got a copy of that pointer that we can use.
OK good.
So at this point the function is now done we start cleaning it up.
So all this is gone now.
Right.
So this pointer here is now gone.
We lose all this and we're back to Maine now I notice Maine has that pointer.
We didn't lose our memory out on that.
That's really important to understand.
OK so now let's display the data.
So I'm calling this function right now.
Display
and I'm passing in.
In this case my array my rate is 5000.
That's the value of that pointer and the size which was 10.
So display now gets activated on the stack and it's got one right here.
Variable one local variable another local variable and it's got another variable right here.
I am not going to worry about you know all about I it's just a looping variable.
So it's going to have this variable array and it's going to have a size.
So 5000 gets copied to array 10 gets copied to size.
Notice that this is not pointing to that same place but it's constant.
We've got a constant pointer and we're pointing to a constant array so we can't mess with that array
either by accident or intentionally.
And all we're doing is we're just looping through there and displaying out every element in the array.
Notice decision in this case I'm using pointer subscript notation here ret whereas over here I use pointer
offset notation.
Same exact thing.
So this function now goes through their displays all those twos 10 of them.
When we're done same as before we basically start unwinding.
So this is done after we do all the displaying or gone here.
This is gone and we're back to Maine.
Now I've got this storage allocated on the heap.
I'm done with it.
I need to release it or free it up.
And that's what's happening right here at 9:34 delete square brackets.
And the name of the pointer you've got to make sure that the value of that pointer is something that
was needed because you can't point to like a stack reference and then delete that.
So in this case this will now be freed up and that memory will be ready to be used again.
So let's clear this up and give it a run.
So we'll build and run here.
So let's say we want to allocate 10 integers and we want to set all of them to 5.
That you see we're displaying all 10 integers each one is set to five pretty easy.
Let's run this again.
And suppose we want to allocate 1000 integers this time and when one set each one of them to I don't
know 88 we run it there we get a thousand integers all set to 98.
What's important to understand here is that it's all on the heap which is pretty cool.
OK.
So that finishes off this video.
I hope this makes a lot of sense if you have any questions please let me know.