In this video we'll learn how we can access class attributes and methods.
Of course we want to create objects from our classes but we also want to be able to use and modify the
objects attributes and call methods for specific objects.
There are two ways to access class members.
We can use the dot operator and we can use the member of pointer operator or the arrow operator.
Remember that some class members may not be accessible since we can hide them we'll see that in the
next video.
We've already seen how we can use the dot operator when we worked with standard vector and string.
If we have an object then we can use the dot operator followed by the class member that we want to reference.
It's as easy as that.
For example if I have an account object named Frank sickout then I can access the balance attribute
with frank account balance and I can deposit a thousand dollars into frank account by writing frank
account dot deposit 1000 in this case we're accessing the deposit method.
Notice that the object is to the left of the dot operator.
So that method will be called on that specific object.
In this case the frank account object
if we have a pointer to an object then we need to dereference the pointer first in order to get to the
object.
And then we can apply the dot operator.
There's two ways we can do that.
Remember in these examples frank account is not an account object.
It is a pointer to an account object which has been dynamically allocated on the heap.
The first way to do this is to explicitly dereference the pointer and then use the dot operator in order
to access the objects class members.
We have to dereference the pointer using the asterisk and then use the dot operator to get the class
member we want but notice that we have to use parentheses here since the dot operator has higher precedence
than the pointer dereference operator and we want to be sure that we dereference first.
While this syntax is explicit it can be a little tedious to read and write.
So C++ provides an alternate operator called the member of pointer operator which is often referred
to as the arrow operator.
It's a dash followed by a greater than sign which looks like an arrow pointing to the right this operator
has the same effect as the first example above it will dereference the pointer and then apply the dot
operator as you can see this operator is very intuitive to read and use and it's used very often.
That's all there is to accessing class members.
Let's head over to the ID and we'll access some class members for the player and account classes.
Ok so I mean the ID and I mean the section 13 workspace The accessing class members project.
What we've got here is we've got the same player class and Account class that we created in the last
video with its attributes and methods just like we did before and what we'd like to do now is access
some of these attributes and methods from within our main.
And we want to access them for specific objects.
Obviously now there's a couple of things we're going to do and we'll discuss them in detail in a few
videos from now but by default all of this information in the class is private and we don't have access
to it.
So let's make it all public.
For this video and in the next video we'll talk about public and private.
So this is what I'm going to do here is say public Colin for the account class and public Colwin for
the player class that says that everything after that access modifier is public which means we've got
access to it.
No worries at all.
OK.
And as I said we'll talk about public and private in the next video.
So what do I do.
Well let's create some objects.
Let's create a player object and let's call it Frank.
And now what I want to do is I want to set Frank's name health and XP.
Those are the attributes for the player class.
Well how do I get to them.
This is where we use the dot operator.
Frank is an object so we can say Frank datt name and we could just set it to Frank or anything else
we'd like we could say Frank-Dodd health is 100 let's say.
And finally we could say Franke's XP is that say 12.
OK so it's really as simple as that.
That sets those attributes the values for those attributes.
Now obviously if I wanted to print out those attributes I would just do a seek out Frank-Dodd health
and that's it and I'm going to get whatever was stored in there as a value.
So let's take a look at this in the debugger and see what it looks like so I'm going to put a breakpoint
right here on 9:33 and let's run this in the debugger so we can see what's going on.
First of all you can see over here that Frank is a player object that's its type.
And if I expand this you can see it's all garbage right now right.
So this is all garbage and let me hit next and I just did.
Let me refresh just one more time you'll see that the string is now empty for the name.
Now what I'm doing here is I'm saying Set the name attribute for the frank object to the string Frank.
OK.
And then I'm setting the health attribute for the frank object and the XP attribute for the frank object
to 112.
So I'll hit next a couple of times one to three times I'll execute those three lines of code and what
I'll do here is our refresh the screen so that we can see that now we've got Frank is the name the health
is 100 the XP is 12.
Exactly what we expected.
OK.
So that's a really easy way to do this.
Now remember this is all based on the fact that this is public.
If this was private you'd get a compiler error and I'll discuss that in detail in the next video.
Same idea holds for accounts but how about these methods here.
I haven't implemented those methods.
So if I try to say something like Frank don't talk and I pass in a strength to say hi hi there or something
like that this will compile just fine but it won't link because I haven't implemented this method.
How do we implement this method.
There's a whole bunch of different ways to do it.
Let's do it the simple way.
And again I'm going to do a whole video on methods and how to implement them.
But for now just to get this to work let's put in a method block here and just like we've always done
I'm going to say seek out what's my name.
Well my name is name someone the same name.
I'm going to put another insertion operator and I'll say says followed by the text to say which is we
pass into me followed by an end line.
That's it.
Now I've implemented that method.
So now when this code executes right here Frank talk.
Hi there.
It should say Frank says Hi there.
OK so let me stop this and let's run this again.
And again we'll run this in the debugger.
And since we have some output what I'm going to do is put that output window right over here so we can
actually see what's going on in our output window.
OK so let's do this again.
I'm going to select next on line 34 now line 35 line 36.
Now I'm going to execute 9:36.
And at this point my frank object has a named Frank health 100.
XP is 12.
Now what's going to happen is we're going to call the talk method for the frank object and control will
be transferred right over here to this method we just wrote we're passing in this string Hi there.
And it should say Frank says Hi there.
And it should display it right out here.
So let's take a look.
That's exactly what happens.
Frank says Hi there.
OK.
So what's neat about this is that since I'm calling the talk method for the frank object these attributes
are available to that method.
And so I don't have to pass in the name of Frank because I've already got it I could just simply say
name as far as this name is concerned remember we talked about scope a while back.
Well we look for the definition of this variable inside the class first.
It's not there then we go global but we're going to look for it here.
There it is.
That's someone we're going to use OK.
So there you go.
That's a real simple example of calling some member method really really easy.
Now how about if we had a pointer Let's try that.
So let me stop this and we'll do the same kind of code will write it with a pointer and I'll leave this
window a little bit smaller so we could see.
So let's say we have a player and it's a pointer this time called enemy which is a pointer to a player.
And I'll just instantiate it right here.
So I say it's a new player.
OK so in order to get to that player object I need to dereference the pointer right remember enemy is
not a player object enemy is a pointer to a player object.
So in this case there's two ways to do it.
We can dereference enemy.
Ok so I just did was I dereference the pointer so now I've got the object and I can say enemy dot name
is and then the simple as that I could say enemy dot health is 100.
And I could do the same thing for XP.
But rather than use this syntax we're explicitly dereferencing the pointer and then doing the dot operator.
Let's use the arrow operator here.
So what we can say is enemy followed by the arrow operator and then we can say x p is that say 15.
Right now how do you call a method here.
Same way we could say enemy arrow.
So what I want to do is I want to dereference that point or I use the dot then I'm going to call talk
and say I will destroy you.
OK so let's try this.
Now let's walk through this one more time.
So we'll debug this
move this over here real quick.
And let's step through the program.
Right now we're on 9:33 that's where we've got the breakpoint.
So we're creating the Frank object we're setting the name to franked the health 100 and the XP to 12
and then we're going to call the talk method on the Frank object which should display.
Frank says Hi there and that's exactly what happens over here in the output.
Now we're going to create this enemy which is a pointer to a player.
Now it's important that you see that you can see the type here what the debugger is really helping you
out here.
You can see Frank is a player enemy is a pointer to a player.
You could see that the debugger is really helping you out there with the type.
So at this point right now that enemy is garbage right we've got garbage data in the pointer.
As soon as I execute 939 now it will be pointing to a real player object.
So I'm going to sit next.
Now we've got enemy pointing to a player object.
And if I come over here you can see the name is junk.
The health is junk and the Czar the name is empty.
The health is junk and the XP is junk.
OK.
So what do I do here.
I want to dereference enemy and then get the names I want to follow the pointer and get the them.
OK.
We can also use this area right here with the watches so I can add a watch and you can put whatever
expression you want.
So I just want to see this expression right here.
Dereference enemy.
That's the object.
So when I add that you can see I'm seeing the same thing that I'm seeing here.
Now for some reason this you need to refresh this you don't.
So it's kind of nice to have these here.
So let's walk through this dereference enemy that means go to the object that I'm pointing to and set
the name to enemy.
OK so let's execute that line of code.
Notice how enemy shows up here doesn't show up here unless I refresh.
But now it does.
They don't want to set the health to 100.
So I'll do that next.
Now the health is 100 XP is 15 but now we're using the arrow operators so but it's all the same XP is
15.
And now I want to call the talk method for the enemy object but I want to do it through the pointer.
And when I run this it should say enemy says I will destroy you.
So let's try that out.
And that's exactly what it says.
And he says I will destroy OK OK so that gives you an idea of how some of this works.
What we'll do next is let's update this a little bit.
We'll do that quickly because this video is getting a little long now and what we'll do is we'll do
the account.
OK.
Same idea except here I'm going to say something like what do I want to do when the user passes in a
number to deposit.
Well what I want to do is just say something like balance plus equals right.
Just something really really simple I don't increment the balance by whatever they passed into me.
And for for withdraw I just want to say balance minus equals be a help.
And while I'm at it I want to also say seek out something like in deposit just so I know that I'm in
there.
So we could see this being called would do that and we'll do the same thing for withdrawal.
And again just so we can see these things are being called now we're defining these methods right in
here right inside the class.
As I said there's other ways to do this and I'll show you what those are in a couple of videos.
But let me just change this so we can understand how to access this.
That's it.
So now let's create right up here.
Let's create an account.
So we'll say account and we'll just say Frank account.
Right.
That creates an account object.
Now I can set the name and the balance of that account.
These are public attributes right now.
So I could say Frank account and I'll just say equals Frank's account.
That could be any C++ string.
And then I'm going to set the balance I'm going to say Frank's account balance and say that there is
$5000 in there.
OK that's it.
Now let's say I want to deposit a thousand dollars into that account I could say again you need the
object that you're working on has to be to the left of the dot operator.
So it's going to be frank account deposit.
And I'm going to deposit a thousand
OK and then we'll save Frank's account withdraw and let's see if we want to withdraw 500
and that's it.
And I'm forgetting semi-colons because I've been working with a programming language all day that doesn't
need them.
So I'll put them in there hope Fed and forget any other ones.
OK so that's it.
Let's put a break point here and just try running through this so again we'll get to the debugger.
And Frank's account equals of course Frank accounts name I need to set that specific attribute
and frank account withdraw five hundred
have an extra portion right there.
OK let's try that now OK.
Perfect.
Let's put the output window over here on the side and let's walk through this.
I'm at 9:33 right now I'm creating frank account so I'm doing that right now.
Now I'm setting Frank accounts name into Frank's account.
We'll do that.
And the balance to 5000.
So let's take a look at Frank's account right here will refresh there's Frank's account and the balance
is 5000.
Now when I call the deposit method it's going to call this method right here for that Frank account
object and increment the balance by a thousand.
OK so let's do that.
And should we should also get an output statement print out over here.
There you go in deposit.
Refresh frank account again notice I've got 6000 in here now.
When I called the withdraw method this should go down to fifty five hundred and it should say in withdraw.
So let's do that one more time and we'll refresh one more time.
There's 1500 exactly what we expected and the withdrawal kicked in OK.
Same idea here with the pointer that we did with the player object.
I won't do that because the video is getting a little bit longer but I'll let you guys try that out.
You can create Mary's account which is a pointer to an account and then you can access the attributes
using this syntax or the error.
OPERATOR OK.
So if you have any questions please drop by the forum and let us know.