In this video we'll learn about how to implement member methods in our C++ classes.
You'll be glad to hear that class methods are implemented in a manner very similar to the way we implemented
functions.
But I'd say that are generally less complex.
This is because member methods have access to the classes member attributes.
So we don't have to pass so many arguments around C++ gives you many options regarding where to write
code for member methods.
You can define the member methods right inside the class declaration.
If you do this then the methods become implicitly in line.
While this is OK for small and relatively simple methods we tend to implement larger more complex methods
outside of the class declaration in order to do so.
We need to tell the compiler that we're implementing a method that belongs to a specific class so we
use the class name followed by the scope resolution operator and then the method name.
This unambiguously tells the compiler that you are implementing a method for a specific class in C++.
It's also very common to separate classes specification from its implementation.
This makes the class much easier to manage.
We usually create a header or include file that has a dot H or dot HP extension for the class specification
and then a separate data file for the class implementation.
First let's look at implementing methods inside the class declaration.
In this example we're declaring an account class.
Notice that the account class has a private double named balance and two public methods.
Set balance and get balance set balance sets the balance to the value passed in by the user and get
balance returns a copy of the account balance.
These public methods are necessary to access the balances the balance is private.
Notice the syntax is exactly as it was for defining regular C++ functions.
Also notice that the public methods have direct access to the private ballots because they're members
of the same class.
Now let's see how we would implement these methods outside the class declaration.
In this example we're defining the set balance and get balance methods outside the class declaration
inside the class declaration we simply provide the method prototype or declaration.
This tells the compiler the name of the methods the parameters they expect them with return type.
The compiler can then type check the method implementation when it sees them.
In order for the compiler to know that these methods belong to the account class we have to prefix the
method names with a count followed by the scope resolution operator.
Then we implement the method as we normally would.
In this case the compiler knows that the two method implementations are for the method declarations
in the account class we provided as our programs get larger we really want a separate class specification
and class implementation of two different files.
Let's see the sample of how we can do that.
In this example we create a file named account.
H.
This is an include or header file that will pass and include in our data files whenever we need to use
the account class.
Notice that in this file we provide the specification for the account class before we can use or poun
include this account that H header file.
We need to take care of a potential problem.
If this file is included by more than one C.P. file then the compiler will see the declaration for the
account class more than once and give us an error about duplicate declarations in order to solve this.
We can use what's called an include guard that ensures that the compiler will process this file only
once.
No matter how many times it's included an include guard.
It's just a series of preprocessor directives that guarantees the file will only be included Once the
way it works is we wrap up our entire class declaration in this include guard.
The first line is pounde.
If not defined underscore account underscore h underscore it all in uppercase.
This checks to see if the preprocessor has a symbol named underscore account underscore H.
Underscore this symbol name can be anything you want.
But best practice is to use some sort of combination of the file name in uppercase with preceding and
ending underscores.
Any name is fine as long as it's unique in the program.
If the preprocessor has that name defined then it skips the entire file and goes to the pound END-IF
at the end.
In other words it doesn't process the file since it's already seen it because the symbol has been defined.
If the symbol has not been defined then the symbol is set and the file is processed as usual.
As you can see it's pretty simple but not very elegant compared to more modern programming languages.
So now this is what the account that h file typically contains.
You can see the include guard wrapping the class declaration.
Now we can provide the implementation for the account class in a separate file named account that C-p
many compilers also support the pound pragma once compiled a directive.
The effect of this directive is the same as the include guard.
While many compilers support this directive some don't.
So check your compiler documentation to be sure.
Now we can provide the implementation for the account class in a separate file named account that C
P P.
Let's take a look at that.
This is the source code for the account that file.
Notice that we include a count H and it's in double quotes.
Up to this point our includes have used angle brackets with no extensions.
There is an important difference between the two forms of include include with angle brackets as in
include IO stream is used to include system header files and the compiler knows where these are located.
Includes with double quotes.
Tell the compiler to include header files that are local to this project.
The compiler also knows where those are.
Notice that this file implements the two methods declared in the account that age header file.
Now our current class is complete.
The specification is an account that H and the implementation is an account that CGP how do we use an
account in our main file though.
Let's see in the next slide.
Here's our main data file.
Notice how we include IO stream as well as account dot H.
It's important to always include that h files never include data files.
Then we just write our main as we normally would when the program is compiled both the main dot TPP
and the account that CBP files are compiled and then link to produce the executive.
Let's see how all this works in the ID OK.
So I mean the ID and I in the section 13 workspace in the implementing methods 1 project.
What I'm going to do here is I'm going to implement these methods in this account class and will implement
some of them inside the class declaration and some of them outside the class declaration.
This will create another project implement implementing methods to where will separate the specification
from the implementation and will create the account that h file and the account that C.P. file.
OK so let's start here.
What we're doing here is we have our class account right here and we've got two private attributes.
Name and balance of them we've got the methods and the methods are really what we're interested in here.
Now in this case I've got six methods all public.
We've got a set balance and a get balance and you can see that these methods have been implemented line
right inside the class declaration.
This is easy to do.
And this is OK to do when you've got methods like these that are really really straightforward methods.
They're done they're implemented and we're all set.
Now we can also implement methods outside the class declaration.
Notice these last four methods I've got set name get name deposit and withdraw.
And what you see right here are basically the function prototypes are the method prototypes.
They're not defined here.
These are only declarations.
What we want to do is we want to find them outside the class.
And you'll notice the class begins here on line 8 and it ends right here on line 26.
So what we want to do is define them outside the class and let me show you how to do that it's really
straightforward.
What we've got here is.
So let me show you how easy it is.
Here are the methods that have been implemented outside the class.
We're starting on line 28 right here.
The method is set name which is this method right there it's called Set name.
Now it's not just good enough to say void set name that would just that would just define any method
we want to define the set name for the account class.
So we need to prefix the name of the method set name with the name of the class followed by the scope
resolution operator.
Now when the compiler sees this it knows.
OK you're defining the set name method that you declared in the account class.
So it's in a come up here and will be able to type check.
All of these things together and make sure that just no mistakes.
OK so you can see what's going on here in this example it's really straightforward.
String is being passed in and the name is said to whatever string was passed in which is an remember
name is one of the attributes of the class.
It was private and that's OK.
This is a member method so it has access to private information.
Get name simply returns a copy of that string.
OK.
And in this case we've got our deposit and withdraw.
So you're going to pass in an amount to deposit.
This method would somehow verify that that amount is indeed there so that you can deposit it and all
it does is it increments balance by whatever the amount is and it returns true.
Obviously would return false if it didn't verify.
And then the last method that will implement is this account withdrawal method.
Again it's the same idea we prefix the name of the method with the name of the class because it's a
class method.
And here's the amount.
And what do we do here.
Well we look at the balance and we subtract the amount from it.
If that's greater than or equal to zero then there is sufficient funds would just decrement the balance
by the amount and we'll return true.
OK.
Simple as that.
If the funds aren't there then we'll just return false.
So let's see how we can use this in the main and it's really really straight about some breakpoints
in here that will follow in the second.
So what I'm doing here is I'm creating an account called frank account and I'm setting the name to Frank's
account and I can't say Frank account dot name because that's private.
So I've got to go through this public method called Set name.
I'm doing the same thing for balance.
Frank account set balance to a thousand.
I can't say Frank account balance equals a thousand because balance is private.
OK.
So at this point I've got an account.
It's got Frank's account as the name 0 0 0.
That is the balance.
And then I want to deposit $200 into that account.
I'm going to call Frank account deposit 200.
If that returns true then the deposit was OK and I'm going to just display that.
If that returns false then the deposit was not allowed for whatever reason.
Now when it cost them withdraw methods here I'm going to call the withdraw method on the frank account
with five hundred.
Someone to check I should have a thousand in there right.
Actually I should have twelve hundred in there.
I just put $200 in there.
So as of.
I'll check to see if.
Twelve hundred minus 500 is greater than zero which it is.
And the withdraw should be ok I should have seven hundred dollars left after that.
Then I try to do another withdraw with 1300 and that should fail.
OK so let's let's run this through the debugger here.
Right now I'm at lined fifty three and I'm going to set a watch to Frank account.
That way I can see that as it changes really easily and that's already set here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to hit next.
And remember I'm right here on line 53 So at this point I've just created the frank account object.
Now I want to set that name.
Notice that the name is empty right now and the balance is garbage.
I want to set the name to Frank's account.
So when I select next you could see that that's changed right here to Frank account.
And I want to set the balance to a thousand.
So we should see that change here as well.
Again remember these two attributes are private.
That's why we're going through those public methods to change them.
Now what we're going to do is we're going to deposit $200 into that account.
So let's step through here and what we're going to do now is we're going to go we're going to jump to
this method right here.
I've got a breakpoint in there that's where I'm at right now assuming there was some business logic
here that would verify that that deposit amount was there going to increase the balance by 200 so I
should have 1200 here when I finish and return true.
And I'm back now you can see I've got 1200 here and I'm going to return true and it should display deposit.
OK over here and exactly what happens.
Now we're going to withdraw 500.
I've got 1200 so that should work.
So let's try that and you can see I'm right in here now.
I've jumped to this function this method right here.
So balance is twelve hundred minus 500 is greater than or equal to zero so we should be good in that
case.
I'm going to decrement the balance by the amount and I want to return true and I'm right back here now
on line 63.
Notice I've got seven hundred left in the account and it should display withdrawal OK.
The last example here is I'm going to withdraw 5300.
I don't have 1300.
So it should fail someone to go back up here.
Balance amount is greater than or equal to zero.
It's not so it's going to go straight to fault's which is going to return.
And then when I come back to my main I'm right here on line 70 and it should display not sufficient
funds and that's exactly what it does.
OK.
So there you go.
This is a real simple example of implementing these class methods both inside the class declaration
and outside the class declaration.
OK what I'm going to do next is we'll create a new project called implementing methods too and what
we'll do is we create the account that age an account that CBP and then will have a main C.P. that runs
the whole thing.
So I set that up and be right back.
OK so I'm back.
I'm still in the section 13 workspace but I've just created a new project called implementing methods
too and all it has in it is a main CGP file that you're looking at right here.
But we're going to do here is we're going to create our countdown h file our current data file and then
we'll use this main file as a driver so that we can create some objects and so forth.
OK so what do we do.
Well we need to create an account class every ID has its way of creating a new class code like is no
different if you select the source directory and right click you'll have an option for new class will
select that and then you get this pop up dialog and it's going to ask you what's the class name.
Well the class name is a count.
Again with a capital A.
Don't worry about name space and then the block card is what you saw with the include guard that I talked
about this is that pound define.
So I'm just going to say underscore account underscore 8 underscore you can really do anything you like.
You can even leave that blank and it's going to use its own way of doing it.
OK.
So that's it.
There's some more advanced options here which should all be off at this point.
And you can choose to create a dot HTP file instead of a dot h file.
I'm not going to.
And you can also choose to use the pragma once command.
Again I'm not going to I'm just going to use the block art you select.
OK.
And what happens here on the left hand side you'll see that we've got two files that were created.
We've got the countdown h file and the account that C-p file that's exactly what we want.
Now we're going to start with the count h file.
Notice the wrapper and I'm going to get rid of what it generated for me and what I'm going to do is
I'm going to copy and paste the account that we were working on and I'm just going to copy and paste
the declaration of the account so that we do that right now and paste it right in here.
It should be pretty familiar.
There's the class account.
Those are the two private attributes that see what we've got here.
Now we've got to do a couple of things we were using a string here.
So we want to do is here we want to pounded clewed string so that our account header file is complete
and we really don't want to use a name in here so I'm just going to prefix this with standard and see
C got a string here as well.
And I believe I've got one here as well and I think that'll do it.
So that's my count.
H file.
You can see it exactly as we had before.
There's my account declaration and it's wrapped up in that guard.
OK.
Now let's go to the account see.
Now you'll notice that it's generated the include for me and also it's generated these two functions
these two member functions.
We're going to get rid of those.
This is a constructor and destructor will talk about those in a couple of videos.
But for now I just want to get rid of them and what I want to do is I want to copy and paste those four
methods that we wrote remember the ones we wrote outside the class.
So I'm going to copy them right in here like that.
There's my account there's my and again I'm going to prefix this with standard wherever we're using
strings.
And I think that was the right.
Here's the other one.
That's it.
Now what we'll do is we'll go to the main and what we're going to do here is we're going to include
a count that H because we're going to need it in our main.
And if you remember the code for the main again I'll copy and paste it because it's really straightforward.
That was the code for the main where we created the frank account we set the name for the account and
so forth.
Now what we're going to do is I want to save this and we'll compile the whole thing would just basically
do build and run control 5.
What's going to happen is the data files were both compiled and everything will be linked into an acceptable.
Now we may run into some errors here and we'll fix those as we go.
So mean take control of 5 no errors.
Everything worked great.
You can see I run the file and I get deposit OK withdrawal OK not sufficient funds exactly like we had
before we could run this through the debugger if we like but it's really as simple as that throughout
the course.
This is the way we're going to start writing code now we're going to have the specification here and
the implementation in the dot C-p file and you can see again to this one more time.
You can see the accounts page the header or the include file that is our declaration for the account
class.
We have to wrap that up so that the compiler only sees it once we're including string here because we've
got our string class that we're using right there and we really don't want to use name spaces inside
these header files because everything that includes them is going to get that all that namespace stuff
which is really not necessary.
So what we've got there is that we've got our private stuff we've got our public stuff we've defined
these two methods right inside the class declaration.
And then these other methods we've defined outside the class declaration in accounts.
Now in order for the compiler to understand what you're talking about here you have to include account
data age.
Once you include account that age the compiler now knows what this is.
OK once that's done you go to your main and you can see the main is now pretty self-contained or just
including account dot H.
It's really really simple to do.
The idea is just you're going to have a lot of header files and a lot of C.P files in your application
and everything gets compiled and linked to a single executable.