In this video we'll look at the difference between a shallow copy and a deep copy in the context of
the copy constructor first will assume that the object we're copying has a raw pointer when the object
is constructed will likely allocate storage for the date of it that pointer is pointing to.
And then when we're done with the copy we'll release the memory as per best practices.
But what happens in the copy constructor we can do a shallow copy or a deep copy.
Let's see what that means.
Let's first look at doing a shallow copy.
And the problem is we can run into a shallow copy as the default behavior provided by the compiler generated
copy constructor.
It basically does member wise copying of all the object attributes.
So you end up with the newly created object and the object being copied both pointed to the same area
of storage in the heap.
So what's the problem.
Well the problem comes into play when one of those objects is destroyed and its destructor is called
When this happens.
The objects destructor releases the memory allocated on the heap as it should.
However the other object is still pointing to this released area and DC area is still valid.
This could lead to settle errors.
The best thing that can happen is that the program crashes while in development so that you can fix
the air.
But we'll learn how to do a deep copy and avoid the error completely.
But first let's walk through an example that has a class with the pointer attribute that does a shallow
copy.
So we can really understand the problem.
Here's the class we use in this example.
The class is called shallow and it has a single data attribute called data that's a pointer to a single
integer.
This class is about as simple an example as we could write that demonstrates the problem with a shallow
copy.
But any class that has a raw pointer as a data member will have the same issues.
This class has a constructor that expects an integer a copy constructor and a destructor.
Let's see how these are implemented.
Here's the code for the constructor.
Notice that the constructor allocates storage for the integer and stores the past in integer D where
that data pointer is pointing since we allocated the storage dynamically.
Then we must be sure to release it in the destructor.
Let's do that now.
Here's the destructor.
It simply frees the storage that was allocated by the constructor as it should.
It also displays a message to the console.
OK so now let's implement the copy constructor.
Here's the copy constructor.
This copy constructor is user defined but it provides the same semantics as the default compiler generated
copy constructor.
If we hadn't provided this one noticed it in the initializer list.
We simply copy the pointer.
This is member Y's copy.
Now we have a problem in this case the source object and the newly created object both point to the
same in heat that was allocated for the data.
But why is this a problem.
Well the problem comes into play when we make a copy of a shallow object using the copy constructor
that's doing a shallow copy.
Suppose we have a function display shallow that expects a shallow object by copy.
We make the copy with the copy constructor as usual but when that local object s goes out of scope its
destructor is called and the destructor releases the storage in the heap that is pointing to.
You see the problem now.
The object that was copied into this function still points to this now release storage but it thinks
that the storage is valid so all kinds of bad things can happen now.
Here's a sample mean we create objects one is a shallow Object object one will be created and an integer
will be allocated on the heap and 100 stored in it.
Now we call display shallow in a copy of object one will be created inside that function and when that
function is done the copy of object 1 will be destroyed.
Since object 1 and the copy that was just destroyed pointed to the same memory area object one now points
to invalid storage.
If we try to access that storage from object 1 our program could crash.
Also when the destructor for object one eventually gets called it will try to release memory that's
no longer valid and will probably crash.
Let's head over to the idea and we'll walk through this example and I'll dry out exactly what's happening.
OK so I'm back in the IEEE.
I'm in the section 13 workspace in the shallow copy project and we've got a program and the class is
called Shallow the same one that I put in the slides.
I would a couple of little changes in the main just to streamline it a little bit.
Anyway this program does a shallow copy in the copy constructor and I'll walk you through that right
now.
But first let's just run it and I'm going to run it without the debugger so you can see that it does
indeed crash.
And there's the crash right here in Windows and it's a bad crash.
It's not the kind of thing we want.
So the point of this.
This video is to try to understand exactly why this is crashing why we need a deep copy and why we've
got to be really careful when we use raw pointers.
So let's take a look at the class.
The class is shallow.
It's got a raw pointer here to a single integer.
We could have created an array of integers a pointer to some sort of object.
Does it really matter in this case it's about as simple as example as you can get.
And here we have a set value in a get value that we're using in my main.
We have a constructor that just expects the integer and when it does is you can see the source code
for the constructor right here on line 21.
It allocates storage on the heap dynamically for that one integer and the integer is being passed in.
Then I'm just dereferencing the pointer and storing that integer where data is pointing.
Really really simple.
OK the destructor.
Let's take a look at that.
Obviously whenever we allocate storage in the constructor the best practice is to release that storage
in the destructor.
That's what we're doing here and in this case we're just displaying destructor fring data so that we
can see when it's being called.
We're going to step through this in the debugger so we will definitely be able to see when it's being
called.
And then we've got the copy constructor.
In this case we're doing a shallow copy and you can see right here on line 27 in the constructor initialization
list.
All we're doing is we're copying the value in that data variable which is the pointer from source to
this which is the object we're creating right now.
So it's copying the pointer not what it's pointing to it's going to happen as both these objects when
we copy them will be pointing to the same area and I'll show you that in the debugger.
Then we've got a real simple function right here called display shallow which we pass in an object by
value.
So we're going to get a copy of it and that's where the problem shows up.
Again I walk you through that.
OK so let's let's debug this and we'll step through it so we can see exactly what's going on.
And I move the output window here to the right so you can see our constructors and destructors being
called.
All right so I'm right here on line 42 and here we're just doing a regular constructor call and we're
passing in the integer to us of this constructor right here in line 21 will be called.
So let's step through this and you can see now on my 22.
We're going to allocate the new integer on the heap.
We just did that.
And now I'm storing 100 into that area and I'm back to line 43 So at this point J one has been created.
It's right here and you can see that data is a pointer to an integer.
And we just store to 100 where that integer was pointing.
OK now we're going to run into a little bit of a problem.
This is where the deep copy is necessary rather than the shallow copy and I'll do another video after
this one will do a deep copy and I'll explain how that exactly works.
But let's walk through this.
We're going to call display shallow which is this function right here on 9:36.
And this is just a regular function it's not a member function and we're going to pass object one into
it.
Well we're doing that by value.
You can see right here there's no pointer there's no reference.
It's just by value so we need to make a copy.
So what we expect is that C++ needs to make a copy so it's going to call the copy constructor to do
that.
And let's do that right now.
So we step through it.
You can see right here we're in the copy constructor and we're doing that shallow copy.
So at this point you can see them just step one more line.
OK.
So what we've got now is let's take a look over here.
We've got source now remember source is what's being passed into the source in this case is O.B. J1.
So we've got so RBJ one right here has a pointer data that points to an area in memory and we stored
100 in there.
Now the location of that memory is right there.
Foxtrot 0 0 so I'll just write that in there those last three digits.
So it's Foxtrot 0 0 that's where that data is on the heap.
OK.
Now what happened I just made a copy of RBJ one but I didn't copy what it's pointing to.
I only copied the data.
So if you can see as I expand this which is right here inside here this is the new object we're creating
this right there.
You can see that the address of that pointer data is exactly the same.
So what we just did we just created a copy of this that's pointing to the same area and memory.
So let's walk through this a couple of more steps and then we'll just keep going here.
Great.
Now we're here.
We've just created the copy.
So what we just did was we created a copy and it's called S.
It's right here.
Now as has a pointer called data.
And guess what it's pointing to the same area and memory as RBJ one.
So what we just did was yes sure we made a copy of Abi J1.
Absolutely but we didn't make a copy of what that data pointer was pointing to.
Ideally what we would want with a deep copy is for S to be pointing to its own copy of that data over
here.
But that's not what's happening here.
And what we can see is clear the screen real quick.
What we can see here is that if we look at the s right here that's that local variable you can see that
fox track 0 0 is pointing to exactly the same memory location.
So here's the problem right now as is just about to go out of scope.
So again let me try that one more time just to be very very clear here.
We've got Obie J1 pointing to this area right here where it's got 100 and again that's the data attribute
that's pointing right.
And then we've got s which is also pointing to that area well now as it goes out of scope what happens
when ESC goes out of scope.
We get the destructor called.
Right.
So let's walk through that.
We can see that destructor being called.
It's out of scope right now.
Boom there's the call to the destructor on line 32 and the destructor deletes data.
So what did the destructor just do.
It freed up this area in memory right here.
So as far as the C++ runtime system is concerned this is no longer valid memory.
Right we just deleted it.
So this guy right here now is pointing to invalid memory.
Now hopefully you can see that that's a big problem here.
So what's going to happen.
Well let's keep going.
We're going to destructor Frina data now we go back to main right here and notice where we're at right
now at this point.
This is now gone right because we were we're all that's been cleaned off the stack and I'll take those
Xs off to see see what's going on here.
This is the situation we've got we've got RBJ one now has a pointer called data that's pointing to an
area on the heap that has 100 in it because that hasn't changed but that memory is invalid.
So now if we try to make a copy of RBJ one and call it object again this calls a copy constructor again.
Let's let's see what happens here.
Let's walk through this again.
Copy constructor gets called because we're making a copy.
And what do we just do what we just copy it again.
So now we've got two objects pointing to invalid data and I'll walk you through this.
And we're back to main.
Here is what I've got now is I've got RBJ to right here pointing to that same and valid data and that's
not good and you can obviously see what's going on here you can see RBJ 1 and RBJ 2 are pointing to
exactly the same memory locations right.
Here you can see Foxtrot 0 0 Foxtrot 0 0.
That's the situation we've got right here.
So this could be problematic in a lot of ways.
Suppose that on line 46 I'm setting the data value for RBJ 2 to 100.
Right.
So I'm coming this way.
Sorry to 1000 some coming this way through this area here and try to put a thousand in there.
Well what did I just do assuming that this works right assuming that we haven't allocated any other
objects and they've used that space.
But why did I just do I just changed RBJ one's data to two thousand indirectly without even knowing
it because they're both pointing to the same area in memory.
So let's walk through that and you'll see exactly what I'm talking about.
Right now you can see they're both pointing me refresh this here.
Since they're both pointing to the same area in memory I just changed O.B. Tuesday to 2000.
But what happened here with one's data changed 2002 of course it did it were pointed to the same error
in memory right.
Now comes the problem and this is where the crash comes in and I'll clear the screen real quick as we
unwind now and start freeing up these two objects right.
I mean they're going out of scope right here in Maine.
So we need to delete the data for both of them are calling both the destructors well that pointers pointing
to invalid data.
And when we try to delete it we're going to have a problem.
That's where the crash comes in and I'll just step through it.
You can see the destructors being unwound now and at some point we will crash there's the crash right
there.
OK.
So you can see what's happening here you can see how important it is to really understand what's going
on with your memory when you're using raw pointers.
What we'll do in the next video is we'll go over deep copy and them will do.
Another example of this that we just did now using deep copy you can see how that works better.