In this video we'll discuss another way to create objects in C++ using a struct or structure.
The struct comes from the C programming language.
In C we create struct as a container for data much like a record in many other programming languages.
C++ also support structure since it has to be compatible with C..
However it adds the ability to treat struct very much like classes.
Everything you can do with classes you can do with struts.
The only difference is that the members of the struct are public by default whereas the members of a
class are private by default.
Here's a simple class declaration for a person class that has a string attribute called name and a method
called Get named returns that name by default.
Class members are private so if we create a p object that's a person and try to access name or call
get name.
The compiler will give us a compiler error saying that we don't have access to those private elements.
Now let's see the same as a struct.
Here we have person declared as a struct.
We have the same attribute and the same member method.
But now when we create the person object p and try to access its attribute or a member function.
The compiler is OK with it.
That's because the default access for a struct is public.
That's it.
That's the only difference between structuring classes and C++.
But there's a few general guidelines that you can use to determine if you need a struct or a class.
It would be appropriate to use a struct when you have passive data so the struct would act very much
like a struct in C..
It simply holds data and that data is public and since the data is passive You really don't need to
create any methods in the struct.
As for a class we've already seen many examples.
If your objects are active or they have complex behavior then you should use a class and implement getters
and setters and member methods as needed.
These guidelines are very general but remember other C++ programmers will likely be modifying and extending
your code.
So don't use C++ in a way that's very different from what C++ programmers expect.
For example don't use a struct and then make everything private in the structure so it behaves like
a class.
Just use a class instead.