Hello everyone.
Welcome back.
I hope you had fun with this challenge.
It can be a very tough challenge sometimes.
You've really got to understand what's going on with returning references returning values conc correctness
and so forth.
So let's go through the solution.
I'm in the section 14 workspace in the challenge Dasch solution one project and here's one possible
solution to this challenge.
There's obviously a lot of different ways to achieve the same result.
First thing is I mean the my strength h file and you can see here the prototype is for the operator
member methods you remember now this is the version we're implementing all of these operators as member
methods.
So right away we've got a little bit of an advantage in the sense that since we're member methods we
have access to all the private information.
So here we go we've got our unity minus that makes a string lowercase we've got our concatenation operator
and remember because we've got member methods here.
This will expect nothing right.
There's nothing in the parameter list for a urinary operator because this object is the operand in the
case of a binary operator.
There's only one item to the right in the parameter list not two with nonmember functions it's different.
We'll have to.
Here is my equality operator.
My not equal operator.
You can see they return booleans less than greater than if you chose to do less than or equal to greater
than or equal to that's great.
And then I've got my plus equal operator that expects a right hand side string obviously.
And then the left hand side we're assigning back to that's my concatenate and assign.
There's my star or repeat operator in this case where I want to repeat a string and number of times
there is the star equal operator and then we've got our pre-increment and post-increment operators that
will simply make a string uppercase.
Notice the pre-increment returns a reference the post increment returns my string by value.
OK so there you go and let's go and see the implementations for these.
And they should be really straightforward it's pretty much what we've been used to doing.
So let me start right here at the very beginning right here on line 3:51 we're looking at equality.
So let's take advantage of that string compare function right.
So we're going to compare this string with the right hand side object string.
And if they're equal to zero then they're the same they're not equals is exactly the same except I'm
just putting a bang in here I'm just saying I'm negating that result.
We could certainly call this guy but it's simple enough just to negate what we get back here.
The less than is the same idea I'm using stood staring come up again and I'm checking to see if the
value returned was less than zero and I'm returning that result.
Greater than exactly the same way as you can see how trivial these methods are to implement because
the stud string function is really doing all the work for us.
Now to make lower case we saw this in the slides and we saw this in some of the code examples that we
did as well.
What we need to do here is allocate the character buffer right here an array of characters on the heap.
That's the length of the string that we're in question plus one then we need to copy the string over
to Buff.
And then just loop through that buffer area and basically make all those characters lowercase.
Right.
And we're using this to add to lower function right here to simply make the lower case version of that
character.
I'm creating the temporary object which I'm returning.
And don't forget to delete the buffer as we mentioned in the slides.
Otherwise we'll leave that memory and that's not something we want to do.
The concatenate method is very very similar.
We're creating an area in the heap.
This time it has to be big enough for both strings plus one.
So we're taking the length of as TR And then the like the length of right hand side as you are and adding
one to them.
I'm copying this straight to the buffer and then I'm concatenating the other string the right hand side
string to that creating a temporary object and returning it and deleting my area again.
Very very common pattern that you can see.
Now let's talk about plus equal since we've already overloaded the concatenation operator.
Let's take advantage of that.
So you can see this basically becomes really one line of code the return doesn't even count because
we've got a return.
So what we're saying here is that the current object is equal to the current object plus the right hand
side object right.
So this right here we'll call this operator that we've already overloaded and take care of everything
for us.
So this becomes a very trivial method once we've overloaded the concatenation operator.
Here is the repeat.
And what I can do here is I can take advantage because remember multiplication or repeating it's just
a bunch of additions.
So what we can do here is we can take advantage of that so we can create a temp object that just an
empty temp objects and then just loop end times and add this to the temp object right.
Which is exactly what we expect.
We're incrementing this so many times and then we just return the temp object.
In this case we could do it all in code to do it like that if you like one is going to be a little bit
more efficient than the other.
But this works really well and this is very very readable and modifiable code which is my preference
right here.
Here's the repeat in a sign.
Same idea as the sequel.
This is the star equal so this equals this time zone.
We're going to call the overloaded star operator repeat operator in this case to do it all for us.
So this method becomes trivial again.
And now let's take a look at the last couple of methods here the pre-increment and the post-increment.
They both make the string upper case the differences in the semantics.
So let's take a look at this one right here.
Pre-increment this one is dead simple.
We've got an object.
It's got an AS TR pointer that points to a character around the heap to do is loop through that character
array and make everything there to.
That's it.
And then we return the current object.
There's no need to copy anything move anything over.
It's the same string we're pointing to.
We're just simply making it upper case and in the case of the post-increment remember the post-increment
is using that right there which is just a placeholder it's a name we don't even use it in here.
It's only used by the compiler behind the scenes.
This returns an object by value.
So what we're doing is we're making a temporary copy of the current object.
That's what this is doing right here.
And then we're calling the pre-increment function.
This guy right here.
That's going to increment that string make it upper case in this case and then we return the temporary
object that we save.
That was the old value.
So these are the semantics for post-increment is going to be a little bit different than the pre because
I've got to return the old value right.
That makes sense because what we're assigning is the value then we're incrementing the string.
So there you go.
That's a real simple implementation for all of these operators.
It may have taken you a while.
That's OK.
But that's part of the learning process.
I remember when I first did operator overloading it's hard to wrap your head around whether you're returning
references or values and you know what exactly is going on here.
The last thing we'll do is let's take a look at maining you'll see some test cases here.
And what I'd like to do I'll just run this real quick and right there there's our output and then it
says enter a string to repeat so let me just enter a string that looks like Dash 0 0 dashed up at three
zeroes is something that we can really see.
And this is testing the extraction operator as well.
And how many times would you like to repeat it the same want to repeat it five times.
And then we go and get back to this output in just a second.
But let's go back to our main here and walk through this.
You can see right here that I've got my string A which is Frank my string B which is frank and I'm saying
is equal to B.
And this will print out true or false because I've said this modifier right here on the string.
So a obviously is equal to be.
So we expect to true that's what we have right here is a not equal to be well that's false.
So we get the false and then we set B to George and we use some of the other comparison operators in
addition to the ones we just did.
So in this case Frank is definitely not equal to George right.
So we expect this to be false which it is right here is Frank not equal to George.
That's true.
Is Frank less than George.
And finally is Frank greater than George.
That's false.
So you can see that out put right over here.
Now we'll get to some other ones in this case.
I've got one is Frank all uppercase and I'm using the minus right here to make it all lowercase and
then I'm outputting x y and z you can see we expect lowercase Frank and that's what we have right here.
The next is using the concatenation operator so we remember S1 is lowercase Frank and we're just saying.
Tack on five Astor's to that concatenate five Astras to the end of that.
So we expect this to be frank followed by five asterisks.
And you see the upper right there and then we're doing it again except this time we're using plus sequel's
some saying s one plus equals I think five dashes again.
In this case dashes not stars.
So what we expect is as one which is right here Frank five Astras and we want to append those dashes
to it.
So the output is something like this is what you see right here.
OK.
Now we're going to use the repeat OPERATOR Right here.
We're simply saying as two as one two three four five and give me three copies of that and assigned
it to s.
So what we expect is 1 2 3 4 5 1 2 3 4 5 and 1 2 3 4 5 just what we see right here.
Let me scroll this up just a little bit.
We put all this on the same screen.
So we're right about OK so that's better.
So now I've got S-3 is ABC DPF and all I'm saying is give me five copies in this case of S-3 and just
put it right back in history.
So we expect five copies of a b c d f and that's what we're getting here.
You can see the five copies of that string.
Now we're using the insertion and extraction operators we're testing those.
So we've got a couple of variables here repeat string and repeat times and we're just simply asking
the user entering string to repeat and we're using the extraction operator to read that writing to repeat
strain that's our own overloaded extraction operator.
So I typed in dash three zeroes and a dash and then how many times would you like me to repeat this.
I entered five times and I simply wrote repeat string star equals repeat time.
So give me five copies of that and then I'm displaying it right here one two three four five copies
of that.
Then the next line just gives me 12 copies of what I just did.
So it's going to give me five times 12 is going to give me 60 of these guys printed out here which is
just a really simple test.
And then finally the last test for the concatenation operator right here I've got repeat string is just
repeat me and then I'm simply outputting repeat string plus repeat string plus repeat string.
So I expect the three copies of that to display and there they are repeat me repeat me and repeat me
again.
There were were chaining the concatenation operators and noticed that here were creating actually a
temporary unnamed.
So you can uncommented move assignments and move constructors and you can see how that's happening efficiently.
Here we're saying repeat string plus equals repeat string plus times three.
So we're basically adding this time right.
So we're taking this repeat string which is repeat me give me three copies of it and then adding it
right back to repeat me which had one copy in there already.
So we expect to end up with four copies.
We have one two three and four read here.
And then the last several test cases are the posts and Prete increments.
So we'll do the pre-increment first.
In this case I've got Frank scroll that down just a little bit right there.
So in this case I've got a pre-increment.
My string is Frank with the uppercase F and I'm saying pre-increment.
So I expect Frank to be uppercase when I output it.
And that's what I'm getting here.
I'm setting it back down to lowercase and up putting it right there.
I'm saying my string result result pre-increment s.
So when that happens I expect both s end result to contain the upper case Frank which is exactly what's
happening here.
And then finally we'll test the post-increment where we're setting as to Frank and just simply incrementing
as we should get member post and pre-increment all alone in the statement.
I mean the same thing.
So in this case I've got Frank as uppercase which I'm displaying I making Frank lower case and then
I'm testing the post-increment.
In this context here which means assign the lower case version to result and then increment S..
So a result we expect to be lower case as we expect to be uppercase.
And there you go.
So a lot of talk with the test cases but they're important that you understand what they're supposed
to do when we look at the challenge solution too we won't go over these again since we went over them
here.
But that's pretty much it.
Implementing these as member methods is pretty straightforward.
It's just a matter of understanding you know what we're changing as to how far we've got the right hand
object as well.
Do we return a reference do we return by value.
And that's it.
If you have questions please let me know.