In this video we'll learn the C++ syntax for deriving classes from existing classes using inheritance.
First we start with the class declaration for the base class.
This is the class that will be creating the new class from this class will have its own member data
and methods as we've already learned in this course then we declared the new class derived in this case
followed by a colon then an access specifier and the name of the base class the access specifier can
be public private or protected.
If you don't provide an access specifier private inheritance is used.
Let's see what the access specifiers do.
C++ allows for three types of inheritance public private and protected.
This is very different from many other object oriented programming languages.
Most other object oriented programming languages only support public inheritance.
Public inheritance is the most common form of inheritance and it's the type of inheritance that will
most often see used in C++.
Public inheritance establishes an is a relationship between derived and base classes and it's the type
of inheritance we'll focus on in this course.
Private and protected inheritance establish a derived class has a base class relationship and is often
used to implement one class in terms of another private and protected inheritance of beyond the scope
of this course.
Let's see an example of deriving a savings account class from an account class using public inheritance.
Notice that we're assuming that we already have an existing account class and it's got its own member
data and methods and we want to reuse it.
Now suppose we want to create a savings account class that has much in common with an account class
but it also has some more specialized behavior.
We can declare the savings account class then provide a colon followed by the public access specifier
and finally the name of the base class.
This establishes an is a relationship between savings account and account.
Now a savings account inherits everything in the account class and it's free to implement its own specialized
behaviors based on the behaviors it inherited from account.
Of course we now have two classes in our application so we can create account objects as in this slide.
We assume that we have no args constructor and the deposit and withdrawal methods handle deposit and
withdraw funds to an account we can create account objects on the stack or on the heap via a pointer
and call these methods as we need.
We also have a savings account class so we can create savings account objects.
In this case the specialized deposit and withdraw methods of the savings account class will be used.
So as you can see conceptually inheritance is pretty simple.
However the nuances of inheritance can get very complex.
Let's head over to the idea and create account and savings account classes and then we'll learn about
protected member access specifiers in the next video OK so I'm in the code light IDM in the section
15 workspace indeed driving are first class project and what I've done is I've created a real simple
account hierarchy with two classes and it really does nothing.
It just has a couple of deposit withdrawal methods that just say Hi I'm deposit Higham withdraw just
so we can see them being called and then what we'll do is we'll tweak this just a little bit so that
we can add some attribute so you can really understand what's going on here.
So let's take a look at the account class first.
This is our base class.
Notice that there is nothing going on here.
Everything's public.
We'll worry about protected and private in the next couple of videos.
But right now all we've got is a deposit method of withdrawal method no args constructor and a destructor.
OK.
So let's take a look at the implementation.
And as you can see the constructors and the structures are just there with no code.
Our deposit method just simply says account deposit called with whatever amount we called it with.
And the withdrawal method says account withdraw called with that same amount.
So can't get any easier than this.
So now we're going to do is we're going to derive a savings account from an account.
So what we'll do is we'll create a savings account Hetter as well as implementation files.
And you'll notice right here in savings account we're including the countdown H.
Right we've got to include that header file.
Otherwise this class of the compiler won't know what an account is.
And here's the syntax class savings account.
That's the class we're deriving.
And then public account account in this case is the base class and you can see that this class is also
really simple.
It's got no args constructor it's got a destructor and it's got its own version of deposit and its own
version of withdraw and the implementation.
Again the constructor and the destructor don't have any code in the body.
The deposits simply says savings account deposit called with amount that would be the difference between
when the account deposit method is called in the savings account deposit method is called.
And the same for withdraw.
OK good.
So now let's take a look at our main It's just a real simple man that exercise is some of these classes.
So what we'll do here is create an account object right here named A.S.C..
And again this is an account this is our base class.
This is not using inheritance right here right.
This is just instantiating a base account.
And then I'm going to call deposit and withdraw what we expect there is for the deposit and withdraw
methods of the account class to be called and we'll do the same thing here with a pointer just so you
can see that it works exactly the same way with the pointer.
Then what we'll do is we'll do the same but with a savings account.
So we'll create this object right here a savings account and it will be a savings account and we'll
call the deposit and the withdrawal methods for the savings account and what we expect there is to see
the output saying savings account deposit savings account withdrawal.
And again we're doing down here with the pointer so I'm going to build and run this and we'll take a
look at the output and then what we'll do is we'll modify these files just a little bit so you can really
understand what's going on behind the scenes.
Okay.
So there's my output and I'm going to move this just next to the main So we can see exactly what's going
on.
Here we go so we're creating the A.S.C. object and we're calling it deposit and withdraw on it and you
can see right here we're calling the account deposit and the account withdraw.
That's exactly what we expect because A.S.C. is an account object.
In this case there is no inheritance going on.
I'm simply using a base class as I've used all along.
And down here you can see these last two statements right there for the account is just using the pointer.
OK so now let's take a look at the savings account.
So here's the savings account right here and I'm creating a save account object right here and then
I'm saying saving you count that deposit saving account withdraw.
So in this case I expect the savings account versions of those methods to be called.
You can see that that's exactly what's happening here.
OK.
So again the account is the more general class the savings account is a more specialized class.
And since we've got those methods that we've specialized in the savings account plus those are the ones
that are being called right here.
OK so hopefully that's clear.
Now let me make a couple of small changes and then we'll run this through the debugger so you can see
the structure of these classes.
So let's go into the account class and what we can do here and again I'm going to keep everything public
for now will change that in the next videos.
What I'm going to do here is I'm simply going to create a double balance and string name just for a
real simple name for an account and let me.
That may include the string Hetter
OK so now we're saying that all accounts have a balance and all accounts have a name.
We obviously need to initialize those.
I'm just going to initialize balance to zero and name to something like an account so we can do that
in our implementation file right here.
We can do it right here in the no args constructor.
We can simply say balance is zero and name is an account or something anything really.
OK so that's it.
So now we'll go into our savings account and we'll say OK a savings account will also provides its own
version of functionality.
Remember this is the specialized class.
So let's say that a savings account has an interest rate and it's a double.
So obviously what will initialize that is well we don't want it to have garbage data.
So we're going to come into our implementation file and we'll do that right here using an initializer
list will say interest rate.
And I don't know let's say it's 3 percent interest.
Okay perfect.
Now if we run this we should get exactly the same output because these being changed output statements
really on display interest rate or name or anything else.
So let's just be sure that it runs.
There's I believe there is a run and again nothing here has changed.
But let's take a look at this in the debugger.
So let me close this up real quick and I'm going to go back to my main and what I want to do is I want
to put a couple of break points here.
We'll put a break point right here on 9:14 where we're actually creating that account object.
We'll put another breakpoint right here on line 29 where we're creating the savings account object.
And what I want to do is debug this and I'll start it.
And I'm really not interested in the output.
What I'm interested in here is a local variable so that's where what we're going to concentrate on.
So we're in line 14.
I'm just about ready to execute that line that that's going to instantiate or create that account object.
So I'm going to go next.
Now it's created.
Let's take a look at it.
There's a c c it was just created you can see the balance is zero and the name is an account member
the name is a C++ string.
Perfect.
Now I'm going to come down here to 9:29.
I'll just keep hitting next as I get to it and what's going to happen when I get here is I'm going to
create a savings account object right here.
So I'm going to press next.
Now that savings account has been created it's called Save underscore account.
I'll refresh this.
And let's take a look at it.
Remember what account was zero an account.
Now let's look at savings account.
Notice that savings account has an interest rate right.
That's what it brought to the table.
But it's also an account because we've got inherit and so everything that was in my parent is in me.
So there's the account part of me being a savings account and you could see that the account part of
me is zero into account name part of me is an account.
OK.
So hopefully you get some insight into what's really going on here.
We really are inheriting all that information from our parent.
So let me just draw this out sort of to be really clear.
Suppose that this is A.S.C. right here that's A.S.C. that's that object right up here and it's an account
and it has two local variables right balance
in name.
And we would never worry about what you're set to you can kind of see that over here and it also has
access to those two methods.
Right.
Deposit and withdraw as well as the constructor's and the destructor.
But I'm not worried about those right now I'm just really concentrating on these two methods.
So the accountant knows about its methods.
Now down here I've got a savings account.
So let me create that and I'll just draw a big box.
And this is a savings account that same of the object and its type is a savings account
that's this guy right there.
Now savings account member is an account so it's got an account part inside it and that account part
is going to look just like this guy right here.
It's going to have a balance.
Right.
It's going to have a name.
It's going to have access to those deposit and withdraw methods.
I'll just write them here.
And those are the deposit and withdraw methods for the account class.
But then our savings account or savings account class as interest rate and it's got its own versions
of deposit and withdraw.
So conceptually this is really what's going on and you can obviously see it right here you can see that
it's got the account part of it right there.
Now obviously the methods aren't here and the methods aren't going to be copied and every single object
they're going to be in in one place.
But think of it conceptually this way and I think you'll be good to go because this is really what's
happening behind the scenes.
So when we said that a savings account is an account it sure is right there is the account part of me.
Now a couple of things we need to talk about what in here what in here is accessible to the savings
account.
How do we initialize the account part of us.
So this is where we're headed with the next few lectures because we really need to be able to know you
know what can I access from these methods.
Am I able to access these guys right here or not.
I'm not sure I read it all depends on our access modifiers.
And also I need to be able to instantiate or initialize that account.
Part of me.
OK so that's what we'll do next.