In this video we'll learn how to invoke base class constructors in passing arguments from the derived
class.
Remember since the base part of a derived class must be initialized first then we know that some base
class constructor must be invoked to do that initialization.
So in this video we'll learn how to control exactly which base constructor will be used.
We can determine which base constructor to be is based on the arguments that we want to pass to it from
the derived class.
So let's see how we can do this.
In this example we have a base class and let's assume that that base class has no args constructor and
an overloaded constructor that expects a single integer parameter.
Now we have a derived class which is derived from base and the derived class has a constructor that
has a single integer parameter.
We can invoke the base class is overloaded constructor and the derived constructors initialization list
as shown in this slide.
That's it.
It's pretty simple and clear syntax.
In this case we're passing the integer x to our base class constructor when it's invoked.
Following this we can have initializers for the derived classes attributes as needed.
Finally we have the code in the body but remember this code executes after both the base and derived
parts of the derived object have been initialized.
If we don't explicitly invoke the base overloaded constructor then the no args constructor will be invoked
automatically since Remember the base part must be initialized.
So let's see the complete example.
Here we see the base class declaration.
Pretty standard code.
The base class has an integer attribute named value and it has two constructors.
The first constructor is the no args constructor and it initializes value to 0 and displays.
Base no args constructor.
The second constructor is an overloaded constructor that expects a single integer parameter and it initializes
a value to the integer x and then it displays Int base constructor.
Now let's see the derived class the derived class is derived from base using public inheritance and
it has an integer attribute named double value.
It also has two constructors.
The first constructor is the No ARFs constructor.
Note that in its initializer list it explicitly invokes the base no args constructor and then initialize
is its own double value attribute.
Finally it displays drive no args constructor.
The second constructor is the overloaded constructor that expects an integer parameter.
This constructor also invokes the base class overloaded in constructor in its initializer list and then
it initializes its own doubled value attribute to two times X. And finally it displays in derived constructor.
Note that we could have implemented the overloaded constructors as delegating constructors but I wanted
to keep the display message is clear so that we could follow the calls.
So now let's create a few objects and see what is called.
First let's create a simple base object with no parameters.
In this case the base no args constructor is called In the second example we're creating a base object
and providing an integer initialization argument.
This will invoke the overloaded Int base constructor as we would expect.
Now in the third example we're creating a Derived object with no parameters.
This will invoke the derived no args constructor which in turn will invoke the base no artiste's constructor
from it's initialization list.
Once the base part is initialized then the rest of the derived no args constructor executes.
So you can see the output is what we expect.
First the base Norge constructor then the derived no args constructor.
The last example works in the similar way.
We're creating a Derived object with an integer initialization argument so the derived int derive constructor
is invoked and then we explicitly invoke the Int base constructor from it.
So the first Int base constructor executes and then the derived constructor.
Of course all these objects will be destroyed by the destructors when they go out of scope.
You can see that we have complete control as to which base class constructors to invoke from our derived
class constructors.
So let's head over to the ID and see this behavior in life code.
Ok so I mean the ID and I'm in the section 15 workspace in the base class initialization project.
This project looks very very similar to the one we did in the previous video.
However I've spread out the code a little bit more just so it's easier to see in the debugger what's
going on and what I'm doing here.
I'm explicitly calling my base class initializers from my derived class so you can see here that I've
got no args constructor my derived class and I explicitly calling my base classes no args instructor
right here.
Similarly in the overloaded integer constructor from my derived class I'm calling my base class is overloaded
integer constructor.
That way I've got explicit control over how my objects are being created not just my part but my base
part as well.
So let's run through some examples.
We won't do the base ones because those are those haven't changed at all.
We'll just worry about the derived ones.
So in this case that's create a derived object and we'll call it D and we'll provide no initialization
information here.
So we'll run the debugger and step through it.
So we're here on line 40 and we're just about to create that derived object.
Again I've got no initialization information so I expect my no args derived constructor be called right
here on line 26.
And if I step through it you can see that that's exactly where I'm at.
But now in this case I'm explicitly invoking my base class constructor.
Also the no args constructor.
And I'll scroll up just a little bit so it's going to be right there on line 11.
So what's going to happen now is and it's important to understand the order here before.
My attributes are initialized doubled values my attribute right here on the derived class before my
attributes were initialized before the body of the derive constructor is initialized.
The base part of me will be initialized.
So in this case when I step three you'll see that it transfers control up to here on 9/11 and the base
no args constructor is called.
It will set that value right here in the base to 0 and it will display based no args constructor.
Then I come back to where I left off initialize double value to 0 and you can see that that will indeed
be 0 here.
Now they're both zero right.
The value in the base as well as the double value that just got initialized to zero right here in the
initializer list.
Then we display Dr. no args constructor and our object is constructed.
So when it goes out of scope the destructors will be called in the reverse order so let's do that.
You can see right here that derive destructors being called and that executes and then we come up to
here and execute our base destructor right here and will display that as well.
OK so there you go.
That's a real simple example of how we can invoke our base class initializers.
Now comment this out and what we'll do now is we'll do the same thing but we'll do derived D and we'll
use an initializer of a thousand.
So I've moved the breakpoint to this line 41 and what we're doing now is we'll start the debugger again
and we'll walk through this example.
So what do we expect in this case.
Well in 9:41 we're creating a D object which is a derived object and repete we're using a thousand and
his initialiser.
So we expect this constructor right here on 09:30 to be invoked because it expects that's the overloaded
integer constructor.
So let's step through and you'll see that that is that's exactly what happens.
But now before we initialize our own variables before we do anything in the body of the constructor
our base needs to be initialized.
So in this case I'm explicitly invoking my base class constructor with the variable x that was passed
into me.
So it going to happen here is this constructor right here on line 14 will be invoked.
So we step through that and you can see that's exactly where we are.
The value for the value will be set to x in this case a thousand.
And then I'll display the message.
Then I come back to my derived overloaded constructor and finish off here.
What just happened was that my doubled value was initialized to 2000 and I'm just about to display this.
So at this point my object has been fully initialized and if I look at D you can see that the base part
of me is is 0 0 0 0 0.
And the doubled value part of me is 2000 which is exactly what we wanted and that's the issue we had
in the previous video that we couldn't get that quite to work that way.
And of course as I destroy this object the derived destructor gets invoked first and then the base destructor
gets that vote.
And our program is complete.
OK so there you go.
That's a real simple example of how to initialize the base part of us when we're using inheritance in
the next video.
What we'll do is we'll look at the way that copy and move constructors and overloaded assignment operators
work with inheritance.