One of the most powerful features of inheritance is that base class member functions are available to
the derived class a derived class can directly invoke base class methods a derived class can also override
or redefine base class methods.
This concept will provide us with a large amount of power when we use polymorphic functions in the next
section in order to redefine or override a method.
You simply provide a method in the derived class with the same name and signature as a method in the
base class.
But see an example here will both use and override a base class method.
Suppose we have an account class and it has a deposit method that simply increments a balance by an
amount.
Now we have a savings account class and it also needs a deposit method but its behavior will be slightly
different in some way.
We can override the account class deposit method in the Savings Account class by providing a specialized
implementation using the same method signature.
Now when the savings account objects deposit funds this specialized method will be invoked.
But since the accounts deposit method does some of the work that we want to do in the savings account
deposit method we don't have to duplicate code.
We can simply call the accounts deposit method from within the savings accounts deposit method.
You can see the syntax makes sense.
We must prefix the method call with the account class so the compiler knows that we're calling the deposit
method in the account class.
It's super important that we don't try to do the actual deposit in the savings account method.
Instead let the account class do what it knows how to do.
If the base functionality for deposit ever changes it won't affect our savings account deposit method.
Since all it's doing is delegating this to the account class
let's finish up this video by talking about static binding by default C++ does static binding of method
calls all that means is that the compiler determines which methods are called based on what it sees
at compile time.
Static binding is super efficient and that's why it's the default in C++.
So if the compiler sees that a b is declared as a base object and we call B deposit then the compiler
will call the base classes deposit.
The same is true for a Derived object if D is a derived object and Deedat deposit is called.
This results in a call to the derived classes deposit method.
While this is very efficient and fine in most cases there are times when we'd like the binding to take
place at runtime.
We'll see that in the next section.
Let's see a couple of examples next.
In the first example here you can see that B.Com deposit we'll call the base classes deposit method
because B is a base object and Deedat deposit.
We'll call the derived classes deposit method since D is a type of derived.
But consider the last two lines of code.
In this case we have a pointer to a base object but we create a Derived object on the heap and assign
it to the pointer.
This is perfectly valid since a derived is a base.
But now if we called the deposit method to the pointer the compiler will call the base classes deposit
method because it sees that pointer is a pointer to a base class but perhaps it would make more sense
to call that derives deposit method.
In this example since the actual object pointed to is a derived object.
As I said we learn how to achieve this kind of dynamic binding in the next section but it's very important
to understand that by default C++ uses static binding.
OK so I mean the idea I mean the section 15 workspace in the redefining base class methods project and
what we've got here is a real simple account class and we'll derive a savings account class from it
similar to what we did in the slides and we'll do it from scratch that where you can see how this works
with using and redefining base class methods.
So let's take a look at the account class.
We've got a friend here that allows us just to put count objects on a stream and display them really
easily.
And what we're modeling is the balance right.
That's the whole idea of an account.
It models a balance and it's a double in this case.
And then we've got some public methods here which are no args constructor.
We've got a constructor right here that's overloaded where you supply the balance and then we've got
a deposit and a withdraw method now the deposit and withdraw functionality is dead simple right.
Give me an amount of deposit it give me an amount I'll withdraw it.
The only thing we're checking is to make sure that there's enough balance so that we can withdraw the
funds.
OK so that's it.
Let's take a look at the implementation.
Now you'll notice that there are no copy constructor has moved constructors overloaded assignment operators
and so forth.
We don't need them.
We're modeling a double.
And it really doesn't make any sense to include them that the compiler provided ones are perfectly adequate.
So let's take a look at the source.
And again you can see real real simple stuff here.
What I've got is my no args constructor right here.
And when that is not is invoked then all I'm doing is I'm calling my regular overloaded constructor
right here and I'm passing in a zero to it.
So I'm delegating to it.
And at this point that constructor just simply sets the balance to balance right.
Simple as that the deposit method increments the balance by whatever amount was passed in the withdraw
method expects an amount we want to make sure that you're sufficient funds if there are we're just going
to subtract the amount from the balance.
Otherwise we'll just display a simple message in sufficient funds.
And here's my overloaded insertion OPERATOR OK.
So there you go.
Simple stuff.
Now what we'll do is let's take a look at our savings account.
OK so here's the savings account class header file we're including account header file and a savings
account is an account so you can see the inheritance right here.
Class savings account public account we are using is a inheritance here and a savings account is an
account so it's going to provide a balance just like the account.
But what it does add is an interest rate.
So the interest rate is used when users deposit funds.
So if you deposit $1000 and we've got a 5 percent interest rate the amount that you deposit will be
one thousand plus $50.
So we're getting folks really good bonuses here.
I wish my bank account did this.
So anyway so that's what we're going to do.
Now the withdrawal method doesn't specialize.
So the idea there is that we can use our parents our accounts withdraw method as is.
We don't have to do anything.
We're going to have to declare it in here because we're automatically inherited.
All right.
So why don't we start doing this class right here.
So let's start writing the code for this class right here.
First thing we want to do is declare that friend of ours might as well get it out of the way and it's
going to return a stood output stream reference its operator and the insertion operator.
And what does expect when it expects a stood out stream by reference and I'll just call that OS this
design pattern here you'll see over and over used in C++ and in this case it expects a savings account
object and we'll call it account by reference.
So that's the prototype for that will implement that in the C++ file later.
Hopefully I don't have any typos I'll deal with typos after when we compile that way we don't waste
a lot of time.
Now that's it.
So now what do we want to do what we have to add what we add.
We're adding in interest rates so we'll use a protected key word here and will supply our interest rate
which will be a double and I'll just call it in rate get.
That's it.
And now what we'll do is we'll provide some public methods in this case our constructor's so it'll be
a savings account constructor that will be a no Arden's constructor will also supply a savings account
constructor.
In this case that will expect the balance which will be handled by the account part of me and the interest
rate which will be handled by me me being the to the savings account less.
And we also have to handle the deposit method because we're redefining it overwriting it.
So in this case we want the same function prototype as we had in our parent.
So it's deposit.
And I believe that was double the amount that it notice withdraw is inherited and the functionality
that we were using to withdraw funds in the account class is all I need in the Savings Account class.
All right so now let's implement this.
Only a few methods to implement so it should be pretty quick and pretty straightforward.
I'm including my savings account header file and let's do the no args constructor Actually let's do
the second constructor first.
The savings account the overloaded constructor.
And it's this guy right here and then expects a double for balance and another double for the interest
rate fix that typo here.
So those are the two parameters in this particular constructor and what we want to do here.
Well we want to we want to initialize the count part of us right.
So we want to invoke our account part constructor right our parents constructor and that expects just
a balance that's all it knows about it doesn't know anything about the interest rate.
And then once that's initialized I can come back and take care of the interest rate and initialize that.
There is nobody to this construct or you could just leave it like that if you want to type something
you know out constructor call.
That's fine.
But we really don't need to do anything else here.
OK so now how about the no args constructor.
Well let's do that.
That was pretty easy to do right.
So here's my no args constructor it expects nothing.
Now what do we want to do here.
Well the simplest thing to do is just to delegate to my overloaded constructor right.
So what I want to do here is delegate to my savings account overloaded constructor up here.
And what I want to pass into it is zero point zero for the balance and zero point zero for the interest
rate and that's it.
That will take care of that.
So my two constructor's are done.
We don't have any Didi's directors or copy constructors or anything like that.
So let's worry about the deposit method right.
So let's say void and its savings account it's my deposit method and it expects a double which is the
amount you deposit what we want to do here is we want to increment that amount by that interest rate.
As I said.
So what we want to do is we want to figure out how much do we need to deposit.
So let's say amount that's that same amount right here.
We could use another variable if we want but this works just fine.
A local variable I mean amount equals amount plus it will say amount times the interest rate divided
by a hundred that will give us the percentage and that should do it.
We could have set amount plus equals as well be a little clearer.
Now we know how much we need to deposit.
So rather than do it ourselves let's just let the account parent part of us do it.
So will say account it's got a deposit method in there and we'll pass in the amount that we wanted to
deposit for us.
That's it.
And then finally will implement the friend overloaded operator.
So this returns a raft to an O stream and we're overloading an operator our insertion operator again
stood up stream by reference and we'll call it o.
And we've got a cost savings account.
Ref OK and all we're doing here is we're saying we're putting onto that output stream we'll say something
like savings account balance
and we'll put the accounts balance on here.
Followed by the interest rate
and the interest rate for the account and we know it's got it because it is a savings account right
here
that should do it.
And we want to return that string.
All right so let's compile this and see if we've got any typos.
We probably do.
And there's one right here
OK.
So we have a run.
Let me show you the main real quick and you'll notice one thing right away it wasn't a lot of work to
do this right.
That's the whole point of reusing all I had to do is create these constructors right override that deposit
method.
The rest is just came right in the withdraw method I didn't have to touch because I mean hurting it
from my parent.
So let's take a look at the main quake and I just wrote a couple of simple test cases here where I'm
creating an account a one with a thousand dollars in it and I'm displaying it and depositing $500 into
it and withdrawing a thousand and then I'm withdrawing 5000 I'm going to get insufficient funds.
So let's build and run that.
And you could see here we've got a thousand 1300 500 insufficient funds and we still have 500 K and
then we've got some test cases down here that work with these actual savings accounts that we just created.
So let's run those.
And you could hear see here now that I've got a savings account with a balance of a thousand and an
interest rate of five.
I've got after the deposit.
Notice that 1 0 0 0 was deposited 1050 was deposited because that was our specialized deposit method.
So now we've got a balance of 20 50 same interest rate.
I'm going to withdraw 2000 which leaves us with a $50 balance right here.
Then if I try to withdraw 0 0 0 Obviously I've got insufficient funds and then display it again and
we still have 50.
OK.
So there you go that's an example of reusing an account class.
And we're reducing the withdrawal method 100 percent right.
And if you look again at the deposit method we really are reusing it we're actually calling it right
here and what we're doing is tweaking the amount that we want deposited and then just said to get right
up.
Now one thing I should mention we overloaded the insertion operator here to work with the savings account
simply to display the interest rate.
Right.
If you send in a savings account object to this guy right here in the account class.
Remember a savings account is an account what will happen here is the object gets sliced and it will
only print out the account balance not the interest rate because the compiler is going to slice that
part out.
So the only reason that we're implementing this guy right here on 9:18 the savings account C.P. is so
that we can see the interest rate.
So what we're doing the next video is I'll give you the beginnings of an account class hierarchy.
And in the challenge what you'll do is add some more accounts to this that have you know more specialized
behaviors you can get some experience with inheritance and remember all of this is using static binding
which is really important.