In this video we'll see a simple example of multiple inheritance in C++ multiple inheritance occurs
when a derived class inherits from two or more base classes at the same time.
The base classes may belong to unrelated class hierarchies.
The class diagram on the right shows an example of multiple inheritance.
In this case the class department chair is derived from both faculty and administrator classes.
So if we use public inheritance then a department chair is a faculty member and a department chair is
also an administrator.
The C++ syntax for multiple inheritance is simple.
We declare our derived class and then provide a comma separated list of the base classes that it's derived
from.
In this case department chair is our derived class and its base classes are faculty and administrator.
We're only showing public inheritance here but we could also use the other types of C++ inheritance
multiple inheritance is beyond the scope of this course and it can be very very complex in practice.
There are some compelling use cases for multiple inheritance.
However in many cases we can refactor our design so that the multiple inheritance can be avoided and
many times we end up with a better design.
This isn't because there's anything wrong with multiple inheritance.
The problem with multiple inheritance is that because it can be so complex.
Many developers don't fully understand it and therefore may mis use it more often.
You see multiple inheritance in class libraries and frameworks that you might be using.