In this section of the course we'll see how we can use polymorphism in inheritance to provide us with
the power to create reusable and flexible programs.
We'll start by understanding the different types of polymorphism available in C++.
And then we'll focus on dynamic polymorphism in this section Some will learn how to use base class pointers
to really take our class hierarchies to a new level and see how we can now think more abstractly and
not have to worry about details throughout this section of the course.
We'll see examples of static and dynamic binding of function calls and we'll understand the pros and
cons of each.
Then we'll use virtual functions to achieve polymorphic functions.
That is functions that are bound at runtime.
We'll see how important it is to have virtual structures.
We'll see how important it is to have virtual destructors and use the C++ 11 override and final specifiers.
Then we'll see how we can use base class references to also achieve dynamic polymorphism.
Finally we'll learn what pure virtual functions and abstract classes are and why we would want to use
them as is and in interfaces is a lot to cover.
But I think you'll find this section pretty easy to grasp since you have a pretty solid foundation already.
So let's get started with polymorphism.