We've already seen that in order for the C++ compiler to use dynamic binding of method calls we must
have an inheritance hierarchy.
We must be using a base class pointer or a base class reference and we must declare the methods we want
dynamically bound is virtual.
In this video we'll look at the base pointer requirement and see why it's so useful and so powerful.
We'll use the account class hierarchy on the right side of the slide as our example.
Let's also assume that this class hierarchy is now using dynamic polymorphism.
We're learning how to do that in this section of the course.
For now let's just concentrate on the effects and the power it gives us.
So we'll create four pointers to account objects and we'll initialize each one to a different type of
account created on the heap.
So as you can see P1 holds the address of an account object.
P2 holds the address of a savings account object.
P3 holds the address of a checking account object and P4 holds the address of a trust account object.
We've already seen that this is valid semantically since there are all accounts due to the public is
a inheritance we're using.
Now we can call the withdraw method using the base class pointers and C++ will figure out which method
to bind at runtime based on the type of the object being pointed to by each pointer.
This is pretty cool.
There's nothing else you need to do.
Once the hierarchy is set up of course we need to delete the storage allocated by the point is when
we're done with them.
OK so now let's see a more compelling use case for using base class pointers.
In this case we have the same four pointers we created in the previous slide but I've declared an array
that holds pointers to account objects.
These will be the base class pointers.
I then initialize the array to hold the four pointers we declared previously.
Now I can simply loop through the array and call the withdraw method for each element in the array and
the correct withdraw method will be called based on the type of the object that each pointer points
to.
You can see how powerful this is.
It doesn't matter how many base class pointers initialized the array with or what type of accounts they're
pointing to.
It will work as expected.
Also if we replace one array element for another it will also work as expected.
This is what I was talking about when I said programming more abstractly or more generally.
Here I'm simply thinking call the withdraw method for each account in the array.
That's it.
No more details required.
Of course this also works with other collections such as a vector.
Here we have the same four pointers.
And then we create a vector of pointers to account.
So the vector holds.
Base class pointers we can then initialize the vector to P1 P2P 3 and 4.
Then we can simply loop through the vector using a range based for loop or an iterator and call the
withdraw method for each vector element.
Think about what would happen if we added another class to our account hierarchy say a bond account.
None of the code that we have that works where the count objects needs to be changed since a bond account
is an account.
It will automatically work with our existing code.
A little note here though.
Be careful when you use raw pointers in collections such as vectors.
It's better to use smart pointers in this type of example.
But you haven't really learned about them yet.
We will soon.
So there you go.
I hope you can see the power of the base pointer and how much more abstractly we can think when writing
our code.
Let's head over to the idea and we'll run these examples so you can see firsthand.
OK so I mean the ID I'm in the U.S. 16 workspace in the base class pointer's project.
Now let me explain what's going on this project.
I've already gone ahead and taken that account hierarchy account checking account savings account and
trustee account and I've made it so that it works with dynamic polymorphism.
So I've done the virtual functions I've done all that already.
I just want to show you how to use this and see how powerful it is in the next video will learn about
virtual functions and will start implementing it ourselves.
But let's take a look at the main.
This is really what the point of this video is.
If you look at the main You can see that first we're going to do the pointers and we'll deal with the
Rays and vectors but it's just plain pointers first US.
Here you can see that I've got the four pointers P1 P2P 3 MP for each one points to a different type
of account.
But they are all accounts right because we've got public inheritance in our hierarchy.
And then what we're doing is we're calling the withdraw method for each one of those objects.
And the idea is if we've done our dynamic polymorphism Correct p one we'll call the account withdraw
P2 we'll call the savings withdraw P3 we'll call the checking withdraw and P4 we'll call the trust withdraw.
OK so let's give this build and run and you can see the output right here I'll just move it over so
we can see it we can see pointers and then the withdrawal methods are called right down here and you
can see that we're calling the accounts withdraw.
Then the savings withdraw and the checking is withdrawn.
And finally a trust withdraw.
So exactly what we expected.
We've got a binding now happening at run time.
That's really really powerful stuff.
We also have the cleanup here I'll show you what that looks like that's just deleting those four pointers.
So we free up the storage that we allocated for them.
All right so now let's take a look at how this would work with a raise and uncomment this out.
And in this case I'm just putting out a line that says array so we know what's going on and what I'm
doing here I'm creating an array.
And this is the declaration right here.
I'm creating an array.
That's what the brackets say of pointers to accounts.
So when you create an array in this case and it's going to have four pointers in it each one of these
pointers is going to point to an account object.
So that's what it looks like.
P1 here.
Right.
The one is the account so this will be an account
P2 will be a savings account you get the idea right.
That's a checking account and a trust account.
And then what I'm doing is I'm simply looping through this array right here and I'm calling the withdraw
method for each one of those pointers.
So this will call the account this will call the savings this will call the checking and this will cover
the trust withdrawal methods.
OK.
So the real powerful piece here is that as you can see I don't have to worry about that in the loop.
All I'm doing here is simply calling the withdrawal method for each one of those guys and whatever happens
to be there will be dynamically bound and it'll be called the correct method which is super super powerful.
So let's give this one a run and we can see that here's the run and you can see the array right here.
And notice what's happening here.
I put people in P2 P3 MP for the array.
Those are base class pointers.
I'm not putting a count objects in the array and putting pointers to count objects in the array.
And they all happen to be base class pointers.
That's why this works.
So in this case I'm calling this four times right.
0 1 2 and 3.
And you can see here in a count in savings in checking and interest.
So we're getting the exact behavior that we want.
So let's modify this just slightly and what we can do is we can take and I'll just copy this again so
we can see that output one more times we can separate it and keep it keep it nice and clean.
What I want to do here is I simply want to say let's set Auray Sub-Zero.
That first item in the array.
Let's set that to p for p for is a pointer to a trust account and then let's just loop again and call
the withdraw method for all of those guys.
Now her output should be a little different now right.
Because our first array element that one at index 0 is no longer an account that was appeared when he
won in there.
Now it's a trust account.
So what we expect in the output now would be trust savings checking.
Trust right.
So let's try that out.
And let's see what we get here.
Trust savings checking trust you see that's exactly what we wanted really doesn't matter what these
pointers point to.
It will get bound correctly.
And the real powerful thing here is I never really changed that loop right.
The loop was exactly the same as it was before.
I didn't have to do any checking for anything.
All right so now let's take a look at the vector version.
And as I mentioned in the slides be really really careful when you use raw pointers and any kind of
collection but especially a vector what you want to do is if you're going to use them use them this
way where you create your initialize the vector this way.
Don't put like something like a new account or something in here because that could be problematic when
it comes to destroying those objects.
You'd have to loop through the vector and destroy them yourself.
But anyway.
But just go look at this example real quick.
So here's my vector.
What am I doing.
Well in this case I'm creating a vector and what is the vector of write my template parameter is a pointer
to an account.
So what if I got decide we had an array right.
We have a vector of pointers to accounts.
That's my base class pointer.
I'm initializing it to P1 P2P 3 P4.
And at this point all I'm doing is a range based for loop right here and it just using the auto keyword
is going to figure out that that's an account pointer and I'm looping through there and that's it.
I'm just calling the withdraw method for each one of those pointers that's in the vector.
Again what we expect here because we've got P1 P2 P3 P4 we expect a count let me go back up and make
sure I get this right.
We expect a count savings checking.
Trust that's where we're putting them in.
So when this runs that's what we expect.
Let's give this a run and there is our vector case right here and in here we've got a count savings
checking trust exactly what we wanted.
All right.
So let's just do one more little quick change here and what we can do is let's add two more items to
that vector and what we can do is we can add that trust point to again we can get it two times at the
back.
So why don't we do that.
Let me copy you this again just so we have some separation in the output and we can better follow it.
So what we'll do here is we'll just say my vector's is called accounts.
So I'm going to say accounts push back and let's push back p 4 so we're adding P for the end and let's
do it again and we'll add P4 again.
So now when we loop through that vector this time we expect those first four output statements to be
the same but we expect to more output statements at the end for the trust withdraw being called right
because now we've got six items in this vector.
So let's keep that around.
And here we go you can see one two three four five six items in the vector we're calling the withdraw
for each one of them and you can see how the last three are trust right.
The fourth one was one that was already in there and then the two that I just added right here as I
said be really careful when you're using raw pointers in these things it's better to use smart pointers.
Well talk about smart pointers in the next section.
We could have used a shared pointer here even a unique pointer which would make things a lot more safe.
All right so there you go.
Hopefully you can see the power here.
Remember if I come up here and I've got my accounts and I decide to add a new account here and some
like I said a bond account or something any kind of account as long as I tied into this hierarchy and
make sure that the methods that are being called are virtual there as well then I can create an account
count object right here P5 that set a bond account and all this will work right.
All these loops everything will work exactly the same.
I won't have to modify any code because that's the point I can think generally I can think of strategy.
If you think of this vector right here this code right here what does this say.
It's basically saying loop through the vector and call the withdraw for everything in the vector.
That's pretty high level thinking and that's pretty powerful if I've got a drawing program that's drawing
shapes I can just loop through all my shapes and ask each shape to draw itself or move itself or transform
itself.
So I'm really able to think abstractly and not get bogged down with details.
And that's the power of dynamic polymorphism.