Welcome back to the Section 16 challenge solution.
This is part one of these dilution to this challenge.
This was a very very challenging exercise.
I hope you're able to finish this and I hope your solution worked.
As usual your solution could be different from mine.
Very likely it is.
So let's get started.
First thing we want to do is we want to make this account class an abstract class and we know that we
can do that with the pure virtual functions.
So that's what I'm going to do right here.
I'm coming down right here to my deposit withdraw functions and I'm going to say virtual and I'm going
to make it pure virtual right there.
My class is now abstract.
I'm going to do for both of them.
And again I've got a pure virtual function here as well.
OK so that was easy right.
That's cool.
Eventually we'll get rid of this guy but replace it with the printable interface but we'll leave that
for later.
So we got those two pure virtual functions.
So if I try to create an account object I won't be able to any longer.
So let's take a look at the account implementation file and see if there's anything in here we need
to change our constructors are fine.
You might be thinking why do we need a constructor from I'm never going to create these things.
Well you are right you are through the derived classes member of the constructor calling up the chain.
So it's important that we have constructors here.
There's our deposit and withdraw.
Now these are pure virtual functions can we implement them.
Absolutely we can and in this case it makes sense we'd get a really simple deposit really simple withdraw.
In the case of the examples I gave you with a shape in your how do you draw a shape in the base class
you really can't.
But here we can say that deposit and withdraw this is the simplest case.
And I'd argue that we could leave this in here.
Now there is one little thing that's missing.
That's our virtual destructor.
That's really important.
So let's do that.
We'll say virtual The structure is the name of the class with the Tilney in front and we could implement
this thing where we could just simply say it equals default and that's good enough that tells the compiler
Hey just give me a default destructor in this case and that's fine.
I don't need any special behavior in the destructor so that will be just fine.
All right so now what are we to do next.
Let's look at one of the derived classes so let's start with checking.
So let's look at the header file for checking account you see here is derived from a count.
That's fine.
So remember I've got two pure virtual functions in my parent that I need to implement here so I'm implementing
one of them right here so I want to make sure that this is virtual and I want to be sure that I'm overwriting
this.
That way the compiler is going to help me out if I rename something incorrectly or if I change one of
the parameters or something.
And what about this guy this deposit method we want to implement this guy and he ourselves as well.
So we'll just say virtual bull and this is the deposit method.
So we're going to implement this ourselves and it's expected to double.
And again I'm overriding here.
So I want to be sure that the compiler is helping me.
Okay perfect.
What else do I need here.
You guessed it I need a virtual destructor for a checking account and I'm going to let the compiler
give me a default version which is fine.
OK.
Now this guy wasn't here before so we're definitely going to have to implement that in the CBP file.
So let's go into our file for checking account.
And here's our withdrawal we're calling our parents withdrawal which is fine.
Here's a constructor that looks good as well.
Again these output operators will get rid of them later.
But we need to implement this guy our deposit and it's going to be a checking account deposit.
That's the class we're in.
We don't need the override here.
We already have it in our header file and we do need a name for this parameter.
So what do we do here.
Well it's simply going to return and color accounts deposit method and pass in the double.
That's it.
Right.
I have nothing special to do here so I'm just calling my parents.
So that takes care of checking account.
Now let's go out to savings account and we did put the destructor in there right.
Yes we did.
So let's get a savings account.
Same idea here.
We've got a virtual function here that we're going to override.
That's my deposit and we'll say override right here and then we've got to withdraw.
So I also want to take care of that one here.
It's all said bhool will call this withdraw and it expects that double amount.
And again we're overriding this is one we'll have to implement because we were not implementing it before
and then we also need a virtual destructor here in the name of the class savings account.
Compiler give us one by default.
OK.
Now this withdrawal method is when we have to write Solas footwear implementation some opening up savings
CGP.
My constructor looks find my deposit looks fine we'll get rid of the insertion operator later.
But let's implement this method here.
So this is bhool for a savings account.
And all we are doing here.
And again we don't need the override here on the in the declaration.
And what we're doing here is we're just simply returning our parent which is the account that we're
asking you to withdraw that amount.
That's it.
And then the last one we've got is the trust accountants on the go to it's header file.
And see what we've got here.
We already have deposit and withdraw.
That's good.
We've already implemented them.
So let's just be sure that we implemented them correctly and we didn't just that we are overriding them
and not redefining them.
So we'll put over right over here as well as on the withdraw.
OK.
That's it.
Let's take a look at the C.P file.
All that looks good.
And the last thing we need here is our destructor.
So we'll create a virtual destructor for our trust account and let the compiler give us one.
All right.
So that's the first step.
So now let's go to our main and you'll notice I commented out all the driver code that I provided for
you.
I just want to start really fresh here and the first thing I want to do is let's just do this right
here.
Just create an account and call it Joe real simple let's build and run and we have an error.
I forgot a semi-colon there.
Try that again.
And I spelled virtual wrong
hands get all those errors out of the way there is a count.
Joe finally So now we have a clean compile and it says variable Joe is abstract abstract.
I can't do this so this is good right.
This is a real good thing.
We now know that our account class is abstract.
We can't create any.
So let's come at that out and let's create a checking account.
Remember this is not using a base class pointer.
This is just a regular old local variable.
And we're going to create a checking account that let's just use the default.
So now let's test this out we've created this object which is just a checking account and let's just
play that and see what we get.
Now this should still work because we overloaded those insertion operators when we did this previously.
And as long as we're not coming at this with a base class pointer they should all still work.
So let's try that out and see what we get.
There we go we've got a checking account unnamed checking account with a zero balance.
That's exactly what we expected.
So let's create a savings account object we'll call it s and we'll initialize it to Frank with $5000
balance and 2.6 percent interest and let's display that and see what it looks like.
All right let's try that out.
Here we go we've got a savings account object Frank five thousand 2.6 perfect.
So this all seems to be working perfectly.
So now why don't we create a base class pointer.
So the base class is the account class rank.
So we'll create a pointer called TTR and let's create a new trust account.
So we'll create a new trust account on the heap and that will be let's say Leo with $10000 balance and
2.6 percent interest.
So that should create that object on the heap and the pointer will point to it.
This was perfectly valid since a trust account is an account.
Now let's display that and see what we get.
We can't just play peachy here because that would display the address of that pointer.
We need to display the object so we need to dereference PTO or we need to go to where Peter is pointing
and an end line here.
Now this won't work as we expect.
The reason is we haven't really handled the insertion operator to work with dynamic polymorphism.
So as far as the compiler is concerned that insertion operator compiler knows that PCR is a pointer
to an account.
It really doesn't care what type of account it's pointing to.
So it's going to bind this statically and it'll slice that object that will slice the trust account
stuff away and just keep the account part.
So this should still display Leo in ten thousand though because all accounts have the name of their
balance so let's give that a try and see what our output is.
And that's exactly what happens.
You see right here Count Leo ten thousand.
We're not getting the trust part of us right.
Sending on display displayed trust account and just displaying account.
We'll fix that when we implement them.
I printable interface that will be pretty cool so we can see that this seems to be working.
Let's test this out and just test it out with s right here.
Let me comment out this Leo part here and let's just say that we want to deposit let's say
$10000 into S and then I want to display X again.
So let's try that out and you can see here I have my savings account frank with 5000 and I just deposited
10000 into it.
It's a savings account so it's going to use that interest rate to give me a little bonus and that's
exactly what happened.
So that looks correct.
And then finally let's withdraw.
So now let's say we want to withdraw $10000 from us
and again will display us and we'll test out our withdraw functionality here we'll give it a run and
we can see that we have savings account 5000 that we deposited 10000 and then we withdrew 10000 So it's
all looking good.
So you see it wasn't too much work to get this to work with dynamic polymorphism.
The next step now is let's get rid of all the overloaded insertion operators it's an that's in this
code and let's create that printable interface and get that working.
And then the last thing we'll do is we'll take care of those functions in the account Udal file and
clean that up because there's a lot of duplicated code in there.