OK so welcome back.
This is part two of the solution to the Section 16 challenge on polymorphism.
If you recall the last part what we did was we took the account class and we made it an abstract base
class by adding those to pure virtual functions for deposit and withdraw.
Then we went through all the classes gave them all virtual destructors made sure our deposits and our
withdraw methods were running correctly and so forth.
So everything was working great.
And right now the source code that you see in challenge solution Dasch Part 2 project which is the active
project right now is exactly where we left off.
In part 1 and this is the only test case I'm really interested in right now.
I've got a base class pointer I'm creating a new trust account and I'm displaying that object on an
output stream.
And when I run this I don't really get what I want.
I get the account part of the object remember what we talked about last time.
So what that means is that this is being statically bound not dynamically bound and the object is being
sliced.
So the trust account part of it is being discarded and we're displaying account instead of trust account
the account name Liow the account name balance which is part of that account part of me but the interest
rate is not displaying and the same will be true for savings and checking accounts.
So what's the fix.
Well there's a lot of ways to fix this but the way we're going to fix it is we're going to create an
interface class called printable and we're going to let a count be derived from my principal and then
all of the concrete classes will implement how they want to be displayed.
OK so let's get started with that.
So the first thing we want to do is we want to create the printable class so you can right click here
on source and select new class and give it to me and principal and you could just call it printable
if you like.
I'll name it I printable and the blackguard I'll use this just underscore printable underscore h underscore
just said we've done before.
You can choose to leave this blank in code like will generate one for you.
That's it.
Select.
OK so there's my principal class.
You can see right now it's a real simple class.
And what we want to do is implement this so let's look at the header file first.
We need to include IO stream since we're going to use an O stream.
So we'll do that right away.
And there's my class I printable.
We don't need a constructor and we want our destructor to be virtual because we're going to have a pure
virtual function in here.
So we want this to be virtual and we want the compiler to just generate one for us.
We don't need anything special we won't have raw pointers.
We're not.
You don't have any resources that we have to clean up.
OK so there's my virtual destructor.
Now I want to have another function.
This is going to be a pure virtual function and it's going to be called print.
We call this anything you like and it expects a stood string and it's going to be by reference and I'll
call it.
Unless it's a constant virtual functions we don't want it to modify anything and it's pure.
So I'm going to add the equal zero at the end.
OK so now we also need to create a friend function here.
And the reason we're creating the friend function is for the syntax right.
Remember when we're using the insertion operator we want to stream on the left side of the object that
we want to display on the right side.
I can't do that with a member function so I'm going to use a friend function so we create will say friend
and it's going to return a stood O stream by reference.
What are we overloading we're overloading the insertion operator.
And what are the parameters.
The first one is a pseudo stream by reference.
Again I'll call that OS and the second parameter is that Konst I printable.
It's really important that this is an IDE printable not an account not anything else.
Since an account will be derived from an i printable everything in that hierarchy will also be an eye
principle and conform to this interface.
And we can call this object or right hand side or whatever you like.
I'll just call it object that's it.
That's our class.
Now what we need to do is we need to implement this function right here and we'll do that in principle.
Implementation Far-Right here will get rid of all of this and I'll include IO stream appear.
Perfect So let's implement this function right here.
So what is this function all about.
This is the function that really runs everything.
We're going to get an eye printable object here by reference so we know that that object has already
overridden print.
It must have right.
Otherwise it wouldn't have compiled.
So what we can do here is we can simply call RBJ don't print and that reference to the output stream.
That's pretty cool.
And you notice that that matches this guy right here right.
There's print and there's the stream.
Now remember all the classes in our account class hierarchy are going to override this virtual function.
So there'll be principal It's really as simple as that.
So that's it.
We're going to put that we're going to call the objects print and then we're just going to return us
and we are done.
It's a real real simple interface.
Perfect.
Now let's go to our account and what are we going to do here.
Well you know what we're going to leave taking this guy out for last because we really do need to take
him out.
But for now let's just leave him in.
But what we need to do first is we need to be principal right.
So let's come over here and we will include I printable.
So now we've got the header file and we want our accounts to be derived publicly from.
Principal.
So what does that tell you now.
An account is an eye principle right.
And I printable has this pure virtual function.
So that account needs to override that function and then it becomes printable.
All right.
So let's come over here.
And what's the function.
The function is virtual
void print.
It expects a stood O stream ref.
It's Konst and I'm overwriting it.
So you're telling the compiler exactly what's going on here.
This guy is a pure virtual function in the printable interface class.
You're telling the compiler that you plan to override it.
Please check his signature.
Make sure I get it right.
So I'm going to copy this because we need to do that in all our classes in the class hierarchy.
So this is a account that h I'm going to go to checking account dot H and I'm going to put it right
in here.
I'm going to go to a savings account dot H put it right in here.
And finally I'm going to go to a trust account that age and put it right in there.
Perfect.
So now what do we need to do.
We actually need to override that function do what we said we were going to do.
So where do we do that what we do that in this file.
So here's my account header file.
This is the function that we want to override.
And what we want to do is we want to say okay if I'm going to count this is I'm going to print myself
if I'm a checking account this is how I want to print myself.
So it's very similar to what we did earlier with those friend with different function right here and
we could just about get rid of that we can actually get rid of it now.
But I like getting rid of it at the very end so we'll do that.
So here's my account C.P and let me copy this since that's the one that we need to override in here.
So I'm going to come right over here.
And you noticed this line right here.
We're going to reuse that line because that's how we want to print an account.
Let's override this function.
This is the print function for the account class and we can get rid of the override.
We don't need that here.
So what do we do here.
Well let's just set the precision for the output stream since we're printing numbers.
We'll just print them to two decimal places.
And what we'll do is we'll also display fixpoint.
That way looks nicer as well.
Now what do we want to do here.
Well we want to do what we said we were going to do.
Right.
We wanted to display the accounted for sure this is how we do it.
So we just need to copy that right in here.
Now there's only one little thing.
This is now a member right.
So we don't need to do account dot.
We could just get rid of all that that we did that we had to do that before because it was a friend
but now we could just access those members directly since we're members and now we can get rid of this
guy.
I don't need him anymore.
We can go back to our header file and get rid of the friend.
That's it.
So now this account class is using that overridden functionality to print itself.
So let's do that for the other ones who will get a checking account.
There it is.
It's good to go here.
We'll go to the implementation and what we'll do is we'll implement this function again.
Again we don't have to say virtual here.
We could simply say this is the checking account
Prit method we can get rid of the override
and then we can write the same code that we wrote before.
And finally we just display how we want to display it pretty easy.
And now we can get rid of this guy and we come to the header file and get rid of our friend as you can
see the steps involved.
I'll go ahead and do the last two.
OK so I've gone ahead and implemented that print function in all of these classes so here's the print
for a count.
You can see it's just printing the name and the balance.
Here's the print for a checking account.
You can see it's printing out checking account name and balance.
Here's the print for the savings account which is printing savings account the name the balance and
the interest rate.
And finally for the trust account is printing out the name the balance the interest rate and the number
of withdrawals on that account.
That's it.
Before we had that trust account Leo and it only printed account Liow ten thousand.
Now we've got dynamic binding so we should get what we want.
So let's give this a run.
And that's exactly what happened.
That's pretty cool.
Now we've got trust to count Leo 10000 two percent 2.6 percent interest rate and zero withdrawals.
All right.
So we're almost done.
The last step is to deal with those functions and account Udal and clean that up and we had a lot of
duplicated code in there once we've got that challenge is done.