We've already seen during this course that raw pointers are extremely powerful and C++.
They allow us to have absolute flexibility with memory management with this flexibility however comes
complexity.
We must explicitly allocate and deallocate storage for HEAP dynamic variables as well as manage their
lifetimes.
And that's where we often see problems.
In fact most defects in programs written in programming languages that provide raw pointers are pointers
related defects we've already discussed some of these errors in this course.
Errors such as uninitialized or wild pointers that could be pointing anywhere in memory.
And if you store data to where they're pointing you could have a potentially catastrophic result.
Another error is when we don't deallocate the storage that we previously allocated on the heap.
In this case will leak memory.
We've also seen dangling pointers that's where one pointer is pointing to storage that it thinks is
valid but in fact has already been deallocated using this invalid memory can lead to all sorts of problems
that are sometimes very very difficult to find and fix.
And finally even if we do everything correctly our program could throw an exception and the code that
releases are allocated memory never execute and we leak memory anyway.
We'll talk about exceptions and exception handling in an upcoming section of the course.
That's where smart pointers come in.
Smart pointers can help us prevent these types of errors.
They can help us be more clear about who owns the pointer and when a pointer should be deleted to free
up allocated memory and the good news is that they're pretty intuitive and easy to use in the next video.
We'll see what a smart pointer is and the types of smart pointers provided by C++.