This video we'll see a use case that's commonly seen in C++ and we'll see how we can use exception handling
with it.
Suppose we have a function.
Of course this will also work with methods and that function is called calculate average it expects
a sum of integers that we can assume has already been calculated somewhere else and the total number
of elements used to get that sum.
And what we want to do is determine the average and return it as a double from this function.
Pretty straightforward stuff.
Also notice that we don't want integer division since we want to return a double.
So we're using a static cast to convert one of the division operands to a double call.
So so far pretty easy right.
Well almost what if total is zero.
What do we do.
What do we return.
We could return 0 but 0 might be a valid average.
We could return negative 1 but negative one might be a valid average.
We could return some other double that represents an error but which one.
Since just about any double could be a valid average we could rewrite this function to return a boolean
and that boolean would indicate success right.
True if it worked false if it didn't.
But then how do we return the average we'd have to use a reference parameter and do it that way or use
a tuple makes the function really clunky to use.
So let's see how we can write this function using exceptions and exception handling.
We can rewrite the function without changing its interface and still provide a guarantee that the function
will not divide by zero by throwing an exception.
First we check if total is equal to zero if it is we don't want to do that division.
Instead we throw zero.
In this case we could throw anything in C++ allows us to throw just about any type but let's use zero
again which is an integer and we've done it previously.
If we throw the exception the division will not happen and the function will terminate.
Now C++ will try to find an exception handler to catch that integer that the function threw.
How does it do that.
Well the handler isn't in this function so where else might it be.
It may not exist at all in which case the program would terminate.
But if an exception handler exists it must be in one of the functions on the call stack that called
this function right.
And C++ will unwind the stack looking for it.
We'll see how this works in a few videos.
So let's see how this function might be called in a way that would allow us to deal with the exception.
Now this code could exist in any function anywhere in your program.
Notice that we have a try block and in the try block we call the calculate average function.
We know this function might throw an exception and if it does we'll deal with it in the catch block.
But first let's see what happens if no exception is thrown.
Again we're assuming that some in total have been declared and initialized.
In this case average is assigned the return value from the function and we display it.
Then we skip the catch block completely since no exceptions were thrown and we execute the last statement
that displays by if calculate average does throw an exception then the remaining code in the try block
is not executed.
So we do not do the division by zero and C++ searches for a catch block that expects an integer since
that's the type of the exception that was thrown in this case it finds it noticed that our catch handler
expects a reference to an integer.
Again best practice is to throw by value and catch by reference.
We'll talk more about that later.
So in this case the code in the body of the catch handler executes displays an error message to the
airstream when the catch block completes we transfer to the last statement and we display by that's
it it's possible to have multiple catch handlers as well as catch all handlers that will catch any type
of exception.
We'll do that in the next video.
But first let's head over to the idea and we'll rewrite the MPG example as a function and use exception
handling with it.
OK so I'm backing the idea again I'm in the section 18 workspace and I'm in the MPG function project
what I've done here is I've taken the calculation for miles per gallon and I've made it a function.
So in this case it expects miles and gallons which are both integers and returns the double which is
the miles per gallon.
And I'm simply abody miles by gallons.
And again I'm casting miles to a double so that we do double division and get an accurate result.
That's it.
My main is just like it was before the user enters the miles the gallons and the only difference now
is that on line 19 right here you can see that I'm calling calculate miles per gallon and I'm passing
in the user entered valleys.
So let's run this as is without any exception handling without any error checking at all.
So we'll run this and let's say I entered 120 miles and I entered 0 there is my result which is infinity
that's not what I want and we'll deal with that in just a sec.
So we know that we don't want to divide by zero.
So what we can do appear in the function is we can say if gallons is 0 we want to throw an exception
and we'll just throw again we'll throw 0 which is a simple integer.
Now let's run this.
You'll see something that's a little bit different now.
When I call calculate miles per gallon here and I use a zero for the gallons it's going to throw this
exception that exceptions not being caught anywhere.
So it's going to go all the way up to the top.
My main that's where I'm at now and our programs going to terminate.
It's going to terminate abnormally.
So let's run this so you can see what that looks like.
So again I'm going to enter 120 and enter 0 for the gallons and you can see right there it says.
I'll cancel that.
You can see it's terminate called after throwing an instance of it.
This application has requested the runtime to terminate it in an unusual way a bad termination right.
Basically an exception was thrown that was not handled that will always terminate your program.
So how do we handle that exception.
Remember the mile to calculate mpg function appear has no clue what to do when it gallons is zero.
All it knows is I can't do a divide by zero and should I just print an error message.
I don't know what to do.
So someone else do it.
I'm just throwing the exception.
So what we can do down here is we can write a try block around this code that could potentially throw
an exception.
So let's do that.
I'll say try and I'll close off the tribe walk here and we'll indent this area right here.
So I'm going to try to execute that function.
If the function works properly then I just print out miles per gallon if that function throws an exception
then we're not going to divide right because it's thrown out before the division.
It's not going to assign miles per gallon basically the tribe will stop and it's going to look for a
catch handler.
Right.
So let's write the catch handler our catch handler looks kind of like this.
What am I going to catch.
Well I'm going to catch an integer by reference and right here I'm simply going to print stood Sierre
tried to divide by zero or something like that.
OK.
That's it.
So you can see now that the errors detected in one place and it's all in one file here just for instruction
purposes.
But this could be anywhere in your program right.
The error has been detected here and it's been handled here.
So let's run this now.
And we'll do it again 120 and 0 tried to divide by zero by our program terminated.
Normally we handle the exception in a controlled manner.
And that's really what it's all about.
Now in this case there could be some issues that we need to catch some other exceptions and that's what
we'll do in the next video.
What if Miles is negative but that doesn't make sense.
I traveled negative 100 miles per gallon.
So we want to also throw an error if Miles is negative or if gallons is negative for that matter right
how can you have negative gallons.
So in this case we're just doing a simple test so we don't divide by zero but in the other cases which
will do in the next video we're going to check to make sure that we've got valid values here.
So if Miles is negative or gallons is negative then my calculation cannot be correct.
So we'll throw another exception there and we'll catch multiple exceptions.
So we'll do that in the next few.