In this video we'll see some of the stream formatting options available for floating point numbers formatting
floating point numbers focuses mainly on the amount of precision used to display the number by default.
The precision is set to six digits will cover the specifics of what that exactly means in this lecture.
We can also set the number of digits to display to the right side of the decimal point by default.
There is no fixed set size.
We can also choose to show trailing zeros up to a certain number and we can also decide if the floating
point number four should be displayed as four or four point zero or 4.00 and so forth.
But by default these trailing zeros are not displayed and then we have some of the same options that
we had when we used integers by default a lowercase e is use when we're displaying floating point numbers
using scientific notation and the plus sign is not displayed when we display positive floating point
numbers.
All of these manipulators persist once they're set.
So first let's take a look at how precision works.
By default the precision used to display floating point numbers is six digits and rounding always occurs.
In this example we have the number one two three four point five six seven eight.
If we display this number it's C plus plus we use 6 as the default precision and started the most significant
digit which is the one and it will display six digits starting from there.
Rounding at the end.
In this case one two three four point five seven will be displayed.
If C++ can't display the number in the given amount of significance the interval use scientific notation
and we'll see that in a bit.
Here's another example.
We have a large number.
One two three four five six seven eight nine point nine eight seven six five four three two one.
I did it that way just so it's really easy to keep track of these digits.
If we display this number C++ we'll try to do it with six significant digits but this won't work since
it will display one two three four five six.
And the number displayed wouldn't be accurate.
So in this case the number we displayed using scientific notation and notice one point two three four
five seven has got the six digits of precision.
That's the default and notice that we're still using precision 6 but this time using scientific notation.
Suppose we wanted to display the number using precision nine.
We can use the set precision manipulator with the 9 as the argument to do just that.
In this case the number will display as 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 9 D.
Note the rounding at the end.
Also notice how no trailing zeros are displayed in this example.
So that's the way precision works when we're not fixing the number of digits to the right of the decimal.
When we use the fixed manipulator precision is handled differently.
Now we're looking at precision starting from the right side of the decimal point.
In this case we still have a default precision of six but we're also using the fixed manipulator.
This will use a precision of six starting with the digits after the decimal and all round is necessary.
So in this case exactly six digits are displayed after the decimal point and zeros are added if necessary.
As you can guess set precision two and fixed are commonly used to display currency amounts.
We actually did this in a few of the course lessons in this example.
We're still using that very large number but we're setting the precision to three.
And also using the fixed manipulator.
So now this will display exactly three digits after the decimal point and rounding will occur.
So we've got a point nine eight eight after the decimal point.
In this example we want to set precision to 3 and also use scientific notation.
You can see the manipulators being use in the displays exactly as we expect.
One point two three times ten to the eighth notice the precision is three.
We see that with the 1.2 three we can display the E in the scientific notation format as a capital G
by using the uppercase manipulator.
Remember by default it's no upper case.
Now let's see how the show positive manipulator works with floating point numbers.
The behavior is the same as we saw with integers.
If we use to show puzzlement if the later then we'll get a preceding plus sign on positive floating
point numbers.
Note that we can toggle back to not showing the plus sign with the no show pause manipulator with floating
We can also use the sharp point manipulator.
This will display trailing zeros based on the level of precision used.
For example if our number is twelve point thirty four and we display it using only the defaults then
twelve point thirty four with display.
We're using a precision of six but only four digits for display in this case.
If we wanted to add trailing zeros up to precision we can use the show Point manipulator.
Now you can see that two zeros are added to the number being displayed.
Again you can use the no show point to toggle back to the default behavior.
Finally if you want to reset the floating point format back to the general format you can do that in
one of two ways.
You can use the unset F. method or you can use the reset Iowas flag manipulator.
There are a bunch of other flags.
But at this point you know what you would need.
So rather than list them all here I'll refer you to the C++ reference docs.
Now let's head over to the IDC and we'll format some floating point values.
Then in the next video we'll finish off formatting was setting field with justification and filling.
OK so I'm backing the idea again and am and still in the section 19 workspace and I mean the manip underscore
floating project and what we'll do here is we'll play around with some floating point numbers.
Now let's take a look at the numbers that we'll be using for this example.
We've got three numbers right here they're all doubles and you can see I've got one that's going from
one up to nine and then from nine down to one after the decimal point that I just make it really easy
for us to see which digits are being rounded.
I've got another one that's a little smaller one two three four five six seven eight and I've got this
last one right here one two three four point zero.
OK.
And what we'll do first is we'll just do normal displaying these guys out to the console with absolutely
nothing fancy no manipulation of all just using pure defaults.
And that's what's going on right here on lines 14 to 16 I'm displaying them one them to name three.
Now remember by default we've got six digits of precision.
We're not showing the positive sign.
We're not showing trailing zeros and we're not showing uppercase letters in scientific notation.
OK that's the default.
So let's run this first.
Now what do we expect here we expect number 1 to not be able to work right I mean if you think about
this for a second here you can see that no one has.
Let's assume we wanted to display six different figures right here.
We would just play one two three four five six.
And that would really give us problems right.
Because that's not even close to being an accurate number.
So C++ won't do that.
What you will do is it'll display that number in scientific notation and it will still use 6 for precision.
I'll show you how that works in a second.
Now this guy can be right we've got there's four digits right here and then two.
So we expect those six digits to display in those last two would be rounded.
And this guy here remember by default we don't display trailing zeros.
I just get to display one two three four.
So let's run this and we'll verify that we got what we expected.
OK.
Let me move this window over here so we can see what's going on and we do that again.
There we go.
So in this case we're displaying them one right.
And notice what happens one point two three four five seven you can see the rounding you can see all
six digits being displayed here.
But we're using scientific notation because there's no way that it can be properly displayed or accurately
displayed I should say in six digits.
This next one though number two right.
Twelve thirty four point fifty seven that's exactly what we expect.
There you see the six digits and then some three.
One two three four it's ASPI there's no zero or zero zero unless we use a modifier which we use in a
little bit.
So that's the default and it's really important that you understand the default and how it begins.
So that's using the default settings.
Now let's try something let's we're going to set the precision to two.
So what we're asking for is two significant digits.
It can't do that with any of these.
Right.
One point to 12 you know where is it going to stop.
So what it'll do is it'll display all three of them in scientific notation using a precision of two.
So I'll show you how that looks.
And you can see exactly what's going on 1.2 for all of them those are the two significant digits of
precision right times 10 to the eighth.
The third and so forth.
So let's set a precision of five and we'll be able to do some of them with a precision of five others
that was so uncomment this block out
and let's execute that.
And now you can see what's going on.
Number one cannot be displayed in five significant digits here.
So the precision is going to be five digits here but it's going to be a scientific notation.
The other number appears scroll up so you can see it went to three four point five six seven.
There are five significant figures here right.
Your precision is five.
So what it's doing is it's rounding that fifth one from which is point fifty six to six.
And then again the last one is one two three four.
We're not adding any zeros or anything.
So that's the default kind of behavior.
So that really gives you an idea of what's going on in this case.
We're going to set precision to 9.
Everything will fit here.
So that's try that.
And you can see what's happening with precision 9.
I get one two three four five six seven instead of eighty nine I'm getting 90.
It's rounding that this guy is displaying all of it because it can display all of it right.
Twelve thirty four point five six seven eight.
And the one two three four still displays the same way because we're not adding any zeroes.
OK so now now you understand precision.
Now let's talk about fixed and how it changes precision.
So what we're doing here is we're setting precision to three.
You can see that happening right here on line 40 and we're fixing the decimal point.
So now the precision happens after the decimal point.
OK.
So let's run this and take a look at the output.
OK so take a look at the output here.
Again I'll scroll up so we can see these numbers up top.
So now we're just playing one two three four five six seven eight nine.
That would explain all of that.
And the precision now applies after the decimal.
So I noticed that all three of these guys are displaying three digits after the decimal because that's
the precision and we're fixing that size.
So it's going around in this case 9 8 7 6 Get it becomes 9 8 8 and 5 6 7 8 becomes 5 6 8.
And in this case here you can see that it's displaying all the zeros on the end.
OK.
Because we set the fixed formatter.
All right.
So hopefully that makes sense.
Let me stop that and we'll run a couple more.
Let's take a look at this example.
What we're doing here is we're setting the precision to three and we want to do a scientific notation.
So this should be very similar to what happened before with the precision to win stuff wouldn't fit.
So again precision is three and scientific notation.
So what we get is right down here 1 point two three five.
Notice the precision is three right.
But what happened because it's fixed.
I set fixed up here and fixed is persistence so it carries down even though I didn't say fixed right
here it's fixed because I've set it up here.
So this case I get the three decimals after the decimal point the three digits I should say after the
decimal point and it's all in scientific notation and then couple of more examples.
You notice that that E and the exponential notation in scientific notation was lower case.
I can make it a capital E by simply using stood up or case here and this is run that to be sure that
we get it.
And there you go right down here at the bottom you can see one point two three and you can see the e
is capitalized here right it was lowercase here in the previous example.
In this case I'm using the show positive and what I'm doing is I'm just setting with precision three
fixed and show positive.
So this will show a positive plus sign in front of positive numbers.
Let's run that.
And then you can see down here at the bottom again.
Move this up just a little so you can see it a little better.
You can see the plus symbol being displayed in front of all these positive floating point numbers.
If they were negative obviously the negative sign would show.
Now we can set these guys back to the defaults either by doing an unset f calling that method and we
can pass in scientific and fixed setting them back to the defaults.
And what we're doing here is just a binary or or we could use to reset U.S. flags manipulator here and
pass in Show position that will unset that.
All right.
So let me end this up here.
Now notice what I'm doing here I'm setting precision to 10 and I'm telling it to show point.
OK what this is going to do is going to add these trailing zeros up to 10 spaces.
All right we're up to 10 precision.
So let's run that and we can see number one number two and I'm three.
There you go.
You can see right here 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0.
It's round here.
And then one two three four point five six seven eight we've got a couple of zeros on the end.
But you notice all of them now are in precision 10 right.
And in this case we have one two three four point and then six zeroes at the end.
We'll set these guys back to the defaults and I'll show you how to do that right here.
And then we'll run one more time when we should get that same behavior we got to the very beginning.
So what I'm doing here is I'm setting this back to the general notation here.
I'm setting the precision to six which was the default and I'm setting show position show positive and
show point back to their defaults and then I'm just displaying them one them to number three at the
end.
And what we should get back is what we got at the beginning.
So down at the bottom here you go.
We get the scientific notation for this guy.
We've got the six precision digits here.
And we've got the 1 2 3 4 right here.
OK.
So that's it.
That's a good example of these floating point formatters.
They're pretty powerful they're pretty easy to use in the next really what we'll do is we'll learn about
setting field widths and justifying things left or right and you can use those along with these to really
format tables and get your format looking really nicely for up.