Welcome to the first challenge for Section 19 this challenge is all about using what you learned about
formatting output to format a table of tours to different cities in South America including prices and
so forth.
And we'll get to that in a second.
But I'm in the section 19 workspace and there are two projects challenge underscore one is the source
code that I'm providing for you and challenge underscore one underscore solution is my solution to the
challenge.
So let's take a look at what the challenge is all about then I'll give you a sample run and then you
can try it out on your own.
So as I said it's about formatting output and we're going to do everything to see out.
We're going to display everything to the console.
Later on we can change that and display the files and that's what we're going to our next in this section.
So let's start I'm giving you the starter source code for the challenge and I'll go through that in
just a second.
But the challenge for you to display the provided data in a nicely formatted table your table doesn't
have to match mine you can do however you like.
The point is for you to become comfortable with these manipulators play around with them.
Don't just try to mimic my table exactly.
You know big pre-created do your do your own thing.
So I'm going to give you three structures.
We haven't really done these sorts of structures before but they're really really straightforward.
They're not classes.
We're going to use structures because we don't really need to model operations.
We just want to model data and member modeling data.
It's really common to just use structures.
Again I'll show you what they look like in just a second.
So the first thing is these structures work together to create a tures structure.
And that's going to contain about information about tours to South America and the tours include the
countries that you can visit the cities within those countries and those cities have population and
cost data associated with the tour.
I know population I was thinking the same thing I just wondered a really big numbers that you could
format it watched the challenge video which you're obviously watching right now.
But if you're looking at the code I'm hoping that you come back to this video and watch it so that you
can see what the expected output looks like.
I tried to copy the output to this document here but everybody's got different fonts and some of the
fonts aren't monospaced in the document would look really weird.
So I'd I'll just run it for you so you can see exactly what it's supposed to look like in the code.
I'm going to give you some starter code that displays all the data from these structures and vectors
using tabs to kind of align things and it looks pretty ugly.
But your job is to clean it up make it look pretty.
OK.
So as I always say have fun create functions Constans do whatever you think makes sense explore play
around do it and then do it again a different way that's how you really really learn.
OK so let's go to the source code so I'll get him in the challenge.
Underscore one project and I'm looking at the main code right here.
And let's go over these data structures.
First of all what we've got is we're including our normal group here.
We've got IO dream we've got iOS manip since we're going to use the manipulators.
We've got a vector and we've got a string and we've got these three structures right here.
Here's the first one it's city country and tours.
And let me start with City.
Think of a struct.
We talked about a struct A little bit earlier in the Object-Oriented classes and phunk method section.
It's like a class except Everything's public.
You can have instructors you can have all kinds of stuff.
But typically we use trucks like this to just model data.
Sometimes you just want pure data and you want to deal with constructors and methods and you really
don't need any of that.
So this is just a good way to collect data together.
So what we've got here is we've got a city and each city has a name so let's say the name for one of
the cities is Bogota in Colombia a population which is a long and I don't know how many millions there
are I made some of those numbers up let's just say 18 million or something like that.
And the cost of taking a tour to Bogota from Miami.
So that's five hundred sixty nine dollars.
And again I don't know what that number is.
It's in the data you see in a minute.
So that's a city.
We're going to have many of these cities right we'll have Rio de Janeiro will have Santiago Chile we'll
have a whole bunch of places that we can visit in South America.
Each one will be modeled by a city.
Perfect.
Now let's look at the country the country has a name.
In this case it will be Colombia.
And it has stood Vektor of cities.
And so I might have three or four cities associated with Colombia I might have two or three cities associated
with Brazil and so forth.
So this is how we structure our data using these structures building one within the other.
Finally we've got our main object here which is the tours and it has a title and that title I don't
remember exactly what it is Prussia tea in a minute when I show you the data.
It's something like you know tours to South America or something and some some big title they'll little
the Tator the header on our report and the tures has a vector of countries that makes sense.
So we could have the title which is this guy
and then we could have let's say Columbia and we could have Brazil as our countries and we could have
Argentina in many countries have cities within them you can see them right here.
So you may have Bogota here and the population is 18 million and the cost is $567 or something like
that.
Then you would display the next city and the next city.
Then you'd go to Brazil and you display Rio and so forth.
So this is what our report is going to look like.
And the reason we structured this data is because it makes it so much easier to process that where we
don't have to just play around with the hundreds of arrays and strings and so forth so we're using what
we should be using.
We're using stood strings and we're using stood vector's and that's what modern C++ is all about.
It's not using character pointers and we're not using any anything else just real solid data structures.
OK so how do we initialize these guys.
Let me scroll down just a little bit and here you see some of the initialization and this is done for
you.
I've already written this for you.
You could just use it.
Notice that this piece right here and this is using our uniform initialization right.
This is the kind of stuff we've been using all along except we're doing it all in one shot here.
So here is a city.
Here's another city here's another city here's another city.
These four cities are a vector and that vector is the vector of cities in that country.
Columbia right.
And that country Columbia is one of these guys.
And is the title at the top of the tures.
So what we're doing is we're building this using uniform initialization which makes it really really
nice to visually see what's going on here.
So you could see that I've got.
Let me scroll up just a little bit here so hopefully we can see them all.
Yep I think we can see them all.
Great.
So in this case there's my title.
Here is a country another country another country another country I don't know what happened to my mouse.
All of a sudden got really big fix that real quick.
And within those countries I've got cities and cities and cities and here's a single city.
You can always assume that there must be.
You've got a country you must have a city so you can assume that you're never going to have a country
without a city that will just make your your processing a little bit easier.
That's it.
So that's our data up.
And let me show you how you would work with this data.
So let me scroll up and clear this a little bit.
Here's the code I'm giving you.
And you may not see it right off the bat but it should be pretty intuitive once you start walking into
it and thinking about it a little bit.
You can see what we're starting out here we're displaying the title.
The title is part of that tures object right towards that title.
And then for each country it's in the countries in that tour object.
So we'll loop through all the different countries like Colombia Brazil Argentina and so forth for each
one of playing the name and then I'm looking through that city's vector that's inside of it for each
city in that city's vector I'm displaying the city.
That's really and it's really really straightforward.
Again take a minute and understand the concept walk through this before you start trying to format this
data.
Make sure you understand how we're getting the data that's really important.
Once we do that we can display this information it's not going to look very pretty but as you can see
we're using tab characters to kind of align these columns.
And it's not going to do a real good job but at least you'll be able to see what's going on.
If I run this now it'll be the output that you should be getting as well.
So let me run that project right now.
That's what you should get.
Tour ticket prices from Miami you can see Colombia and the cities Brazil cities Chile and Argentina.
But you can see this is lined up nicely because we're not doing any real formatting we're just using
the tab character.
OK so let me stop that and then let me show you the solution.
Output looks something like this which is much nicer and I've been displaying this ruler appear I'm
doing this in the width of 70 total.
You don't have to do that and that's just what I chose because it's easy to see.
You can see here I'm displaying tour ticket prices from Miami centered.
There is no way to center something you remember with when we use the set width and the justification
we get on the left or right.
So centering it you're going have to do maybe a little bit of math and figure out what's the center.
Now I've got a header here I'm just playing the country the city the population the price line of dashes
and then I'm just lining up the data.
So I've got all the countries Colombia Brazil Chile Argentina.
The cities within the countries the population of the cities it's right just to fight here in this field
as well as the price which is right justified and I've got the two decimal digits displaying.
OK so that's it.
Good luck with this one.
Again this is this.
This project is this little challenge is more than just formatting.
I really want you to understand the structures and how you access those structures using the vectors
within the structures.
It's really simple once you get it and it's really powerful be able to use those structures that have
those vectors of structures within them very powerful very easy to use.
You saw how easy it was to declare the data.
OK so that's it.
Good luck with the challenge.
I'll see you on the other side in the solution.
Don't rush through this.
Take your time.
Once this challenge is over we'll start working with files.