In this video we'll go over some examples of reading text files.
So I'm in the section 19 workspace and I'm in the read file.
Underscore one project.
And right now I've got nothing in here.
The only thing I've done is I've included IO stream and I've included extreme we obviously need to include
lifestream to work with files.
That's all I've got here is my project you can see it's open and the file that I'm going to read is
not there yet.
I wanted to show you how to create it first.
And we want to do is let's write the code to open the file then it will obviously fail because the file
is not there.
And then we'll put the file in there and will read it.
OK.
So first thing we need to do is we need to create an input file stream and we'll just call it in file
just like we've done in the slides and I'll initialize it on the next line up open it on the next line.
That way you can see that kind of syntax so we'll say in file open and here we give it a file name.
Now this is the part that's pretty operating system specific.
It's specific if you're in Windows.
You might be tempted to do this kind of thing.
See colon backslash and then some directory and then some other directory may be followed by some test
text or something like that right.
That's the way that Windows filenames look.
The problem with this is you remember that it's that character literal that starts with a slash that
won't work because that right there becomes a character.
So we want to do if you do it this way you want to use two slashes don't forget.
That's really really important.
You would want to use two slashes everywhere if you're on Windows.
Now if you're on Mac or Unix or some other operating system then you really don't do that you kind of
just know slash forward slash forward slash directory names to the file.
Now the good thing about this is even if you're on Windows you can still use this slash and behind the
scenes it will be mapped to the proper ones so that's what I would recommend you do.
I would not recommend that you do anything like Seacole energy Colin does that really really ties your
code to your computer.
So for example if you trying to open a file in C colon slash Frank slash test and then someone else
tries to run this program unless they've got a frank directory.
It's not going to work that file won't be there.
So the best thing to do is just to do something like that.
That way to look in the current directory no matter what computer system you're on.
Now this is where the ID issues come in and I'll talk about that a little bit.
For now let me just leave that just like that I want to open a file called test data.
It doesn't exist yet here as you can see but worry about that a little bit.
So we're trying to open that here.
The next thing we need to do is we need to see if it was open.
So let's say if not infile.
And remember here we could say we could have said if not in file is open like that.
Either one will work.
This is the style I like and that's the one I've been using a long time.
I'll keep you in it.
So if not infile that means we could not open this.
OK so in this case we're just going to say stood.
See air.
We're going to display an error message that says
open a file it's just something real simple like that.
What do we do here.
I want to get out of here.
I've got nothing else to do.
I need this file to run my program.
So I've got a couple of options.
I can say return anything other than 0 0 means the program completed successfully I could return I want
I could return a negative one.
It really depends on what number you're looking for.
That means I couldn't find a file.
So we could I'm just going to say return one.
Sometimes you'll see code that looks like this.
It says Exit 1 or more properly stood exit.
And in this case that calls a function named X it that closes up certain things and you know destroys
static variables and things.
But right now I'm just going to simply return one.
If I were having some sort of problem opening the file.
Now if I get beyond this piece right here I've got the file.
It's good to go so I'm just going to say stood out.
File is going to go.
I'm ready to read from it.
That's it.
That's the program.
This will fail when I run it.
So let's try it.
I'm going to build and run.
And it says problem opening file.
How come.
Because the file is not there.
OK so let's create the file.
What I'll do is I'll come in here into my project and I'm going to click on the source directory.
This is what I would recommend that you do whatever files you create create them in the same directory
where your data files are.
OK so in this case I'm going to put it right where my main CGP file is.
When I right click on that source folder and I'm going to select Add new file.
You could also do it from up here add new file and then I'm going to select any file and just give it
a name and I'm going to give it this name right here test that TXI.
So I'm going to say test dot the x t.
I'm going to press enter.
And now you can see that test the ex-chief file right here.
And I can type some data into there and I will in a moment.
So now I've got the file.
So now let's run it still problem.
Opening file.
How come.
Well this is where the ideas are all different.
If I open this file up this project right here I'm on the right click on it and I'm going to say open
the containing folder just so I can open it up and explore here and look at it and move it over from
my other monitor.
You can see that here's my C++ source file right here my C.P. file right there.
And here is that test he actually followed just created right.
But the executor is not here.
The file is not here.
It's in de-bug.
It's right here.
That's my ex he filed the application.
So when it runs it's looking for that THC file in here and it's not finding it.
That's why with code like we have to do something like this dot dot slash.
So in other words I'm in Debug I need to go one level above one directory above me.
Now if I try to run this file is good to go found.
Usually this is what you want to do.
Most ideas will work this way.
Code like does not I believe code blocks and Visual Studio will all work if you just type in the file
and just like that.
And then what you do is when you create your file you create it where your CPV file is and it'll find
it depending on what you're using you're just going to have to play around with it and to get it.
It opens it means you're good to go.
OK.
Next code if you're using X code we'll talk about that in the video.
The x is x code is a little bit little bit different Sea-Lion it'll just a regular test that.
He will also work.
OK.
So that's it.
So now we've got a file we're able to open it so that's perfect.
That's the first step.
Right.
We can't open it we can't read it.
So I'm going to get rid of this file is good to go statement.
I really don't want to say that again because I've got it.
Now what I want to do is I just want to read some information from that file.
So let's put something in there.
I'm going to go into t test he t.
And it's just a text file.
Someone to say hello.
That's it.
And I just saved it just now and I want to go back to main CPV and I'll create these variables up here
just sort of they're all in one place.
So let's create a stud string and let's just call it line and it's just any variable name will do.
And down here what I want to do is remember when we had C and we would say C in into mine.
Well it's the same thing except we're not reading from CN we're reading from infile.
So what that will do is it'll read one string it is going remember of the way the extraction operator
works he'll stop at a space or at end of file at a stop as soon as it sees some white space.
Now we should have that string in line and we could just simply display it
right to the consul.
OK so let me go through this again before I run it.
I'm opening the file.
I'm testing to be sure that it's open.
If it's not open I'm displaying problem opening file and I'm out of here.
Otherwise I'm reading from the file into line.
Line is a string and then I'm displaying whatever I just read.
Remember the file contains hello So that's what I should see.
Right.
So let's give it a run there's Hello.
So that came from that textfile.
OK so now what we'll do is let's read a couple of other things in here so I'm going to have an aunt
we'll call it numb and we'll have a double and let's just call it total just like we did in the slides.
So now what we'll do is we'll modify that file here so that it's got a string in it did a double it's
already got a string.
So we'll give it an int and let's give it a double
three.
Two hundred point three forty five.
So that's my father's got a string and then did a double.
OK so now we'll come down here and what we'll do is we can read the string and we could do this in separate
lines.
We could just do it all in one I'm just going to do it all in one to save a little time.
Someone to read the string that I'm going to read the integer and then I'm going to read the total and
what I'm going to do here is I'm going to display the line I'll just display them in three lines.
Copy that one.
So here we're displaying the line here we're displaying the number.
And then finally we'll be displaying the total down here.
OK.
So all we've done now is rather than just read Hello we're reading Hello the integer and the double.
And when I run this I should get three pieces of information displaying.
There they are.
Hello.
One hundred and two hundred point three four five.
Pretty cool.
And if we modify this file to look like this
this will still work.
Right because we're using that extraction operator and it's going to stop right here when it sees a
white space in X and a stop right here when it sees a white space.
So we were pretty flexible as far as the format of this file.
So if I run this again you can see I still got those numbers right there OK so that takes care of that
example and what I'll do next is we're going to read file to and will do exactly the same thing.
It will create more data here and we'll read these insightful.
OK so I'll be right back to do that.
And actually before we go to the next example I forgot to close the file.
So I wanted to be sure that you know that we need to close this file so I'm just going to do in file
close.
OK that's very very important.
I got carried away with showing you how to read I forget the simple things to close the file.
So make sure you close the file at the end.
OK so I've switched over to Section 19 workspace read file underscore to project.
OK.
So what we want to do now is rather than just read those three data items we want to continuously read
three data items and show you what I did to the test file.
Now we've got Frank 100 and a double Larry an integer and a double M-O an integer and a double and so
forth.
So what I want to do is rather than just read the one line I want to read as many lines as there there.
So we need to do this in some sort of loop right so we're going to use a while loop.
And let me go back to my main and I'll show you what's happening here.
Everything else is exactly the same I have included IO manip here just because I want to display those
guys out at the end and a little bit of a formatted column that where you can see it a little better.
So I'm just displaying line numb and total a little bit formatted.
So here I've opened the file and I've checked that it's open.
I'm assuming it's open right here otherwise I can't get here because the return one would kick me out.
So what do I want to do.
Well I want to have some sort of while loop here.
I want to loop while not infile dot and of file e o f and that's a function that will return true if
it's end of file or no not true if it's not the end of file.
And what I want to do in there is basically display this.
But first I want to read the input.
Right.
So again I'm reading from infile And first I'm reading the line actually should be name right but would
just keep the name line the nom which is the INT and the total and that should do it.
So again while we're not at the end of the file we're reading three items displaying them looping back
up reading another three items displaying them and so forth.
They were done this time I remember to close the file.
OK so let's run this.
And when it runs.
That's the information you get you get Frank Larry Moe Curly and you get the integers and the doubles
here nicely formatted because I'm using the set w manipulator so we can do that with end of file but
we can also do that by putting that extra this statement right here read inside the while.
So what we can do is we can refactor this a little bit and what we'll do is we'll put this statement
right in there and just move it up here just like that.
All right.
So now this is a little different and we have to wrap your head around this a little bit.
So there's my infile and I'm reading those three items.
If I hit and defile if anything fails if I've got illegal data anything this will fail in the while
loop will fail and I'm out of here if I'm able to read all those three items.
Remember this is using formatted input because I'm using those extraction operators.
So that's it you will read them and then I'll display them.
So if I run this I should get exactly the same output as before.
And there it is ok cool.
So now in the next video this will get a little bit long so I cut it off here and the next video what
would you lose we'll read one of Shakespeare's poems.
Line by line display it out to the consul.