In this video we'll talk about string stream's strings dreams allow us to use in-memory String objects
as streams.
That means that we can read and write data strings in the same way that we can read write data to any
stream.
This is a very powerful concept and it's very useful for data validation.
It's also very easy to use since we already know how to use streams.
There are three classes that we can use when using string streams the string stream class allows us
to read and write from string streams the string stream class allows us to read from string streams
and the O stream string class allows us to write to string streams for all of these we must include
the stream header file.
The rest is very much like using any other stream.
First we declare a string stream object of one of the three types that I mentioned.
Then we connected to a string.
That's it.
Now we can read or write to that string stream using formatted IO and stream manipulators if we wish.
Let's see an example of how we could read from a string stream.
Suppose we have three variables declared an integer named Naam a double named total and a string called
name.
Now suppose that we have a string info with the string Moe one hundred one two three four point five
is its contents.
Remember we did this example in this section and that same data was in a file.
Well now it's in memory in a string.
We can create an ice stream stream object we'll call it ISIS and connect it to the info string.
So now we can read from the string stream now we can use the stream extraction operator to extract those
data from the string.
That's pretty cool.
I'm sure you could see lots of applications for this especially in Data Validation So now let's see
how we can write data to a stream stream.
In this case we've initialized our variables name total and name to 100.
One two three four point five and Mo respectively.
We can create an o string stream object named o ss and we can write to the stream object.
In this case I'm inserting the three values onto the string stream.
Remember we can use any stream manipulators to format that data that we're putting on the stream.
So now how do we display the string that we just formatted.
Notice I didn't notice that in this case we didn't connect the stream stream to any string object we
could have just like we did with the string stream example in the previous slide the string stream has
a string buffer that it uses internally and we can use that.
So if we want to display that string Oh we have to do is call the string streams dot as our method.
In this last example we'll do some basic data validation.
The idea is that I want to ask the user to enter an integer.
The idea is that I want to ask the user to enter an integer and I want to be sure that they do enter
an integer not some invalid data like a name.
So we have a string named input and we read the user's input into that string.
We don't read it into an integer.
Again we read it into a string.
Then what we want to do is to try to convert that string to an integer if possible.
There are many ways to accomplish this in C++.
Some are better than others.
Let's do it with a string stream it's pretty easy.
What we can do is we can create a string stream object we'll call it s s and we can connect it to the
input string that the user just entered.
Then we can try to extract an integer from SS and store it in value.
We can do that using the stream extraction operator if the extraction was successful.
That means that we have a valid integer stored in value.
If the extraction was not successful we know that the user didn't enter an integer and we can ask them
to enter the number again or we can do whatever else makes sense in our program.
So now let's head over to the IDC and we'll see these examples and we'll do a more complete data validation
example as well.
Ok so many the IDM in the section 19 workspace in the string Stream project what we'll do here is we'll
do a few examples using strings James will read from them or right from them and then I'll show you
a little bit better data validation example then the one in the slide a little more complete.
So what we're doing here is we've got some includes And we were including limits and I'll show you what
that's about later.
But right now we have IO stream I manip are extreme for our string streams and the string class.
OK.
So here's what we've got.
We've got these three variables just like we saw on the slides numbers and in totals a double and name
as a string and we've created this string right here called info that just has those three pieces of
data in there.
It's all a string right now but what we want to do is we want to be able to read that or extract that
information from the string as a string an integer and a double and store them into these variables
right up here.
It's really easy to do.
All we have to do is create an AI string Stream we'll call it ISIS and we're going to hook it up to
that string info.
This guy right here.
And what we can do is we can extract information from ISIS which is a stream the same way that we extracted
information from C in the same way we extract information from a file.
Same idea member we're using the stream abstraction.
And we really don't care what the stream is connected to.
In this case it's connected to an in-memory string and that's what we're doing here.
We're reading name numb and total.
The compiler knows the types for these guys because they're defined right up here.
So it's going to try to read a string from the string ISIS which is connected to this guy right here
and he's going to grab Moe and stored a name and it's going to get 100 stored and numb and it's going
to get 123 4.5 and stored in total will display this information out to the console right here and see
out and we'll get a nice formatted output so let's see what it looks like.
And there you go mo one hundred and one twenty three point forty five.
That's the data that was in this string.
So you can see how easily we really what we were doing is actually parsing that string and parsing information
out of there type it which is kind of cool.
And it was so easy to do we really had to do very little.
We had to do this one line 17 right here.
Once we hooked up the strength stream.
OK.
So that's an example of input.
An example of output I'll comment.
This piece of code out or comment and I should say.
Notice what we're doing here.
We're going to use an output string stream here and we'll call it.
Oh yes.
And we're not going to hook it up to anything behind the scenes the stream stream class has its own
string buffer and that's what we're going to use.
So in this case what we're doing is we're instantiating o ss right here and then we're just going to
write to the stream and the stream is going to store that information in that string buffer that it
has.
So what we're going to do is we're going to display name.
We're going to display Namma when display total we still have those from this piece of code up here
and we're going to display them using these three manipulators.
And then when we're done we want to display the string.
Right but all we have is that stream o ss and a string and stream sounds like it's hard for me to say
them because I confused them myself.
So all we have is a stream o ss it's connected to a string.
So what we want to do is display the string and the way we get to that string is we use the as our method
for the Stream.
And that will return that internal string buffer that it's got and will display it.
So what we're doing here is where we're putting all of this information to that stream which is connected
to its own string.
And then we're displaying the string.
So when we display the string you should see this display in a formatted manner.
So let's try that.
There it is.
Mo one hundred twenty three point forty five it's the same formatting that we used right up here.
Makes sense of what we're doing is where we're displaying this member before it went to see out.
Now it's not going to see that now it's going to that string stream.
They're both streams right out is an output stream and SS is an output stream.
It just happens to go to a string.
And now let's do an example for data validation you guys had a lot of questions about data validations
on the forums.
So I decided to do an example using the stream stream.
All right.
So let's go through this one really slowly here.
This is the value at the end of this.
I want the user to enter an integer and I want that integer to be in that value variable right here.
OK.
But I can't.
And you've seen how we can't just ask the user for an integer and then do something like C in.
So we could read the console input into that value variable.
That doesn't work for a right when they type strings and when they type silly stuff on the keyboard
it's going to fail.
So we've got to have a better way to do that.
We have to be able to validate the type that are entering.
So that's what we're going to do here rather than read directly into an integer.
We're going to read into a string right here entry.
OK.
And we're going to do this in a loop and we're going to keep doing it until they enter something that's
valid.
So let's talk about the loop.
What we're doing what we'll do first is we're going to create a boolean flag right here called done
and we're going to see that done to fault's because we're not done.
We're done when we're done right when we're starting out.
Obviously we're not done when we first start.
So we've got to loop or do wollop here and what we're going to do first is we're going to say hey user
please enter an integer and we're going to read the integer into entry.
Remember entry is that string.
So now we're allowing them to enter anything they want.
We're going to grab a string so they can type in numbers letters decimals whatever they want and what
we'll do is we'll try to validate that to make sure that what they typed in is an integer.
This is where the string stream comes in and we're going to use an ice string stream here we have just
used a regular string string it doesn't really matter cause it goes both ways.
But this is an input string stream and we're going to call a validator called it anything you want.
Typically you see these things called s s out there in real code.
I don't know why but it's very very common to see strings James named.
SS So I call a validator and I'm looking at up to entry.
So now I remember entry is suppose entry has a user entered one instead of the number one.
They entered the string one.
What we're doing is we're hooking up this string right input sorry entry right here to that validator
string stream and then this is the key right here.
I'm going to try to extract value once value an integer.
I'm going to try to extract a value from the stream.
There's no way.
Right we've got a string here that's all o n e.
That's not an integer.
This will fail if this fails we're going to say sorry that's not an integer.
Done is still false.
We're going to loop again and I'll talk about this statement here in a second.
But now suppose that they do enter a valid integer suppose they enter 123.
Remember it's a string they're entry strings but that's a valid integer in that string.
When we get to here and we try to extract that integer from that entry that they put in through the
stream we're going to get back 123 and that's going to be stored right in value.
So that's going to be perfect.
This will pass we'll set Dunta true and we're looping while we're not done so we're done right.
Our loop will finish and then I believe there's a statement done here at the bottom that says you entered
the integer value and I'll run this for you in a minute.
Now let's talk about this statement right here.
This is something I hadn't talked about yet and this is these are the more advanced edge cases and nuances
of C++.
Suppose that the user entered something like twelve point thirty eight.
Well this right here will extract the 12 and 12 will be put into value.
But then we have all this stuff left over on the stream.
So the next stream read doesn't really know that that's there.
So what we're doing here is we're saying stood CN and we're using C-n here because that's where we're
reading data from.
We're going to ignore everything in that stream up to the new line and that's what we're doing here.
And that's where that limits header file comes in.
So we're using student numeric limits up to whatever the Studd stream size is and that's dependent on
your platform.
So how big that stream is the maximum number I'm getting rid of all of this stuff I'm just ignoring
all them clearing up that stream so that the next time I read from the stream it's clean and there's
nothing left over.
They remember that the user could have typed in 12.
Hello there.
Right.
And that space right there Rab's that 12 and that 12 goes into value this passes this is true.
So we've got an integer.
They did that to type in an integer.
They typed in a bunch of other stuff as well.
But what we do is we can grab the 12 and just delete that rest of that stuff so the next time we read
we're clean.
All right so let's run this example.
And please enter an integer 12 you entered into your 12.
Good.
That wasn't until just what we expected.
So let's run this again.
Please enter an integer.
Let's say I typed in Frank.
Sorry that's not an integer.
How about point 0 1.
But notice now that when I loop around whatever was left in that input stream is gone because I ignored
it I got rid of it all.
So that really helps us with with future input.
So now if I did something like 10 Frank is a good teacher.
Something like that you entered 10 notice it grabbed the integer but then it just discarded everything
else.
So we're ready to read again and our stream will be in a known state and not some unknown state.
All right.
So that's it.
I hope you enjoyed this.
This section on stream streams they're very very powerful.
They're not used that often out there but sometimes you'll see them used and they used a lot in GUI
work sometimes when you want to display strings too gooey a graphical user interface elements.
We tend to format them in memory and then display them out.
That's it.
So let me know if you have any questions about this.