It is go over some of the popular ideas and where you should place the input files that you're going
to read from code like I won't do because we're been using it throughout the course but we've got Windows
Visual Studio code blocks Sea-Lion the next code and I do a really short video on all of them it's the
same little program that all it tries to do is open a file called testee XTi.
And what I found was that in code like we need to do a dot dot slash test that text in Windows Visual
Studio is just a filename and code blocks is also just the filename in sea lion just like in code like
we need to go up a directory and then provide the name of the file and X code is a little different.
So please watch the video if you're using X code and I'll show you how to set it up so that you can
use input files.
Ok so first let's start with your studio.
So this example I've got visual studio and you can see when I run this sample it says error opening
file because the founders exist.
So what we want to do is create the file so we can click the resource area and click add new item and
then select text file and give it the name test.
T x t it's lowercase
and press add.
And at this point that files Banat and we can go back to our C++ file and executed at this point.
And notice we're just using tests he exceeds the filename and we should get good to go.
There we go.
Good to go.
So it's all set.
So that's the way you would create an input file in Visual Studio.
So now let's see how we can get this to work using the code blocks ID for this example I mean the code
blocks ID and you can see I've got the same file here where I'm trying to open an input file stream
name test that TXI T.
It's not here right now so if I try to run it says problem opening file to 6 we expect.
So what we'll do is we'll come up here.
So what we can do is we can come up here to select our project and say file new empty file.
Do you want to add this new file to the active project.
I'll save the project first.
And all we're doing here is we're just creating that file.
Test Dot T S T and make sure that it's in the file test directory or whatever the project directory
is and where basically where you see your source file right here save that it's going to ask me to select
a target so that's important make sure those are checked selected and at that point you can see it creates
this folder called others with the test in it.
And now if we run this we're going to go.
OK so that's how you would create a file for input in code blocks.
Next up is Seelye And let's see how we can get the input files to read using Sea-Lion.
I mean the sea lion ID on Windows.
And you can see I've got a real simple program that's going to test opening a file the file name is
test TXI.
If I run this.
He just clicked that little green arrow right here.
Or I can click the green arrow up here.
I'll just do it right here.
You'll see that what we'll have is we'll have an error says problem opening file just as we expect because
the file doesn't exist.
So I'm going to come up here to the project right click and say new file the file name would be.
Test t x T.
I'll save that and will try to run it again and I'll click the CBP file again.
Again we're seeing a problem opening file.
And if we look at the directory structure you'll see the problem is that the file is being created in
here you can see it right here.
File tests are easy.
So it's a level up.
So you need to do the same thing with didn't code light we just basically say dot dot slash will save
it.
We're running again and we're good to go.
So that's how you do this in Sea-Lion and we'll finish up this section with X code x code is a little
bit different.
So what's the value of using X code and you need to have input files.
Ok so I'm on a Mac running X code and I've got that simple program here I'm trying to open a file and
text 16.
If I try to run this I'll get an error out here same problem opening file.
So that part of the file is not there.
So let's add the file.
So let's right click here.
Will say new file.
So like Mac OS and Austro all the way to the bottom two says empty
and we'll create test that T.
That sits the files there now.
So if we run again it still won't find it will have a problem opening files the way the tax code works
and Mac works is that you see file that app is stored in some derived data directory really really far
removed from the project.
So the best way to do this on a Mac is to come up to product
then select scheme and end it's game and then look for this working directory right here.
It's under options on run debug.
You select working directory and you select.
You say use a custom working directory.
And what we want to choose is we want to suits that one to and what you want to do is select the working
directory where those files are humane CVP and your test he Eckstine you selected.
We closed this up now and now we run.
We should be good to go.
And we are and it will find the file just fine.
Most of the other IDs will also allow you to change the working directory but it's much easier just
to change the file path on those but on a map.
This is the best way to do it.