In this video I'd like to do an overview of the basic elements of the C++ standard template library
and see what it's all about the SPL is a library of powerful reusable adaptable generic classes and
functions.
OK so what do all those words mean.
Well the SBL is powerful.
We've already seen a bit of that power when we use the vector class the FCL is reusable.
Remember when we created vectors of integers and doubles in accounts and so forth we didn't have to
do anything except tell the vector what we wanted it to hold the ASIO's adaptable.
It provides containers iterators in algorithms that we can adapt to make them do whatever we need them
to do with our programs.
Finally the ACL is implemented using template functions and classes.
We learn about C++ templates in the next few videos.
They are one of the features that makes the post so powerful.
The ACL is a huge class library will only be scratching the surface in this section.
But once you understand how to use DSTO the principals will learn will apply across the entire SPL.
The ACL was developed around 1994 by Alexander Stepanov and even today it's considered one of the best
designed generic class libraries ever created.
So what is the best deal.
Well at its core the SBL is an assortment of commonly used containers.
We'll see some of these containers in the next slide.
The algorithms provided by the SBL have published and well understood time and size complexity information.
That means that when you use the containers and algorithms in the CEO there are no surprises.
You know exactly how the algorithms behave as the size of the collection increases.
Complexity theory is beyond the scope of this course but it's an important part of software development.
The SCA has been around a long time it's been tried and tested across many millions of lines of code.
The ACL is consistent.
Fast typesafe as well it's extensible.
The ACL has three main components container's algorithms and iterators.
Containers are collections of objects or primitive types.
These include array vector deck stack set map and more algorithms are functions for processing sequence
of elements from containers.
The SPL has about 60 algorithms that can be used and extended to work with any type of data.
These algorithms allow us to find a specific element in a container find the max or min element in a
container count the number of elements in a container accumulate or sum up the values of container elements.
Sort containers and that's just a few examples we can do much much more.
Finally iterators generate the sequences of elements from the containers that the algorithms use.
There are several types of iterators that allow us to generate sequences of elements in various ways.
Note that one of the beautiful aspects of the design of the SBL is that the containers algorithms and
iterators are designed totally independently from one another yet they work together seamlessly.
Also note that I said the SBL has three main components.
It also has a few other components such as functors and allocators.
But we won't be covering those in this section before we get into the details of the SPL.
Let's see a simple example of how we could use some of its functionality will use a vector of integers
for these examples.
Since we're already familiar with vectors in this example I'm including the vector and algorithm header
files.
Vector allows me to work with vectors an algorithm allows me to use the ECL algorithms.
So let's create a simple vector of integers we'll call it V and initialize it to 3 integers 1 5 and
3.
Now suppose we want to sort that vector.
We can use the FCL sort algorithm to do that but the sort algorithm needs a sequence of objects to sort.
That's where the iterator comes in.
We provide the sequence using vidette began and V.
This provides the sort outgrow them with the integers in the vector v from the beginning element to
the ending element.
In other words the entire vector.
That's it.
Now we can display the vector using a range base for loop and we can see the elements in the vector.
Now sorted.
Pretty easy right.
The iterator we used produced a sequence of all the integers in the vector but we could have easily
provided only a subset if that's what we needed.
So suppose we had need to only sort the first half of a vector.
We could modify the iterator to produce just the first half of the elements.
Also we aren't restricted to using a vector.
We can sort just about any as T.L. container exactly the same way.
Also we can extend the sorda algorithm to tell them exactly how to compare the elements when sorting.
For example maybe we have a vector of account objects and we want to sort them by balance suppose that
now we want to reverse the order of the integers in this vector we can use the SBL reverse algorithm
to do that.
The code is exactly the same but we use the reverse function instead of sort.
And when we display the fact as elements we get 5 3 1 as we expect.
Also I should mention that behind the scenes the range based for loop is itself an iterator.
We'll talk more about that later.
Now let's see a different type of algorithm function the accumulate function.
In this case I want to add up all the integers in the vector and store the result in a variable called
sum.
To do this I can use the accumulate function.
Notice that the function has parameters.
The first two are iterators.
Where do I start.
Where do I end.
This produces the sequence of elements that the accumulate function will process the third parameter
0 in this case is what the running sum will start at Typically 0.
But we can use any number we want the type of this third parameter is very important.
So if you want to sum integers use 0 if you want to sum doubles use zero point zero the total is stored
in sum and in this case we display 9 which is one plus three plus five.
The sum of the elements in the vector from these simple examples you can see how powerful using containers
iterators and algorithms can be.
Now let's talk about the various types of containers provided by DSTO.
We have three basic categories of containers.
Sequence associative and container adapter's sequence containers are containers that maintain the ordering
of inserted elements.
These containers include array vector list forward lists and deck will discuss each of these containers
in this section of the Course associative containers insert elements in a predefined order or no order
at all.
For example a set is a collection of elements where there are no duplicates but there may be an order
associated with it or not.
We've got the option to choose whatever one we want.
A map is like a dictionary where we associate a word with its definition.
There are many variants of this category so we can have ordered sets an ordered sets sets that allow
duplicates maps that allow duplicates and so forth.
These are very powerful data structures that are often underused.
We'll talk about them in this section and I'll show you how to use them.
The last category.
Container adapters are variations of the other containers.
This category does not support iterators so they can't be used with as T.L. algorithms but they're so
commonly used in programming that DSL provide support for them.
These include the stack the queue and the priority queue.
In this slide you can see that the ACL has several types of iterators input iterators make container
elements available to your program output iterators can iterate over a sequence and write an element
to a container for iterators can iterate forward over a sequence and can rewrite any element by directional
iterators are like forward iterators but they can iterate over a sequence in both directions and finally
random access iterators can use the subscript operator to directly access elements.
We saw that with the Vector class.
Finally we have the ACL algorithms as I mentioned previously there are about 60 algorithms in the SPL
and the algorithms are classified into two major groups not modifying and modifying algorithms depending
on whether the algorithm modifies the sequence it acts upon.
As you can see there is a lot to the T.L. and we can't possibly cover it all in detail in a single section.
In fact entire books have been written about the ACL but by the time you get to the end of this section
you'll understand the fundamentals of the ACL and be able to use this heal containers iterators and
algorithms to solve real problems.
But before we get to the ACL Let's talk a little bit about generic programming and templates so that
we can understand the design behind DSTO.