This video I'd like to go over some live examples of how to use iterators.
There'll be a bunch of examples here and I'll go through them one at a time so that you can really understand
what's going on.
I'm in the Section 20 workspace in the iterators project and first things first so notice them I'm including
a bunch of header files here.
Set map and list.
These are all containers in the SPL.
We haven't really talked about set map and list too much but that's the whole point we really don't
need to know that much about them to be able to iterate through them.
We'll talk about them in detail in future videos.
So the first thing we'll do is we'll have a couple of functions and here's a function that we're going
to use and we're going to use it too much.
But if we ever need to display a vector of integers we're going to call this function it's just going
to display a nice little format.
OK.
Someone to close that up and that way you know what it is.
So here's my first function and what I did was I broke this up into I think five different functions.
That way it's all more self-contained rather than having one just huge main with all the examples in
it.
So in this case let's walk through this.
We're creating a vector right here of integers called Numbers 1 and we're putting 1 2 3 4 and 5 into
that vector.
So this is where we're at right now 1 2 three four and five.
And remember the end of the vectors after the last element.
So we want to create an iterator now and that's what I'm doing right here.
I'm using I-T.
And notice I'm using Auto I'm letting the compiler deduce the type of the iterator obvious it's going
to be an iterator that iterates over vectors of integers right.
That's the idea here.
So I'm going to call numbers 1 began.
That's going to give me the iterator to the first element and assign it to I-T.
So I t's here and it's going to be pointing there.
I remember is not a real pointer.
This is an object.
OK but the syntax and the way it feels is very pointier like and that's by design.
So that's pointing to the one in order to get to the one I need to dereference that iterator right there.
And what that's meant to do is it's going to give me the one the the object in the container.
And in this case I'm going to display it.
OK.
So it's as simple as that.
Now what I want to do is move this iterator so I'm incrementing the iterator right here and I'm incrementing
it by 1.
So what's going to happen the iterator now will be pointing to two.
What do we do.
We're displaying it again.
So I want to display it to not notice what's happening in the next line I'm saying.
Iterator plus equals to some increment the iterator by 2.
Was it to someone to go 1 2.
Now it's going to be pointing to the limit number four what do I do.
Display it.
Now I'm going to move it right back down by to someone to move it back to the two
and display that and then the last thing I'll do is I'll city iterator to point to the element.
That's not a dn.
Remember there is no element in the end just means you're at the end of the list.
But I want to go one back from it.
So I really want to point to the end of the list the five in this case.
So what we're doing is in this case we're going over here and there we're back and up one so that.
So if I run this this test function right here there should be the output 1 2 4 to 5.
And what's interesting here is you can see how these integrators feel just like pointers right.
And that's real handy.
I'm using the auto here it saves a lot of makes it a lot easier read.
I'll use it in some places I won't use.
Another is that where you can actually see both styles.
So that's it.
If I run this program now let me go through my main and make sure that I'm calling tests 1 am right
there.
So if I run this now what I've got is I should get one to 4 to 5 exactly like we thought.
So let's test once let me collapse this guy will move on to test to and I'll go down to my main and
I'll just make sure that I comment about tests 1 and uncomment test to perfect.
So now let's take a look at a test to see what's going on in there.
So here's test two who we're doing the same thing we're creating a vector of integers and initializing
it from 1 to 5.
So we've got one two three four five.
And here is the end right here.
Croak created another iterator I'm calling it again this way and this time I'm doing it long style I'm
not using auto and you can see it's really pretty straightforward it's just a lot of extra typing.
So we're creating a stood vector of integers and that's the iterator and we're calling it I-T and we're
initialising it comes one dot began which is the first element in this vector which is that one right
there.
So that's where we're at now.
And now you can see what's happening here I've got a while it gets really simple I'm saying while the
iterator is not pointing to this guy over here the end.
In other words while the iterators in the real list in the container in this case a vector what I want
to do is display what is pointing to and then increment.
So you can see what this is doing is just going here and then here and then here and then here and then
it says stop.
So this will print out one two three four and five write just like that.
So let's take a look at this loop right here.
What we're doing here it's really the same thing I remember this iterator.
Now it is over here.
It's pointing to the end.
So if I want to go back to the beginning I could just simply say it's equals numbers 1.
Begin right from resetting that iterator to points in the beginning of this container.
This vector.
So what I'm doing is Acemoglu while I'm not at the end of the list this time I'm doing this right here.
Now that's an interesting statement.
Members dereference the iterator equals zero.
Just like we did with pointers.
What are we doing we're storing 0 where the iterators pointing here were looping through.
So what we're doing is we're doing this.
We're changing all of those values in that vector to zero.
And then I'm just calling display Nom's which should display a bunch of zeros.
All right so let me raise this and give this a run and see what we get there is our output 1 2 3 4 5
just like we expected.
And then a bunch of zeros when we call the display function.
Hopefully you all are with me.
These iterators are pretty straightforward but it's important to understand them because we really need
to use them with the algorithms so we have to be able to make sure that what we're getting is what we
want.
So let's take a look at test three.
Let me take care of main real quick and I'll comment this one out so we can run test three.
And here's test three.
Now what we're going to do here is a constant iterator all the concentrator is is an iterator by it
can't change what it's pointing to it's constant.
So we can do this a couple of different ways.
We're doing the same declaration here of number ones.
That's my vector of integers.
Again one two three four five.
Now what I'm doing here is I'm saying I-T one is a contest iterator noticed Konst underscore iterator.
What that's doing is it's creating a constant iterator not just an iterator again a constant iterator
and it's starting at the 1 again.
Number one to begin.
And I'm not going to write that again because you guys kind of know what's going on.
Now if I wanted to not use this long style I just use the auto.
I can't just say auto I-T one equals numbers one dot begin.
Because I'll give me a regular iterator I have to say See begin.
That's going to give me the constant iterator.
So these two lines would be equivalent.
Hey we could do it either way.
Now what we're doing here is we're just looping through and printing out again one through 5.
But let's see if we can change things right member here.
We're trying to change each one of those elements to zero just like we did in test two a little while
ago.
I can't do that and I'm not allowed to do that because it's a Konst iterator right here.
So if I try to do that let me comment that line out right here if I try to do that I should get a compiler
and it's exactly right.
This is one of the things that you'll notice about compiler errors for the standard template library.
They're not exactly readable compiler.
Here are some of them are really really nasty or hard to understand but this one is not too bad.
It says error assignment of read only location that gives you a clue.
Right.
We've got a constant iterator here you're trying to write through it.
So that's the rest of the error message which is kind of nasty to read so I'll comment this back out
and if I run it now I should just get the one through the five just like we did before.
Perfect.
Now let's take a look test for which adds a few more little things to the mix.
Well we'll use some containers that we haven't used yet.
So any comment tests for.
And let's take a look at test for this.
A lot going on here.
First thing is we're going to use a reverse iterator first.
So what we're doing here we've got a vector.
One two three four.
Probably should put the 5 in there I forgot.
So but doesn't matter.
We've got a vector one two three four and it's vec.
It's a vector of integers.
Now I'm creating i t one is my iterator.
And notice that I'm using auto and I'm using R begin right there.
That's a reverse iterator.
That's what the R stands for.
And then what I'm doing is while I-T one is not equal to Veck dot our end.
So now we're just going the other way around.
So we're going for three to one and the end is actually over here now and we're simply displaying and
notice I'm incrementing right you may want to decrements and you're going the other way but we're using
a reverse iterator so incrementing here really means detrimental here.
And the other way around as well.
Now let's look at a couple of more examples here what we've got is a container we haven't used yet.
We'll use it a lot later on watching and do a nice little challenge with it.
It's a list a list is basically a doubly linked list.
So remember how a vector was a bunch of data contiguous in memory.
Well a list is some items that kind of look like that are elements.
And then we've got pointers back and forth so that we can move from one to the next one really easily.
So that's all it is.
We don't really have to worry too much about how it's implemented behind the scenes to use it which
is really cool.
So what I'm doing here declaring name I should call that names but that's ok name is a list of strings
and then initializing it to Larry Moe and Curly.
Now what I'm doing is I'm setting.
Teach and this would be Larry here.
This would be moe here and this would be curly over here.
Then I'm saying I T-2 is a constant reverse iterator.
That's the C R.
So right now I T-2 is pointing right over here and it's its reverse iterator.
If I dereference it it's going to print out curly.
Now I'm going to increment it which simply means move it over here incrementing means going reverse.
So in this case I'm coming over here in a mo and right here I'm going to display Mo over here I displayed
Curly.
So that takes care of that one.
And then let's do a few more.
Now this is a data structure that we haven't used yet a container we haven't used.
It's a map.
What is a map.
A map is a map is a key and a value.
So it's a pear and I talked about this earlier.
There's a class called stood pear and that's basically what's happening.
The first item in there is called first and the second item in the pair is called second.
And we can access them directly.
So look what I'm doing here I'm creating favorites and favorites is a map of string string pairs.
And I would just say initializing them.
So all we're doing here is creating an association between two strings of Frank like C++.
Bill likes Java.
James likes Haskell or Frank hate C++.
Bill hates just whatever makes sense here.
So that's the map.
You know what we're going to do we're going to have another iterator in this case I T-3 and it's favorite's
not began.
So it's going to go to the first item in that map which in this case is phrenic.
And I'm going to loop while I T-3 while that iterator is not pointing to the end of that map.
Now how is a map stored behind the scenes.
It's a complex data structure.
It doesn't matter.
I don't need to know that to use this kind of logic.
That's the beauty of this.
I don't really doesn't matter what and how it's implemented.
Behind the scenes.
So in this case while I haven't hit the end of that map for each one of those guys I'm going to take
83 first and 83 second make sense right.
So we're basically using the arrow operator dereferencing the iterator getting to that pair and then
taking the first item and the second item in the pair.
And then we're incrementing the out in the iterator.
So let's run this.
And here are results.
Let me scroll up just a little bit here.
Here we're displaying this reverse iterator.
We're using the reverse iterator to display this vector VEC and we're getting four three two one.
Over here we got curly and Moe remember we're starting at the back so we're getting curly and then we're
incrementing which means move to the left and I've got mo.
And then I'm just iterating over this map so I'm getting built Java Frank C++ James Haskell.
Now notice the order here.
It's not the order I put them in.
The last one we'll do is we'll do test 5 and test 5 is pretty easy so far everything we've done we've
iterated through an entire container.
Well we're going to do here was just going to iterate over a subset of the container.
So we have a vector of integers.
Again one two three four five six seven eight nine and 10.
And here's the end.
And now I've got two iterators I'm using auto for both so the compiler can figure out the type and I'm
saying start that's the name of my iterator is equal to VEC that begin plus two vector begin is this
guy plus two would be the three and finish
vector and minus three.
Well here's Vicot end minus one two three.
That's what we've got that's starting to finish.
So now what I want to do is I just want to display the elements between them.
So right there is the logic while start is not equal to finish.
Display what start is pointing to.
So it's going to display three and then increments start.
Display for display five display six display seven.
Now they are equal.
So this fails and we're done.
So this will display this subset of that vector.
Right.
So let's run this.
And you can see three four five six and seven being displayed right here.
OK.
So play with these examples.
I've broken them up into these small test cases.
That way you can tweak them a little bit rather than having one huge man that's going to get really
complicated.
So come in here comment them out add your own logic.
Play around with reverse iterators constant iterators regular iterators.
You saw how I created the map so you can kind of figure out based on my code what I did.
Obviously I'm going to talk about lists and forward lists and maps and vectors and sets and everything
else in the upcoming videos.