Hello and welcome to the Section 20 second challenge.
This challenge is all about using a stood list a doubly linked list.
What we're going to do in this challenge is we're going to simulate a playlist.
So imagine you've got a CD and you want to put it in your car or you want to play it and move to the
next song in the previous song in the beginning and so forth was going to be able to add songs to this
so that's the idea here.
We're going to model that playlist using a doubly linked list of song objects.
So I mean the Section 20 workspace and here is the challenge to project and then there's the challenge
to solution project which her has my solution and I'll go over that in the next video.
So let's talk about this challenge a little bit.
The idea here is that you want to learn how to use a stud list and that's what we're going to use in
this challenge.
We want to create a menu driven application.
This would be really cool to do graphically but we haven't learned how to do that stuff.
So what we want to do is we want to simulate the user selecting the first song in the playlist and then
going to the next the previous playing forward and backwards through the playlist.
Simple as that.
We're also going to allow users to add new songs to the playlist and every time we add a new song it's
going to be added prior to the currently playing song.
OK.
So here's the menu.
And I've got a sample run coming over here on the right and I'll get that in just a second but here's
the menu.
Play the first song play the next song play the previous song and play a new song at the current location
and then just list the current playlist in that it lists the playlists.
In other words the songs that are out there and it will also list the currently playing song and q to
quit.
So that's it.
It's real simple.
The available play list is modeled as a list of song objects.
I'll provide the song class and I'll go over that in just a second.
And these are the songs that I put into playlists just by default.
I just grabbed a bunch of them from the pop charts.
You can change these to whatever you like or just put on one song two song Three to keep track of them.
I got kind of bored doing song one song too I wanted to see some real song names so here they are.
Drake Kamila Kameo and Maroon 5 Imagine Dragons a bunch of popular songs.
That's it.
So let me go over the run first and then what I do is I go over the sample code that I'm giving it will
be here on the right.
You can see the program running the first run it just displays the playlist right here that's the playlist
so you can see these songs right here are showing up right here and the current song that's playing
is the one by Drake which is the first song on the playlist.
You see it right up here.
So by default that's that's our starting point.
When we first run the program the first song will be played.
Imagine you're putting a CD in your car.
Here's the menu played the first song so when the time you press F is going to jump to Drake's song
and play it next.
Obviously it's pretty straightforward happening.
If I'm playing Drake song and I press next then it's going to go to Kamila song and if I press next.
Again the weekend Zed Maroon 5 imagine dragons and so forth.
Now since we have a doubly linked list these songs are modeled as the linguists right.
You've kept your links coming back and forth and then I've got something called current song and that's
an iterator that is pointing to the current song.
So when you press next All we're doing is we're moving the iterator over here and the press again.
Next we're going to move it over here.
Now what's going to be interesting is if I'm right here the first and I press previous I want to wrap
around to here and if I'm over here and I press next I want to wrap around to here.
So I always want to be in that playlist.
OK.
So let's walk through this a little demo right now.
When we first start the program you can see the play list and you can see that drake song is playing.
That's the very first song on the playlist.
If I press and or next it says playing next song and it says now it's playing the song which is this
guy right here.
Never be the same if I press next again and I'm going to scroll up so you can always have this in context
here.
Now it's playing the PRAY FOR ME song which is the third song I'll press next again.
Now I was playing the middle when I pressed necks again it should be wait.
And then whatever it takes.
So I pressed necks again.
Wait.
Is playing by Maroon 5.
One More Time.
And now whatever it takes by Imagine Dragons is play now I'm at the end of my playlist if I press next
again.
I wanted to wrap around back to the drake song so let's do that.
I'll press n and you could see that we scroll that up we could see that drake song is now playing.
Now if I'm here at the beginning and I press P for previous It should wrap around back down to the Imagine
Dragons song so I'll press P for previous Now I'm right here and right at the end here.
Imagine Dragons is playing.
Let me move that up for you.
You can see a little better.
OK.
So that's it.
Now of course if I press previous here it's going to go to the Maroon 5 song and you can see it's just
a linked lists and I'm able to go around it which is pretty cool if at any point you can press l and
that will list what's currently happening.
So you could see the play list right here.
That hasn't changed because we haven't modified it at all but you can see the play list right here and
the current song is The Maroon 5 song.
So any time you want some information you press l.
All right so now let's get to the good stuff.
Let's add a song and we're going to scroll up just a little bit.
I'm going to press OK.
And when I press a it says adding I'm playing a new song called.
So what's the song name I want to add.
I say I want to add imagine who's the artist.
It's the Beatles.
What's my rating for the song.
I'll give it a five.
Now when I press enter that song will be added before the current song.
And if you remember the current song was wait that's the one that's currently playing.
So imagine will be added between the middle and wait so I'll press enter and it will play it will be
the current song.
I'm going to press enter and you can see now it's playing imagined by the Beatles.
And if I listed me scroll up a little bit if I list my playlist now you can see that imagine is right
here.
Me Mark that for you with my pen and see that imagine is right here now and it's between.
Wait in the middle.
So what I wanted.
Now suppose I want to press F and I want to go to the first song.
So when you hear the drake song then I want to insert a new song before that.
So let's do that now.
So the first thing I'll do is clear this real quick and I'll scroll up.
So I'm going to go to the first song which is the drake song when I press F right here.
I'm playing Drake song now I want to add another song so let's add.
What's the song's name.
That say it's New York and let's say that this is Frank Sinatra.
And I'll give it a 5.
I'm giving everybody fives.
That's it.
Now it's playing New York.
Remember we were at the beginning.
So if I display my playlist you can see that New York has now been added at the beginning of the list
and it's playing right here current song New York.
That's it.
That's the program you press Q to quit.
Now there's a couple of interesting things here that you can extend.
Once you get this basic functionality going.
Notice that in my menu I have no way to play the last song in the list or the ending song in the list
you could certainly add that you could add a whole bunch of other things you could save this to file
you can read this information from a file so you can extend this program in a bunch of different ways.
OK so now let me show you the source code that I'm giving you and that is right in here.
I've gone ahead and included the include files that you're going to need and let me show you what the
song class looks like.
It's a real simple class.
Obviously this is what we're modeling the name of the song The Artist and the rating which is an integer
in this case I have a friend function here which is my overloaded insertion operator so that I can display
this kind of stuff over here real easy.
I've got a default constructor.
I've got an overloaded constructor here that allows me to create whatever I need using name artist and
rating.
Then I've got some getters that I'm only in think I'm using the getters but I put them in there anyway.
Now the most important thing we need to do here is and it's not so important in this program but it's
just best practice to always do we need to overload these operators the less than operator and the equality
operator.
Those are the only two operators that we must overload if we're going to use our own custom classes
with the SPL.
So in this case less than just defining less than as this name of this song is less than that name of
the other song.
And the same thing with the quality of the two names are the same then I'm considering them equal.
OK.
So that's that's that here I'm overloading the insertion operator as I mentioned.
I'm giving you the code for the display menu which is really really easy.
And then I've got a couple of methods here her functions I should say that you're going to implement.
One is play the current song and all this does is it does this right here.
Here we go.
So I just went forward it says playing and the song that's playing.
That's all it just displays that.
And the song it's being played has passed into it so it's a really one liner right.
You basically just have to put that to an up and stream display playlist.
Here we're getting an entire playlist and the current song and this is the one that you're going to
call from the list functionality it's just going to display all those songs.
So in this case we're going to see something like this right here all that good information is going
to display and that here's the main probably just what you expect.
Here's my playlist.
That's my object and it is a list of song objects and I'm initializing it right here.
So that's done and I'm setting my current song this is the most important piece here.
That object right there that current song is an iterator to that's pointing to some object in that in
this playlist and I'm setting it to the beginning of the list.
I'm setting it right there it's going to start right there from that point on.
It's your logic to display the menu get the input from the user depending on what they select.
This is the guy that you're going to have to increment or decrement depending on how you want to walk
across this list.
That's it.
Have fun.
Get the basic functionality working before you extend it and then you can extend it like I said a bunch
of different ways you can go to go to the yen go at the beginning save it to a file so next time you
run this you can just load the information the song information from the file because remember as it
is now every time I add a new song to the playlist it's not being persisted so the next time I run this
it's not going to be there.
So be kind of nice to be able to save that and then load it up again.
OK so that's it.
Have fun.
It's a nice little challenge project.
It's simpler than you would think.
Think iterators think as T.L..
Don't don't think about you know I's and J's and looping variables and things like that.
Let us do the work for you.
All right have fun and I'll see you in the next solution video.