In this video we'll learn about our first as T.L. adapter container the stack the stack is a last in
first out data structure.
It's an adapter because it's implemented in terms of already existing as T.L. containers.
Since all operations on a stack happen on only one end of the top we can easily implement a stack based
on any container that has a back.
These are vector lists and deck.
So the way that the stack methods work is they use delegation and they call the back push back and putback
methods of the underlying container.
Stacks have wide applications in computer science and the ACL provides a simple concise implementation.
You can think of a stack as a stack of books or a stack of plates.
If we stack plates one on top of the other we can't pull out a plate from the middle or from the bottom.
Instead we add plates at the top and remove them from the top.
Since stacks are limited to insertions and deletions and only one end iterators really don't make sense
and they're not supported.
So we can't use stacks with AS HE'LL.
In order to use the stack container.
We have to include the stack header file.
The stack provides a handful of methods that have well-defined behavior.
The push method inserts an element at the top of the stack.
The pop method removes an element from the top of the stack.
The top method access is the top element of the stack but it doesn't remove it.
Finally we have the empty incise methods that we've already seen in the other ACL containers
since the stack is an adapter class.
We can choose what underlying container will be used when we create our stack objects.
In the first example I'm providing no information about the underlying container.
So the T.L. will use a deck by default.
You can see in the next three examples that I'm explicitly stating which underlying container to use
in a template parameter
so let's see how the push method works.
Suppose we have a stack of integers named s and it's empty.
When we push 10 onto the stack we add 10 at the top of the stack.
You can see the top of the stack is a shaded box in the diagrams.
We then push 20 now 20 becomes the top of the stack.
Finally we push 30 and the 30 becomes the new top of the stack.
Once we have a stack that contains elements we can access the element at the top of the stack with the
top method.
This returns a reference to the element at the top and does not remove it.
In this example estat top returns 30 which we display.
Now if we pop the stack the element at the top is removed in this case to 30 and now the 20 becomes
the new top of the stack.
If I pop the stack again the 20 is removed and now the 10 is the new top of the stack if we call the
size method for as here it will display one since there is just one element left in the stack as you
can see the stack API is very straightforward.
But a stack is extremely useful and it's used in computer science to solve many types of problems.
Let's head over to the idea and we'll see some stack examples.
Ok so I'm back in the IDM in the Section 20 workspace in the stack project.
This is a really simple example there's not really a lot we can do with a stack push pop and top.
That's about it.
So let's go over a few examples here.
I'm including stack right here.
Someone to use in a must including vector list.
I'm going to show you how you can create those stacks based on vector and the list underlying container.
So that's the reason I'm including them.
I'm really not using it.
I just wanted to show you how you would declare it here.
But let's talk about this template function.
This is the one that's going to display a stack.
We can't use iterators with stacks.
So there's no real way to display a stack easily.
The only way to display a stack is to let's say we've got a stack here with the 10 and a 20 and I want
to display it.
I need to get the top.
Display it pop it hit the top display it pop it.
So it's a destructive process because of that I'm passing in this stack by value.
I don't want to upset the stack as being passed into me at all.
I don't want to modify it at all.
So that's making a copy.
And what I'm doing over here is I'm destroying that copy which is fine once I finish this function the
stack has been passed into me has not been modified at all and you could see the code it's pretty straightforward.
This is a template function.
There's the type right here.
We're using integer stacks in this example.
And while the stack is not empty I'm getting the top element of the stack that I'm deleting it from
the stack and then displaying it.
That's it.
So this is going to display my stack and you could see the output over here I'd go over that in just
a second.
All right so let me scroll up and there's no test here is just amazing.
Which is pretty straightforward.
Let's go over these examples here.
Here I'm creating a stack of integers.
Call it s.
That's someone we're going to use in these examples.
But I can also create a one as two and three that are stacks of integers.
But the underlying container would be a vector or list or a deck whatever you choose on 925 here you
can see that I'm just not providing anything in which case it defaults to a deck.
All right so let's push some values on the stack and pop them off and play around with it a little bit.
Then we'd just scroll up just a little bit right about there.
OK.
So I've got that stack S10 have already defined.
And what I want to do is I want to use arr. base for a loop is going to loop over this range right here
one two three four five and push those numbers onto that stack.
Yes.
Remember that.
Assume that this is my stack right here.
The numbers are being pushed this way and then popped off.
So for someone to push one and then two and then three and then four and then five.
So that's the situation right now.
Then I'm going to call display remember display is going to make a copy of this stack.
It's not going to mess with this one.
And what it's going to do is it's going to pop the elements off the stacks and pop off the five the
four the three the two in the one member everything happens appear at the top.
So it's going to display exactly what I just said.
Five four three two one you could see five was the top of the stack in that copy.
Now if I pop two elements off of this stack the five and the four up sorry I missed one step right here.
Let's back up to that.
In this case I'm pushing 100 onto the stack so I'm pushing 100 on to here and then I'm displaying that
stack again and then you can see that the 100 is there.
The 100 is now at the top of the stack.
Now I'm popping off two elements off the stack.
The hundred and five are being popped off the stack.
So the top of my stack now is the four.
And when I display my stack right here on line 39 you can see it's displaying four three two and one
in this code here on line 41.
I'm just looping while the stack is not empty.
So as long as the stack is not empty I'm deleting stuff in it.
This is how we can clear a stack.
There is no clear method for a stack.
So this is how you would clear it you would just have to pop everything off of it.
Then when we display the stack here on line 43 we get the empty stack which is exactly what we expected.
What's the size of that stack.
It better be 0 right because it's empty and that's exactly what it is right here.
Zero.
And the last thing I wanted to show you was suppose I push 10 onto the stack from that stack is gone
it's empty now.
So I said I want to push 10 onto the stack just like I did right here.
And then I display the stack I get back at 10 top returns a reference to the top of the stack the top
of the stack right now is the 10.
It's a reference so I can modify it.
I could say that top is 100.
So I can change that top to 100 now.
So when I display the stack you can see it's display a hundred right here OK.
I think that's about it that's really all there is to a stack.
It's a very very specific data structure that we're going to use when you use it.
All you care about is pushing popping top checking to see if it's empty.
That's it.
You're not concerned with anything else.
Those are the only methods that are important and most only methods you actually want if you've got
a stack that gives you a bunch of other methods.
It's not really a stack and they're you know be careful because you don't want and you don't want to
have a stack of integers let's say 10 20 and 30 and that whatever thing you're using that you think
might be a stack is letting you have access to these guys.
That's not a stack stack all.
Everything happens right up here at the top.
Sometimes you'll see these data structures defined by programmers that have pushes and pops and inserts
stack and all kinds of things and it's not really a stack.
It's just a mess.
In this case this is a true stack.
It supports exactly what a stack is supposed to support.
All right in the next video we'll talk about the Q which is a waiting line and of course here you can
see that the last one in was the first one out.
That's why the stack is called a life flow data structure.
The cue is called a five fold data structures.
The first one in is the first one out like a waiting line or waiting queue.
And that's what we're talking about in the next video.