Hello welcome to the Section 20 challenge for video.
You've already seen before we did this challenge in set in challenge one.
This is where we decided whether a string was a palindrome or not.
We use the deck and challenge one what we're going to use here and challenge for is we're going to use
a stack and a cue to do the same thing.
It's actually exactly the same main driver.
The only difference is your function is going to be different obviously because it has to use a stack
in a cue to solve the problem.
What I would ask you to do is go back to challenge 1 and play the description video where I go into
what a palindrome is and so forth rather than repeat it here.
But if you're here already and you don't want to go over there I'll do a real quick review.
A palindrome is a string that reads the same backwards or forwards so we have a couple of examples here
madam.
Bob Tutte radar.
So no matter how you read it from the left or from the right it's the same word.
And we can have entire phrases that are palindromes as well.
So a Toyota is a Toyota a Santa NASA a man a plan a cat a ham a yak yam a hat a canal Panama.
It's amazing that this actually is a palindrome for palindrome phrases like this what we're going to
do is we're going to remove all the spaces and we're going to remove all the special characters and
we're going to make those upper case.
So in the case of a Santa at NASA what we're going to do is we're going to create that string from it.
You can see it says a Santa at NASA right in there but no spaces.
Everything is uppercase.
And if there were any apostrophes or anything else we're going to get rid of it.
So we're only going to process alpha characters and you can use the CC type header file for that.
That's it.
Good luck with this one.
Like I said go back to challenge one description and I talk a lot more about that.
Actually let me show you a sample run so you don't have to go back there.
I'm going to show you a sample run of my solution here and I'll build and run.
The main driver assure you the code also in the second the main driver has a bunch of test cases that
they run.
All you have to do is write one function.
It's called is palindrome and it returns True or false.
I pass you a string you return true or false.
So in this case a is a palindrome A is palindrome a B A's a palindrome and so forth.
Obviously a b and ABC are not radar and Bob and Anna and avid diva.
And there's a Toyota Toyota Center at NASA.
C++ is also a palindrome because what we're doing is we're removing the plus plus and just using the
capital C we're getting rid of the special characters.
So there are some test cases and here you can see the man the planned the cat and so forth is a palindrome.
You can read it the same both ways.
So that's the the sample run.
And let me show you the main that I'm giving you.
This is the main I'm giving you it's the same exact main that I gave you for challenge one.
Except what I want you to do is I want you to use.
You can see right there.
Use a stack in a cube before we use the deck.
So this will give you a little bit of experience with that.
You can see the main here and all I'm doing in the main is I've got a vector of strings.
And those are my test cases.
I'm just looping through that vector and I'm calling your function is palindrome right here and passing
in the string and you're returning true or false and I'm displaying that it's as simple as that.
Here's the function you have to implement.
It's called is palindrome it expects the string and it returns True False right now just returning false
for everything.
So if you run this right now you're going to get that shot.
Run it right now so you could see what it looks like if I run this guy right now it's going to say fault's
all the way down the line because there's no real logic in that function.
But it all runs and compiles and no worries at all.
So that's it.
If you solve the problem with the deck you kind of know how to approach it.
I'm not going to give you any hints here.
If you have you want a hint or if you have questions please post in the Q&amp;A and I'll be glad to answer
them there.
All right.
So good luck.
I'll see you in the next video and I'll show you my solution.