So there's a little bit of an issue with Android where apps and that's that.
If you ever wanted to get some text some input from the user it be extremely hard to have that user
try and type it out on the wrist.
However with awesome advancements with voice recognition we can actually use the user's voice and figure
out what they're trying to say and get that turned into a string.
And so what we're going to do is we're going to start a new project to show you how you can access that.
Now it's a little bit unfortunate because with the current set up you have to have an actual Android
Wear device in order to test that.
So unfortunately we won't be able to do that right now but I'm going to show you all the code that you
would need and you'll see in the emulator at least getting fairly far with this one example.
So let's go ahead and create a new project I'm just going to call this one voice demo and once we have
that we'll go ahead and hit next.
Make sure that we are doing a ware project not a phone or a tablet thing.
And we'll go ahead and create our project.
So with this we're not even going to mess with anything on lay out.
This is going to be an all coding activity here.
And so we're going to move over to our main activity and what we're going to do inside of here is you
may have been able to guess this but any time you want to sort of jump to something new we need to use
an intent and that's what we're going to use in this case so if you were to build an app you might have
some situation where when the user hits a button then you would initiate this intent but I just want
to show you what this content would look like now.
So with this intent we're going to make a new intent which we can just call I and let me do the auto
complete on that.
So I will say intent is equal to a new intent and what we want to pass in there is you know what we're
trying to get to and that is something called a recognizer
cogging Nizer intent.
There we go.
And on this we are going to do in all caps action recognize speech.
So that's our second option right there and this is saying hey we want to go get some speech from the
user.
Now with this there's a little bit of extra information that we have to add.
So if you do I put extra We are going to say recognizer intent dot extra language model.
And on this we are going to say there's a couple of different types of speech that you can grab.
We want the free form kind so again we're going to do this recognizer intent and on this we're going
to do language.
All caps here.
Language model.
And we want free form so you can see there's other ones like a web search and whatnot but we want free
form here.
OK so once you have that in place you just simply want to start an activity which will pass in the eye.
And we also want to be able to pass and then to say you know hey this is the one that we.
Excuse me it's not start activity.
That's if we're trying to move from activity to activity.
But we want start activity for results.
There we go.
That allows us to pass on the intent and in and like the numbers zero which is our request code so we
can know which one we're getting information back from.
So with all of this in place let's go ahead and you know if the user should instantly prompt them to
you know have a little screen where they can talk.
And then once we get back the text how do we handle that information.
Well we make a new method called on activity result and inside of here we're going to do some code after
that super call and we're going to do an if statement first to make sure that we're getting back the
correct information.
So the first one is to make sure that we have the same request code.
So I'm going to say if request code is equal to zero and the next thing that we want to check is that
the result code.
So not the request code but the result code.
If this is equal to all caps result OK because that means you know we got back something successful.
Now if this is the case we can go ahead and get back a list of strings from the user about what it is
that they said.
So we're going to have a list here of string objects and let's go ahead and get the auto complete on
that.
There we go.
And I'm going to just call this results and we're going to say results you are equal to the data dot
get string array list extra.
And inside of here we're going to pass our recognizer intent and we're going to dot extra results do
extra.
Let's scroll down so we can find results.
There we go.
All right.
So that gives us this list of strings and then you know we want to be able to go out and use these and
so this is where I would go ahead and do a for loop where you would probably go through each of these
typically there's only going to have one come back.
But you want to be up the list through.
It will give you multiple strings if it thinks it heard different things.
And so I would maybe do something where you say string result.
Notice this is singular not plural and I'll do my colon for results x and then you could go through
and you know use this particular string.
And so you could you know maybe in this case we'd want to go log it out so we could say log.
I will say something like.
Result.
And the go ahead and print out that result so we can go ahead and test this somewhat.
I mean you'll see the screen pop up but we can actually try saying something to the device so we'll
go ahead and give this a second to load up on the emulator here.
But if you do have an Android Wear device of course you can test this and see what it looks like.
And there we have it.
Here's our screen where it says tap to speak.
And I mean we can try hitting this button to say hello my name is Nick but you can see as soon as I
tap that we get errors and all sorts of problems there.
So anyways hopefully you enjoyed learning about this.
We still got more to learn.