So this is going to be an interesting lecture here.
And the main thing that I want you to learn from this is I want you to be able to learn how to hide
and show you the elements in that.
So we learned how to enable and disable some elements in our last egg time wrap but this one I want
you to be able to completely show them or hide them.
And the big kind of difference here is I want you to try and learn this on your own so I actually want
you to go on on the internet.
Figure out how to do this maybe like Android documentation's Stack Overflow questions whatever it is
you want but I want you to learn the skill of being able to figure out something on your own.
And this is going to be a quick one.
All I want you to do is make an app that has two buttons one that says show one that says hide if the
user taps the show on.
There should be a text view on the screen that is visible.
And if the user taps the Hide button that text you should become invisible so the show in the hide depending
on which one you click is going to make the text you either appear or disappear.
OK.
So go ahead hit pause on your videos.
I want you to go ahead and do this on your own.
Then I'll come back and talk about it this really shouldn't take long this is going to be a quick lecture.
But go ahead and hit pause now.
All right so hopefully that went well for you and I'm not trying to be lazy here and say you know go
ahead and google this yourself.
I'm trying to help you develop that skill of you know.
So let's say you're making an app on your own and you think others want to learn how to do this but
I don't exactly know how to do it by having that skill to be able to go out and find the answer to your
question is very very valuable.
So what I would do if I was in this situation I'd go to Google and look at something like maybe Android
hide UI element or something like that maybe you I view could be another one to go to.
Let's see what the stack overview question says.
And you know we get some good information here.
Look at this set.
Visibility view visible.
OK.
So this will probably get us along the right track.
Right like this question wasn't exactly what we were trying to find there working with the table lay
out in all this different stuff.
But this visibility stuff that looks like probably you know what we're looking for and you know we'll
see what we can do there.
So let's go ahead and open up Android studio.
We're going to start a new project we're going to call this one show to show hide really simple on this
we just want to kind of make sure that we can you know make an app that learns this new skill.
And yeah I've had some students say well it feels really good you know weird Googling things like you
know I feel like I'm not a real developer when I do that.
Let me tell you all developers Google and have to look up things like the idea that you should just
have in your brain how to do every single thing in programming is absurd.
I mean we have the Internet available to us we don't have to remember things we just have to know how
to get them we have to remember how to get to the information and if we can do that we are going to
be in great shape.
So let's go ahead and move to our display here.
We're going to work on the visual side of things.
And again we're going to be very simple here.
So the first thing that we just need is a text view.
And in fact we could just keep the existing text you that we have if we want to.
And I think I'll just do that and we just need two buttons here so I'm going to put one button here.
Up at the top left then put another button.
Right below it.
So this first button I want it to say show go ahead and change that.
And with this next button I want it to say hide case so those are sort of the two options there with
the show one.
We want to for the unclick have it it's name B show and for the hide one.
Let's just go ahead and have that one called Hide.
And for this hello world button here let's go ahead and give it a proper I.D..
We'll just call this.
Now I'm just going to call it.
Are you saying just because you know we're just trying to get a quick example out here time.
So with this let's go ahead and move over to our main activity.
So the big thing that we've got to do is we've got to write the functions for when someone either wants
to show the text for you or hide the text for you.
So we're going to say public void forgot the V on there their public void.
And I want to do show where we pass in a capital view and we'll call that view that our curly brackets.
And on that view better make sure I hit enter to import what we need.
And I'm just going to copy and paste the same thing but I'm going to change the name to hide so we should
have our show and hide functions here.
Next in order to manipulate the text view we have to have access to it.
So we're going to say you know text view here and we want to say text view.
Well I mean we could just simply call it text you maybe that's the simplest name and we'll come down
here and say all right text view.
You're going to be equal to find you by ID.
Capitol dot ID dot text view thing.
And here we go.
And I brought this up as a property so we can reference it in both of these.
So again if we go back to our Google search we were saying OK the set visibility.
Maybe this is what we're looking for.
So let's go ahead and try.
We're going to say text few dot set visibility.
And we're going to come back.
What did they say here view dot visible in all caps looks like so we're going to say View dot.
And then there it is capital visible.
That looks good.
Let's go ahead and copy the same chunk of code for the hide that instead of visible.
We need to find the opposite of that.
So maybe invisible.
Look at that.
We've got the option there.
Invisible can.
So this looks good in theory.
Let's go ahead and check it out make sure that it actually works.
We'll go ahead and throw this on to the old simulator and see what we can get there.
So again hopefully I mean you probably already have some sort of skill here with being able to google
things you know the fact that you found this course and were able to get into it I mean you probably
did some of your own research there but the main goal of this lecture were to sort of really release
and give you some freedom to say hey in programming you do not have to know everything.
You know it's perfectly OK to go reference up look up things Google when you get lost on stuff totally
totally normal behavior.
So well the hide button shows up but the the show one cancels it out and that's because visually we
didn't put any good constraints here I guess more correctly.
I didn't put any good constraint.
So I'm just going to go ahead.
Go ahead and add some quick ones here.
I think even just that enough is going to do it.
I mean if we were going to make a more in-depth app that we really cared about I think we'd put a little
bit more time into the interface there.
But again we just want to make sure the functionality works so let's hit the high.
Look at that it goes away we have the show it comes back and we can hit show multiple time.
We can hit hide multiple times and you know no matter what if we need to do the opposite it comes through
OK.
So I hope you enjoyed this little quick one.
We have now learned a new skill about how to do the visibility of objects and hopefully now you're feeling
a little bit more confident about your ability to go learn new things.
Now that was kind of a little break for us because I know we had just made that big egg timer app and
we've got an even awesomer app here is that a word awesome or I don't know we're going to be building
a great app in the next lecture so let's go ahead and dive into that now.