Hello and welcome to the section we're we're going to be building an app called hiker's watch.
So the basic idea this app is if you're someone who loves to hike explore you can open up this app and
without tapping any buttons this is the real magic of this you just open it up and it will tell you
what your latitude longitude is how accurate the GPS is at the current moment what your current altitude
is and what the address is for the place that you are in.
So for example I put in a new location I'm going to try and get us back to New York.
I go ahead and hit send here and boom.
All sudden we're on 16th Street in New York and I've listed out the zip code the state the street address
just all sorts of awesome stuff there.
So this is the app that I want you to build.
One thing that you may notice is we are full screen here.
We don't even have that little bar at the top and we've got an image filling up the whole things you're
going have to figure out how to do that.
Awesome Web site to go get images on Splash dot com I've mentioned before but just wanted you to know.
Great place to go get those.
And yeah you should have all the know how to do this right.
This is our geo location.
This is working with location objects and stuff.
So go ahead try and tackle this yourself.
I really believe that you can do this on without any of my help.
But if you need anything or you just want to see how I did it you can always move forward.
OK.
So go ahead and attack it now.
All right let's go ahead and get started here.
We're going to start a new Android project and we're going to go ahead and call this hiker's watch.
Again I would avoid the apostrophe there because you don't want to come through with that messing up
anything.
So let's go ahead and hit next on this one at least API 23 and we'll just do the empty activity because
we're not showing maps in this one.
And then we'll go ahead and hit finish here.
So while this is going we want to have that nice full screen image for our app.
So let's go ahead and go here to splash.
Lots of different pictures here that you could use for your app.
Just go ahead and kind of pick one that you think looks nice.
I like this one of sort of the stars out at night.
It's got that camping tent there you can decide whether or not you know this is the right picture for
you but I'm going to go ahead and download this one can.
And go ahead and minimize that.
And look we've got this awesome picture so I'm probably going to crop this a little bit so oops I mean
to rotate like that.
So I want to see my tools here where are those.
Here we go.
So I just want to make this a little bit smaller I'm going to take like a nice chunk of the galaxy here
maybe I'll just have it even be all stars like that.
But get a nice swatch of that or crop it and then I'm going to go ahead and export this to my desktop
and I'm going to call this the sky and we'll go ahead and do that.
Save one more thing that we do want to add it here.
We want to adjust the size.
I'm going to bring this down to room.
Let's maybe do like 500 with you know we might want to do a little bit more than that.
I mean let's do like a seven hundred and we'll go ahead and say OK there and then we'll save file export
or this puppy on the desktop again.
But I just want to call it sky replace that other one.
Great.
Now that we've got that let's go ahead and exit out of there and we'll come into.
So the first thing that I want to dive into is that if we want this to be a full screen app we've got
to go to our Android manifest here and rather than do this style app theme where we have the little
bar at the top and all that stuff we want to go ahead and change this to style slash theme at compact
dot and there's all sorts of different options here.
But we want to go ahead and choose the no action bar.
So we'll go ahead and pick that one.
And this is a basically allows our app to go full screen.
So that's kind of the first quick thing that we want to fix here.
Let's go ahead and work about the work on the visual side of our app so go ahead and make some space
for us to move around in and give Android studio a second here to launch up.
We do want to get rid of this text view.
So I'll go ahead and delete that.
Next we're looking for image view that's going to fill the entire screen so go ahead pull out an image
and it's going to ask you which image that you want and be nice to just pass this.
So let's go ahead and before we do that we'll open up our file system and inside of a bowl.
All right click this and say reveal and finder J once we have that open up drawable and open up in a
new tab our desktop folders do command to to get that.
And here we've got our sky.
I can copy this and then paste this here into drawable And let's see if we can get that show up.
There it goes.
Just to confirm here I'm going to do synchronize selected files.
Looks good.
So now that we have that in place if I want to bring out an image view it's going to ask me hey what
do you want.
And I'm going to choose this guy.
So there we go that's looking pretty good.
Now one thing that we want to do first is just make sure this goes edged edge so we'll add in these
constraints.
But just make sure you've got zero for each of them.
So there is zero there there is zero and there's zero.
So we can see from this right side that it's touching all the edges but it's not exactly filling the
whole screen.
So what we want to do here is we want to go change the scale type.
And again lots of different options here.
My favorite tends to be centered crop.
So let's go ahead and pick that one.
OK.
I want to make sure that this actually fills up the entire screen so we'll go ahead and fire up our
emulator here while we're doing a little bit more.
The next step for us while we're waiting for that to load is we want to have a nice title here that
shows that this is the hikers watch and then we want to start listing out some information here like
the latitude and longitude.
So what we need to do first is go ahead and grab a text for you.
We'll bring that down right in the middle.
In fact let's right click this and say you should be centered horizontally and we'll have you be a certain
distance from the top there.
And we have lost our image of you here.
Let's go ahead and do a control Z with that looks like maybe our better solution here is we're going
to select this text for you and we're just going to do a controlled drug.
We want the next few here.
There we go and I just want to button up top and I'm going to drag it to the edge there.
That gives me that nice distance.
Now I think eight is too close.
Maybe see something like 20.
If that gives us a little more space on that seam seems better.
We'll talk more if there is something that we can change looks like that emulator opened up.
Ooh look at that.
It's looking really cool.
I love how that looks.
So because this is a dark background we want to make sure that our text here is a light color so go
ahead and switch to the advanced attributes roll down to where we can change the text color and let's
make sure we have the text few selected here come down and select text color.
Here we go.
So change changes to be background light or something white.
Right so we can see this.
We also want to change the text size Let's see what 40 looks like.
Yeah I think this could be pretty good.
And let's go ahead and change this to say hiker's watch can.
So we've got that in place now we need to go ahead and create some text labels that are text views that
are going to show the latitude and longitude.
So we'll go ahead and grab some more text use here.
And we'll bring out this one first.
So again we want to go put some attributes here so text size maybe see what 20 looks like.
The big one here this text color we've got to make sure this is nice and light so we can even read the
text and then we'll go ahead and give this something so might say latitude and put like something 40
point blah blah blah.
Who knows.
Right.
Let's go ahead and have this be a certain distance from hiker's watch here.
It's going to go ahead and put that.
We wanted to be a certain distance from the left.
Looks like we're going to do this visually so we'll go ahead and grab that.
And it gets too close the idea of going to see what 20 looks like for spacing seem seems pretty good.
I'm also going to bump up the space in as well let's see what.
Something like 30 looks like that should give us a good distance.
OK.
So once we have that in place we can actually go ahead and copy this text view and paste it because
we want one a similar size and text color right.
So with text views three selected Let's go ahead and drag that down.
We'll bring in a little bit below and we want to get rid of the top constraint there instead grab this
and bring it to our friend there.
We want to bump up the size to be 20 and we want the spacing on the left side to be 20 as well.
OK so that looks pretty good.
And so this one being latitude we want it to be longit Tud.
Excellent.
And now we've got that in place.
OK so this is a fairly solid start of where we're trying to get to.
We're going to have to go through and connected these to our code but we'll come back to that in just
a second.
One thing that we want to do before we forget and that's that we need to make sure we get the correct
use permission here so instead use permission we want to get the fine location and we'll just go ahead
and handle that to make sure we don't forget it.
Something just popped in my head and I thought you know what we should do that before we run into any
issues inside the set.
All right so let's get back to our main activity and start writing all our location code.
And you should be an absolute pro by now by this and if you want to you feel free to copy and paste
from a different project.
But what we're going to do here is we're going to create our location manager like we've done before
and we're going to create a lake location listener that we'll call location Lester.
So we'll go ahead and set those two up.
And then inside of our on Create this is where we want to get these all set up so we'll say we first
want to set up our location manager say this is equal to this dot get system service and the service
that we're looking for is context that location service great.
So remember we've always got to cast this.
So I'll go ahead and say that this is going to be a location manager once we have that in place.
The next step for us is we want to set up the location listener and again you should be like Come on
Nick I already know this stuff and feel free if you can go faster than me.
Go ahead.
Set this out.
You're going to do great.
We just need to go ahead and get this stuff set up.
So for simple version right now let's just go ahead The only thing that we want to do is on location
changed.
We want to log some information so let's say a log that high and we want to say location and then we're
going to go ahead and pass in that location object right there and make sure we do two strings so we
can read the info from it.
OK.
So once we've got that all finished we then got to go do our classic opener.
Forget the semi-colon there.
Where we go ahead and try and get access and see you know hey are they able to you know has the user
given us permission.
If not we need to go request.
Right that's sort of the big thing that we're looking for here.
So we're going to set up an if statement.
Nice old curly brackets.
And so the first big thing is we got to check if we have permission.
So going to say context compact compact dot check self permission and the permission that we're looking
for is we're going to say this comma manifest dot permission thought access fine location excellent.
So we're going to make sure that this does not equal and we go want to go ahead and check package manager
permission granted.
So if the permission is not granted that's when we're worried and we're going to do something about
it.
OK.
And so if that is not the case then we need to go ask for that permission.
So we're going to say activity compact compact dot request permissions and inside of here we're going
to say this now we're going to do a new String Array.
And with this inside of some curly brackets Curly.
There we go.
We are going to say capital manifest permission got access fine location.
So that's going to go ahead and ask for that information.
OK.
Then after that oh we're missing one here.
That's why it's yelling at us we have to put a proper tag in there request code excuse me.
So once we've done that this is you know if we didn't get permission if we do have permission that's
the ELTs part of this equation.
Then we just want to go ahead and move forward with what we got going.
So for example the location manager want to access this and say OK let's go request location updates
and to get this role and will first pass in the location manager dot CPS provider and then we'll just
do zero and zero.
So we want all the info and then we're going to pass in a location.
Lester are we though.
OK.
There we go.
Finally did that then the next step for us is we want to get the last known location.
Right so this is in case the app opens for the first time they've already given us permission.
We've got to figure out what the last location wants so we'll say last known location
location.
There we go.
Is equal to location manager dot get last known location and inside of here again we're going to do
our location manager dot GPS provider to get that good stuff.
So once we've got this in place and let's see why we are upset here.
Require location manager film location.
That's because we should not be setting up a location manager We're setting up a location that was my
mistake there.
All right so now with that in place we can go ahead and we want to go ahead and see if location is known
or not.
So I say if curly brackets all check and see if location last known location that is is not equal to.
No.
Then we want to go ahead and you know update some information but rather than just go ahead and type
this here we're going to go ahead and make our own function that says update location information.
So let's go up to the top here.
I guess not above the street.
I'm going to try and start keeping concrete up at the top I feel like that's a good practice.
So I'm going to make a new public void function that I'm going to call update location
info and with this we need to be able to pass in a location that will just call location and then we'll
go ahead and have our curly brackets there.
So then inside of this function this is where we're going to call update location info.
We're going to pass in the last known location.
So then it's up to this function to then go ahead and write log out some information or do whatever
it is that we think is best.
And in this case I think we should just log out the information for the time being sort of say log.
I will say location and we'll go ahead and pass this location dot to street so that we can have a sense
of what's going on there.
So of course this is the first part of the equation which also got to respond for what happens when
someone actually is able to say yes or no to the permissions.
So we'll go ahead and put that above here and this is going to be on request permission result.
Remember when this gets called Whenever someone says yes or no to one of the permissions that we've
asked for so we're going to do a cool little statement here where we just say All right first thing
that we want to check and see is if we were able to successfully get the grant results and check that
and see if the length is greater than zero.
And we also want to check and see if Grant results the first object inside of there is equal to the
package manager got permission granted.
So if we get this this means that we've we've got that info right and then we'd want to go about you
know basically the same code that we had of the.
Right here where we go requesting for information.
Now what we have to do is you know do this check because remember if we just go ahead and copy this
line of code it's totally fine.
Let's get to the end of this.
So we have this line of code copy that say OK if we got permission we'll go ahead and do this.
The problem is this needs that one more if statement there.
And this is kind of code that's going to happen over and over again.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy this line of code I'm going to copy it this way it seems
to move faster here.
So I'm going to copy this and go ahead and paste that there.
And we've got to make sure we put an ending curly bracket on it.
Good.
And we've got to make sure that we change this to equals because we're saying OK if we were able to
get permission then go ahead and do this request thing.
We're going to go ahead and just put this inside of its own function.
So we'll just go ahead here and say public void and we're going to call this start listening it won't
take in any parameters but it's simply just going to do this code right here.
Right.
We check make sure that we have permission and if we do we're going to start requesting that information.
And so we'll just put start listening right here and that will solve the problem for us rather than
have to always type that every single time that we want to know about the information.
OK so now that we've got this in place what we're going to do is go ahead and give this a test.
See if we can get some of this information showing up for us.
So we'll wait for the emulator here.
And look at that finished up and see this popping up in a moment there we go ooh I love color so I'll
go ahead and say allow.
And that was the first time I was able to hit allow and actually just start into the app and mean to
do that for a while.
OK.
So what we're going to do down here is now that we've got Lague had open we're going to go back to the
emulator and we'll go ahead and hit the send button here.
So when we go back to log cat look at that it's showing latitude longitude but there's also some other
cool information here showing the accuracy it's showing the altitude.
Now this altitude is just one that we can manually send through the emulator.
So it's not like it goes and looks up the location gets the altitude and sends it back.
So if I put in 64 here and I send this we come back and we can look oh look the altitudes 64 and I found
this out because I kept changing my location all around the world and I was like how was there not altitude.
Like I put it on Everest.
I put in the exact locations for Everest and I was still getting zero and I just thought This is insane
and then I realized oh you can manually enter the altitude that's how you do this let's you know if
we don't do 645.
Oh that's totally possible right there.
So those are the next two pieces of information that we want to add.
Is the accuracy and the altitude we want to add those things and then we're going to move into the reverse
geotagging where we actually go through and add right like what the address is for this specific place.
So let's go back to the design view here or X-amount This is where we're going to finish off all of
our visual things.
So let's go ahead and grab text you three.
We're going to copy and paste that.
Now we should have a text view for let's bring that down.
So a couple of fixes you're going to get rid of the top one and move it.
So it's just connecting those two and we're going to change that to 20.
And also it's left constraint 220 and a set of longitude.
This is going to tell us if I can go and change the text here let's see text 4 right.
Yes.
So instead of longitude we are going to put in accuracy.
OK.
I mean that's not going to have a big decimal behind it.
And then let's go ahead and copy text you sure should give us a text for you 5.
There we go.
We want to move this guy down as well except with this one let's get rid of its top and connect it like
this and change its constraints to say 20 and 20 here.
And this one rather than accuracy.
This is going to tell us about the altitude.
All right.
And then the very last thing that we want to add here is we want to go ahead and add a place for the
address again.
Let's just copy one of these text fuse paste about drag one down get rid of its top and connect the
two there.
And let's be consistent we'll say 20 and 20.
Now with this one we've got to be a little bit careful because we want to say something like address
and then we want to go ahead and do a new line.
And then it's on that New Line where we're going to start sharing some information.
So we just got to make sure that this can handle it.
So let's go ahead and say you know we had an address like 40 street Boulevard and then we do a new line
and then we say somewhere Kansas like that.
OK.
So if we go ahead and do that.
Oh look.
That's a that's a beautiful address.
OK.
So that came through.
That's looking awesome.
We want to go ahead and add some proper text view ID's here so that we can access these things.
So to kind of make this a little bit quick I'm going to cop type out capital Tech's view and I'm going
to copy this.
So then I can just put names really quickly in front of your so I'm just going to say Latt text you
for this one.
And yes go ahead and update this.
I call this number three.
And I call this long the longitude text view.
Go ahead and enter that I say just say yes to all these.
OK so for this one this is our accuracy Tech's view.
Go ahead and put that in or else to do alt text you.
Excellent.
And then this one will be our address view excellent.
So now we can have the proper codes so that we can go ahead and actually get access to those different
pieces of information.
So let's go back to our code here and talk about where we need to move next.
So whenever we are going to get some information about the user's location it's going to be called here
in this update location info.
Right.
Because we're going to come here in fact on this location change you want to change this to update location
info.
OK.
We're going to pass at that location.
So this is sort of our real moneymaker.
This is where we want to make sure we just go through and update everything here.
So we need to get access to all those text views.
So what we're going to do is just type them all out right here so we're going to say capital Tech's
view and I'm going to call this one.
Start first with the lat text view I will say this is equal to fine view by the Capitol our ID lat text
you beautiful and we just want to copy this and paste for the next five that we need here.
OK.
So for this one this is going to be the long text view like that so we'll change this to say a long
text view.
This one is going to be the accuracy text us soldiers change to a CC.
This should be Allt.
I'll change that to be on that last one.
Is it going to be our address text for you.
So then we can change this to address textfield.
All right so now that we have access to each of those we just have to go about the business of sort
of updating all of these with the appropriate text and it's actually quite straightforward here.
I'm impressed with how is handled this so for example let's start with the last text view.
We're going to set the text there.
OK.
So with this we want to have one string that's going to say you know we want to set the latitude and
do our little call with a space and then we want to add on a string of whatever the latitude is.
So use this location object or one parameter here and we do dot get latitude just that easy and all
say Dot to a string it to string let's see is that I mean if get latitude is a string then we'll be
OK.
No it gives us a double.
So we're going to have to do some conversion there.
So go ahead and say double that to string and we can pass in this double.
All right.
And I forgot I deleted the location so we got to do location get latitude and that'll go ahead and convert
it into a string and then we can go ahead and put that there.
So looks like we're missing and in parentheses.
Great.
So let's go ahead and first test this.
Just one make sure that we're getting to the correct place here.
Right so we'll have our app fired up here and I just want to see that this works and if it does then
we can go rapid fire on the next pieces of information here.
Then we're going to go into reverse geocoding the address but that's going to come soon enough.
So let's just confirm that this part is working right now.
So let's go ahead and send some information and we sent a latitude of forty point seven so let's try
like 40 points 6 6.
Go ahead and do that and look at that.
It came through there.
So that's great.
You can see it's slightly off like I did 40 points 6 6 and it had 40 points 6 5 9 9 9 8 whatever right.
So kind of interesting the different details that you get there.
But then we're going to go ahead and just rapid fire this for the next three.
So of course these are going to be a little bit different.
So this is going to be our longitude Tech's view.
This is going to be our accuracy.
You and I'm realizing that shouldn't be a C A C It's a c c.
Like go ahead and update that.
And this last one here.
This is the altitude text you.
So for this one very simple we just got to get longitude no issues there and you'd be surprised.
It's about the same for all.
So we're just going to say get accuracy like we get that.
And for our last one here we'll do get altitude and we'll go ahead and get that information.
So let's go ahead and give that a run make sure this is working.
And then if we do that really the only thing standing in our way is being able to update the address.
So you should have an emulator now.
Let's go ahead and update some information and change this altitude to be like five or something like
that and boom look at updates that if you're wondering why it shows up the first time.
That's because we have the code to automatically update that.
Right but if I change this to be one point six six bam it can automatically change all that.
So we're looking really good really just the last thing that we need to do is work on this address and
accidently put some breakpoints there if you ever put those you just click on it click again it's going
to go away.
So it's time to now work with the address so remember this is where we kind of have to do some reverse
engineering here.
So first thing is we're going to make a string that I'm simply just going to call the address.
All right.
And this is initially just going to be equal to some sort of warning like could not find address frowny
face.
This is kind of our warning message in case things don't go right.
We want to have access to that there.
But then the next thing that we're going to do is over time compile an address and then update our text
view with that.
So first thing that we need to do is get information from a geocoder which then means we need to create
a geocoder.
So we're going to say geocoder I think quite naturally we'll call that geocoder is equal to a new geocoder
just like that.
And we have to pass it a context so we're going to go ahead and say this the locale are going to go
ahead and say OK now not get the fault.
So then I'll give us that next thing that we need to do here is with this geocoder we need to go get
some address this or we're going to say first we're going to pass this into a list.
So let's just go ahead and get that set up now.
Is going to be a list of addresses so a list of addresses that we'll call we'll call this list addresses
and we'll go ahead and set this equal to geocoder dot and we want to get the from location and location
that we're going to pass as the location at top and we're going to get the latitude and then location
get longitude.
I kind of wish we could almost just pass at a single location and it could do the rest for us.
But whatever result we want to go ahead and keep that at one then what we're going to do is a nice statement
here.
Now this is code that's got to be surrounded with a try catch So let's go ahead and do that or go down
here to try and end that curly bracket then do a catch.
We weren't going to take any exception that we might call the K and then we'll do our DOT print stack
trace in case we get to there.
But in case things are working here then what we want to do is a little if statement so we're going
to say if we get our curly brackets all right if list addresses is not equal to no.
And we actually got something there and do our two Ampere's stamps list addresses get we want to go
ahead and get to that position 0 and then we want to check on the size of this so we don't want to get
quite yet.
Excuse me we want to do the list addresses that size got ahead of myself and make sure that this is
grade up to zero because then that would tell us there is at least one in there.
So if this is the case then what we're going to do is if we have an actual address then we know that
we can get rid of this could not find address stuff.
So we'll go ahead and say address here.
You should be equal to a string that says capital address and has a colon and then a new line break.
OK.
So that sort of says all right.
We believe that we're going to get an address now.
Then the next thing that we need to do is we need to go through that process of pulling out all the
individual pieces of an address.
So we had done this before.
Remember we have to do if statements to make sure we're getting what we think we're getting.
So we're going to check first.
We're going to say list addresses that get.
And this is where we want to get the zero object.
And once we have that we're going to you know we have the opportunity to get the different pieces of
information.
So if I remember correctly the get thoroughfare gives us the street address so go ahead and grab that
and check if this is not equal to no.
So if that is the case then we'll go ahead and add this to our address so we'll say you know address.
That's not our address address plus equals.
And this is where we're going to add this right here so this will add the beginning part of the address
and once we have this in place we definitely want to add a new line here so we'll just go ahead and
put a new line lower case there and then it's just a matter of setting up the other pieces of this address
so you know we're going to want to go get stuff like the city name so let's do.
In fact I'm just going to copy all of this paste it down below but rather than get thoroughfare we're
going to get locality update this one to get locality and we don't want a new line after this one we
do want a space though so just make that a space or copy this one more time and we'll paste it out so
that we have the state or actually let's do the zip code so we're going to say get.
And I believe that's postal code.
There we go get the postal code.
Then the last thing that we want to do is get the states all go and put that down and say get I believe
that's referenced and get admin there admin area and depending on how you like your addresses you're
going to change up this to fit your needs.
But once you have this all in place you know all set up.
Then it's time for us to take this address and update the address text for you.
So we want to make sure that this happens outside of this big IF statement here right because if for
some reason we weren't able to get the address right we want to do it outside of all of them.
So we're going to go ahead and say address text view that set text and we're going to simply set it
equal to her address.
OK.
So once you've gone ahead and gotten that in place let's go ahead and give us a roll.
This is sort of our big moment of truth here we might have some missing pieces we'll have to come back
and fix.
But this should be pretty solid for what we're looking for.
Let's open up the emulator here and look at that.
So we are somewhere random law.
Mark Garrincha some big postal code there.
Let's go ahead and make this something like 50.
See where we are now.
Oh we're in Quebec.
Maybe if we go down we can get to the U.S. and look at that.
We're back in New York.
I mean that's what things that we had before.
So I guess that makes sense.
What happens if we move.
I think that makes us more west.
Yeah.
Somewhere in Ohio look at this.
Now we're in Iowa.
Oh my goodness this is so much fun.
Colorado we could probably go one more.
Look at that we're in Utah.
That's where I'm from.
So just keep going.
And there we are in California.
I bet one more this puts us off in the ocean.
Could not find address so that's kind of cool.
We saw one of the examples where we couldn't get an address for something.
So anyways there we have it.
We made it.
We successfully have this really cool hikers watch.
Sort of gives us nice detailed information.
Now there are some improvements that you can make with this right.
I think a big one is you could trim down these numbers sort of round them down so it's not some big
massive number and the other thing is probably if you're hiking you don't need to know your latitude
longitude and oh my goodness I just caught an the accuracy and the altitude at those right now are listed
as latitude but these things probably don't need to be updated every second and every time you move.
So if you change how often these are updated you could probably really save the user some battery worth
or hiking for a long time that could be very very important to them.
So let's go ahead make that last change.
I just want to make sure that this is exactly what we wanted.
So we do want this one to say accuracy and that one when we have the updated information.
I don't know why.
Because in our code to change this I thought that's really strange.
OK.
Longitude right there.
We're going to change this one to accuracy and
and the last one that we're going to change here is we're going to what is the altitude.
OK.
So I thought that is really strange how that's doing that well because programmatically set that wrong.
So this should look a lot better that's some of the if when you copy and paste you've got to be make
sure you're sort of on your game that you're fixing the different pieces that you need.
So there you go.
That looks much better if I change this to.
Let's make this something like 20 125.
That put us off the ocean and see if we're still in there.
See the opposite direction if I go here.
Douglas City California.
OK.
Interesting how that all works.
And you'll probably see now how it was very important that we were checking for Noal in different situations
right.
Because some of these don't have a thoroughfare the street address and so it's simply just saying the
city and the state so that you know in those situations it didn't crash or anything right.
It was still able to go.
OK.
So still more to learn in the section we're going to be making a very big app.
Let's talk about it in the next lecture.