Now with that audio to our apps using the sound demo in the previous video but now we're going to extend
that using sliders to seek backwards and forwards through our audio and to change the volume.
And actually this involves a few new techniques within Java and Android development that we haven't
used that so it's quite a lot to be covered in this video.
First off we're going to find a new widget that we haven't used and that is known as the sick bar essentially
a slide up.
So we're going to drag it in.
You're probably using these if you've used an Android or iOS device before.
So we'll call this one the volume seek Bob and we'll stretch it out.
To the edge
of the screen.
So in constraints left and right there that's fixed.
Both
too it will change the width to match the constraints.
OK so if we just run that and see how the slider behaves we should be able to just drag it back and
forth
obviously we might be able to control anything with it as yet.
You may have forgotten the top constraint but you can see at least that is the effect that we want.
So our first challenge after we've had it back in the top constraint is to do something when the user
drags that slider along.
So let's add in some code to control it.
OK.
So we do this in the concreate method and we're first going to find Ceiba and we'll call it volume
control and we'll use good old fine V by ID.
ID dot
volume to predict is no kicking in successfully at the moment.
That's OK.
Volume seek by and
we'll cast it to seek above and then we take our volume control SIKMA and we set and on Seek bar change
listner which is exactly what you might think it is.
It listens for a change in the CGC by waits until the user moves the bar and then calls this method.
And within that method we want to define a new on Seek bar change listener.
And you can see that gives us 3 handy methods.
One is on progress changed.
That's the one we're going to be most interested in.
But we've also got on start tracking touch and on stop tracking touch.
So that's when the user touches the Zeba and that's when they stop touching MiSeq about.
For our purposes those are pretty irrelevant.
We only want to know when they change the seat about.
But in some cases you might want to do something when the user starts touching or stops.
OK so now let's just do a quick log to make sure everything looking OK.
So first we'll use the tags seek part changed but then we'll try to get the value of the Seeker.
You can see we've got an integer.
I bet that's actually the value of the Sikh bar.
So if we convert that to a string we'll be able to see it's value
in the logs every time we move it.
Let's take a look.
I play my ball will be in the right place now as well.
It looks a lot better.
Just select the right device
and they you can see it's changing has really got up and down and it changes from zero all the way up
to 100.
OK so that's the basic way to interact with sick ball.
Of course we don't want to do any actual logging.
We want to change the volume and we do that first by defining an Audio Manager which enables us to manage
the audio
more define it so that we can access it in any of these methods and then setting the volume is actually
pretty straightforward.
We just take out all Audio Manager and we set the stream volume.
You can see there's lots of other things you can control when you're working with Orio.
Don't play around with those.
But for our purposes we just want to set the stream volume and we need to put an integer in there.
Now the difficulty is these integer is not a number from 0 to 100.
And in fact it varies from device to device what the maximum volume is.
So we need to establish that before we can set it.
So we'll do that.
Up here we can create an integer called max volume which is going to be equal to the maximum volume
of the device that the app is running on.
And we can get that from Odeo manager don't get stream max volume.
And then there's a number of different maximum volumes that you might want to access all of which are
fairly self-explanatory.
We want the music max volume and then we can just set the maximum value for the CGC bar to be whatever
the max volume is.
So take volume control to access our symbol and then set max so it won't be 100 anymore.
It will be whatever how max volume is
and then we can set our variables for a set stream volume and the stream type as before is stream music.
The value that we want to set it to is all the and there are some other options that we could put in
there but we're just going to leave that as 08.
OK so now we should be able to use the seek bar to set the volume of the device or at least the music
part of the device.
Now we have a crash that let's not worry too much about it and find out what's going on.
So in the locks
in C we're attempting to invoke virtual method.
Get stream max volume I no object reference.
Aha.
So what's going on there is I've forgotten to set up my Audio Manager.
So I've created it as a variable.
But up here it's just a no variable.
It's the same era that I talked about in the previous video.
If we had tried to pause the audio stream before we'd set it up.
So I thought I'd leave that area in because it's quite useful to be able to look in the logs and work
out what it is that's going wrong.
And so to set up the audio manager
we just use
GET system service and then the system service that we need is the ordinary service.
But we do need to cast that to an ordinary manager.
All right.
So let's try that again.
Now we should be able to control the volume of the device
as we get.
I hope you had that.
So it's definitely working it's controlling the volume.
But obviously you've got one problem here that the slider's starting at zero.
But the volume is not initially at zero.
So we want to update the slide.
So it has the initial value of the current volume So let's take that as create a variable called current
volume.
And as you might imagine we're going to use a fairly similar code to the line before the Audio Manager
don't get stream volume.
And then again the stream that we want is music.
And then again we want to take our volume control slider and set the current position which is known
as the progress because it's kind of a progress bar.
There we go.
So now when we run the app we should find that it starts off with the current volume which I think was
at 0 rather unhelpfully before.
That's just
check.
The volume is working well.
It is.
So we're just going to restart the app just to make sure that it does set the bar to the current volume
level that we get.
So it set it to 100 percent there.
Wonderful.
So now we have a fully working volume seek.
Now we're going to add a second seek power which will be to actually seek back and forth through the
sound effects or of course music or whatever sound it is that's being played.
So that's that a second seat but I'm going to do it this way.
Just for a bit of variety.
At a bigger margin top so that it actually brings it down maybe even bigger than that
maybe even bigger than that that we get.
And we'll give it a new ID of scrubbing seek out or just scrub seek out scrubbing being a term for moving
back and forth within a sound or piece of music.
So a quick simple challenge for you.
Can you set up our Scrubb seek ball so that it's displays its value in the logs when it's moved up and
down.
Try to do it without looking too hard.
The code that we've got in place for the volume Ziebell go for it.
All right.
I like that wasn't too bad.
I'll set it up down here.
So as before we'll need to create a sick ball.
Call it scrub seek but this time
cast it to a seek by using find by ID card or ID score AB
seek power.
It's not finding it there or just see
it does seem to be that fleet will pick it up
when I run the app
Yep hit it.
So if you have that problem just run the app keep your fingers crossed.
And then we'll take our Scrubb seek power and will set and seek about change Lessner which is going
to require I knew on seek seek changelessness with those methods and when the progress is changed.
As before log
scrub seek
Naved and then
change the value to a string
and pop it in the box
let's have a look.
OK here we go.
And yet as before we get all the values pretty.
So there are a few things we need to change to make this work well and the first is to set the maximum
value of the Scrubb seek bar to be equal to the length of the piece of Odeo that's being played.
So we know how to set the maximum value because we did it here.
So we just use scrub seek power to upset Max and we want to set it to the length of the audio.
The audio is within Media Player remember.
So we can use Media Player and then get duration
OK.
So that would mean that we can scrub to the end of the song but no further.
What makes this a little bit more complicated than the volume seek bother is that we want this to update
as the piece of sound is being played not when the user actually interacts with it.
So we're going to have to regularly update this as the sound is being played.
So we need yet another new concept which is the timer.
So time allows us to do something every secondo every minute or every hour while our app is running
and we can grade them using new timer and at the time of class and we want to shed a lot time and there's
lots of ways that we can do that but we want to share it at a fixed
and within that we'll need to create a new time a task
that that's new task which ends there.
So we will define what we want to happen every second just before we do that.
Define when we want the timer to start that is now.
So 0 3 seconds 0 milliseconds in the future.
And we wanted to run every second.
So that is a thousand milliseconds so no delay and a period of a thousand milliseconds
OK.
And the thing that we want to happen is for the CGC bar to be updated to the new value of the current
position of the media player.
So we'll take our scrub seek but we'll set the progress to the current position of the media player.
And there it is.
OK.
So these timers are really useful.
And this is a good point to be introduced to them.
We should now see a seatbelt move by itself as the sound is being played.
Let's have a look.
There it goes.
So you can see the.
But perhaps for our purposes.
Every second was a little bit slower.
So let's try perhaps every third of a second or so.
That looks better.
Obviously the smaller you make the period the smoother it will be but the more resource intensive your
app will be used up battery life more quickly etc..
It's up to you to decide.
Balance there.
You also might want to start the schedule when the media player actually starts playing and stop it
when it stops playing as you won't need it.
Then if you want your app to be really efficient but I'll leave that as a challenge for you.
The last thing I'm going to set up here is actually make how seek but do some things so we want to affect
the current position.
When the Scrubb seek buy has moved back and forth and we can do that very easily using Media Player.
Don't seek to amend the value we want it to seek t is just the value of the seek ball.
So we can now control
the playing of the sound with the seek ball.
If I can grab it I would get sounds quite horrible.
And a note that is what you might want today.
If you heard that seeking whilst the audio is still playing sounds pretty horrendous so you might want
to pause the playing of the audio when the user starts interacting with the fake part and then unpause
it when they let go of the ball but only that as a fairly simple exercise for you.
Wonderful.
So when nearly done with with this section on animations audio and video which is going to take a brief
detour into the world of grid layouts to enable us to create the slightly complex layout for our final
app of this section which will be basic phrase it's.