All right the next step for us in this project is we have to have a way for the user to upload some
images.
And so we're actually going to start a separate project here so we can learn how to do this.
So while we have our current projects here we're going to go to file new project and started a completely
new one learn how to work with photos and we'll come back and implemented into our own out.
So the name for this one I'll maybe just go ahead and call it photo import demo tape and I'm going to
do this at the latest API you don't have to go that far in advance.
You can choose which one you want but I'll do that for this one.
And we'll go ahead and hit finish here.
So we'll go ahead and give Android studio a second here to get all caught up.
And basically Android has provided us a way to very easily go get photos from a user's device whether
that's photos they've taken or downloaded to their phone.
It makes it very simple to go and grab those.
And we do that through an intent.
So a user intends to move to our own activities that we've created.
But in this instance we're going to use activities to move to an android provided activity that's going
to allow us to go and pick those particular images.
So really the first step for us is we've got to go ahead and fill up the activity with him image view
so that after we pick one we can go ahead and fill that.
So we are going to be working with our main activity first and then like I said we want to be able to
fill that in.
And while it's taken a little bit of time here for the main activity lay out to pull up let's go to
the main activity and we can very simply write the code to get the intent so that we can go grab an
image and it's as follows we're going to make a new intent.
And I'll just call that intent.
We're going to say this is equal to new intent just like we've done before but this time we're going
to say we're going to have intent that we want all caps action pic.
So let's go down till we get to action.
Pick Oh I and realize we have to scroll a long way down to get that.
And there we go.
Action pick then we're going to provide that we need to go to this media store.
Think so.
When you say Capital Media store and enter on that and then we're going to do dot capital images dot
Capital Media dot and then an all caps onto external content.
You or I can.
So that's all it takes to get the intent.
And really once we have this we're going to do start activity and we're not going to do just a straight
up started activity.
We wanted to start activity for result.
So we're going to do the start activity for result.
We're going to pass in the intent.
And we're also going to be passing in a number here so we're going to go ahead and do the number one
this is do you remember before we were requesting permissions where you could add codes and stuff.
Well this is the request code so that you can keep track of the different results that you have.
So with that I bet our layouts are ready to go here.
Well just about.
And so instead of having this text you let's go ahead and grab an image of you know we're going to have
it take up the whole screen.
So for the background the default image I'm just going to have this fill up a color for the time being.
But with this image view let's go ahead and just set some constraints and I'm going to go ahead and
set all of these to zero so that we have an image that fills up the entire screen.
Excellent.
And we'll go ahead and adjust our constraints so that it actually goes edge edged edge here so we can
boom like that we have those nice pink color there.
Well some people might think it's nice.
Others not.
And let's go ahead and set the image you now we could probably just call image that's fine enough.
So with this in place we are now ready to start writing the code in order to go and get information
when somebody picks an image and in fact if you want to see what this looks like I'm going to go ahead
and get the emulator running here.
It's going to show us this activity that has been provided by the Android system but it's not going
to.
If we select an image it's not going to be able to do anything we need to write the code the code to
be able to handle that.
So let's go ahead and start doing that now while we're waiting for the emulator to come.
So just go ahead and start typing on activity.
Result is what we're looking for.
And then we go on activity result.
And this is the function that's going to be called when we get a result back from this activity over
here.
And so you know we have to write the code write the code to essentially get the image that they selected
and then choose something to do with it.
Looks like emulators ready.
So you'll notice when you get here there's no images and that's because this emulator doesn't have any
images.
And so it'd be hard to make an an immature app if we don't have any.
So what I recommend to do is you can you can go download an image if you want to.
If we do the camera button let's see if we can find the photo app here.
We should be able to just take our own camera.
So if you go to the camera all the emulators you want to get location.
Sure whatever.
All right.
So we've got that.
It's going to do this we're little square thing and if any time you take a photo it will take this little
square thing so that now if we were to go back and let's run this app one more time we could select
one of those images that won't do anything again because we don't have actually this function right
here.
This method that we needed to write some more for that's going to handle that situation.
But you'll see when our app opens up look now we have two items that we could potentially choose from
maybe I like the square here.
So I go ahead and I select that but it doesn't show up yet because we haven't written the code for that.
So the proper code that we need here is first we need to make sure it's the correct result that we're
looking for.
And so that has to do with this request code that we just made.
So we're going to first check and say OK request code.
Are you equal to one and the other thing that we're going to check is that there's this thing called
the result code.
It should be telling us that everything is OK.
So that was our request code.
We also have a result code.
We're going to see if this is equal to capital result.
OK.
And we also are going to be checking to make sure that the data that we got back is not equal to you
no.
I'm thinking of stuff with swift.
OK so we're going to make sure that the request code is one to make sure that's that one that we had
picked.
The result code is ok and that we actually have some data to work with.
Now if that's the case we're going to be working with some code that's going to require a try catch.
So let's go ahead and create one of those.
We'll be able to handle an exception here that we'll call e.
And let's just do the print stack trace if we have any sort of issue.
And then in our tri here we are going to create a bitmap from this data.
So we're going to make a new variable called bitmap and that we're going to go to media store dot images
dot media dot get that map.
Now while we are really going for this and then we're going to do this dot get to content resolver and
we're also going to pass in the selected image.
So we see that or not whereas our selected image how can that is.
Oh I forgot one step here so we need to create something called a u r i which is basically the location
of our selected images are selected and we sort of say you or I will call selected image and we're going
to set this equal to data to get data.
So with this now we can pass in the selected image for a semi-colon on that.
So after we have this bit map we can update the image you with it but that means we have to get access
to the imagery.
So we're going to do image view.
I'll just call it image view as equal to find view by ID.
Capitol art indeed.
Image you.
And then we can take our image view and say Dot set image bitmap and we will provide that map right
there.
OK.
So this should be the code that we need in order to take whatever image it was that was picked and have
it show up inside of that nice big image that we have so let's open up the emulator here.
And once this comes.
Go ahead select one of these images and we'll come back and boom.
Look at that.
We have this image showing up.
So I'm not sure why it's this way here in our app but most of the time if we're going to get into user's
photo we have to have permission to do that.
I'm not sure if the emulator just allows us to bypass that but we don't want to move forward without
being able to write the appropriate code.
So there's a couple of steps that we've got to do here.
The first one is we need to get into the manifest for our app and we want to make sure that that's a
use that we can access the user for so we're going to use permission.
And the one that we're looking for in this situation is we want to get to the read external storage.
So we're going to scroll down till we get to the Rs.
We want that read.
External storage.
So go ahead and close that up and once we have that in place then let's go ahead and start writing the
code.
We're going to be needing an X that only did a new line.
There we go.
That looks better.
So back inside of our main activity this is very similar to GPS.
When we needed to get permission you know we had to request it on the handle all the different situations
so we're going to go ahead and type out on the quest permission result.
In fact the same exact method that we had before but this time we're you know doing it with getting
the user's photo and we're going to say if we want to check that it's the proper request code so where
you say if requests request code is equal to one and then the next thing we want to make sure is that
you know we have access to be able to do this.
And so.
So that's first seen.
Did you know is this even coming for the right thing and if it is that we want to say OK if Grant results
length is greater than zero and Grant results at the first item is equal to package manager not permission
granted.
So that tells us that we got the proper information that we need.
So if this is all good then we're going to want to go and ask for the photos which we there's a couple
of times when we might want to do that.
So let's go ahead and make a new function here.
I'm going to say public void and I'll just call this maybe get a photo.
And with this we're basically going to do this code of you know start and make a new intent and start
that activity so we're going to go ahead and paste that in there and now that we have that in place
if we get permission then we're going to go ahead and type that here.
Say you know if we've got permission Let's go and get the photo and then the other situation you know
we want to do it in this on create.
But before we go ahead and do this get photo we would want to check first and see if we even have permission
so let's do an if statement here first.
So we're going to say if and the thing that we want to check for is check self permission and we're
going to pass in capital manifest permission.
Read external storage.
Remember that's the one that we're working with.
And so the location thing.
So we're going to say if this is does not equal package manager dot.
Permission granted.
So we've go ahead and we will do that check to see hey you know if they don't have permission we probably
need to go ahead and request permission so we're going to do I request permission and what we're going
to pass inside of here is a new String Array.
And we're going to do our curly brackets like we did before little say capitol manifest got permission
that Capitol read external storage.
The one that we asked for in the manifest.
So we'll go ahead and pass the request code of one.
So once we've gone ahead and done that we'll do an else statement here saying you know hey if it is
the case that they actually do already have permission then we'll just automatically call get photo
which we'll go ahead and start that in 10.
But if they have to ask for permission it'll go ahead.
Go ahead and do that.
And if it all works out there it's going to call this function where then we can appropriately say hey
if they gave permission then we can go ahead and get the photo.
So again this is some code that we need to make sure that this all works out with our app.
So let's go ahead and give this one last try and make sure everything's OK here and then we'll actually
have everything we need to move back to our Instagram app and get that up and rolling.
So here comes our app
and you can see now it's asking for access and we say allow you can still go to an image choose an image
so I'm still not 100 percent sure why it let us do it with out asking for that.
I can promise that's going to be the case on the device so you want to we really want to make sure we
have this code.
But this is enough for us to go ahead and move back to our project.
The Instagram app where we want to go ahead and add this code.
So there's a couple of things that we want to do here first and that happens to be the way that we want
someone to add a photo to this particular app.
And let's go back to our other project on just up the simulator there.
Go ahead and cut that out is we want someone to be able to hit the menu bar and be able to go and add
this so we're going to open up our project and we are going to add a new directory here.
So we're going to do a new resource directory and this is going to be for our menu.
So just go ahead and call it menu.
And then we're going to right click our menu here and say that we want to add a new menu resource file.
So we'll go ahead and just give this a name a share underscore menu and we'll have this and this is
going to allow us to put a little menu inside of our app.
So with this it's best to just go ahead and go straight to the text view of this.
And once we're inside of here there's really only one item that we want to add so we're going to add
an item.
And this is going to have the title solutes Android title is equal to capital share and we're also going
to say Android D.
Let's go ahead and set this equal to share just all lowercase and don't forget your app plus ID.
All right so with this in place we can go ahead and that tag and we go back to the design.
Look we get that nice little share functionality there.
That puts us in a good place.
Then we've got to go write the code in order to implement the menu option so let's go ahead and move
over to we want to do this instead of our user list activity.
So we're going to have to add a method up here at the top for the on create.
We want to do this for the menu so create an options menu.
And we go.
And with this we want to do this return eventually at the end so before we do the return we're going
to get a menu inflator we'll just call menu inflator is equal to our Get menu inflator and then will
inflate the menu.
So we're saying menu inflator dot inflate will pass and our menu Shearman you can.
So that's going to be all we need to get that.
Oh I forgot one parameter there and that's that we have to pass the menu parameter right there.
Then once we have that in place there's a couple of things that we're going to have to add to our permissions
here right because we want to access the user's photos so let's go ahead and open up in our Instagram
app the Android manifest and up here at the top you can see there's already some permissions here it's
asking for internet access access the network States and we actually already have read external storage.
So that came bundled with the project so we're good there but it's a good thing to check to make sure
you know that that is the case.
So now we're going to want to go back to the user list so when someone select something from the menu
the on options item selected gets called.
And so with this let's go ahead we're going to leave our return there at the bottom.
Well we want to do is make sure that they selected the share options so we're going to give an if statement
here.
And let's go ahead and check and make sure give ourselves some space to type.
We're going to see if the item get item ID is equal to capital our menu share menu.
So that's going to go ahead and tell us if this is correct and if we have that in not doing the proper
thing here not the menu we're looking for the ID actually of just straight up share that would be for
the actual share menu but this is what we're looking for so we're making sure they tapped on share.
So if that is the case let's go ahead and check and make sure that they have permission and in fact
the code that goes inside of here we've already written it.
So I'm just going to pull up the other project where we go ahead and check for permissions and then
you know if not we can go and request it.
So I'm just going to go ahead and paste that in there.
We're going to get a little air here because we don't have the photo code running.
So in that situation there's a few more things we'll have to go copy and paste.
So for example we are going to want to do this on request permission result.
We also want to know what happens when someone doesn't want to have that get photo cut so I'm just going
to go ahead and paste that in at the top of the project.
Excellent.
So with that in place that sort of settles the one air that we were having there.
And the next thing that we want to do is we want to sort of move around a few things so let's go ahead
and move down to this on activity result.
Let's see do.
Oh that reminds me we need to get the on activity results so when someone selects one of these we need
to actually go ahead and copy this code so we're going to copy this bring that into our project.
All right.
Yes go ahead and import all those things so you'll notice we'll get a little bit of an air here because
you know before when we were taking a bitmap of the image and we were trying to then go you know set
the image view with it.
In this case we're not trying to do that we want to eventually upload it to par so in this case let's
just go ahead and log that we got this Orsay image selected
and all tell ourselves.
Good work.
OK.
So give ourselves a nice little pat on the back.
Let's go ahead and run this and see if we can at least get the option to pick and imagine you know it's
not going to do anything as of right now it's just going to simply log this.
But the next step for us is you know we want to upload that to parse so we'll go ahead and give the
emulator here a second.
We really are close to getting to the end of this Instagram project now that we have the ability to
grab an image we just have to learn in this lecture how to upload that to parse and then we're going
to wrap everything up in the next lecture allowing users to not only upload images but also view other
people's images.
That's you know if you have an Instagram app and you can't see other people's pictures you know what's
the point.
I mean you're on Instagram you're trying to share your photos with the world so that's kind of the big
pull there and looks like we're taking a little bit of time to get this emulator up and running.
So while we're doing that I'm going to go ahead and get started on the parse code.
So it can get pretty complex.
To upload an image to parse but just go ahead and follow along with me in the code.
It's you know this is nothing that you have to have memorized like I had to definitely reference material
to make sure I was doing this correctly but once you kind of get in the flow of it it's not too bad
and looks like maybe I was explaining that the emulator finish so let's go ahead and try our menu option
for share.
Yes allow that.
Well go ahead and pick one of these.
And if that worked we should get the image selected.
Good work.
So open up blog cat and image selected.
OK.
So we know that that worked.
Now let's go ahead and dive in and upload our code to parse.
So the first thing that we need to get is a byte array output stream.
So go ahead and just call this stream and we are going to set this equal to a new byte array output
stream.
Excellent.
Once we have that in place we want to take that bitmap that we had just extracted earlier and we're
going to say bitmap dot and we want to compress this in so we're going to go ahead and take type out
capital map compress format and we get to choose how we want to do this.
So let's go ahead and you see there's Jay pagen and I haven't heard of wepe before but we're going to
use p n g.
So let's do that PMG.
Next is going to ask you for the quality here let's go ahead and do 100.
And then for the output stream while we already created one of those we'll go ahead and have that stream.
So this is just getting our image into the correct format here.
Once we have this then we are going to create a byte array.
So let's go ahead and just call this lowercase byte array and we'll set this equal to our stream dot
to byte array that's going to go and do our conversion there.
Then once we have that in place we're able to create something called a parse file.
So we're going to say capital parse file and we'll call the name of this file is equal to the new capital
parse file.
First we've got to go ahead and give this a name.
And so we're going to maybe just call this image of P and G and then we have to give it a byte array.
So we'll go ahead and pass in that byte array that we had created earlier.
Once we have that file in place next we want to create a whole object or class around this file.
So this is code that you've done before you should know how to do this.
We're just going to make a new parse object and with this we'll just give it the name of object and
we're going to say this is equal to a new parse object but the name of the class we're going to pass
through here is image.
So this is just going and creating something new here like we should see image showing up now inside
of our dashboard.
So back to android studio once we have that in place we'll take this new object that we have and we're
going to put some data into here so we're going to stay put.
And the first thing that we want to pass in is the actual image itself so we're going to pass the parse
file right inside of there.
And the next thing that we're going to pass are put on this object is a user name of who this user of
who this image belongs to.
So when I say put in all lowercase username and then we are going to go get whatever the current user
is.
So let me make sure I'm outside of the double quote there is say parse and I want Parsee user dot get
current user dot get user name.
All right so then I'll go get us whoever it is that took the image and as you know it was uploading
that so we'll have that information.
And now it's just like a regular parse object where we just say OK go ahead and save a background I'm
going to pass you a callback so in this case we're going to say you save callback and this will tell
us you know when it's all done so let's go ahead and do our normal checks where we say first you know
hey if each is equal to no.
That means that things have worked out.
In this case we should do a text message to the user to let them know that everything worked out so
do not make text.
We're going to go ahead and pass in capital user list activity.
Stop this and we're going to pass in a little message that says image has been shared.
Excellent point and then we're going to see how long this should last for I like to do the shorts and
we'll go ahead and show that to the user.
Now the situation here means something has gone wrong.
Right.
So we could do a print drak trace but I'd rather just do a text message.
Oh I forgot to add the extra equal.
But I'm just going to go ahead and do a toast message here that says you know hey we had some sort of
problem on the copy that tells from above and just change it to say something like there has been an
issue uploading the image frowny face can better spell uploading correctly.
All right so with this all in place let's go ahead and give this a try.
We'll run this on the emulator and we should be able to upload one of our images and actually see it
in the parce dashboard which is pretty great.
So go ahead and get our emulator here.
It is coming on the phone.
So look we can see the users and I'm currently logged in as John so I'm going to say you know what I
want to share an image and I want to share this lovely square box.
So I go and I pick that one and it says hey the image has been shared so if that's the case when I reload
here we should see image and then reload.
Look there's a new image class if we selected there's a new object given uploaded with the user name
of John that's a step in the right direction if we click on this PMG if we do download here we can actually
see the image.
Man how cool is that.
So there you have it we have in place now the ability to upload images to parse for a particular user
and now really just the next step for us is be able to view other users images.
We're going to go ahead and cover that in the next lecture.
It's the final one of the section.