All right.
Welcome to the very last lecture here in the Android where many course.
And what we're going to do is learn how to make watch faces.
This is my favorite thing because I think this is probably something you could spend the most time on
as far as making an app for the Watch what it is that the user is going to be looking at.
The risk most of the time and there's so much customization we can do.
So let's go ahead and give it a name here.
I'm just going to call it something pretty boring like my watch face.
And I mean you can decide what you want to call it but that seems fine for me and I'm going to go ahead
and make sure this is Android where I'm going to do the latest And next on this.
And you can tell so rather than doing a blank activity we want to do a watch face.
Make sure you have that selected.
So we'll just go ahead and call this my watch face for style.
I think digital is a little bit more fun than analog especially for customizing it.
It's going to be a lot easier to customize what is digital and you want to have interactive check there.
So I'll go ahead and hit finish and this will start up our project.
So with this there's really only one file that this whole app consists of quote unquote app.
And if we open up this app folder here and go into Java you can see a file called my watch face.
Now there's some other information here like in rez there's you know we've got some values here.
And you know we've also got some images and stuff like that.
But as far as like actual code it's really just this my watch phrase file and most of it's been written
out for you.
You can just see all this code that's been provided for you.
And there's great documentation here about how you can edit these things.
But first I want to just show you how you can test out a watch face so you can see if we want to try
and run this right now we're going to get in there and says hey the default activity is not found.
And so in order to fix this we've got to go up to app here and say configurations.
And with this default app selected under launch we're going to change from default activity to nothing.
So this says hey you know if you're going to be starting a new activity or whatnot we should be able
to just go ahead and open this game.
So once you have that set you can go ahead and X out of there and should now be able to run this
as I was about to say but it looks like it's not.
Oh for some reason my OK button was getting cutoff but it changed that to nothing and then hit the OK
or applied button down at the bottom.
So now that I've done that we should be able to hit run here.
I'm going to do this on my round device.
OK so let's go ahead and get that emulator up and rolling in here.
So we're going to wait until this finishes and I'm going to show you how you can add a new watch face
to your device because it seems to change every time there's a new update that comes out for the watch
operating system here.
But once it looks like that's finally finished you'll notice nothing really changes here and that's
because we said when it launches do nothing.
But if you go ahead and do a swipe from left to right here you're going to see this option to add more
watch faces.
So we're going to do that again and then click on this so you can see there's this elements analog elements
digital but also there's this one called my digital and that's in fact our one that we had just created.
So if we go ahead and click on this this is our watch face.
Now let's go ahead and walk through this.
My watch face file here and talk about the different things that we can customize so you can say you
know how often you want this thing to update here.
It's creating this new engine.
I mean this is also really kind of complex stuff that we don't really need to know all the specifics
of what's going on there.
But the real things that we can start customizing is you can see here like here's a calendar that's
going to handle all the time information for us.
Here's the thing that goes and gets the time zone that should be shown up you could make it so that
your app only shows up for one particular time zone.
There's a background paint and there's background text now it doesn't have to be just you know one color
or the other like you could add images here if you wanted to but probably just solid colors.
A good way to roll.
There's all these information about how you can have ambiant watch faces which can kind of save some
battery power.
And this is sort of the big method here the Create this is when everything gets set up just like in
other activity files right on create method.
And so you can see things here like where we're setting the background color.
And so right now it's just getting the default background color.
But if we wanted to change this for example like let's say we want to make the Christmas watch face
we could do a red color for the background and here for the typeface we could go ahead and change this
to be something like green.
So if we have red and green in there and we go ahead and run on our emulator Let's get this ready to
rock and roll the app should open up here.
Boom.
Look at that.
All sudden we're in this very ugly Christmas looking watch face here.
And we have you know some space down here that we get at other things if we want to do this on destroyed
basically just clears the cache whenever the user is switching away from your watch face.
So you can add some code there if you need to do some more complex stuff.
Other information about when things are changing into the timer and out of the timer and you know in
this case they're just updating the time zone to see if anything's working.
There are just all sorts of options that you can impact here.
Now I'm going to take you down to what I consider to be the most important changes here.
And so one of them is this on time tick.
And so this occurs as we had mentioned up above.
We had set the specification here to I believe every second or milliseconds here.
This was seconds.
So we have that.
And so it's updating every second and every second that it updates.
It comes down to this.
No I lost it this on time.
And so you could run some code that every second you want to change something and this invalidate function
is called which basically says hey you need to redraw the watch face and so if there's any sort of special
customization that you want to do you can do it here.
That's a really important one to know.
And then another one is on the on tap command if you want to be able to respond to the user touching
the screen.
You can you know put in custom code to handle that there but this one I think this is where you can
really get the most bang for your buck and that's that this is where we actually draw the time on the
screen.
And so there's two different options here the text if it's an ambient moan mode just shows the hours
in the minutes.
But if it's not it shows the hours the minutes and the seconds and we're not in ambient mode so that's
why we get all three of those.
So let's say for example we don't want to show out the hours cold and minute like we wanted to put a
dash in between those.
Well we could go ahead and do that we could put dashes there.
And now if we go ahead and hit run on this we should see our updates come up.
It looks like we had our updates but we're going to have to move to our watch face here.
Well it was until the left so I have to swipe to the left there and look at that.
All sudden now we have a dash inside the colon like there's a cool little customizations that we can
do you know here inside of this watch face which I just think is amazing.
So there's so many different options that you can cover here.
Another one that you might be able to just quickly change here if you wanted to was the typeface.
That's something that you could quickly get to but again completely up to you.
So I really hope you enjoyed learning about Android Wear.
Like I said at the beginning this is kind of a little mini course inside of this whole bundle and there's
this whole world of extra things that you go get into.
Android has excellent documentation on the where functionality and you can go check out all sorts of
new things.
But hopefully this was a good launching pad for you if you're interested in that.
All right.
Well I hope you enjoyed that.
We still have more for you.
So let's keep moving in the overall bigger course.