Hello and welcome to the lecture where we're going to learn how to download some web content so we've
been building up to this you understand what the try catch is.
Now we're ready to move forward.
So let's go ahead and start a new project so that we'll have a space to play around with.
And I'm just going to go ahead and call this project downloading better spell downloading correctly
downloading web content.
You can go ahead and use defaults for everything here.
And so like I said the big thing is we want to be able to learn how to download some web content so
I have a browser here with a Web site this happens to be mine.
And on any Web site it doesn't matter which one it is and in most browsers if you do a two finger or
right click you can get to inspect element.
I think it's easier to get to on Chrome on safari here I think you have to enable something.
Firefox should be easy too.
But basically there's this huge I mean all web sites are made from this thing called H.C. Amelle CSSA
javascript but it's just this huge big chunk of text that's here and so this is what we're going to
try and download the mail for some different Web sites and then from there we'll move forward with other
things like how to access web services from like Google Maps Facebook Twitter right.
Like anything where we can connect with that if it has an API We'll dive into that later.
That's sort of the big goal of what we've got going on here.
So with that let's go ahead and move back to android studio here.
Thank you for getting this project all up and running.
So in order to download some information we are going to do it in the background.
When I say the background we are going to do it on a separate thread.
And you're saying well what's a separate thread.
I don't even know these thread things are well just think about when an app is running on an Android
device there's multiple threads going on and the threads are where work happens.
So there's something called the main thread which is where if you don't specify otherwise all your code
runs right.
So when we have the app that you know the egg timer and it was keeping track and displaying the new
timer.
And I means it was checking in every 1000 milliseconds that was happening on the main thread.
But if for example you want to go download something from the Internet like the HCM mail from this Web
site you should do that in the background.
And the reason for that is if you go and try and get something from the Internet on the main thread
you have to say hey Web site what you know HD M-L do you have.
And if it takes you know two or three seconds to come back if you're on the main thread nothing can
happen during that time right like.
Users can't click on buttons they can't see animations happening just everything shuts down and so threads
are basically just where work happens in an app.
And if you do things on a background thread then you can come back with the results from that background
thread in the main thread update your UI with that.
So that's what Google recommends is that you do all your visual UI stuff on the main thread and if you
have to do any big intensive data stuff and that includes web requests that those happen on a background
thread.
OK.
So hopefully not to confuse with that.
Plenty of great content out there if you want to learn more but let me keep walking you through this.
So we are going to now create a class and don't worry too much about this class.
You can almost think through it as just a collection of variables and methods.
But we're going to use a create a new class in order to download some stuff from the Internet.
So just kind of follow with me here for a second.
We're going to say public class and we're not going to create a name for this class and we're going
to call it download task.
Now there's nothing special about this name but I just think it's appropriate because this class that
we're creating download task extends something called a sync task.
Now this is something where you want to make sure you get the correct one then hit enter on there so
you get everything imported.
And then we're also inside of our angle brackets going to say string comma void comma string.
And once we've got that in place we want to do our curly brackets but that's it.
OK.
So this download class or this download task.
It basically extends it borrows from this existing class called a sync task.
Google has written a ton of code to allow us to run things in the background quickly.
Now anything that happens with this download task can happen in the background.
So you see you've got an error if we hover over it with this red light bulb we want to implement the
methods that suggest this do in background so this is the code that we can have run in the background.
Now if you're wondering about what the string voyde string is well this is talking about what things
we can pass into this download task and you know how it's going to handle it what it's going to pass
back.
And basically there's an opportunity here with this void thing in the middle with some functionality
but by saying void we're kind of just excluding that for now.
But the string here on the beginning and the end this is saying hey we can pass in a string and we can
pass out a string.
So the basic idea would be we would pass in a u r l and then we would get back the h t m l for that
right as a string.
That's sort of you know we'd put that into the download task and we'd get that back out of it.
So you also might be wondering with this protected string doing background like what's going on here.
Well protected is pretty similar to public.
The basic idea with protected is that it's available throughout this whole package.
So essentially your whole app you can get access to this so this is very important if you're doing things
on the background you want other classes to be able to work with it.
So that's why this project is important.
And then we've got this string dot dot dot strings and you might be wondering what this is.
And this is a way to essentially create an array it's not technically an array if you want to learn
more about it you can go look at our vars on the internet about this but it's basically a way to add
in as many strings as you'd like and then work with them if you want to as far as accessing information
from here.
It's basically like working with an array.
So the idea with this is let's go ahead and do this in the uncreate I want to show you an example of
how this might work.
So let's make a new download task object here we're going to say download task and call this task and
say this is equal to a new download task.
And with this we'll just go ahead and put our semi-colon and then with our object task we want to go
ahead and go with this and run some code.
So we're going to say task thought execute.
Okay.
And this is where we're going to pass that information.
So for example we are going to pass it a string and this should be that your all of what we want to
go grab a copy that you're in I'll come back and paste it there.
OK.
And let's go ahead and do our semi-colon here so this will then come through here.
This into this method does do in background.
And then if we want to get some information back out of here.
Well we need to return it here so maybe we return something like done to say that you know we were able
to successfully process some information.
Now it kind of just confirmed that this works and I'm going to go ahead and get the emulator rock'n'roll
in here because it might take a second to fire up but if we want to display some information and confirm
that we were able to get this string to come out here we would probably want to do a log.
So let's go ahead and say log I.
And we're just going to simply display what the u r l is.
So we're going to say you are all comma and then we want to provide what you are.
So we're going to say strings.
Square brackets 0.
So again this string ellipses here essentially think of this as a string array.
And when we say string 0 or say and we want to know the very first item there and if we're wondering
like well what other you know can we pass multiple things in there.
Yes we can.
So the idea with this is that we could essentially say OK there there's one you're L maybe will pass
another your l of like Google dot com.
Maybe you will pass another your l of stack overflow.
Dot com I mean we can just keep adding as many strings as we want and if we you know pass through here
strings would contain three different things.
But if we you know only limit that to zap B code Dotcom's string.
Then there's only one item in there and we can get to that by passing in a zero index.
So that's basically what's going on there.
Now before we go ahead and move forward.
Remember when we learned about the try catch Well we have to be able to put a try catch around this
execute because we don't know for sure whether it's going to work out right.
All sorts of situations about maybe I'll just never hear back from the server where you request this
Web site.
Maybe you're going to have the issue that the users internet's not connected.
There's all sorts of different things that could happen here.
So what we want to do is we want to wrap this up inside of a trial so we're going to go ahead and put
a try there.
And then let's go ahead and add a catch as well.
We're going to say we are looking for just a general exception and typically we call that he doesn't
have to be.
But I think that's probably a good name for it.
And if we do get an exception Let's go ahead and log that let's say log dot and say exception and then
we'll go ahead and provide the actual exception.
So we'll just go ahead and say me and maybe we'll see a print stack trace and that's going to give us
some more.
Oh well that doesn't give us let's see if we can do a two string.
No.
All right.
Well maybe what we'll do that instead is if we just do eat up print stack strict eat print stack trace.
This essentially prints out and logs whatever air there is.
So this is probably the better way to work with this.
OK.
So let's go ahead and run this again.
All we're hoping to see is that we can see what the U R L is and then it's going to try and execute
this and if there's an issue we're going to get you know see the stack trace here.
But if not it should run just fine.
OK.
So we'll go ahead and fire this up and we'll wait for this to open Kang here comes the app and let's
go ahead and scroll through here see if we got that.
You are all showing up anywhere.
I don't see it right now.
So I don't see the exceptions so I'm wondering whether this got run will go ahead and try that one more
time because we should have your L being logged right there.
Try this one more time.
And again we come down.
I'm not seen oh there it is it was right in front of my face your L's at Cocom.
OK so we successfully know that that code is being run but you might be saying Well where do we get
this done information.
Well what we can do is we can actually take the information from here and put it into a variable So
let's say let's make a new string and we'll call this result you know kind of saying this is what we
are getting back from the URL and we'll say result is equal to this.
Excuse me we've got seven deleted tasks so result is equal to the task.
Execute.
And the issue that we're running into here is we have to add a dot get at the end this goes ahead and
grabs whatever it is the string that we're going to be returning here which in this case is done.
So let's go ahead and once we get that result back we'll go ahead and log this out.
So we'll just go ahead and say Lagat say result and we'll go ahead and pass in whatever the result is.
There we go.
OK.
So let's go ahead and run this.
It's not liking what I have here that's the result might not have been initialized.
We have to set it equal to something and actually so let's go ahead and set it equal to no.
That way we know if we don't get something back right if there's an error in the exception in the stack
trace comes right then we will know about that.
That will say result no.
But let's go ahead and run this.
Now look at that we are so much happier now this time.
And here it comes.
So we've got to go back to log cat over here but we can see we got the you are able to print out there
just like we did before.
And then we also got results done printed out so this kind of just proves that we were able to run some
code in the background now.
It was very simple code right we didn't download anything from the Internet.
We literally just passed a string here into this function.
We printed out that string essentially with this log and we return back none which we put in this result
and then we logged out result that's all really did.
So let's go ahead and take things a step further.
Let's make it so we can actually go reach out on the internet try and grab the contents or whatever
you are as we pass through here and then get it to show back.
So in order to do this let's go ahead and do a little work on this do in background method and here's
what we want to do.
So we're no longer logging out information we're going to say that we're done with that but we do want
to do here is we want to start setting up something.
So eventually at some point we want to return a result.
So we're going to make a string that we're going to call result and initially we'll just set this thing
equal to an empty string.
Ten other things that we need is we need to get an actual u r l object so I've referred to your l a
few times but I mean really what we have is a string that is a u r l but like in Java there's an actual
u r l object where you need to convert a string into a your L object and I'll show you how to do that
conversion.
So we're going to create a variable called u r l lowercase there and then we need something called an
h t t p u r l connection.
There we go just like that.
And then what we're going to do is say the name of this is u r l connection.
Excellent.
And we will set this equal to know for the time being.
So think of ACP your L connection as a way to it's like a browser just like we have Safari here where
we give it to your L and it goes and shows us the information in HTP your connection does the same thing
and we can go grab the H.T. mail back from that.
The big difference is that a browser can turn it into this cool looking thing whereas in our app we're
just going to simply get the text from there.
So the first thing that we want to do is you want to try to convert your L that comes through here into
a actual You are l object so to just make this a little bit easier.
Right now the name for this parameter is strings.
Let's go ahead and call it you are Elle's because it's possible that multiple would come through here.
And what we want to do is we're going to make a new york object and inside of here we're going to pass
the first item in the you are Elle's quote unquote array.
I know it's not an actual array but I will go ahead and grab that.
And let's put it inside of r u r l object so we're going to say OK U R L is equal to this.
And you'll notice we get an error here and that's because this might not work out.
We not all strings can be turned into a U R L So for example if I forget the H TDP and the B W and I
just pass this this would not successfully pass.
And same as if I just like if this was just the number four that wouldn't turn into a U R L is not valid.
And so if it doesn't work you know there would be an exception and we have to handle that.
So it's kind of cool we can go ahead and just click on the surround try catch and it actually handles
all of this for us.
So I think this looks pretty good.
I would maybe just change this to a general exception because I just want to say hey whatever exception
comes our way.
Just go ahead and print that out.
We don't need to get too specific there.
So we've converted our string into a u r l.
The next thing that we want to do is we want to create a u r l connection.
So remember we had provided this name here but we actually want to make u r l connection.
So we're going to say we want to have r u r l dot open connection can and we have to specify the type
that this is going to be and we say hey this is going to be an H P or L connection just kind of cast
that as we go through.
Then we need to create something called an input stream so the input stream is just going to be able
to gather the data as it's coming through as it's hitting.
So we're going to say input stream and we'll call that in.
This is going to be equal to r u r l connections get input stream and connected with that.
Not only do we have to have an input stream but we need to have an input stream of readers so this is
going to be able to actually read the data or just call that one reader simply and will say this is
a new input stream reader and we have to pass in our input stream in here in order to create that.
After that we want to actually go ahead and read some data from there so we're going to say reader Scott
Reed and you can see this gives us back an int which is a little bit curious you might be saying hey
how is this going to work.
But this is its way of giving us each individual character in fact when we go through this input stream
we have to go character by character to get our information.
So we'll just call this data we're going to say make a new event called data and it's going to be equal
to whatever we just read that sort of gets the very first piece of data that comes through.
And this is where we get a little bit tricky as we're going to create a wall loop where we say OK walde
data is not equal to negative 1.
We'll do our curly brackets here.
We want to run some code.
And basically what we're doing here is we're going to want to say data is equal to reader dot.
Read and read basically moves on to the next item.
And it basically data could be equal to 1 2 3 4 5 6 all the way up and it's just the way that it converts
it back to a string you'll see here in a second.
But if it's ever equal the negative one that's the reader's way of saying hey we're done we got to the
last thing.
So that's why this keeps running Intel data is equal to negative one at which point it will not go through
the while loop anymore.
So we've got to turn this data into a character so we're going to say char current is equal to the data
and we need to cast this through that is coming through a char just like that.
Then what we're going to do is we're going to say result.
Remember this is our string that we had up there we're going to say result plus equals current.
So that just adds a character onto it so it's just letter by letter.
For example if we go to here on Zappy code like it's going to do this angled bracket then an exclamation
point then a capital D then the capital O then a capital C and just letter by letter character by character
it's going to add it onto the results string.
And this reader not read that sort of moves on to the next one.
So after this while loop is done running we are going to go ahead and return the result.
We'll go ahead and type that out and that's it.
So this is going to go do all of our information for us hopefully get to you or else successfully.
The one thing we do want to fix is right now we're returning done.
We either want to return the e-mail or we want to return something that says like hey this didn't go
right.
So we're actually going to get rid of this return and we're going to put a return inside of this catch.
So after we've printed out a stack stack trace we're going to say return failed just like this and this
is basically our way of saying hey something don't go right.
You've got to figure that out.
So we currently have the code to take whatever it spits back to us and logged that out which means we're
in a good place.
So let's go ahead and run this and see what we get.
And I just thought of something that we're going to get on the air with but maybe it will be good to
see the air and then we can go ahead and roll through there.
Okay opened up and.
I think this is the big issue.
Yeah.
And this is what it is.
Permission denied missing Internet permission.
So on Android If someone's app if a user downloads an app and that app wants to connect the internet
GPS GPS whatever it is you've probably seen this before and it has to ask permission from the user to
say hey is it OK if I go do this.
So we have to you know state that we want that permission from the user so if we open up our project
structure here and we go to the Android manifest we can go ahead and add this permission.
So above application but below manifests here we are going to ask for a user's permission.
And there's all sorts of different ones here.
But we want the one for the Internet so there is a whole lot if you scroll down though you can find
the one that says Android not permission.
Internet.
And then we have to make an ending tag for that.
But this basically when the app opens up especially if you push this the Google Play store it's going
to say hey can we get this app use the Internet.
And you know at that point the user would have to say yes if they wanted that to go through.
But let's go ahead and run this.
That should fix our issue that we had.
And I should get Lague get up and running here so we can see what we get and see the app is opening
up here.
And so far nothing here.
I guess it's taken a long time to go grab this information and look at this.
So here you see this big chunk of Texas doc type H.C. mail had met go in and doing all this stuff that
eventually went out and got all this information and it printed it out into the result here.
So we'll you can see it is really long at some point.
So that means it worked.
So I hope you enjoyed learning about that.
We took our try catch though we kind of learned in a theoretical sense and then actually applied it
to a real situation where you know hey there could be a whole lot of things that go wrong in this situation.
But we made it all work and were able to successfully print out some HD mail.
Now there's all other sorts of things that we can do much more advanced that you just covered I know
things got a little intense here with some of this reader stuff but there's even better ways that we
can handle this and we'll talk about that in the future but the next thing that we want to talk about
is how we can actually go download images from the Internet so that bit by bit you're going to keep
learning these skills about working with downloading data.
It's going to be great.