Get into Chapter 4 of the complete and redevelop course in which we'll be looking at animations sound
and video.
But before we do that in this first video we're going to take a few moments to consider lay out in a
bit more detail as this is primarily a development course we focus more on the code than the actual
look of our apps.
Of course the look is important as well.
So in this video I'm just going to show you a few tricks to get your apps looking the way you want them.
And first is to bring your attention to the constraint lay out in Android Studio 3 this is now the default.
Whereas an android Studio 2 it was a relative layout and we use constraints over here to decide exactly
where they're going to display on the screen.
So just to clarify if I get rid of that text and bring in a button I can position this scented or near
the margins of the screen but if I just leave it there it won't actually be centered on the app as we
saw in a couple of the videos in the previous section.
So it will jump to 0 0 i.e. the top left.
So if I wanted to actually send to this I need to add left and right constraints as well as a top constraint.
And a bottom constraint to center it in the app.
Now if you're more familiar with relative layout we can use those instead.
So if you look down the widget palette to layouts and you can see here we have the good old relative
layout so we can drag that in and that will then exist within our constrained layout.
And that just changes the rules slightly of how things are laid out within the relative layout.
So if I now bring in a button wherever I drag it it will be positioned according to the nearest margins.
So if I leave it there it will be positioned relative to the top left of the screen.
Here be positioned relative to the top right et cetera.
So that's how the default used to work in our studio.
So if you want to get back to that you can know that you still need to add constraints for the relative
lay out because it's within the constraint lay out its position.
Our button near the top left
somewhere like that.
And now I'm going to show you the text tab at the bottom there.
You may have noticed that and I'm wondering what it is.
Well the text tab uses SML describe.
Lay out there if you come from web development you might think of this a bit like an h t m l document
describing the layout of a web page.
And if you prefer working with text or code rather than dragging and dropping you might be more comfortable
creating your layout using this SML and it does have integers.
For example if I want to have a button that has exactly the same properties as this button that already
exists rather than creating it afresh and adding all the properties I can just copy and paste the code
for that button.
And it will appear now you might not be able to see it there.
That's because it's positioned relative to the relative layout i.e. the parent and it's exactly the
same number of pixels from the top as the original button was.
So you'd need to add for example a greater margin at the top to move it down.
Note that when you do use copy and paste you'll get two items with the same ID which will cause a problem.
So you'll need to change the ID of one of them for example to button to and button three.
Now just to show you how these two relate i.e. the design and the text view.
If for example I wanted my button to be positioned relative to the previous button rather than to the
relative layout I can drag it around and you can see that our power now points to the button above.
So this button is now positioned relative to the other button.
If I move the top button down then the other button will move with it.
And this is reflected in the text because in the original button you can see it's aligned to the left
of the parent whereas this one is aligned to the left of button too.
And of course you can update the attributes of your elements directly here.
So if we wanted a full width button we could just change the width to match
parents and we'll get a nice full width button that OK.
So there's a lot of things you can do here a lot of ways that you can lay things out.
It's very very flexible.
I'm just going to show you one nice trick which will use later in the course and that is if you want
two items next to each other centered on the screen that can be a slightly tricky thing to work out.
In fact if you want to give it a try.
Pause the video and try and have two buttons positioned next to each other so that they're both centered
together on the screen.
Give it a go.
Did you manage it.
Probably trickier than you thought it might be but a nice way to do it is to use this linear layout
here which simply lays things out from left to right.
So let's just get rid of existing buttons.
And then bring in a horizontal linear layout.
Centuri for now.
We're going to change the size in a minute and then let's bring in our buttons and put them inside the
linear layout.
So there's one you can see it's stretched to full width fab.
But if we squeeze in another one then within the horizontal linear layout it will always lay them out
from left to right.
So if we want those to be centered on the screen we can take our linear layout and change the width
instead of being full width.
We'll change it to wrap the content.
So it's just the width of the buttons.
And we'll also change the height to wrap content as well.
And now we've got a centered Sedgley centered horizontally and vertically linear layout containing two
buttons which might be something like
a cancel button and an OK button.
Something that is a very common use case for the buttons next to each other.
So using sub layouts like that can be a very useful way of positioning objects within your app exactly
where you want them.
There's a few other types of course as well.
We've got the vertical linear layout which is exactly the same thing but vertically a grid lay out which
is the same but a bit more flexible and frame and table layouts as well.
All of which will use at various points later in the course.
So feel free to play around with these and try and create a nice layout for your app but for now we're
going to go back to working with media and we're going to start with looking at how to create animations
in Android.