All right.
So I'll go ahead and get the section all started by talking about what it is that we're trying to build.
So we're trying to build little Instagram clone and if you don't know what Instagram is it's an app
where you can take some pictures.
Post those other friends can see them.
I mean we're going to build a simple version of Instagram if we were trying to build the actual real
deal we need like you know a team of hundreds of developers and millions and millions of dollars to
do that.
But it is pretty amazing with you know using technology like parce and androids to you we can get fairly
far with just working by ourselves.
So anyways this is the end goal of what we're moving towards.
Now I kind of mentioned Parsa before.
Parce is a place for us to make the whole back end for app.
We're going to store our photos there.
We're also going to have you know some communications about like creating user accounts and whatnot.
So to get access to parse and learn more about it go to parse dot com.
This is going to force you to parse platform or so parse was a company that helped you build the back
ends for apps whether you're making an Android app an iPhone app.
I think even worked with like Windows Phone and then Facebook acquired them and then Facebook decided
at some point that they were going to shut this part of the business down and so they kind of gave everyone
some time to get their apps off of parce but then they decided to open source parks.
And so it's been pretty interesting now all the parks has been open sourced and people have been updating
it on their own which is pretty great to see and the awesome thing about parce being open source now
is that if you want to run this parce on your own server it is completely yours.
Right.
Like there's no chance of Facebook shutting this down or you know Google they have firebase of them
shutting that down like if you use parce server that is now open sourced or on your own server you are
in complete control of it.
So it's obviously hasn't seen as many updates you know as it did before when you know there was a dedicated
team working on it with money behind it.
But still pretty impressive that you can get all this functionality in this very awesome open source
project.
So anyways this is what we're gonna be working with and there's all sorts of great tools there.
The next thing is you know where are we going to host this content rank.
I said we need to save it onto a server.
So we are going to be doing that on the world's most popular hosting service and that's Amazon's Web
services so you might have heard it before it's commonly referred to as AWOS.
So just go to AWOS dot Amazon Dot com.
Jane this is where we're going to go ahead and get all signed up and everything.
And so again this is where we're going to host the server code is on a server here from AWOS And what's
awesome about AWOS is they have a free tier where we can run our app and not have to pay for anything
because it's going to be such a small footprint.
So anyways go ahead and get moving forward by creating an AWOS account.
Go ahead and plug in your information and then I'll rejoin you once you're finished with that.
So while you're signing up if you're concerned when they prompt you to put in some credit card information
they say hey we're not going to charge you unless you break the free tier if you want to know more about
the free tier.
Go to AWOS on Amazon.com slash free and go ahead and show you everything here.
So Amazon E.S. is what we're going to be working with.
And as you can see you get 12 months of free here so.
Pretty awesome stuff.
But anyways.
Yes.
Just wanted to kind of if you're having concerns like I'm not sure if I want to put in this information.
Here's more information about the free tier which we will definitely be working inside of.
All right once you are signed in.
You want to go up to the top here to services and we want to click on E.C to the stands for elastic
compute 2 and basically the idea here is that it's going to be the server that can run the parse code
that can grow and shrink as needed.
So with this let's go ahead and click on launch instance this is going to start a new two server with
that.
There's all sorts of different starting points for your server that you can come from.
But we want to go to the AWOS marketplace here and we are simply just going to do a search for PARSE.
So go ahead and search for PARSE and we want to get this parse server powered by bit NAMI.
So go ahead and select this and once you're here go ahead take a look at you know the different hourly
fees that are there.
Like I said for we're going to be working within the free tier free tier eligible to go ahead and hit
continue there.
Now you want to make sure that you have this T-2 micro the one that says free tier eligible.
We'll go ahead and move forward with that by saying review and launch.
Okay.
So just go ahead and hit that now.
Once you have this in place you just want to you know kind of confirm here that this is what we're looking
for PARSE server powered by bit NAMI and the awesome thing about this is it basically launches a server
with this parse server code all ready to rock and roll which is pretty great.
So we'll go ahead and hit launch.
Now once we do this we're going to have to create this key pair.
And so once you see this in place what we're going to do is first come here and say we want to create
a new key pair.
When we got to give it a name.
So let's just go ahead and call this Instagram Android or something like that there's nothing magical
about that name you just have to pick something.
And once you have that go ahead and hit download key pair so that you have this on your computer you
can see we've got that as a text file.
And there once we have it let's go ahead and say watch instance can pull this will go through and get
everything set up.
This will take a little bit of time here so I'm going to go ahead and restart the video once this is
finished.
Now once you have that finished go ahead and click on this link so you can look at your instance.
If you ever get lost you can always go back to services and then go to YouTube and click on the you
know should be only one instance that you have running now.
And once you're at this place then we want to go ahead and hit this connect button because this is going
to allow us to log into the server which is basically just a computer that Amazon's hosting for us that
has all this parsed code on it so go ahead and hit the connect button.
Now there's two options here.
There's a standalone S-sh client and a Java S-sh client and you're saying well what's an S-sh client.
Well a S-sh client allows us to communicate with the computer and it does it via text so if you've ever
used the terminal on a Mac I'll go ahead and open it up here.
This is also like the command prompt in Windows where you just via text are interfacing with the computer.
That's how you work with your server here on A.W..
So unfortunately the Java client really doesn't work as well as it claims to be so we want to go ahead
and use the standard standalone S-sh client so you're going to have to find one on your computer so
on the Mac it's the terminal.
So if you go ahead and do a command spacebar to open up spots spotlight just go ahead and search for
terminal.
And if you're on Windows I would recommend using something called puttee.
And luckily they have a link to it here which is pretty great.
So with this in place let's go ahead move forward.
The one thing that we do want to check is that the file that we had downloaded was downloaded as a dot
text.
He might have been I was a little bit concerned about that.
So let's go ahead and switch to this to date added PEM that text so I'm going to remove just the text
on the end of our downloaded file.
And in fact we're going to keep that is dropped him and I'm going to go ahead and move that to my desktop
so I can easily access that.
OK.
So once we have that in place we're just going to go ahead and follow the instructions that we have
here.
So again remember you're going to have to you know tweak this according to your situation.
But on the Mac here let's go ahead and open up the terminal.
So the first thing we've got to do is get to where our keys are.
So we're going to ours are on the desktop so I'm going to say CD which is short for change directory
space Capitol desktop.
And if we do that we should see that it's moved us into the desktop and we want to do an ls and hit
enter.
That shows you all the files that are in the current directory that you're showing and there's that
Instagram Android PIMs So we know OK we're in a good place.
So once we've done that we want to run this code to make sure that we're going to be able to access
this so we're going to do the S.H. maade 400 for the instagram pen and now that we're in the correct
place we'll just go ahead and hit enter on that.
Then we want to use copy this right here.
And well might as we'll copy this whole thing because this is going to allow us to log into our instance
here so we're going to go ahead and copy this line of code.
Go ahead and paste it in there.
It's going to say are you sure that you want to connect to this.
I'm going to say yes.
And if you see this screen this means that you have successfully been able to connect and you are ready
to rock and roll.
So once you get to the screen we need to move in to where the parts code is to kind of do some setup
so inside of now which is our server AWOS we're going to say CD space apps slash.
This is all lowercase parce slash H.T. docs just like that.
So go ahead and hit enter.
Next we have a file that we need to edit.
So we're going to use vi here which is going to allow us to edit this code so we can say Vi server dot
J.S. all lowercase there.
So go ahead and hit enter on this.
This is going to bring up a screen here where we can go and get all these different pieces here.
So there's you know like an app idea master key We're going to need all of this in order to connect
so once we have this in place where we're in a good position here there's something else that we've
got to go grab.
So open up a new tab in your browser and we need to go and get something from Rob's Web site so we're
going to go to Android of course dot com.
And then once we've done that we are going to do lowercase parce project dot zip and just go ahead and
hit enter on that.
That should prompt a download that's going to come to your computer so this is just an android studio
project that's sort of a starting point for you to move forward with it's got the parts code all ready
to rock and roll and so it just kind of saves us one extra step in working with us.
So we're going to go ahead and once this is finished downloading then we'll have find you here ready
to take our folders so I'm going to move this to our desktop for the time being.
And once you're inside of here you can see this is just like any other you know project that we've opened
before so if we go ahead and get Android studio opened up we can use it to open up this project and
move forward from there.
So give Android studio a second to load here.
And this is bringing up our last project that I was working on so we'll close that out.
Now I want to do open an existing Android studio project will point to the desktop and will say open
that and into a studio SDK.
OK so it's saying it's going to be putting that in the new location.
Okay that sounds good to me.
So we'll wait for this to pop up.
So when the project opens up you might not have the same build tools that the project has.
So if not you want to go ahead and just click install build tools and Android studio will go through
and get you all the right pieces of information that you need in order to get that up and running.
So whatever prompts you need in order to get this moving you just want to go ahead and move forward
with those.
But and look it already finished up there so that's pretty great.
And while this is opening up.
So let's talk about the code that is inside of you and I'm going to open this up so you can kind of
see what we've got inside of here so is a typical main activity that you'd like have in any other place
and it looks pretty standard except we've got this parse analytics.
And yes let's go ahead and do an update here.
But this parse analytics and this is going to essentially allow us to do some checks on our code to
see how many how much a user is using the app and stuff like that.
But the real interesting stuff here is in this starter application because this has some code that allows
us to connect to a parson you know down here we're going to create some objects that we're going to
put in that parse server and you know try and get them and read them back.
And so with all of this we've got to then plug in some stuff like the application ID client key server
all that good stuff.
So luckily we have all this information inside of our terminal.
So we just need to go ahead and move forward with entering that information.
So the first one is the application ID.
You can see we've got an app ID here so don't get the double quotes but go grab that huge string of
letters and numbers and we're going to go ahead and paste that into our app.
Android studio here is taking a second so let's see.
Try and update get through some of our issues there but I'll go ahead and paste that one in the next
one that we need is the client key.
So this is going to be what's the file key.
Make sure you don't do or the Master Key don't do the file key so we're going to copy the master key
and we'll go ahead and paste it there.
All right.
And then the last one that we need is the server.
So and we've got more errors here.
So and support and let's open up a terminal here we want to get the server your l.
So grab all of that including the HTP all the way to parse and we'll go ahead and paste that in.
And the one kind of additional bonus thing that we need to add is a slash here on the end of the code.
So with this in place we now successfully have everything that we need in order to connect to this parse
instance.
And so what we're going to do is we're going to run this and see if we can get this code to run and
if it works successfully it's going to log some information on to or it's going to save some information
onto the server and we'll actually be able to via a web browser check that everything worked.
And you know move forward from there.
So let's go ahead and hit the start button here.
We're going to have to pick a device to work with.
So go ahead and use this and I'll come back and start the video when the emulator is ready to rock n
roll.
Well I guess actually while it's going we can talk about how we can get to the correct u r l in order
to check out the code.
So what we're going to do is go back to our code or even the terminal here.
We just need to be able to get to this parse location so we're going to go ahead copy whatever the L
is and we're going to paste this in and after this instead of doing the slash parse we are going to
do slash and we're going to just type in apps just like that.
So if we go ahead and hit enter on that you can see this then brings us to a log in page here for the
parse server now to log in the username is just user or that set by default.
Now the password is something a bit NAMI has created for us and they've actually spit it out in the
logs but it takes a little bit of work to go find that.
So we're going to go to our SETI Management Council page and we'll x out of this.
And on our instance page we're going to go to actions instant settings get System log and if we click
on this this has got a ton of information about when it was all set up and stuff.
And what's been happening on that server.
But if we keep scrolling we want to look for a box like this says setin bit NAMI application password
to follow.
And so we want to go ahead and just copy this code and it might be worth it to you know somewhere in
your Android studio project maybe leave this as a comment so that you make sure you remember this.
You can go oh looks like and copy this right click copy if you want to go and change his password to
maybe something more secure and a something that you would actually remember.
But with that we can go back to the parce dashboard go ahead and paste that in and log in.
So there you can see my bit Namli bit NAMI parce API that's all there.
That's right.
Rock n Roll.
Let's see if our emulator opened up and yes it did.
So that's a good starting point.
We'll go back to android studio.
Let's go ahead and check log cat because we had said if things are successful here we should say successful
along that Parsa result.
Successful So we know that it worked here at least in the code but to really confirm that everything
worked here we're going to go into back to the project here.
Click on this and we should see if we go check out this thing called example object something that says
Rob.
One two three.
And the awesome thing about this is if we go back to our code this is the thing that we put in over
there we said we're going to make something called Rob with one two three and we're going to save this
to the server and look it is there.
So you may be saying this.
OK we got it up and running.
You know whatever.
I can't tell you how big of a deal this is that we have it up and running.
I've tried to make my own back end servers for my apps before and I've written them from scratch rather
than using something like parson.
Holy cow what a drain that was trying to get things up and running.
And the fact that we are here were able to work with parce.
It's a great starting point to just keep rocking with the rest of the app.
So we still got more to do but the fact that we're here is a great starting point.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next one.