Hello and welcome to the section on Bluetooth we're going to go ahead and walk you through how to create
a Bluetooth app in Android.
Now let me go ahead and give a little bit of background about Bluetooth what it is how you can use it
Bluetooth allows you to make a quick connection between two devices that it's typically thought to be
a short range communication.
So sometimes Bluetooth communication can only go a couple of feet and sometimes it can go hundreds of
feet it really depends on what type of devices you're using and what version of Bluetooth it is that
you're working with.
But we'll typically see Bluetooth used for things like audio for example.
So if you've been in a car that has Bluetooth technology and you can stream Bluetooth music via Bluetooth
from your phone to the car's audio system and then it you know will play there.
We see that with bluetooth headphones and that definitely seems to be the way that things are moving
forward more and more as phone companies seem to be getting rid of that headphone jack because they
just say you know what.
Maybe the whole thing should be wireless.
We don't have room for a headphone jack.
And that's kind of the trend that we see there and also you see it in health products.
So whether it's Android Wear the Apple Watch a pebble I'm trying to think of some of the other fitness
smart watches out there but things that can track your heart rate GPS GPS whatever it is.
Those are commonly communicated back to your phone through Bluetooth.
My favorite one in my house is I have a Bluetooth scale so I can weigh myself and automatically the
scale will talk with my phone and upload how much I've waited what points and times and I can log in
my phone and say Oh look I can see over the past year how my weight has gone up and down.
So kind of cool thing there but if you'd like to know more about Bluetooth just a wealth of knowledge.
This is the Bluetooth dotcom Web site.
So I have a thing here about developing with Bluetooth.
Honestly this is the nitty gritty which I really don't recommend.
I think there is a lot better way to work with Bluetooth devices and they have so many specific instances.
But companies like Android Apple with their Iowas platform have made it easier for us to work with Bluetooth
so we need to go ahead and take advantage of that.
So with that large introduction let's go ahead and finally start a new Android studio project and I'm
going call this blue tooth finder.
And I would like to note at the beginning of this is that you're going to need a device a physical Android
device if you want to test Bluetooth functionality.
So for me personally I have a little Android device here that runs on API 22 Sun about this down to
22 and I'll go ahead and hit next so we can move forward with that.
All right.
So go ahead and start your new project
and we'll give this a second to load up here.
And if you don't know how to load an app onto your Android device I'm going to go ahead and walk you
through that.
I found this really awesome screen sharing app that is just absolutely phenomenal so simple to get up
and running so I'm excited to share that with you.
So the basic idea with this app is that we wanted to go and try and find Bluetooth devices near us.
We're going to go ahead and show them inside of a list view.
And with that list view we're going to have a button below where you can hit that button to search again
and then it will start looking again and sort of update that list view.
So let's go ahead and work on the visual side of things first.
Go ahead and open up design give ourselves some space to work with.
So let's go ahead and delete that text view.
I'm actually going to start with what we have at the bottom and then add the list view to the top so
we want to have a bottom.
At the very bottom a button at the very bottom excuse me and we'll go ahead and anchor that to the bottom.
Let's go ahead and center this.
And we want this to be a button.
So if someone wants to you know go search for some Bluetooth devices so we're going to change the text
of this say search.
All right.
Now with this we want to have a text view right above that that says the current state of what's going
on so we're going to go ahead and add a text view and it doesn't need to be too big.
This is going to be kind of just a small indicator for the user about what's going on.
So we're going to connect that below.
And again right click.
Make sure that this gets centered correctly then with these two things in place.
Now I'm going to go to the list for you.
Drag that out and have this take up the whole space are going to go ahead and just add the constraints
all around there.
Now let's make sure everything has a proper ID.
I'm going to just call this list view and I'm going to go ahead and call this view text for you status
text view and go ahead and change this button to be the Search button.
OK.
So we've got all of those things in place in the starting text for this.
We actually just want it to be blank.
So I'm actually going to go ahead and just highlight that text and the way that we're going to fill
that up with information later.
So let's move now to our main activity and I should have done on click method for this button.
So let me go ahead and do that.
And for those on click I'll go ahead and just call this search clicked.
All right so I'll start there first I'm going to say public void search.
Click it or pass a view there make sure you enter to import.
So this is where we want to launch off the blue tooth searching.
And like I said we can't really test this on a Bluetooth device are not going to load that emulator
quite yet.
But let's go ahead and talk about what it is that we need to do next so when someone wants to go search
we need to alert the user that we are doing the search and we probably want to disable that button.
Let's go ahead and make sure we can get access to everything that we need here.
We're going to get access to the list view which will just call list for you.
We're going to get access to the text view which we are going to call a status text view and we also
need access have to do the autocomplete there.
And the last thing that we need is the button.
So to make it a button called Search button.
All right so with those things in place we want to go ahead and set those up in the on create.
So I'll start first with a list view or equal define view by IDR.
Heidi list view and I'm just going to go ahead and copy and paste this twice down below.
So this will be for the status.
Spell it correctly status text if you want change this to status text view and then we want this one
to be the search button and we'll have the idea change to search button.
All right.
So all those things are in place and again the first thing that we want to do is when that search button
is clicked on we want to show that you know we are going out and searching.
So the first thing that we should do is we should take our text view which is the status text for you
which should say Dot set text instead of equal to something like searching dot dot dot.
So the user knows that something's going on.
And we also want to disable that button.
So we're going to go ahead and say search button is set enabled and we want to set that equal to false
so that the user can't hit the button again and start this whole launch process.
And we want to restrict that from the user for a second.
So with that in place let's go ahead and load this on my Android device.
So there's a couple a multi-step process here and to show you that process I'm going to go ahead and
load this new app that I have called vizor that allows you to me to show you my device what's going
on on the screen there.
And so I have my device plugged in with us B and it's ready to rock and roll.
Here let's go ahead and go to the home page and I'm now going to hit view so that you can see this if
you'd like to check this out visor.
Pretty neat little apps that you can see what's going on on my screen.
So with that there if you're going to be using visor or if you're just going to be using you know this
one to test something on your Android device the first thing that you have to do is you have to enable
your app to work with you have to put it in developer mode.
So what you need to do is go ahead and open your settings app.
And luckily I have mine here recently used.
And so we want to go to all the way to the bottom down to about phone if you scroll down to the bottom
where it says Build number.
If you actually go ahead and tap on that seven times it's going to pop up a thing that saying hey you
know do you want to enable developer version and all this stuff.
Because I've already done it.
You'll see I get the text message that says no need you're already a developer.
So with that in place loops and lay out stuff here.
That's so cool how quick it can respond all that but if I want to go ahead and test my app I'm going
to hit run here.
Rather than choosing one of the virtual devices I'm going to choose the connected device.
So technically we could have tried out this code with a emulator here because we're not doing any Bluetooth
stuff yet but I thought let's go ahead and just get you know in the flow of working with a physical
Android device.
So it's going to take a second here for this to pop up see we got the great will build coming or go
ahead and take this moment to talk to you about what it is that we need to do after this and that's
where that we're going to do something called a Bluetooth adapter and this is going to power everything
that we do in Bluetooth so what we want to add to the top here is something called a blue tooth adapter.
And I'm just going to go ahead and call this lower case Bluetooth.
Well let me spell it correctly.
Bluetooth adapter like that so we'll go ahead and talk about how we can get that set up and whatnot
in the next lecture.
But for now it looks like our app is finally opening up here.
So we go ahead and open up visors so you can see this.
And here's the phone that pops up and if I hit the search button that it disables the button and it
says searching.
All right.
So we're on the right path in order to go now connect with the Bluetooth world but we still got more
to do.
Let's cover that in the next lecture.