In this section we'll be making a clone of one of the most popular apps in recent times uber Ebba is
a pretty straightforward idea.
A writer taps on the app when they want to take a car somewhere and then a nearby driver is alerted
of that rider and then goes and pick them up.
So simple idea but for us it will give us an opportunity to merge our past server cloud storage skills
with maps and GPS which are perhaps the two most powerful aspects of mobile apps working together.
So it should be a lot of fun and we're going to start over on AWOS creating a new easy to instance for
our past server code.
So if you miss that go to US Amazon Dot com where we went before for Instagram and we're just going
to follow that process again.
If you really don't want to go through the process again you can use the same path server set up as
before.
But I wouldn't recommend it it's easier to keep different instances in the Hap's separate and will cause
less confusion in the long term.
So here we go we're looking into AWOS and then we'll jump over to ECAC member it's in the services dropdown
as well.
Either that or the.
And then as before we want to launch a new C-2 instant cyclic the big blue launch instance button and
then down to AWOS marketplace search for pass and select pass server powered by bit NAMI.
Make sure you choose the T-2 micro instance to avoid any charges and then click launch.
I'm going to create a new key pair and this is going to be uber Android keep
download.
That's
and then launch instance and that's now in the process of setting up.
So what that's doing that's let's jump over and download our past project Android dev of course dot
com slash pass project zip so we'll open that up.
And then when that's downloaded we can see we've got it there on the desktop.
So I'm now going to open that up in Android studio and get it ready to change out new Passover settings.
Actually I we'll just rename the folder to the then we're looking in users for a possible desktop and
there it is
OK.
So while that's opening up back over to Firefox and are easy to see management console and now we want
to connect to our new instance as before we'll use our Java S-sh client and the keypad.
Remember if you're in Windows it will be wherever you saved it.
If you're in Mac it'll be something like slashy uses slash and then your username and then wherever
you saved it.
So for me it was the desktop and then just to remind myself I call that Uber Android keypad.
PM
And I don't want to type that in next time so I'll store it in the browser cache.
And then launch S-sh client and off we go.
And here we go.
So now we're locked into the server via S-sh or secure shell.
So we start by changing directory using CD to apps slash pass slash H.T. Dokes which is where the paths
files are stored and then we use vi to open up the text editor and we want to edit the file server at
J.S. because that has allowed server settings in it.
And here we go.
So I'll start by copying the app the.
And then back over to Android studio is out Hiba app.
So I open up the project Java starter application and then our new application ID goes in there next
the client key which is the same as the master key.
Copy that's
there we go.
And then the server is that long you are out there.
Forget the slash at the end.
All right.
So we'll run that's on our Nexus device.
And while it's running we'll jump back over to Firefox and into you again so that we can view the data
browser which is exactly the same you are.
But instead of parse it has apps on the end.
And here we go.
So here's our data browser type on them.
So we haven't got anything in there yet but when our app is up and running which it should be seen.
Now we do have a small issue here.
I think that was worth living in what's happened here.
This has failed because of invalid session tokens.
What's going on is that they passed on to it is recognized as the same app as the Instagram project
that we had before.
So it's trying to log on as the previous user but because we've got a new pass installation that's not
working.
So what I'd recommend doing is between apps if we're using the same simulator just delete the app
by dragging it to uninstall
and then re-install it again via Android studio.
And that will get rid of the nasty invalid session token error.
All right let's have a look.
And there we go.
Much better passwords result.
Successful.
And just to confirm.
Let's jump back over to Firefox and refresh the page and we should now see not only a user but also
the example object.
And there we go.
All right so now we're set up to use pass once again for our app that's go on to the next video where
we're going to be creating our pass anonymous logon page.