All right.
Welcome to the second lecture here where we're going to go ahead and finish getting this a.r course
services onto our phones so then we can test out the app.
So what we need to do now is we need to get Adeeb working and to confirm that this works.
Again you should be in the platform tools directory you're going to do a dot slash and then ADP.
And if you hit enter on this you should see some texts like this that basically says hey ADP is working
and to really test this we're going to do a dot slash and do a D and then space devices.
And this is going to tell us all the devices that are currently connected to the computer.
So I have my Google pixel to plugged in and I have it connected via USP So it's listed here and that's
its device name.
So now that we have this then we can you know start talking to that specific device and there's all
sorts of instructions in here about how to work with this and you know get to whatever device it is
that you want to be working with.
So you can kind of see from here when you're trying to list out the devices.
Let's go ahead and see here.
You can connect also via Wi-Fi which is kind of interesting I thought.
But anyways lots of different things that you can use.
So with this what we want to do is go back and we want to install this A-R core preview.
A B kit which this is in our download directory.
So what we're going to do is we're going to open up our terminal here and I'm going to kind of move
it off to the side so I can still see what's going on with this web page.
Maybe I'll kind of squash this off to the side.
Now that didn't work as well as I thought.
There we go.
So that will have some room to see both.
So again we're going to do our dot slash HDB and then we're going to type the install space dash our
dash D and then we need to get to the A-R core Dasch previous AP K-8 which for me is in my download
directory.
So I'm going to do slash capital users slash Zappy code and if I hit tab it's doing this autocomplete
for me if you get the autocomplete that's a good sign that you're on the right path.
Once I'm in Zappy code then I can get to my downloads so I'm going to start typing downloads.
There we go.
And then I want to get to the core and have a hit tab.
Well that gives me the zip.
And in fact I remember we actually move that to the desktop so I'm going to change this now to get to
the desktop.
There we go.
And now if I start typing a our core and the hit tab.
Oh good we get the dash.
And then let's do preview.
AP Okay.
Excellent.
So that means that open up there will go ahead and hit enter here.
Make sure when you do this that you have your device turned on plugged in via US be you set up that
you're going to be a developer and that you you know did us be debugging.
So you'll see the success message if everything worked out and on my device like a little pop up message
that said hey you know we just got things up and running here.
So if this is the case if you got all this fixed and I know this is really kind of weird step that we
have here in order to get to the finish line.
But with all of that now we can actually go ahead and open up this project.
So I'm going to go back to android studio and I'm just going to hit run on this app I'm going to select
my phone and we'll go ahead and get that running.
So basically this app it will try to detect the floor and then once it detects some floor it will allow
you to place a little Android doods on the ground which is pretty fun.
And so I think you'll enjoy seeing that.
Also you get to see a little preview of my basement here where I'm recording this.
So let's go ahead and get visor up and run in here so you can see what this looks like so you can see
my phone.
I'm going to move the camera off here to the side and I'm going to have it trying to take this ground.
I have this inflatable pumpkin from Halloween still out on the ground.
But look at that.
You can see it's picking up some of the ground here that's where like that red is.
I know it looks pretty blurry there but you can sort of see those winds that are coming up.
I'll get a little bit closer so that you can see that trying to be really steady.
But if I tap my finger and all of a sudden pop up these little Android dudes everywhere on the screen.
So that is so cool.
And these are completely 3D so I can you know move in get really close to them come back you know like
I'm totally part of the world now like this.
So a pretty cool little A-R world that we can get connected with here.
So that is the A Our core example app that was provided by Google.
Now as far as you know how all this worked.
Well there's a couple of things that fed into this.
So the big one here is the assets as far as the 3D objects are involved and so the little Android dude
whose name here is Andy.
There's lots of different things that create this guy.
The piano this is sort of his skin.
Everything that creates him but these Drobe files as far as I was able to research are able to create
the 3D model of him and his shadow.
There's also a image file for his shadow and the trigram.
This is what sort of goes on the floor is when it's detecting where the floor is.
So it's a combination of these sort of skins for these 3D objects that come together as far as the coding
files goes.
The big one is this.
Hello our activity.
So inside of here this is where it does all the work of like detecting the ground.
And once the user taps on the screen getting one of those little and used to show up.
So in fact if you wanted to go test this out you could just go ahead and do find if you search for Andy
you can see this is the one particular place where Andy gets created.
So if you had your own 3-D objects that you wanted to go in there then you could go ahead and you know
plop them into here and you could also change the size of your android like make it super huge and it's
just going to dominate the whole screen.
There's all sorts of different things that you could do here.
So with a hard core this really advanced technology.
And like I said this Web site that we have here.
Excellent resource for you if you want to go learn more.
Like when you get to the bottom here for the next steps There's this awesome API references and if we
go back to that main screen there's some really cool guides in order to help you build your very first
app so.
So pretty cool stuff here.
You can kind of choose your own way when you got to go about this but I hope you enjoyed checking out
our core and all the functionality there.