And this lecture we're going to cover the beginning points of starting our app we're going to learn
how to add our character coin man to the screen how to apply a background all sorts of fun stuff like
that.
But the first thing I want to do is I want to fix the layout of this app.
And so it's right now set to be landscape and we can fix that if we go to our Android manifest go ahead
and double click on that you'll see as we scroll through here the screen orientation right now is set
to landscape.
We want to go ahead and change this to portrait.
So just go ahead and put lowercase portrait there and that's all we need to get this app running in
the correct direction for us.
Now maybe in your game you wanted to be landscape that's the decision up to you that you can decide
how you want to handle that but for us I think it looks better if we have things in more of a portrait
style So let's go ahead and open up the emulator and look at it.
It's now in the correct position.
All right.
So with this we don't need this image texture right that we had before.
We don't need to do any of this stuff.
They've kind of pre-done for us we're just going to go ahead and delete everything except for this dispose
keep batched not dispose.
Then we're not going to really touch this function for the rest of this.
We clear everything and render and we're going to keep everything or get rid of everything except for
this batch.
And we'll even get rid of this texture called image.
So let's start first with how we can add a background to our app.
And so I actually have a series of image assets for you and so I want you to go on your browser.
I want you to go to Android of course dot com slash.
Let's go ahead and do this in a new tab.
I want you to go to Android of course dot com slash and then we're going to do a coin or lowercase coin
pan dot zip so just go ahead and hit enter on that and that's going to download this folder.
I already have one here on my desktop that's going to have some images.
Let me go ahead and grab that.
So I'm just going to go ahead and open this up made a folder by the same name so I'm going to rename
this to be coign man images.
Excellent.
And you can see inside of here we just have some images that we're going to be using.
So for example this background beat up piano.
That's what we want to fill the screen.
We're going to put coins in there there's a little dude and you can see we've got some different photos
of him running.
Also one when he dies what that's going to look like.
So we've got the bomb and we've got the coins.
Now I got these images from a multiple few places.
One of almost flat icons.
So again I think this is a great place to go and get images this one was by Smash icons and then also
I just did a simple search for a bomb.
And you can replace these with any images that you want.
You don't have to use the same ones but this one came from free pick.
And then also the character this came from open game art or this is a really cool Web site this one
happens to come with the Creative Commons zero license which means you don't have to give attribution
if you don't want to.
But I thought it would cool to give a shout out to the author Bev ovule and I don't know how to pronounce
your name but there is the website if you want to see more.
So with all of that in place we now have those extracted images.
We're going to go back to our Android studio project and on this asset folder.
Go ahead and right click this and do reveal in Finder because we want to move in those images.
So we'll go ahead.
We've got this asset folder here that just right now has that bad logic image.
We're going to take all these images from the desktop.
Go ahead select all of them.
We're just going to drag and drop right into that asset folder.
So now we have access to all of those.
And we should see here an android studio if we right click and say synchronize assets boom there's all
those images.
Now step number one for us is we want to get a background showing up inside of our app.
And so what we're going to do is we're going to create a texture texture is a way to add an image into
that we're going to do this for like our Queen Mab and also the coins the bombs any sort of visual image
you want to use a texture so we're going to make a new texture and for this one we're going to go ahead
and just call it the background.
So we'll just simply type out background here you are semi-colon and then we're going to go through
the process of getting this all set up.
So step number one for us.
You might have seen this from what we had before but we want to get this background set up and we'll
just do that by same background is equal to a new texture.
And we want to pass in the name of the image so that's B.G. peahens.
You can see that from over there in the menu.
Don't forget your semi-colon.
And then once you have this in place we now move on to how we get things to show up on the screen.
This is the drawing part of this so we have to first take this batch that we have up here and in order
to start things we want to go ahead and say batch that begin.
And eventually when we're finished with every single thing that we could possibly want to put on that
screen we are going to do a batch dot and change.
So those are kind of the two positions that we want to go to.
But then the question comes well how do we get an image to show up inside the app like what is you know
the proper way to quote unquote draw something there.
Well for this we simply want to say Bache dot draw and then it's going to ask us a series of questions
here.
So the first one is you know what texture is it that you want to draw.
So we're going to pass in background here.
Well just go ahead and type that out.
Sure we spell that correctly.
Background.
There we go.
Then it's going to ask us for the starting position of this.
And it actually starts things in the corner so we want to actually just put zero and zero here.
And then it's going to ask us for the height and the width of this and we want to say hey however wide
the screen is and however tall the screen is that's what we want.
So to do that we're going to type capital G but lowercase d x so GDX dot and we want to get to the graphics
and then we're going to say don't get with it's going to fill it up.
And then for the height same thing GDX dot graphics get height.
So if we go ahead and pass and all that information this will draw a background for us.
And let's go ahead and run this and just make sure that we can get this situation to show up
so we'll go ahead and give this a moment here and look at that.
We see that nice landscape filling up the entire screen and just looking great now something I will
mention my fan is going crazy because whenever you're running the game this renders is being called
over and over and over and over again it's just as crazy loop that won't stop.
So I like hitting the stop button after I've tested out the app because that way my computer doesn't
go crazy and the fan sounds like it's a you know 7:47 about to take off.
It kind of makes things chill out a little bit.
So the next position for us is we want to draw our little map.
So you might think OK let's go ahead and add a texture.
But the thing is we have lots of different pictures for our guy.
So here he is at frame one frame too like that we're trying to give the illusion that he's running.
And so we have to have a way to show all these different frames to the users we have to have a bunch
of textures so in this case we're going to make a texture array for our coin man who will simply call
man.
So we have coin man here inside of create.
We want to go in ahead and get him set up.
So with this we're going to say man is equal to a new texture array and we've got to say how many are
going to be in there and we have four images.
So we'll go ahead and pass and for then the next thing that we want to do is fill up that array.
So we're going to say for man at position 0 we want to go ahead and set you equal to a new capital texture
and again we just want to pass in the name of the image so this one's going to be frame all lowercase
one p n g and that's all it takes to add our first one and we want to do this for the other three positions
inside of the array.
So we're just going to copy and paste this and we'll just increment our numbers here.
So there we go that's all the positions in the array and we'll just change these numbers to 2 3 and
4.
So that gives us the proper array for our new man.
But then the question is Will how do we get to show all these different textures and you don't remember
this render method just gets called over and over and over again like it's just constantly repeating
loop.
So basically what we want to do is we want to keep track of you know what position we are on with the
man and we want to draw the man at that particular time with you know whatever it is that it's going
to be.
So you know it's going to take a little bit of you know math to figure out what it is that we should
do but really not all that much.
So what we want to do is let's go ahead and just draw our little guy once.
And it's important that you do this after the background because the order in which you draw things
is very important because now the man's going to appear on top of the background.
If you did it before the background he would be completely smothered by the background so we're going
to say Bache dot draw and we're going to pass on our man and let's say just initially we're going to
do the very first texture inside of there and let's say we want him to fill the center of the screen
right like that would probably seem like a reasonable thing.
Well the math that we'd want to do for this is we first have to figure out his x and y position if he's
going to go to the center of the screen we have to take the high divided by two and the width divided
by two.
So start first with X which is referring to the left and right position on the screen.
We're going to say Jeeta X graphics.
Get with.
We're going to divide that number by two.
OK.
And we're also going to say X dot graphics and get the height we're going to divide that number by two.
Then with those two positions in place let's go ahead and see what this looks like.
So again this is only going to show our little dude in one position.
But then we're going to learn how we can loop through and make this happen.
So go ahead and give a second to have this show up on the emulator.
And look there's our guy.
So you'll notice he's not exactly in the center of the screen.
And the reason for that is that you know we went to the position for him it starts at the corner here
the bottom left corner.
So he said go to the center of the width which is here and then the center of this like we actually
want to go to the center position.
And then half of his width to move him over just enough.
So if we want to get technical and go to that position let me stop that before my computer heats up.
We're going to get half the width and then we're also going to subtract whatever the width of our man
is.
And you know let's say position zero.
We can just do the get with from here but then we want to also divide that by two.
So let's go ahead and do that and we should see that he is centered on the screen.
It's important that we get him centered on the screen because if he's too far to the right you know
the player doesn't have enough time to see the coins you could arguably put a maybe more to the left
if you really wanted to.
But look at that all of a sudden now he's in the center he's still a little bit high.
But we're going to talk about his height in the second here and we're not going to want to put too much
effort into that.
So the one thing that I want to finish before we end this lecture is I want to make it look like he
is running.
And so we have to have a way to loop through all of his different running positions.
So in order to do that what we're going to do is create a new integer that we are going to call man's
state.
So this is going to tell us you know is he in the zero position the one the two the three.
Right.
And so we're just going to do a cool little statement here and we say if Man state is equal to or excuse
me if it's less than three.
So if it's for example 0 when it starts up we want to say Man state plus plus.
So that's going to add once so that it will initially be zero and one and two.
And then when it gets to three that's when that's kind of our pushing point.
Well in that case that's when we're all going to want to say ELTs and flip man's state back to zero.
It's all set that equal to zero.
So now rather than saying man's at the zero position here we're going to use the man state and here
as well rather than just saying zero.
We want to do the man state.
So let's go ahead and see what this looks like.
I forgot to hit stop there.
So that's Peter's heating up again.
So let's go ahead and see what this looks like.
I think that he's running put it is way way way too fast in the so we've got to find a way to sort of
time this down a bit.
So let's go ahead and stop that.
We're going to bring yet another INT into the equation and we're going to call this pause.
Now we're going to use this number to just kind of give pause to our Apple and set it equal to zero
initially.
But what we're going to do here is we're going to set up an if statement where we say hey if.
Pause and you'll have to pick the number I found that 8 below 8 is a good one to say if pause is less
than eight then I want you to go ahead and say pause.
Plus plus OK and if that's not the case in the else situation here then I want you to have our man here.
Excuse me I want pause to be equal to zero so you'll notice every eight times that we run through this
loop then we'll come through and change the man's state.
So it kind of gives pause here.
So it's like runs through eight times and it just hits there but once it's pauses equal to it it comes
down says oh I can update the Mansei that comes back Pozzi equal to zero so I to run through there eight
times and it comes back says oh I'll move and say it again.
So if you want to see this in action hit this run button and we will see hopefully our little dude run
in here and a much more visual good pace.
And again I thought this was the right number.
You can have it be less or more to change the speed at which he runs.
But I think this looks pretty good.
So this is a good stopping point for our app right here in the next lecture.
We're going to cover how we can make Quain man fall to the ground and then eventually start doing things
like adding the coins and the bombs.