Excellence so you've now installed and or a studio and you're hopefully presented with the Welcome screen
here as you can see there are lots of options here.
Most of which are reasonably self-explanatory but we're going to dive straight in and start a new Android
studio project.
This takes us to the first of a few options screens.
Let's start by filling in the application name and for now we'll just call it example app.
The next option is to select your company Dumaine.
Now at this point in your Android development career you probably don't have your own domain name but
don't worry you can really put anything you like here for now though when you start publishing apps
you will need to have a unique domain.
So if you like you can leave that as the example that you're given.
Or you can change it to really whatever you like.
I'm going to change it to rob my app company dot com just to show you that you can use literally anything
you like here.
Then you can choose where the project is saved on your harddrive.
I'm just going to use the default location if you want to you can edit the package name just created
from your company domain and the name of your app.
But generally I would leave that as the default as it might cause confusion later if you do change it.
And down here you can choose to include C++ or Kollin support.
We'll be looking at Cartland later on in the course but we're not using it yet.
So you can leave both of those blank.
All right click next and you can now choose the form factors and minimum SDK so form factors are reasonably
straightforward.
If you're developing an app which is going to be used on phone and tablets which you probably are then
select the first option and the options down here we've got android where Android TV and 2.0 and Android
things if you're developing for those platforms you would select those a slightly trickier question
is which API version to use.
Now if you look at the drop down menu you can see that the various API versions correspond to the different
versions of Android that are out there.
So the later version you choose the more recent functions and features will be available to you but
the fewer devices your app will run on because a lot of devices are still running onsite lollipop.
So if we select Android 6 marshmallow you can see that we can use any API from 23 and later but your
app will only run on about 40 percent of devices.
So it's a choice that you'll need to make.
But most of the time and at least in the early stages of your app development career you probably won't
bump into too many features that you need but don't have.
So let's stick with API 15 for now.
Click next and were given the option to add a default activity now an activity on Android is essentially
a screen.
So as you build variety of different apps you'll be adding different types of activities to your apps.
You can see we've got some examples there.
So you might start your app with a basic activity and then when the user wants to do something on a
map will jump to a Google Maps activity you can see there's a full screen activity.
Various other types of activity that we'll see later on as we go through the course.
For now they will just choose an empty activity so a very simple one get started and click next.
And this is our final option screen where we're allowed to name our activity.
The default for your initial activity is main activity.
So we're going to leave that as it is and the layout you can see the name for that is just the name
but reversed.
So activity underscore main Those are the defaults.
So we leave them as they are and click next.
You might find that there's some new components that have been installed to allow you to create your
app for that particular version of Android.
So if you do then click Finish.
And finally Android studio itself should boot up and create your example App project.
And here we go.
Your first glimpse of Android studio now for me Android studio has opened two default files here.
But you might not be able to see those.
It doesn't always open up the same default files when you create a new project.
So I'm just going to close everything down.
Clicking the X is there.
And there.
And I'm going to click project just to get us back to a completely empty screen.
I'd recommend doing the same.
So we're all at the same starting point.
So you can see we've got lots of different options here.
But part of the skill of learning to code is working out what's important and what's not particularly
at the early stages of your journey.
So at the top here we've got the file structure of our app leading to that main activity file that I
showed you a moment ago.
And then over here on the right we've got a number of different options.
The most important and the most exciting is this playbook which we'll be using in a minute to actually
run our app feel free to hover over these other buttons if you like to get a bit more information about
what they are.
But don't worry too much at this point want to keep it simple and then round the edge.
We've got some buttons.
All of which we'll be using at some point in the course but for the moment we're going to focus on the
project button which allows us to view our project.
Now we've got two key folders here.
We've got app and graded scripts cradle is an open source app building to Android studio uses to build
your app later on in the course.
We're going to be customizing these great old build scripts to customize and add features to our apps
but for the moment we can just leave those as they are.
So let's have a look inside the app folder.
So I've got three folders here.
The first is manifests which has a single file in it called Android manifest Let's have a quick look
at that one.
This is what's known as an X M-L file and it contains information about your app so you can see we've
got the app name there.
We've got details about the icons the package name and various other bits and pieces.
We'll be editing this later on just like with the greatest scripts to add features.
But for now we can pop that back in its folder and leave it as is of more interest at this point is
the java folder which is where the code for our app resides.
There's three folders within that these are test folders which we won't be using again.
Right now the one we're really interested in is that top folder which has a single file in it.
The main activity file and as I mentioned earlier this is some Java code which creates and sets up the
main activity in our app.
We'll be looking at that in much more detail in the next couple of videos.
And finally we have Reade's short for resources fold up which is where we keep things like images and
music.
Most importantly to us right now is the layout subfolder within That's where we can see this activity
main direct XML file.
And if you DoubleClick that you can actually see a visual representation of your app and this is where
you get started editing the actual content of the app and the layout.
So we're going to spend a lot of time in activity main Torex M-L working with layout and in main activity
working with some Java to actually make your app do things.
So feel free to take a moment to play around here and maybe add some buttons to your app and see what
effect it has.
Have a look at the different widgets that are available.
Different type of text views.
There's a lot that you can add to your app from there.
You might also want to see how your app would look on different devices.
So we've got a nexus 4 by default there but we can try the pixel fine.
We can look at some bigger resolution devices like the Nexus 9 and we can even look at watches or TV
screens.
We'll leave it on nexus for now.
But feel free again to play around with that.
And also you can see where your app would look like in landscape mode and switch back and forth as well.
So there's a huge amount you can do here.
Most of which we're going to look at at various points during the course but for now let's just try
and run our example app on a phone within the emulator and Android studio.
So we click the green play button there and here we get the screen that allows us to select the device
that we want the app to run on.
I don't have any phones or devices connected so we need to use a virtual device because I've only just
installed Android studio only to create a new one.
So let's do that create new virtual device.
And so this is very exciting you can choose any phone you like and you'll have an emulator for it and
you can use it right there within your computer and you can create a TV emulator an Android where emulator
and it's happy I might as well so I'm going to use the options as much as possible so we'll stick with
Nexus 5 x.
But really you can choose whichever one you like here.
Click next.
And now we get an option to flex a system image.
So what kind of Android do we want our device to run.
I'm going to go for the latest version of the recording of this video but at this point you're welcome
to try out other versions of Android If you prefer.
You'll likely have to download the version unless it's already installed.
So I click accept accept the terms and conditions and again it will take a few minutes to install and
there we go.
So that's installed.
Click finish.
And then you should be able to select the version that you've downloaded next.
It's just a summary of the options that you've selected.
A few advance settings we'll be using later on in the course.
But for now we'll leave those all that he felt and click Finish.
That will then set up our Android virtual device.
And we can select it and click OK.
And there it is.
So it'll pop up on our screen we can control it using the icons then we do have to then wait for our
app to build using cradle.
And we'll also have to wait for the emulator to start up.
Here we go so our app is built with zero errors and our phone is just beating up the.
And here we go.
So the app is up and running.
You can see we've got a message here is to me why isn't responding.
That's just because the startup process is still going on by clicking wait usually just makes the message
go away.
So congratulations you've built and run your first Android app.
Obviously it doesn't do a great deal yet but that will change as we learn how to customize and code
our apps in the next few years.