All right.
So we were able to successfully go find some information about when we started searching.
When we finished but now let's go ahead and write some code so for when we actually get information
back saying hey we found a bluetooth device how do we work with that.
So what we're going to do is add another statement here.
So we're just going to add an else if on this.
Go ahead get that set up.
And similarly as above we want to you know check this.
But in this situation rather than working with the Bluetooth adapter we want to work with the Bluetooth
device.
So we're going to go ahead and type in here.
Bluetooth device dot action and we want to do the action found that tells us hey we got something new.
And see if this is equal to the action string that we had pulled out earlier.
So if that's the case this means you know that they found an actual Bluetooth device and you know now
we can learn some information about this.
So there's a couple of things that we can do here.
The first thing is we have to extract the Bluetooth device or we're going to say cable a bluetooth device
is equal to device or device is equal to.
And this is where we're going to go and grab the intent and say intent get and we want the parsable
extra.
And once we have that we're looking for capital Bluetooth device that extra device can and then this
Bluetooth device class here this allows us to get information about you know whatever it is that we
had just grabbed and let's see what sort of air it is that we're having a problem with here.
You know I believe we got oh I don't want parsable array extra I just want to parsable extra.
Now that's good.
I can see why there would be an error if I told them that that was going to be an array.
All right.
So with them in place there's a couple of cool things that we can do with the device and you can really
just see them with the auto complete if you just do device dot and say Get For example you could get
the address Bluetooth class bound state name type you use IDS like all sorts of different cool things.
The main ones that we want to be looking for are the address and the name.
So if we have a name that's going to be the best one to move forward with the next best thing would
be the address and then we also can find out how strong our signal is to something by using something
getting into something called RSS.
And so let's go ahead and dive into each of these I'm just going to make a bunch of strings so the first
one is going to be the name so just say string name is equal to the device get name the next item that
we're going to be looking for is we want to go ahead and get the address are going to say address is
equal to device that get address.
And then lastly in order to get the RSS side it's a little bit of a multi-step process here.
So the first thing that we want to do is this one's going to be represented by an end.
So we're going to say Aunt our SS is equal to K and this is where it gets a little crazy we're going
to say intent not get short extra just like we had done before.
And then inside of here we want to do capital Bluetooth device dot and then we're going to say extra
and we want the our access.
So this tells us about that also.
We're going to say we're going to do capital short here to say that we want the minimum value chain.
So this gives us back in our SSI these are kind of tricky numbers where I think essentially it's the
they're almost always negative numbers and they're like more negative.
The number is the stronger the connection you have.
So you can kind of prioritize which Bluetooth devices are near or far away from you.
But we are able to then take this RSI our SSI information and we could turn it into a string so as a
matter of fact if we wanted to you know go ahead and convert this to a string we could say you know
integer to string.
Let's go ahead and pass and this whole shebang here.
All right.
Which then means we're in I have to say that this should be represented as a string but that should
make it easier when we're logging all this.
So if this all works let's go ahead and do the most epic log we've done yet in those cores.
We're going to say device found and this is the information that we want to provide.
So the first thing that we're going to say is we're going to state what the name is going to be namespace
and then we're going to add the name after that.
We want to add the address
space and then we're going to you guessed it add the address.
And after that we're going to add one more here we're going to say the last thing you're looking for
is the our SSI.
And let's go ahead and add that in at the end suicide.
Excellent.
Okay.
So a lot of information that we're log on there but I think we're up to it.
So we'll go ahead and run this on the actual device but Lague cat we really want to be paying attention
to that one.
So let's go ahead and get that ready to rock and roll and look.
Oh I thought that was some information coming through I have to hit the search button first so I hit
search and look at this.
So we have some information coming through.
We have device found.
Name no address.
This string of letters and numbers are SSI negative 91 again.
Here's another name no native 80 So apparently this one's closer.
Negative 74 or even farther away that one's.
No no no.
And you'll notice it's pretty common to have the name be no on most Android devices.
Now for example I believe if I set up my Bluetooth preferences here on my Mac this was working earlier
I'm going to say open Bluetooth preferences case I've got this open and now if I go ahead and get all
the way down to the bottom and I hit search here I think it should find my Mac book.
So it's finding some devices like that.
It found that notebook pro that's the name of my mac book here you know kind of dumb joke there but
you know that sometimes Bluetooth devices can have a name so you know typically you're going to see
things like headphones would have a name.
You know I honestly trying to figure out what these different Bluetooth devices are around me.
I know that I have another computer here and my guess is that computers when they're not actively looking
for a Bluetooth like this don't broadcast that you know a proper name.
And you know it's I mean I can't tell you I'm trying to think about the devices around me.
I don't have a solid idea but it just shows you I think you'll be interested to see when you run this
how many Bluetooth devices there are sort of roaming around your spot.
Maybe they're not.
Maybe there's no bluetooth going on.
I'm just apparently bathing in Bluetooth.
But pretty interesting.
All the information that we can find there.
So with all of this I think we're really one step away from finishing our app and that's that we want
to show all this information inside of a list view and we want to be able to show users hey you know
there's a device that has this name if it has a name that's the one that we want to show if not maybe
we could show the address.
But I do also think it's worth showing the our SSI so they can know hey how near Is this thing.
So we're going to go ahead and cover how to do that in the next lecture.