So were able to successfully upload an image to the fire based storage.
Now the next step for us is we want to make it when we hit this next button then we can go select you
know what user we want to send this information to.
So in order to do that we have to have a list of users which means we now have to talk about firebase
databases is a really exciting part of firebase.
So let's go ahead and click on database here on the firebase Web site.
Let's just go ahead and do the get started here.
And basically the firebase databases anything that you want it to be I like to think of it as a big
Jaison file where you can make arrays and dictionaries things like that.
And so it's basically if you want to add something onto it you just say plus and you're going to add
something new like in this case.
If I want to have a whole bunch of users here I'm going to type out you know I'm going to have some
users and then on those users right if I'm going to have a bunch of these one could have the name.
You know Joe or something like that.
And what does Joe have.
Well Joe might have an e-mail which could be like Joe Zappy code dot com.
Right.
So if we go ahead and add this you can sort of see the breakdown and then you know if we want to add
an additional user we might have like Jane or something in Jane's going to have an e-mail of like Jane
at Zappy code dot com.
So you'll notice this database it's not like Q Well or anything like that.
It's sort of it's own thing here that firebase is created.
But you can really set this up however you want.
And so it kind of takes some time to learn how to appropriately create a database for your app that
works well.
I mean I'm going to show you the one that I created for snapchat here but lots of great documentation
online that I encourage you to read more if you want to learn more about this.
But just know this is sort of essentially what we want to do here is we want to have a list of users
and we want to be able to get their e-mails and list those out.
And then additionally be able to have these users to you know hold a bunch of snaps that people have
sent them and things like that.
Now with this we're not going to be storing anybody's users names in fact instead of using the name
Jane here.
We're going to use what's called the you I.D. which means like it stands for.
I think just user ID and so with this if we were going to change this.
C'mon let me change your name here.
No maybe it won't.
Let me change it here sort of on the fly.
But basically these user names if we were going to add a new user usernames it's going to look something
crazy like this and then they'll still have an e-mail that is going to be like you know Jane that be
code dot com.
Right.
But just know when we list out all our users are going to look more like this.
That's going to say Joe or something like that.
So in order for this to work we have to make sure all of our users are here inside of the database.
And I know this is a little bit different because you're thinking well over here in authentication we
have a list of users like can't we just query the list of users here and it's not exactly the case and
oh look it up.
There's a user ID right here maybe stands for unique ID.
I'm not sure.
But you know that's what that's going to look like.
But you might be seen walking can I just get a list of all the users here and know you need to be able
to set this up on your own.
And so I think the best way to handle this to add users onto here is we should make it so when someone
signs up for the very first time that they will just automatically be added here and we'll go put in
their e-mail.
All that proper stuff.
So I'm going to go ahead and delete everything here so we sort of start with a blank slate and you'll
see how this gets out of hand.
But we need to go at it.
Our authentication code so we're going to move back to our main activity.
Remember this is where we do all the log in stuff and we're going to change this to say hey if someone
is signing up for the first time we need to add them to the database.
So if we scroll down here.
So if they were able to sign on we don't want to worry about that.
They should already be in the database.
But remember this common outline here add to database this is finally where we're going to start doing
that.
So what we need to do is access the firebase database which in order to do that we're going to have
to go add another component to our great also.
Let's get back to the documentation.
We're now going to move to the real time database and let's just do get started with Android here.
So now that we've got this we have to compile some code here so we'll go ahead and copy this go back
to our project and the app level Bill doc great all add one more line here and you'll notice this ones
11. 6.2.
I'm going to keep this consistent with everything else I want everything to be 11. 6 thought.
So once I've changed that I'm going to go ahead and get that sync up.
But then let's move to our main activity and start writing the code for this to work.
So we'll give this a second here because we need sort of some of that autocomplete that comes from this
cradle function that's running right now but it's going to be called firebase database so I'm just going
to start typing see if I can get that to come firebase database.
There we go.
Excellent.
So firebase database thought Get instance does get reference.
That's seems to be always our starting point for when we you know get to somewhere and think about this
far based on the Get it and start get reference.
This is essentially it starting at the beginning point in the database so if we want to create a bunch
of users Well you know we need to create essentially a folder or an option here called users.
In this case it's called a child so we're going to say Get reference that child and this is where we're
going to pass in the term just lower case users.
So this would be the exact same thing as hitting the plus button here and saying users and you know
we'd have to put something inside of here.
But think of that's you know we've added this then on this we're going to say Dot child again because
we want to go even further down through here so we're going to say Dot child and on this this is where
we want to add the user's ID so we can get that from this task object or I guess in this case it's that
task object so we're going to say task dot result dot user dot you idea know kind of a long step to
get there but tasks that result.
User ID.
So that's going to then essentially go into a database and say OK and let me type the cell a little
bit better here.
It's the same thing as saying All right we added the child users than on users we added someone new
with the name like whatever the idea is some random thing.
Then on top of that we want to be able to add their email so we're going to add one more child and we're
going to say child and we're just going to type out all lowercase e-mail this is sort of our key.
Now we're going to set the value for this and then we'll say Dot set value and we just want to get whatever
the user's email is and we've done this a few times this email and text text to string we'll just copy
this page sat right inside and that is all we need to add to the database it's amazing.
So this is to kind of keep going with the example here this is the same thing as saying oh can you add
something onto this you ID it's going to be email and it will be something like Nick Zappy code whatever
dotcom we're going to delete this in a second.
So this is essentially what we're trying to do sort of prove this.
I'm going to go ahead and delete all of this so we can start fresh.
And let's go ahead and run this on the emulator
and we'll go ahead and give this a second.
Now for everything to properly work here we're going to have to delete the user that we already have.
Right.
Because if we try and sign in with Nick at Zappy Cocom Well that's already a correct user so we'll just
always go into the seinen portion and you know we won't ever get to do this so we have to do go back
to firebase here and let's make sure the app opens up first so opens up.
Let's do our log out here and then we're going to go to authentication.
We want to hit the ellipsis here and delete this account.
So now we have no users whatsoever.
So now if I do for example Nick at Zappy code dot com I give the password of know ABC 1 2 3 4 and I
hit go.
Now I have to make sure I'm in the proper place before I hit go so I'm going to go to a database get
started.
Right.
And I just want you to see this in real time is amazing.
So I'm going to hit go first tries to sign in so then it says I'm going to do the sign up and when it
does the sign up.
Boom.
Look at that.
Did you see this.
It created the child users then created the child of whatever the user is you idea was then on that
it gave the e-mail of Nick Zappy code dot com.
So watch this.
Let's say I log out and now I want to add Joe at Zappy Cocom.
So I hit the go button and boom.
Look at that.
We now have another user inside of here with their you I.D. right there.
Just awesome how simple this is to work with.
OK.
So now that we have a couple of users here listen inside of our database.
This means that when I go through the whole process of creating a new snap and then I want to send that
snap to a user I can list out that information.
So we need to make a new activity.
Let's go to Android studio here we one new activity and empty activity.
And let's go ahead and call this one choose user activity that's kind of the gist of what should be
going on in this one.
And this should just be one big list.
List view.
So I'm going to go to this choose user SML and basically just fill this up with a list view so let's
go to containers.
There's a nice list view.
We'll bring that in and we'll go ahead and give an idea to this list view.
Maybe you will just call this choose news or list view.
Excellent.
So now we've got this nice list view that we can have filled up with all the different e-mail addresses
that you could send that snap to.
So we need to make it so that we can actually move over here so I'm now going to go back to our create
snap activity and this is where we have way too many things up at the top here song to close out a lot
so that we can actually have some space to work with here.
So there's that create snap activity.
And with this we want to do an intent after we've successfully uploaded everything.
This is where we want to make an intent to say hey you know we should go move on to the next one.
So after we have the download your L all that stuff we are going to make a new intense save.
So intent is equal to capital intent.
It will pass and this and then we're trying to move to the choose user activity coal and coal and class
Java and then we want to start that activity right now.
There's a whole lot of different things that we're going to want to send forward like the image your
L for instance they're calling it download your own but we're going to want to provide like the image
or the message and also like the image name there's a couple of things that we want to throw for there
but for the time being we're just going to simply move over on to the next one so that's OK.
But let's go ahead and write the code to fill up that list view.
So now let's get the choose user activity.
And now we're going to make it so that when someone wants to you know pick somebody we can have them
all show up in a list.
So first thing that we got to do is provide the list view here so let's say var choose news or list
view is going to be of type List View nullable will set that equal to no initially and then inside of
our on create we'll say hey choose user list view your equal to find view by ID or Id choose news or
list view.
Great.
All right so with that in place with any list view it's got to have an array adapter so we can show
what should go inside of there so let's make a new thou here that I'm going to call adapter.
And this is going to be a new array adapter.
And with this will this provide.
This is the context.
And then we need to get what type of lay out there we want so Android are lay out.
And I just want simple list item 1.
So when we go ahead a simple list item one just like that.
And then we need to provide a list view here and we don't have one yet so let's go ahead and talk about
this.
We're going to make a variable here called e-mails right.
We want a list of all the user e-mails and we're going to say this is going to be an array list of type
string.
OK.
And we'll simply set this equal to a new array list just like that and then we'll go ahead and provide
e-mails here as the array that the adapter should look to in order to fill up that list view.
Now that in place we've got to take our list view chooses your list view and set the adapter and say
adapter so equal to adapter just like that and make sure we put a question mark there so that's all
happy and ready to go.
But then the next part is we have to be able to fill up this email's array list with actual emails from
the database write like we want to go get this and this.
Right.
So how do we do that.
Well we've got to work with the database and since we've already imported the cradle stuffer app we
can start working with the database.
We're going to add something called an event listener that says I'm looking at a particular part of
the database to see if anything is added there remove their whatever it's going to give us back some
info.
So we're going to type out firebase database get instance get reference remember that sort of the starting
point and we want to get to look we want to listen on this user's child here we want to say Hey any
time something new is added removed updated we want to know about it.
So on this after we do got in get instant stock get reference we're going to say Dot child and we have
to provide the name here of users all lowercase exactly like it is here.
It's important that that's exactly the same.
So we're going to say on users we are then going to add a child event listener.
So this is going to allow us to then you know successfully know oh what was it that they did someone
add remove whatever.
So we're first just going to give a name to this that we'll just call object colon and then now this
is where we're going to say we want a child event listener and we're going to go ahead and provide curly
brackets here for all the information that should go inside there.
So now with this there's a ton of methods that we have to add here and in fact if we go ahead and hover
over this let's go ahead and click on this red guy implement members.
There's all these different options here.
We just want to select everything and say OK.
And it's going to provide these.
So you might be thinking like whoa what have I done this is way too much.
But that's OK.
We just have to have these here we don't have to actually put code in them.
And in fact the only one that we're interested in is the on child added on the removed cancelled whatever
we're not necessarily interested in those the child added just tells us what is currently there and
if anybody new has added it we'll sort of update for us and so on all of these we want to get rid of
the DO's because that's going to crash are going to go ahead and get rid of all of those.
Just like that and then what I want to do is I want to move this at on child out and I'm going to move
this up to the top to know that this is kind of the most important one that we're working with here.
And then for all these other ones I'm just going to make these be two curly brackets like this because
we're not going to do anything with them we'll just sort of have them all together and if we ever want
to do something you know or we have to do is put some information inside of those curly brackets.
But it's I think sort of a waste to have those take up a ton of space to sort of have those all listed
out there.
All right.
But then inside of this on child added again this tells us each user that they're inside of the database.
So this is where we would want to for example start adding some e-mails to the survey list.
So to get somebody's e-mail they give us back this p zero which is something called a data snapshot
it contains everything that we need there.
So to get somebody's e-mail we would say we want the G-0 dot child and be the child that we're looking
for if I go back to the database it's given us this whole user.
Right.
But you'll see this user that signified with this you I.D. It has an email child.
So we want to say we want to get to the child e-mail and then we want to get to e-mails value.
So we've essentially said
value just like that.
We're trying to move into take this guy move to a child e-mail and get it's value.
That's how we sort of arrived at that position.
So when you say pay ZERO child whatever and we want this to come through as a string.
And let's go ahead and put this inside of a value so we're say vile and we'll go ahead and call this
e-mail and say that this is equal to this.
Now with this you can see because this is knowable we've got to make sure that we haven't had a question
mark there so that we'll be happy with what we've got.
We've got another inaudible so I have to put a question mark there but then this gives us an e-mail
so that then we can take this value and say All right e-mails a re list.
We are going to add the last e-mail.
Just simple as that.
So now that will be something inside of there and after we've done this we should probably let the array
adapter know that we have something new.
So we're going to say guess what we're going to add a new or we want to get to our adapter so adapter
dot notify data set change.
So that should say hey each time we had somebody you should update that.
So let's go ahead and see if this works.
If it does we should see listed out the e-mails for our two current users that we have in the database
so kind of a big moment of truth for us here.
You know just to confirm right we've got these two users right here.
And looks like that's finishing up because it's jumping up onto our screen here.
An app opens up.
So I want to create a new snap so I'm just actually going to use this default pink image and it will
just upload that and just kind of make it simpler and look at that.
There's nickered Zappy code and there's Joe Zappy code.
Wow.
We're moving really far through this app.
We're doing great.
So what's the next step for us right because now the user can select one of these people right and they've
given everything that they need.
They've provided an image.
They provided a message and they've said who they want to send it to.
We need to take all of that compile it into something and deliver it to the appropriate user.
So to get to that point we have to write some code to recognize when someone has selected one of these
options so let's go ahead and do that but then we'll talk about how we can sort of pack everything in.
So let's go ahead and back to android studio after we've gone and grab everything.
Let's go ahead and add a listener for the list view so that whenever somebody selects one of the items
we know about it.
So we're going to take our list view the choose news or list view a question mark there because that's
novel.
I want to set.
It's on item click listener equal to and just do capital adapter view dot on item click listener and
we want to make sure we do the one with the curly bracket here because that'll sort of auto add some
code for us and if you've done this correctly should see like adapter iView view.
Well you can change the names of those if you want to but I think that's pretty good for us.
And then we now have these curly brackets that we can write any sort of code when somebody selects something
inside of here.
All right.
And with this if somebody has selected the user right we need to package all the information and create
a new snap or what goes into creating a new snap right.
Like what.
What does it take.
Well let me just show you what it is that we're ultimately adding.
Want to add to the database so if Nick at Zappy code dotcom for example wants to send a snap to Joe
at Zappy code.
Well what we should try and do is go to DZO's user ID here that you I.D. and we're going to add a new
child here called Snap's and Snap's is going to be a list of all the snaps that people have sent.
So in this snap there's a lot of different pieces that we want to add here.
One of them is just going to say who it is that this is from.
So we're going to say from as the name and then the value of this should be.
For example Nick at Zappy code dot com.
All right.
So you can see Joe here Joe Zappy code.
He has a list of snaps and one of them is going to be from this Nicot Zappy.
And I guess I should mention each snap should have its own unique name.
So first we should have something like this which then has you know some informations inside of it like
from.
And then Nick at Zappy code dot com.
All right.
So I'll go ahead and delete this guy.
There we go.
So you can see Joe has one snap here.
And what's the information for the Snapple.
One thing we know about is who it's from.
We know who it's sent to because it's already inside of Joe's.
You I.D. here.
The next thing that we want to add onto this though is for example how do you download the image what
is the image your L. So we're going to have something like image.
You are.
All right.
And this will be like WWE image dot com.
I don't know.
Right like where someone can go ahead and download the image so that's another thing that we want to
know.
We want to know what the images name is so that we can.
We're going to need that to delete things later so just trust me on this one.
Image name should be like whatever dot Jay Pegge right.
Do you I.D. stuff.
So that's another thing that we should add inside of there.
And the other thing that we want to add is whatever the messages so we want to add a message maybe something
like Hey Joe you're cool.
Really cheesy message here but this is all the information we need in order to send someone to snap.
We need to know who it's going to so we can add it to their Snap's child here.
Then we need to say who it's from the image name the image you are and what the message is this is what
composes a snap.
So if this is what we want to send We can do this in one fell swoop by creating a map and then setting
that inside of the snaps for a particular user.
So let me show you what this looks like inside if you're inside of the on item click Lessner.
We want to create a new map so I'm going to call maybe new values are going to call the snap map write
a map that represents the snap.
And this is going to be of type map.
And for our keys we want all of those to be string.
And then for the values if we go ahead and look at our app here all of these are going to be strings.
Now in some instances you would want to like be careful careful here to make sure that like you could
have numbers for example if I said something I don't know like age.
Right.
Like you would want to be able to have a chance to add numbers there but we're actually not dealing
with any.
So we're going to make this a map of strings as keys and strings as the values.
But if you were going to work with other options you'd want this to be any capital any.
But in this case it's just going to be a map of strings of the keys strings is the values.
So with that in place we're going to start creating this and we're going to just say map of.
To create a map and we'll start writing things.
So what is the first thing that we want to add here.
We want to say who it's from.
So we're going to say from and then to and right now we'll just leave that blank.
Let's add the next thing that we need to have inside of there.
The image name.
So we're going to do image name too.
We'll leave that blank.
What's the next piece of information that we need.
Well we need to know what the image your ls will say.
OK.
Image you are ill and connect that to something which right now will just leave blank.
And then the last piece of information is the message right.
What are they trying to tell the user with their picture.
So we want to include a message and say to an empty string.
So we're going to come back and fill in these empty strings.
But for the time being we have a map that we're ready to add to the database.
So how do we appropriately add this to the database.
Well we've got to get to the correct position so we're going to do our firebase database Stockett instance
I got reference as sort of our starting point that we want to move into the users so we're going to
say child you want to get to users.
Next we want to get to the user that we're sending it to.
And so we're going to do child here.
But then we're going to go to our e-mail list and while the e-mails would be great if we could use that
e-mail but we've got to figure out the user's ID.
So in order for that to work or going to have to have a separate array list here where we're we're going
to list out the keys for all the different users so I'm going to copy and paste this array list and
change this one to be called Keys.
And again it's going to be an array of strings.
But here when we're adding an e-mail to the e-mails R-ALA right we're going to also add one to the Keys
and so on we're going to do here is say all right keys frailest list add and we can simply take this
data snapshot which is called Zero sort of say zero dot and we can just get it's key.
Now it's nullable So we want to make sure that we go do the double exclamation point here.
So at least I thought it was knowable apparently not so we can go ahead and leave that as that.
But now we have an array list of keys so then inside of here we can say okay for the child we're going
to go do t's dot net and we want to pass in high which is the index the the one that they selected.
OK so after we've done that then we want to go ahead and move on to.
We've got this particular person we need to add it to their steps.
So when I say Dot child and we're just going to do lowercase snaps if we're sort of following along
here we've gone.
All right.
First of the child users then who we're sending it to their you ID then to their snaps then we have
to create some sort of random ID for the snap and you could go use that ID code that we've done before
but you could also just use this as an awesome functionality.
You can just say push and it adds a new random child on a new child with a random name and then you
can start putting information in here in this case we're going to say set value and we're going to pass
in this whole map that we had just created so that snap map just like that.
OK.
So let's go ahead and give this a try.
See what happens if we go ahead and run this code so we'll go ahead and start this.
And while this is you know getting ready on the emulator I want to talk about after a user selects who
they want to send it to we basically want to send them back to that Snap's activity right where they
can see all the snaps you know been sent to them.
And so if you want to do this it's as simple as Krien the but we're going to do something special here.
So we're in a safe vault intent and we're going to get this equal to a new intent.
Not instance we want intent.
There we go past this and we're trying to move to the Snap's activity.
So we'll go ahead and do that but we want to make it so that when the user hits the back button they
don't go back to the select user screen like that kind of be a bad user experience.
So with this intent we're going to say Dot add flags and we are going to do capital intent dot and we
want flag underscore activity and we're looking for clear top Oh look there it is.
And this basically says hey wipe everything out of you know the back button history there and we'll
just keep it where it's currently at and then we'll just simply start that activity by passing that
intent.
OK.
So this code that we just added won't be on the emulator right now but we should at least be able to
add a snap to the database.
So I want to get the database up and open here so that we can see that.
So we've got our emulator and we are going to create a snap.
We'll just kind of leave everything blank there and we want to send this to Joe at Zappy code so it
should be going inside of here.
Moment of Truth.
We tap on Joe and look at that.
It's a new snap.
Exactly where we want it to the person that we want to if we want to test this.
Let's try adding one to Nick.
Look at that.
Now it's added one to the snaps and there's something here but here's the thing that you should know
right now the from the image name that you are.
All this stuff is blank right now because we didn't put anything into that map yet we've got to go back
and fix that so I'm going to delete the snaps for both these users because we know where it was that
we were trying to go and the proper names for everything.
Now it's just a matter of getting the correct data into those pieces of information.
So you know for like the from the image name right this is where we got to start filling in things.
So as far as who it's from.
We just have to go get the current user and display their name here.
So with this we're just going to do firebase off dot get instance and we want to get the current user.
And then on this current user we want to get their e-mail.
All right.
And that's really as simple as it gets.
Now with this we've got to sort of confirm that this is not going to add some exclamation points here
to sort of confirm that but we've now provided who it is that it's from Bill one of the four is done.
Now the next thing that we're going to be adding here like the image name the image or the message.
All of these things we know about in the previous activity to create snap and we need to send them over
to this one so that we can get that.
So we should provide those as extras inside of the intent so here inside of our intent.
This is where we're going to have to do a little bit of extra work to send that information.
So remember three things that we've got to add so intent put extra.
One of them is going to be the image your well.
All right.
And I'm just going to go ahead and copy and paste this two more times.
So we want to add the image you are l want to add the image name.
And we also want to add the message.
So those three things.
So where do we get the image you are.
Oh look it's this download you are all things so we're just going to say download your elders to string
and boom that's all we need to send that as an extra.
Well what about the image name.
Well remember we had that as a property up here at the top so we simply just have to type image name.
Boom.
That was handled.
How do we get the message.
Well we get our message at.
Text Text and then turn that into a string.
Now it's important.
Make sure you have message and text text to string.
Also a question mark there but when I was building this app preparing for it to teach you this I forgot
the text and did to string and literally the message check that was coming through was that was saying
oh edit text that blah blah blah blah.
And it was trying to turn the actual edit text into a string rather than the text inside of the text
anyways.
Small little difference make sure you have this text or to get a really weird air that will just kind
of make your mind hurt.
So once we were passing these three pieces of information then we can come back and start adding these
in.
So as far as the image name goes rather than an empty string We're first going to get the intent.
And we want to get a string extra with the name of Dimage name boom.
That one's done as far as the image you are all goes again.
Let's get the intent.
Get string extra and the name for this one is image you are.
Boom that's all done.
And the last one for the message we're going to do our intent not get string extra and we'll just provide
the name of the message here.
Make sure it's spelled correctly and that should be all we need.
So now if we we're going to send when it should have everything required so let's go ahead and try this
or run this and this will kind of be our final step to see if you know if we're ready to then allow
user to see if they have any new snaps to view.
So go ahead and run that.
Looks like it's coming up.
So here's the app.
And in the background I want to have this here so you can see this so let's create a snap and I'm actually
going to send this to ourselves so we can see what it is.
And in this case I'm actually going to pick a particular image and I can provide a message like our
first snap and I'll hit next year.
I should go do all that.
Awesome upload stuff and I'm going to send it to my self so that I can.
When we're you know sort of testing I'm working around here that I can actually see this information.
So I a select Nick at Zappy code just like that.
Oh my goodness.
Look at that.
Nick now has a Snap's inside of his Snap's child.
And if we open it up hey this is from Joe at Zappy.
Oh I forgot we were signed in as Joe.
OK.
Well I'll have to sign out and come back in his neck.
But there's an image name here.
There's an image you are all in.
There's the text.
Our first snaps we have everything that we need.
So let's go ahead and log out here.
I'm going to come back in as Nick and I have the code at the Cocom the BCT one two three four and we
should be able to come in so now because I'm signed in as Nick this is where we should be seen a list
of all the snaps that have been sent to us.
But right now we don't have anything.
So let's go ahead and get a snap listing.
And then in the next lecture We'll talk about how we can view it get it to delete all that stuff but
I at least want them to show up in a list.
This will be a big step for us.
So let's go ahead and go back to our Snap's activity right.
That's where we should be listing out all the snaps that people have sent to us and talk about what
it is that we're going to need here.
So the first thing is we need a list view.
So we're going to have to open up the layout file for that so Snap's activity.
And we don't even have a list view inside of there so I can't even get an idea.
I don't have a list view so containers.
Let's have a list view.
I'm going to call this the snaps list view seems simple enough.
OK.
Now we don't need this file anymore.
That's the only thing visually that's going to be inside of there.
But once we have that we need to go ahead and add this to the top as a prop..
So will the Save our snaps list view is going to be of type list view nullable that you get to know
them inside of her and create We're going to set that up so Snap's list views equal defined view by
ID or not.
Id snaps list view.
Awesome.
So now we have an appropriate list view.
Then we need to go ahead and do similar to only what we've done before to get you know the adapter and
everything working out.
So in fact we can just go to our Choose user activity and I'm just going to copy these two lines of
code come back and paste it in.
All right we will have to change a few things like it's not choose user list view it's snaps list view
and then also here we don't have something called emails in fact we don't have anything which then brings
up the question what what is it that we're going to have.
We want to have a list of the emails of people who have sent us a snap and so we're going to create
a new array list here so going to call this one e-mails.
And this is going to be of type Snap's or we want this to be re list of strings and we're going to set
this equal to a new array list boom.
So now we can go ahead and provide e-mails.
There we go.
All right I guess that was the same name so that's pretty good that that all worked out we ended up
not having to change that but then we need to fill up the e-mails array list with some actual pertinent
information.
So with this in place let's go ahead and talk about how we can get these from the firebase database
like we're trying to if I'm signed in as Nick is that be code I'm trying to get to my snaps and list
all of these out and I'm trying to you know poll who it is that it's from.
So I'm going to go back to android studio here after I've set up the adapter and all that good stuff.
I'm going to get access to firebase database of firebase database.
Get instance Dockett reference.
Let's give ourselves some space to work with here then on this.
I want to get to the child of users then I want to find myself right which in order to do that I'm going
to have to you know figure out where that is and so we need to use this time off so we're going to say
Dot child we're looking for em off dot and we want to get the current user.
And then we want to go ahead and get the current users you ID.
All right.
So with this we've got to go ahead and provide that this is not going to be no else will go and then
that question mark and then after we're here we want to go and get to the Snap's for ourselves so we're
going to go to child one more time and say Snap's right inside of there and then this is where again
we want to do a add child eventless center just like we've done before so I say add child event listener
and we're going to provide inside of here something like object colon and then we want a child event
listener.
Now with this we have no functionality in fact let's go ahead and do our curly brackets here.
But if we select object here and go hit the red light bulb we can say hey go implement.
I wanted all of them so go back and do that again but forgot to select them so select everything had
OK boom.
Now we have everything.
And in fact it might be a little bit simpler if I just go back to the choose user activity and copy
what we have here because that's sort of already formatted how we like it.
So we'll just paysite in.
But now we'll just know that we can't we're not going to use the information that we had done before
there.
So now we get this awesome code for the on child added and then we have to make it so that we can go
through each of these and go pull the appropriate emails and then add them to the list.
So what we're going to do is take our e-mails array list and we are going to add onto that and we're
going to add on this piece zero snapshot.
We need to do this to say Dot child to then go see who it's from.
So essentially you know we've gotten to for example this that we're trying to see who it's from so we're
doing that.
So we're going to get to the child from then on that we want to get to it's value.
And we should specify that this should come through as a string.
So that's going to add it to the e-mails array list then we've got to say that our adapter should be
notified of that the dataset changed and then we should be able to list out all the steps.
So let's go ahead and try this I will run the app here.
So this should work.
The second that this opens up it should show the one that came from Joe at Zappy code.
But then also did just kind of prove that this works and oh we've got an error here.
We forgot to do a question mark here.
Go ahead and that well we're not done yet.
Let's see it still needs to have another question mark there.
All right.
Let's go ahead and test that out which is what it told me before I started trying to build the app or
whatnot but we'll get the one from Joe Zappy code but then also we'll send one to ourselves to really
prove that this is working exactly like we were hoping for.
So let me go ahead and get the database in the background so should be this snap that should show up
and look there's a Joe Zappy code.
I think that's the one to really prove that this is working.
Let's go ahead and create a new snap for this one.
Select one of these images and I'll say from me.
Smiley face for this one that will go and upload that and look it spinless back to the Snap's page and
it shows I've got one now from Nicot zip code and one from Joe Zappy called com.
All right.
So excellent place to stop right here we're getting really really close.
We just need to make it so now when a user taps on one of these then we can go ahead and add the appropriate
information like oh or not add the appropriate information we need to show the user the information
right.
When you download the image show him what the messages whatever that may be.
And then we need to make it when they hit the back button delete so will cover all of that in the next
lecture.