So were able to successfully now log into the app create a snap including uploading an image and a message
saying who we want to send it to and then then that person when they open up the app is going to see
all the messages that they have.
So really the last step for us is we have to let the user be able to view the snaps that have been sent
to them and when they're done viewing to then go delete the image on the back and delete it from the
database.
All that good information.
So let's now write the code that we need to make it so that when someone taps on one of these then we
can go see what that particular snap looks like.
So in order to do that we're gonna have to move on to a new activity so let's get back to android studio
and make our last activities are a new activity and we'll just go ahead and do our empty one just like
we've done before and I'm going to call this the view snap activity that kind of describes what's going
on.
So we'll get finished there.
Now with this view snap activity what is it that we're trying to display here.
What we'll try to display whatever the message is and then also the image the image is kind of the most
important thing here.
But let's go ahead and put just with text a text you up at the top here that will display whatever it
is that the messages.
So we'll go ahead and add that one to make sure that we right click here and say this should be centered.
And we also want to it looks like we're going to have to wait for the grade all to finish up here to
do that.
So it's looks like it's done now going to Right-Click center that good to have it be connected up to
the top and looks like that's been connected now with a height of 16 that looks good.
We wanted to go all the way to the edges in case it's really big.
And so I'm going to go ahead and put the 16 on the edges here and then we'll just go ahead and change
this so it actually fills all the way then that's going to make it so that we have to have our text
be centered because you can see it's kind of off to left.
I think it looks best if it's all sort of centered so for text alignment we'll go ahead and change this
too.
Let's get that dropdown menu we want it to be Center.
There we go that looks looking good.
We got the text view there.
Now we need to add an image view.
So I'm going to bring out an image view by default.
We'll just have it you know fill some sort of color in just to keep things different.
We'll have this one maybe be a dark color.
Well let's keep it pink so that we can know that's kind of what we've used to tell the user that we're
waiting for an image to come through.
But with this you know we want to connect this up to the friend there who like that.
Let's go ahead and make this big enough that we can actually work with it.
And it's not going to let us do that.
OK so we want to connect this to the left to the right to the bottom save maybe say 16 for this 16 for
that and 16 for the bottom.
We also want to connect up to the top and that is not connecting to the text you like I like it.
So maybe you'll have to manually click drag.
There we go.
And we'll have that be 16 as well.
I will go ahead and change these so they fill up the appropriate space.
Ooh.
There we go.
Nice big image you.
It's great then with this text view.
I'm going to go ahead and call this the message text view.
All right.
And then we'll have to give a proper ID for the image of you.
Let's call this the snap image.
You all right now that we got that all in place we shouldn't need that design file anymore but we'll
have to go ahead and get some stuff connected here like that text view and the image view that we just
brought over.
So let's go ahead and start there.
We'll call this first.
The message text view and this will be a text view knowable which will initially be no notice and then
will also have the snap image view which should be a image you know a ball and that will also be able
to know initially.
OK so let's go ahead and set these up message text for you your equal to find view by id our DOT ID
message it.
Oh not a text message text view.
There we go.
And then for a snap image view say you're equal to find view by ID card that Id snap the image view.
Excellent.
So we've got all of that in place but then we've got to make right the code so that we can move into
this view snap activity so let's go back to our Snap's activity and even I guess before then we need
to make it so that when someone selects an item from the list view that we go ahead and get them to
the correct place.
So we need to get our list view which is the Snap's list view and put a little question mark there and
we're going to set in an item click listener so that equal to adapter view dot on item click list or
the one with curly brackets.
So say yes for all those.
So now we can run some code when we get all this information.
And I guess the first thing that we want to do is we want to get the appropriate snap that someone has
selected right because there's going to be you know one from Joe one from Nick there could be a whole
lot more there.
Got to know which one it is that they picked.
So I hear tell us the proper index that was used but you know we have to use that appropriately.
And so right now we're not listing all the actual snapshots of these snaps and that's important because
the snapshots can stain contain information about you know what the image you are l is what the message
is.
And so we need to get all of that inside of a separate array list.
So we're going to make a new frailest here cold snaps.
And this is also going to be an array list but it's not going to be in a list of strings.
This is going to be an array list of the data snapshots of data snapshot.
I just set this equal to an empty array list and then here inside of this on child added We're going
to take our snaps array list and we are going to add on to it.
This data snapshot that we got so it's really just as simple as passing peer zero into there.
I mean we'll have to you know confirm that there's actually something in there so that are two exclamation
points but that's all we need to add that to there.
So now down below we can say.
All right.
On a new value that I'm going to be calling the snapshot in this is equal to Snap's dot get and then
we just simply pass and.
And now we have the snapshot that we can work with and pull out all the proper information.
So what things do we need we need to know the image name the image you are l the message the key that's
part of that snap and so there's all sorts of different things that we need here.
But first let's just make an intent that will get us to that new activity so we'll say intent is equal
to new capital intent and inside of here.
We're going to provide this.
And then where we're trying to move to is the viewer snap activity once you get the class for that.
Eventually we're going to want to start that intent.
So we'll go ahead and do our start activity but in between there's a lot of information that we want
to provide via extras.
So we're going to do our intent put extra.
So one of those things is going to be the image name.
All right and we're going to go ahead and copy and paste this for everything that we need so copy and
paste paste paste.
So once the image name one is going to be the image you are all one is going to be the message.
And then lastly we need to have the key for this snapshot so that we can go ahead and properly delete
it.
So we're also going to have to provide these when I'm going to call the snap key.
You'll see how this comes into play.
But first if we want to provide the image name well let's get into this snapshot that we have so snapshot
dot and let's get to the child child and we want to get to the one that's named image name and then
we want it's value which should come through as a string.
And that is properly set and we're essentially doing the same thing for the next two.
So I'm just going to copy and paste this below and then we'll have to change.
You know in this case we're trying to get the image you are ill and in this case we're trying to get
the message right.
So then the last piece for the snap key we just have to do snapshot snapshot dot and then it has this
key function here which will go get the key for that which this is going to be you know a little random
string of letters and numbers here.
So with all of that in place we then have all the proper information flowing over to this view snap
activity.
So with all of this now we can then go ahead and fill up everything that we need to.
So for example we can set that message text view we can download an image right.
All that good stuff.
And so first let's just go ahead and set the message text for you I think that's a good place to start.
So we're going to say message text viewed text is going to be equal to.
Let's go grab the intent dot get string extra.
And we should get whatever the messages and pass that through.
Let me do a question mark there because that's knowable but that's literally all it takes to show the
message.
Now to get the image.
Now that's a little bit more work because we have to go and download an image and I talked about this
earlier in the section but we've already done the code to properly go find and download an image and
so I'm just going to open that up from a previous project again.
I think that was Section 5 that we've done that.
So I'm going to go to my downloads here and this project called downloading images and I'm going to
open this up.
This should have all the code that we need in order to make this work.
So here it comes.
Yep and here inside of this mine activity remember the big thing was this image downloader that allows
us to go and grab an image so I'm going to copy this public class and just copyright like that we're
going to move this down below so we can sort of differentiate between the two.
And so I'm going to come back to my view snap activity and after outside of the function here I'm going
to paste in that class which is going to say hey do you want to convert this.
We'll say yes and yes please go get all those awesome imports.
All right so that'll go do all the proper importation that we need.
But then the next thing that we needed to do is we need to you know go fire off that function of you
know going and getting that image.
So when we go back to our other project here and this is where we want to then go copy all this code
where we create a new image downloader and you know we try catch all this stuff so I'm just going to
copy come back and paste this in.
And yes I'm going to ask it to do the import of this last time we work on this.
It was getting the image of Homer Simpson How great is that.
So rather than get your own We're not we're not looking for Homer Simpson here.
Instead we want to get whatever the image your L is and we have that via the intent so we're just going
to say intent get string extra not a Rackstraw get string extra.
And that will just be image you l.
And then once we've done that we're trying to set the image which in this case is not called image you
would snap image.
So we'll just change this to snap image view and remember to put a little question mark there to make
sure that everything works out.
And really that's all it should take in order to get this up and running.
So big moment for us here we should see now when we run this app that we have the ability to view these
snaps that people have sent us.
So let's go ahead and give this a moment and while this is loading I'm going to close out of these other
projects so it doesn't slow us down here.
Leave open this snap chat project.
But here we go.
Pops the app and I'm so excite Let's see what that one from Joe is that should be the one that says
like our first snapper or whatever sold click on that and boom look at that.
Our first snap and it shows the proper image there we can go back.
Let's look at Nick what did he send us from me.
Kind of the message but look at that.
We have a functional project now.
You could argue that we have left out maybe the most important part of this and that's that the whole
lure of Snapchat is that once you open something it's then deleted so that you know you can kind of
send stuff and not really care like oh maybe there's an ugly picture of me but you know it's going to
be deleted doesn't really matter.
So we've got to make it so that after a user views something and then hits the back button that that
image that snap is completely deleted.
Well how do we do that.
First we've got to run some code here inside of the snap activity when someone hits the back button.
So we're going to go ahead and type out one of those on back pressed again.
Keep in that super combat press but now inside of here this is where we want to run some code to go
delete information.
So there's kind of two things that we have to delete.
One is we have to delete the database reference so if we looked at this snap from Joe we want to delete
from this level right here.
That's one thing that we want to delete.
The next thing that we want to delete is in storage.
We have images right.
And we would want to delete the image file so that we don't know if we've promised the users that we
delete it we should delete it but even more than that if we don't delete these images they're just going
to get bigger and bigger and eventually you know it's going to we're going to pass on to a page here
of firebase And you know then we're going to start paying money for this thing and it's like now just
kind of sucks the fun out of your thing.
So remember you've got to delete the database and the storage.
So step one for us let's work on the database side of things so on this back pressed.
We're going to first work with the fire base database and we go get instance get reference you that
should just be clockwork at this point and we want to go to the child for users and we want to go to
our selves which then means we have to say Dot child and then we're going to do or we're going to have
to do the whole am off operation here so let's go back to snacks at Snap's activity because we've got
em off there we'll just copy and paste and then boom.
OK.
Also in Snap's activity we basically got all the way to where it is that we're trying to go so I'm actually
just going to copy all this code that gets us to the Snap's level for ourselves so when we come back
here and paste this in.
Right so we've got get to the database instance reference we go to users we get to the current users
you ID then we get to the Snap's and then we want to delete the particular snap here so then we're going
to say Dot and then this is where we want to do another child but we need to get the intent of from
the intent the snap key.
So we're going to say intent not get string extra.
And we want the one that we called SNAP key.
All right.
So once we've done that this part is really simple I love this.
We just say remove value and that's it.
It deletes it from the database.
That's really all we need.
I'll bring that back if you need a second here so after we go to the child where we you know figure
out what the snap key was we just simply say remove that and what it's going to do is it's going to
remove this whole thing right here.
So this whole snap with all of its information or if we deleted this one is going to delete the whole
thing.
So that's a database but what about the image side of things.
Well if we want to delete an image we're going to have to be working with firebase storage.
So when you file storage Dogget instance not get reference.
OK.
Then once we're there we want to get to the child of images right because everything is inside a folder
named images.
Then we want to get to the particular image.
So again we pass through the image name.
This is why we've included the image name as part of a snap so then we can say all right then go to
the child of intent get string extra.
We want the image name.
So this is that big long string of letters and numbers.
J bag so this will allow us to then go ahead and delete that.
So once we get to that whatever dot J pig will just simply say Dot delete.
I love the end of these two functions we have don't remove value delete.
This is just destruction going on here and it's excellent.
So this will go ahead and delete that information.
So let's go ahead and see what this looks like.
Spoiler alert there's still one more step for us to finish up here and if you can guess what it is.
Brownie points to you about why everything won't work perfectly but visually.
I mean on the back side of things you should see everything working so let's say let's view this now
from Joe.
So we'll click on it and oh we're looking at it it's great now I'm going to hit my back button.
Look at that.
It deletes it from the database.
And if we went and looked at it we would have seen the image delete this well let's do this again with
like the next one here.
So if I click on Nick right.
So I'm going to you should see this disappear.
But also the image this named six a D.
So just kind of remember that six a d f.
And in fact I guess if we wanted to really show this here let's open storage in a new tab we can see
both these things disappear.
So if we go into our images look there's that 6 ADF which is this image right here.
So once we hit the back button here that deletes from the database and if we go over here and reload
this page you will see downturn.
That image is gone.
So we've successfully cleaned up everything from the snap the image connected with it and then also
the database information.
Now you'll notice we have viewed these things they're deleted.
But when we come here they still show up and if we were to you know log out log back in it would show
empty just like we were hoping for.
But we need to add a little bit more code and that's if we go back to our Snap's activity here inside
of this on child remove.
So whenever something gets deleted this function gets called.
This is where we can appropriately say hey we've got to go remove a snap from the snaps array list and
we also got to remove something from the e-mails a re list came.
So what we're going to do is inside of here first we've got to detect and see if we're working with
the correct kind of snap.
So in order to do all of this we're going to create a for loop.
So we're going to say for let's get our curly brackets so for SNAP which is going to be of type data
a snapshot in Snap's.
Right because that's an array list here of data snapshot objects.
So for SNAP we want to go ahead and check and see if this particular snap that we're looking at in the
array list if it's key is equal to.
We want to see if it's equal to this p o here which is a data snapshot if it's equal to that key.
So if it's equal to zero dot key just like that we'll have to put a little question mark here.
But you might be wondering hey why is it that we can just say if a snap is equal to zero.
Well the problem with that is that they're not exactly the same object like they are in the Java world
they're a little bit different but the keys we can compare keys and if those are the same then we know
we can delete it.
So if that's the case if these are the same then we're going to want to go ahead and remove these from
the appropriate array list for both the e-mails and the Snap's right and our two array lists here.
So for the Snap's right we're going to say Snap's dot remove at and when we do this remove at we have
to know what index it is that we're at.
So we're going to kind of do a little cheat here where we're going to say var index is equal to zero.
We're going to make this little variable here.
And after the end of the state will say index plus plus.
So it might have been better to do a for loop where we you know said I's equal to zero blah blah blah.
But this is kind of a little fun way to do this index.
There we go.
But now we since we're keeping track the index of how we're looping through here we can say remove at
index pass that through.
Same thing goes for the e-mails we can see e-mails that remove at and pass in the index.
So this should be everything that we need.
Let's go ahead and run this big big moment here for us.
App is opening up and just for fun here just because let's go back in our database.
There's no Snap's.
I'm going to race everything out of because remember we had created a few images without you know connecting
them to a Snap's I'm going to select everything here.
Delete it all just so we're at a completely clean slate.
So you know let's do the full process here.
I'm going to log in and in fact I'll make a new user.
I'm going to make Laura at Zappy code dot com password.
BCT one two three four.
This will create a new user for us which if we go to the database look at that.
Oh we have somebody new.
We will then create a snap.
I'm going to choose an image.
Oh look this square looks nice.
I'll say a message.
We did it.
Exclamation point.
Super happy face x happy face then will hit next.
This will upload the image.
So to check this out go ahead reload here.
Should see an image now.
Yes that looks good.
Then we're going to say who should we send this to send it to ourselves so we can see this.
We'll go ahead and select that.
Boom.
There's something in the database and already it's showing for us here inside of our Snap's activity.
Look and it should have all of this information inside of it.
With that we did it in our funny faces so we'll select this.
Look at that shows the message shows the image.
Now watch as we hit the back button that gets deleted.
And oh it still shows here.
Also I built this all up.
It didn't even work well.
That's because we forgot to notify the list adapter that we needed to update things.
So what we're going to do is after we've done this will then go ahead and say OK after you've done your
cool re loop for loop or whatever we need to get our adapter and say notify data set change.
It was going to be so cool to show you that we had all of that but just to prove that everything's gone
here over on the storage side of things there should be no images and no images.
So I won't go through the full process again I'll just very quickly create a snap here.
So we'll pick a cool image say boy.
This time not as graceful but it to Laura which sends it to ourselves.
Oh look.
There it is.
I select it.
A nice nap and moment of truth that the back button.
It's gone.
We deleted it.
OK.
Well congratulations.
You finished it.
We have a fully functional snap chat up.
This is probably one of the most difficult apps that we've built to date.
And we did it with the new technology of firebase and Cartland So pretty cool that you got to cover
a whole lot of different things with a really complex app.
You know should be one of the crown jewels that you keep inside of your folder of all your Android studio
projects but excited to see where you go from here.
Maybe you have your own social network that you're trying to create or an app that just requires a back
end.
I'm sure you can do great things with this so congratulations and thanks for coming along.