Now let's look at how we query.
The first step is to implement a query resolver,
which will use our repository to query the database.
I've opened the project and navigated to the Query.java file. The query
resolver allows Spring to automatically detect and call the right method in
response to one of the GraphUL queries defined inside of a schema. Notice
we have the implementation for the findAllApplications operation and the
countApplications operation.
If you remember from the GraphUL schema within our query section,
we had these two operations, findAllApplications, countApplications. Notice
for the find all applications, it's a simple call out to our
applicationRepository to find all of the applications. And in a similar
manner, on line 21 for countApplications, we're making a call to the count
method of the application repository. The query response is typically sent using JSON.