Now that we have everything in place, let's see the GraphQL server in action.
We'll look at the GraphQL server, testing the GraphQL API, we'll look
a GraphiQL, and we'll run queries and mutations.
Let's take a look at GraphiQL. I've deployed and launched the
application, and let's navigate to a web browser.
And in that web browser,
the URL that you would use is localhost:8080/graphiql. Notice there is an
i in between graph and ql. On the left‑hand side, this is the command
window where you enter the queries or mutations.
The Execute button is right here in the upper left‑hand corner.
When you execute a query, it will show here on the right‑hand side.
If you expand this Docs,
there is a documentation tab where you can see all of
the queries and mutations available.
So, for example,
for the queries, we have findAllApplications,
countApplications. And for the mutation,
we have newApplication, deleteApplication,
updateApplication.
That's what we expect.
So let's test the query type.
So let's input this query. Notice the query is findAllApplications,
and in this case, I want it to return an id.
Let's execute, and it returns back only the IDs of the
applications because that's what I asked for.
Now let's return back the id and the owner. And notice there's auto
complete. That really helps. And notice now I get back the id and the
owner because that's what I asked for.
Lastly, let's bring back the description, and there we have it.
We have the id, owner, and description. GraphQL offers ultimate flexibility in
that you can get back exactly what you need from the API.
Now let's test mutations.
I do want to note that I went back and stopped the application and
renamed this data.sqlzzzz file so that I could start with an empty
database and relaunch my application.
Now let's add a mutation to create a new application. So
notice I have the keyword mutation.
I have the name of the operation, newApplication.
I have the values that I'm passing in, name,
owner, and description, and then I'm having the values here that I want returned.
So let's execute this, and it created a newApplication with an
id of 1 with the values that I provided.
Now let's look at an update.
So again, we have the mutation keyword.
Now we're calling out to the updateApplicationOwner operation.
We're passing in the newOwner and the id.
So this is for the one that we just created,
and I want back id, name, description, and owner.
So here, Kim Jones is now the new owner for the application.
Now let's see what happens when we attempt to update
an application that doesn't exist.
So let's just change this id to a random number that
does not exist, and let's execute.
And as we expected,
we're receiving the custom Application Not Found error
message that we created for error handling.
You can also delete data. So notice here, we're using the
mutation keyword again, the operation,
which is deleteApplication, and we're passing in the id.
So let's execute it, and we receive back deleteApplication equals true,
so that means the application was deleted. So that's a quick
look at GraphiQL. It's a very useful tool for testing mutations and queries against a GraphQL server.