For starters,
the dependency needed for spring MVC is spring‑boot‑starter‑web, and as
soon as I add spring‑boot‑starter‑web as a dependency in the project,
Spring Boot's autoconfiguration sees that Spring MVC's on the class path
and autoconfiguration kicks in,
and it provides all of the dependencies and the autoconfiguration
needed to develop web applications, a dispatcher servlet, a default
error page, an embedded servlet container, Tomcat is the default, and
WebJars to manage static dependencies.
Next, let's talk about MVC,
which stands for model‑view‑controller and is one of
the most common design patterns.
I've been in the IT industry for over 20 years,
and one of the very first web apps I developed used this pattern. MVC
decouples major components to promote faster development cycles and
works well for developing large‑scale web applications that need to be
supported by large teams of developers.
Let's look at each component.
The M in MVC stands for model,
and it is the representation of data in a system,
sometimes called an entity or a domain model.
The model is typically data stored in a database,
and is programmatically represented as a java object.
For example, in TrackZilla, there's a screen that shows a list of applications.
The model contains the list of applications.
The V in MVC stands for view.
The view layer is responsible for displaying data, or the model.
In Java the view is typically done in JSP, JSF.
In our case study, we are using Thymeleaf,
which we will talk about in more detail.
The C in MVC stands for controller.
The controller is responsible for directing incoming user
requests to the correct resources and sending responses from
those resources back to the user.
For example,
the controller will get a request to see a list of TrackZilla tickets.
Then it will direct that request to the ticket service,
which returns the list of tickets, and the controller routes
the list of tickets to the view for display.
Thymeleaf has this concept of fragments, which is very powerful.
Fragments allow you to define repeatable chunks of code that can be
reused in another Thymeleaf template file. This works great for
components which you wish to reuse across your web pages. For the
TrackZilla application, the nav bar is a fragment, or a component, that is shared across the index page, the applications page, releases, and tickets.