REST stands for Representational State Transfer.
It's a set of guidelines that application developers use to design APIs.
There are four principles that APIs follow. First data and functionality in
the API are considered resources and identify through something called the
URI, or the Uniform Resource Identifier.
These are accessed by Web links. Second, resources are
manipulated using a fixed set of operations.
GET retrieves a resource, POST creates one, use PUT to update the resource, and,
of course, DELETE will remove it.
Third, resources can be represented in multiple formats like HTML,
XML, plain text, and other formats defined by a media type.
Finally, communication between the client and endpoint is stateless,
meaning the server will not remember or store any state about the client that made the call.