Now that we have the database properly configured
and accessible via a web browser,
let's talk about object‑relational mapping with the Java Persistence
API. There are several layers of abstraction. At the lowest level,
there is the persistence data store.
Above that is JDBC. JDBC is a Java API to connect and
execute queries against the database.
JPA is an abstraction on top of JDBC that makes it easy to map Java
objects to relational databases and vice versa.
Now JPA is just a specification or a set of
guidelines and can do nothing on its own,
as it is only a set of empty methods and collection of interfaces that
only describe Java persistence methodologies. In order to be fully
functional, JPA needs an implementation,
also known as an instance provider.
If you're familiar with Spring, Spring with JPA uses Hibernate
as the persistence provider and makes it very easy to access our
H2 database. Spring Data JPA provides repository support for the
Java persistence API.
It eases development of applications that need to access JPA Data sources.
Spring Boot selects a recent version of Spring Data modules for you. In
the POM file, I've included spring‑boot‑starter‑jpa,
which is a starter that provides a quick way to get started.
It provides the following key dependencies, Hibernate,
which is one of the most popular JPA implementations, Spring Data JPA,
which makes it easy to implement JPA‑based repositories, and Spring ORM. It's the core ORM support for the Spring framework.