I just wanted to show you a quick and easy way to test the REST
API. I'm using a tool called cURL, and that essentially lets us
call out to APIs from the command line.
So the command is curl and then the URL.
So in this case,
it's tza/applications. And we see a list of the
applications in the database returned.
Let's also look at the tickets. So you would use curl and then the URL,
which is tza/tickets, and then this shows a list of tickets.
And let's look for one specific application.
So we're going to pass in the ID of one,
and that returns back the correct application.
This just shows a quick way to test APIs that you develop.
You can also use a tool like Postman, it has a really nice graphical user interface.