Entities are objects that live in a database,
and they have the ability to be mapped to a database.
Entities are defined by the @Entity annotation,
and on this screen we are looking at the Application entity. And we
will see the detailed code for this in a moment.
Traditionally, JPA entity classes are specified in a persistence.xml file.
However, with Spring Boot, this file is not necessary,
and entity scanning is used. By default, all packages
below the main configuration class,
the one annotated with either @SpringBootApplication or
@EnableAllConfiguration are searched. Any classes annotated with @Entity are included.