I've opened the code for Module4 and navigated to the pom.xml file.
Let's take a look at the dependencies.
First, on line 24, we have the spring‑boot‑starter.
Next, on line 29, we have the spring‑boot‑starter‑test.
We've seen these two before.
Notice here on line 34, there's now a dependency for the H2 in‑memory database,
and its scope is set at runtime. And here on line 41, there's also a dependency
for the spring‑boot‑starter‑data‑jpa. This adds the Spring Data JPA so that we
can communicate with the database.
Now let's look more closely at the TrackZilla Application.
TrackZilla has three domain entities that represent the business
data captured by the system, so Application,
Release, and Ticket.
Let's take a look at Application. For Application, this domain
entity represents the application that a bug or enhancement
request or ticket will be tracked against. Notice here on line
5, the @Entity annotation.
This is just indicating that it's a JPA entity. For a lack of
a table annotation, it assumes that this entity will be mapped
to a table named Application.
Let's look at the id property here on line 11.
The id property is annotated with @Id so that JPA
will recognize it as an object's ID.
The object property is also annotated here on line 9 with the @GeneratedValue
to indicate that the ID should be generated automatically.
There's another domain entity called a Ticket.
Let's look at that. Again, it's annotated with @Entity.
The Ticket simply represents the actual bug or
enhancement request for a given application.
So notice it has an ID, it has a title,
and it has a description. And the last entity is a Release.
Again, we're using the @Entity annotation,
and the Release represents a software release.
So notice there's an ID, a releaseDate, and a description.
Now let's talk about repositories.
The Spring Data repository abstraction greatly reduces the
need to have boilerplate code to implement data access for an
H2 in‑memory database, and, really, for any database.
So let's take a look at that.
There are actually three here, ApplicationRepository,
ReleaseRepository, and TicketRepository.
Let's look at the ApplicationRepository. The Spring Data JPA
repository allows us to access data by creating JPA queries
automatically from a method name.
So let's look at this in more detail.
Notice this is an interface. And, as a matter of fact,
all three of these are interfaces. But notice there's no implementation.
That's because Spring Boot automatically provides the implementation for us.
So let's look at this.
All we need to do is extend CrudRepository and pass in the
domain class or the entity class to be managed and then the
ID of the domain class type.
And that's it.
Spring Data JPA handles the rest for us.
Now let's test this out.
Navigate to the Main application class. In our example,
it's FundamentalsApplication. Notice here on line 23,
I've added a CommandLineRunner.
This makes it a simple command line base application.
So, first, it fetches the ApplicationRepository from the Spring
application context. And then on lines 25 through 28, I'm just
simply saving new Applications to the database,
and I'm using the save method on the ApplicationRepository, so three
applications, TrackZilla, Expenses, and Notifications with additional
detail like the owner and the description. Next, here on lines 29
through 31, I'm fetching all of the application objects and printing
it out to the screen.
In order to execute this, simply click the green arrow here,
or you can click the Run here, and we'll see the output in the bottom window.
And I'm copying that so I can search for it when it finally comes up.
And so let's search for it in here.
We're printing out the three applications that we just added,
TrackZilla, Expenses, and Notifications. So that's a look at how easy it is to access databases from Spring Boot.