[Autogenerated] Hello and welcome to my cost on deploying code
with AWS Codedeploy first a little bit about me.
My name's Joshua Edwards.
I'm the vice president of Engineering, Blockchain and Cryptocurrency Focus.
Business.
I have previously being the head of devils,
and I've used codedeploy on a day to day basis.
This course is going to be focused on Amazon.
Web service is codedeploy.
Codedeploy is a super powerful automated deployment service for eight of
us that allows you to deploy coat in a number of ways.
This course will cover free Main Service's codedeploy deploys, too.
Pre records is required to make this possible and finally,
how to monitor and deep of the deployment.
By the end of this cause, you'll be well on your way to becoming a codedeploy.
But before beginning the course, you should be familiar with E.
C.
Two E.
S on London.
It's not necessary to be well versed in these service is
as a walking through using all of them.
From here, you should feel comfortable diving into further aid.
Arrest Deb Up service is with courses on codepipeline on code pilled.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn all about codedeploy with the deploying code with AWS codedeploy calls at a florist