[Autogenerated] first we need to make sure you have
the right prerequisites in places.
Employee code to London with codedeploy.
So let's take a look at what we've got to do.
There are five things you're going to need to have ready and set up
before deploying Code of co deployed to London.
You're going to need tohave an I am identity user.
You're going to need to have a duress sale I set up.
You're going to new service role for London.
You guys,
even I am instance profile are finally going to need to have Sam cli Let's
go ahead and jump into a demo and create the psalms.
Eli.
Good news.
Because we've already created the four first
prerequisites in the previous modules.
We just need to focus on setting up the eight arrests.
I'm cli so let's get started.
Okay, so I'm on the Sam page on the AWS website on.
You can see what your other is up here.
All you need to do scroll down on this page, pick your operating system.
I am a Mac, so I'm going to install a brew tap for eight of us.
Perfect.
And then I'm going to install the Sam CLI.
Okay, And that's really it.
That's all you have to do unless test that's being installed.
I just typing in, Sam.
Uh, there it is.
How close up. Let's move on to the next section of our module.