[Autogenerated] Okay, so now we have set up that easy to is this profile,
which is our final prerequisite?
Let's take a look at managing the CODEDEPLOY.
Agent in this next demo.
We're going to cover the following.
We're going to install the CODEDEPLOY.
Agent.
We're gonna verify the agent is ruining.
Begin, determine Aversion.
I'm a go to update the agent.
Okay, so the first part of our demo,
we're going to create a Amazon Lennox instance.
And then we're going to install the CODEDEPLOY agent more.
Select Amazon Lennox, too.
Frito is fine.
All the defaults of fine default storage is fired.
I don't need any tax on.
I'm going Thio Great.
A security group that allows me to access the instance from my I p address.
Only that all looks fine.
Pit launch.
I have access to this keeper on Let's launch this instant.
Ooh, Awesome.
Right.
Let's have a look at this.
So take the public I p address.
Okay, so now that's instances.
Readyto ss Section two.
Let's go on there.
Effect on.
The first thing we're going to do is we're going to
update you so pseudo your update.
That's why perfect.
And then we're going to install Ruby,
then going to curl and install file from the codedeploy ESRI bucket sources.
So let's have a look what we've got here.
I'm currently deploying this into Ireland,
so wherever your region is, you'll just replace that part of the girl.
So let's install this.
This check is there forces, right?
Let's make it executable.
But it on then we're going to run the installer.
How easy was that?
So now we've just installed the CODEDEPLOY agent.
Ah, how do we check that?
It's really and how do we start it on etcetera?
So let's have a look so you can use the service command
and check that it's running perfect, because you can also restart a cz.
Well, if we change out the status to start on our restart,
their you could just check That's running again.
Brilliant.
The next thing we're gonna do is we're gonna check the age and version.
So if we have a look at this file and we can it out,
you see what version is running a cult?
A place.
So we here we can see agent version official, they're perfect on.
We can also update that really easy as well.
We can audience stole the Asian.
We can literally just run this command.
I know no update itself.
And then that's checker.
That's running again.
Cool. How easy is that?