[Autogenerated] Okay, so now we have e CS and code to play set up.
Let's look at how to monitor the service is And it's gonna be
similar to in the previous module when we looked at cloudwatch in
this demo would go into cover the following.
We're going to look a tko deploy and cloudwatch events
similar to in the previous module on.
Then we're going to look at some of the logs in Cloudwatch, too.
Okay, So when we're deep book in codedeploy with VCs,
it's going to be similar to when we were deployed to the sea,
too.
I think the first port of call really would be to look at the
deployment and see if there are any areas that pop up and then
go through those errors and fix him.
We have a lot of these Service is already being created forwards and
automatically building on that cloud free point.
Oh, architecture.
Probably not a lot really going to go wrong.
Um, and if it does, you'd probably see it here.
So, you know, similar to it.
With easy to, we can see all the different deployment hooks from the expect file.
We can see what succeeded eso.
Then let's jump over to E.
C.
S on here.
Remember when we seen the task spinning up?
We could probably see here if a task failed to spin up.
That's probably more to do with your container.
You can actually have a look at the logs as well.
Here.
Ah, and these are just pulled in from Cloudwatch.
So we can actually see what was out.
Put it from a container from the commands that we put in.
Um, if we switch over to the cloudwatch dashboard on we go thio locks, maybe.
Look, groups, Yes.
Oh,
we can see here that the that's where the locks that would be
important to VCs are created on might be a little bit more
comprehensive in here would be easier to read.
So that's that part of it that's probably more deep
booking your container probably a little bit outside of
scope of this module on course on.
And then you also have the cloudwatch events which are
similar to of easy to where we can, you know,
select the service in here.
There it is.
You know, then we can also, uh, notifications and alerts on these events.
too.
Such a state changes and you already know that from the last module.
So again,
super easy to use on super simple to debug on monitor using 80
rest service's that are already available.
Let's have a quick recap.
We just covered codedeploy on E.
C s.
We looked at the prerequisites required.
We then deployed T.
C s and then we updated E CSU's in Codedeploy.
We then looked at some monitoring indeed,
bugging similar to with the easy to module.
The thing is, well,
it's good to remember that codedeploy is really flexible and we used
it as a quick hello world service with fargate.
But you don't have to use fargate to use code diplo VCs.
You can't create more customizable configurations and also use that. Okay, let's go on to the next module.