[Autogenerated] Okay, so now we have the codedeploy.
Agent running and have an application deployed to R E.
C to Auto Scaling Group.
Let's have a look how to monitor and troubleshoot in this demo.
We're going to cover monitoring and troubleshooting.
We're going to view locked air from the codedeploy agent on R E.
C.
Two instance,
and then we're going to look at the cloud watch events for codedeploy We
can then see from here if it's being a success or fail.
You will also get an alert message that pops up saying the error.
If we scroll down, we can select our deployment event to our instance,
and we can also see from here if anything have failed,
that's probably the easiest way to see if a deployment has failed or no.
The next step I would do after that is I would go on to
the actual instance on view the locks.
So if we head over to our easy to dashboard on DDE,
we jump onto ah instance from here,
we can see if the codedeploy service is running on the instant.
Yeah, we can check.
That's right on.
We can also view the lock data for our deployment.
So if we tail the code to play log file here,
you can actually see if anything has been a success or an error
code to play makes it super easy to debug.
The next thing over check is,
if your instance has the correct permissions to access s free,
or whether your codedeploy has the correct service role to access.
Easy to.
You can also check the security groups to make sure that your
instance has the right level of outbound Internet access on
the right level of inbound access.
Here we can see the code to play.
I am Roll we created earlier is attached to our instance on Over On code apply.
We should be able to also see with service role.
Okay, so for the next part of the demo,
we're going to look at the cloudwatch codedeploy events.
So let's go overto the cloudwatch dashboard and then let's go on to the events.
We're guests died.
If we select service in here,
we can go to Codedeploy and then we can also select a different
type of events that we want to have a look at.
So all events will look any state changes on a P I calls from cloudtrail.
Let's drill into the state changes a bit more.
We can specify any detail types that we want thio alert on, such as ST Changes.
We're gonna have a look at specific states such as Ready Start,
stop or success on.
We can actually set it up toe have our specific application that we created.
Here's a preview of the event pattern.
Let me just make that bit bigger.
And you can see here that on a successful state change,
we can create a notification that's all well and good.
But if we don't actually do something without notification,
then what's the point?
So you can actually set up a target for your cloudwatch event,
such as a lambda function.
If you have one on, then that lambda function can manipulate that data on dhe.
Potentially send it to slack.
This builds upon a death SEK ups approach on.
You can monitor on alert on any changes in your environment.
If you want to be super secure, we can have a look at the cloudtrail ones,
and here we can see on alert on any user's actions within code,
a play and the same thing again, we can out put that to the target on that.
Pass it to a function there are all sorts of talk is available.
But I think the London function was probably the most powerful because you could
manipulate the data and send it to somewhere such a slack.
Okay, let's have a quick recap.
We just covered codedeploy and easy to We looked at the
prerequisites required to install the codedeploy agent and
deploy from the code to play dashboard.
We did that using an auto scaling group on a lobe answer. And then we looked at monitoring a debugging our deployments on event actions.