Below this is Carol from for explode dot com.
And welcome to Turrell number 10 in our series of em call for Torrijos for beginners.
Today we're going to finish up of the if else statements and we're finally going to add the last bit
which is the else statement.
And so this is the code from the previous tutorial where we had two statements if and else and we'll
just get rid of this comment here at the bottom.
And as you can remember we checked whether the current bid price is less than a certain level and if
it was then we executed this bit of code which told give us some information told us to sell it gave
us recommendation to sell.
And if this condition was false then we asked the program to execute this other bit of code which also
gave us some information and gave us recommissioned by.
So going back to the terminal that's where we set our last level.
And when we execute tural turn we see that the prices above are 1 3 one point thirty six nine hundred
which is correct.
The price is above and it's telling us that we shouldn't buy in this case which could be a rule set
in our strategy.
And also it's all so but that's the sort of commission we're getting.
And before that we see this message.
So these are in reverse order.
I forget that sometimes myself.
Now let's go back to Mr. Editor and what we're going to do now is we're going to add another
condition which is called LCF another statement which also.
So in between an if and else are or even if we don't have it.
So basically after and if we can always add an ELSE else if something then do something else.
So what that means is that if your first condition is false then the program will go on to this block
and or check the second condition.
And if the second condition is true then the program will execute the code that's in here.
If this condition is also false then and only then the program will move onto getting out.
So basically we moved from two separate blocks of code to three separate blocks of code.
The first one gets executed only if this condition is true.
And then if that is the case then the rest get ignored.
If this condition is false then the same rules apply to this block and this condition is false then
the else is finely executed.
So that's not a condition here.
And to do that we'll look at another level so we have this red level Now let's say a level here.
This looks like like a support resistance level and we'll just change the color here to say aqua and
the value is one point 3 7 3.
I think we can change the it around the other way there you go.
So one point thirty seven 400 And let's go back to code and that information here so we'll add another
level.
This will be level 2 and this will be 1:37 400.
And so in case if the bid is I'll just change this to level 1 so that it makes more sense.
One year in case when the bid is less than level 1 then this code will be executed.
And then if the bid is not less than level 1.
So if it's above Level 1 we want to check whether it's still below level 2.
So this is the one.
This is level 2.
So we want to check if the bid is too low level to him he is less than 2.
In that case we will say lurks.
Price is.
We can all just leave it as takes a level one and level
and then if so but if that is not the case meaning that price is actually a bar to then you know find
a whole block of code.
We want to say exactly that the price is above level two and that's why we want to buy.
So let's compile that and see how that works.
So see here it says are the prices of Bob 1:36 mind.
Sorry my bad.
Why did I just say I can so compile it and try and
others because it took to out.
There you go.
So bid is is over there.
One point thirty seven hundred five and the price is above 1.3 74 so buy and that is correct.
Now let's see what will happen if we move this level to say for example for instance here so be 1 3
7 900 go back to Mr. Editor and replace that with that so that's level 2.
Now that's where it is.
And so as you saw in the previous case this was executed because the price was above all levels.
But now what we're expecting is that prices between these two levels.
So what we're expecting is for this part to be executed because it is less than 1.
This is level 1 this is not true this is false.
But then when we go into checking the second condition bid is less than level 2.
This condition will be true.
So this code will be executed and this code will be ignored.
So let's compile that and have a look at how it works for upturn.
So that's our current bid.
And that's the message we wanted to see.
The price is between Level 1 and level 2 goes and the price is between these two levels and what that
means is that we have just developed a very simple script that are based on this.
These two pieces of information in the beginning can provide us recommendations on what we should do
on the forex market.
So let's recap the script tells us first of all what the current price is.
And then by comparing the current bid price to these levels it will tell us whether we should buy sell
or basically do nothing in this middle case.
So the script will tell us to sell when the bid is less than level 1.
So basically whenever we're whenever the price is here the script will tell us to sell.
Now whenever whenever that's not the case this group will check if the price is still below level 2.
So the script will check if the price is below the level where we know that in that case it will be
above Level 1.
So somewhere here.
But the script will check if it's also below level 2.
So when the when prices here the script will tell us not to do anything.
Just tell us the price is between these two levels and there will be no recommendation whether to buy
or sell.
And then finally if this is not correct this is false then the script knows that the price must be somewhere
up here.
And in that case the script gives a recommendation to buy by printing this last message.
And also we're also and also were able to control the script by setting these levels here in the code.
So there you go.
Those are your first
simple advisors type typescript and I hope you found this Tauriel interesting and I encourage you to
play around with the code and see how you can adjust it to suit your own requirements.
At the same time you can always find more information tutorials on for example dot com.
I hope you can join me next.
And until then coding.