Hello this is Carol from frigs both dot com.
And welcome to the seventh tutorial in our series of em kill for tutorials for beginners.
And today we're going to be talking about the for loop.
This is the middle editor of programming environment.
And let's go ahead and create a new script.
I know we've done this a couple times already but I just think that it's a good idea to do it few more
times so it sinks in and is basically on autopilot.
So here we give our script a name here we quickly check that this is our information.
We don't need a parameters to finish and voila.
This is our script and it's going to get rid of these lines as usual.
And so today we will be talking about for loop.
It is very similar to the While loop which we talked about in tutorial 5 and that's from just going
to go back to file and copy this part of the code
and I'll just put it in here.
And so that it doesn't distract us we'll just come me up.
And as you can see this is where the multi-line comments come in handy.
All right.
So that was the while loop which we discussed previously today we're going to talk about for the for
loop also consists of three parts the word for than normal brackets and then curly brackets the curve
brackets will contain the body of the look just like with the While loop.
However the normal brackets will be different to the ones a while loop because here we'll have three
different segments and you'll see in a moment why all these three segments are relevant and how they
relate to what we saw with the wild.
So basically the first part of the four brackets is an opportunity for the programmer to introduce a
new counter variable or just a kind of variable that will be used in the loop itself.
So here we are going to introduce a new variable and i equals zero.
Second part of brackets is responsible for the value that is checked.
So here for example we will check that it is less than 5.
And then the last part of the brackets allows for the increments that are supposed to occur at the end
of each iteration of the loop.
So here we can say five plus plus and plus plus is an impression that we haven't discussed before.
Plus plus basically means the same as equals plus one.
So this will increase the value of.
I'd buy one a shorter way of writing them till four is a plus plus.
All right.
So let's see how this compares to what we had before in the wild.
So as you remember in the while loop we had a counter which we used to in order to count the iterations
of the loop and exit it when we needed to.
That counter was just before that.
Here we can introduce the counter inside the normal brackets of four.
So basically this part is the same as this part.
Eyes listen five is this is a logical expression that is checked on before every iteration of the loop
and all of the while loop that Tartaros this part inside the brackets.
So this middle part of the for loop is same as this part of the.
And finally the increment is now located in the for loop in this part of the for loop whereas we had
to put the increment into the bottom of the well.
So basically from this we can tell that the while in the four loops are very similar but in my opinion
the for loop is just much more convenient than the while loop because it allows you to kind of cluster
all of this of the admin functions into these brackets.
So let's give our for loop body and say for example say hello or how long.
So learn how long.
And because it's a string of text string quotation marks and that's that's basically it.
So we'll compile that and when we run it we're supposed to see five flow statements so when I is zero
origine zero this will be true.
This will print then I will be incremented become one.
This will still be true.
This will be printed and I'll come to.
This will be true.
This will be printed.
I will become three.
This will be true this will be printed out.
I will get code for this will still be true this will be printed and I will become five.
This will become false and the body will be ignored just as the while loop and the program will move
on.
So let's compile that and check and traitor for Tauriel 7.
We have 1 2 3 4 5 House.
So basically that's how the for loop works.
That brings us to the end of this tutorial.
Hope you enjoyed it.
More tutorials and information are available on for export.
Dot com.
Also that's where I post all of the source code.
If you ever would like to download them and reference them and can join me for the next turn.
Until then take.