Hello this is Carol from Foxborough dot com.
And welcome back to the series of tutorials on em kill for programming for complete beginners.
And today we're going to be talking about the if statement.
I'm really excited about this title and that's because we're finally going to get a chance to work with
some charts and some prizes and see how we can apply all this programming knowledge that we've already
accumulated in a real life scenario on the real Forex market.
And it's all pretty basic but at the same time is going to be really fun.
So let's get straight into it.
Now in the previous couple of Toro's we had a close look at the While loop and the for loop.
And because of that we also looked at logical expressions and boolean variables.
And that's something that we need today again.
So let's quickly recap on that.
So let's create a more simple boolean variable and we'll call it condition or call for short and we'll
assign this variable the result of the following check 5 is greater than 4.
So as we know this expression will be replaced with one of the only two possible boolean values true
or false.
So in this case because 5 is actually greater than 4.
This expression will be replaced with true and then true will be assigned to QAnd and we can check that
by just using a simpler alert.
Compile that and go to the terminal Tauriel it call and as you can see it's true.
That's great.
Now let's look at another one which is a bit trickier.
We're called Con 2 and here we'll check if three is actually called for.
This one's a bit it might be a little bit confusing because of the double equal sign and the equal sign
here as well.
So the best way to look at it is that the double equal sign in Emco for has no association with the
single equal sign.
There are completely two different operate as we know the single equal sign is an assignment operator.
It assigns the value on the right to the variable on the left are the double equal sign on the other
hand is a logical operator.
It checks whether the value on the left is actually equal to the value on the right.
And so in this case because three does not equal to four.
The result of this expression is false.
And then falls is assigned to Cantor and we can also check that really it's a simple way sprint out
to compile that and toilet as you can see we have two alerts.
True and False and True is the first one false.
Second on true and false just as we expected.
So now we can move on to the if statement if statement is similar to the structure of the if statement
is similar to the while loop and has three parts the word if.
Then in the normal brackets you need to specify a condition that you would like to check.
So let's check ten and five for example.
And then based on the result of this check if it is true the program will execute the code in the current
brackets.
So here let's put something simple such as.
The condition is true.
And so compound that actually I'll get all of these two them out so they're not in the way comp. that.
And let's see what we get.
So is 10 grand and five condition is true.
Yes 10 is Grade 5.
Perfect.
All right so that's how the if statement works.
It allows you to isolate a block of code put it within these curly brackets and only allow the program
to executed when a certain condition is met.
What does that mean to you as a call for programmer for the Forex market.
Well let's look at the chart here.
This is the euro dollar H-1 and let's say for example you have identified a resistance line here
correct those surround it.
So 1 3 7 9 0 0 so we can see that this is actually a resistance line because price has bounced around
it a couple of times.
And currently the price is below it.
And so you would like to say hypothetically you'd like to execute some code when the price whenever
the price is below this line.
So how would you tell your program to do that.
It's very simple.
So here in the if statement I'll just put this in comments.
So we have a copy of that copy that an IF statement instead of this expression we we will need to look
at the price.
So to look at the current price we have to use the big variable.
And this is an inbuilt variable which is always available and then kill for and you can access and access
it whenever you want.
It always represents the current bid price.
So at this at this moment it's one point 3 7 5 4 7.
And as you can see it's changing here.
So that's the current bid price.
Now you want to check if the current bid price is less than your designated supported resistance level
in this case it's 1 point 3 7 9 0.
And so if that is the case we would like to perform some sort of actions.
Ideally it would be buy or sell or you know just a position or something like that.
But in this case we'll just type in something simple like the bid price is low.
All that said price is below 1 3 7 9 0 0 and we'll just print another one or actually here will print
an alert before just to control that the bid is correct.
So I'll say bid equals.
And just as we did before we'll say string would convert a bit to a string.
So this line will print the value of the bid and all showed on the screen and then if the bid is actually
less than 1.3 So 9 0 0 then the alert will print out this message which in further tutorials we will
learn how to replace were actual actions on the forex market.
So let's compile that and launched Tauriel it and then we got so big is 1.3 7 5 3 7 1 3 7 5 3 7.
And the price is below 1 3 7 9 0 0 which is correct.
So there we go.
That is how we use if statements in and kill for.
It's a really powerful tool and will handle the bulk of your decision making in Forex automated trading
systems.
And so this source code and more tutorials are available on forums about dot com.
Hope you enjoyed this and
I hope you can also join me for the next Tauriel until then.
CONAN.