Migration and transfer services are tools that you're really going to want to use.
If you're migrating from on premises into the cloud, there's also other use cases migrating between
different resources in the cloud as well.
But primarily, it's going to be migrating from an on premise infrastructure.
And lots of the eight up U.S. exam questions are going to pose scenarios along that kind of line.
So in this section, we'll look at some of the services you can use, like the Database Migration Service,
the Server Migration Service, AWOL data sync, snowmobile and Snowbowl, as well as importing and exporting
virtual machines.
Now, this is quite a short section and it's mostly faery based because you don't need to go into too
much detail or spend too much time on these topics.
But make sure that you do go through these lessons and understand the level of detail that I provide.