In this section on guns, COVID, DNS caching and performance optimization, there's a few services
I'm going to cover.
The first service is Amazon Rout 53, which is a DNS server, and I'll explain all about what that is
and how it works in the very next lesson.
Essentially, a DNS server helps your computer to understand where to go, to speak to an application.
Then we're going to look at Amazon Cloud Front.
Cloud Front is a content delivery network that means it caches data in different locations around the
world to get it closer to the people who are actually using that data.
So it's about optimization of performance through reducing latency will also cover IWC global accelerator.
It's similar to cloud front in that it's helping you to reduce latency, but it has some differences
and different use cases in which we will use it.
So we'll cover that in quite a bit of detail as well.
So I hope you enjoyed the section and I'll see you in the next lesson.