Hi, guys.
We've got a couple of laps now on public, private and elastic IP addresses.
Now, it can be a bit of a dry subject.
And so I'm going to break it up into two or three labs.
And this one is really going to be a lesson.
So I'm just going to talk to you about some of the fairy now and then we're going to get into some examples
and I'm going to show you the behavior of the addresses.
So let's get started with a bit of fairy.
So as you know, we have public IP addresses, private IP addresses and also an elastic IP addresses.
So a couple of facts about them.
A public IP address is lost when the instance is stopped.
So if you run your instance and you reboot it, it will retain its public IP address.
But if you stop the instance and then started again, it actually picks up a new one because these are
dynamic public IP addresses.
Obviously, you use them in public subnets and you don't actually pay for their usage, so it's a free
address that you get from Amazon.
Public and elastic IP addresses are both associated to a private IP address on the instance, and I'm
going to show you a diagram and explain this concept to you a bit further in a second.
With private IP addresses, the address is retained when the instance is stopped and your instance will
have a private IP address, whether it's in a public or a private subnet.
And like I say, that's because the private IP address is actually what the operating system sees.
So the public or elastic IP address is associated to that address will say this a bit further and a
second.
We then have the elastic IP addresses.
So this is a static public IP address.
Now, what you have to do is request the address and then you can associate it with an instance if it's
not used.
So it's disassociated or the instance instances stopped, you do get a charge for it.
So you're not actually charged if you're using it, but you're incentivized to actually make sure you're
using it and you're charged if you don't.
So let's have a look at a couple of diagrams to understand these concepts a bit further in this diagram.
We have an 82 instance.
So this box here is an easy to instance.
Let's say it's running Linux, but it really doesn't matter.
The instance has to Infonet interfaces, both of them have a private IP address, but one of them the
primary interface if zero.
Has a public IP address associated with it.
Now, this could be a public or an elastic, so even though dynamic or a static address, it doesn't
matter.
The point is, this is outside of the operating system.
The Linux operating system doesn't know anything about this address.
All it knows is this address.
However, eight US map this address to this one, and that's actually performed over the Internet gateway.
So the Internet gateway performs one to one network address translation.
And what that means is when data comes into this public IP address, the Internet will then swap that
address from the public IP address to the private IP address so that the operating system can then pick
it up and process that data.
When data goes outbound, the source address from the operating systems perspective would be the private
IP address.
But to make it accountable on the Internet, the Internet gateway then needs to translate the source
address to the public IP address of the instance.
And now that data can go out with a source address that's actually relevant on the Internet.
So that's just a bit of faery.
And what we're going to do in the next lab is we're actually going to run through a couple of scenarios
with private, public and elastic IP addresses to see how they work and how they behave.