We're moving on now to Amazon cloud trial, so cloud trial is a service that records activity about
the API actions that are taking place in your account.
So rather than looking at performance metrics or events, states like Cloud Watch, it's actually looking
at what is happening, like who is creating a resource, terminating a resource, updating a resource.
And of course, this might not necessarily be a user performing those actions.
It can be a service performing those actions as well.
So, for example, with LAMDA, you might have a crit or update function API action with easy to run
instances or terminate instances.
We've asked us it could be to set the key attributes or delete the Q and with Dinamo DB, it might be
to delete a table or update one.
So Cloud Trail is a web service that records activity made on your account and you create something
called a trial and a trial can be created and it delivers log files to an S3 bucket cloud enables governance,
compliance and operational and risk auditing of your Adewusi account.
So just remember this in exam questions, it's usually pretty obvious when something is pointing towards
cloud trial rather than cloud watch because cloud watch is all about performance monitoring.
And usually when it's cloud trial, it's something related to governance or compliance where you need
to record some information about what's happening in your account, what actions are being taken place.
Events include actions taken in the management console of the command line interface.
The SDK is in the API, so pretty much any event is recorded.
So if you're modifying a resource in any way or creating a resource or deleting a resource, then that
is an action that can be recorded by Amazon cloud trail.
Now, cloud trial is enabled on your account when you create it.
You can create two different types of trials so you can get one that applies to all regions.
This records events in all regions and delivers them to a single S3 bucket.
Or you can have a trial that applies to a single region and that records events in that single region
and delivers them to a necessary bucket.
And if you create additional single trails, they can use the same or different bucket.
There are a couple of different types of events that you get in Cloudera one's called a management event.
So this provides information about management operations that are performed on your resources in your
account and also known as control plan operations.
So some of the examples would be configuring security, like attaching an IBM policy, registering devices
like creating a default VPC, configuring rules for routing data such as creating a subnet and setting
up logging such as the crit trial API operations.
We then have data events.
So these provide information about the resource operations performed on or in a resource and then known
as data plan operations.
And these are often the high volume activities, examples of data.
Events include Ezri object level API activity like get object, lead object and put objects and adewusi
lambda function execution activity.
Where you invoking the API?
So again, just to make sure we're completely clear on the differences there.
So Cloud, which is about performance monitoring, cloud trial, is about auditing.
So think of it as a security service.
Cloud watch logs, events across services, and this is more about operations where as cloud trimmers
logging API activity across services.
So that's about the activity in your account cloud, which is high level comprehensive monitoring and
a venting cloud trollers, lower level and very granular.
We've cloud watch and cloud travel, you can log from multiple accounts and cloud watch logs stored
indefinitely in cloud prologues are stored to ESRI or cloud watch indefinitely.
We've cloud what you have alarms history for 14 days now, remember that with cloud, you don't have
native alarming, but you can use the alarm feature of cloud watch.