In this lesson, we're going to cover signed URLs and origin access identities, eyes.
So let's start with signs, URLs.
We're also going to look at assigned cookies.
Signed URLs provide control over access to your content.
You can specify a beginning and an expiration date and time.
The IP address is in the range of users that are allowed to use the signed URL.
So let's say we have an application running on a mobile device.
We've got cloud front and we've got a surplus application.
The mobile device wants to access content on cloud front.
Now, first, it authenticates to the mobile application and requests a signed URL.
The application responds, provides the signed URL and using that signed URL.
The mobile app is unable to access the content.
Signed URLs should be used for individual files and clients that don't support cookies.
So you can't use it for multiple files.
The signed cookies are very similar to sign URLs.
You use them when you don't want to change your URLs and you can use them also when you want to access
multiple restricted files.
So that was a limitation of signed URLs, but it is something you can do with sign cookies.
Now that's a fairly basic overview, but in reality, that's about all you need to know for the exam.
Now onto origin access identity.
This one comes up quite a lot.
So you've got an origin in this case, an S3 bucket configured as a static website.
We've got cloud front and we've got some users and the users are trying to access some content, which
comes from an S3 bucket.
In this case, the users are connecting over the standard cloud from domain name.
Of course, it could be a custom domain name as well.
Then Cloud Fund is trying to fetch from the origin.
And it does say using a special user account called an origin access identity.
The bucket policy has a statement which will only allow access to the origin access identity.
So we happen to allow role here for the principle.
And this is the principle which corresponds to this origin access identity.
So that means the policies restricting access to the Oh I only access in this case is granted and the
object gets returned.
So what happens if a user tries to circumvent cloud front and actually use the free URL?
Well, in that case, the request will be blocked by the bucket policy.
So this is a way that we can make sure that our consent is served by a cloud front and that no one is
able to circumvent cloud front and go to our origin.
So this is a great solution for free.
Now, if you have an easy to origin, it's different.
It's a bit harder with an easy to origin and the reason being so you can't use an A.I., but what you
can do is IWC publish a list of the IP addresses of the nodes on cloud front, and you can use those
in security group rules to only allow access from the cloud front nodes.
You've got to keep on top of that and you need to keep updating it as they change the IP address ranges
that they use.
But it is a way of doing that.
You sometimes see that coming up and exam questions.
So remember the key thing there is another way AI is use of free.
It's not used with to.