Hello and welcome to this lesson.
There are quite a few circumstances where we might want to be able to connect machines that we're running
in different vehicles together using IPv4 or IPv6.
So for instance, we might have two pieces which could be in the same region that could be in a different
region or even a different accounts.
And we want the easy two instances in those two pieces to be able to communicate using private IPv4
addresses or maybe IPv6 addresses.
Now, a way that we can do that is to use VPC pairing.
BPC pairing allows routing for those addresses internally between those VPC.
So when I say internally, what I mean is it's not going out to the internet.
It's using the IWC global network to route traffic between the VPC, so it never touches the internet.
It does get encrypted when it moves between regions, and it uses private IP full and also IPv6 addresses.
So it's a great technology for lots of use cases.
Let's have a look at how we can use VPC pairing.
So let's say we have a VPC, this is VCA, and then we have another VPC, VPC, b, and we want to be
able to route connections between these two.
So we've got two instances maybe Audeze databases, even lambda functions, anything that communicates
inside a VPC, and we want to be able to connect those resources together using private IPv4 addresses.
So what we can do is establish a VPC pairing connection between those two pieces.
So this will enable routing using private IPv4 addresses or IPv6 addresses.
Now, the side of blocks full of Epix's must not overlap.
So this is a very important consideration when you're choosing the side of blocks to use your VP CS,
because even if they're in different accounts, you might someday want to connect your pieces together.
And if they have the same side of blocks or side blocks to overlap with each other, then that won't
work.
So you must have side of blocks that don't overlap.
Now what if we have another VP, CPPCC and VPC, a fourth one?
So they all have their own side, a block so looks good.
We can definitely set up VPC pairing between these.
So what we do?
We establish a VPC pairing connection between PPK and VPC between VPC B and BPC D, and then with VPC
C and BPC D.
So we now have for pairing connection sets up.
But the problem with BPC pairing is it doesn't support transitive pairing.
Now what that means is, let's say we have resources in VPC II and it has a pairing connection with
VPC, b, BPC B then has appeared in connection with VPC d.
So does that mean the VPC A can communicate with resources and VPC d by going via the BBC?
Well, no, it doesn't work.
Transitive routing doesn't work.
So what we actually have to do is set up two more pairing connections.
We've now got a pairing connection between A and D and between B and C, so we've got a full mesh topology
because VPC pairing doesn't support transitive relationships.
We do need this full mesh, so that becomes quite a lot of connections.
Now with these four episodes, it's not too bad, but you can imagine if you spread this out across
a lot more VP CS soon.
This full mesh topology means you've got a huge number of connections to set up and to manage, so it
becomes a bit unwieldy.
And there are other solutions which we're going to look at later on in the section and in sections to
come.
Now, as I mentioned before, the VP six can be in different accounts and they can be in different regions
as well.
Now, let's have a look in a bit more detail about how we set this up.
So we've got region one and we've got Region two.
So in this example, we've got two episodes in different regions could be in the same account or different
accounts, and we want to pair them together.
Now they each have their own side of blocks, which are unique.
They're not overlapping.
So that's good.
And then we've got some subnets.
Now these could be private or public subnet, because remember, it's the private addresses of the instances
that will be used for the VPC to VPC communication.
And we've got some instances running in these subnets.
Now I'm showing public because we're going to set up a lab very much like this.
It makes it easier for us to connect to our two instances if they're in public subnets.
So we create a VPC pairing connection, and I'll show you how to do this in the console.
Now, the next thing we need to do is set up our security groups.
So let's say we want to use the ICMP protocol to send a ping request from one instance to another and
the other, for instance, back again.
Well, in that case, we have to set up a security group rules as well, and we can use the side of
the other region so we can use the site of lockers to source and say that anything coming from that
side a block is going to be allowed based on this rule.
Now, another thing we have to set up for this to work is the root tables.
And what we do is we have a destination rounds, which goes to the side, a block of the remote VPC,
and we specify the pairing IDs when we set up the pairing connection will have a pairing I.D..
I'm going to specify that as a target.
And then we do the reverse on the other side so that the root table will send any traffic destined for
this side, a block to the pairing connection and then it gets routed across to the correct free PC.