Hi guys it's time to move on to access control lists now so we've already seen how we can use policies,
identity based and resource based.
But the other type of access control is the access control list or ACL and these are more of an older
technology and AWS are trying to scare people away from using them.
In fact on one of the web pages we're going to have a look at shortly.
It actually has a statement that says only use objects ACLs to manage permissions for specific scenarios
and only if ACLs meet your needs better than IAM and S3 bucket policies.
So in other words ACLs kind of your last resort.
But there are some specific circumstances where you might want to use them.
So before we get into that let's just look at what an ACL is first.
So an ACL provides access control at the bucket and at the object level.
So each bucket and each object has an ACL.
So that's different to a policy in that you can apply a different ACL setting to each objects in each
bucket.
Now the settings that you can be applied to either an AWS account or one of these predefined groups so
they don't actually go down to the user level as you do with policies.
So you can't call out a specific IAM user and give him permissions through ACL.
You actually grant permissions to an entire account or to one of these groups and these predefined groups
are authenticated users.
That means anyone who is an authenticated user.
That means they have an account in AWS and they have an authentication token all users which
means Uno pencil case it uses.
So that means pretty much you're opening up to everyone in the world.
And then the log Delivery Group which is a special group which is for writing server access logs.
So the other thing that's different about an access control list is the types of permissions that you
can grant.
So let's have a look onto this table here and we can see that you have fewer options in the way that
you can control.
So the granularity is lower.
So you have read rights read access control permissions and right access control permissions or rights
ACP read ICP and then full control which is all of the above.
And then these are granted onto a bucket or an object.
And as you can see there's some slight differences between buckets and objects
so let's head over to the console and we're going to have a look at the ACLs and what I'm going to
do is I'm going to enable cross account access so I'm going to show how we can use an ACL to enable
to use in another account to access our bucket.
So a couple of things I want to draw your attention see firstly is this page.
Access Control List overview.
It's worth having a read of this tells you about grantees.
So a grantee is an AWS account or one of those predefined s3 groups that we just spoke
about.
And there's a few limitations on how you can use email addresses to specify a grantee.
Otherwise you typically use the canonical use right.
And I'll show you what that looks like.
Shortly it then gives you a bit more information on each of these groups the authenticated users or users
in the delivery group.
And then the permissions and how they're actually put into effect on a bucket or an object.
So that's one that you might want to have a look over.
I also want to draw your attention to this article and we use this before to create the cross account.
IAM rules for programmatic and console access to actually bucket objects.
And that was the exercise we did in the previous lab.
We're now going to follow through this exercise which is using access control lists and IAM policies
for programmatic access to every bucket objects.
And if you head down the page a bit this is where the information is.
Now I'm going to follow this loosely and you can come back and refer to this if you need to.
So let's get back to the console and firstly I just want to show you where bucket ACLs are actually
stored set against permissions.
Here we have access control list and this here is the canonical ID that I mentioned.
So by default the ACL has the canonical ID of the account so that the account actually owns this bucket
and all objects within it.
So it's the same for objects every object also has an ACL.
So if we go to permissions we can say the same thing.
Your AWS accounts and that account has full permissions.
Let's just go back out to the bucket level and what we want to do in this exercise is we want to get
a grant access for enough write up U.S. account.
So firstly let's just head over to that other account and just want to show you what I've set up here
so logged in as an administrative user I've given this user full S3 access.
But remember this is a different account.
So I haven't given him any access the only reason I've done this is just it's really a shortcut just
to provide the user the API access to read and write.
It doesn't grant any permissions on the destination bucket.
And we'll see that shortly.
So let's head over to a command line now and see if we can get our user Julian to access the est free
bucket in the other account.
So I need to set up the credentials on this computer for a command line access.
So I'm going to do "aws configure" paste in the user's access key I'm going to come back to another
screen and copy the secret I.D. and we could paste that in and then I'm gonna leave the default region
before output and let's now try to access this bucket.
Now remember the secret I.D. and the access key are definitely security sensitive.
You don't want to share them normally but I'm going to delete them as soon as I finish the lab.
So I'm not too fussed about that.
So we're gonna do "aws s3 ls" and then we're going to put in DCT company bucket name and we get
an access denied.
So that's exactly what we expected.
Let's go back now and we're going to configure access to the bucket.
So firstly I need to grab that canonical I.D. So I'm actually in a bucket here on my offshore account
and I'm going to go to the access control list and I can find the canonical I.D. for this account so
copy.
That someone clipboard and now I'm back in the ACL for DCT company and I can click Add account paste
in the ID and I'm just going to provide full access to this account on this bucket so they can list
objects, write objects, and read and write permissions
so we've granted access at the bucket level.
Now let's head back and see if we can list our bucket and then we go so we can now see the bucket and
if we wanted to we'd be able to upload a file as well.
So let's do a "aws s3 cp" and I'm going to copy a file called index.txt and put that into the
bucket
and now if we call ls again we should see we've got our index file so that's access control lists.
Just remember that an ACL can be applied straight to a bucket and an object every bucket and every object
has an ACL and you can also only specify at the account level or at the predefined group level.