So we're now going to talk about AWB Direct Connect Direct Connect enables you to connect your corporate
data datacenter into the AWB cloud using private connections.
So it does that by using connectivity between your customer router and the aid of U.S. router via a
partner router or a router which you have in a specific location.
So this is not a W.S. cloud location.
This is a direct connect location and what that means is it's a data center somewhere in a city near
you.
There'll be one or more of these and they'll have a cage in that data center where a W.S. host a bunch
of routers and switches.
Now what you need to do is cross connect your routers and switches into the W.S. cage.
So you even need to have your own rack in that data center or you can leverage a partner who provides
that to you as a service.
So you have private connections then go all the way into into NWS now from the W.S. cage you connect
to public services using what's called a public therefore public virtual interface or private services
such as VPN gateways using a private set of public faith goes to public IP spaces so as free as addressable
by public IP as is easy to.
Whereas the private def goes into your data center your load balancers your easy two instances addressing
them with private IP addresses and you can have multiple private vest connects into different pieces
and you can have multiple public events and they can connect to NWS locations around the world.
So NWS provide two options for bandwidth.
One is one gigabit per second than the other is 10 gigabits per second.
If you want lower bandwidth right the way down to 50 megabits per second you can use a partner service
where they provide a subdivision of the bandwidth but otherwise you use one gigabit or 10 gigabit.
Now the main use case for direct connects is to have this dedicated low latency high bandwidth connection
into the cloud.
So use direct connect whenever you expect to require low latency or you just need consistency and dedicated
bandwidth.
You can't rely on the Internet for licensee.
So if an application demands low latency and you see some exam questions and one option is direct connect
and another is VPN then in the case where you need to ensure low latency you definitely go for direct
connect it is much more costly than a VPN and it takes some time as well it can take months to provision.
So you actually have to put in an order and IWM to give you some information about which cables to connect
to which ports within the data center and then it can take some time for the whole provisioning process
to take place so that can be weeks it can be months.
Let's just go back to the console and what I'm gonna do is I'm just going to show you where direct connect
is configured.
So we're just going to search for direct connect and so within here you can then create your order so
you'd go to create a connection and I could just put in my connection and I can choose one of these
locations so you just find the location that's news to you.
You know that could be you know Equinix Manchester for instance you choose your speed and then you create
connection and then you get a bunch of information from a W as on what you need to then connect.
They give you a detailed sheet which provides port to port mappings and then you can go and start provisioning
that.
So I can't really show you this within this land.
We are going to cover some more about Direct Connect gateways shortly so direct connect gateways give
you some more capabilities about creating a sort of hub and spoke architecture so key thing to remember.
Use direct connect when you need low latency dedicated connections and you can have private and public
bits connecting to either the private IP spaces or the public IP spaces.