Hello and welcome to the exam cram for Section nine, so we're starting off with the Plastic Container
Service X.
X is a highly scalable, high performance container management system that supports DOCA containers,
and it's a managed infrastructure so you can eliminate the need to build your own system just like any
other cloud service.
It can be used to schedule the placement of containers across clusters based on resource needs and availability
requirements.
Now, there's no additional charge for using the extra service.
You just pay for the resources you create.
So that's the easy two instances and ebb's volumes associated with them that actually run your container
infrastructure.
It's possible to associate a service on X to an Albi for a plastic load balancing.
Now there are two different types of service available for containers in the US.
There's the Plastic Container Service and the elastic community service.
So this table just gives you a bit of detail about the differences between the two.
They're both managed platforms with high availability and scalability.
Remember that with the Cuban 80s with X, that's all about having a hosted Cuban êtes platform for you.
With X, we got two different launch types and the launch types are the Amazon EC2 or the far launch
type.
Got to remember, the difference between these for the exam so far is essentially a kind of serverless
service.
So you don't have to prevision or launch any two instances.
With the easy to launch type, you do so you have to launch two instances.
If you go into the active management console, you can actually see the two instances that are running
your containers.
You're therefore responsible for managing those two instances and also you've got to configure any cluster
optimization, whereas with FOGGER you don't have to worry about that.
It's a serverless service.
So you basically just launch your containers and everything underneath is managed for you.
Containers are created from a read only template that's called an image and that has the instructions
for creating the docker container.
Images are built from a Docker file and only docker containers are currently supported on X.
An image contains the instructions for creating that docker container, they're stored in a registry
such as Docker Hub or the Elastic Container Registry.
NCR is a managed registry that's secure, scalable and reliable.
A task definition is required to run a DOCA contain index.
The task definition is a text file in JSON format that describes one or more consignors.
Up to 10 task definitions used images to actually launch the container.
So you specify the number of tasks you want to run, and that equates to the number of containers that
are actually going to run.
We then have clusters.
This is a logical grouping of container instances that you place tasks on.
So the container instances are the two instances that you run your containers on top of.
And a cluster is a group of those two instances and you place a task on it.
And remember, the task is the actual container itself.
A default clusters created and then you can create your own clusters.
You can specify the definition of a specified number or desired count of tasks to run in the cluster
clusters can contain tasks using both foggy and easy to launch type.
The clusters with the easy to launch type, the clusters can contain different container instance types.
But each container instance can only be part of one cluster at a time.
Now, to provide auto scaling, you create what's called a service, so the services provide you auto
scaling functions for X, specifically, a service scales automatically the number of tasks that are
being executed on your container infrastructure.
A cluster is region specific.
You can create Iame policies for your clusters to allow or restrict users to access specific clusters.
Each consignor instance needs to have a container agent running on it.
So the X container agent allows to contain instances to actually then connect to the X cluster.
It runs on every infrastructure resource.
It's included by default in the X optimized Amoy, and you can install it on overeasy, two instances
that support the X specification.
You can install the X container agent on both Linux and Windows.
For non-native US Linux instances to be used on AWEX, you have to manually install the X container
agent.
So again, for auto scanning you have a service and that can be configured to use auto scanning to adjust
the number of tasks or the number of containers up or down automatically.
And that actually leverages application, also skiting to provide the functionality it supports to different
types of scanning policies, the target tracking screening policy and the steps coding policy.
We then have Kluster also scaling.
Now, this is very new.
So this was actually released in December 2019.
So I don't think it's going to appear on the zero one.
But you might be watching this and actually preparing for the SAAC zero two, especially if it's after
March twenty twenty.
So I'm pretty sure that it will start appearing in that soon.
It uses a new resource type called a capacity provider, and that's associated with an auto scaling
group.
So what this means is you're able to scale not just the tasks, the number of containers you're running
automatically, but you're now able to automatically scale the number of cluster instances, the hosts
on which your clusters or your X tasks actually run.
It leverages to new features, ones called manage scaling and once called managed instance termination
protection.