Continuing our crime with Amazon Rafina, so remember, Rafina is an interactive query service that
makes it easy to analyze data Innisfree using siecle.
So the key to remember here is the data is sitting on Amazon is free and you use standard structured
query language queries to query that data.
It's Cervalis and there's no infrastructure to manage and you pay for what you use.
And it uses the managed data catalog provided by Glew to store information and schemas about the databases
and tables that you create for data stored Innisfree.
It uses something called Pressplay will full standard SQL support and supports a variety of different
formats for the data.
Now it's optimized for fast performance of free as well.
With a FEIGNER, there's no need for complex extract, transform and load jobs to prepare data for analysis.
So it's easy for anyone with SQL skills to just quickly go and query data on as free.
Moving on to Glew, this is the fully managed pay as you go escort service, so this does the extract
transform and load, which automates the time-Consuming steps of data preparation.
So preparing data ready for analytics.
It automatically discovers and profiles data by the data catalog and generates the code to transform
source data into target schemas, Glu runs the eco jobs on fully managed scale Apache Spark environment
to load your data into its destination.
So you simply point glue to your data stored on us and Glu discovers data and stores.
The associated metadata in the glue data catalog once catalogued, the data is then immediately searchable
variable and available for ECL.
Now remember, this works with not just data links on history, but also data warehouses such as redshift
and data stores such as A.D.s or databases running on Amazon Etsy to.