Hi guys we just got a little bit more theory to cover before we get stuck into the practical on read replicas.
MySQL replicas, global databases, multi-masters, can all get a bit confusing with Aurora.
So what I want to do is just try and in the next couple of labs really try and make this stuff very
clear.
As I mentioned multi-Master's something that's in preview so we're going to push that to the side.
We're not going to cover that in the next couple of labs.
But what I am going to do is make sure that you guys fully understand what an aurora replica is.
What a mysql replica is the difference between those and the global database.
So first off between the role of replicas and mysql replicas you've got up to 15 Aurora replicas.
Now remember these are in region and we'll see in a diagram what this all looks like in a second.
You've then got the mysql replicas these are only up to five.
And these are all in different regions and yet across region.
So this is not within a region.
So these are very different use cases.
This is just for scaling your reeds up within your region.
Very low latency fast synchronization whereas with mysql replica you got a bit of a longer lag in
terms of your replication time but you're gonna be using these for scaling reads across region and also
for using as a failover target in different regions.
There's a performance impact with mysql replica because it's using that sequel then log replication
whereas with a raw replica the impact on the primary is very low with both you can failover.
So you can use these as failover targets with obviously with the Aurora replica that's within the same
region and with the mysql replica that's cross region and you can see a little bit difference between
the amount of data that you might lose you can automatically fai over two in aurora replica but you
can't have mysql replica.
So there's some manual interface intervention required there.
There's a couple of other features because of the sequel binlog replication a couple of things that
you can do.
mysql so let's get onto a diagram.
This diagram shows you what Aurora looks like within a region.
So as I mentioned before you always get two copies of your data and at least three availability zones
so that's six way replication are six copies of your data storage is actually provisioned in 10 gigabyte
chunks and then that's replicated across to all these different copies.
You have one primary so this is the one where the rights come from the primary rights to all copies
of the data in each of these availability zones
a single logical volume is actually presented to the DB instances so they're not aware they don't see
different copies of the data and that's how you're read replicas can then read the data so they read
that data and that's why it's such a low lag time because the primary is basic just writing to all three
of these pretty much at the same time.
Your read replicas or your Aurora replicas can then read that data and serve applications we've read traffic
just as with the other databases.
The primary has its own endpoint and then the replicas have different endpoints.
And then you can then promote a replica to be a primary.
Now in terms of the automatic promotion there's a thing called tiers and tiers represent the order in
which you would like replicas to be automatically promoted to primaries in the event of a failure.
So you can specify tiers for each of the replicas.
And that that controls the order of promotion as I mentioned before you can also use auto scaling to
add replicas and we'll look at that in the console.
So let's get on and actually start building some stuff in the console.
I'm locked into the IWC management console and I'm just going to head over to RDS
and what we're going to do is we're going to create a database and the first thing we're gonna do is
we're just going to try a standard Aurora database and before we go any further I've gotta warn you
guys this is not free tier.
So none of the labs that we're going to do on Aurora are gonna be free tier and I'm gonna be adding
quite a few copies of databases to show you the various features.
So this is definitely going to cost them money wouldn't be a lot if you shut it down fast enough.
But you know this could be could be some dollars.
So just bear in mind if you don't want to incur any costs you should just watch along and not actually
perform these labs.
So I'm going to choose the Aurora database engine and we're going to choose my school five point six
we're not going to go for the latest version because there are some limitations with mysql.
Five point seven.
Some of the features aren't available yet.
And note the Aurora global database feature.
So you actually have to click on this option here and go into a different wizard and we're going to
do that in a couple of laps time.
So I click next and this is where you can see that you have the option to even provision and manage
the servants and sizes or use service.
So if I provision then I've got my DB engine and then I've got my instance class so I might change this
to one of the other DV instance classes and that'll be that.
And then I could use multi easy and I can create read replicas if I then go to service.
Some of those options disappear and what I'll do instead is I'll be able to specify the minimum and
maximum resources for the DB cluster.
So let's just have a look at that.
I'm just going to call this database digital cloud paste that into a few places there and this is where
you then have the option to specify the amount of RAM so you can say the minimum there is one 1 unit.
So these are units and then this is the amount of RAM.
So one unit is 2 gig 2 units is 4 gig 4 units is 8 gig so I can say I want to start at 1 unit so 2 gigabytes
of RAM and go up to a maximum of 16 units or 32 gigabytes of RAM and it will automatically scale the
database for us.
Now I don't want to use that option now because it does have some limitations so I'm just gonna go back
to provisioned and I'm going to choose the smallest option available and I'm not going to create a replica
right now because we're going to create one for the console and I'm just going to paste in my deviance
and so identifier keep my master username and password the same click on Next
I'm going to put something in for the cluster identifier and database name and we're just going to leave
this in the default VPC and subnet group
and I don't need public accessibility.
I'm gonna choose an existing security group because I know I've already got some ideas.
Launch was at one set so just grab one of those
and you can leave encryption on or turn it off.
And then here this is where you can specify the failover priorities that I mentioned before.
Which control the order of promotion then got back up and backtracks backtrack allows you to determine
how far back in time you want to go so you can specify the amount of time and then you're able to
move your database back to that point in time without needing to do a restore.
So that's a pretty cool feature.
We're going to disable enhanced model of showing hacks we don't need it and I'm going to disable this
option leave the maintenance window has no preference and I'm going to disable the deletion protection
and create database
so we're now in the console and we can see that we're in a state of creating and you can see that you
have a hierarchy here.
So first off this is showing as reader.
But once it's created it will change to writer.
So it's been several minutes and we now have the database available and we can see that the role is
changed to writer.
So let's go in and have a look at the database we can see that we have an endpoint ports 3306
because the engine is still mysql and we can see the availability zone that the primary instance
is running from.
And then we have monitoring where you can see some metrics from cloud watch on what's going on from
a performance perspective.
Now the key thing that I want to show you is let's go back up to this level.
So you go up to the database configuration level and you go to actions and here you got a few options.
So one is you can create a clone.
So this creates a full clone of your database.
And if you click on it you get a few options including you can specify the database engine or the database
instance class so you actually can't change the engine but you can change the instance class and you
can specify some different parameters and so on.
So that's a great way to clone your database and you can also then create a cross region read replica.
So this is going to be the subject of the next lab.
You can restore to a point in time so that's the BackTrack feature and you can add a replica free auto
scaling so we're going to go and add a reader.
But this is the same thing as just using auto scaling.
So if you come in here you can use two different metrics even CPU utilization or average connections
both on your existing replicas.
So it's even a percentage of the CPU or number of connections and then you could also specify some
scale parameters and cool down stuff.
And obviously you can go from one to 50 and you can't have more than 15 because that's the maximum number
of rural replicas
who come back and just go here.
Then what we want to do now is click Add reader and we can actually choose the availability zone if
we want.
Remember that the Aurora replicas are within region.
So you you can choose an availability zone but you can't choose a different region and you can choose
to change this ones publicly available if you want to.
You can't change the encryption attributes because the primary is already encrypted but you could also
change the DB instance class if you wanted to.
So let's just go in and let's put in
read only D.B. as the instance identifier.
Let's give it a priority of Tier 1 and we'll leave the other attributes as they are and just click Add
reader so we can see now that we can we have the hierarchy here where we can see the writer and the
reader it's in a state of creating at the moment it's gonna take a few minutes to provision this instance
we can see it's in the creating state and we can say it's a reader whereas the digital cloud database
is a writer and what we're gonna do is we're going to end the lab here but we're going to leave things
running because in the next lab we're going to create a cross region read replica.