Hi guys.
The next item on our list for securing our account is to create individual IAM users.
Now what this means is we're going to create a user account that we can log on which isn't the root account.
Now I keep telling you about the root account and how important that is.
And I just want to show you an article here and all the links that I show you in this course.
And any code that we use is going to be in the course downloads so you can find this link there.
Otherwise just search for AWS tasks that require AWS account root user credentials and you can see
some of the things that require root.
So changing support plans closing the accounts there's billing changes using the billing and cost management
console and so on.
So have a look through those and try and understand what they are.
But for the most part we're going to just be logging on as an individual IAM user.
We can click the down arrow and choose manage users or we can just go up to users here.
It's the same thing.
And what we want to do is add a user.
Now I'm just going to call this Neal and then we have two access types programmatic access is where
we create an access key I.D. and a secret access key.
So these are used for the AWSAPI.
The CLI the SDK and other development tools I do want to be able to use programmatic access so I'm
going to enable that.
The other type of access is management console access and this is where we have a username and password
to log in and use the management console.
So you don't have to have both of these.
You can have one or the other or both together.
We can then choose to auto generate a password or set a custom password.
In this case I'm going to set my own password and I'm going to select this option because I don't want
to have to reset it then go next to permissions we have the option to create a group and I do want to
do this I want to create a group and I want to give that group administrator access I'm going to call
the group AWS-Admins and so this will create a group called a AWS-Admins and it will add the
user that we're creating to that group we're going to select the administrator access policy and this
is going to give full administrative privileges to our user through the group.
Now if you go down and look at the JSON code here JSON stands for JavaScript object notation and it's
the type of code that you write these policy statements in.
There's always a version then there's a statement and then you can see the effect is to allow the action
and the star means a wild card.
So anything, and then the resource is a star also which means any resource.
So this allows any action on any resource.
So it's a very privileged policy and you need to be careful who this is assigned to.
Now that we have our policy selected in our group name instead we can just choose create group.
And so we're now creating our user and we're creating our group we can choose to assign tags which are
key value pairs and you can use this for assigning metadata to resources in AWS.
I'm just gonna leave it blank for now and then we can go to review and we can see the user name the
access types that we've assigned that we've set a custom password and we can see the group that we've
enabled and now we're just going to choose crate user and the user has been created.
Now you'll see that you get an access key idea and a secret access key really important thing to note
is firstly these are very security sensitive.
Anybody who has these keys will be able to do whatever you have privileges to do in your account.
So if someone got ahold of this access key and secret I.D. they would be able to do almost anything
in the account.
Anything that this user has privileges to which due to the policy we just assigned through the group
is going to be a lot of privileges.
The other thing you need to know is you can only see this once.
So this secret access key is only generated at creation time so it's only visible at creation time.
So what you need to do is actually take a copy of this.
Keep it somewhere very secure and make sure no one gets access to it.
Now I'm not worried about you guys seeing it because I'm recording this and I'm just going to delete
my access key I.D. and create a new one well before I release this course.
But in normal circumstances you won't want to share this.
I've copied my access key idea and secret access key and now I can choose close so let's just have a
look at what we've created.
We've got a group and the group is called AWS-Admins.
And that group has the following permissions.
It has a policy for administrator access.
And as we've seen that policy has very extensive permissions.
We can do anything on any resource.
We then created a user called Neal and that user is a member of this group.
So when you see permissions here you can see that the user has these permissions attached through the
group.
And you could then go over to access advisor.
What this does is it shows you the service permissions that are granted to this user.
So in this case it's a very extensive list obviously because of the group and the policy that we've
assigned to this user and actually tells you which policy grants the permissions in this case is just
one policy.
But in many cases it will be lots of different policies.
So this gives you a good idea of where the permissions have been granted from.
That's all we need to do now but what we can do is choose sign out and we're going to sign back into
the console.
Now in this case we're going to choose sign into a different account and we're going to enter the account
alias which I said earlier as DCTLabs and choose next.
We now get this screen again where we've got the accounts I.D. or alias which is DCT labs and we get
to put in our user name.
So I'm going to put in my username and my password and sign in.
So that's it.
We've now logged in with our new user account and if we go to Identity and Access Management we can
now see that we've created an individual IAM user and use the group to assign permissions.
So we've got a couple more nice texts.
The next thing we need to do is apply an IAM password policy and we're gonna have a look at that in
the next lab.