Hi, guys, in this lesson, I'm going to cover AWB Resource Access Manager.
Now, this is a really exciting service because it lets you share resources between AWB accounts.
So what you can do is you can share certain resources.
And there's a list of them on this Web page that I'm looking at now, and you can share them across
accounts.
So this could be really useful in lots of different use cases.
So let's have a look at what services you can actually share so we can see Ammash, Amazon and Rora
Code build Ekta Easy to image builder license manager resource groups and round 53.
And then if you go to one of these you can see a bit more detail which types of services within these
categories you can actually share.
So for instance, you can share transit gateways, subnets, dedicated hosts and so on.
And what we're going to do in the lab in this lesson is I'm going to show you how we can share a subnet
between two different accounts.
So this is the diagram.
And in this diagram, we have two accounts.
So let's say on the left here, we have accounts which could be your development environment.
And then let's say we have a test environment on the right here, which is account B.
So in this case, what I want to do is I need my instances in this public subnet and it could be a private
subnet as well.
It doesn't matter.
But I want my instances here to actually be able to communicate using private IP addresses to my instances
in my other account here.
So we've ram I can actually extend this subnet the same subnet into account B.
So that's what we're going to do in the lab now, so let's go to the management console and what we're
going to do is go to resource access manager, which is under security, identity and compliance.
Now, a couple of things before we get started.
You can see I've actually deleted a couple of subnets that I shared when I was testing go down to settings.
And if you're going to use an AWB organization, you need to enable sharing here.
You'll see what I mean in a minute.
So you might want to do that first.
Also, if you are using Adewusi organizations, just head into the council for organizations and then
what you need to do here is head over to settings again and then just scroll down and you might need
to enable access for resource access manager here as well.
So once you've done those things, let's come back and we're going to go to resource shares and we're
going to create a resource share.
So I'm just going to call this shared subnet and it's going to be free for me because I've already created
a couple and I'm going to choose a public subnet.
So I'm going to choose public to I only because it's going to make the lab a bit easier for you guys
in terms of connecting to your subnet, to your AC to instance in your subnet, so that you can prove
that the lab works.
So I can now come down here and for Awassa organizations, I can show organization structure now, otherwise
you just put in the account side.
So if you don't have an organization, you can just put in your account ID of your second account here.
And if you don't have a second account, just watch along and I'm going to show you what Resource Access
Manager is anyway.
If you do have one and it's in an organization, you can come down and choose it here.
So I have two that are called Digital Cloud Training Lab, so I'm going to.
Choose to share with this second account here.
So then I come down and I choose, create resource share.
And that's it, I've got my Shadd subnet shared and what will happen is in my other account now, I
should be able to find that shared subnet.
So this is the management console for my second account.
I'm going to go to resource access manager and let's see resource shares.
And sure enough, I've got shared subnet free.
So that's been shared with me.
And if I click on that and I can actually go into that subnet and I can see the configuration for that
subnet.
So there it is.
Now, I'm just going to turn off the new VPC experience for now just to make things a bit clearer and
cancel.
So that's my subnet and it's been shared.
So what I want to do now is I'm going to go to Ekta and in EC2 I'm going to launch an instance.
So I'm just going to choose Linux.
And what I'm going to do now is I'm going to change and you'll find that I've got a second VPC.
So on this account I only have one VPC, but now I can see a second VPC and it says it's shared and
then there's just one subnet.
So we can see that AP switched to a subnet has been shared.
And I'm just going to remember that I'd say the subnet ID ends NCEA eight.
So that's my subnet that's just go forwards and we're going to put it in a security group.
Now I have SNH on this one and also ICMP.
So let's just launch and what I'm going to do is head back to my other account.
So this is where I'm also going to launch an easy to instant's.
So let's launch an instance and I'm going to find that same VPC, which I know is this one here, and
this is the subnet that I want to put it into.
So it's the same subnet that I just shared across accounts to select the existing security group.
Got to choose the right one hand.
This is the VPC and again, I've got SNH in this one.
And so I'm going to launch and I don't need ICMP in this one.
I'm just going to ping one direction.
So I'm going to ping from this instance to the other instance to prove that I can connect to it over
the same subnet, but from two different accounts and we're going to ping using the private IP address.
So it's been a few minutes.
Let's try and log in to our instance.
So I'm just going to copy the public IP to connect to the instance and let's just use S.H. So I'm connected
in and I just need to go and get the IP address of my other instance.
So my second instance is this one running in account B and I'm just going to copy its private IP here
and then let's ping and hopefully yeah, we've got a response.
So that's exactly as expected.
What we've done is we've got two accounts.
We've shared a subnet from Account A to account B.
We've then launched an instant in each subnet.
And what I just did then was connect to this instance and then ping this instant here using a private
IP address.
So that shows that we've now got that private access that we want between these two accounts.
By putting the instances on the same shared subnet, you can use IAM policies to control access to RAM
and your resources.
And by the way, this does not cost anything.
So there's no cost to sharing a resource.
And you can always stop sharing a resource at any point in time as well.
So that's it for this lab.
All I'm going to do is just go back and terminate my instances and those are the things that are costing
money.
And then you might want to go back in and delete your shared subnet as well once you've got rid of your
instances.
So I hope you enjoyed that lot.
Guys, this is a really exciting, so very, very useful for lots of different use cases where you want
to share certain resources between different accounts.