There are a couple of ways we can use multifactor authentication with Amazon S3, so multifactor authentication
means you have a second factor of authentication above and beyond your password.
So you have a username and password and then you have to supply something else.
And that something else is typically a code that's generated by either a physical device like a token
generating key card or it's actually a app on your phone like Google Authenticator.
So the first one is multifactor authentication delete this simply as a requirement for a second factual
friend's location when performing certain operations that is changing the version in state of a bucket
and permanently deleting an object version.
It's important for the exam to remember those two specific operations, and those are the operations
for which the extra requirement for MFA will be enforced.
When you use MFA, delete the AMS that MFA requests that it gets included in the requests for those
specific operations.
The second factor of authentication is typically a code that's generated by a hardware device or software
program, and the image here is from Google Authenticator.
Now it does require versioning to be enabled on the bucket's.
Versioning can be enabled by bucket owners.
The IWC account that created the bucket or authorized I Am uses MFA to Leeds can only be enabled by
the Buckets owner, so that's an important distinction to remember.
The next use of MFA is something called MFA Protected API Access.
This is used to enforce another factor of authentication when accessing IWC resources.
Not just this free other resources as well using the API or the SEELYE, it's enforced using the IWC
multifactor or age key in a bucket policy.
So you might have a bucket policy that looks like this.
What this does is it denies any principle, any as free action on a specific resource in this case.
But it could be, you know, broadly across all three buckets as well.
And the condition is if the IWC multifactor authentication age true is not set if it's null, and that
particular attribute will be included in your request if you have authenticated using MFA, if you haven't,
then it's going to deny the access.
Now, if you log in to the console with MFA, but then you issue a command via the Seelye or the API,
it doesn't matter.
The MFA from the console is completely separate from this.
What this means is you actually have to supply a token from an MFA device to the Seelye or API to get
your temporary security credentials, and then you go and issue your API request to free.
And that information gets included, so you must be authenticated with MFA at the command line or the
API rather than through the console.
So I hope that was useful and I'll see you in the next lesson.