In this lesson, we're going to use query string routing to conditionally route all connections to different
target groups based on the query string parameters that we define.
There is some code that you're going to need.
This is in the co-director of the course.
Download auto scanning and Ailbhe, and it's called User Dash data.
Dash app Dash Group to search what this does is simply creates a web service and adds the text.
This EC2 instance is in App Group B to the web page.
So we're going to copy all of this to our clipboards and in the active management console, we're going
to launch an instance.
It's going to be the Linux to my C2 micro.
And what we're going to do is make sure that we put it in one of the subnets that is attached to our
target group.
So I'm going to use USC SW1A.
If I scroll down to the bottom, I can paste in my code.
Go to next.
Next.
And then across the security.
And I need to choose my Web Access Security Group.
Let's go to launch, choose our keeper, and we've launched that instance.
We can now view instances and we should have these free instances.
I'm going to label this one.
This is the one we just created.
So this is the one for the query test and click on Safe.
So that would take a few minutes to come up.
We also need a separate target group.
So we're going to come down to target groups choose Create Target Group.
The target site will be instance.
The target group name will be tJI, Dash, Ielpi, Dash two and the Protocol HD CPAC again, BP sees
already selected.
All of the other information is fine as the defaults.
Let's click on next, and we're going to manually add a query test instance, so I'm going to include
as pending below and then create that target group.
So we have a target group with an instance.
Of course, you can probably imagine because we saw this recently that it's going to be unused, and
that's because it's not attached to a load balancer.
So what we need to do now is go back to our load balancer.
We're going to choose listeners and once you're going to create a role for this listener.
So what we do is click on view edit rules.
Now, a listener is a protocol combination, so if you wanted another listener, it would have to be
a different port could be HD 281, for example, or HTTPS for for free.
So we don't want another listener.
We want a role within this listener.
Now I find this one of the most unintuitive consoles in IWC, but I'll show you how to work it.
So we click on Plus.
Then you go to insert rule and condition.
We're going to use query string.
Now this is where you have path, Hofstetter, HTP, header and others.
So there's quite a lot of different ways you can route your data.
We're going to use query string.
The query string is going to be App Group and the value is going to be a.
Add action forward, too, and we're going to choose Teague Albi and we're going to save these.
Click on Save.
We're now going to add another rule.
We're going to do the same thing, but this time it's going to be App Group and we're going to enter
B.
And this time we're going to forward to Target Group Albi to click on the tick marks and save.
So what we have now, we have free rules.
The first rule is going to check for the query string parameter app Group B, and if it finds that it's
going to forward to the Albi to Target Group, if that's not the case, it's going to have a look for
the query string app Group A and if it finds that it will forward to Target Group Albi and if neither
of those happen, it's just going to forward it to Target Group LP.
That's the default rule at the end.
So those rules are set up correctly.
Let's go back and check our target group.
We want to make sure that all instance is healthy.
So now that we click Refresh, we should find it is used because it's used in that rule and the instance
has quickly become healthy.
So all looks good.
Let's go to low balances description and I'm going to copy the DNS name.
Now let's go to a new browser window before what we did was just pasted in this DNS name.
Now, for now, because we're going to add a query string, you must add HTP colon slash slash at the
beginning, and then we're going to put in our query string.
So I'm going to put a question mark.
App Group equals high unless hit enter and we get forwarded to our issue instance in USC SW1A.
Now, remember, there's a different message with all other instance, it might be in the same A-Z,
but it should provide a different message.
So what I'm going to do now is just change this to App Group equals B and hit enter.
And now I get the different instance, the one that's in the new target group we just created.
So that's an example of using query string parameter based routing with an application load balancer.
And that's it for this lesson.
What we're going to do is we will remove the instance that we just launched because we don't need this
one anymore, but we'll leave everything else running.
We're still going to continue using this in more hands on lessons.
So once that's terminated, you're all done for this lesson.