Hello and welcome to another exam cram.
So this time we're talking about AWS lambda and API gateway. So Lambda lets you run code as functions
without provisioning or managing servers.
So this is AWSs serverless product. Or one of the serverless products that
AWS offers. Lambda based applications also referred to as serverless applications
are composed of functions which are triggered by events. With serverless computing
your application is running on a server but all the server management is done by AWS. You specify the
amount of memory you need allocated to your lambda function.
And AWS Lambda allocates CPU power proportional to the memory that you specified using the same ratio
as a general purpose EC2 instance type. A Lambda function can access AWS services or non-AWS
service. Service is running in VPCs, non-AWS services running on ECS instances in an AWS
the VPC. For compute resources you can request additional memory in 64 megabyte increments starting
at 128 make up to 3008 megabytes. Functions larger than one thousand five hundred and thirty
six megabytes are allocated multiple CPU threads and multi-threaded or multi-process code is needed
so that you can take advantage of those CPU threads. There's a maximum execution time out of 15 minutes.
This definitely comes up in an exam question now you'll never get asked directly what's the maximum
execution time for Lambda. Instead it will be weaved into a scenario so you might have a scenario something
like you have some code or a script that needs to run and today you only need to run this maybe once
or twice a week so you want to be cost optimized what's the best solution and one of those solutions
might be lambda. Now you know that it completes in ten minutes and you know that you only ever pay for
lambda when you're executing your code that would be a good option if the script was completed in twenty
minutes it wouldn't work, or you'd at least need to be able to execute multiple functions in parallel
or once or sequentially in order to be able to complete your code so if that's not included in the scenario
then you'd assume that lambda doesn't work for that scenario. You only pay for the time it runs. Lambda
terminates the function at the timeout. Lambda is an event driven compute service so it executes code
in response to events and that could be things like changes to data and an S3 bucket or dynamoDB
table. The event source is the AWS service or application that produces events that trigger a lambda
function and an event source is mapped to a lambda function.
Now you remember this from the labs the event sources maintain the mapping configuration.
So if it's Amazon S3 then you configure.
Amazon S3 to let lambda know when something is changed like you've uploaded data but it's different
for stream based services such as dynamoDB and Kinesis. On those cases you configure the event source
on the lambda side, so lambda actually polls those services. You can deploy managed service applications
using what's called the serverless application model.
That's a specification that prescribes the rules for expressing serverless applications and it aligns with
the syntax used by cloudformation and is supported by cloudformation as a set of resource
types known as serverless resources.
You can automate serverless applications release processes using AWS CodePipeline and CodeDeploy
as well.
Now you probably won't have those come up on the solution architect exam but you might well have those
come up on the developer associate exam.
You can enable your lambda function for tracing with AWS X-Ray as well.
So moving on to Amazon API Gateway.
This is a collection of resources and methods that are integrated with backend HTTP endpoints, lambda
functions or other AWS services.
So it's a fully managed service that makes it easy to publish maintain and monitor secure APIs.
It's a pay as you go fully managed service that handles all the aspects of creating and operating your
API.
And it handles all the tasks involved in accepting and processing hundreds or thousands of concurrent
API calls API calls can include traffic management authorization and access control monitoring an API
version management.
So together with Lambda, API Gateway forms the application facing part of the serverless infrastructure.
Backend services can include EC2, AWS lambda or any web application cloudfront is used as the public
endpoint for API Gateway and all of the APIs created in API Gateway are HTTPS
endpoints so you can't have a HTTP endpoint. An API endpoint type refers to the hostname of
the API and it can be optimized regional or private depending on where the majority of your traffic
originates from.
There are several features that can help you create and manage API so you got metering security resiliency
operations monitoring and lifecycle management as well.
For the solutions architects associate exam you shouldn't need to know API gateway in too much depth
but definitely just to understand these features of API Gateway and know that it uses the cloudfront
network and understand that it works with AWS lambda to form that application facing part of the AWS
serverless infrastructure.