To placement groups in a way that you can control how IWC deploys your ISA to instances and places them
within your availability zones or across availability zones.
Now the best way to get started with this is to look at the different options we have for how we can
control that placement.
Now, the first type of placement group is called a cluster placement group.
Now this PAX instance is within and availability zone closely together.
Now, when I say closely within an availability zone, of course, and availability zone is one or more
data centers.
Now, if we want to achieve really low latency better than you can, if your instances were perhaps
randomly deployed within that easy, then we might want to make sure that they're really close, like
they're in the same rack or they're in adjacent racks.
So there's a very short physical distance between them.
And that will mean that we can achieve even lower latency.
So that's what a cluster placement group aims to do.
This enables your workloads to achieve very low latency.
And this is really good for tightly coupled workloads where you have nodes, no communication.
And that's typical of HPC applications.
High performance computing applications.
So I've highlighted a few words there which are really useful to remember because these can come up
in exam questions.
The next type is a partitioned placement group.
This spreads your instances across logical partitions so that the groups of instances in one partition
do not share the underlying hardware with groups of instances in another partition.
So this is where you want to ensure that if one of these partitions within an availability zone or across
availability zones fails, then you still have a group of instances that are in another partition,
which should still be running.
This strategy is often used for distributed and replicated workloads, and examples are Hadoop, Cassandra
and Kafka.
So by distributed and replicated, we mean that we have all nodes of our application in different places
and we might be replicating data between them.
So each cluster of those nodes may have the same or a portion of the overall data.
And if we lose one of those clusters, so a partition fails in the data center, we still have another
copy or multiple other copies.
The last type of placement group we have is a spread placement group, and here us is making sure that
every instance of your application is on different underlying hardware.
Now, to make this easier, we're going to visualize it now.
So firstly, we have our cluster placement group.
As you can see, we only have one availability zone here, and we've created the cluster placement group
and our nodes of that application are all very close together, which means that when they're trying
to send communications to each other, they can do so with extremely low latency.
So we have low network latency and high free for inter node communications.
Next, we have the Partition Placement Group.
As you can see, the partitions can be within an availability zone or across availability zones, and
IWC is going to make sure that these partitions on separate underlying hardware.
So if the underlying hardware of one partition fails, then the other politicians should not be affected.
In other words, each of these partitions will be in a separate WC rack.
Now, your partitions can be in multiple places up to seven per availability zone.
Lastly, we have a spread placement group and here each of all instances is in a separate WC rack.
So the underlying hardware that that instance is running on is in a completely separate rack, and therefore
the failure of that rack is not going to affect any of the other instances.
Now lastly, let's look at a few use cases, so we understand how we might use this in the real world.
So we have cluster placement groups, partition and then spread placement groups, and let's look at
some use cases and match them to these particular types of placement group.
So firstly, we have an application that is tightly coupled and it requires very low latency and high
network throughput between instances.
In that case, of course, we'd want to use a cluster placement group.
Next, we have a distributed and replicated NoSQL database that requires separate hardware for node
groups.
In that case, that's going to be a partition placement group.
And then lastly, we have a small number of critical instances that must be kept separate from each
other.
Well, then you would, of course, use a spread placement group.
So that's the theory behind placement groups.
Actually deploying a placement group is very simple in the easy to management console.
When you're configuring an instance that you're launching, you choose to either add it to an existing
placement group or create a new one.
If you create a new one, you give it a name.
Choose the type of placement group, and that's all you need to do.