Hi, guys.
This lesson, we're going to look at cash and behavior settings, and we're going to go into cloud front
and create our own distribution.
I'm locked into my account.
I've got cloud front open, which you'll notice is global.
And then I've also opened up.
As right now, the first thing we're going to do is create two buckets.
I'm going to call this one origin one.
And then I'm just going to give it some random letters and numbers.
And I want this to be us east one.
So you should do the same.
And click on Create Bucket, and the reason we use U.S. East one is when we create our cloud for distribution.
If we've just created our buckets, it can take time for the DNS names to propagate.
So if you use East one, that's fine.
But if you use of regions, sometimes you'll find that cloud front starts redirecting you to the.
S3 bucket, rather than retrieving the falls, so that's because the DNS names on updated, so now I'm
creating another bucket.
This one is origin, too.
Again, it's going to be in US East one.
So let's create that bucket.
Now, let's go back into the origin one.
I'm going to upload a file that files Choose My Beach or JPEG.
Upload that file that's come out of here.
And then it's go to Argentina and we're going to upload a different file.
So in this case, I have a copy for file here, so let's upload that file.
And that's done.
So that's great.
Let's go back up a level and we're not going to change anything else, we're not setting any permissions.
Let's create a distribution.
Click on Get Started.
So origin domain name.
We now choose our bucket name.
So this is why you can choose your origins and you see the various types and you got free elastic load
balancers, media package and media store.
We're going to choose our origin one bucket.
I'm not going to put in a path and I am going to restrict bucket access.
So this is where we can use origin, access identity.
I'm going to choose, create new identity and it's going to create one for me, and I wanted to update
the bucket policy as well.
So it's going to do that automatically.
We'll have a look at the policy in a moment.
Who scroll down this is where the viewer protocol policy is, so we can enable HDTV and HD https redirects
any HDTV connections to HD tapes or force HDTV only, and it gives us a warning here because that means
you will block any traffic coming in over HDTV.
I'll leave the default to scroll down a bit.
You can change things like the cache policy policies say we'll look at that a bit later on.
And also the origin request policy.
We're going to leave those for now.
This is where you restrict viewer access.
You can use signed you URLs or sign cookies.
We'll leave that off for now coming down.
You can also choose the price clause so you can change between the best performance or just have certain
regions.
I'll just go with us, Canada and Europe only now.
A.W. SWF comes up quite a lot in the program.
So you know that Aswath is a web application firewall.
You can create access control lists and you can attach those to cloud front.
So it's a great way of preventing known malicious attacks and doing so right at the edge there, where
the connections are coming in from the internet.
You can also specify a C name here so you can have your own alternate domain name rather than using
the default domain name of cloud phone.
You could also specify certificates and import through ACM.
You can specify a default route object, so if you have like an indexed or HDL file, you can specify
that here and that would be returned by default.
We're not going to do that.
We're just going to come down and create our distribution.
We'll see now that the distribution is in progress, so it can take a little while for that to actually
complete.
And then once that's complete, we're going to test and see that we can access our beach or JPEG file.
So I gave it a few minutes and we now have a state of enabled.
And let's go over now and see if we can connect to our distribution.
So I'm going to copy the domain name paste site into a new tab and then put in South Beach Dot JPEG,
and then we actually have a JPEG file.
Now, if you do try it without beached or JPEG, what you will find is probably there's nothing there.
And that's because we don't have a default document.
But the good thing is that beach shot JPEG is working, so that means origin one is actually the one
where we have that JPEG file and that is actually serving this content.
So let's head back over on the origins page.
We can create an origin, and in this case, I'm going to choose Origin two.
And then you can enable some of the other options here like we did before.
Now what we do want to do is restrict market access, create a new origin, access identity and also
update the bucket policy.
So just make sure you got those free selected and click on Create.
Now let's have a look at the buckets and see what's happened there.
If we go to Origin one permissions, scroll down and you'll see that cloud font has automatically updated
the policy, so it has the origin access identity.
It's an allow statement for the S3 gets object on this specific resource, so that looks good.
Now let's go and check Origin two permissions.
Scroll down.
And sure enough, it also has its own Origin Access Identity statement.
So coming back, the next thing that I want to do, I have an origin now, but I need to specify a way
of directing certain requests to that origin, and we're going to do that through behaviors.
So I'm going to create a behavior and this behavior is going to be four star MP full and it's going
to go to origin to.
We can then specify the protocol policies and HTTP methods.
All of these other settings, if we want.
I'm going to leave all of those as defaults.
Click on Create.
So we now have a path pattern defined, which means the default is going to go to S3 or June one.
But if we have an MP for fall requested, then it's going to go to origin too.
So the next thing to do is go and check if that actually works.
So back on our page here, I'm going to backspace this beach dot JPEG and put in DCT or MP for and hit
enter.
And sure enough, it's going to load this video.
So that works.
It successfully loads the video, but then it also will go back to the JPEG that comes from a different
bucket.
If we want it to as well.
So that's part patterns in action, and this can come up quite often on the exam, which is why I wanted
to show you practically how to use it.
So we've cloud front.
You can also generate error pages.
You can set up restrictions such as geo restrictions.
So if we click on Edit here, you'll see that you can restrict and use a whitelist or blacklist based
approach based on country cancel out of their.
You can also invalidate, so this is where you can invalidate in objects.
And this means it's going to remove it from the cache.
You do have to pay for these requests.
So I'm actually done with this now, so I'm going to come back and I'm simply going to disable my distribution.
Now, if you work with Cloudflare before you'll know that it then takes several minutes for the distribution
to be disabled.
And then once it's disabled, you're able to go in and delete it.
So don't forget to come back and delete your origin.
And that's it for this lesson.