Welcome to this lesson.
We've already looked at quite a few I am policies and in the hands on that's coming up, we're going
to use quite a few more as well.
So this is a lesson to help you understand the structure of I am policies.
So this is the basic structure.
Remember, it's a JSON document, JavaScript object notation, and it consists of one or more statements
at the top.
There we have the effects this can be allow or deny.
We then got the action element and that will be the specific API action for which you're granting or
denying permissions.
We then have the resource element.
So this is the specific resource that is affected by the action.
So we'll put in the Amazon resource name the Arrow and into the resource element.
And then lastly, here we have an optional element, which is the condition element.
And this can be used to control when the policy is put into effect, and we'll see some examples showing
this in a moment.
So let's look at a few examples, this is a very simple one.
In this case, the administrator access policy is using wild cards to allow all actions on all resources.
So we simply have the effect allow.
We have the action, which is a wild card.
And then the resource, which is a wild card.
So this will allow any action on any resource.
Now let's look at one that's a little bit more complex.
In this case, the specific API action is defined, so we're not using a wild card under action.
We have easy to on terminate instances.
So that's the specific API action that we want to control.
Now, in this case, the resource is stored, so is a wild card.
But we then have a conditional elements and the conditional element uses the not my IP address and it's
looking for the source IP.
So it's looking into that request context for the IP address that you're making the request from.
And the effects in this case is to deny the action if the IP address is not in the specified range.
So this is one where you want to make sure that nobody is terminating 82 instances unless they're actually
and in some office somewhere on a particular network.
The next example is a resource based policy and the way that we can tell that this is a resource based
policy is because we have this principle element here.
So in this case, the principle is a star, so it's a wild card.
But we could also put a specific principles in in here as well, like a user.
In this case, the policy grants read and write access to Amazon Elastic File System file systems to
all principles, so it's allowing all users access.
And note also that the condition element is looking for secure transport to be true.
That means it's checking in the request context to make sure that the connection that you're coming
from is encrypted with SSL TLS certificates.
In this last policy here, we're trying to control access to S3 buckets, and what we want to do is
have a particular folder for each user and allow them access to that particular folder.
So what we're going to do here is use an S3 prefix variable and that will replace this particular variable
here with the user's friendly name.
So my account that would be nil.
So just replace this with nil.
So it would then give access to the particular folder within the bucket that has this name.
So give me permissions to my own folder within that bucket.
That's it for now, and you will get plenty of opportunity to work with some policies in the hands on
labs that are coming up.