The Amazon Simple Notification Service S.A. is a pub sub, so publisher subscriber messaging service
that allows you to decouple applications.
So the way it works is you have a publisher and the publisher sends a message to a topic.
And the topic will then deliver the message over various different transport protocols, such as SMS,
email, https to a subscriber and a subscriber can be things like excuse lamda a web application, perhaps
running on Ekta and also email and SMS.
So text messages.
So it's another way that you can decouple your applications by putting something in the middle so that
your publishers here are not directly integrating with your subscribers.
So S.A.S. is a highly available, durable, secure and fully managed pub sub messaging service.
S.A.S. provides topics for high throughput, push based many to many messaging.
So this means you can have many publishers and many subscribers.
The publisher systems can fan out the messages to a large number of endpoints.
So, for instance, you can have a single publisher system that might send messages to a large number
of subscriber endpoints, and those endpoints can be excused.
Lambda functions, https web hooks, mobile push and SMS text messaging as well as email.
You group your recipients by what's called a topic and a topic is an access point, which allows the
recipients to dynamically subscribe for identical copies of the same notification so multiple subscribers
can receive an identical copy of the same message.
One topic can also support deliveries to multiple endpoint types, and all messages are stored redundantly
across multiple bases.
With S.A.S., you get instantaneous push based delivery and it uses simple APIs for easy integration
of applications.
Like most other services, you get flexible message delivery over multiple transport protocols.
And as I mentioned before, you can send messages to many receivers, so the event producer sends one
message to one S.A.S. topic and then many event receivers subscribers listen for those notifications
and each subscriber will get all of the messages.
So you send a message once all the subscribers will receive the same message.
But subscribers can then filter messages in terms of limits.
You get up to 10 million subscriptions per topic and you have a limit of 100000 topics.
Another use case is what's called S.A.S. and skews fan out.
So in this case, you can subscribe one or more excuse to an SS topic.
So in this case, messages are being published from the topic and they get sent to the queue.
So the HQ receives the same message.
Escalus manages the subscription and any necessary permissions.
And when you publish a message to a topic, S.A.S. will send the message to every subscribe queue.
So that's it for the ferry.
And what we're going to do in the next lesson is we're going to set up this configuration where we're
able to send messages to an SMS topic, have them go into a queue and then have LAMDA polling the queue
and writing an event account which logs.