When now grounds cover the fail over routing policy we've failed over routing.
You can have a primary and secondary target and using health checks you can determine whether your primary
is healthy or not.
So you have to have a health check on your primary resource and then if that health check fails you
will cut over to your secondary resource.
So let's head over to the console and have a look at how this works and what we're gonna do is we're
going to create a record set.
Let's just go and get the IP address of our North Virginia server.
So that's this one here
and I'm going to paste this in excuse me I'm pasting that in the wrong place that's it in the correct
place and we're just going to call this file over so we change the file over and then fight over records
like this primary for this one and then we have to associate health checks.
If I click on Create Now it's gonna give us an error.
So you absolutely have to have that health check and I'm going to choose my North Virginia health check
so I can now configure the secondary in this case I'm going to choose our elastic load balancer so let's
choose my Alby and choose fail over and this time it's the secondary.
And let's just see if we can get away without the health check on this one and we can.
So we only need it on the primary so we've got those two records.
And if we head over to a browser window and type file over DCT labs dot com we should find that we get
a response from North Virginia.
So what happens then when this server is not accessible.
Well the way I'm going to simulate that let's just head over it's easy to
and I'm going to change it now looks like I'm in north Virginia and I'm just gonna go down to security
groups
and I'm gonna go to the web access security group and I'm going to remove the port 80 rule.
So remember our health check is actually functioning by looking at ports 80 on the machine.
So it's doing a a request to report AC and if that's not accessible then the health checks going to
fail so you can now come back to health checks and everything looks good at the moment so let's just
give it a little a little while so that it can actually catch up and realize that that server is not
accessible.
So while that's happening this just quickly go over to the console and hit refreshing to see what happens.
So remember our instance doesn't have the secondary address at this stage or our client doesn't have
the secondary address at this stage because Ralph 50 free has only supplied the address of the primary
resource but we remove poor data from the security group so it can no longer access it.
So it's just timing out.
So let's go back.
We need to wait for this health check to fail before Ralph 53 is actually going to give us that secondary
record
so it looks like we've got an unhealthy record now for North Virginia.
So let's go back and see what happens if we refresh our browser and we're not getting anything yet.
So let's go to Digg and see what record we get returned to us.
If we type find over the DCT labs dot com and we get the 241 address which I'm pretty sure that's obviously
the the North Virginia instance.
So we're still getting that
though we can see that we have a failed health check here so it shouldn't be long before we get the
correct response and it may be due to the TTL him so I just waited a couple of minutes while the TTL
expired and now I've run Digg again and you can see that I've got the multiple addresses which corresponded
my load balancer.
So we should be at a refresh the browser now and this is a good example of why you want to be careful
with UTC ls because clearly the website went down and it's a fair amount of time this is closeouts haven't
started it another one because it might be caching something in the browser.
So now we are getting that secondary address and we're on the instance into B and I'm pretty sure if
we just keep hitting refresh we're getting cycled by the load balancer.
So that's it really.
Clearly this is something where you do need to think about that TTL because if it's too high and your
Web site goes down you're not going to fail over to your second day for a while.
So your clients are still going to have that primary record cached and they're not going to be able
to get the new secondary records to connect to the correct resource.
So be careful when determining the TTL is for your application records.