Hi guys.
So carrying on from the last lap.
We're going to just have a quick look at private IP addresses.
Now before we go on to learn about public ip addresses a bit more.
So all I want to show you is I've launched an instance and the instance as we can see in the console
here has a public address but it has a private address here.
So every instance will have a private address whether it's in a public subnet or a private subnet.
It doesn't matter.
It's always going to have one and the address is going to be from the range assigned to our VPC and
the subnet which we launched this one into.
So if we head over to BPC and this subnet is assigned to availability zone AP SD to A and we can see
it has a site a block of 1 7 2 31 0 0 0 slash 20.
And that's where our easy two instances.
So we can see that this instance
is in AP southeast to A and therefore our addresses within that side to block range.
You can also see there's a private DNS address which just like the public DNS address contains the actual
IP address within the first section here.
Now I've logged on to this instance and I just want to show you what the operating system sees.
Now remember this has a public IP address and a private IP address.
So I'm logged onto the console for the easy to instance and let's run the command.
I have config and this shows us our local interfaces and we only have one interface if zero and we can
see that it has an IP address and that's the private IP address.
So there's absolutely no sign of the public IP address here.
That's because the operating system is not aware of it at all.
So there's nothing about the public IP address on the instance the public IP address is external to
the operating system and NWS takes care of the association between that address and the private address
if we go back to our instance.
Let's just have a quick look at the behavior.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to shut down my instance.
And so just make sure you remember the address is 1 7 2 dot 31 dot for dot 1 9 2 and we'll stop our
instance.
So the instance has stopped and in fact we didn't need to remember anything because we can see that
the private IP address is still here but the public IP address is gone.
So when you stop the instance you do retain this private IP address but you lose your public address.
And if we start this instance back up again we're actually going to get a completely different public
IP address.
Just going back to the slide so that just reinforces what we knew here that we have private IP addresses
in public and private subnets and the private addresses are retained when the instance is stopped.
And this is all the operating system sees it doesn't see the public IP addresses and it doesn't see
the elastic IP addresses either.
So that's it for this lab in the next lab.
We're going to cover the public and elastic IP addresses in more detail.