Welcome to the exam cram for Section 16 and we're starting off with
Identity and Access Management. So IAM is used to security control individual and group access to
AWS resources. With IAM
we can manage users groups access policies roles user credentials user password policies and also multi
factor authentication and API keys for programmatic access. By default new users are created with no access
to any IAM services.
That's a key one that comes up in exam questions.
If you create a new user and you don't assign them to a group or assign any permissions directly to
them they're not going to have any permissions at all.
So you have to explicitly grant permissions to allow a user to access an AWS service. IAM or IAM is
not used for application level authentication.
So your application might use some other mechanism.
It could be something like Active Directory or samba directory service or some other third party service
or if you have a mobile application it could be using something like AWS Cognito.
You can enable identity Federation.
So this is includes Active Directory and Facebook and other identity providers which means that you
can allow secure access to resources in your account without the user needing to have an IAM account.
So they might have an account in Active Directory rather than an account in
IAM. With MFA
you can enable and enforce this at the account level or for individual users in the accounts.
Now the best practice today..
It has changed a couple of times in the last year but the best practice at the moment is that you should
use MFA for all users and use U2F or hardware MFA devices for all privileged users.
They used to say just enable MFA for the root account.
Then they changed it to enable MFA for all privileged users.
Now they're saying enable it for everyone but use a hardware device to make it even more secure for
any privileged users.
Remember that IAM is global so it doesn't apply to regions.
That means if you create an account and IAM that account can be used anywhere in the world for instance
exam questions sometimes come up and say something along the lines of a company is setting up a new
office in another part of the world and you need to work out what do you do in terms of setting the
user accounts up for that office.
Well of course you don't need to do anything because IAM is a global service.
The root account is the accountant that's created when you set up your IAM account and that has complete administrative
access and by default it's the only account that will have complete administrative access.
It's best practice to not use the root account for anything other than billing.
That's the only account that has access to billing information and that's the only reason you should
use it. In terms of authentication methods.
So we've got the console password.
So as we know this is when you log in to the management console with a user account and you have a password
and a user name and you have the password.
We then have access keys so these are the combination of the Access Key I.D. and the secret access key.
Access keys are used for making programmatic calls to AWS services using the API so you can put those
in program code or the command prompt. Remember it's a best practice not to do that at least not to embed
it in some code somewhere.
You've got to keep these pretty secure. Then we have service certificates.
These can be used to authenticate with some AWS
services and AWS recommend that you use the AWS certificate manager to provision and manage those certificates.
IAM users are an entity that represents a person an individual or a service and they can be assigned
an access key I.D. and secret access key, so that's for the programmatic access so we've seen where
we've created all individual user account and then we can create access keys for those user accounts
and then you can get a password for access to the management console as well.
And remember you can have one or the other or both of these so you can enable a user account so they
only have access to the management console or you can enable them to also have programmatic access or
just given programmatic access.
Users can also be created to represent applications and that's known as a service account.
We then have groups so remember we use groups to create a collection of users and then attach a policy.
So you're using a group to assign permissions to multiple users a group not an identity so you can't
actually identify or specify the group name in an iron policy but what you can do is apply a policy
to the group so you use groups to assign permissions to users.
Always use the principle of least privilege when assigning permissions.
So only give people the minimum amount of privileges they need to do their job.
That's a security best practice.
You can't miss groups say can't put one group inside another group moving on to roles these are created
and then assumed by a trusted entity.
So we remember that if we wanted to give our EC2 instance access to Amazon S3 we create a role
that had the privileges that allowed to read and write to S3.
And then we assign that to the EC2 instance it can then assume that role and perform actions against
S3.
So that means that you're delegating permissions to resources without using those permanent credentials.
So remember that this is how you can get around having to embed those access keys into code which is
a big security no no.
So both uses and services can assume roles to obtain temporary security or credentials that they then
use to make API calls and think of this as being delegation and there's no credentials so no password
and no access key.
So much more secure than using passwords or access keys in your code.
So we then have the policy itself.
So these are the documents that actually define the permissions to be applied to the users groups or
rows to which they are assigned.
They're written in JSON using key value pairs all permissions are implicitly denied so that just means
that unless you explicitly define a permission then it's just going to be denied by default.
If there are multiple conflicting statements so something is allowed but it's restricted somewhere else
then the most restrictive policy will be applied.
So let's have another look at IAM best practices, so there's quite a few of these.
I recommend that you actually have a look on the AWS Web site.
Just search for IAM best practices on google and you'll find the article and just make sure you're familiar
with these.
So firstly lock away your AWS account root user access keys and better still if you don't need them
delete them.
You should create individual IAM users so don't share accounts will use the administrative accounts.
Always use groups to assign permissions to IAM users so that means that you can create the permission
policies once and apply them to a group.
And that means that lots of users in that group will have those permissions always grant these privilege
only give people the access they need get started using permissions with AWS to manage policy.
So this means used to manage policies that AWS created.
So there's some pre configured policies that you can use and that would just make life easier and make
sure that especially when an organization is using the cloud for the first time and they're not that
advanced with creating policies it means there's less chance of human error.
Use custom managed policies instead of in-line policies.
So what this means is use managed policies where you can define everything in one place and manage it
in one place rather than inline so inline means that you create the policy and you attach it to the
user directly or the service directly whereas a managed policy will be something centrally that can
be managed in one place.
Now if you have inline policies and you needed to make a change you'd have to do it on every user that
you've created and assign that policy to use access levels to review and permission.
So this just means that you should regularly review the amount of access your users have through that
IAM permissions.
So make sure that you're monitoring and making sure that people don't have more access than they need
configure a strong password policy so obviously a stronger passwords harder to crack. Enable MFA.
So again the latest advice is to enable MFA for all users and use hardware MFA devices for privileged
users. Use roles for applications that run on EC2 instances.
We've done this in the labs.
This is about where we want to use a role to provide access to EC2 say.
In the example again of S3.
We can assign a role to EC2 and EC2 instance can then access s3.
The other way of doing it is to use access keys where we actually have to copy the access keys onto
the EC2 instance and that's a big security concern.
Use roles to delegate permissions again use those roles to delegate permissions rather than using passwords
rather than using access keys.
Never share access keys.
Remember whoever has access to your access keys.
They can then use those access keys and whatever privileges are assigned to the account where those
access keys are being created.
Those users will be able to use those permissions.
Make sure you rotate credentials regularly so with those access keys delete them and rotate them regularly.
Always remove unnecessary credentials if you don't need them.
Get rid of them.
You can use conditions in policies to apply extra security so for instance a condition in a policy might
say something like you are allowing access only if a request is coming from a specific IP address.
Also always monitor activity in your AWS account.