In this lab I want to show you the VPC wizard.
So you now know how to create your own VPC manually and that's probably the way you're going to do it.
Most of the time however it's worth knowing that there is a VPC wizard which automates part of that
process.
And it's also worth noting for the exam because there are some questions that come up sometimes which
ask you about the configurations that are created through the VPC wizard.
So if you come in here you get a few options.
You can select VPC with a single public subnet and it will create a slash 16 network with it.
So it's a slash 16 side a block that is with a 24 subnet.
So a single subnet and public subnet instances use elastic eyepiece or public eyepiece to access the
Internet.
So it's basically just creating a public subnet and we know exactly what those are.
And then if you collects click select it will just ask you to define your own site a block you can choose
to use IP B6 and you can specify Availability Zones and subnet names and so on.
So that's very simple.
Then there's the public and private subnets.
So in this case you get two subnets you still get the slash 16 network and you get a public subnet and
a private subnet and the private subnet instances access the Internet via net.
So what that would actually do then is create a NAT gateway for you.
So if you have a look in here you can see it's all very similar except we have the private subnet as
well.
And then we have the NAT gateway and it's going to ask for an elastic IP
so the third option here is VPC with public and private subnets and hardware VPN access.
So this is the same as the previous one except that we connect the corporate data center using a virtual
private network.
So let's select this option and what you'll see in here is very similar let's just give it a name so
that we can get to the next screen.
And then when we click next it's going to ask us for the customer Gateway information
so I'll cancel out of that one and this is go back to the ABC wizard and then the last one is a VPC
of a private subnet only and hardware VPN access.
So in this case there's no connectivity via the Internet.
So this is other VPN is obviously an encrypted connection that goes over the Internet.
But what I mean is nothing is addressable by the Internet.
So as a purely private subnet and you're able to then round data between your corporate datacenter and
that private subnet without any public exposure so very simple just need to know it's there it's under
VPC dashboard not under you'll be pieces so you'll find the wizard here and you just understand that
different options in the Wizard and what configurations they create.