You'll remember that earlier in the course, I talked about how some IWC services are private and that
they run within a VPC like EC2, whereas other services are public because they have a public endpoint
like Amazon is free, for example.
So that means when you connect to Amazon, it's free.
You use a public DNS name to connect to it as a public end point.
Now what if you wanted to connect an instance to Amazon free, but you didn't want to use the public
internet?
It might be an instance in a private subnet.
Well, that's where the IPC endpoints come in, and there's a few use cases for PPC endpoints with connecting
privately to S3 being one of them.
And there are two different types.
There's a VPC interface endpoint and a VPC gateway endpoint.
The Gateway endpoint is one which we could use for free, and the interface endpoint is slightly different
is used for other services.
So let's start there first.
Let's look at an example using a VPC interface endpoint.
So we've got EC2 running in a private subnet, and we don't want this instance to have a public IP,
and we don't want it to be rousted out to the internet via a NAT gateway.
So we provision an interface endpoint, which creates an Illinois in the subnet.
And then the instance can connect via that Illinois to public services, but it's using private IP addresses
to connect to them.
Now, each interface endpoint can connect to one of many services, and you can connect to an AWG private
link powered service as well.
We'll look at that shortly to see what that means.
So this is a way that we can connect or two instances to these services using private IP addresses.
Now let's look at the difference between that and a gateway endpoint.
So in this case, I want to connect to Amazon as free to store data in an S3 bucket.
And again, I don't want to have a public IP address.
So an instance at a public subnet.
In this case, it isn't a private subnet.
And I don't want a provision in that gateway.
Or at least I don't want this traffic to go out to the internet so I could provision a free gateway
endpoint.
This is slightly different.
It uses a route table entry.
So we now have to put a round table entry to point our traffic to the free gateway endpoint, and that
uses the prefix list for the S3 and the Gateway.
The instance again connects using a private IP address to the gateway endpoint, and then from there
it connects to Amazon S3.
Now you can secure this with IAM policies so you can apply a policy to the endpoint.
And you can also apply bucket policies.
So, for example, you can have a bucket policy that limits access to any traffic that's coming from
the gateway endpoint.
So you now have a bucket, which will only accept traffic from instances that are using the S3 gateway
endpoint.
So let's just recap the differences with the interface endpoint.
You've got an elastic network interface with a private IP with a gateway endpoint.
You have a target in your root table for the Gateway.
So interface endpoints.
We use DNS entries to redirect traffic, whereas gateway endpoints use the prefix list in the roundtable
to redirect traffic.
Now what services?
While there's quite a few with an interface, endpoint API Gateway Cloud formation and cloud blocks
are just a few examples.
Lots of the public services can be accessed via an interface endpoint, but a gateway endpoint is restricted
to Amazon S3 and Dynamo DB only.
With an interface endpoint, you use security groups to control traffic, whereas with a gateway endpoint,
you can use VPC endpoint policies.
Now lastly, let's look at how we can use this in a service provider model.
So what I mean is we have a consumer of APC and a service provider PPC, so we've got a couple of subnets
in each VPC.
And what's happening is the service provider is creating a service and that service is behind a network
load balancer and they want to provide that service to consumers.
So what happens as a consumer is you provision an endpoint and then you use that endpoint to access
the service.
So we're actually publishing a service in one side and then we're consuming it in the VPC, on the left
and using an interface endpoint to actually consume that service.
So that's how it works.
And in the next lesson, we're going to set up a gateway endpoint.