So we've now learned about the different access control options.
And I just want to do a quick lab to talk about the choices around when you would use one over another.
So we know that the identity based policies are where we use policies that are attached to roles, users
and groups and then we have bucket policies which are policies that are applied at the bucket level.
We then have the ACLs and the ACLs apply at the bucket and object level and have less granularity especially
in terms of the permissions that can be assigned and the uses that they can be assigned to so the account
level not the user level.
So those are some key differences.
And then it's even the account or one of these predefined groups as I mentioned before.
So authenticated users, all users, or the log Delivery Group.
Now I want to take you to a Web page where AWS talk about the guidelines for using the available
access policy options.
So that's the title of the article.
And if you come down here there's really a couple of areas that are worth highlighting.
And that is the use cases for using ACL based policies because there's a few of them and then pretty
much everything else falls into the category of use a policy applied at the identity level or the bucket
level.
So with object ACLs there's a few use cases.
One is that an object ACL is the only way to manage access to objects that aren't owned by the bucket
owner.
So you might own the bucket but you provide another account access to upload objects and then as
the bucket owner you don't actually control or have permissions to those objects and it says here the
AWS account that created the object must grant permissions using objects ACL.
And so the restriction here is that the bucket owner cannot grant permissions on the objects that it
doesn't own so there are some use cases where you might want to apply this configuration so Another
use case is when your permissions vary by objects.
And so you want to manage your permissions at the object level but each object may have a different
setting.
So in this case you could use a policy.
However if there's a large number of objects that may become impractical and your bucket policies are
limited to 20 kb so you may find that trying to do that through statements in a policy becomes
unwieldy.
And in that case you can use an ACL.
It does state however that even the object ACL is limited to a maximum of 100 grants. And then the third
use case is when object ACL is control only object level permissions.
So you've got one bucket policy but each object has different permissions so in this case rather than
providing too much permission to another account to actually change the permissions you grant the write ACL
rights access control permissions on a subset of the objects.
And that means that that account will then be able to create and write the permissions for those objects
without having the access to do that with any other objects and then the bucket ACL level the only recommended
use case is to grant right permission to the S3 lock Delivery Group to write access logs.
So that's it really there's a few use cases for ACLs
But mainly you're gonna be using policies, identity based policies or resource based policies.