Hi, guys.
We've launched a few easy two instances so far, and they've always had a elastic network interface
attached, so when you launch an instance, it comes with a network interface attached to it and that
will have a private IP address.
And then in some cases, it can also have a public IP address if it's in a public subnet.
Now, an elastic network interface is one type of adapter.
There's also something called an elastic network adapter and an elastic fabric adapter in this lesson.
I'll go through the key information you need to know about these different adapters.
So let's have a look at a example of an easy to instance.
And when we launch, like two instances, we usually choose a subnet.
Now, when you do that, it will attach a interface in that subnet.
But the actual AC instance itself isn't in the subnet.
It's within the availability zone because remember, an AC is essentially a data center or one or more
data centers.
Now that means the easy to instance can be attached to multiple subnet fruit different adapters.
So here we have an easy to instance it has its EF zero adapter in the public subnet and that has a private
IP address assigned to it.
And it also has a public IP address as well.
Now we could also have another network interface, which is in a private subnet, but it has to be within
the same availability zone.
So if one is in the private subnet.
But that private subnet is within the same availability zone as the public subnet, where if zero is
now, we could not attach an adapter from a subnet in another availability zone that just won't work.
So the key thing to remember is you can have multiple adapters connected to an instance.
They can be in different subnet.
But the subnets have to be in the same availability zone.
Now, as I mentioned as Elastic Network interfaces, elastic network adapters and elastic fabric adapters.
So what's the difference between these?
Well, the Illinois is the basic adapter for when you don't have any specific high performance requirements
and you can use it with any EC2 instance type.
The Elastic Network adapter is for enhanced networking performance.
It has much higher bandwidth and lower, in instance, latency.
You have to choose supported instance types.
You can't use any instance type with an Ayeni.
Lastly, we have the elastic fabric adapt, so this is for more specialized use cases.
You use this for high performance computing, HPC and MPI and ML use cases.
So that's message passing interface and machine learning use cases so more specialized, it's more tightly
coupled applications.
So those applications, which will typically be in low latency environments where they're very close
to each other and they have a lot of interconnectivity between them, lots of messaging happening between
components of the application.
You can use those with all instance types, but again, you'd only use them when you have a specific
use case.
So that's it for the ferry will go into a hands on in the next lesson and have a look at how we can
assign additional adapters to our active instances.