The IAM policy simulator is a really useful tool that enables you to actually simulate policies being
applied to users and actually view what permissions they should be granted or restricted.
There is a link attached to this lesson that you'll need to follow to open the IAM policy simulator
and you'll need to be locked into your account as well.
So this is the main page for the policy simulator.
On the left hand side, we can choose users groups or roles.
Let's keep it on users.
Now I only have one user, so I don't need to use a filter to search.
I can see my user account on the left.
So let's choose Neil and we can see that Neil has the administrator access policy applied.
On the right hand side, I can then select a service, so perhaps I'm going to type two and select that
easy to service.
Now there's lots of API actions associated with the service.
As you can see, there's a few hundred of them.
In fact, what I'm going to do is select all and I want to see which permissions I have now.
As you can imagine, I should have permissions to all of these.
So let's run the simulation and very quickly it returns these results, and it's showing each of the
individual API actions and the permission is allowed.
So I definitely am allowed all of these permissions.
Let's now create an IAM user who will have fewer permissions and see how useful this tool is back in
IAM.
I've chosen users and I'm going to add a new user.
I'll call this user Sara Enable Management Console Access with an auto generated password because we're
not actually going to log in as this user.
Now what I'm going to do is rather than adding to a group for this particular use case, I'm going to
attach an existing policy directly.
So let's search for easy to.
And I'm going to scroll down to where it says easy to read only access, then after selecting that policy,
click on Next, go to review and create the user.
Let's now close out of that.
Select the user and we can see the permissions policies that are attached because we left the option
selected to force a password, reset the users being granted the permission that the other policy that's
applied is easy to read, only access.
So let's now go and see what access this user has too easy to say back in the policy simulator.
I'm going to choose back up in the top left.
The page might need to be refreshed, and now it's showing Sarah we can see the policies apply to Sarah.
Let's do the same thing again, and in the right hand side, choose to.
I'm going to select all permissions.
And then run the simulation.
So this time we get lots of the so we're getting deniers for things like assign an IP address or associate
a DHC option, all things that are involving changing, deleting or adding a configuration.
If we scroll down quite a way, we should find some allowed permissions.
So here we go.
For allow permissions, we can see things like describe addresses, describe bundle tasks, described
carrier gateways, et cetera.
So anything that's just about viewing information.
So that's the policy simulator is very useful, especially when you have quite complex policies applied
to users and you want to be able to view the results here rather than actually logging in as these users
and testing the results.
So really great tool for simulating the effects of the policies that you apply to your principles in
a.