Hi guys.
This is a lesson on auto scaling termination policies.
Now the reason I have this slide up is I just wanted to set the scene so a termination policy applies
when auto scaling determines that it needs to terminate an instance in response to a scaling adjustment.
So let's say you have a step scaling policy which states that when your CPA goes over 60 or 70 percent
auto scaling should add an additional instance.
Now let's say what's happened is you your load on your application has decreased.
And now auto scaling realizes that you've dropped beneath a certain threshold and it now needs to terminate
one of your instances because you don't need the capacity anymore.
So this is not in response to an instance becoming unhealthy.
It's just in response to auto scaling scaling in your pool of instances to reduce cost running your
application.
So the question is which instance does auto scaling terminate first.
And that's the subject of this lesson.
There are a number of policies that can be applied to determine which instance auto scaling terminates
first.
Now by default there's a default policy applied.
What that does is goes through a series of steps.
The first one is it determines which AC has the most instances.
So in this case it would be simple easy to hear has free instances.
So one of these will be terminated if that's not the case and you've got an even number of instances
and both your Availability Zones.
The next thing is step two auto scaling determines which instance to terminate.
So as to a line the remaining instances to the allocation strategy for the OnDemand or spot instance
that is terminating and your current selection of instance types.
So that's quite a mouthful but what is essentially saying is it's trying to align the number of on demand
versus spot instances that you have.
Now this applies when you're using launch templates where you can specify a mixture of on demand or
spot instances doesn't apply to launch configurations.
If Step Two doesn't apply.
We move on to Step 3 auto scaling determines whether any of the instances use the oldest launch template.
So if there's multiple versions of launch templates auto scaling will terminate an instance that uses
the oldest launch template.
If that doesn't apply Step Four says the auto scaling determines whether any of the instances use the
oldest launch configuration.
So if you're using launch configurations instead of launch templates it's going to look at which instances
use the oldest launch configuration.
Step five then applies and one step five says is after applying all of the criteria in steps 2 to 4
if there are multiple unprotected instances to terminate.
Determine which instances are closest to the next billing hour.
So for example if you had a situation where you had multiple launch configurations auto scaling would
select the instances with the oldest launch configuration and if there were multiple instances that
applies to within that launch configuration it would terminate the instance that's closest to the next
billing hour.
Now just a note on unprotected instances.
This means they're not termination protected.
And we'll see this in the console in a second.
So I'm in the console now and I just want to show you where you can figure the termination policy.
So if you edit the details of your auto screening group you'll find termination policies here and you
can see the default termination policy is applied.
You can then select from these different termination policies and you can actually look these up on
the Amazon website.
You can click learn more and find out about the configuration of these different launch configurations.
You won't need to know what all of these are for the exam but it's worth understanding the default termination
policy instance protection as I mentioned before is how you can protect an instance from Sky Lane.
So if you select this option then new instances that are launched into the auto scanning group will
be protected from scale in events which means they can't be terminated while we're here I also want
to show you suspended processes.
This is something where you can configure auto scaling to not process certain events.
So for instance you can suspend the termination process and auto screening won't terminate instances.
You can suspend the replacement of unhealthy instances so it won't terminate and then replace an unhealthy
instance.
So if you select these options and you can select multiple at a time you can stop the auto scaling behaviour
from occurring and that might be good when you're trying to troubleshoot an unhealthy instance you might
want to go in there and terminate or shut down that instance reboot it whatever it might be and use
one auto scaling to replace it at this stage you're trying to find out what's going on.
I'm just gonna cancel out of here and that's it for termination policies in the next lab.
We're going to cover cross zone load balancing.