Hi, guys, and this lesson, we're going to use S.A.S. with excuse and Lamda, so this will be a hands
on lab.
We're going to go over.
We're going to try and S.A.S. topic and excuse.
Q and a LAMDA function.
And what's going to happen is the when we send a message to the topic, it's going to get put into the
Q Lamda will poll the Q and it will write an event, a cloud watch logs and won't be able to read the
message that we sent to the topic.
So let's head over to the console and build this out.
So first off, I'm going to create my topic, I go into S.A.S. and choose Creutz topic, and I'm just
going to call this one my first topic.
You can optionally put it in a display name.
You can set encryption.
So in this case, you can use encryption and by default, it's going to use ECMC from CM's or you can
select a custom SMK.
I'm going to disable that.
We then have an access policy.
Now, we don't need to modify this now, but you can see here you have the basic option or advanced
where you just do the device on yourself.
You have to put in your own JSON code.
If you choose basic, then on the left here we can change these settings and automatically change the
policy.
So we could put in a specified AWB account change position for everyone to be able to publish to this
topic or just the owner of the topic.
Similarly, we can do the same for subscribers.
I'm going to leave those defaults.
We then have the delivery retry policy and we can also configure logging and the role that's used by
S.A.S. for logging.
I don't need to change any of those, so I'm just going to choose.
Great topic.
The next thing I want to do is go over to us.
And we're going to create a queue, just going to call this my US queue, and it will be a standard
queue and just choose quick creates.
Now that we've created the queue, we can actually subscribe the queue to the next topic.
So if we come in here, we can find our topic and choose, subscribe, and that's successful.
So let's just test out this portion of the set up.
If we come back and go to subscriptions, we can now see that we have a subscription to us and that's
been automatically created.
Let's go back to topics, choose our topic.
Publish a message and we'll put first test message in the subject line.
And then I'm just going to type.
My test message in the message body here, and I don't need to change anything else, so that's published
a message.
Now, if we head over to us and hit refresh, we can see we've got the message and if we go into the
Q and poll, we can actually pick up that message and see that we've got the subjects and the message
body in there.
So that's all working great.
Let's go over to LAMDA now, and I'm going to create a function, I'll call it my excuse, S.A.S. test,
it's going to be no notorious.
I'm going to choose an execution row and go down and choose my lambda basic execution.
Now, I've already got the permissions I need here, but what you're going to need to do if you're using
a new role is come in to the role and attach the lambda queue execution roles.
So just going to attach policies and attach that policy and that will give us the privileges we need.
So we need to allow them to be able to receive message and delete message and get Q attributes.
And it will also be able to log to Clowned, which logs.
So that looks good.
Let's come back and what we're going to do in our function is we need to copy over this code.
So I've got this code here.
And if you go into your code directory.
In the course download, you'll find this under S.A.S., Lambda Code, S.A.S. test, and you just need
to copy this code and then delete out all the code from the function and paste that in.
So what this is going to do is it's going to actually log the body of the message it receives from us.
So this will mean that the payload, in other words, the message body, so whatever we write into the
message will end up in cloud, which logs.
And in this case, because we're using S.A.S. to create the message, it's going to be whatever we write
in our S.A.S. message that ends up in cloud watch.
So I'm going to save that.
And now we need to actually create the trigger.
So I'm going to do it the other way around.
This time before, in a previous lab, I showed you how to do it from us.
So we went in and configure a trigger for Lambda.
But you can also do the same thing here so you can just use and trigger.
I'm going to put in ask us to filter the view.
And then let's choose our cue and leave it on a table trigger.
So that's it, we've got our trigger.
Let's come back and it's publish a message I'm going to call this second test message and that's right
in this is a message from S.A..
And she's published message, so hopefully now that should end up going through the queue and it will
be processed by Lambda, S.C. Both of those messages have gone now.
And if we come back to Lambda, go to monitoring and view cloud watch logs and we've got two log streams
here.
So let's have a look into this one here.
And if we go into info, we can see the second text message.
This is a message from S.A.S. so that messages come through from S.A.S..
So back in our diagram, what we've done is we created a topic.
In essence, we've published a message to the topic.
That message has then gone to the subscriber, which is the excuse.
Q.
And then Lamda has polled the key, found the message, run the function code and written an event cloud
watch logs.
So I hope you enjoyed that, guys, in terms of clean up, very, very simple to go back in and just
delete your topic.
You just have to put in delete me.
You can delete your subscription.
And back and ask us to leave the queue, go to functions on the lamda and then just delete your function.