Hi guys.
This is a lesson on the AWS global infrastructure.
So in this lesson this is purely going to be theory.
I'm not actually going to take you into the console and show you any of this at this stage but what
I will do after this slide the next are gonna be visually based.
So want to keep things visual as much as possible in this course but just need to go over a few facts
with you before I get to that.
So these are some of the components of the AWS global infrastructure.
The most important ones you need to know at this stage.
So there's a region and a region is a geographical area with at least two Availability Zones in it and
each region is isolated from other AWS regions.
And there's about 23 of them around the world at the moment.
And that changes all the time.
So by the time you watch this you may find that there's you know 24 or 25 or more so don't quote me
on the exact number.
Have a look for yourself.
I'll provide some links as well in the course download so you'll be out to go and have a look.
We then have Availability Zones.
So as I mentioned a region will have at least two Availability Zones within it.
Sometimes they have five or more an availability zone actually is comprised of one or more data centers
and these are physically separated from other Availability Zones.
So you can consider each availability zone as being isolated from other Availability Zones.
That being said they're connected with low latency highly available high bandwidth links.
So what you can do with Availability Zones is deploy your resources within a region but into separate
Availability Zones for high availability and redundancy.
And that means if there's an outage or one availability zone your resources in the other one aren't
affected and you've got networking connectivity between all of the AZs as well.
We then have edge locations and regional edge caches.
Now these are both part of the cloud front network cloud front is all about caching content and it caches
content around the world and a lot of locations and those kind of locations are closer to your users.
So the idea is to reduce latency when accessing cached content.
There are two concepts here, the edge location and the regional edge cache with the edge location
there is about 176 of those at the moment around the world.
And with the regional edge caches there's about 11 and they're just a bit bigger they have a bigger
cache bandwidth and they're set between the services that you have in a AWS and the edge locations
themselves.
So you don't need to know any more about those at this stage you really just need to understand what
are the constructs of the global infrastructure.
So this is what makes up  AWS, of course there's a global network.
And this is a private global network which AWS manage its highly available, its low latency, and..
it interconnects every datacenter availability zone and a AWS region.
Let's have a look at a slide now with a bit more information about regions in this slide you can see
three regions one's in U.S. East one, one's in EU West one and the other is an AP Southeast-2.
These are actually Norfolk Virginia, Dublin in Ireland and Sydney in Australia.
In this diagram each region has three availability zones.
In reality they might have more or less but they'll have at least two and they might have five or more.
Each region is completely independent however they're all connected by this global network which is
a private global network managed by AWS which has high bandwidth low latency and is fully redundant.
Regions enable you to deploy your resources in whatever location is closest to you.
So for instance for me I'm in Australia so it makes most sense for me if my customers are also in Australia
to use this region.
However if I have a business that runs straight out of North America I might just choose to use U.S.
East one and deploy my resources here.
This slide shows the current state of regions around the world.
The red ones are new ones which will be coming online soon and the remainder of all existing regions
on this slide we have regional edge caches and edge locations.
As I mentioned these are all over the world and there are currently 176 of them.
Your users therefore can be around the world and the location should be close to your users.
And that means a shorter network distance and therefore lower licensee for your applications and you
might use this for storing media or web files.
And in this case for instance we have Amazon EC2.
Perhaps this is a web server running on the elastic compute cloud up Amazon S3 which is object storage
so you could have media files for instance on here and the locations enable you to cache those objects
closer to your users the regional edge caches set between the locations and these origins.
Now you don't need to know any more than that at this stage we'll go through a lab later in this course
and I'll show you in detail how cloud front works.
This diagram just shows you the edge locations around the world today with all the blue are existing
locations where it's purple.
It means that there's multiple locations in that region and then these big circles with the orange Rim
Regional edge caches.
That's it for this lesson guys.
I just wanted to take you through with a high level what the AWS global infrastructure is in the next
lab.
We're going to discuss virtual private cloud.