Welcome back.
Encryption is a big topic for the exam, and there's a few different types of encryption with Amazon,
it's free that you need to be aware of.
Now, specifically here we're talking about encryption of data at rest.
That means that data that's actually stored not in transit, which is when the actual data is traversing
a network for encryption in transit.
We do use HDTV as the secure version of HDTV with Amazon as free, so your data is encrypted in transit
using an SSL TLS certificate.
For encryption at rest as a few different options.
Firstly, we have something called server side encryption with free managed keys.
It's abbreviated as SSD Dash as free.
Now with this, you have as free managed keys, so the keys are managed by the Amazon S3 service.
You get unique object keys and a master key all managed for you, and it uses the advanced encryption
standard as 256 bit encryption keys.
The encryption and the decryption will actually take place in Amazon as free.
So as your data is written to a bucket, it gets encrypted and as it's read from a bucket, it becomes
decrypted.
Now, that doesn't mean it's traversing the network and clear attacks, because remember, we are using
certificates, so you do have an encrypted tunnel for that data as it passes over the network.
But the actual data itself, once it reaches its destination, is still in clear text.
So if we have a client and the client puts an object into us free, it's going to encrypt it.
And then when they remove that object from us free, it's going to decrypt it.
Now the next option is called server side encryption, with eight of US Cames managed keys, and that's
abbreviated as SASE CMS.
Now, in this case, the keys are managed by the Kojima's service.
That's the IWC Key Management Service.
We have comms generated customer master keys, or you can have a CE mark that's generated by the customer.
The encryption and decryption again happens on the bucket, so the client is writing data to as free
as free as encrypting that data.
And when they read it back again, it's decrypt again.
The next option is called server side encryption with client provided keys.
Dash C.
In this case, the keys are managed by the client and not stored on a WC.
But still, the encryption and decryption is taking place on IWC.
It just gives you more control over the encryption keys.
Now, the last option is not a server side encryption option.
This is the only one that's a client side encryption option, so that means you have client managed
keys, so you as a customer have to manage the keys, the creation of them, the rotation, etcetera.
They're not stored on IWC, but you can actually use a KMC in case you can export that.
And then you can use that now.
The encryption in this case is happening on the client side.
So IWC doesn't really know anything about it.
You encrypt your data, you write, it's as free.
The data is encrypted on as free.
You read it back again and then you decrypt it on the client side.
There's no way of decrypting this data on IWC because the keys are actually in your data center on your
systems.
We can configure default encryption on our S3 buckets.
When we do this, we can configure the encryption behavior so we can choose which type of encryption
we want to use.
And then all objects that get written to the bucket will become encrypted using whatever you specify.
Now, note that this mentions new objects.
Existing objects will not be encrypted, so you enable default encryption, but if you have existing
objects in that bucket, they're not going to become encrypted.
But new objects that you up later after you've enabled encryption will be encrypted.
In this case with default encryption, we are talking about using one of these server side encryption
options.
And as I mentioned, that means the S3 is going to encrypt objects as you write them to disk and then
decrypt them when you pull them off of, it's free and there's no change to the encryption status of
objects that already existed in the bucket before you enable default encryption.
Now you can also prevent uploads of unencrypted objects as well.
So you can create a policy like this, and this one will enforce encryption using SASE as free.
We can see that what's happening here is we have a deny for any principle and the action as free puts
objects, so uploading a file to S3.
We would then choose our packet specifying our bucket name and a slash star.
So this applies to objects that we want to put in the bucket.
And the condition is if the string does not equal as free x AMS ad server side encryption with a value
of a two five six.
If you wanted to use SASE CMS, you would instead have a CMS instead of a 256.
So this top portion of the code here is all about defining the encryption headers you want to see.
Whether you want your data to be encrypted using SASE as free or SASE came, for example.
Now, then we deny the actual upload.
So here we have the same with S3 put objects.
We have our resource again, and this time it's condition of null x aims at server side encryption.
True.
So that means if we're not adding encryption to our object when we upload it, then it's not going to
allow it to take place.
And it puts might look like this.
So this is the example of a put request, and we can see the server side encryption had a header as
two five six.
So this object will be encrypted and therefore it will be allowed.
And that's it for this lesson.
We'll do a hands on in the next lesson actually put this into action using a policy to prevent uploads
of unencrypted objects.