AWS Step Functions makes it easy to coordinate the components of distributed applications as a series
of steps.
And it does so in a visual workflow so you can define your code and then you can see for a visual workflow
what the execution of that code looks like what we're going to do in this lab is just run a very simple
Hello World application using the Get Started button.
So if you're on the splash screen of AWS Step Functions you'll see this button here get started let's
just click on that and you can now see the code and the code is written in Amazon states language and
as you can see on the left hand side here you have the code and then on the right you have the graph
which shows you a visual workflow.
We're not gonna change any of this code.
We're just going to click next and I am role can then be specified or in this case we're just going
to leave
Step Functions to create one for us and we can choose create state machine.
Once it's created it then offers to run a new execution and in that execution we have some code and
I'm just gonna copy that's on my clipboard so we can rerun this as well.
And this just says is hello world example code on true.
So the code is looking for this value.
So let's click.
Start execution and you can now see the visual workflow here and it's got to a point where it's waiting
for three seconds and then it's going to continue and complete very quickly.
So that's what it looks like.
So you can actually see your applications executing.
You get the input here and you get whatever output here.
You can then just go and rerun that execution.
We can do the same as you already got the code in there so you can start execution and just see that
run through again.
Now if you scroll down you can also get a history of your execution events back at the top here.
You can then go to activities and create an activity.
And this enables you to have tasks in the state machine where the work is performed by EC2,
mobile devices, and pretty much from anywhere.
As I mentioned at the beginning of the section, AWS are recommending that you use Step Functions instead
of simple workflow service for new applications.
So unless you have a specific requirement for SWF, Step Functions is likely to be the answer in any
question that asks for coordinated workflows.
Also look out on the exam for mention of a visual workflow.
Now if you have human interaction with your orchestration or your workflow you then might have to go
to SWF and we're going to talk about that in the next lab.