Welcome back, we're now going to Elastic Skylight application by adding some stress to the CPU's on
our instances and using a dynamic scaling policy to actually respond to that and add more instances
for us.
So let's go back to the console back in the console here.
The first thing I'm going to do.
We still have our EC2 instances running.
I'm going to go to monitoring with one of them selected and I'm going to enable detailed monitoring
now.
This can come with a small cost, so you don't have to do this, but it makes things a bit faster.
I'm going to get some monitoring again for the second instance and enable detailed monitoring, and
that means the metrics will be sent to Cloud Watch every one minute rather than five.
Next, I'm going to come down to my auto scaling group and we're going to create a target tracking scaling
policy.
So select HD One, go to automatic scaling, choose dynamic scaling policy.
It's going to select target tracking by default, average CPU utilization.
And we can put it as, let's say, 60 percent and just create that scaling policy.
So that's going to create an alarm for us.
And when that alarm gets triggered, EC2 auto scaling will launch more instances as are needed.
So now we need to generate some load on our CPU's because at the moment they're going to be sitting
idle, not really doing anything.
So back in instances, I'm going to select each of my instances and connect.
So we're going to use instance connect.
That's one of them.
Let's come back.
Let's choose the other instance do the same thing.
And now I'm connected to both of my instances.
In your course download.
You'll find in the auto scaling and LP directory this install stress utility to what we need to do is
copy each of these commands.
So I'm going to copy this command and we're going to install the stress utility.
I'm going to pay that into my Linux terminal.
Hit enter in my other than it's terminal, I'm going to hit enter with the same command, so I've now
installed it on behalf of my ISA two instances.
And this is the actual stress utility.
So these are just the Linux extras for the Amazon Linux to Amy.
Now we're actually going to install the stress utility.
So back on the command line here.
Let's enter that and.
That should be installed do the same on our other two instance, and we have that installed now, I'm
just going to clear the screen here, bring this down and I'm going to type the command stress space
that see six.
And that should add quite a bit of load to my CPU.
Let's do the same thing now for our other instance.
So again, I'll clear the screen type stress test the six and hit enter.
So let's go back and monitor what's happening back in the ACG management console.
If we select our instances and go to monitoring soon, we should start seeing some information, so
we should start seeing the CPU going up.
Now, another thing we can do is go to Cloud Watch.
Let's open this up in another tab and in Cloud Watch, we can see we have an alarm.
So if I go to all alarms, we can see we have this target tracking alarm that's being created here.
So that's watching for those metrics that are coming in and it's not in an alarm state at this stage.
So what's going to happen soon is hopefully it will go into an alarm state.
Now another thing we can do is go to metrics we can choose to, per instance, metrics, and then we
can see the metrics coming in.
So, for example, we can come back, take the instance I.D. of one of my instances.
Let's plug that in here.
Hit enter to filter the display.
Come down to CPU utilization.
And so very soon we should start seeing some data coming back and we're going to see the load on the
CPU.
If you want to, you can also add your other instance.
So let's take the instance side of this instance and then come back and it's filter by this instance.
Remove that one and find the CPU utilization.
And now we're going to graph both of these CPUs.
Another place you can watch, what's happening is under auto scaling groups.
We choose our auto scanning group and go to activity.
Once our alarm has been breached, we should then see auto scaling respond that we'll see some activity
in here by changing my periods one minute here.
I can now see the spike happening.
You can see the CPU is going right up to about 100 percent and we can see that we no longer have that
healthy alarm.
It's actually been triggered.
So if I choose alarm, we can see that it's an an alarm state.
So let's go back to auto scaling, and let's refresh this page and we can see that we've actually got
some activity happening.
So we've got some instances being launched in response to that alarm.
And it's going to take it up to the maximum allowed instances which we defined as full.
So coming back to instances, we should now see that we have four instances running now.
We'll give these a couple of minutes and then once they're in service, what we should see is we're
able to then use our load balancer DNS name and we're going to load balance between them because they're
actually assigned automatically to the load balance of through the target group.
Remember, we have the auto scaling group.
We attached the target group to the auto scaling group and the load balancer has the target group associated
with it.
That means when auto scaling launches an instance, it automatically gets registered as a target in
the target group, and the load balancer can start distributing connections to it.
So let's just give this a few minutes.
It looks like our instances are running now.
So let's go to load balancers, copy the DNS name and open a new browser tab.
I'll paste the DNS name in, and let's start refreshing our browser and you can see we're moving between
instances in free, different availability zones.
Now we only added free.
So there'll be two instances in one A-Z.
But as you can see, we're quite evenly distributing between them.
So that's how elastic scaling works with its target tracking scaling policy.
For now, we're not going to need to use our target tracking scaling policy anymore.
So I'm going to come back to auto scaling groups, go into my ASG automatic scaling.
And with the target tracking policy selected, I'm going to delete it now that we've removed the scaling
policy.
I'm just going to show you back on the details there.
Do you remember where we set the design capacity to two, where you can see it changed?
And that's because the target tracking scaling policy updated the design capacity.
And if you look through the activity here, you'll see you actually mention that it updated the design
capacity from two to four.
Let's click on Edit, and I'm going to put it back down to two again, and let's click on Update.
So that should terminate a couple of instances.
And that's it for this lesson.
Leave everything running.
We will be coming back to it again and another hands on.