Welcome back to another hands on lesson.
So this time we're going to have a look at working with Elastic Network interfaces.
So let's head over to the console on the easy to management console.
I'm going to launch an instance again.
It's going to be the Linux two army to micro.
I'm going to put this one in public, one A and then I'm going to click on next.
Go free.
We don't need to change any other settings.
Just choose our web access security group and we're going to launch this instance.
So the instance is launching now while that's happening.
We're going to scroll down here to network interfaces and we can see we have an existing network interface.
Let's just pull this box up from the bottom here and we can see a bit more information.
You can see the interface I.D. We can say it's in use what VPC and Sublette it's in, and we can see
the address information here as well.
And you can say it's not an elastic fabric adaptor.
We know what availability zone it's in.
This is quite a bit of information here.
You can also see the Mac address, so that's the layer to address associated with this particular in.I.
What I want to do is create a new network interface.
I'm going to call this F1 because it's essentially the second interface, for instance, and I need
to put it in the same subnet because I want to attach it to the instance we've just launched.
Now remember, you can attach an interface in a different subnet as long as the sublets in the same.
So we're going to choose public one.
We're going to leave the default settings for IP addresses and choose Web Access Security Group and
then create the network interface.
So that's done.
Let's select this interface.
We can say it's available, it's not in use, and we can see some information.
We can see that it has a V6 address, a V4 address and DNS names as well.
So now let's go up to actions.
Choose Attach.
And that's it's hatchets, for instance, there's only one instance available so we can see the ID and
attach.
So that is now attached to an instance so we can see it's in use if we go up two instances choose our
running instance go to networking and we can now see that we have multiple interfaces, select our running
instance, go to networking and we can see it now has multiple network interfaces.
So that's how we can work with Illinois.
So we could quite easily now detach that yanai and move it to a different instance.
Now we only have one instance now, but if you want to play around, launch enough.
For instance, you can detach this interface and then just attach it to another instance as long as
that instance is in the same availability zone.
Now, alternatively, create another subnet in the same availability zone and practice moving between
different subnets as well.
So you can attach your instance to multiple subnet.
So those are options available to you.
Now I'm going to leave the lab here, and we're going to leave this instance running because we will
be using it in a future lab.