Hi guys.
Welcome back.
We're now going to continue with a discussion on plastic IP addresses.
I've launched two instances into my VPC.
Now all I've done is put them both in the same subnet so that both in the same availability zone here
and I just used an Amazon and it's to a mine and to micro instances that's where you or you need to
do so.
Both of these are in a public subnet and therefore they have a public IP address.
Now as you know these are just the dynamic public IP addresses that instances pick up when their subnet
is configured to provide them with one.
What we want to do now is actually create an elastic IP address and associate that with an instance.
So you come down to elastic IP here under network and security and choose allocate new address and the
scope is VPC.
And that really is it.
There's nothing else to do you just choose allocate and as you can see we now have a public IP address
and this is gonna be a static address.
So if we close we can come back here we can see we have this allocated to our account and it's not going
anywhere.
It's not even associated with an instance or a network adapter.
So what I want to do now is actually associate it with my instance.
So I choose actions associate address and under here you can choose two different types of resource
either an easy to instance or a network interface.
So that's an elastic network interface and we'll see how to create one of those shortly.
I'm going to choose instance I'm going to choose instance one and then I have to associate it with the
private IP address.
So that means it's going to disassociate the existing public address so it warns you here by saying
if you so associate an elastic IP with you instance your current public address is released.
So the dynamic addresses released and the new elastic or static address is assigned so I'm going gonna
choose associate before I do that I'm just going to choose learn more I just want to bring this article
to your attention.
If you scroll down a little way you can see some information about the behavior of public Hopis.
It says here that a W.S. will release your instance his public address when the instance is stopped
or terminated.
We know that from the previous lab it also says we release your instances public address when you associate
an elastic IP address.
So that's what we're doing now.
And then if you disassociate the elastic address the instance will pick up a public IP.
However if your instance has more than one network interface it won't pick up a new dynamic public IP
address.
And also if your instance has a secondary private IP address with an elastic IP associated with it it
also won't pick up a new dynamic public address.
So those are just a few things to understand.
Let's close that and choose associate.
So we now have our address associated.
Let's go back to instances choose instance one and we can see now here under elastic eyepiece we have
an address and that address now shows as the primary IP V for public address.
We still have only one if an interface if zero and if we choose that we can see that we have the public
address and the public private IP address.
So very simple.
And now if we stopped our instance and started it again it would retain that IP address the other way
you can associate an elastic IP is using an elastic network interface.
So let's first go to elastic IP addresses and allocate another one to our account so we have the second
address here.
Let's go to network interfaces and what you can see here of the elastic network interfaces associated
with your existing easy two instances.
So these are the if zero interface on those instances I'm gonna create a new one I'm just gonna call
it my E and I I'm going to choose my AP SD to a availability zones so that I'm in the same subnet and
then you can choose custom or auto assigned IP before I'm going to leave it on it's on auto assign and
then we're just going to choose a security group.
Now just a note the elastic fabric adapter here if you choose the information icon it tells you that
this is a device used for reducing latency and increasing Freeport for hate UPC high performance computing
and machine learning applications.
So those are for specific use cases.
We don't need those now let's just choose create.
And what I'm going to do to make sure this is clear in the console I'm going to put the name here as
well so my E and I and just.
Okay.
And now if we come back to Alaska co-pays I'm going to go to actions associated dress choose network
interface I could find my IP address I know I could find my network interface and then I can associate
with a private IP address and click associate.
So we now have an elastic network adapter and it has a public IP and its status is available so it's
not in use.
What we need to do is sign it to an instance.
So we do that by clicking attach and we choose our instance one and attach if we now had back to instances
under instance one we can see we have two elastic IP addresses and two network interfaces so you can
see the new elastic IP is associated with each one.
Now remember one of the key benefits of elastic IP addresses is they can be read it and it's the same
for elastic network interfaces.
So you can't move if 0 to another instance and you can't move a public IP to another instance but you
can move your elastic eyepiece and your additional elastic network interfaces so if I go down to network
interfaces I can choose to detach my interface she's forced to make short works and now that it's detached
I can attach it and choose instance to.
Now remember in the real world you might want to do this programmatically and that means that you can
then file over your address to another instance maybe that's something that you programmatically use
for failure scenarios or you might move an elastic network interface because of re platforming or something
like that.
So let's go back to instances and if we choose instance to we can now say that it has each one with
the same public IP address.
So I've just moved that interface onto a different instance.
Now if you can imagine that you have a public DNS name that's resolving to the IP on that network instant
interface it would now be directed to instance to rather than instance one and you can easily remap
it to a third instance if instance two failed.
So that's just a little bit about classical piece.
What I'm gonna do now is terminate my instances and remember this is really important now that you need
to release your elastic eyepiece because you do get charged for elastic IP addresses when they're not
in use.
Now you have to wait until you instance is shut down because as long as they're associated with an adapter
that is in use you won't be able to release them.
But that should just take a few seconds and then we'll go into a elastic eyepiece and release our addresses.
So both of my instances are terminated.
Let's go to a plastic eyepiece and I'm going to choose to release this address and I can see that this
other one is associated with a network interface that's my elastic network interface so I need to disassociate
it first and then I can release the address and now you won't get charged and we can go in and delete
your elastic network interface as well.
So that's it for this lab guys in the next lab.
We're going to cover private subnets and Bastion hosts.