Hi guys.
In this lesson we're going to discuss virtual private cloud VPC.
And I'm going to take you for a bit of theory.
And then we're going to go into the console and see what it all looks like a virtual private cloud or
VPC is a logically isolated section of the AWS cloud where you can launch your own resources within
a VPC.
You can create your own networks using your own IP ranges.
Now a VPC sits within a region so you can see here we have a region so this could be one of the 20 free
locations around the world.
There are 20 free today and you can create a VPC within that region and then you create subnets within
that region which set within Availability Zones and those can be public or private.
You then launch your resources into your subnets that are within your VPC with other resources that
don't sit in subnets You can also choose to put them in a VPC we'll see more about that throughout the
course.
But what you need to understand at this stage is that you have a region within a region you have a VPC
and you can have up to five VPCs within each region by default like with many AWS services.
There is a default quota limit but you can increase that if you need to by contacting AWS.
You normally need to fill out a form and submit for a request for approval.
So we have our VPC within our region.
You can have multiple beeps within that region.
So for each region around the world you'll need to have separate pieces.
There is a default VPC that's created by default and that's in every of those every one of those regions
around the world.
So you then have the availability zones which as we know from the previous lesson are one or more data
centers within a region and within there you create your subnets and deploy you instances.
Now the way that you can communicate between Availability Zones and within between subnets whether they're
in the same availability zone or not is free the VPC router the VPC router has a route table which you
can configure and it actually has a IP address range.
So every VPC has what's called a cyber block which stands for classless inter domain routing and you
can look that up on Google if you're not familiar of what it is you do need to understand it for your
exam.
And so you define the IP range for your VPC and then the round table will automatically be configured
to route between all your Availability Zones and subnets within your VPC.
You can also have an Internet gateway attached to your VPC and that allows you to access the outside
world.
So for instance you can send requests out to an Internet Web site through the Internet gateway and for
that you need to specify the Internet gateway I.D. and an IP address as a destination in this case.
This is essentially a wild card which means any destination send it to the Internet gateway.
You then have Internet gateways and these allow you to be able to communicate outside of AWS to the
Internet and to enable you to do that you have to create an Internet gateway and then you have to add
an entry to your round table which says for this destination ip address range in this case it means
any address send the connection to the Internet gateway and then it reference it out to the outside
world.
On this diagram I just wanted to show you an example of a region with multiple VPCs. As you can see
each has an IP address block and all the subnets within this VPC will be part of this block and each
VPC will have a different block.
So that's it for the theory.
Let's go into the console and start looking at what VPC is look like in the AWS management console.
I'm here in the AWS management console and we can find VPC by going up to services and then choosing
networking and content delivery and his VPC.
This is the VPC dashboard and it gives us a bit of information about the pieces around the world.
So in this case you can have a look at the VPCs that we have.
And so my account actually has a VPC in all of these regions and that's not because I created one that's
just because as part of this free tier account or as part of any account you will have one VPC a default
VPC in each region around the world.
You can then see subnets.
And in this case in Sydney we have three.  There's three availability zones in Sydney and there's one subnet
mapped to each of those availability zones.
By default. You can see it varies but there's no less than two.
We then have route tables and every VPC we'll have a route table so there's gonna be one for each of
these VPCs and we'll have a look at what they look like in shortly for internet gateways.
Again each VPC has an internet gateway.
You can only attach one to a VPC and there's one for each region.
One of the things you need to understand in the AWS management console is when you go up to the right
hand corner here so you can see I'm up here in Sydney.
So that's the region that I'm connected to if you see the name of a region here.
It means that the service that you're working with is a regional service.
Sometimes you won't see that you'll see global here and there's no dropdown list so you can't select
a different region at the moment.
I can change regions for instance to us west north California and my console just connects there and
I can start configuring my VPC in Northern California.
But if it says global that means it's a global service and you don't have a regional scope where you
can configure things separately for different regions.
So right now I'm connected to Sydney.
Let's go to my VPCs and we can see here we have a default VPC.
It doesn't have a name.
It's just got an I.D. you can see the site a block here and there's a bit more information you can see
the round table.
The network ACL we can see that this is a default VPC as it says yes here.
And it has a default tenancy.
Now we'll go through a lot of these settings and more detail when we get to the VPC deep dive section
of the course.
For now what I'm trying to do is just familiarize you with VPC enough that we can carry on and start
actually building some resources in the next section where we're going to deploy some easy two instances
into the VPC.
So I'm trying to build on your knowledge throughout this course rather than just deep diving on one
thing and then moving on to the next.
That way you'll be able to repeatedly learn the same facts over and over again and actually use them
in practical contexts which will hopefully help you to really learn.
If we go down to subnets you can see those three subnets here and each of these will be matched to a
different availability zone.
So for instance the first one I've highlighted here is maps of availability zone AP-southeast-2c if
I select the next one on the list.
It's connected to AP-southeast-2b  and the next one will be on 2a. One of the key things to note
here is it says auto assign public IP v full and it's set to Yes.
Now if we want are easy two instances which is are elastic compute cloud instances so you might deploy
a Linux or Windows operating system onto a W.S. those operating systems will then pick up an IP V for
address.
If you have auto assign set to a yes you can also see for each of these subnets what the IP V for side
a block is.
So for this one it's 1 7 2 2 31 or 32 dot 0 slash 20.
And then if we go to this next one here it's 1 7 2 231 dot 0 0 slash 20.
So each subnet will have a different block of addresses but they're all within the overall side a block
of the BPC we now go to round tables and we can see we have one round table by default there's a route
that allows full routing between all subnets within the overall side of block for the VPC and then there's
one here which has a destination which basically means any IP address so any address that isn't within
this range.
Send it to the Internet gateway whereas anything that's within this range it gets routed locally.
So we then have the Internet gateway and this is what we just looked at.
It's specified in the route table so that we know how to route to the Internet gateway to get to the
outside world.
So that's it for this lesson guys.
This is really just a sort of getting started really just wanted to show you through VPC so that you understand
it and we're gonna be moving on in the next section to actually learning about the elastic compute cloud
easy to and deploying some easy two instances into a VPC before we do that.
There's an optional lab coming up where I'm actually going to register a DNS domain name using the AWS
Route 53 service.
It does cost a bit of money so you don't have to do it but if you want to it's useful for some of the
exercises in the rest of the course.
So if you want to go to that lab see you there.
Otherwise you can move to the next section and we'll get started on easy to.