So we're at the end of the I Am section of the course, and I just want to go over the best practices
for using the IAM service now really important to know these again, this is something that comes up
in the exam.
So it's a bit of a bullet point list, but it's really important to understand these.
So the first thing is that you should lock away your IWC account user access keys.
So you remember I talked about the user account and how it has so many permissions and you can't restrict
them now.
Access keys are those keys that you could use for programmatic access.
You should even delete them from that user account or just make sure that they're very well secured.
Great individual.
I am users.
So that's what we've done in this section.
We created our own user account and now we're logging in as that user account rather than roots use
groups to assign permissions to IAM users.
Now you can assign policies directly to users, but remember we looked at how you can do it free groups.
So you assign the permissions to the group once and then everyone who gets put in that group gets those
permissions.
Much better way of doing it always grant least privilege.
So don't give people more access rights than they need to do their job.
Get started using permissions with managed policies.
Now, when we were adding a policy to our group earlier on, they were the IWC managed policies, their
predefined for you.
Now, if you don't have a lot of experience with writing policies, you can make mistakes.
So that's why there's a best practice to get started by using the managed policies.
Once you really understand them and you've got more expertise, then create your own use customer managed
policies instead of inline policies.
This is again talking about not assigning the policies directly to a user that's known as an inline
policy.
Instead, create your own custom policies and use those use access levels to review and permissions.
What this means is that you should regularly audit the permissions that are assigned to all of your
users and other principles in your account.
Just make sure that they only have the permissions they need that least privilege.
Configure a strong password policy for your users.
You can enforce a password policy within IAM, and that enables you to make sure that users have complex
passwords that are difficult to guess.
Enable MFA.
We did that in this section.
Multifactor authentication is a great way to add additional security to your account, use roles for
applications that run on two instances.
Now we're going to look at this in the next section.
It's a way of assigning the ability for an easy to instance to assume a role.
Rather than having access keys hardcoded into the code, they can be a security risk.
Now, don't worry if that doesn't make sense, because I'm going to show you in the next section use
rules to delegate permissions.
Great way to delegate permissions.
Again, we'll see that in action soon and do not share access keys.
It's really important not to share them.
These give people access to perform whatever permissions are assigned to your user.
Accounts rotate credentials regularly, so this means make sure you change your passwords, you renew
your access keys.
So if they do get compromised, then at least two are mitigating the amount of time that they can be
used.
Remove unnecessary credentials, so only have the ones you need.
Use policy conditions for extra security.
Now you've already seen a few policy documents and you've got some JSON code in there.
Now you can assign something called a condition that might say that the policy applies only to users
coming from a certain computer IP address, for example.
So that's a condition, and that's an extra level of security.
You should also monitor activity in your accounts, always monitor and try and know what is going on
so that if there's any suspicious activity, you can identify it and then act upon it.
So those are the eight of us Iam best practices.