Welcome to another hands on in this lesson, we're going to create a VPC endpoint.
It's going to be a gateway endpoint and we're going to use of policies to see how we can control access
to an Amazon has free buckets.
So this is basically the configuration we already have a VPC and a public subnet, and we've got an
instance running in it from earlier on.
Now we're going to create an Amazon S3 bucket.
I'm getting ahead of myself a little bit here because we actually cover S3 and a lot of detail in the
next section.
If you're completely unfamiliar with it and you want to get a primer, you could flick forward, but
we won't be doing too much here is going to be fairly straightforward stuff.
Now, when we create our endpoint, a route will be added to our roundtable and that will point to a
destination which will result to the IP addresses of Amazon S3.
Now what happens is this is a more specific route than any other route, like the route going out to
the internet.
So it should follow this path, which means any connections that go to the IWC as free endpoints should
be routed via the gateway endpoint.
And we'll be out to prove that that's happening and that we're not using the public internet, so we
will modify the policy here to do that.
You'll see what I mean shortly.
And on the S3 bucket, we'll add a policy now.
Bucket policies are basically just resource based policies.
It uses JSON language just like we do with IAM policies, but we just use them to control access to
our buckets, so we apply them directly to the buckets rather than to a principle like an identity based
policy.
The first thing to do is to head over and create the VPC endpoint.
I'm in my management account in Norfolk, Virginia, on the left and the endpoints.
We can create an endpoint.
Let's click this button right endpoint and under services.
If we put in S3 and search, we get these options.
We're going to choose Gateway for Amazon as free.
Now we need to specify which route table to actually update.
Now, as you can see the round table full of APC, the custom one is not there.
That's because we need to make sure we specify our custom VPC.
Now we can see our route tables and I'm going to choose the one that's the main round table.
So that's the one associated with my public subnets.
Now the policy by default, is full access.
So we have a statement here.
That's action.
Any action star effects allow.
And then any resource and any principle.
So it's very open, but you can customize that.
So let's just create the endpoints and it's being created for us.
So here is our endpoint.
Now what we want to do is go to tables and just make sure that the round table has been updated.
So that's this one here.
The main round table for our custom BPC undercounts, we can now see that we have the destination.
And this is going via a VPC endpoint.
So that's the routes to Amazon as free going via the endpoint.
So that set up correctly.
Another thing we need to do, we're going to run some commands against Amazon that's free from our EC2
instance.
So I need to give it some privileges.
I'm going to create a role.
So let's choose create role here in the IAM service.
Common use cases is going to be easy, too, so we're going to allow easy to to call in service for
permissions.
Just type in as free and search.
And we're going to give full access.
I'm going to copy the name of this policy and we're going to use that for the wrong name as well.
So let's just paste on in create the role.
And now we have a role that we can assign to our easy to instance.
So over an easy to choose our instance, go to actions, security, modify.
I am role.
I'm going to choose a role and we should see it in here.
And there it is.
Amazon has free, full access, so let's save another instance now has the privileges it needs over
in the Amazon as free console, which you can find the services and storage.
We're going to create an S3 bucket, so a bucket is just a container into which we add objects, objects
of files and videos or whatever you want to add.
I'm going to call mine a VPC test and it's going to be in North Virginia.
I can scroll down.
Don't need to change anything else at this point.
And create this bucket.
So now that we have a bucket, we can add some objects, objects, as I say, just files, this is an
object based storage system so we can come in and add files.
I'm just going to add a couple of JPEG images and upload.
So simple as that, we have some files on Amazon S3.
Now let's come back to easy to choose a public one instance.
Go to instance, connect and connect.
Now, we haven't specified any policies yet, but let's just check that we can connect to Amazon S3.
So now we should be able to run commands against us.
Free.
Let's try running IWC S3 Ellis.
And hit enter.
And we can see our buckets.
We should be able to run IWC as free.
Ellis and then free colon slash slash and our bucket name as well.
And if we hit Enza here, we should see the contents of the bucket.
So at the moment, everything is working great now.
How do we know this is going over the endpoint rather than going over the internet because we are in
a public subnet?
Well, let's go back to your endpoint.
With my endpoint selected, I'm going to choose policy.
I'm going to copy this code here in the endpoint policy.
Choose custom pasted in, and let's just change the policy to deny.
So this should deny everything.
Now, if we're going by the internet, this shouldn't make any difference.
But if we're going via the endpoint, then this should block access.
So back in our instance, let's try and rerun that command and we get an access denied.
Let's try and run the olass command again.
We get an access denied.
So it's definitely not working back in my endpoint.
I'm just going to change this back again because I don't really want that to deny me from access at
this point.
So let's just go back to full access, click on Save.
The next thing we're going to do is set up our bucket policy and the bucket policy is going to prevent
any access except from the VPC endpoint.
And that's something that comes up in a lot of exam scenarios.
So let's go into our bucket here.
Go to permissions, come down to bucket policy.
Click Edit and I'm going to copy the bucket Iran.
Now this is the bucket policy, so it's in your code.
Amazon VPC Directory Bucket Policy BPC What you need to do is take this whole in here and just paste
your correct air and over the top for your bucket.
And there's two options here.
One is without the slash style and one is with.
So the one with the slash star means that you can also look at the objects within the bucket.
Now, the last thing we need here is the VPC I.D. So back at my end point here, I'm going to copy the
Endpoint ID and then come back and paste that into my policy.
So that's it.
This policy should now apply now, what does it do?
Let's have a look.
The policy is that the nine, so it's going to deny any principal, any free action on these resources,
specifically if the condition does not equal this VPC endpoint.
So in other words, if you're not coming from this VPC endpoint ID, you're going to get denied.
If you are coming from this VPC Endpoint ID, it doesn't apply.
So let's copy all of this code to our clipboards and back in the bucket policy editor here.
I'm going to paste it all in and just save these changes.
So let's go back and make sure we haven't broken access back in our instance.
Let's try to run the IWC free LS command and we sell buckets.
Let's check that we can see inside a bucket and that works correctly.
Now that's good because this instance is coming from the VPC endpoint.
So again, we've proven we're coming via the endpoint.
But the other thing we can do is check from our own computers and we shouldn't be allowed access.
So back in the terminal here, I'm going to run IWC S3 Ellis and I do see the buckets.
But what about if I try to see inside the bucket?
So the full command is IWC, S3, LS, S3, colon, slash slash and then your bucket name and hit enter.
So I've got an access is denied, so that proves that I'm not able to access the bucket from my computer
because I'm not coming via the endpoint.
Now let's just go back to the console and have a look at the bucket in the bucket.
Here you can see that we no longer have permissions to this bucket.
We've actually locked ourselves out because I'm actually coming through the console here and the console
doesn't come by the endpoint.
So what we need to do is go back to our EC2 instance and we're going to run the command IWC s free arm
and then put in the name of the bucket.
So the full command is S3, r m S3 code on slash slash and then your bucket name.
And let's see if that removes our bucket.
So that's remove the bucket, so it doesn't matter that we're locked out.
Another way you can get access to buckets when you've put in a policy and you can't actually get back
into it again is to log in his route.
That's always the way out.
Now that is it.
For this lesson, we have finished with the ISA to instance and the VPC endpoint, where the end point,
you can simply select the endpoint, go to actions and then delete endpoint.
And it should clean up the entry in your root table as well.
But you can always just go and check.
You might need to refresh the page and then it has gone.
So once you've done that, terminate your instance and we finish for this lesson.