Hi, guys, I'm in the NWS management console and I'm going to head to services, go down to management
and governance and choose config.
Now, if you haven't run config before, you may not see this screen, you might actually be put into
a wizard which asks you a few questions.
So firstly, it's going to ask you which resources you want to enable config to be able to discover
inventory information from.
So I just chose to enable all resources within the region.
And you can see what resources I have available here.
It's then going to ask you to choose a bucket and the S3 bucket is where the data, each configuration
item is actually going to get stored.
Thirdly, it's going to ask you to specify a role.
So this is an Iame role that's used for the service and it will create one by default for you or you
can specify a role.
It may then also put you into a wizard to create your first rules.
So what will happen then is if you can just continue to add the rule and follow my instructions or you
can exit out of that wizard and then just go to rules on the left hand side here and choose and rule.
And what we have is a series of AWB management rules excuse me, AWB managed rules.
So these are predefined rules that already exist.
So they cover quite a few scenarios, but you'll likely want to create your own custom rules for what
we're going to do now is just look for some rules.
So firstly and type two and then choose this rule here.
And what this does is this checks we have a detailed monitoring in the neighborhood for two instances
and I've actually launched an active instance here and this one is using basic monitoring because that's
the default.
So that means it will send information to cloud watch every five minutes, whereas detail means every
one minutes.
So this rule will just check to see if my two instances are actually compliant with this rule that states
that they should have detailed monitoring enabled so of would just choose, save and then going to go
back into add rules.
And I'm just going to type security and we should have some rules coming up that are related to security
groups.
So this one here is the one I'm looking for.
So it checks that security groups are attached to two instances or elastic network interfaces.
So what that means is every security group in your account, it's going to check whether it's actually
being used by an elastic network interface or an 82 instance.
So this is a good way of auditing your ruleset to check whether your security groups are being used
or whether they're just sitting there not doing anything.
So what happens straight away is we can see that we very quickly got a response here that says that
we have a non-compliant resource for the detailed monitoring and the overall is still evaluating.
So let's choose to go in and have a look at this rule.
And we can see that we've actually got the I.D. of the instance actually identified here and it says
it's non-compliant and that's because we don't have detailed monitoring enabled.
That's exactly what we'd expect to see.
You can have a look at a bit more information.
For instance, you can see our compliance timeline, and it shows you that at a certain point in time,
the resource was non-compliant.
You can also look at a configuration timeline and this will show you things such as the relationships
as well.
So you can see that this particular instance is related to a network interface, a security group,
a subnet and Ebb's volume and a VPC.
Now let's head back up to config, going to have a look at our rules.
And now we have eight non-compliant resources.
So I've got quite a few security groups in my account, but I've only got one instance running at the
moment.
So most of those security groups aren't being used.
So it's definitely had a look and it's found out that the security groups are not actually currently
in use.
So those are just a couple of quick examples of what you can do with these compliance rules.
Also, I just want to show you quickly that within the rule now, let's just choose anyone at random
here.
We have this remediation action so the remediation action can do things like publish and since notification.
But there's also all these other options here as well.
And, you know, these are predefined.
You can create your own and you can run lambda functions and that kind of thing.
But you can see there's lots of things that you could do here, like release an elastic IP.
You know, you might restart or start or stop an active instance or terminate in AC2 instance.
So there's lots of remediation actions that can be performed.
So I'm just going to cancel out of there now.
I did mention I'm going to go into Asri, so I just want to show you where the actual configuration
items are stored.
So Innisfree, I have my bucket, which is called config bucket DCT lamp's yours will be something different.
And if we head into here, we can see you've got a few folders and then we've got config and then we've
got the region.
So this is a neighborhood at a regional level.
So if I go in and it's got a whole directory structure based on dates I suppose, and then we go into
here, we can find that we've got lots and lots of configuration items.
So as you can see, we've got configuration items for Internet gateways.
We've got Network ECLSS, we've got network interfaces, subnet security groups, volumes, elastic
beanstalk cards and so on.
So it's it's found lots of resources in my account.
And then it's pulled some configuration information about those resources and stored it in this bucket.
And it will keep it there long term as well, which is how you can look into your configuration history
and see at a point in time what the resource state was.
So as you changed or as it re-evaluates, it's going to create new configuration items and keep those
in your bucket as well.
So that's just a quick overview of config.
Now, to delete our rules, we can edit if you just go down to the bottom, we can hit delete rule.
And then I'm just going to repeat that for the other rule and that's it.
So that's it for this lab, guys.
Hope you enjoyed that.
Don't forget, if you have launched any resources to go and terminate them.
And I'll see you in the next lesson.