We're moving on now to the Amazon elastic filesystem ETFs, ETFs is an implementation of an NFC based
file storage system which you attach over a network.
So it's often known as network attached storage.
Now, NAS devices are followed by storage systems.
So you connect to your file system.
So what does that mean?
Well, on the left here, we have the file management console of a computer that computer uses its own
network interface card to connect to a Nassib over a network.
That NASA server will have a bunch of disks in it and it actually shares those disks as a file system
over the network.
So this is different.
Ebb's Ebb's.
There is actually a server in the U.S. data center that has disks in it, but it shares them as Volney
at a volume level.
So you can actually see them as a volume.
You can format the drivers C or D or whatever, and your operating system is talking to it by manipulating
sectors and tracks and blocks and so on.
Now, in this case, with an NFL or a NASA based storage system, you actually connect into a file system.
So you map a drive letter.
You can't format that file system that's already done for you.
All you do is connect to it and then you can read and write data to that file system over the network.
So that's basically how it works.
So there are a few differences.
And the main one is you actually can't use windows with FS.
So in the example here I am showing you a Windows system with its C and D drives and Z Drive, which
we just mapped to the NAS.
But you actually can't do that with AFSC.
You would have to use Linux instead.
So let's have a look at Amazon FS.
So FS is a file based storage system which you can create an endpoint for in your VPC and then you can
simultaneously connect many instances up to thousands of instances to one file system.
So all of those instances can then see the same data.
Now, you can also connect instances from other episodes as well, and you can connect on premises computers,
and to do that, you must use a VPN or direct connect connection.
Now, the protocol that's used is NAFS, so that's the network filesystem protocol.
And this is only supported for Linux, as I mentioned before.
So your AC2 instances must be Linux instances to connect to your AIFS file system.
IFES offers automatic backups and they're enabled by default.
There's also lifecycle management.
With lifecycle management, you can configure a period after which files that have not been accessed
can then be moved to the infrequent access storage class.
So that's a separate storage class for EFS, which is a bit lower and cost.
Now there are two performance modes with AFSC you've got general-purpose, which is suitable for most
use cases, and then you've got Máximo where you can scale to higher levels of aggregate throughput
and operations per second.
So just watch out where exam questions might ask for a particular performance.
Attribute Fornier filesystem, something that might push you to use Máximo instead of general purpose.
So you can figure those through the wizard when you're actually creating our file system.
Now there are also two throughput modes you've got bursting where the throughput scales with the filesystem
size and then you've got provisioned where you actually provisioning the amount of throughput you believe
you need.
And so you're going to pay for that amount.
So that's going to cost more.
But if you know you need it and you need it to be available immediately, then you could choose provisioned.
And again, this is something you can configure through the wizard as we're creating our filesystem.
IFES offers the ability to encrypt data at rest and in transit, it's actually enabled by default and
you can enable it in the console or the SLA or case as well.
So these are the default settings and you can choose to customize your encryption key settings or create
an AWA krimsky.
If you don't use that, then it will just use a default key.
So encryption keys are managed by CDMS and encryption of data at rest and of transit can be configured
separately or together.
So there are two different configurations here.
It's not like Heap's where it's just encryption on or off.
In this case, you can choose encryption for data in transit and encryption for data at risk.
When you create your file system, you have to create something called a target.
So these are the endpoints in your VPC and they're within each of your availability zones.
And that's what you'll actually use to connect your instances to the local point.
Now, the filesystems Deerness name will actually resolve to the Mount Target's IP address.
So here's an example where we have free availability zones.
You can see a target ID and then an IP address and also has a network interface side.
You can control administration using AYAM and you can do so using user based or resource based policies
so you can configure policies and attachment to a user and define what they're allowed to do in Air
Force.
Or you can create a policy and apply it actually to AIFS itself and define who you want to be able to
administer your file system.
You then have control for NAFS clients.
So these are resource based policies.
So you apply these to the actual file system and they control who is or which.
Neff's clients can actually connect to your file systems and what they're able to do.
And we'll have a look at a couple of policy examples later in a section.
You can also control access to files and directories with POSIX compliant user and group level permissions.
So this is useful if you're using your file system for one of the common use cases, which is a shared
corporate directory.
And you might want to control access to certain directories using group level permissions, or you might
have user level permissions for a home drive, for example.
So that's it for the ferry.
And in the next lesson, we're going to go in, create a file system and connect a couple of easy to
instances to it.