Hi, guys.
As many of you have noticed, the US management console has been undergoing quite a few changes over
the last few months and it's an ongoing thing.
So they're still changing the console regularly.
Now, the key thing that I want to let you know is it's mostly cosmetic updates.
So overall, it's generally just look and feel changes.
Now, have a look at the video at the end of Section two in your course, because what I do there is
I actually go through and show you quite a few examples in two and a few other services just to show
you that overall, it's mainly just the way that the presentation is.
So it looks slightly different, but the settings are generally the same.
Now, there are a few exceptions.
There are some services where it goes a bit beyond just look and feel changes.
And Amazon easy to auto scaling is one of those exceptions.
So with easy to auto scaling, the actual configuration options that you need to configure are pretty
much the same.
So it's not that they've made any major changes to the fundamental architecture of easy to auto scaling,
but what they have done is modified the presentation of the options.
So if you are used to using the old console, when you're going through some of my videos that are recorded
using that console, auto scaling is one of the services where you're going to look at it and go, well,
it's so it looks very different now.
So what we're going to do is we're going to head over shortly to a video which I shot for my sister's
associate is a brand new video.
And in that I actually use auto scaling with the new console and I cover the difference between launch
configurations and launch templates.
Now, just before we do that, I just want to make you very comfortable that you're not going to get
tested in the exam on the new console versus the old console.
The exam actually lags updates by about six months anyway.
But as I said, the configuration options are pretty much the same.
So you're not going to come up on the exam questions that are going to trip you up because you were
used to using one console or the other one.
So with that being said, let's go over now to one of these new videos using auto scaling with the new
console.
Hi, guys.
So we're now going to talk about Amazon Ekta Auto scaling.
So also scaling allows us to elastically scale are two instances.
So that's about horizontally scaling our actual instances by launching or terminating easy to instances.
So how does it work?
Well, auto scaling will configure a certain amount of instances according to your scaling policies
that you define.
Then f an easy to status check fails auto scaling to replace the instance.
So in this example, this isn't about scaling as much as replacing something that's failed.
So it helps you to build in that resilience to your application as well.
Now, the other way it works is with metrics, so metrics are performance related information getting
sent to cloud watch.
And in this case, the metrics have reported that the aggregate CPU across our instances has hit 80
percent.
So they're under quite a bit of pressure.
The cloud watch service will then notify auto scaling and auto scaling will respond by launching an
extra instance.
So we now have more capacity.
And so that's how auto scaling works at a basic level.
So it also works with elastic load balancing very well.
So in this case, users connect to our load balancer.
They get distributed to Ekta instances.
Then if an easy two instance fails, the low balance of reroutes the connection and then Elby takes
the instance out of service.
Auto scaling will be notified, it will terminate the instance and then auto scanning goes and launches
a new instance, and then new connections can come in and note that this is now instant's five.
It used to be instance one that was here.
And that's because it is a brand new instance.
So auto scaling doesn't fix anything.
It just terminates it and launches a new one.
Now note that this architecture includes high availability and fault tolerance.
So not only are you highly available across different availability zones, but auto scanning will automatically
re introduce instances into your auto scaling group after other instances fail.
So you have that resiliency and that high availability.
Now, when we configure auto scaling, there's a couple of things that we can use to define the configuration
of the instances that we launch.
The first one is called a launch configuration.
And this has been around quite a long while.
With a launch configuration, you specify the hammy and the instance type that you want to use.
So here we've got a Linux to AMAI and a T2 micro.
You can also configure things such as the roles, the monitoring, the tendency and so on.
So you can see there's quite a few things that you can configure here and also storage and security
groups.
So you define those in the launch configuration and then the auto scaling group uses that launch configuration
to launch your instances according to that config.
Now, one thing to note about launch conflicts is you can't edit them, so once you've saved it, you
have to use it as it is.
And if you need to modify it, you basically have to create a new one with the different settings and
then update your auto scanning group to use the new launch configuration.
Now, another option, a bit newer is launch templates, and US seem to be pushing people towards using
launch templates now instead of launch conflicts.
It's very similar, but has a few additional features.
Firstly, you can have multiple versions so you can edit your launch templates and save them as a new
version.
It can use dedicated hosts.
You can use a combination of Spot and On-Demand instances, different instance types, and there's lots
more advanced settings as well, like termination protection and shut down behavior.
And you can configure your instances to launch in a placement group as well.
So there are more we'll see that in the console.
Let's head over there now and start creating our first auto scaling group.
So I'm back in 82.
I'm going to come down to auto scanning groups here and I'm going to collect freight and also scanning
group.
I'm going to just call this one.
And here we can actually create a launch template so we don't actually have one at the moment.
I have some launch config from before, but I want to show you how to create one new.
So let's click on create a launch template.
And this actually takes us into the launch template console, and I'm going to call this launch template
one, so let's scroll down and see what we need to configure.
So firstly, I want to select my Amazon the next two, am I?
So that's the first one at the top here.
I can choose the instance type well, I want to keep this in the freezer, so let's go for two micro.
I can choose my keeper.
I've just got one, so let's select that one, we can put it in a VPC and I'm also going to choose my
security group as well.
You can then do things like configure the storage volumes to resource tanks and the network interfaces,
and then there's more advanced details here as well.
So if we come down to advanced details, you see, you can request spot instances, configure the shutdown
behavior.
And there's quite a lot of options that are not going to go through all of those now at the bottom.
We have user data, so let's go and grab our user data again.
So I copied my user data to my clipboard.
Same stuff we used earlier and I've just posted that in.
And the last thing we need to do is come up and just remember to connect our instance profile.
So that's how we connect Iam role.
So I need S3 READ-ONLY permissions here.
So that's everything.
I'm going to create that launch template, click on View Launch Templates and now we've got this new
one.
Now we have to go back and just restart this with it.
So let's go back in and create our auto scanning group.
Call it ASG one.
Choose the launch template.
Click on next.
Now, this is where you could combine on demand and spot capacity so you can combine purchase options
when you're using a launch template.
We're going to stick to just adhering to the launch template.
I'm going to select two subnets to aim to be click on next.
I can enable load balancing here, so I'm going to actually attach my target group one.
So remember that you attach the target group.
You don't actually attach the load balancer, you attach the target group.
And that has the same effect.
I'm going to enable Elby health checks.
I'll talk about that.
Two different types of health check in the next lesson in more detail.
And let's click on Next.
This is where we can adjust our capacity, so to start with, let's put it at two to and too, so that's
just going to have a design capacity or to the minimum is going to be to in the maximum is going to
be two.
So it should just launch two instances and register those of our load balancer.
So we're not using any kind of screening policy.
Will look at those more later on in the section.
You can enable scale in protection.
That means the auto scanning group will not terminate instances.
I don't want to do that.
So I'm going to click on next.
I don't need any notifications or tags, so I just go free to review.
It all looks good to me.
So let's create the auto scanning group.
So that should go ahead now and it's going to launch those two instances and then it's going to register
them with the target group, so we should find that they're available for our load balancer shortly.
Now let's have a look at what's going on.
So I head up to instances.
And sure enough, I've got these two pending instances here.
So let's go and have a look at our auto scaling group, and here we can see plenty of information about
the auto scanning group.
So you can check the configuration here.
We've got some activity, so you'll see some entries.
So here it's telling us that it's launching two different instances.
We can look at these scanning options here, the screening policies, which will cover again shortly.
You can look at the instances here and manage them.
And then we've got a monitoring tab as well.
So you can monitor what's going on with your auto scanning group.
Now, you do need to enable this metric collection as well.
So if you want to see that information here, you just need to go ahead and enable it.
Or you can have a look at the EU level as well, so that will be using the EU standard metrics.
So let's now go and have a look at our target group.
And so we should see that we have some targets coming in, our target one here and sure enough, here
they are and they're healthy already.
So now if we go to our labor answer, we should find that we're able to connect to our two instances.
So we've put in the DNS name and now we've got Ravon and I've hit refresh and I'm not getting the other
one because I've left sticky sessions on.
So let's go back and disable sticky sessions for our target group.
So I wanted to show you that because I know that you might have done the same thing.
So let's go into target group, edit attributes and just disable stickiness.
So now by the time that load balancer Cookie expires, we should then be able to refresh and head our
two different instances.
So now I'm able to cycle and we've got these two instances called Raven and Kensi.
So that's all looking good.
So that's it for this lesson.
Keep your configuration running because we've got more work to do on it.