Hi, guys.
Up until now, we've been using public subnets, which, as you know, means that your E.S. two instances
are accessible from the Internet.
As long as you have the right security group rules, you can access them over a secure shell or put
80 or whatever it is that you open up.
So obviously, that's not ideal for many scenarios.
You want to keep your servers internal in a private subnet that don't have direct access to the Internet.
And that's what we call a private subnet.
So the key difference with a private subnet is that it doesn't have an Internet gateway in its roots
able.
So remember, every subnet must be associated with a roundtable.
Now, a public subnet has a round table that has two entries at a minimum.
So firstly, you have this room, which is the site, a block for your VPC.
And what that means is that all traffic.
To any subnets that are within this side, a block are rooted locally, so that enables routing between
subnets, between public private subnets, across multiple availability zones.
It doesn't matter everything within that side.
A block is going to get routed locally by the VPC router.
The other entry in the round table is going to be the entry to the Internet Gateway I.D..
So in this case, you normally put zero zero zero zero slash zero, which means any destination.
In other words, any other destination.
Anything that isn't within this block.
Send it to the Internet gateway.
So any address within this block routes it locally.
Any other address outside of that route?
It's the Internet gateway and it can go out to the outside world.
A private subnet outside doesn't have the Internet gateway around, so it doesn't have a route to the
outside world.
Also, it's not configured to provide public IP addresses to the instances that are launched into it.
So if we launch an easy two instance into a private subnet, it gets a private IP.
There is no public IP and therefore there's no way to access it directly.
If you're trying to manage your instance from the Internet.
So one of the ways around this is you use what's called a bastion host.
A Bastion host is literally an instance in a public subnet that you use to then jump to your private
subnet.
So it's also called a jump post.
So even a bastion host or jump post, I think in A.W. s terminology, it's usually Bastiaan hosts,
but many people call them jump posts.
So what you do is, for instance, in this case, you might be these might be Linux instances and you
use Secure Shell and you, S.H., into this AC2 instance, you get a command line and then from there,
you, S.H. into this one.
And now you can manage your instance in your private subnet from the Internet or from some other network.
So that's the theory.
And we're actually gonna create this configuration in the lab now.
So we're going to create an easy two instance in a public subnet.
We're going to create an easy two instance at a private subnet.
Now, we don't actually have any private subnets yet.
So that's going to be the first task is to go into the VPC management console and create ourselves a
couple of private subnets.
So I'm on the AWB management console in the VPC dashboard.
And what I'm gonna do first is I'm going to create a new round table.
So just to show you what we have at the moment, we just have our default VPC.
We just have free subnets, the default subnets that are created with our account.
And those are all public subnets.
And you can see that because they have default subnet here and also assigned public IP here.
So we know that default subnets and they're going to assign public IP addresses to instances that are
launched into them.
Now, under round tables, we just have a single round table and that has the roots to side a block
local.
And the round to the outside world via an Internet gateway.
And you can see under subnet associations which subnets are associated with it.
And at the moment, we have just these three.
Now, bear in mind, guys, I'm taking you straight into the virtual private cloud here, despite the
fact that we haven't actually covered that in the course yet.
Now, the reason is I'm going to show you bits and pieces along the way so that you can build your skill
set.
And then when we get to the VPC section of the course, we're going to do more of a deep dive.
And you'll already understand the foundations.
So be much more easy for you.
So let's go back to route tables, and I'm going to create my second round table and I'm gonna call
this artsy one.
And you associate that to a VPC.
We only have one option.
I choose creates, and that's all I need to do.
So it will have a route to the side, a block of all VPC.
It doesn't have any subnet associations yet.
There's none in the list here.
And what we want to do now is create our subnets.
So I'm going to choose create subnet.
I'm going to call this one private subnet, one choose the VPC.
I'm going to put this one, associate this to an availability zone, AP, SD two way.
So each subnet can be associated with one and only one availability zone.
So it's a one to one relationship.
And you then have to choose the side a block.
So how do we work out what IP address range to use here?
Well, let's just open a another tab.
I'm going to open the VPC management console in a second tab here.
And what I'm going to do is just have a look at these subnet ranges that we've got.
So what we have here is one seven two top 30, one dot zero.
And then it's a dot 32.
So then it's a dot 16.
So I suspect the next one is going to be dot forty.
But I can easily put this into a subnet calculator to work this out.
So to do that, we can go over to Google and Social IP subnet calculator.
And I like to use this one IP subnet subnet calculator, which is on calculator dot net.
So what I need to do is put in my range here.
So let's take this address here.
And we know it's a slash 20.
So I just copy that to my clipboard.
Put that in and then change here to slash 20 and choose.
And if we scroll down here, what we can see is the network address ranges.
So we've got one seven tudo thirty one dot zero.
Then dot 16.
Then dot 32.
Then dot forty eight.
So what I'm gonna do is choose this one dot forty eight for my first subnet.
So let's come back to the VPC management console.
I'm going to paste this in.
Put dot zero.
And then slash twenty four subnet mask and choose.
Create.
So that's subnet one.
And we can then do the same again.
I could just call it private subnet to choose my VPC.
Choose to put this in to be.
And then what's my next range.
So the next one is sixty four.
So I'm going to copy.
That's my clipboard pasted in dot zero and then slash twenty.
Got two dots and then let's go to that one and create.
So now we've got two private subnets that we could keep doing that we could do that for the third availability
zone if we want.
I don't need those so I'm just gonna leave it there.
But what we do need to do now is go to route tables and under round table.
We need to choose subnet associations and we need to find our subnets and associate them.
So we choose edit subnet associations.
And I can choose these two new subnets, the DOT 48 and the DOT 64.
And you can see that currently associated with the main round table, which is what happens by default
when you create a subnet.
That's to say.
So we now have our private subnets that are associated with a round table.
So what we have is two private subnets and the only thing they have in there out SABL is this side,
a block for the local VPC.
So what we want to do now is actually go and launch our public instance and an instance into our private
subnet as well.
So I many setu I'm going to launch an instance.
So it's gonna be an Amazon and it's two a.m. I t to micro as always, and I'm going to choose my public
subnet to a choose next.
And just go to our security group and we need to give this web access.
So again, that's for SSX.
We will be using the SSA protocol to connect into this instance.
And now I can choose launch.
So that's one done.
Let's do the other one.
So the other one, it's gonna be the same, except we're going to put it into one of our private subnet.
So let's just put it into private subnet one.
And again, we're going to need to SSA into this one.
So we need to use our Web access security group.
And that's it.
We've got all instances launching.
So let's grab the public IP address of our instance in the public subnet.
And we're going to use SSA H to connect into it.
And so I'm going to use my public key file.
And that's connected.
So that's great.
So it connects connected in that instance in the public subnet.
So now we want to be able to connect from this instance to the instance in our private subnet.
Now, the question is, as you know, we've just connected by running a command and specifying our key
profile.
So as you know, the key file is security sensitive because it allows people to access your AC to instances
and gain root level administrative permissions.
So how do you connect from your public instance?
To your private instance, because we've used to keep our far, which we stored securely on our client.
But we don't have that keep our file on here, so let's just go back and see what happens if we try
to connect and the instance in the private subnet is only going to have a private IP address.
So let's copy that and let's go SSA easy to dash user at and give it the private IP address and astute.
Yes.
And of course we get a permission denied public key.
So we can't do that.
We need to be able to connect using a key profile.
So what we have to do is we just going to lose that connection and I'm going to clear the screen to
make things easier.
And I need to run a command.
And that is S.H. Dash ad.
And then if you're on Linux, you do Dasch.
See, I'm on a Mac.
So I do dash capital K.
And then we specify the key per file and it says that the identity is being added.
And that means that we can now connect without having to specify the keeper file, but also we can configure
agent forwarding.
So you do SSA dash a.
And that's a capital way, and then you do.
Easy to dash user.
At and then let's just go back to the console and we're going to need the public IP of our public instance
and we connect, so we're connected in that instance now.
And what we can do this time is let's just go back and get the private IP address of our private instance.
And now we should be able to SSA each to the private IP address.
And there we are.
We're actually in.
So that's how you do agent forwarding.
And that allows you to be able to connect from your Bastian host to your instance in a private subnet.
So just to summarize what we've done, we've created a private subnet, which is a subnet in which instances
do not pick up public IP addresses.
And they they have a round table that doesn't have a route to the outside world via an Internet gateway.
We've then created a Bastion host, which is a jump post in our public subnet.
And we've used that to connect using agent forwarding for our keeper to an instance in the private subnet
so we can now manage that instance.
So that's pretty cool, guys.
One of the things that you might have noticed is, though, we are able to connect to the outside world
from our public subnets going outbound.
We can't do that from our private subnet because we don't have an Internet gateway.
So if we go back to the console and I just do ping Google dot com, it's just going to fail and we're
going to see that we got 100 percent packet loss.
So we don't have a path to the outside world.
And that's going to be the subject of the next couple of labs where we're going to look at how we can
do that.
And there's two ways.
One is called a net instance and one is called a net gateway.
And we're going to cover both of those in detail.
See that, guys?