Cross load balancing is a feature of elastic load balancers, which attempts to evenly distribute traffic
to registered instances.
So when cross own load balancing is enabled, each load balance node will distribute traffic across
registered targets in all availability zones.
When cross own load balancing is disabled, each load balancer no distributes traffic only across the
registered instances in its availability zone.
And this can result in an uneven distribution of the incoming traffic.
With application load balances, cross own load balancing is always enabled with network load balancers
and gateway load balances.
Cross line load balancing is disabled by default, but can be enabled.
Now, the best way to really understand this is with a diagram.
We have an elastic load balancer sets up, and as you can see, we have five active instances spread
unevenly across availability zones.
Now, the load balance is going to provision nodes in each of these subnets.
And when traffic comes in, that traffic is going to get split, so 50 percent will go to one subnet
and 50 percent will go to the other.
And of course, that results in an uneven distribution of the traffic because each of the free targets
in Zone A is going to receive sixteen point six percent of the traffic because it's getting one third
of 50 percent and an availability zone B. We're going to get 25 percent of the traffic distributed to
these nodes so they can have a higher distribution.
That's because there's two instances splitting the 50 percent of incoming traffic.
So that's cross zone load balancing being disabled.
Now let's look what happens when it's enabled.
We've got the same situation and the connections are coming in.
But this time, 60 percent of the traffic is going to go to the Subnet and Availability Zone II, which
means that each of the targets will get 20 percent.
The other 40 percent will get split into availability zone B, which means the targets that also only
receive 20 percent of the traffic.
So now we have an even distribution of the connections to AC two instances.
Now this is going to help you to evenly distribute those incoming connections across your back end instances.