So moving on to network ACLs they function at the subnet level not at the instance level. With NACLs
you can have both permit and deny rules.
They contain a numbered list of rules that get evaluated in order from the lowest number until the explicit
deny which is at the end of the ruleset.
Network ACLs also have separate inbound and outbound rules and each rule can allow or deny traffic.
They're stateless so in the example I gave before.
If you send traffic on port 80 to a web server and the response traffic is coming back on a different
port number that port number has to be allowed.
So you have to allow the whole higher address range block or you have to just have a sort of general outbound
rule that allows any traffic. NACLs apply to traffic that's both ingress and egress so traffic going
in or out of the subnet but not traffic that's within the subnet so going from one instance to another
instance in the same subnet for that you need a security group they automatically come with a default
network ACL or the BPC automatically comes with a default network ACL and that allows all inbound and
outbound traffic custom NACLs deny all traffic by default.
If you create a custom NACLs associate with a subnet it's going to block everything until we create
rules all subnets must be associated with one network ACL.
So by default they'll just be associated with the default NACL which will allow all traffic.
You can associate a network ACL with multiple subnets however a subnet can only be associated with one
network ACL at a time. Network ACLs don't filter traffic between instances in the same subnet.
So this is what network ACLs look like.
This is an example of the default network ACL.
Allows all protocols all ports from any source inbound.
It allows all protocols ports and sources outbound and then you have a custom network ACL.
So this is what will happen if you create one by default and associate it with a subnet is going to
deny absolutely everything so network ACLs are the preferred option for blocking specific IPs
or ranges.
So you might see an exam question that says that a malicious IP address has been identified.
You need to very quickly block that specific IP or that specific range of IPs and you could do
that from a network ACL but not a security group so you can't do a security groups and network ACL is
the first line of defense because traffic going into the subnet hits the network ACL first and then
the security group gets hit because that's associated with the instance which is already within the
subnet.
Changes take effect immediately.
So just to summarize those differences you really need to know this for the exam so security groups operate
the instance level network ACL is at the subnet level. Security groups have allow rules only, network
ACLs both allow and deny the security group is stateful the network ACL is stateless. Security groups
evaluate all rules whereas network ACLs process rules in order until they hit an allow or deny.
Security group applies to an instance only if it's associated with a group whereas a network ACL applies
to everything in the subnets it's associated with.
So moving on to connectivity there's several methods you can connect to a VPC you got the managed VPN
you got direct connect direct connect plus a VPN, VPN cloud Hub, software VPN, transit and
VPC peering as well as private link and VPC endpoints.
So lets look at these in a bit more detail.
We've got the managed VPN.
This is an IP set VPN connection over the Internet as quick and easy to setup support static routes
or BGP peering and you know this is really dependent on an internet connection.
So you've got the latency issues of the Internet to worry about and you create this by creating a virtual private
gateway on AWS and the customer gateway
on the on-premises side, we then have direct connect.
So this is network connection over private lines.
Think about connecting one cloud to another cloud or a data center to AWS.
Whenever you see questions that mention creating a hybrid cloud network connection it's probably going
to be direct connect because it's a private link.
It requires a large network link and you'd use it when you have lots of resources and services being
provided on AWS and you need that high bandwidth low-latency connection.
Now you do have to set this up.
You might have to have a relationship with a networking or telecom provider, you might have to put your
own rack into a data center somewhere so that you can cross connect in or use a third party provider.
And this does take a bit of time to set up and that's something to remember for the exam I've definitely
seen questions that test your knowledge of the fact that direct connect does take time to set up.
So always remember if there's a very quick timeline for deployment like you need to get something set
up within two weeks or a month.
Direct connects.
Probably not going to be provisioned in that time frame it could be two or three months.
So watch out for that one.
We then have direct connect plus VPN.
This is another exam question that comes up.
So make sure you understand this.
You can't encrypt a direct connect connection natively so there's no sort of button that you press and
you can enable encryption for direct connect but you can create a VPN connection over direct connect
and that will enable IP security.
So if you see an exam question that says that you need to enable encryption on a direct connect connection
it might be a VPN so you need a virtual private gateway and a customer Gateway. VPN cloud
hub.
So this is essentially creating a hub and spoke topology with VPN connections so again it's using the
Internet.
We have a software VPN.
This is really your providing your own software and just setting up a VPN connection into VPC transit
VPC is a way that you can connect geographically dispersed pieces in order to create a global network
transit center as they call it.
We then have VPC peering so this is how you can connect the VPCs to each other using private IP addresses.
So AWS private link is enabling network connectivity between VPC and AWS services using interface endpoints.
And this is used to keep private subnets private by using the AWS backbone to reach other a AWS marketplace
services rather than the public Internet so where you're publishing services in a kind of service provider
model to other accounts or other VPCs.
We then have the VPC endpoints you do need to know the difference between these.
You need to know which services use which type of endpoint.
So the interface endpoint is where you have an ENI with a private IP and the gateway endpoint is where
you have a target for a specific route.
So you update your route table.
Now the key thing to remember here is the gateway endpoint is for Amazon S3 and dynamoDB definitely
need to know this for the exam.
You will definitely see questions about VPC endpoints.
You need to know that the gateway endpoint requires you to update the table and its use with these two
services.
Anything else is and there's quite a long list of services.
This is just a few will be an elastic network interface with a private IP address in the subnet.
Now something new that might come up on the exam is that you can allow offer AWS accounts to create
their application resources into a shared centrally managed VPC. VPC sharing enables subnets to be shared
with other accounts within the same AWS organization and we'll be covering AWS organizations later
in the course.
This means that you can separate duties centrally controlled VPC structure routing and IP address allocation
application owners still continue to own the resources accounts and security groups and the participants
can reference security group by these of each other.
Now this might lead to higher density and subnets efficient use of VPN and AWS direct connect.
You can also avoid some of the hard limits of the number of IPs and direct connect connections by simplifying
your network architecture.
Cost can also be optimized through reuse of components such as NAT gateways, VPC interface endpoints
and intra availability zone traffic.
So not getting those network costs now I would just say that you just need to understand VPC sharing
at a high level.
It may come up in exam scenario.
We then have VPC flow logs.
So remember this is how you can capture information about the traffic that's going to and from network
interfaces and it's stored using cloudwatch logs and you can create them at the VPC level.
The subnet level or the network interface level
and just finally a little bit of guidance on high availability.
Some of the best practices are that you should create subnets in all available places to create multi
AZ presence for your VPC create at least two VPN tunnels into your virtual private gateway for using
a VPN Direct Connect is not hijacked by default.
So you do need to establish a second connection that could be direct connect ideally or it could be
using a VPN as a backup for multi AZ redundancy of NAT gateways, create gateways in each availability
zone with routes for private subnets to use the local gateway.
So that's it for this exam cram guys.
Hope you got lots of value.