Hi guys.
Another method of authenticating in S3 that we haven't spoken about yet is using query string authentication
which is also known probably more often known as pre signed URLs.
So the use case for this is that let's say you have an object going got jpeg file here.
But let's say you had some videos and we've got a video file there.
So just imagine you have this video file and you want to share that with some people but you don't want
to give them credentials in order to authenticate against AWS and you don't want to allow this file
to be available to the public.
So you want to keep it secure.
Just this group of people.
So one way of doing that is that you create a presigned URL and then that URL will enable
anyone who has the URL to use it and access the object you can generate pre signed you URLs even manually
which is pretty tedious or you can do it programmatically.
So in most cases you would programmatically enable your application to generate these URLs.
And what you can do is you can have an expiration on it as well so you can say that it will expire within
24 hours or whatever it might be.
So let's just have a look at a Web page here.
And so you can look this up authenticating requests using query parameters and it gives you lots of
detail about how this works.
Now one of the things is it takes an access key ID and a secret I.D..
So in other words it takes the credentials of a user or role from IAM and it uses those credentials
to authenticate.
So it's quite important to be careful which credentials you use which access keys and secret I.D. you
actually use the other thing as I mentioned before is that you can put a date and then you can put an
expiry so you can expire this after a certain period of time and it says here that the maximum amount
of time is seven days.
So that's one to remember.
So what we want to do in this lab is we're just going to use the command line to generate  a
presigned URL
So we actually have this audit document here.
And I would like to access this document.
So let's just say if we can do that straight off so I'm just gonna copy this year I'll open a new tab
and put it in and we get the access denied message because this object is not publicly available.
So what we're gonna do now we've got to come online here.
I'm just going to first I need to go and get the IP address of my instance
and then we're going to SSH into this instance
and now if we if we try to list S3 we don't have the option here.
So we've got a couple of options we can either use a role or we can configure our credentials.
It's a lot more secure to use a role.
So let's just go back and I know I have a role which I can apply to this service so let's just go into
instance settings attach IAM role and go to S3 full access
so let's try and reissue that command and we're sure we can see the bucket now and if I want to list
inside the bucket just to see my file name I can do this command with the bucket name
and now can see my file name as well.
So what I want to do is I'm going to run a command called aws s3 presign
and then going to give the path to the bucket and the object within the bucket.
And then I'm going to add on the parameter expires in sixty.
Now this is in seconds so it's a very short timeframe for this URL so we get this huge URL here.
And I'm going to copy that and let's head back to safari and I'm going to put this in my new tab in
my browser.
So there we go.
We can see the image file and we've been able to do that even though this is not a public object.
Now we know that this is going to expire in 60 seconds.
So let's hit a refresh next.
I've given it a bit of time and sure enough it says access denied request has expired.
So that's set ready for pre signed your URLs.
So just remember query string parameters or query string authentication pre signed your URLs so different
terms for the same thing.
And the typical use cases as I mentioned before are going to be where you need to provide secure access
to some objects or buckets within your account to users who don't have an AWP as accounts that they
don't have an account in
IAM
And you don't want to allow it to be publicly available.