Hi, guys.
You've already seen that there are different types of addresses assigned to our active instances.
So we have public addresses, private addresses and then there's also elastic IP addresses.
So I want to go over the differences between these.
So we have our IWC accounts and in that there's an availability zone.
And let's say we have two subnets within that availability zone and we have an instance and that instance
has an interface in one of the public subnets.
That interface has a private IP address, and it also has a public IP address.
It then has another interface in another subnet within the same A-Z.
It also has an interface and another subnet with a private IP, so a public IP address is a dynamic
address.
What that means is it might change.
So when you stop your instance and start your instance again, it will pick up a new IPv4 public address.
The private address stays the same, but the public address will change.
So that means you got to make sure you don't use that IP address in application code because it could
change at any time.
So another thing we can do is a sign something called an elastic IP.
Now an elastic IP is also a public IP, but it's a static address, so it doesn't change now.
Elastic pipes can be assigned to our network interfaces as well.
So what we can do is associate the elastic IP with this network interface here.
So this second address, this public address is an elastic address, and that means it's static and
it won't change so we can stop our instance.
We can start our instance again as many times as we want.
That address will always be the same.
Now what if our instance fails?
And let's say we have some applications that are pointing at this IP address, what we want to do is
a sign that IP address to another instance.
So what we can do, we have two options here.
One of the things is we can move the Elastic Network adapter because remember, we can move these between
different instances within this same availability zone.
So both ionize and IPRs can be remapped to a different instance.
So once we've done that, that means the second instance is now responding to any requests that are
coming in to this IP address.
And of course, you can automate this programmatically as well.
Now, another option is what if you have a failure, but you want to be able to fail over between availability
zones so you want to be able to protect in case that availability zone fails?
Well, now we have an instance in a separate availability zone.
It also has two network interfaces.
And what we're going to do is move the elastic IP address so IPRs can be remapped across availability
zones.
But remember, the elastic network interfaces cannot there within an availability zone, so you can
remap them to a different subnet in the same A-Z or different instance in the same subnet.
But you can't remap them across availability zones, but you can do that for the elastic IP address.
So let's just summarize the key differences public addresses are dynamic that lost 20 instances stopped
they used in public subnets.
You don't pay for them, and they are associated with a private IP on the instance you can't move them
between instances.
Private addresses are retained when the instance is stopped and they used in both public and private
subnet.
So you always have a private address and then elastic IP addresses are static public addresses.
You get charged if you're not using them.
So if they're allocated to your accounts for unused, then you will pay a fee for them.
They're associated with a private IP on the instance, and they can be moved between instances and elastic
network adapters.
That's it for this lesson.
Now there is a little bit more ferry, and then we're actually going to get on with using elastic IP
addresses in the console.