Hi guys.
I just wanted to make a quick apology.
The audio in this lab is not very good quality but I did actually record myself registering a DNS domain
name and I can't really redo that and we actually use that domain name in the labs for the rest of
the course.
So I've left it in there.
Hope you don't mind, see you in the lab guys. Hi guys.
This is an optional lab in which we're going to register a DNS domain name using AWS Route 53 service
Route 53 is Amazon's DNS service and we're going to register this domain name so that we can use
it later on in some of the labs in the next section and other sections of the course.
Now it's not essential but it is useful so if you can spare the cash then please follow along.
So we're in the AWS management console.
I'm just gonna head up to services here.
Click the down arrow go down to networking and content delivery and we can choose Route 53
So this is the welcome screen tells you a little bit about Route 53
So it does DNS management traffic management availability monitoring and domain registration.
And this is what we want to do right now so I'm going to click get started on the domain registration
so the moment I've got no domains I'm just gonna click up here on registered domain and you can now
search and you can choose where you want to use dot com or dot net
There are many others here.
I'm just gonna leave it on dot com and I'm going to choose dctlabs and then click on check
and it's available.
So I'm going to add to cart and that's going to be 12 year dollars for one year
so on this page I just need to fill out the registrant contact information and then click continue.
One of the things to note is privacy protection hide some of your details and that's enabled by default.
I usually leave that on because you will need to put in some some details like your phone number and
your address so I filled out my contact information and I'm now on the verifying purchase screen.
One of the things that you'll know here is it asks if you want to automatically renew your domain.
I'm just gonna leave this on enable for now.
But bear in mind after the first year you will be charged again to your NWS account when it renews and
I think you normally get an email to remind you before that happens as well.
So I'm just gonna click I have read and agreed to the domain name registration agreement and click on
complete purchase.
So now just says thank you and I can click on go to domains so we can now see that the domain registration
is in progress.
And once that's complete the domain will then appear under registered domains and that might take a
little while so I left there for 15 or maybe 20 minutes and I've just come back and I can see that the
dctlabs.com domain is now registered
You can see the expiration date and the auto renew if we come up to host in zones we can also see that
the hosting zone is being created
and if we have a look in the hosted zone we can see the name server records and the startup authority
records and we're now going to be at a create records we have been this hosting zone and connect them
to AWS resources later in the course.
Again don't worry if you don't want to spend the money on registering a domain you don't need it for
this course but it's pretty awesome if you can do it.