In this lab we're going to create a table in dynamoDB and which can add some items to it and have
a look around the console.
So simple thing to do.
You go into tables and create a table and then what we're gonna do is we're going to create a table
I'm going to call this TV series and then you need to specify a partition key and for this I'm going
to put in series name and it's gonna be a string value.
You can then optionally add a sort key So for instance for the TV series I'm going to add the season
and you will now have to put in these values so you now are required to put in a value for each of these.
If you then select this option for default settings you then have options for secondary indexes.
You have options for the read and write capacity mates.
This is what I mentioned in the previous lab so you have provisioned and then you have on demand so
you might want to stick in provision for free tier if you choose on demand.
It will then scale your dynamoDB database as required to perform.
Let's put it on provisioned and you can see here that you have a read.
Capacity units option and a write capacity units and it estimates the amount of cost per month.
That's very low for five read and five write.
You can then choose to enable auto scaling and you can choose for which read all the right capacity
you specify your target database utilization and then your minimum and your maximum capacity units.
You can also then change the IAM role that's assigned to dynamoDB in this case.
This is for auto scaling and you can also enable encryption even under the default settings using server
side encryption using AWS owned customer master key or by using KMS where you can then sort
of specify another master key.
I'm going to leave these and what am I going to do.
I'm just gonna go back up here and choose the default settings and click Create.
So that's it.
It's really fast to create a table.
We'll go to items in a minute.
We can go into metrics and I'm so you can see some cloud Watch metrics here so you can see how many
of your reach capacity units are being used and how many of your write capacity units you can then go
to alarms and create an alarm.
You can change your capacity settings here you can create your indexes global tables so if you remember
this is this is what we want to do in a couple of labs time.
What are you going to credit global tables so that we can have a multi master multi region database
and for that you need to enable dynamo DV streams.
We then have our backup options and we can't see this at the moment because the table is just being
created.
We'll go back to that and then we have under access control here.
You can choose identity providers so you can specify a specific identity provider and then provide a
policy.
And this is use of Web identity Federation.
Let's go back to items and what we're going to do is we're going to start creating some items.
So we need to put in a series name so let's call Let's go for Game of Thrones.
What else!
And let's choose season as Season 8.
And I don't need to specify any other attributes here but I do need to specify these and then I can
add additional attributes.
So for instance I could choose to add a string and that string might be the network.
So let's see which network was this.
Well it's HBO and so I can click on save.
And now that item is now added to my table.
So let's create another one now and let's create one for the Walking Dead and let's put in Season 6
and I don't want to specify the network for this one but what I do want to specify is the year so I
can put in number and I can go a year and this one was 2015
and I could also go in and let's say add another number and this might be the number of episodes - 16
and click save.
So we can see that I didn't enter the network.
I don't have to.
Every item can have different entries, it must have the partition key.... so you must provide
a value for these but you can then change what values you assign to the other ones.
I could then go in and add Sherlock for instance and I need to again put in season.
So let's put in four.
And then I could add another string and that might be starring and I can put the name of an actor
and click on save.
So now you have all these different attributes and you can see each of my items has different attributes
and this is really the power of the nosql databases.
With a structured database like RDS you can't do this.
You must provide the same attributes for each row or each line item that you put in.
We then have a couple of options for searching for data.
You can have a scan or query queries.
Use the partition key and the sort key whereas this and they're very fast and then a scan uses filters
and you can then add in these filters.
Let's just go back up to have a look at backups.
It's enabled.
Now we can see some options here so you could click on enable for points in time recovery and you can
create your on demand backups here and choose a backup name.
There's also an option in dynamoDB to purchase reserve capacity so you can click on this option here
choose your read or write capacity units and then select a term.
So you could do read capacity units and then you have the options of one or three years and you'll get
a significant discount.
So here we go.
You got a 76 percent discount for your read capacity units over four years.
We then have dynamoDB accelerator or Dax and this is an in-memory cache for your dynamoDB database.
So this is the way that you can get your latency down to the microseconds.
And this is gonna be the subject of the next lab where we're going to actually try a Dax cluster and
we're going to use an EC2 instance to query the cluster.