Hi, guys, there's an exam crime lesson for most sections in this course, so I just want to explain
quickly what they are before we get started.
Exam crimes are a quick run through of important facts, and I will go quite quickly.
You can always change the playback speed if I'm too fast for you.
You should use these after going through the section for revision and cramming.
Mainly, I'm going to be reminding you about things rather than explaining.
Now that being said, there may be some facts that are covered here that weren't covered in the lessons
or vice versa.
Some topics are quite suitable for this bullet point format, and I prefer to keep it as visual as possible
and as engaging as possible throughout the main lessons in the course.
Now, most lessons in this course are highly visual, but exam crimes are absolutely not violent death
by bullet points.
I deliberately make sure that I have everyone covered.
No matter what your learning style is, some people are more visual.
Some people like to read and some people hands on is the most important way to learn.
So whatever way you learn best, you're covered in this course.
And exam crimes are an additional tool which is going to be useful for most people.
This entire slide back is offered for download with a white background so suitable for printing as well,
so you might want to print it out and then just keep it as a reference so you can remind yourself of
certain things.
Make sure you also use the cheat sheets.
That's another place where there's some important information.
I haven't put everything into the exam crimes.
They would just get too long.
So let's get started with the exam cram for I am I am is used to security, control individual and group
access to AWG resources.
It makes it easy to provide multiple users with access to resources and with IAM.
You can manage users groups, access policies and roles and also user credentials.
User password policies can be configured in IAM as well.
We can also enable multifactor authentication, and that's definitely recommended.
We can also generate API keys for programmatic access to IAM.
By default, all new uses are created with no access to any services they can only log into IWC, but
they can't actually do anything.
Permissions must then be explicitly granted to allow users to access an IWC service.
I am uses are the individuals who've been granted access to an AWB accounts.
Now I am is a universal or global service, so it doesn't apply to specific regions.
I am is eventually consistent.
What that means is if you make a change and then you immediately try to read from IAM, you might not
see that change.
It might just take a bit longer for forensics and methods.
We've got console passwords for logging into the management console, access keys for programmatic access
service certificates, which can be used for some services as well.
I am users are the entities that represent a person or a service.
By default, they cannot access anything in the account.
The root user credentials are the email address used to create the accounts.
And there's a password associated with that account.
The root account has full administrative permissions, and they cannot be restricted.
I am users can be created to represent applications, and those are known then as service accounts.
You can have up to 5000 users per IWC account.
I am groups are collections of users and have policies attached to them.
A group's not an identity in itself, so it can't be identified as a principle in a policy.
So where you have a policy statement and you put in the R.N of a principle like a user, you can't do
that with a group.
You use groups to assign permissions to users, and you should always follow the principle of least
privilege when assigning permissions.
You can't newsgroups, so you can't create a group within a group.
I am.
Roles are created and then assumed by trusted entities.
And there a way of delegating permissions to resources for users and services.
Users and services can assume a role to obtain temporary security credentials, and those are issued
by the Security Token Service to SDS service.
I am.
Policies are documents that define the permissions and they can be applied to users groups and roles
and include key value pairs that consist of an attribute and a value.
All permissions are implicitly denied by default.
The most restrictive policy is applied if there's multiple policies with conflicting statements.
Now what are the types of policy?
We've got identity based policies which you can attach to users groups or roles.
We've got resource based policies.
They get attached to resources like S3 buckets, and you can define permissions for principals accessing
the resources using a resource policy.
We then got permissions boundaries.
These set the maximum permissions that an identity based policy can grant to an IAM entity.
Permissions Boundaries aren't really covered at the associate level, but they are at the professional
level.
We then have organizations service control policies, these specify the maximum permissions for an organization
or in view.
And lastly, we have session policies that are used with assume role API actions.
Now onto the IAM best practices, lock away your account route user access keys.
Create individual users use groups to assign permissions to users, grant lease privilege, get started
using permissions with AWB, manage policies and use customer managed policies instead of in line policies.
Use access levels to review I am permissions always bearing in mind that list privilege and configure
a strong password policy for your users.
Enable multi-factor authentication.
Use roles for applications that run on easy to instances and use roles to delegate permissions.
Do not share access keys.
Always keep them to yourself and use them only for your accounts and wroteI or credentials regularly
and remove any unnecessary credentials.
You can use policy conditions for extra security when you're writing your own policies.
And lastly, monitor activity in your account to see what's actually happening.
And that's it for this exam crime.