Continuing our exam crime with a single sign on, so, so, so makes it easy to centrally manage access
to multiple eyewitness accounts as well as business applications.
This is single sign on access to applications as well as your AWB accounts.
You can use AIDS organizations, so you can essentially create your organizations configuration and
attach that to us.
So and then grant access for single sign on through those accounts.
There's also lots of built in integration's to many business applications, including some of those
on the screen, and we saw in the lecture earlier in the section that there are many, many more as
well.
So you can create and manage your user identities in Awassa identity store, so you can create your
user accounts within AYSO or you can connect to Active Directory or 018.
So Ezo is integrated with very obvious organizations and that means that you can select one or more
accounts from your organization and grant users access to these accounts.
So it's about granting single Sinon access to those accounts.
You still got to do the permissions somewhere else.
So onto identity providers and federations.
So this is when we're looking at IAM.
So Identity and access management and you can configure identity providers to federate external identity
sources.
And this means you can manage use your user identities outside of us and give these external user identities
permissions to AWEX resources in your account when you use Ayam identity provider.
You don't have to create a custom signing code or manage your own user identities.
The ODP provides that for you.
External users then sign in through the IDP and in the case of Web Identity Federation, that can be
something like Amazon or Facebook or Google Iame identity providers help keep your account secure because
you don't have to distribute or embed long term security credentials.
So remember, you've got your identity source, maybe active directory.
You use Samal to connect to your active directory and then you're able to have those user accounts,
login and access resources in Adewusi.
So to set it up, you create an Iame identity provider entity and that establishes a trust relationship
between your account, your account and the IDPs of the identity source, which could be active directory.
I supports IDPs that are compatible with either Open It Connects or Samal 2.0.
So moving on to the managed Microsoft Active Directory, this is a fully managed service on AYSO infrastructure.
You should use this when you have more than 5000 users or you have to set up a trust relationship.
It runs on windows.
You can perform schema extensions, works with many Microsoft applications, and you can set up trust
relationships to extend authentication from your own premises.
And so the actual managed back into your own premises so you can set up a trust relationship going between
those two entities on premise users and groups can then access resources in evea domain using single
sign on.
This requires a VPN or direct connect connection, and it can be used as a standalone active directly
in the cloud.
When used as a standalone active directory.
Users can also access third party applications such as Office 365 Free Federation, The Simple.
Now this is different to Microsoft and this is an inexpensive active directory compatible service.
So it's not Microsoft that's interaction, but it's compatible with it and has similar directory features.
It's a standalone, fully managed directory on the cloud, and it's generally the least expensive option
and best choice for less than five thousand users.
And if you don't need the advanced features of Microsoft, add it's actually powered by Sambor for Active
Directory compatible server.
And with this you can also create your own users and control access to applications on AWP, very similar
to the managed Microsoft ad, but it's sort of cheaper option.
And it provides only a subset of the features that you'll get with Microsoft active directory, but
that does include user accounts, groups, policies, Kerberos by single sign on and joining Linux and
Windows based instances.
So just a little more then we've got the ad connector.
This is a directory gateway for redirecting directory requests to your on premise.
It connects, eliminates the need for directory synchronization.
So it means that you don't have to have a domain controller from your active directory in the cloud,
which means you have to synchronize your credentials.
So the usernames and passwords into the cloud with add connect.
So you don't need to do that.
And it's also much simpler and cheaper than hosting a federation infrastructure.
So it connects to your on premise.
It's the best choice when you want to use an existing on premise active directory with services.
Now I say on premise, it could be also in SETI, but it's going to be a self managed Microsoft.
That territory comes in two sizes.
You've got the small four, up to five hundred users in the large four, up to five thousand.
And again, your VPC needs to be connected via VPN or direct connect when users log in to AYSO applications
and connected will then forward or proxy the sign in request to your on premise active every domain
controllers.
So just to go over these tables very quickly, remember Hédi Connector's, where you have an existing
active directory on premise and existing users need to be able to access resources in.
So ID Connector allows them to do that and it does support multifactor authentication.
And then simply this is the sort of cut down, cheaper version of Active Directory.
It does support user accounts, groups and policies and so on.
It does support Kerberos based single sign on.
You can also add your Linux or Windows machines to the domain.
But multifactor authentication is not supported.
Trust relationships are not supported.
And then remember the free use cases here.
So we've got your AWG directory service for Microsoft Adès, and that's when you have an enterprise
that once hosted Microsoft Active Directory in the cloud.
You then have add Kenexa for when your domain controller is on premises and then you have simplicity,
which is the sort of cutdown version of Active Directory, a sort of cheaper version that you can use
that has fewer features.