And Free Press on URL is a method of allowing access to users to a specific objects for a limited period
of time.
So maybe you have a certain group of users and they don't have IWC account, so you can't authorize
them that way.
But what you need to do is just give them a limited time access to some important update, a video or
whatever it might be.
So S3 priest signed URLs are a good choice there.
You can use the API or the SEELYE to create your free, free signed URLs so you might build an application
to do it automatically through the API.
Or what we're going to do in this hands on lesson is used to see a line.
And this is the command that you might issue.
So you literally run the command for free priest sign and then you give it the bucket name and the object
that you want to share, and that will generate the priest on URL, which will look something like this.
You can also specify the amount of time in seconds that you want this URL to be valid for.
Otherwise, it has a default, which I believe is about an hour.
So let's go to free and we'll see how we can create a priest signed URL.
So back in my DCT cloud storage bucket, I'm going to upload a file.
The file is known as Priest Sign Test or HD HTML.
It's in your course.
Download.
Let's add that file, and by default, we won't be able to access this publicly.
So if we just choose the file copy, the object URL, go to a new browser window and hit Enter.
And of course, we get an access denied.
Now we want to allow a certain number of users to access this particular objects.
So let's go and do that now.
Let's run a command using the Seelye and generate a priest signed URL back on the Seelye.
I've already created my command and I'm just pasting it in.
So the command is IWC as free priest sign as free colon slash slash, whatever your bucket name is,
slash and then the file name that we just uploaded.
And mine's going to expire in 60 seconds so I can show you that it's going to work and then it's going
to stop working again.
So let's say it ends up.
And you can see we get this massive URL.
We're literally going to copy all of this to my clipboard and back in my browser window.
I'm going to paste this in and hit enter.
And we can see that we can see this object.
The object is a simple HDMI file that gives us a quick message.
So that's a very simple way of creating a pre signed URL using the Seelye.
Now, of course, this one is time limited to 60 seconds.
So if I try and refresh now, let's see if we still got access.
And there you go.
I refreshed a couple of times and eventually I got an access denied after it is expired so we can see
the request has expired and gives us a bit of information on the expiry time for that precise and URL.
So that's it.
It's very simple to use pre signed URLs using the Seelye.