Hi, guys, the other type of VPN that we can establish in IWC is a site to site VPN, so a site to
site VPN is where you might connect, for instance, a customer data center or office location in the
IWC and have a private network established over the internet.
So an encrypted connection, which you can then tunnel through your traffic and again use internal IP
address, private IP addresses.
So the set up looks something like this.
We've got an IWC VPC on the left and then on the right hand side, we've got a corporate data center
that could be a data center or an office, and you want to connect that into IWC.
So a VPN is a managed IP SEC VPN.
And what we do is we create something called a virtual private gateway, which is also known as a V.W
on the IWC side.
The VW is deployed on the IWC and then a customer gateway is deployed on the customer side.
When you have those two components, you can then establish a encrypted VPN connection over the internet.
The VPN connection supports either static routes or BGP pairing and routing.
So in our roundtables, we can actually specify a destination for the side, a block of the corporate
data center and then points it to a virtual gateway I.D. So that's this device here.
So that means any traffic go into this IP range will be sent over the VPN connection.
So it's fairly straightforward.
And the most common use case for this is what we see here.
It's connecting in data centers or office locations to IWC so that you can then tunnel your traffic
over an encrypted connection using the incident.
It can also be used sometimes as a back up connection for Direct Connect, and we'll look at that later
on in this section.