Continuing on same crime with U.S. convicts.
Remember, this is a fully managed service that provides you with resource inventory, configuration,
history and configuration change notifications, which you can use for security and governance.
You can discover existing resources in your account and export a complete inventory of resources with
all configuration details.
Remember, this creates a configuration item for all the resources in your account, if you can figure
it to do so.
So this can be used for compliance, auditing, security analysis, resource change, tracking and troubleshooting
and allows you to assess, audit and evaluate configurations of your resources.
So remember, this is about keeping a record of all changes that are made to your resources and you
can do so historically.
So it creates a history of change control and what's been changed at any point in time.
And it's very useful, therefore, for configuration management as part of an Excel program.
Now, again, just to make sure you're clear on the difference between config and cloud trail cloud
trollers about user API activity on your account.
So it's about who did something config records, point in time configuration, details of your resources
as configuration items.
So as about the configuration, stay at a point in time.
So configures about saying what did my resource look like at a point in time?
What was its configuration?
Whereas Cloud Trail is about saying who made an API call to modify the resource, who deleted it, who
changed it?
And you're able to then track through API activity, who did what?
So those are the key differences that you need to know between config and cloud from.