Hello and welcome to the first architecture patterns lesson of the course.
What I'm trying to do with these lessons is take some of the knowledge that you've learned and put it
into the context of the type of scenarios you're going to see both in the exam and in the real world.
So imagine your solutions architects and you're working for some customers and those customers are saying
that you need to build a solution and they're going to present some specific requirements to you, present
some challenges that they're trying to deal with, and you've got to come up with the best solution
for the job.
That's the kind of thing that does come up in exam questions.
So I'm going to pose a few scenarios for you here and give you my idea of what the best solution would
be.
The first requirement is that a select group of users only should be allowed to change that IAM password.
So we don't want to let everybody change that Lam passwords, but we do want some privileged users to
be able to do so.
In this case, you can create a group for the users and apply a permissions policy that grants the IAM
Change Password API permission.
Moving on to the next requirement and Amazon EC2 instance must be delegated with permissions to an Amazon
Dynamo DB table.
Now, we haven't covered Dynamo DB yet, but it's another IWC service.
So how do you delegate permissions?
Well, you would create a role assign a permissions policy to the role that grants access to the Dynamo
DB database service.
A company has created that first IWC account.
They need to assign permissions to users based on job function.
That is a couple of things to note here.
Firstly, this company has created their first ever IWC account, so they may well not have very good
skills with IWC.
So what are the IAM best practices tell you?
In this scenario, will they suggest that you use the IWC managed policies and those can be aligned
with specific common job functions?
A solutions architect needs to restrict access to an AWB service based on the source IP address of the
requester.
Remember, we looked at some example policies.
You can create an IAM permissions policy and use the condition element to control access based on source
IP address, a developer needs to make programmatic API calls from a top U.S. ally.
In this case, you can instruct the developer to create a set of access keys and use those for any programmatic
access.
A group of users require full access to all Amazon to API actions.
Well, in that case, you could create a permissions policy that uses a wildcard for the action element
relating to and that would look like the easy to code on star action.
And that's it for this architecture patterns lesson.