Amazon FSx is a new storage service that provides fully managed third party file systems.
Now you'll see this coming up on the SAA-C02 exam and I had a few questions on my exam when I did the
beta.
Some of the design patterns that you'll associate FSx with are high performance computing, machine learning
and electronic design automation.
There are two different types of file system that are available today.
There's the FSx for windows file server and there's the FSx for Lustre for compute intensive workloads.
So let's have a quick look at each of these different types of FSx file system.
So this is the FSx for Windows file server.
And what you have is you can connect your Windows based application.
So for instance you might have two instances running Windows but you could also have on premises clients
running Windows connected over a VPN or direct connect connection and you can then talk to a file system
and that file system supports the native Windows file system features such as NTFS file systems and
ACLs, shadow copies and user quotas amongst other features and has access over the server message block
or SMB protocol.
So just as you would mount any other windows file system you're talking to over SMB, it's formatted
in NTFS and it offers you the same features of a native Windows file system.
Now it will automatically talk to an AWS managed Microsoft AD so you can configure your authentication
to happen from Microsoft AD.
And when we go through the wizard I'll show you how that's set up.
You can also set up multi AZ which means a standby is created in another availability zone.
I'm not showing that on the diagram but that's possible.
So that's the FSx for windows file server.
We then have the Amazon FSx for Lustre.
I'm not sure if I'm pronouncing that correctly because I haven't worked with this service before but this
is what it is. Now
the key thing that we'll notice here first off is that we have an S3 bucket.
This is key to know for the exam so you'll need to identify when to use FSx for Windows versus NSX for Lustre.
Now in this case you can have S3 objects in your bucket and they can actually be viewed as files
in the file system here and then you can perform your processing on that data and then write the data
back to S3. Just like with the FSx for Windows you can connect on premises clients over VPN or direct
connect connections and you can also use NSX the Lustre for cloud bursting and data migration so you
might be migrating your on premise data into the cloud or you might be bursting into the cloud when
you have that requirement to access extra capacity.
So that's basically what these two different types of file system are.
There's gonna be some more information in the exam cram at the end of the section and there's also lots
more information on the training notes and obviously the AWS website as well.
So make sure you do know these services especially if you're going into the SAA-C02 exam.
Now what we're going to do now is head over to the console and we're not going to set up a full implementation
like this because it would require quite a lot of resources and especially with the lustre you actually
have to provision quite a large chunk of storage.
So it could be expensive for you but I'm gonna show you where you create your FSx file systems and we'll
go into the wizard and have a look around and see what the options are.
So I'm in the AWS management console.
Let's go down to storage and choose NSX and we can simply choose create file system and first off let's
choose Windows File Server. So it says here that the Windows file server provides a fully managed native Windows
file system so you can easily move your Windows based applications that require file storage to AWS
and we can see some additional features here that I didn't mentioned before like distributed file
system so it supports that as well as the SMB protocol, the NTFS file system type and active directory
integration so let's just choose next and we can choose multi AZ or single AZ and this will depend
on your region for instance when I was connected to Sydney earlier.
I couldn't choose multi AZ. And you'll just give it a full system name.
So myFSx and then you can choose your file system size so let's just choose the minimum size here
and you can then choose where to place your endpoints for your file system so you can choose your VPC.
You can choose your security groups, it's selected one for us and you can choose one subnet in which the
file system's network interface will reside.
So just looking back on the diagram that's why I'm showing the FSx instance as being within an availability
zone or within a subnet.
If you want to have your file system available in multiple subnets then that's going to be the multi
AZ feature which means it's gonna be a standby that gets failed over but otherwise the end point
is going to be within a subnet you then get to choose whether you use a managed Microsoft AD.
And that's going to be like we have in the diagram here or whether you choose a self managed Microsoft
Active Directory and in that case you're going to have to just give the details supply the details for
your self managed Active Directory.
In this case you can choose a directory or you can just chooses to use this wizard to create the directory
and so we actually have to set that up.
I'm not going to set that up now but basically after that you'll then just complete the wizard and the
file system will be created and then you can take your applications and connect and mount that file
system.
So we're not going to go into that level of detail in this lab.
What I'm going to do now is just back down and we're going to go and have a look in the FSx for Lustre.
Let's just choose next and again I'm just going to put something in here.
And in this case you can see that the supported sizes are 1200 gigabytes or give your bytes or two thousand
four hundred or increments of thirty six hundred so you know it's got to be pretty big.
So we don't want to.
We don't we want to provision this but let's just put something in for now and again you can choose
your VPC your security group and you can choose the subnet in which the network interface will reside
and you can see there's a note here about allowing inbound traffic to TCP port 988.
It's encrypted at rest by default using this AES 256 block cipher and we just choose next.
It's not going to create anything yet but it's just going to give us that summary and you can see you'd
then create the file system so I wouldn't go ahead and do that because you're going to be basically
paying for some storage here that you really don't want to pay for.
So I will just back out of that but that's the FSx file system.
So again it's in a single subnet the network interface for the service will actually reside in one subnet
key exam point here.
The thing to remember is whenever you see S3 being mentioned and it looks like an FSx use case it's
gonna be NSX for Lustre.
And if it's SMB or if it's gonna be a Windows based application then it's going to push you to FSx for
Windows.