This is a lab about transfer acceleration as free transfer acceleration is a technology that you can
use to accelerate the transfer of objects that you're uploading into a bucket so if you have a lot of
latency between you and your bucket that can affect the transfer times when you upload data to your
bucket S3 transfer acceleration does is it
leverages the Amazon cloudfront network specifically the edge locations that are part of the cloud
front service.
So we haven't talked about the cloudfront service yet but as a content delivery network and there are
edge locations all over the world.
In fact if we have a quick look at this diagram from AWS it shows you the locations of the edge locations
where there are multiple locations where we've got the purple dots and regional edge caches as well
which are all part of the Amazon cloudfront network.
So they're in quite a few locations around the world with transfer acceleration you have different end
points so you may remember these end points from a previous lab and there are a couple of different
formats for the endpoints that you can use and they look a bit like this where you'd replace your region
name and your bucket name.
However with transfer acceleration the bucket name comes first and then you have dot s3 dash accelerate
and then there are two different end points here ones dual stack so that's the IPv6 whereas the other
one is for IPv4.
So you end up using a different endpoint to access and your data is uploaded to a cloudfront edge location
where whereas then forwarded onto your bucket.
Now that the benefits that you can get can really vary but we'll have a look at them in a minute and
they can vary from a small benefit or even no benefit to a huge benefit.
Multiple uploads can also be used with transfer acceleration so this can also be used where you have
large amounts of data or large files that you need to break up into pieces.
Now there is a charge so you will incur a cost.
So you really need to have a look and see how much benefit you're going to get from S3 transfer acceleration
before you start using it.
So coming over to the console here I just to go into a bucket and click on properties and if we come
down to advance settings we have transfer acceleration and that's the learn more link to give you a
bit more information and you can then enable or suspend.
So you can't actually disable this once you've enabled it.
You can only then go and suspend it.
You can also see here the end point for this bucket.
So we can now say that this would be the end point that you would use if you wanted to accelerate your
uploads.
So it doesn't mean that you can't still upload traditionally using the normal endpoint but you can also
choose to use this end point when you need to try and get some kind of benefit from the acceleration
and you can also have a look at the data transfer speeds here.
So if I click on this link it actually chooses then the local region where I am which is ap-southeast-2 and
it starts doing an upload and it gives you an S3 direct upload speed and then a transfer an accelerated
transfer upload speed so you can see what the benefit is sometimes takes a bit of time to populate.
So I actually have one running here and in this case it was using us-east-1.
So it's saying that from where I am which is Sydney it's six hundred ninety three percent faster to
upload using S3 transfer acceleration versus using S3 directly.
So that's huge.
And then we can come down and see all these different regions here and it shows us the benefit
so not a huge advantage if I was just transferring data from where I am now straight into the Sydney
data center.
But as you can see pretty much the farther you get away the better
but not always because London is quite a long way from here and that's that's not that's not a huge
advantage.
So so it varies a lot.
You really have to come in here and check out the benefit that you're going to get coming back here.
We could just enable this and click save but it's not really going to do much in terms of a lab so it
does cost money.
So I'm not going to bother doing that for this lab.
I just wanted to show you where it is.
You need to understand the circumstances where this might be useful.
So just remember if you have latency and your uploads are latency sensitive or that time sensitive so
you need to get that data into your bucket quickly and you will benefit financially or by some kind
of benefit to the business if you get that data out quickly that it might be worth spending the extra
money to ensure that your upload is quicker.
Couple of other notes about transfer acceleration as I said before it kind of cannot be disabled only
suspended.
Also you are actually only charged if there is a benefit but as far as I know that means if you get
some benefit whether it's a small benefit or not you'll be charged.
So you've got to work out if you do get a small benefit is it cost effective and just also remember
for the exam that you must use the correct endpoint to get the advantage.
So you have to use the extra accelerate endpoints.