We're now going to create a global tables configuration.
So if you remember from a couple of labs back or the lesson at the beginning of the dynamoDB part
of this section I discussed what global tables is.
So it's a multi region multi master database.
That means you can have a dynamoDB table that's replicated asynchronously around the world to different
regions and you're able to read and write to that database within those regions.
So you can have your users in whatever region.
This could be you know the U.S. you could have one in Australasia somewhere you can have one in South
America and your users are reading and writing to the database and it's the same database that they're
sharing and that data is being replicated.
And this comes with five nines of availability.
So it's pretty amazing very highly available very fast synchronization.
It is a synchronous replication but it uses the AWS as global backbone which is very high bandwidth
and low latency.
So this is what it looks like.
Let's go into the console and actually build the configuration out.
So what we're going to do is just create two regions and it's very simple.
We go in and create a table and I'm going to call this global table and we can choose a partition K
and then a name doesn't really matter.
We're not going to put any data into this table we're just going to create the configuration.
So my table is being created and I go to global tables and you'll notice that we have global table regions
here but you can't add a region because we haven't enabled streams yet.
So what we need to do is click here, enable streams, just choose enable.
And now we can go in and add our region.
So I'm going to choose Singapore and it will check that the regions locator deploy in C and then we
can click on continue
and that's really all there is to it.
It's really simple to create and we now have a table in these two regions which is being replicated
and you can see an IAM role here that's being used for the replication
and you can also look here at the replication latency and pending replication counts as well to see
you know what's outstanding so we can now just clean up this configuration by going into Singapore and
choosing remove region and we just need to confirm by typing remove
and then we can just go in and delete our table in the Sydney region
so that got rid of our table here in Sydney.
And now let's head over to the console and we can see that the table is still available so we removed
the configuration for replicating the tables but the table in the other region in Singapore actually
still exists.
So don't forget.
So as you go into your region don't confuse the removing it from replication with actually deleting
the table you still need to come in here and choose Delete table and that's really all there is to it.
It's really amazing how easy it is to create a multi region multi master database.
This is something that in the past would've taken months of planning and a really complex configuration
and the AWS cloud really allows us to create these complex configurations that under the hood are very
complex but very very easy to create in AWS.
So I hope you had some fun with DynamoDB and in the next lesson we're going to start going over
Elasticache.