In this lab we're going to talk about one of the newer features of rat 53 called Rat 53 resolve.
So this was released late in 2018 so it's been around for several months.
Will probably start appearing on the exam soon if it hasn't done already.
So Route 53 resolve aims to solve the problem of enabling seamless DNS resolution across hybrid cloud
environments.
So as in the diagram here some organizations will have their own private cloud or just a corporate data
center environment which they connect into a W S.
And so this is termed a hybrid cloud and they may have DNS servers on premises and then there's obviously
a DNS service within your VPC and there's about 50 free.
So what might happen is customers want to be able to resolve AWB specific records from machines within
their corporate datacenter.
And conversely they may be it needs to look up records that are hosted on the DNS server on premises
and you know the query might come from an easy to instance.
So this is done for around 50 free resolve using endpoints and they have outbound endpoints and inbound
endpoints.
So the way this works is you can figure this free Ralph 50 free.
You create an end point which creates an elastic network interface in each availability zone that you
place it in and then when you're easy to instance needs to query a record on the DNS server.
So let's say for instance your easy to instance might be an application that needs to send an email
and rather than using an AWP specific service it might want to use a mail server that's somewhere on
your on premise datacenter.
So it would then query the mail exchange Amex record.
Now that doesn't exist here because it's hosted on the DNS server on premises.
So what happens is the easy to instance connect around 50 free which says right we've got an outbound
endpoint and a rule which says that you can find the response to your query by going across the VPN.
And this could be a VPN or it could be a direct connect connection to the corporate data center DNS
server which will be able to respond to the query.
So that's how it works for outbound endpoints.
We then have the inbound endpoints.
So this is the reverse where you have a client or it could be a server or anything within your corporate
datacenter that needs to resolve a record that's hosted in the Amazon DNS or Ralph 53.
So in this case the client queries its own DNS server which has a forwarding role to say well for that
domain name you need to go to the IP address of the endpoint and that will then be routed across the
VPN or direct connect connection hit the inbound endpoint here which will then forward it's around 50
free for resolution so that's how that works.
Let's go back over to the console and we can search to find room 53 resolve.
Here it is
so if we come down in the console here it shows us some diagrams on how this works.
So it's a combination of the endpoints within the availability zones and then rules which determine
how traffic is forwarded for specific domain name spaces.
So let's go in and create a bit of a configuration.
We're not gonna be able to make a working configuration because we would need an on premise connect
on on premise environment that's connected via a VPN.
I don't have that at this point.
So but we can just walk through and see what the configuration would be.
So for instance you can create this inbound endpoint so I'm just going to call it my inbound endpoint
and then you choose your VPC and then you can choose a security group and then you choose your Availability
Zones and Amazon recommend that you have at least two Availability Zones so choose the AC.
I'm going to choose one of my private subnets allow NWS to choose the IP address themselves and then
have them to choose a different availability zone which also has a private subnet.
And I'm not going to tag at this point so I can just click submit and that's creating an inbound endpoint
and then we'll just do the same thing here.
I would just call this my outbound endpoint.
She's my BPC.
Just choose a security group.
Doesn't really matter because this isn't going to work.
Anyway we're not going to have a fully working configuration and again I'm just going to choose the
same availability zones
and click submit and that's really it.
That would just create those endpoints within those DP CS or within those Availability Zones with elastic
network interfaces and then the last thing to do then is to create the rules so we can go into this
wizard and this just call this my rule 1 and types can be forward or system.
In this case we're going to use forward.
So in this case maybe we've got a domain called DCT private dot com and we want resolution for this
domain to happen within our VPC
and we want to choose our outbound endpoint and then we want to specify the target.
So this could be your on premise DNS server and you can add to for redundancy or however many you want.
I'm not sure what the limit is but so you've added your on premise target IP addresses.
So what this is saying is it will forward traffic that's destined to DCT private dot com and it's going
to respond for queries that originate in the VPC and then it's going to send that traffic out via this
endpoint and the endpoint will forward using these IP addresses so these you are on premise DNS service
and click on submit and that's it.
And you know it's a very similar process for doing an inbound rule you.
This is very new so it may or may not be on the exam yet but just go through and have a play around
and try to understand what the use cases are for this.
So remember it's all about seamless integration of DNS between on premises and a W S environment.
So I think hybrid cloud and DNS and conditional forwarding those are the sorts of bits of language that
your hair when you read in your exam questions.
So yeah just read up on the service and hopefully you'll be fully prepared now I believe there is a
charge for using the service so you might want to go in and what you need to do is find you in your
rule you go to disassociate the VPC and just go to type disassociate.
Or I'm just going to copy it and submit and that can take a few minutes and then you can just go in
and delete your rule delete your inbound and outbound endpoints.