In this exam crime, I'm going to cover DNS caching and performance optimization, starting with Root
53.
Brown, 53, gives you domain name registry, DNS resolution and health checking of resources, and
it's located along side edge locations.
53 becomes the authoritative DNS server for registered domains and will create a public hosted zone
for you with private DNS that lets you have an authoritative DNS server within your sees.
Without exposing or DNS records, you can transfer existing domains to Route 53 if the top level domain
is supported.
You can also transfer domain from Route 50 free to another registrar, but you have to contact IWC support.
You can transfer a domain to another account in IWC, but that doesn't migrate the zone by default.
You can also have a domain registered in one IWC accounts and the hosted zone in another IWC accounts.
So a hosted zone is a collection of records for a specified domain.
There are two types public hosted zone for routing traffic on the internet and a private hosted zone
for your VPC, which helps to route traffic within your VPC.
Now, remember that routing in this case is DNS resolutions.
What we're talking about is finding out the address of a destination so we can connect to it.
It's not IP routing the private hosted zones.
You must set the following BPC settings to true enable DNS hostname and enable DNS support.
With health checks, these check the instances health by connecting to it, and you can point health
checks on endpoints, the status of other health checks and the status of a cloud watch.
Alarm endpoints can be IP addresses or domain names.
There are two types of record sea name and ideas which come up in exam questions a lot, so it's useful
to understand the difference.
We've seen a Route 53 charges for queries.
You can't create a name record at the top node of DNS namespace, and that's the key exam set there.
So if you have the domain namespace example dot com, you can't create a C name, for example dot com,
but you can, for example, dot com because that's a subdomain.
So not the zone apacs.
A C name can point to any DNS record hosted anywhere with aliases.
Ralph, 53, doesn't charge for queries to AWG resources.
You can create an alias record at his own apex, which is what you can't do with C names as a key difference.
An alias record can only point to cloud front Elastic Beanstalk LP S3 buckets configured as static websites.
Also another record in the same hosted zone.
Now he went free routing policies in quite a bit of detail in the course.
Remember, Simple is just a name to an IP address.
Failover is where you can fail over to a novel resource when your primary resource goes down and that's
based on health checks.
Geo location is routing you to the closest geographic region, and proximity gives you a bit more control
about routing to the closest region within a certain geographic area.
Licensee is about reducing latency, directing you to the closest resource.
Multi Value Answer returns several IP addresses, so it's almost like a load balancing function, and
it uses relative weights like 80 percent to one record and twenty to another.
Amazon cloud run is the seed again, as we know for caching content around the world.
You can define a maximum time to live and a default TCL for records, and those are defined at the behavior
level and cloud front.
This can be used to define different skills for different file types, so you could have a different
time to lift your pages versus your JPEGs.
After exploration, Cloud Front checks the origin for any new requests.
Headers can be used to control the cache, so you've got the cache control max age in seconds, and
that specifies how long before cloud fun gets the objects again from the origin server and then expires,
which specifies an expiration time and date.
You can also cache based on request headers.
You can configure cloud funds with forward headers in the viewer.
Request to the Origin Cloud run can then cache multiple versions of an object based on the values in
one or more request settings, and that's controlled in a behavior to do one of the following forward
all headers to your origin, which means the objects are not cached for the whitelist of headers that
you specify or forward only the default headers, and then it doesn't cache the objects based on values.
In the request, headers then got signed, URLs and cookies was signed your URLs.
These provide more control over access to content.
You can specify the beginning and expiration date and time and IP addresses or ranges of IP addresses
for users with sign cookies that similar to signed URLs.
And you can use these when you don't want to change URLs, and they can also be used when you want to
provide access to multiple restricted files as a key difference.
A signed your URL is for a single object, whereas if you want multiple objects to be included, then
you should use sign cookies.
We then have lambda at edge.
This is where you run Node.js and Python lambda functions to customize the content that cloud front
delivers, and it executes the functions closer to the view of a better performance.
You can run Landore edge at the following points off the cloud front receives a request from a viewer
that's called a viewer request before cloud run forwards.
The request to the origin that's an origin request off the cloud front receives the response from the
Origin Origin response.
And lastly, before cloud forwards, the response to the viewer and that's called the viewer response.
And that's it for this example.