AWS global accelerator is a new service and it's one that's going to come up in the SAA-C02 exam.
And I saw it quite a lot in my beta exam.
I think two or three questions you had it as an answer or had it as a distractor so an incorrect answer.
So you definitely need to know what it is.
And it's also quite an exciting service as well.
So it's one that you might find really useful in certain scenarios in your
work as a solutions architect.
So AWS global accelerator is a service that improves the availability and performance of your applications
with local or global users so it provides static IP addresses that act as a fixed entry point to your
applications in single or multiple AWS regions such as ALBs and NLB's and EC2 instances. So that
means you get static IP addresses which are fixed IP addresses that you can use to direct users to applications
in multiple regions.
And we'll see what this means in the diagram shortly as well.
So I've got a diagram and we're also going to do a hands on. Global Accelerator also uses the AWS global
network and that optimizes the path for users to applications.
And it does TCP and UDP traffic so what this means is that global accelerator is actually going
to direct traffic over the AWSs' network.
So when you go and hit an endpoint for Global Accelerator you're actually hitting in the cloudfront
network which means that there's the cloudfront edge locations around the world.
Your being directed to an edge location and then from there your traffic no matter what region is
going to is going to go through the global network.
So that means you're not using the Internet so you're not subject to the potential latency issues that
can occur on the Internet especially over long distances when you're failing your application between
regions.
So let's have a look at what this looks like.
So in this diagram we have users and these users are in the US and what they need to do is they need
to connect to an application that's running on the domain name dctlabs.com.
So what they're going to do firstly is they punch that into their browser and they try to connect to
this web application and what they need to do first is resolve the IP address for dctlabs.com and
we're going to use Route 53 for that.
So they send a request, Route 53 then responds with two IP addresses.
Now these IP addresses are static anycast IP addresses and that means there can be multiple hosts behind
these IP addresses but all you're ever going to see for your application is these two IP addresses.
So let's say that you have users around the world and you have customers potentially and they need to
whitelist IP addresses in order to be able to connect to the application that you're providing
for them.
These are the two addresses they're going to need to use.
Nothing else it doesn't matter where they are in the world.
So that's really useful.
It also means when we have a failover between different regions, so our application endpoints in different
regions, these IP addresses don't need to be changed and that in the client's browser.
So they'll be cached in the client's computer on their browser and it doesn't matter because normally
you have to worry about how long it's going to take for those cached entries to expire before the browser
or the computer needs to go and do another look up to find out some new IP addresses.
In this case the IPs don't change.
So that's not an issue.
So what happens next is these IP addresses are associated with Edge locations so the users get directed
to a cloudfront edge location and that then connects them to the AWS Global Accelerator which forwards
them to dctlabs.com.
In this case in the us-east-1 the user is now connected to the application running in us-east-1.
So what happens if this application fails.
So let's say the application has failed and the user now needs to connect to another version of your application.
Another instance of your application running somewhere else in the world.
So what happens is AWS Global Accelerator will direct the users straight to dctlabs.com
in
In this case eu-central-1.
Now it's the same IP addresses the IP addresses haven't changed the browser cache doesn't need to change
and the traffic is going over the global network.
So even though their users are in the US and the application is now in Europe the traffic is going via
the AWS global network.
That means it's very fast and very low latency.
Let's head over to the console now and we're going to build out a architecture very similar to this
one.
And what we're going to have is we're going to have an application endpoint running in two locations
probably both in the US but you'll see how this works what we're going to do now is go over to the as
management console and we're going to build a solution very similar to this.
I'll probably have instances both running in the US but in different regions within the US and otherwise
this is going to be very much the same and it will assign some different IP addresses as well they're
automatically assigned when you create the Global Accelerator.
So let's head over to the console and build this out.