Hi guys we're going to talk about ElastiCache now ElastiCache is a fully managed service that gives
you two popular in-memory data stores once called Memcached and the others called Redis and you use
ElastiCache in situations where you want to improve latency and throughput for read heavy applications
or compute intensive workloads. There's a few key differences between memcached and Redis and redis
also has two different modes that you can deploy it in cluster-mode customer disabled or cluster mode enabled
and what I want to do is go through these with you today because the key differences between these engines
are likely to come up in exam questions. So firstly with memcached you don't get any data persistence
so it's a pure in memory caching service. With Redis you do in both modes. Memcached is used for
simple data types whereas Redis can be used for complex data types. with memcached you get partitioning
so that is you have multiple nodes and each node has a partition of your data. With Redis it's cluster
mode disabled you don't you have a single partition essentially with multiple replicas of it whereas
we have cluster mode enabled you now have what's called shards and each shard is a partition of your
data with a bunch of replicas and I'll show you some diagrams and we're going to build this out so you
understand fully there's no replication out of options with memcached each node is an individual partition
of your data whereas we've read this there is replication and this is done between so you have multiple
shards and then you have replication to replicas within each shard you can't do any kind of high availability. With
memcached You can place nodes in different phases but these are again partitions of your data so if
you lose a node you lose the data that's on that node. With Redis you can have replication and you
can have also failover
for scaling with memcached you scale up by increasing the node size and out by adding nodes. With Redis
you add shards and shards can have replicas. Now with a redis cluster mode disable you can only have
a single shard.
So all you can do is add replicas whereas with Redis cluster mode enabled you can add shards and
each of those shards can have replicas. memcached is multi threaded whereas redis isn't, you don't
get any backups with memcached.
So again in scenarios where nodes fail or AZs fail whichever partitions are affected that's where you're
going to lose your data.
Whereas we've redis you can you have automatic and manual snapshots.
So let's have a look at a couple of diagrams so this makes a bit more sense so here's memcached you
have a memcached cluster and you have multiple Availability Zones and then you deploy nodes and each
of these is a partition of data.
And like I say that's no persistence and there's no replication each node contains a piece of data and
you can have those across multiple databases.
Of course if you lose a node you lose whatever data is on it.
This is the the cache. With Redis you have shards and with cluster mode disabled.
You have one shard that shard can have a primary and then multiple replicas so you're writing to the
primary and then replicating to the replicas. Those replicas can be in multiple places and you can fail
over to your replicas and that can take place automatically.
We then have elasticache readers with cluster mode enabled.
And in this case you have multiple shards.
So each shard is a partition of data and each shard will have a primary node and then multiple replica
nodes or it can have none.
They can have zero replica names or can have up to five replica nodes and those replicas can be across
Availability Zones.
Another thing I'd recommend is having a look on the AWS Web site.
There's some great information on here where you can see the differences between the engines and that
will give you a bit more insight.
But the key things that we need to know for the exam are covered on this table here and what we're going
to do in the next couple of labs is actually just build a couple of clusters on elasticache.