Hi guys and welcome to another exam cram so we're starting off with the elastic block store.
EBS volumes on network attached storage that you attach to your EC2 instances.
And the data is persistent.
So remember it exists independently of your EC2 instance you don't have to attach a volume to an
instance.
The data can be stored in any EBS volume without being attached to anything.
You can attach multiple volumes to an instance.
You cannot attach a volume to multiple instances though.
For that you'd want to use your the elastic file system. EBS volume data is replicated across multiple
servers in an availability zone.
Volumes must be in the same AZ as the instances that you want to attached and to group EBS volumes
are deleted on termination by default.
Whereas anything extra you add is not deleted by default.
So the behavior can be changed by altering the delay on termination attributes. Instance stores are for
temporary non-persistent block level storage.
So this is different to EBS. EBS is persistent storage but it is also a block storage system. An instance store can
be a root device or an additional volume, it's located on disks that are physically attached to the
host computer.
So you get really high performance. Use cases are for temporary information that changes frequently
so you might think buffers and caches and scratch data or other temporary content or for data that's
replicated across a fleet of instances.
Watch out for exam questions here.
I've noticed instance store coming up a bit more often now and the type of scenario where it's really
good is you might need some really high I/O some really high storage performance and the data is replicated
across multiple instances.
So every instance has a full copy of the data.
In that scenario an instance store makes sense.
Also one of the reasons why it makes sense is because if you're provisioning that type of instance that
comes with an instance store the instance store volume is part of the cost of the EC2 instance.
So you're not paying extra for the storage.
The instance type that you choose determines the size of instance store available and the type of hardware
used for the instance store volume so it's included as part of the instance's usage costs.
So you're paying for the volume as part of the EC2 instance.
So you're not paying extra so for instance the alternative might be that you put data on provisioned
IOPS (EBS) and provision a very high I/O that might cost a lot more than using an instance store and you'd
have to make that evaluation on a case by case basis. So comparing EBS with instance store, EBS means
that the volume is less volume and the storage is persistent.
An instance store backed means the root volume's and instance store volume and the data is not persistent.
Instance store backed instances cannot be stopped.
If the underlying host fails the data will be lost. Instance store volume root devices are created from
AMI templates stored on a S3 whereas EBS backed instances can be stopped and you won't lose the
data.
And EBS volumes can be attached and reattached to different instances.
The EBS root devices are launched from AMIs that are backed by EBS snapshots.
So they sit S3.
Instance store volumes cannot be detached or reattached.
If you reboot the instances for both volume types data doesn't get lost.
So even with an instance store if you reboot the instance data is not lost.
But if you stop the instance it is lost.
Now here's a table that describes the different type of EBS volumes that are available.
I'm not going to go through all of this but just make sure you're aware of the differences.
Make sure you're aware of the use cases as well.
So you've got provisioned IOPS which is where you can specify the amounts of I/O that you want the amount
of performance. You've got the general purpose and these are both SSD and then these are the hard disk drive
options the throughput optimized or the cold. EBS snapshots capture a point in time state of an instance
or specifically of an EBS volume. They're an easy backup strategy and you can also use them to migrate
a system to a different availability zone or region.
You can also use a snapshot to convert an unencrypted volume to be an encrypted volume.
Snapshots are stored on S3.
They're not a granular backup solution so if you need folder and file level backup then don't use snapshots.
Even though snapshots are actually incremental,
so each one is incremental and stores the change data from the previous snapshot.
You actually only have to retain the most recent one to restore the volume in full. Snapshots
can only be accessed through the EC2 API.
EBS volumes remember are AZ specific but snapshots are region specific because they're stored on S3.
EBS you can encrypt the boot and data volumes of an EC2 instance. When you create an EBS volume
that's encrypted and attach it to the right instance type you can encrypt data at rest inside the volume
but also all data moving between the volume and the instance because remember EBS volumes are attached
over a network.
All that data is also encrypted and any snapshot you create will also be encrypted and any volumes you
create from those snapshots will be encrypted. So encryption is supported by all EBS volume types.
You can expect the same IOPS performance on encrypted as unencrypted. All instance families support
encryption as well. So the AMIs are the Amazon machine images and these are what specify the information
about the EC2 instance that you're all going to launch so they include a template for the root
volume.
They include launch permissions and a block device mapping that defines what volumes are attached to
the instance when it's launched and these can be even instance store backed or EBS backed. You can copy
AMIs within or across an AWS region using the command line the management console, SDKs or the
EC2 API.