Welcome to the architecture patterns, the DNS caching and performance optimization.
So let's have a look at the first requirement an elastic load balance must be resolvable using a company's
public domain name, around 50 free hosted zone already exists.
Well, in this case, you can create an alias record that maps the domain name to the LP, and you must
use an alias here rather than the C name.
Remember, C name can be used for a subdomain.
But in this case, it's not a sub domain and it's mapping to an LP.
A website runs across to AWG regions.
All traffic goes to one region and should be redirected only if the website is unavailable.
Well, in that case, you can create a fail over routing policy and Route 53 and configure health checks
on the primary.
Websites run in several countries and distribution rights require restricting access to content based
on the geographic source of the connection.
Well, in this case, you can use Route 53 geo location routing and restrict distribution based on geographic
location.
A cloud front distribution has multiple S3 origins.
Requests should be served from different regions based on file type being requested.
Well, here you can use a behavior and configure a path pattern that you do that within your distribution
content is accessed using an application and cloud front distribution.
You need to control access to multiple files on the distribution for this solution.
You can configure signed cookies and then update the application so it processes those cookies.
An application runs behind an application load balancer in multiple regions.
You need to intelligently route traffic based on latency as well as availability.
For this, you can create an IWC global accelerator and add the albee's and that's it for this lesson.