Hi guys.
In this lab we're going to get a bit deeper into the application load balancer listeners and SSL tier
less.
So what I want to do is show you how we can create multiple listeners and have multiple target groups
sitting behind them.
So there's a few things on the slide which are worth noting.
The first is we have two listeners here and there on different ports.
One is a secure port.
One is and now you can only have one listener per port number you can't have multiple listeners with
port four for free.
So on the front end you have to have unique ports.
However you can connect to target groups on the back end that have the same port number.
So that means your instances can be listening on port 80 and be in type in multiple target groups that
are attached to the same load balancer and even the same listener.
Now you also notice that one instance here is kind of between two target groups.
That's because it's part of both.
So an instance can be in multiple target groups.
We then have the rules here and the rules that we're going to set up in this lab are going to be that
we on our secure listener have a default rule that takes us to instance one.
But then if we put in shop dot DCT labs dot coms this will be DCT labs dot com and this will be shopped
or DCT labs dot com.
If you put that into the URL the host based routing condition will forward the traffic to target group
to you and it should be out a cycle between instance to an instance free.
Alternatively if you use the unsecure port port 80 it's going to pick it up on a different listener
and that listener is going to forward on to target group free.
So we're going to set up this exact configuration including the SSL TALF certificates and I'm going
to show you how to generate those as well.
So that's enough for the fairy.
Let's get into the console and start building this out.
The first thing we need to do is actually create a certificate for use with our load balancer.
Now I mean the AWB certificate manager you can find this by typing in certificate and you'll find certificate
manager here.
It's under security identity and compliance.
What I'm gonna do is click get started.
Request a public certificate.
I'm gonna put in DCT lamps dot com and click next and then going to choose the email validation option
and choose review and confirm and request I'll continue.
And then what I want to do is request another certificate and this one is going to be shop DCT labs
dot com and again I'll use email validation.
So what I need to do now is actually go to my email and there'll be an email that's waiting for me where
I need to click a link to validate my certificate.
And that really just proves that I have ownership of the domain DCT labs dot com.
So this is the email I received and all I need to do is click on the link here to approve the request
and then ask me to approve.
So I get a click I approve and that's it it's done.
I've also got another e-mail for the shop that DCC labs dot com certificate.
So I'm just gonna go and do that now.
So I only took a few seconds and one side approved both of those requests.
I've now got my certificates issued so I can go back to easy too.
And we're going to set up our load balancer.
Now before we do that let's actually get our instances running.
So I'm going to create a auto scaling group and I'm going to use four instances t to micros gonna call
my launch configuration LC 1 gonna use my I role for S3 full access and then I'm going to put in this
code same code that you've seen before.
Again it's always in the course downloads for each section.
So just grab that code and paste it in and it's gonna give a name to our instance on a web page so I
can click Next figure security group I'm going to choose web access and create my launch configuration
now for the auto scanning group again I'm going to just call it ASG one I'm going to use four instances
and I'm going to put those across two availability zones.
It doesn't matter and we're not testing cross so no balancing or anything like that.
So we can just collect configure screening policies keep it over its initial size and just go through
and click review and crazy also scaling group.
So that will be our instance is being created.
Now let's go and create our load balancer.
I'm going to create an application load balancer again it's just going to be called My Alby now for
the listener.
Paul I want to have two listeners so I'm going to also add my hasty CPS listener.
We put instances in AP SD to a to b so I'm going to choose those two subnets and now I need to choose
my cert so you can choose a certificate from AWB cert manager.
That's where we just created our certificate a few minutes ago or you can upload one chooses to forgive
him.
I am or uploads a certificate to I am.
In this case I'm going to choose one of my available certificates and it's going to be shopped at these
t labs dot com.
So actually what I want to do is I want shopped at these d labs dot com to be my secure site.
There isn't an option to configure the security policy.
I'm just gonna leave it on the most recent security policy that's selected by default.
I'm going to choose my web access security group and then I'm going to create a new target group called
G1 and I'm just going to change my healthy threshold to 2 and everyone else can stay as it is just to
keep reusing skills.
I'm not going to add these to registered.
What I'm gonna do is just create my load balancer and while that's provisioning what I want to do is
go to my instances I should have for running instances and I'm just going to label these.
So it's going to be instance one instance to instance for a and instance for so we can now go back to
are load balancer and what I want to do is configure the listener.
So we now have two listeners once listening on port 80 and one's listening on hasty CPS four for free.
Now what I want to do is create two additional target groups so if you remember from the diagram two
of them are going to lessen on port 80 and note that we have port four for free on the front end but
poor 80 on the back end.
So secure in the front but then it's unsecure.
Whereas in this side it's unsecure on the front but secure on the back and I really set it up like this
just so that you can see the different combinations.
We're not actually going to set up a certificate on instance for because that would mean going into
the instance and having to upload the cert files but outside of the scope of the course.
But I just want to show you that you can have 80 on the front unsecure and then secure on the back end
or the reverse combination.
So let's get into the console now and we're going to set this up.
First thing I need to do is just create my other target groups.
So let's create C.G. to first thing we need to do is create our target groups.
So we're going to create T2 and this is going to listen on port 80 again healthy fresh I was going gonna
be 2 and then this target group free.
So it's cool that C G free and in this case what we want to do is listen on port four for free the hasty
TPA secure port.
Now of course what this means is you need a certificate on the actual instance itself.
So we're not gonna do that we're just I'm just showing you how we can figure this out click on Create
and that's our free target groups.
We now need to add our instances to our target groups.
So let's go into target group 1.
And we want to add instance one and instance to the target group to we're going to add instance to an
instance free and the target group free.
We're just going to add instance four.
So there we've got all our instances registered to our target groups.
Now what we need to do is go to the load balancer and set up the listeners.
If I try to add an additional listener on port 80 it tells me that I can't have duplicate load balance
supports the same for hasty CPS but we could then change it.
So for instance we could have another listener in port 81 and that would be fine but we've got our two
listeners what I need to do is edit them so that they reflect the diagram that we saw before in our
diagram we have a secure listener which is forwarding to target group 1 and target group 2.
So you got shocked DCT lamps dot com here and we've got DCT nabs dot com going through the default rule.
So let's see how we can set this up.
The first thing I want to do is add an additional cert so if you go view edit certificates you'll see
that you have the option to add additional certificates so I can click the plus here and it shows me
the available certificates.
So I'm going to select the DCT lapsed dot com certificate and click add.
Now what this means is we've got two certificates and they have different DNS names.
So an application load balancer can use what's called server name indication.
And that means that it can select a certificate based on the name that is presented as part of the url.
So it will know to use DCT lapsed dot com or shopped or DCT labs dot com depending what the host name
is in the URL.
Now the other thing I want to do is I actually should have my DC labs dot com as the default rather
than shopped at DCT labs dot com.
So let's just go back and what we can do is edit the listener and I'm just going to change to DCT labs
dot com and click update.
So now that's my default.
Let's head back and just go into view edit certificates and we've now got these t labs dot com as the
default and I need to go back in and just add shocked that these steel labs dot com again.
So we've now got both fast difficult selected what we need to do next is edit the actual rules so we
can go to view edit rules and we can see here that requests will be forwarded to target group 1 but
what we want to do is add a rule with a host had a condition that says if the host header is shop dot
DCT lamps dot com and wanting to forward it to target group 2.
So that's that what we should have now is a single secure listener running on port four for free.
We've got two rules we've got the default rule and we've got the default certificate which are both
going to take anyone that tries to go to DCC labs dot com to target group 1 if they try to go to shop
of these t labs dot com the conditional host based rule will forward them to target group to where we
have instance to an instance free.
The only other thing we need to do is just edit our rule for target group free.
So let's have a look at our other listener and we just need to change the rule in here.
We need to collect the pen icon here to edit and then the pen here as well.
And then we can just go and remove that option and add another action to forward to target group free.
So we should now be set up exactly as in this diagram.
Now as I mentioned we're not going to be able to connect a target group free because we don't have a
certificate on the back end and we configured HDTV yes but we will be able to connect to target group
1 and target group 2.
And if we put in DCC labs dot com we'll go to target group 1 and if we put in shopped these t labs dot
com we'll go to target group 2.
Now of course there's one more important thing we need to do we need to go across to Route 53 and we
need to set up our DNS records.
So let's go and find Ralph 50 free and I'm going to go into my DC livestock on hosted zone and try to
couple of record sets.
So the first one is going to be the DCT labs dot com and this is going to be the zone apex.
So there's nothing to write in the name you choose alias and then we choose our MLP and create and then
we create another record set.
And this one is gonna be for shop that DEA labs dot com.
It's also an alias.
And it also goes to the B.
So that's set we're set up now and let's try and go to DCT labs dot com and we need to do so with a
secure connection and there we go.
So we get a response and the name of the instance is called Resa and if we try and cycle we're going
to hit Bonita and Rita.
So we've got two instances and they should be instance one an instance two in our diagram.
Let's now try and go to shop dot DCT labs dot com and this time we get Marietta and if we now cycle
we get Marietta and Benita remember Benita was in Target group 1 and target group 2 whereas Marietta
is just in target group 2.
So this is behaving exactly as we expected to in this diagram.
We've got Risa and Benita and then we've got Marietta.
I hope you had a lot of fun in this lab guys and everything worked okay for you.
Let me know if it didn't or reach out on the forums we're finished with this configuration for now.
So we can go back in and remove everything.
So I'll just show you how to go and clean up.
Remember to remove your records from Route 53 and this is important if you're going to be running other
labs because it means that your records deleted and they get removed from your cash.
And then next time you try and create a record you shouldn't have any problems with actually getting
resolution working straight away.
Now we need to go and delete our load balancer.
We can get rid of all of these target groups.
We can delete our auto scaling group and our launch configuration and that should mean that our senses
are shutting down.
But if not just go in there and terminate your instances.
And I said for this lab guys in the next lab I'm going to show you a common use case where we have a
public facing application load balancer.
So in Internet facing application load balancer but we have instances in a private subnet I'll show
you how to set that up.