I'm in the AWS management console.
Let's go to services and we go down to networking and content delivery and choose Global Accelerator.
So before we start configuring global accelerator what we need to do is launch our instances so all
application endpoints.
The first one I'm going to do is in U.S. West 1 North California.
And what I'm going to do is launch an instance it's gonna be a Linux 2 AMI.
It will be a T2 micro and I'm going to put in this user data.
So what I'm going to do here is all I'm gonna do is just update this to us west 1.
So this instance is in us west 1.
And that's that's basically what's going to be on the index.html when we connect to this web
server.
So let's us know which endpoint we're connecting to and let's just go through to security groups.
I need to give it web access which in this case all I need is port 80.
Let's launch and now we're going to do the same with us east 1 .
So Linux 2 AMI.
And then let's put in us W to into this user data and again just make sure you've got a inbound rule
for Port 80 your security group.
And that instance is now going to launch so we can go to our accelerator just before I do that.
I want to search for eight AWS Global Accelerator rates pricing and let's just have a look at the pricing
for global accelerator.
Now I don't know if there's any credits for the free tier but what you will see here there's a fixed fee
for every hour you have an accelerator running and that's $0.025
hour.
The other component of the pricing is the per gigabyte pricing so how much data you put through accelerated.
So we're really not going to generate much traffic at all.
It's gonna be kilobytes if anything.
So I wouldn't worry too much about this pricing but you will pay a small fee for each hour that you
have you accelerator running.
So just remember to disable your accelerator at the end of the lab.
So let's go and create our accelerator.
Now I'm just gonna call this my accelerator choose next.
We create a listener it's gonna be port 80 HTTP.
It's gonna be TCP.
You can choose to set up client affinity but we don't need that for now.
And we now need to set up our region.
So the first one was US West 1.
And we're also going to set up US West to now the traffic dial controls how much traffic you send to.
Different regions.
So it's kind of like a waiting and you say I want to send this amount to this region and this amount
to this region.
Now we're not going to change that.
So what that will mean is you would be directed to the region that's healthy.
That's closest to you choose next.
And we can now go and add our endpoints and you can choose from an ISP and it'll be an EC2 instance
or an elastic IP so let's choose EC2 and let's find our endpoint.
So you can see that the instance we just created is actually present here.
And as you can see you have a wait here and the dial that we looked to in the previous screen that controlled
how the traffic is sent to the region but then within a region you can have a weight assigned to each
instance that you have.
Now we've only got one instance in each group so that doesn't matter so we'll just leave it as default.
I'm going to set up my EC2 instance endpoint in U.S. West 2 and there's one EC2 instance and
that's all we need to do.
So we can just create the accelerator.
Now just close that out.
I did delete an accelerator that I set up a few minutes ago and we can now see that our latest accelerator
has been created and it's an in progress status but straight away we can see that we have our static
IP addresses.
So these IP addresses even one of these will direct you to whichever endpoint is...
that has to be healthy but is closest to you unless you have those dials set in some kind of way
to deliberately control traffic one way or the other.
Now while this is being set up what I want to do is just go to Route 53 open this in a new tab and
I'm going to set up those records in Round 53. So I'm just going to copy these IP addresses we've
got Route 53 go to hosted zones and choose dctlabs.com and I'm gonna create a record
set.
Now if you haven't registered a domain name just use the IP address as you don't have to do this.
But I just want to set it up anyway to make this look like a more complete solution.
So I'm gonna leave this blank up here because I just want the name to be dctlabs.com.
It's gonna be an A type of address that means resolving a domain name to an IP address and we're going
to put these IP addresses on separate lines.
Now we're just going to leave as simple routing policy that means that we'll use round robin.
So it will sort of basically give even these as a response and it kind of just cycle through let's choose
create and now we have our record set.
So that took a few minutes and the accelerator is now showing is being deployed.
And if we just click on accelerator here we can see that we have our end points in U.S. West 1 in and
U.S. West 2 and they're all healthy.
That's great.
So we've got Route 53 set up with the IP addresses of the Global Accelerator.
So what we should be able to do now is let's just go to http:/dctlabs.com and we get
directed to the instance in the US West 1.
So that's great.
We know that we've set up Route 53 properly.
We've set up our Global Accelerator our global accelerator has an endpoint which is healthy and we've
connected to that endpoint so going back to our diagram this is basically where we're at.
We have a couple of IP addresses we resolve dctlabs.com to those IP addresses and we've connected
to an endpoint in our case it's us West 1.
Now what we want to do now is simulate the failure of one of those instances so that we then get directed
to our other instance or other application endpoint just like in the diagram here.
So let's go back and we're gonna terminate one of the EC2 instances so that we then get a fail
over.
So I'm in us west 1 and what I'm gonna do is this is my instance I'm just going to terminate my instance
and choose terminate and so that instance is no longer available if we come back and refresh the screen
we can say it's kind of timing out because there is a period of time by the full it's maybe 30 seconds
for the health checks.
So the global accelerator needs to identify that the endpoint is unhealthy before it starts routing
traffic to the other end point.
So if we head back in and have a look at our accelerator we can see the endpoints are still all healthy.
So just refreshing to make sure that that's current.
Now once we see that at least one endpoint is unhealthy in this case it will only be one endpoint then
at that point the Global Accelerator will direct us to the other endpoint so we can now see that we
have an unhealthy endpoint.
And if we just look ahead into the listener and going to US West 1 and we can see that US West 1 is
definitely unhealthy.
So let's go back and refresh our page.
And now we go to the instance in US West 2.
So that's exactly what we're expecting in the lab.
We've basically gone from this point where we had one healthy instance and that healthy instance then
became unhealthy and using the same IP addresses.
We then were redirected to the second instance.
So that's the way global accelerator works.
Just remember this is really good when you want to static ip addresses so even the question in the exam
might say something like you need to be out a white list to IP addresses only and you want to be at
a fail over between endpoints in different regions.
That's where a global accelerator is really good.
Another way it's really great is that it directs traffic over the AWS global network.
So wherever you hear about having multiple endpoints and you need to reduce the latency between them
then because it's using edge locations and the global network then it's actually lowering the latency
for that traffic to your endpoints in different regions.
So those are the kind of things that might come up in the exam.
Now let's just head back one more time to the console because what we need to do now is just go back
in and delete our accelerator.
Let's go back up to accelerators and going to choose the accelerator and delete and you have to click
on disable and then that takes a few seconds while that's happening.
I've got to go and terminate my second instance.
So just don't forget to clean this all up that's done ran 50 free.
It's just a matter of deleting the record you know going to pay for that anyway and then once the accelerator
is disabled you can go back in and choose Delete.
So I hope you enjoyed that.
The AWS Global Accelerator is something that's definitely going to be showing up on the SAA-C02
version of the exam.
So make sure that you are fully aware of what it is and how it works before you sit the exam.