Hi guys.
We're in the Elasticache dashboard and we're going to create a cluster using Memcached.
Now one of the things I want to mention about Alaska cash is it's quite different to DynamoDB DAX which
we covered a couple of labs ago DynamoDB Dax automatically connects to your DynamoDB tables to
cached data.
So it's really easy you just set it up you can point your application at the Elasticache excuse me
at the DynamoDB Dax endpoints and then it will automatically pull data form your DynamoDB database
as long as it has the right information in the request and it has the access it's a bit different with
Elasticache and you really need to program your application to take advantage of the caching service.
So it's not as easy as saying well let's just connect a database to Elasticache.
You actually have to create it in your code.
So what we're going to do in these labs is just build out the databases so we're going to provision
them so that you can see through the console the various options that are available and understand the
differences between Memcached and Redis.
So let's click Create and Australia where we get two different options and we have readers and we have
the cache nodes.
So for Redis it says it's an in-memory data structure store used as a database cache and message broker.
Whereas with Memcached it says it's a high performance distributed memory object caching system
intended for use in speeding up dynamic web applications.
So Memcached these use cases are often things like caching data for web applications
and that might be something like session state data whereas we've read this because it's a persistent
data store.
You can actually use it as a database.
So let's choose Memcached and we're just going to call this one.
memcached one and we're going to leave the defaults there.
Now what I want to show you here is that no type.
So you can go into your know types and you can choose the no time you want.
I'm just going to go with the T2 micros and then you can choose the number of nodes.
And those are really the only options were available.
And as it says here the number of nodes in this cache cluster a node is a partition of your data.
So you remember from the diagram that each node is a separate partition of data.
We can then enable advanced settings.
And here let's just first change the number of nodes that say Free nodes and then we could go in and
choose a subnet group.
Now I already created one.
But you can go in and create a subnet group choose your VPC in the subnets
you can then decide which zones you want and say for instance you can say well I would like to select
a B and C and you can see where your nodes are going to go.
You can then specify maintenance windows and assign s topics.
Now we're just going to leave the rest of that as defaults and click on Create.
And that's really all there is to memcached.
Very very simple to set up and very few options to configure our cluster is now available and we can
have a look at some of the properties we can go into and modify and a few things we can change we can
go in and change the security group we can change parameter groups and we can change the maintenance
window and the topics for SNS notifications.
Another thing we can do and you have to click on the actual cluster name is go in and out nodes.
So we added three nodes we could grow in here now and add an additional node and choose the availability
zone that we want to put it in another way we can do it is by going to the command line and we can run
some commands using AWS Elasticache and to start with we could do describe cache clusters that would
get us some information so we now know the class cache cluster I.D. which is just the name that we gave
to it before we could then run aws elasticache modify cache cluster.
Then we give it the cache cluster I.D. and that would be Memcached one and then we tell it the number
of nodes we do dash dash num cache nodes and let's give it four and we can apply this immediately
so we can now see that the cache cluster status is in modifying.
Let's head back to the console and hit refresh and we can now say we have an extra node being provisioned.
We've lost a cache.
We can also go and purchase reserve nodes so hey just like we have other reserved instances.
You choose your product and then you choose your term.
And that is one or three years.
So if you select three years and you can then select the type of utilization you're going to use.
So you can choose medium utilization there and then it tells you how much you can have to pay
backups are not an option for memcached but they are for Redis which we'll be covering in the
next lab.
You can also see the events that are happening here so you can see that we're increasing the number
of requested notes the Elasticache plus the client is for men cash deals and supports auto discovery.
So I can find nodes automatically and there's a few different languages that you can use there send
back to the cache and the cluster is still in the modifying status.
Now we finished the lab.
I'm just going to wait for this to become available again and then I'm going to be able to delete the
cluster that only took a few minutes.
It's available again now.
And what I'm going to do is just select the cluster and delete.