Hi guys we're now going to create a net instance.
I just wanted to put the slide back up just to remind you some of the pros and cons again not gateways
to the ones the eight of us have recommended for most use cases you're going to use a net Gateway because
it's managed for you.
It's a classically scalable it has hate Che and so on but you can't add security groups of your own
and you can't use it as a bastion host.
So there are a couple of advantages to using in that instance you might want to use it in some scenarios
and that's what we're going to do in this lab.
So we're going to create this configuration we're going to have an easy to instance and a private subnet
and we're going to have a net instance in a public subnet.
And we're going to create a round table entry that points to the net instance for any IP address destinations
that aren't within the VPC.
So that's what we're going to do.
And we can also use this net instance as a jump post so that we can assess age into the net instance
across to our private instance and then paying the outside world via the Net instance.
So that's something that we weren't able to do when we set up our bastion hosting in the original bastion
host lab so that's what we're going to do.
Let's head over to the console and get this setup.
So I'm back in the easy to management console and we already have a couple of instances running.
Now I'm gonna keep my private instance but actually I'm going to just terminate this instance in the
public subnet because I still want to show you how you can use a net instance as a bastion host.
So let's go to launch an instance and what I want to do now is actually search for community semis and
I'm going to type I am set N Dash I corrected it for me.
Let's just make sure it doesn't Dash.
Am I dash VPC dash Nat and let's just search and so you get a list of EMI like Amazon machine images
that are pre configured and I want to use this one that's not hate VM and this might look slightly different
when you search but if you just put that in you'll be able to find your EMI.
So we choose select we keep it as a T2 micro.
We want to put this into our public subnet and we can then go to security groups and I'm just going
to choose Web access.
So what we need from this is we need SSA each inbound because we want to use it as a bastion host and
for the outbound we need to be able to send traffic out to the Internet and that's already allowed by
default in the in the security group.
So let's choose review and launch and launch.
So that instance is launching and this couple of things we need to do we need to go to actions networking
and change source destination check.
So by default an instance in EU does not allow port forwarding and we need to enable port forwarding
for it to function as a net instance.
So we choose yes disable and we can then take the public IP address and head over to the console and
we're going to SSA into this box.
So I'm going to SSA H and I'm going to use port forwarding again as we did in the previous lamps and
I'm going to put in the public IP and choose yes.
And I'm now going to SSA each into my instance in the private subnet.
So let's go back and get the IP of my instance in the private subnet and I'll just need to put an at
sign in there so let's just do that.
And there we are we're in.
So let's see if we can ping Google dot com and we're not getting a response because remember what we
need to do is actually add an entry into the round table.
So let's go back to our console and I'm gonna go to VPC open in a new tab and we're going to head down
to round tables and choose round type of one.
Now we've still got this target for on that gateway that we had in the previous lab and because that's
been deleted.
It says black hole.
So all we can do is we can just delete that out and I need to get the instance I.D. of my net instance
so this one with a public address is my net instance and I need to copy the instance I.D. ed back to
rounds at around and it's going to be 0 0 0 0 slash 0 and then I'm going to choose instance and it was
this one here so I don't need to paste it in I can just choose it from the list or remember it is the
one that finished with F one.
So let's choose that and click save rounds and we now have an active route via our instance and you
can see it's changed the target to the elastic network interface of that instance.
So let's head back over to the command line and let's try and ping.
Hi guys.
I just got disconnected.
So I had to clear my screen but I pinged Google dot com and I still got a failure.
And the reason for this is what we need to do is go back to our Web access group security group and
choose edit rules and we need to add a rule to allow ICMP traffic and I'm to choose from anywhere and
choose safe rules and if we go back to the console now and we ping.
There we go.
We get a response so that's all working.
So we have our Nat instance which is also functioning as a bastion host.
We've created the Nats instance from the Amazon EMI for VPC net.
We've added a roundtable entry to point to the net instance in the roundtable for the private subnet.
And we've also had to enable ICMP inbound to get the response traffic that comes back when we send our
pings.
Course we already have a role in our security groups to allow all traffic outbound so we didn't have
to change anything there.
So that's the configuration and we're now able to SSA age in to our instance via our not instance and
then pinging the outside world via the Net instance that's enabled Internet connectivity.
So that's all it is for NATS instances guys.
Let's go back to the console and what we can do is firstly I'm going to remove the ICMP rule here because
I use this for Internet facing instances so I don't want everything to be able to ping me and save rules
and then I'm gonna go and terminate my instances choose both instances.
Let's go back to the VPC management console and what we're going to do is just go to our round table
and we can remove that entry which has now gone into a black hole and that's everything cleaned up for
this lap and we're now all done with Nat gateways and Nat instances.