Another great feature of Amazon S3 is cross region replication.
So CRR enables you to asynchronously copy objects between buckets that are in different AWS
regions so AWS already replicates your data between geographically distant Availability Zones but
you might want to copy it to even greater distances across regions.
You also might do it so that you can minimize the latency in other words the distance between your users
and your data.
It might also be for operational reasons so you might have computer clusters in different regions they
could be processing some data and you want that information to be locally available for those compute
instances.
So there are a few reasons for enabling CRR and a few requirements that you need to understand for
how you set it up.
So firstly you need to have versioning enabled.
So you need to have the regions that able to account as well but versioning is essential and you need
to have that set up straight away before you can use CRR the source and destination buckets have to
be in different AWS regions so you can't use it as a way to backup one bucket to another bucket within
the same region.
We also need to provide permissions to S3 to replicate the objects and we're going to do that for
a role.
So let's head over to the S3 console and we're going to set up a couple of buckets there.
So we're going to create one which we're going to call DCTTestCRR
and we can go into this bucket and straight away we can go to properties and enable versioning
and before we set up the configuration because we can actually go in now and set up our replication
rule to enable cross region replication but we're going to need a role.
And so we're going to create a role and we need to come down here and choose S3 because this is
the service that's going to assume this role and we'll see why this is required shortly.
We then got a permissions and what I'm gonna do is we could lock this down but just for this exercise
I'm just gonna go with full access so let's go through and we're just gonna call this S3 our
now if we have a look at this role.
The reason that we choose the service is because when you go to trust relationships here you can see
the service is specified as S3 to Amazon AWS dot com and the action is assumed role.
So this means that S3 can assume this role the role that we've created earlier for S3 in this case
was used for EC2 so if we have a look at this one the service is easy to which means that an EC2
instance can assume this role.
So you have to have that set up you've got to have the correct trust relationship as well as the permissions.
So let's go back to S4.
So we're back in S3 and before we carry on I just want to create a folder and I'm gonna call
this replicated and I'm not going to upload any objects yet because objects that are uploaded before
you enable CRR won't actually be replicated so let's now go to replication and add a rule and instead of
replicating the entire bucket we're going to choose a prefix and the prefix is going to be the folder
replicated we can optionally enable encryption and now we need to create a destination bucket.
Obviously if you had one existing you'd just choose it.
But in this case I'm just going to create a new bucket and you could optionally create one in another
account using an account I.D..
So in this case we're going to create a new bucket.
We're going to select a region and choose Singapore and then I'm going to call this DCTTestCRR
tfor destination we could optionally change the storage class for the replicated objects so we could
for instance change to a cheaper storage tier such as one zone IA.
I'm not going to do that.
You can even change the object ownership to the destination bucket owner.
So now we need to choose our role and we're going to choose the role we created earlier.
And we just need to give this a name.
And if we click on Next we get a summary.
So it says and it's going to replicate the bucket DCCTestCRR from Sydney to DCTTestCRR
in Singapore.
And this is the role we're going to use.
So let's click save
and this will automatically enable versioning in the destination bucket.
So you need versioning enabled in both the source and the destination.
And so we can now see it's being created successfully and we can see the scope as the prefix replicated.
So let's go back to the bucket and what we're gonna do is we're going to upload some objects so I'm
going to upload a couple of these JPEG files
and they're going to be in the roots of the bucket and then I'm going to go into replicated.
And here we're going to upload let's say these two HTML files here
so we've now got these files in the folder that's called replicated and we've got a couple in the root
here as well.
But remember we enabled the role to replicate the folder that's called replicated.
So let's now go back up a level and we can now see that we have the destination bucket here which is
in Singapore.
So let's go in and we can see the replicated folder and just as expected we can't see those objects
that were at the bucket root level but if we go into here we can see these files and we have versioning
enabled on this destination bucket as well.
So if there were multiple versions we would see them here
we go back to the source bucket again we have versioning.
So we can see if there's a different version here.
There are some peculiarities around cross region replication.
So have a look at the documentation and definitely have a play with it.
It's worth trying to understand what happens when you delete an object.
What is replicates it and what if you delete an object in the destination or the source.
So there's a few different behaviours there which you can practice where it's very easy to set this
up and have a play around.