And this lesson we're going to deploy a to instance, in a public subnet as a bastion hosts and then
use that to jump to an easy to instance in a private subnet.
So basically what we covered in the previous lesson in that fairy and this diagram basically shows what
we're going to do.
We're going to use the default VPC in this case, which already has a public subnet.
And we already have a root table correctly configured and an internet gateway attached to the VPC.
What we then need to do is create a private subnet with a root table, and then we're going to be able
to launch our instances in the appropriate subnets and then connect in and jump from our public instance
to a private instance.
I'm in the VPC management console here, which you can find on the services.
Just scroll down to networking and content delivery and BPC.
Now, I haven't covered the theory behind VPC in much detail yet.
I'm going to build you up to that and we're going to go into a lot at that later on in the course.
For now, I'm just going to give you the information you need to know so that you can deploy your EC2
instances and then you load balancers and auto scaling groups within a BPC.
So VPC is essentially a virtual private cloud that's a kind of virtual data center in the cloud.
Now I'm connected to the North Virginia.
This is a regional service.
You can select a region.
I suggest you also use USC, East North Virginia.
That's going to make this particular exercise a lot easier.
So we have BBQs here under your VPI.
And this is the default VPC, every single region will have a default VPC.
The default VPC will have a subnet in each availability zone.
So we have six, Subnet said, because US East North Virginia has six availability zones.
If I change to another one like Sydney, for example, we can see we only have free subnets.
And that's because Sydney only has free availability zones.
So back to US East North Virginia so we can see our six subnets each in a different availability zone.
If I scroll all the way across here, I can see that you auto assign public IP addresses configuration
setting.
It sets a yes for all of these.
These are public subnets.
Now, if I go to round tables will find there's one round table for that default VPC.
This round table has a route for the actual site a block, so the overall address block the IP v4 address
block for the VPC of locals.
Remember, that means that it's going to route within the VPC, and then it has the.
IP address block for all other addresses via the Internet Gateway, you can find your internet gateway
here, and this one is attached to a specific default VPC, so all of that is set up for us.
We don't need to do anything here.
You'll see how to create your own BPC later on.
Now what I want to do is create a private subnet.
So firstly, I need to know the IPv4 address block to use for this particular subnet.
It has to be within the overall site, the block for the VPC.
It stands for classless into domain routing.
That's another concept we'll cover later on in the course.
When we look at these IP addresses, we can see that they all start with 172 Dot 31 and then it's different.
We have Dot Zero Dot, 16, Dot 32, Dot 64 and or 80, and then it's a dot zero slashed 20 and that's
the subnet mask.
Again, we'll cover those concepts in more detail later.
For now, I just want you to follow my instructions.
Now I'm going to copy this one to my clipboard just to make life easier and click on Create Subnet.
And what I'm going to do is choose my BPC.
Scroll down to where it says IPv4 slider block.
Paste us in and then I'm going to delete the 80.
And I know that the next address range is 96, so I'm going to add that in now.
I want to give the subnet a name.
I want to know that it's private, so I'm going to call it private.
I want to know which deep BPC it's connected to.
So I'm going to put Dash DCF for default, and I want to know which availability zone I'm going to put
one.
I hear and then choose the availability zone.
So now from the name, I know some important information about the subnet that you can then add new
subsets and add more.
But I'm just going to create this particular subnet so that subnet is created.
We've got a filtered view here.
And if I scroll all the way across, you can see the auto assigned public IPv4 is no.
So we're not going to get a public IP address, so that's the correct setting for a private subnet.
Now also, we want to associate this subnet with a round table that does not have an internet gateway
at the moment.
It's actually going to be associated with all public subnet routing table, the one that does have an
internet gateway and that's an implicit association.
We haven't explicitly defined that it should be associated with that round table.
There's no other option, so the default route table is chosen.
So what we're going to do is create a round table.
We're just going to give this a name.
I'm going to call it private that Shati.
Select my VPC and then just create the round table.
Now I can go to subnet associations.
Choose Edit Subnet Associations.
And I'm going to select my private.
Subnet and click on Save.
So now when we look at the subnet associations, we should see an explicit subnet association with our
private subnet.
So that's great.
That's all set up correctly.
Let's now go to EC2 in easy too.
We're going to launch a couple of instances.
I'm going to choose to launch an instance.
Then it's two am I to micro?
And this time I'm going to make sure I put it in a particular subnet.
Now I'm happy with this one going into one, eh?
But it's going to be the public one I.
So we should see that the auto assigned public IP on the subnet setting is enabled.
So that's the default.
So that's good.
Click on Next.
Com Afraid of tax security groups?
Select Web Access Security Group and we should have a role for Port 22 because I'm going to use the
secure shell protocol.
And that's from any source.
So let's launch this instance.
And that's on its way.
Now let's launch another instance, and this one is going to go into a different subnet.
So this one is going to go to a private subnet.
So again, let's just go through at a security group.
We're also going to need SSL.
And let's just launch this issue to, for instance.
Now you need to make sure you've got your keypad available.
Now you might want to actually give these some names here.
So this one is public and this one I'm going to call private, and that's just going to make things
a bit easier to identify here in the console.
So we now have a public instance in our private instance.
And what we're going to do is connect from all computers through our internet gateway to the public
IP of this instance and then from there to this instance.
Now there's one problem, and that is that I have my keep a file on my computer, which means I can
connect to this instance.
Remember, I need to present my keeper file in order to be able to connect to this instance.
But this instance does not have a copy of that key file.
So how can we connect from here to here?
It's not going to allow that connection unless we have that particular key file available that we can
present when we're connecting with SSL.
So there is a way that we can do that, and it's called agent forwarding, which I'm going to show you
how to do now.
To use agent forwarding.
We need to follow a particular process, and I've documented that in this blog article.
I'll add a link to this to the video, and they'll also be a link to a similar article from IWC.
And what we need to do is we're going to run this command SSA ad that's going to add our private key
file to S.H. so that it can then be used in subsequent commands.
And that means we're able to then connect to our public instance and we'll still have the key file stored
in memory that we can then use to connect to our private instance.
Now it's a bit different if you on Linux or Mac.
And there's also instructions here for how to do on Windows if you're using the Putty tool.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to follow the instructions up here to use the switch at command
with my Mac on a command line.
Here I'm in a directory where I have the key file I need so I can run SSA Dash at Dash and then I can
put in the name of my key file, which is Cloud Labs, Dash and V p.m. So that identity has been added.
And now I can connect to my to instance.
So back in the active management console, I'm going to use my public IP address here.
I've copied that to my clipboard.
And what I can do now is run SSA Dash, a easy to dash user hat and then put in the IP address of my
instance and I should be able to connect.
And then we all went on our instance.
So I'm on the public instance, and now I want to be able to connect to my private instance back in
DC to let's go to our private instance and I'm going to copy its private IP address.
And now let's try and connect S.H. easy to dash user at, and I'm going to put in the IP and note that
I have not specified a private key file here.
I'm just going to try and connect and let's see.
And that works.
So that's how you can use a bastion host.
We're now connected to all instance, in the private subnet via the instance in the public subnet.
Now what if we want to connect to the outside world?
Well, let me just clear my screen.
Bring this down so you can see it.
Let's try and ping Google dot com.
And it's a fail.
And the reason it's a fail is we don't have any type of outbound network connectivity.
That's something for a subsequent lesson.
I'm going to show you how to configure outbound internet connectivity for your instances in your private
subnets.
So leave your instances running for now, and we're going to pick this up in another lesson.