Hi, guys, in this lesson, we're going to create a secure listener for our load balancer.
Now to do that, we're going to need to register a certificate in the Certificate Manager service.
And for that, we need to have a hosted zone in Route 53, which means we need to register a domain
name.
Now, I haven't done that yet in the course.
So if you do want to follow along and it is optional, then you can go forward to the DNS caching and
performance optimization section and you'll find a lesson called Register Domain with Route 53.
Now it does cost somewhere between five and $12, typically to register a domain name, but it will
be useful for some lessons in this course.
So if you want to follow along, then skip forward, do that lesson and then come back here and then
we can carry on.
Otherwise, you can just watch what I do.
So let's get started back in the easy to management console.
I'm going to open certificate manager.
You got a services, scroll down to security, identity and compliance, and you'll find certificate
manager here in Certificate Manager.
I'm going to click on Get Started.
Request a public certificate.
And then I'm going to add in the domain name.
Now this must correspond to your hosted zone.
So what you need to do there is go down to networking and content delivery Route 53.
And for this lesson, if you're going to follow along, you need to go to hosted signs and you should
have a domain name minus DCT Cloud Labs dot com.
So I'm just going to copy that name, come back and paste it in, and you can add alternate names as
well, but I'm happy with that for now.
So let's click on next.
Now here, what you would want to do is use email validation and then you'll get an email and you have
to approve the request.
Now please, please don't use DCT Cloud Labs dot com.
This is a domain that I've registered.
You will not get the email and you will not be able to register a certificate.
I get lots of emails from there, so please don't do that.
So make sure you use your own domain name that you've registered and that you have an email address
registered as your contact details for your domain registration.
That's the address that the confirmation will go to.
So if I click on next?
Make sure email validation is selected next.
Review and confirm and what a fine now is.
I have an email.
I need to click on a link in that email and then when I refresh this page, the certificate should be
registered.
So I've done that in the background.
Now let's refresh.
And the certificate has been issued successfully.
So what I can do now is come back to my load balancer, go to listeners and we're going to add a new
listener.
And it's telling me I can't use your AC again.
But of course I don't want to because I'm going to create a secure listener using Port 443.
Now you can see the default SSL certificate is going to be from ACM by default.
And so I'm going to select my certificate here for default actions.
We need to set up a rule for how our traffic is routed.
I'm going to forward it to my TG Dash Alb.
Now know that you can add additional target groups and specify a weighted distribution, and you can
have what's called group level stickiness.
In this case, what it means is we essentially have something like sticky sessions, but at the target
group level.
So for a period of time that you can specify anything that's routed to one target group, those connections
will remain going to that target group.
They're not going to get routed across to a different target group, even if your traffic distribution
would otherwise allow that.
Now I just want one target group, so I'm going to OK this and add my listener and that's it.
If we come back now, we should have two listeners.
So that's the lesson I set up correctly.
But of course, we need a DNS resolution.
So the way we're going to do that is we're going to add an alias record in Route 53 back in round 53.
I'm going to select the hosted zone.
And we're going to add a record, and this record is we're not going to put anything here, it's not
going to be a dub dub dub or anything like that.
It's going to be straight for the cloud loudobbs.com.
It's going to be an alias record.
And when we choose Alias, we can choose an end point.
And these are IWC services.
It's an application load balancer.
The region in this case is USC's one, and then I can find my load balancer, and that's it.
That's how you create a record in Route 53.
So what this means is when we try to get a resolution for DCT Labs dot com that should then get resolved
to the DNS name of our application load balancer.
Now, another thing we need before we're going to be able to make any connections to our load balancing
using HD TPS is to make sure we have the right security group rules in place, so let's select Web Access
Security Group and down here under inbound rules.
I'm going to select edit inbound rules and then I'm going to add a rule and let's just type in each
step and we'll find HD CBS and that also fills the protocol in the port range.
And what I'm going to do is any IPv4 say from any IPv4 address and then save rules.
And that's it.
Now we have our security group rules set up to make sure we allow inbound connections.
So let's now try and connect to this domain name using HTTPS.
So I've entered TPS colon slash slash.
I'm going to put in DCT cloud labs, dot com and hit enter.
And of course, I do get directed to my in-situ instance and I can cycle through my instances.
As with before, the key difference is this time we're connected over HTTPS and that means we have a
certificate and we can see that certificate here.
And that was issued by Amazon.
So that's how we create a secure listener.
Now, I don't need my entry in Ralph 5:3 anymore, so I'm just going to come back in here and choose
this record.
Don't delete the NSA or the CIA, and I'm just going to delete this record.
And that's gone.
And that's it for this lesson.
And all we're going to do in the next lesson is clean things up to make sure that you don't leave anything
running.
So I'll see you there.