And this lesson on guns cover, not gateways and not instances now within the section, we've already
talked about network address translation and how it's used to translate the addresses, often between
public and private IP address ranges, not gateways, and that instances are both used for the one purpose.
And that purpose is to enable the instances that we deploy into private subnet to connect to the internet.
This is outbound only it doesn't mean there's going to be bidirectional traffic.
If we wanted that, we would just deploy instances into a public subnet and they would have a public
IP and use the internet gateway.
But sometimes we want private instances, so no one in the outside world from the internet can connect
to are easy to instance, but we can connect outbound.
We might want to be able to connect to an outbound service, a service located on the internet, or
we might want to download software, software updates, that kind of thing.
So let's see how this works visually.
So again, we have an availability zone with a public subnet and a private subnet.
And we've deployed in EC2 instance in a private subnet.
And it has a private IP address and there's an internet gateway attached to the VPC.
What we might then do is deploy, and that's gateway into a public subnet.
Now it's important to understand that this Nat Gateway is in a public subnet because it needs a public
IP address.
It will have an elastic IP address assigned to it, and it uses that to be able to talk to the internet
gateway on behalf of our private instance.
So remember that for exam questions, it comes up a lot.
You always deploy your NAT gateways or your NAT instances in public subnet.
So we then have our roundtable, as you know, the root table for the public subnet.
The main round table has a route to the internet gateway.
But we also have a private roundtable.
And in this case, we have added an entry and that entry is for the NAT Gateway out of this NAT gateway
we've deployed.
And just like with the Internet Gateway entry here, it's four zero zero zero zero zero.
So it means any address other than this address here that's already been specified.
So any address range outside of the VPC with this configuration are easy to instance can now use its
private IP address to connect to the private IP address of the NAT Gateway.
And then traffic can get forwarded to the internet gateway from the NAT Gateway using network address
translation.
And from there, it would go out to the internet so whatever service you want to connect to.
So that's a Nat Gateway, and Nat Gateway is an IWC service that you can deploy.
We then have NAT instances these are a lot less popular now.
We used to use these a lot before NAT gateways came along, and that instance isn't an IWC service.
It's just an easy two instance that you configure a certain way.
The deployments apology is very similar.
We've got our instance in a private, subnet or internet gateway.
And on that instance, when we deploy in that instance, we use a special am-I that's already been preconfigured
a certain way and that will have the string aims that end Dash, am-I Dash, VPC, Dash, Nat.
So you can search for that when you're looking for an EMI and you should see some entries come up.
Really important thing to do is you have to disable source and destination checks.
This is the key one that pops up in exam questions.
Now, in true, if not, instances aren't covered as much as NAT gateways anymore.
And for most use cases, you're always going to choose a NAT gateway.
If it does come up, sometimes they're just checking your knowledge.
That's a NAT instance requires the source and destination checks to be disabled.
And that's essentially a setting that allows the NAT Gateway to function as a network address, translate
to receive traffic on one IP address and then translate it and send it out using a different one root
tables or set up almost the same as within Nat Gateway.
But we're just going to specify the Nats instance side instead.
And then, as with before we're connecting using a private IP to the NAT instance, using the BBC router,
and then we're connecting to the outside world by using the elastic IP of the NAT instance.
Now let's look finally at a few differences between NAT gateways and NAT instances, and I'm just going
to highlight a few of these that are really important for the exam.
The very first one is, in that instance, is managed by you.
It's an easy two instance.
You have to manage the operating system, install software updates and so on with a NAT Gateway.
It's a managed service, so AWB.
Manage it for you with a NAT instance if you want to scale it.
You have to scale up by changing the instance type, whereas with a NAT gateway, it's fully elastic.
Within that instance, you don't get a high availability.
You could potentially create a high availability solution, but there's no easy.
Way of doing it.
Whereas with a NAT gateway, it provides automatic high availability within an availability zone.
And you can place your NAT gateways in multiple availability zones or separate NAT gateways in different
availability zones.
So you have that hichi across all bases with a NAT instance, you can use security groups, you have
to use security groups because it's an easy to instance.
So you get a bit of control over how you configure the networking and who's allowed to connect with
a NAT gate where you don't.
There are no security groups, but it only allows outbound access anyway and can't be used in any other
fashion.
Whereas with in that instance, you could make it dual purpose so that it's actually your bastion host
as well, and users are connecting into your EC2 instance, your NAT instance, and then connecting
from there to private subnets.
You can't do that with a NAT Gateway, but really, that's a small limitation.
You should probably separate that functionality onto a separate host anyway.
Now those are the main ones for the exam, so you should be well set up now.
In the next lesson, we're actually going to configure and Nat Gateway and see how it works in action.