Hi, guys, just a short lesson to go back in and make sure we clean up all the resources that we launched
in the section, that might cost us some money back in the easy to management console.
Let's first go down to auto scaling groups or we need to do here is select auto scaling group and delete.
And that's going to be deleted.
Now remember, we do have a launch template, but you don't pay for launch templates, so there's no
need to actually get rid of that.
We might use it again later on in the course.
And by terminating or deleting the auto scaling group, we should find that these instances had do terminate
shortly.
We'll come back and check that in a moment.
In the meantime, let's go to load balances.
I've got my load balancer here running my Albi.
We're going to delete the load balancer under target groups.
We have these free target groups.
Again, these don't cost you any money, so there's no need to delete them and we might well use them
again.
Make sure you release any elastic IP addresses.
So if you do have some left over from the NHLBI labs, do the release.
Elastic IP addresses action for each of them to make sure that they go from this view.
So let's just come back up now to instances and give this a refresh that's still running.
So let's go back down to auto scaling groups and have a look at what's going on now.
We can see that an action is taking place.
It says it's deleting.
So if you go to activity and what we have here is a waiting for LP connection draining status, and
that means that the auto scanning group is giving a period of time for the elastic load balancer to
finish off any connections and closed them out before the instance is terminated.
So that might take a few minutes and then we should see things change.
So let's just keep an eye on this.
Now you will note in the message here that it's changed the design capacity from two to zero.
So we should see that if we come back up to the details page, we can see that all the capacity configurations
are zeros here.
So the auto scanning group does want to get rid of those instances.
Let's come back to activity and just wait a few minutes for this to occur.
Now, of course, you could go and manually terminate the instances, but I think it's good when you're
learning to actually watch what happens when you leave it to its own devices with default settings that
would have taken about five minutes or 300 seconds.
And now that's happened, and I can see this in progress and we're terminating the active instance.
So if we come back up to instances here, we should see that the instances are being shut down.
So that should be all of the resources that might cost you money.
Cleaned up.
And that's it.
For now, I will see you in the next lesson.