We're now going to cover object lifecycle management so with object lifecycle management.
you can automatically move data between different storage tiers or archive and delete that data.
So you might use this to move data that's not so frequently access from as standard as free to another
storage class and then you can expire data when you no longer need it.
So let's go into a bucket and have a look how this is configured.
So we head over to management and we've got the lifecycle rule option here and there's a couple of
different links here which take you to some more information.
So we've object lifecycle management.
There are a couple of actions that you can configure.
One is a transition action.
And this means that you actually move your objects from one class such as S3 standard to another class
such as Standard I.A. which is the infrequently accessed class.
And that's a lower cost storage than standard.
So you might move it there when you don't need to access it as often and then you could move it to glacier
when you think that you really won't need it or need to retrieve it very often at all.
And that will save you even more money.
And with the caveat being that you have longer retrieval times if you do need to access that data.
So those are things that you can automate for a transition action.
Then you've got expiration actions.
And this literally means that you can inspire your objects which means that Amazon deletes them another
link here gives you a bit of a diagram which shows you about how you can configure these actions.
So with the transition actions you can move for instance from standard to standard IA you could then
go to one-zone IA which has less redundancy you could then move from there to Glacier or to deep Archive
which is the version of glacier which has even longer retrieval times.
So there's lots of options they call it a waterfall model where you can just move between different
tiers and all of this can be set up to happen automatically as well.
The third link talks about objects expiration which really is deleting the data so let's go back to
the console and let's actually configure a rule.
So I'm just gonna call this my lifecycle rule and you can put in a prefix here if you just want to
apply this to certain prefixes and the objects underneath those prefixes within the bucket.
I'm just going to leave that blank and you can then choose.
So if you have versioning enabled you can choose to apply your transition action to the current version
or also to the previous versions so you can have a transition action for the current version which says
let's go to standard I.A. after 30 days and then you could say well for the previous versions I don't
need those very often at all but I'll have a backup of them so let's just transition those to Glacier
and you can then expire so you can say the current version should expire 395 days previous versions
can perhaps you bring that down to 180 days
so that's all you need to do.
And then you can click on Save to hit refresh and ....
There you go.
Those your rule so very simple and lots of flexibility in how you can use lifecycle rules and very
good for ensuring that you're using the best tier at a certain time.
So if you have a lifecycle for your data that you're very well aware of you can configure the rules
here to move that data between different storage tiers and then deletes it according to your known lifecycle
for your data.
If you don't know the lifecycle for your data that's where you might want to use something like the
intelligent tiering of S3 which then moves data around automatically.
But that's a different thing to this.
So this is more about configuring when you know what the lifecycle of your data is a couple of other
things I want to bring to your attention are on this web page which talks about transitioning objects
using the S3 lifecycle.
It tells you what these supported transitions are and what the unsupported transitions are.
So you should be aware of these just understand you know which what you can move from where to where.
And then there are some more constraints as well to understand there.
And also have a look at the pricing.
You don't need to know every detail in here for the exam but what you do need to really understand is
the price differences just have a good understanding of what the price factors are.
What you get charged for such as you can see here is free transfer acceleration something you need to
pay for.
So that might be something that changes the design data transfer pricing as well.
So you need to know what you try and what you pay for.
And it's really data that goes out.
It's not data that comes in as you can see here.
It's all data that goes out and that includes two different regions.
There's also some costs around storage management requests as well so the get in the puts and so on
requests that you issue to S3.
So just get an understanding of those and then also this chart here which is on this web page called
Amazon S3 storage classes what you need to know here.
Now you won't again be asked it's unlikely at least that these days that the exam will ask for a specific
thing like how many zones are there in you know S3 standard IA or one zone IA.
But you do need to know this because it might ask you a question about what the redundancy is or you
might have a constraint in a question that says that you need to ensure that your data is replicated
between at least three Availability Zones which storage tier should you use.
And so it might sway you one way or another.
Also understand the minimum storage duration which applies to certain tiers and then also you can see
here you pay per gigabyte retrieved with some tiers but not with others.
So just get an understanding of what the charges are I'd get an understanding of which constraints apply
to each tier and how they're designed and architected.