In this lab we're going to cover a quick overview of Route 53.
So you've already had some exposure to Route 53 throughout this course and you may even have registered
your own domain at the beginning.
But if not that's okay.
We're gonna go over each of the key areas of Route 53 in this lab.
So Route 53 has a few key capabilities.
One is domain registration so you can go and register a domain name using many different domain suffixes
such as dot net dot com dot org dot dot uk there's a huge list so you can come on search for your domain
name and if it's not taken you can register. What will then happen is a hosted zone gets created for
your domain.
Now you know that could be a public domain or you can create a private hosting zone and we're gonna
go over there shortly.
So private hosted zone would be for instances to resolve within a VPC so it can be pretty much any
domain name you want because it's not going to be publicly registered.
So hosted zones are collections of records for one of these domain names and you can then add your own
records and we're going to go over all the different record types and show how they work in labs for
this section.
So another thing Route 53 can do is health checks.
So it has the capability to check your instances but also your load balancers and you can even create
health checks for resources outside of AWS.
So you can for instance have your web servers that are listening on port 80 and you can send health
checks to them on port 80.
You can do the same for your on premise servers if they're publicly accessible and you can do the same
for load balancers.
And the result of those health checks can then determine the DNS responses that you get from Route
So Route 53 principally is a DNS service.
So what you're doing is you're looking for the IP address that's associated with a domain name.
It's then going out and checking the health of your servers your web servers and responding and saying
all right if that's healthy then I'm going to give you a certain IP address.
But if this instance has become unhealthy I'm going to give you a different one. We then have traffic
flow which is a relatively new service.
It's been around for a little while now but it's relatively new and what it does we'll talk a lot more
about the different types of records that you can create in Route 53 shortly and we'll cover this
traffic flow towards the end of the section because basically you can then take the different types
of record sets that you use you can create some logic that creates a flow.
So it's a logical flow to to work out  which responses to provide to your clients.
So that's a simple high level overview.
Let's just go to the console and have a look at this.
So this is the route 53 dashboard.
We've got the DNS management here and I've got one hosted zone which is dctlabs.com which we registered
in an earlier section.
You can then create your traffic management policies here.
You can create your health checks through availability monitoring and you can register domains here
through domain registration.
So that's it for this and I just wanted to give you a really quick overview.
We're now going to talk about hosted zones in the next lab.