Hi guys.
In this lab we're going to cover Amazon called Cognito. Cognito is a service which is used with web and
mobile apps.
So when you see exam questions that talk about authentication using web or mobile apps Cognito is
definitely something that should come to your mind and then you can start thinking about does it fit
this use case.
So Cognito provides authentication authorization and use and management for web and mobile apps.
And that means that your users can sign in directly with a username and password or even for a third
party provider such as Facebook Amazon or Google.
Now there are two main components to Cognito.
And you can see these up on a screen here.
You've got user pools and you've got identity pools the user pool is the is a user directory
and your users sign in to the web or mobile app through Cognito or federate with a third party identity
provider using a user pool.
Identity pools on the other hand are used to obtain temporary AWS credentials to access AWS services
and that would include things such as S3 and DynamoDB.
So you have the user pool which is used for sign up and sign in services and then you have the identity
pool which is about connecting to AWS services.
So a little bit more about user polls you can have social signin with Facebook Google you can also
log in with Amazon and you can also use SAML and IDP identity providers. You have user directory management
and user profiles and you have the option for multi factor authentication and other security features.
We have identity pools,
you also get social signin with Facebook Google or Amazon.
You also get open ID connect and SAML so you can actually use identity pools for that kind of
authentication and you can use user pools for it so you can use them independently or you can use them
together.
Now what I want to do is just show you a diagram which shows you a typical use case for called meta.
So in this diagram what you can see is on the left hand side here you have an app and that apps running
and needs to get access to some AWS services.
So in this case you have a Cognito user pool and the first thing that happens is you need to get a
token from the company so you support so your fence casing here.
But you then need to access state AWS services so now what happens is you exchange your tokens for
AWS credentials and that's temporary AWS credentials and you can then access the service.
So you have the user ID stored in the user pool you have the Cognito identity pool where you are
then allowing access to the services and then this whole exchange takes place which allows the web user
or the app user to access the service.
So that's a bit about what it is and you probably don't need to know a huge amount more than that at
this stage for the exam.
But what we're gonna do is we're just going to go into the console and have a look around.
Now I may add a lap a bit later on that shows an actual use case where we can actually build this out
and really get it working.
But for now what I'm gonna do is just show you around the console so we can go in and manage user pools
and you can then click on Create a user pool and you need to give it a pool name so let's just call
this my user pool and you can see all these options on the left here so you can go free and modify these.
So you might say that you want a user name and also allow signin with an email address.
You can choose which attributes you want to require.
So in this case we're requiring an email.
You can set a password policy.
You can integrate with MFA.
You can customize addresses and tags and choose whether you want to remember the devices that the clients
connect it from.
You can then have your app clients which you would add in here and you can add triggers for workflows
and then you can just go down and create your pull.
So we haven't changed much.
We do need to provide a name parameter.
So let's just go back up here and it's lost my name my user pool.
And if you click on review defaults and then create pool and so we now have a pool and you can see on
the left there are a couple of additional sections have come in.
You've got the app integration where you can specify domains UI customization for your app client and
so on.
And these are the actual places we can put that information in.
And then you've got a federation.
So under here you can enable certain identity providers and obviously here you can see Facebook Google
Amazon, SAML and OpenID connect.
So that's a user pool.
Let's go back up to the front screen and choose manage identity pools so hey let's just create one
called MyID pull and you can configure your authentication providers here.
So you'd need to go in and specify this information.
You could specify your user pull here or you could choose to enter your app ID for Amazon or for Facebook
or so on.
And you've also got Twitter as you can see in here and custom.
Alternatively you can just select this option here enable access to UNO fence gated identities and that
will allow us just to create the pool without having to specify any more information.
So once that's created you can view details and you can specify and IAM role can view the policy document
and so on.
We then go back up to the dashboard here and you can see our identity pool is being created.
We don't have any identities in there yet.
You've got this sample code here which you can download.
And we've got the identity browser so we don't actually have any identities at the moment.
Let's just go back up to user pools if you wanted to add identities to your user pool you can then go
in here and create a user and then you can specify a user name and an email address and you need to
select this option for phone number.
If you just want to leave that blank and you can create a user you can also import users.
So in this case you can choose to import a job.
Now we're not going to do any more with these at this stage.
I think the key thing to remember for the exam is that Cognito is used for web and app authentication.
Now we're not going to do any more with Cognito right now.
But what you need to remember for the exam is that company so is used for authentication, authorization
and user management for web and mobile apps.
Make sure you understand the providers that you can integrate with in other words the identity providers.
So that's Facebook, Google, Amazon, SAML and OID connect and know the difference between user pools
and identity pools.
And I'll share some links for some further reading with the course downloads.
So if you want to delete your user pool you can just go in and delete pool and you just type in delete
and then we can go to identity Paul.
And if you just go into the pool and edit identity pol and then scroll down and choose Delete identity
poll and that's all you need to do.