Guys, the next service I'm going to talk about in this section is Amazon Kinesis.
So this is a service that deals with streaming data.
So it allows you to collect, process and analyze that streaming data in real time.
And what you can see on the screen here are free of the services.
So there's Kinesis, data streams, data analytics and data firehose.
Now, they don't necessarily work together in this pattern, but they can do.
And in this case, we have producers.
So this could be Iot data or some form of streaming data that's coming into data streams.
And then data analytics allows you to run Esquibel queries on that data.
And you could then put the data into firehose, which can load it into a data store, in this case,
redshift, or as free.
So it's a collection of services for processing streams of various types of data.
Kinesis family includes data streams, data firehose, data analytics and video streams.
Now, video streams is definitely out of scope and data analytics doesn't come up much.
The key thing to know about data analytics is it's a way that you can run escudo queries on your streaming
data.
Other than that, I don't think you need to know much more.
So what we're going to focus on is data streams and data firehose.
So Kinesis deals with streaming data and that means use cases such as purchases from online stores could
be stock price information, could be game data like the statistics and results of a game.
It could be social network data, geospatial data, Iot sensor data and so on.
So let's look at data streams and a bit more detail with data streams.
You have producers and they capture and send data to Kinesis.
You then have a stream.
So this blue box here is the stream.
And within that stream you have what are called shards and shards actually carry the data and data is
stored in those shards for 24 hours by default or up to seven days.
So the data is captured and then it can be stored in assured for processing.
So then you have the consumers in this case, two instances which are consuming data from the shards.
So they make an API calls to Kinesis to pull that data down and they can use something called the Kinesis
Client Library to do that.
You then have destination's and these can be Amazon S3, Dinamo, DB Redshift, EMR and firehose.
And you could then run analytics on your data once it's there.
So consumers take the data and process it and the data can be saved into another service.
One Shard provides a capacity of one make per second data invert and two megabytes a second data output
and one shard can support up to a thousand records per second.
So you need to remember that there are limits at the Shahd level.
So the actual capacity of your stream depends on the number of shards that you have and you pay per
Shahd.
So that's another consideration.
When designing Kinesis streams, the total capacity of the stream is the sum of the capacities of its
shards, because each of those shards has a maximum capacity and data stream supports something called
resodding, which lets you adjust the number of shards.
Now, this is used to adapt to changes in the rate of data flow in your stream, and it is important
to know this for the exam.
So there are two types of resodding.
You've got shot, split and a shard merge.
So in a sharp split on the left there, you divide a single shard into two shots and that means you're
increasing the capacity of your stream.
Otherwise you can merge Assad.
And in this case, you're combining shards into a single shard.
So you might do that if the shards are underutilized and now you're going to decrease cost and also
decrease the capacity of the stream.
So splitting increases the number of shards in your stream and consequently increases the data capacity
of the stream and also the cost.
So you pay per shard, which means that the more shards you have, the more you're going to pay.
Now merging will decrease the data capacity and also therefore decrease the cost of the stream.
So you've got to be very careful about how you allocate shards and monitor their utilization.
So the next service is data firehose and it looks something like this.
You have producers that send data to firehose and then you have your stream.
Now there are no shards.
It's completely automated, which means scalability is elastic, whereas with data streams you actually
have to add shards manually, which means scalability is something that you've got to keep on top of
from the stream teaches, then loaded to the destination's so it can go to another AWG service and it
can also optionally be processed by LAMDA as it's.
Being moved over there, it's a fully managed service and it's near real time.
There's about 60 seconds of licencee, so the destinations are as free Redshift ElasticSearch and Splunk.
To finish off this lesson.
I just want to compare Kinesis with Excuse and S.A. So with Kinesis, consumers pull data that's the
same excuse.
Whereas with S.A.S., data is pushed to a subscriber now a kinesis.
You've got as many consumers as you need.
There's a few key advantages.
You can route related records to the same record processor.
You can have multiple applications accessing the stream concurrently and you get ordering at the sharp
level and you can also consume records in the correct order at a later time as well.
The caveat with Kinesis is you do have to manage your stream throughput, so you've got to constantly
consider how many shots you've got and how much data is going through them.
With Ishikawa's data is deleted after it's consumed, you can have many, as many workers as you need.
There's no ordering guaranteed, though, except for with FIFO queues.
And as you know, they have some limitations in terms of throughput.
Escalus does provide messaging semantics.
It also gives you individual message delay and it scales dynamically with S.A.S..
It's a publisher subscriber model.
It integrates with us for that financial architecture pattern that we looked at earlier in the section.
And it does have some limits.
So there are 10 million subscribers maximum and up to 10000 topics.
That is not persistent and you don't need sufficient throughput.
So it's another dynamic service.
So those are a few key considerations between these services to help you understand the use cases and
the limitations of each.
And they could be useful for you in exam.