In this lesson I'm just going to cover a quick overview of a few application integration services offered
by AWS so starting at the top of the table we've got simple notification service and we use this a few
times where we've actually used it to send email notifications when a cloudwatch alarm was triggered
you have topics with SNS, and publishers and subscribers, and we'll go into that in more detail in the
lesson on SQS which will be next.
We've then got step functions.
This is a relatively new service it's been around a while but it's it's newer than the simple workflow
service which is next in the list and I'll talk about that in a second. Step functions provides out of
the box coordination of AWS service components.
Now you can even use code or you can use a visual workflow editor and it's all about processing workflows.
So think of it as a kind of orchestration service. Simple workflow service known as SWF has been around
for a long time now. For new use cases AWS are recommending that you use step functions wherever
you can.
However there are some specific use cases for SWF and that is for instance in human enabled workflows
like order fulfillment.
So think about Amazon.com.
They've got people picking up parcels processing them and then putting them back into an automated system.
And so there are those steps in the workflow where things go from automated to humans doing something
and then you automated logic continues.
So that's where SWF comes in useful. We've then got the SQS service. Now
SQS does get covered fairly heavily on the exam or at least there can be some fairly tricky questions
so we're going to go into that one probably in more detail than the others on this list and it's all
about message queuing so it's a way of decoupling your applications by being able to place messages
in a queue and then have other parts of your application infrastructure polling that queue and pulling the
messages from the queue. Amazon MQ is very similar except that it's based on Apache MQ
which is open source.
The key use case for Amazon MQ is when you have an existing environment on premise or in some other cloud
that's using Apache MQ message brokers and you want to migrate that into AWS. That's just a quick
overview of these services and a few examples of use cases.
What we're going to do now is go into more detail on each of these in the subsequent labs.