Hello and welcome to the container section of the course.
I'm quite excited about this section.
Containers are a very interesting technology.
They've been around for several years now and definitely in the last few years they've really exploded
in usage.
It doesn't matter if you don't have a background with containers as I'm going to start from the basics.
The key service that we're going to be looking at is the Elastic container service we''ll also cover the
Elastic Kubernetes service in some detail as well within this section.
Before we get into details of ECS let's just review what containers are.
So as you can see here ECS makes it easy to deploy management scale docker containers so Docker is a
software provider who really started the recent movement towards containerization and ECS is compatible
with Docker.
So let's just go over to a slide here.
Now this comes straight from the docker Web site and it just explains what a container is.
So I'm just going to quickly read through this to you.
So Docker say a container is a standard unit of software that packages up code and all its dependencies.
So the application runs quickly and reliably from one computing environment to another a docker container
image is a lightweight standalone executable package of software that includes everything needed to
run an application code runtime system tools system libraries and settings
so you then got a diagram here.
Now in the AWS the infrastructure is abstracted away from you.
So AWS manage the infrastructure you then have a host operating system.
Now there's a couple of different types of implementation of ECS that you can use.
They're called Launch types and we'll go into that in a bit more detail shortly.
In one type you don't actually have an operating system to manage and in the other you do.
But there's always going to be an operating system layer and then there's going to be the docker software
that sits above that.
And then the containers are where your application code resides.
And there they have the minimal information.
So just like it says here they have the code, the runtime, the systems or system libraries and settings.
It's the absolute minimum.
So they're quite small.
They're fast, you can start them and stop them extremely quickly much faster than you would
an instance or a virtual machine and it means that you can use these really well in micro services
environments where you can run lots of processes in parallel.
You can isolate them from each other so it doesn't matter about compatibility
at the operating system level because each of these is isolated from each other and you can scale them
very easily.
Let's have a look at the details of the Elastic Container Service now.
There are few components that you need to understand and we're going to go through these again and again
through this section so you really understand it.
Firstly there's the ECS cluster and there are two launch types with the Elastic container service. In one
you have EC2 instances that you manage and in the other you don't have an EC2 instances
to manage.
So it's more of a server-less service.
For now we're going to talk about the launch type where you do have EC2 instances and that's known
as the EC2 launch type.
So in the ECS cluster you have a logical grouping of EC2 instances within that cluster you then
have container instances.
So this is actually an EC2 instance.
You can go into the EC2 management console and you can see this instance running
and that instance runs the container agent and you use an ECS optimized AMI to launch a container instance.
And that way you actually get the agent installed for you.
You can install it manually if you like on another AMI
on top of a container instance.
We run tasks and these are actually containers and they're launched from a task definition which is
a file with some JSON in it like this.
So we have a task which is a running container using settings in a task definition.
We then have a service and the service which is optional you can run EC2 instances with tasks without
having the ECS service.
But if you install the ECS service we create a configuration using the ECS service.
What it does is it allows you to control the amount of tasks that are running and some of the parameters
of those tasks and you can also use auto scaling and attach an Elastic load balancer.
So the other thing you'll notice here is an image.
So the image sits in the Elastic container registry in this diagram.
It can also be in Docker Hub and in the case of this launch type, the EC2 launch type, where you have
your own instances to manage.
You can also use a self-hosted registry as well.
So what happens is you create your cluster you create your container instances within that cluster
and they could be spread across different Availability Zones.
You create a task definition and that defines how to launch a task and the task definition actually
references an image.
So this could be your WordPress image here for instance.
And here it tells you to launch this task with the WordPress image.
So when you run this task it's going to go to a registry and it's going to pull that image down so let's
just have a quick look now at launch types.
We talked about these just now and there's two different types you got EC2 and Fargate. EC2 is
what we just showed on the slide and with easy to launch type you have container instances.
So these are your EC2 instances and you can see on the right hand side hey you still got a cluster
you still got a service and you've got tasks but there are no container instances over here couple of
differences up the top four registries with it easy to launch type.
You can use the Elastic container registry Docker Hub or self hosted registry with the far right launch
type.
You can use the Elastic container registry and Docker Hub so there's no self-hosted registry of the
key differences you explicitly provision your EC2 instances.
And we'll see how you do that in the labs in this section with ECR.
You don't so that automatically provision.
There are two instances running somewhere that you don't see them so that's not something you have to
worry about and you don't have to manage them at all.
Whereas with the EC2 launch type you do have to manage those instances. Pricing is different as well
with the EC2 launch type, your charged per running EC2 instance so you're charged not for the
tasks that run but for the actual container instance.
With Fargate you're charged for the tasks so it's a different pricing model
to the EC2 launch launch type.
You can use persistent storage so you can attach persistent storage volumes to a task and that can be
EFS and EBS.
With Fargate
you can't.
There's no persistent storage options with Fargate launch type.
You handle any cluster optimization so you can actually launch and also scaling group for containers.
But it's not actually within EC2 it's within the ECS management console. Slightly different when you
use services because that has more of an integration at the task level in terms of Fargate.
They have little cluster optimization for you BBC to launch time.
You have more granular control you actually have to manage this instance you have root access to it
whereas with fargate you don't have that level of control so you've always got to think in a certain situation
for a certain solution.
Is it more important to abstract away some of that management and not have to worry about the management
so it's more operationally efficient or do you need some level of control where you need to get access
to the operating system.
Maybe you need to install some kind of management software for your organisation and that might sway
you towards using the EC2 launch type.
So that's it for this lesson.
I know this has been more theory than actual lab but we're gonna do lots and lots of labs in this section
so I just wanted to make sure that all this all these concepts are clear in your mind before we continue.