Hi, guys, in this lesson, I'm going to give you an overview of the I Am service, the Identity and
Access Management Service.
Now you have seen this in the last section when we logged in to U.S. and we configured our account.
We actually went into the IAM management console.
IAM is the identity and access management service, and it's a way that we can authenticate and be authorized
to access services on IWC.
So let's say we're connecting to an end up U.S. service via either the management console, the command
line interface or the API will connect to IWC IAM and we can then authenticate and all principles must
be authenticated to send requests.
Now what is a principle?
Well, a principle is a person or an application that can make a request for an action or an operation
on a resource.
Now, actions and operations are both where we're using the API to interact with an IWC service.
So we have users roles, federated users and applications.
We then have a couple of types of policy so we can assign permissions to users and then we can use policies
to control access to resources.
We have identity based policies and resource based policies, and these determine whether to authorize
the request, whether to allow or to deny the request to the resource.
And once you've got an allow or deny, assuming as a deny in this case, you're then able to run an
action against a resource.
Now remember I said that everything in IWC is an API call.
So when you're trying to launch an issue to instance, you're basically executing the run instances
command.
If you're trying to get information about an S3 buckets, you're running the gets bucket API action.
And if you're trying to create a user in IAM, you're running the create user action.
So whatever resource you're interacting with in IWC, an API action is actually being executed and you
need to have the permissions assigned to your accounts and you need to be allowed for a policy to be
able to actually perform that specific action.
So the actions are then authorized on the IWC resources.
So that's a really quick overview of what this service does.
And in the next lesson, we're going to delve in more depth into users groups, roles and policies.