And the short lesson I just want to cover off a top U.S. managed and customer managed policies so you
understand the difference.
So you've got the eight up U.S. managed policies.
These are standalone policies that are created and administered by a W.S. so that already in your account
and pre configured standalone policy means that the policy has its own aiyah and includes the policy
name.
Now, the managed policies are designed to provide permissions for common use cases and you can't change
those permissions.
So that defined for you and you can't modify them.
The following is a list of policies that are A.W. managed.
Now there's a lot of them in the console.
You can see them if you go into.
I am.
And look under policies and they'll have the type as a W.S. managed.
So we've used quite a few of these to then add them to roles, for instance, or groups.
Some A.W. manage policies are designed for specific job functions.
So you've got policies for these job functions.
So administrators' data scientists, security auditors, system administrators and so on.
We then have the customer managed policies.
So in this case, you create your own standalone policies that you administer in your own A.W. W.S.
account.
And these are referred to as customer managed policies.
So, again, standalone means they have their own ayran.
It means that they're an entity that exists independent of what you attach them to.
So you can then attach the policies to multiple principal entities in your A.W. account.
So both a W.S. managed and customer managed our standalone.
And again, that means that they exist independently.
So this is different to inline policies which only exist within the identity that you attached them
to when you attach a policy to a principal entity.
You then give that entity the permissions defined in the policy.
So this is just an example from the console on the left here.
We can see from the ACTU management console.
We've created a policy.
We've selected E.S. to all actions or resources and then as a condition in there that says that the
source IP address has to be a certain value and then that's on the right hand side.
What it would look like in Jason.
So those are the key things to understand.
And just remember that the use cases for managed policies are when you have job specific functions or
you need to use a policy for which the permissions defined in the managed policy are suitable for your
use case.
And then it might be an easy way to sort of apply that policy, and especially if you're using multiple
accounts so you can have some consistency between those accounts.
And at the end of the section, we actually cover all best practices.
And you'll see the best practice in certain circumstances is to use an A.W. managed policy.