Hi guys and welcome to the first lap of Section 4.
So what we're going to do in this lab is we're actually going to go through Amazon S3 and IAM roles.
So the reason that this is at the front of the Elastic Load Balancing section is we're going to be using
the Amazon Simple Storage Service (s3) for storing and retrieving some files that we're going to
use with our EC2 instances.
So what I want to do and this is part of the theme of this course is to introduce something to you get
you to use it and then build on that knowledge.
So rather than just having an S3 section which we do we have a very detailed deep dive section
on S3 later in the course.
But I want to start introducing you to S3 and to IAM Roles which are identity and access management
roles right now because you need to use them for Elastic Load Balancing and then we'll keep using those
skills throughout the course so you'll build upon them.
So what is Amazon S3.
So it's the Simple Storage Service and it's an object based storage system.
So what you do is you upload objects which are files to S3 Buckets.
A bit more information on this slide than you actually need at this stage but you just need to understand
that you access S3 using a URL, it's a public service so it's available directly via the public internet
so it sits outside your VPC and you'll access it through an Internet gateway.
There is another method to access S3 directly from a VPC but that's not for this section we'll do that
in the S3 section of the course.
So anyone on the Internet can then use the URL to access the objects in the bucket as long as the permissions
are set to share those objects to those people.
So that's what S3 is
It's just a way of storing files.
And what we're going to do in this section of the course is we're going to create some buckets which
are the containers in which your objects reside.
And we're going to put some objects and files within those buckets and then our EC2 instances are
going to pull those files down when they launch and we're going to use those as part of the demonstration
of elastic load balancing.
So that's just a quick overview S3 we're going to go into the console in a minute and have a look
at it. Before we get there.
Let's just have a quick look at IAM roles.
So identity and access management is the service that allows you to create users, groups, and roles and specify
policies and password policies and that kind of thing.
Now we did go over a brief overview of IAM earlier in the course.
But right now we're talking about roles. What a role is is it's an identity to which you can assign permissions
through a policy and then you're able to assume that role.
So what that means is rather than your EC2 instance or user account directly having the permissions
to access an S3 bucket you specify the permissions in a policy, attach the policy to a role, and
then that EC2 instance can assume the role temporarily and it gives it some short lived credentials
to allow it to access the data in the bucket according to the permissions policy.
So this is a way of not storing the access key and secret ID that you would need to access the bucket
for programmatically on the EC2 instance.
So we'll see in the console we're actually going to do this we're going to set up an EC2 instance
and you're going to see how we can access an S3 bucket without storing some credentials.
So that means we're more secure because we're not storing those access key IDs and secret keys within
the EC2 instance which is definitely a no no from a security perspective.
So that's just a quick overview.
Let's go into the console and we're going to look at how this works.
So I'm in the Amazon S3 console and you can see that I already have some buckets here.
And so a couple of things about these the name of the bucket needs to be unique.
So you remember from the URL here that this portion here is the bucket name.
So it's even a here bucket.s3.aws-region and that would be the actual region name or it's on the
end here slash bucket name.
So that would be the name of your bucket.
So it's a public DNS name and therefore it must be unique globally.
However you might notice here as well that the region is specified.
So that means that though the namespace is global you actually store your data within a region so you
can see up here that this is a global service.
You don't choose a region but when you create a bucket you specify where you want your data to be stored.
So that's something important to remember.
So what we can do also is make up objects public or we can secure them with policies.
Now what we're going to do now is I'm just going to show you how to create a bucket so let's just call
this DCT labs test and I can specify the region I want to place these files in and choose Sydney and
you can then just click Create there's some more stuff in the wizard you can go through and you can
specify by some information around versioning and object logging and encryption.
You can also configure your public settings and you then just create your bucket.
So that's how you create a bucket.
It's as simple as that.
I don't need this one because I'm actually going to use this DCT labs bucket for the exercises in this
course.
So I can delete now when you delete you have to copy the bucket nine so you can take that from here.
Copy paste and then you can confirm deletion and that's gone.
So that's S3.
That's what it looks like and what we're going to do now is we're going to go too EC2 and I'm going
to show you how you can access an S3 bucket.
So I'm in the EC2 management console and I'm going to choose launch an instance I'm just going to use
a Amazon Linux to my T2 micro and I'm going to leave all these settings as default, all I need to do
is go through and I'm going to select my web access security group so I can access the instance over
SSH port 22.
So I'll just give that instance a minute to launch and then we'll get started again.
Hi guys.
I'm now logged into the instance that we started and what I want to do is run an AWS CLI command
aws s3 ls.
So this should list the buckets in my NWS account and assess unable to locate credentials you can configure
credentials by running aws configure.
So let's have a look at aws configure.
So this tool allows you to specify your access key I.D. and your secret access key.
But what I need to do is just generate a new one for this test.
So of course normally you wouldn't want to share that.
So I'm just going to use it and then delete it.
But let's just grab an access key I.D. paste that in it will ask for the secret access key.
Remember this only gets shown once so you can only access it at this stage.
I'm gonna go back paste that in.
It asked me for the default region I'm gonna use AP southeast-2 and I can just hit enter.
So now let's try rerunning that command and that's great.
So now I can actually see the buckets I have access to as free using my access key I.D. and secret access
key.
But the problem is the credentials are stored on this machine.
So if we run ls .aws/credentials.
There's a file here and actually if I run the tool cat so I can actually look inside this file.
You can see that the access key I.D. and secret access key are stored on the easy to instance.
So this is very insecure.
We don't want to do this.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm just going to remove
the file and I should now I've lost access so if I rerun that command I'm no no longer able to access
S3
That's fine.
What we're gonna use now is an IAM role.
So if you remember with an IAM role.
What we're going to do is get the EC2 instance to use the role or assume the role in order to access
the bucket and we give the IAM role certain permissions through a permissions policy.
So this is a secure way because we don't end up storing those credentials on the instance.
So let's go to IAM and set up a role.
So I'm in IAM and I'm going to create a role.
And what we need to do is choose the service that we use the role we're going to choose EC2.
Which means that EC2 instances are able to call aws services.
So we'll use that choose next and you can now choose from some predefined permissions policy.
And I'm gonna choose this one S3 full access and I'm going to call it S3 dash admin and we choose
create role and if we go down and have a look at that role now we'll see that's under trust relationships.
Edit trust relationship we can see a policy here and what it says is it allows the service Ec2.
Amazon.aws.com to assume role.
So that's the trust relationship that we allowed and then if we actually have a look at the policy we
can see the JSON code here and it says the effect is allow S3* so wild card and any resource.
So it's given us full access to S3 free.
So that's what it looks like.
What we need to do now is attach it to our EC2 instance.
So we go into instance settings and then we go attach replace IAM role and we can choose our role from
the list and click apply and that's it.
We should now head back to the console and rerun our command to see our S3 Buckets so let's
run that command again and this time we've got the buckets.
But there's no credentials stored on the EC2 instance.
So we're much more secure now.
So that's it for this lab guys.
We're gonna get straight onto Elastic Load Balancing now and you're gonna use some of the skills you've
just learned multiple times throughout the rest of this section.