And this lesson, I'm going to cover the DNS system and Amazon around 53.
So let's start off talking about what DNS is.
It's called the domain name system.
Now DNS is a way that we can resolve the IP address of servers internally in our company networks as
well as on the internet.
So remember I said earlier in the course that when we connect to a computer over a network, we connect
via the IP address.
But the IP address is not a very friendly name to remember.
And that's why we use domain names.
So, for example, here we have a user on a computer and an internal company network, and there's a
web server running in that network.
Now, the user wants to use a browser to connect to the web server, and they can put in a domain name,
which is much easier to remember than an IP address.
So in this case, it's my company, Dot Local.
The computer will then go to a DNS server, so it already has the addresses of the DNS server stored
in its configuration so it can connect to the DNS server and ask the DNS server question.
It will say What is the IP address to my company Dot Local?
Now, the DNS server has a database which stores this information, so it knows that the IP address
value is 192.168.0.1, so it returns that information back to the requesting computer and the computer
that can then connect directly to the web server using the IP address.
Now this happens on the internet as well, and we can use a service called Amazon Route 53, both for
our resources within us and also on the internet.
So let's say we have an internet connected computer here, and we have a web service running and an
IWC data center within the Amazon Route 50 free service, which is a dinner service.
We create something called a hosted zone, and the hosted zone stores the records belonging to that
domain.
This domain is example dot com.
So now our user on the internet can connect to Amazon, ran out 50 free and ask What is the IP address,
for example, dot com.
The address gets returned and the browser is then able to connect to the web server using its IP address.
So that's how DNS and Route 53 works at a basic level.
Now, Route 53 is an intelligent DNS service.
We can use things called routing policies.
Now these do go a little bit beyond the scope of the exam.
You shouldn't be asked in the cloud process you to remember these, but I just want to give you an idea
of the capabilities of Route 53.
So what we were just looking at is something called a simple routing policy, simply saying, Well,
I want to know what the IP is, for example, dot com.
We can also have a failure that means we have multiple IP addresses associated with a name, and DNS
will automatically route users or computers to the secondary address if it knows that the primary is
failed.
It can do routing based on the location of the actual request.
Where is it coming from in the world or based on latency?
What is the delay on the line, the distance between the requester and the actual resource, and it
tries to direct you to the closest resource possible.
It can provide multiple answers, or you can have waited where you say, Well, I want to send 80 percent
of my traffic to one record and 20 percent to another.
So it's quite clever.
It does all of those different things.
Now there are a few more features as well.
We have two main registration, so you can actually register our own domains.
We can create the hosted zones, which is what we just looked at.
It also does health checks so it can actually connect to your resources and check that they're responding,
that they're healthy.
It uses these health checks to determine the status of your resources so it knows wherever to send any
traffic that or not.
There's also something called traffic flow, which gives you another level of automation for how you
send your traffic to your resources.
So that's all I want to cover for Amazon Brown 53.
I'll see you in the next lesson.