Welcome to the databases section of the course. There's lots of great labs
we're going to get stuck into in this section
But before we do that there's a bit of theory to cover.
So I want to start off talking about the difference between relational and non relational databases.
And then shortly we're going to talk about the difference between certain use cases and optimizations
where a database is more suitable for operational workloads or analytical workloads before I get stuck
into the discussion.
I just want to mention that in these areas there's definitely a few grey areas.
So the statements which I'm making some of these are a bit broad in that they can be argued in some
way that some some databases will take on the actual characteristics for instance of relational and non relational
or operational and analytics.
But for the purposes of this exam what I'm giving you here is a good starting point.
And this is pretty much what you need to know.
So, as an architecture exam you need to be able work out given a specific scenario
what is the best database that you should be using or what is the most operationally efficient option
to use or what is the highest performance option or which one has the most ability to manage it at the
operating system level.
Those are all the sorts of things that you need to know.
And so let's get started and we'll talk about relational and non relational first.
The key differences are how data are managed and stored. With relational data is stored in tables rows
and columns with non-relational data is varied.
So it's not in a fixed form.
There can be hierarchies for instance, relational databases have a rigid schema and SQL stands
for Structured Query Language and that's the language that you use to query and find the data.
And it's a very powerful language. With non-relational
there's a flexible schema so it's known as NoSQL.
It doesn't have the same capabilities for searching.
At least it's more limited more simple.
And the schema is flexible.
So that means that the data can be varied.
So what data is associated with an individual item or record can be different throughout the database.
There are different types of non-relational database.
We have key value pairs, columnar, documents, or graph databases.
And I'll just show you a diagram just to make this a bit more clear.
So in this example here we have a key value store and it's Amazon dynamoDB and we can see some items
in the database and we can see a number associated with them.
But let's have a look at the actual beats.
So products I.D. one here the first item has Odyssey Homer and 1871 has attributes.
So we've got a book we've got an author and we have a publishing date.
But the second item here has six bar teachers and bark.
So this is I suppose a symphony and a composer.
So there are different attributes between different records.
You don't get that with a relational database.
You have your columns and you must populate those columns with the same data for each record in your
database.
So this gives you lots and lots of flexibility with a non-relational database.
So those rules I just mentioned they're in force within the database for relational database.
You can have rules for your non relational database but they're not in the database they're in the code
that you use to manipulate data to read and write data in your database. Relational databases are typically
scaled vertically.
So when we get to the RDS section which is one of the Amazon relational databases you'll see that you
actually use EC2 instances for the database.
So when you want to scale the database you have to choose a larger instance one with more CPU and memory
whereas with DynamoDB for instance, the non-relational database we just talked about, it scales horizontally.
So it's scaling sideways and that means you don't have to worry about the limitations and how big your
instance can go vertically, scaling horizontally typically means you can scale a lot further. Relational
databases support complex queries and joins. So joins means joins between tables and complex queries
means the ability of the SQL language to be able to perform all sorts of complexity in times
in terms of the way that you query the data in the database.
This is a phrase that you might see come up on the exam.
So look out for that when they say that you will you require support for complex queries and joins you
know it's relational database is probably going to be RDS. Non-relational is unstructured.
So simple language that supports any kind of schema as we saw in the diagram the structure is different
for our database and you can change it at any time. Relational databases are typically ACID compliance
and this is stands for Atomicity, consistency, isolation, and durability.
So just think relational when you think about relational database is they're optimized for consistency
they're optimized for integrity of the database whereas. With non relational they're more optimized for
performance rather than consistency and integrity and a few examples here we talked about RDS other
ones out there for relational Oracle.
MySQL which you can run on RDS, by the way MariaDB and Postgresql which can also
be run on RDS and then in the non relational world do you have Amazon dynamoDB,  MongoDB a very
popular database and then you have Redis and...
So just going back to this slide here just to give you an idea of some of the other types.
So we have the document database so these are non relational database types remember there are several
different types you got key value document and graph here.
Just going back to the slide you also have column databases as well.
So this is MongoDB.
So you could run MongoDB on an EC2 instance but there's no actual Amazon service for this.
But in this case you can see that it's got the name of a movie and it's got some information about that
movie and then it's got a jpeg file associated with it.
We've then got Amazon Neptune which is a graph type of database.
So what this means is its priority is to find the relations between data between data.
So for instance if you have users like Howard here you can see that Howard is friends with Jack who's
friends of Annie who's friends with Sam.
And if that relationship between those users is useful to you to know then a graph database is going
to be the way to go.
Think things like Facebook where the relations between people are very very important.
That's where a lot of the value of the database comes from.
The next thing we need to talk about is the difference between operational and analytical databases
and what we're really talking about here are the use cases and how the data bases optimized so on the
left you have the operational or also known as transactional databases and this is known as online transaction
processing or OLTP.
So here we're talking about production.
DBs that process transactions.
So if you think about your public facing applications they speak to a database.
Customers could be updating records.
They could be placing orders they could be checking stocks available that kind of thing.
The database that you use for that is going to be an operational database or a transactional database.
So what you're looking at is fairly short transactions and simple queries.
Someone's looking at what is something available in the database they're buying some shoes they want
to check if the shoes were available and they're going to place an order.
So it's very fast.
The order is complete done on the other hand you have the analytical databases also known as online
analytics processing or OLAP databases and your source data comes from your OLTPs.
So you might have a OLDP database and perhaps you've got them around the world around the
country.
You've got lots of different databases and what you need to do is create a data warehouse and that you're
going to use that so that you can extract data and make decisions understand your customers understand
their buying habits look at trends that kind of thing.
So what you do is you aggregate that data into a data warehouse and then you can perform your queries
and these are gonna be complex queries and they're often going to take a long time.
So you're looking at complex queries sometimes could run for hours or days and they're going to take
a lot of CPU power or a lot of overall compute power.
So you definitely don't want to run those kind of queries on your transactional processing databases
because that's going to slow down your system and affect your user experience.
So instead you take the data offline you put it all into a data warehouse and then you can do all those
queries on it.
So a few examples here for relational examples are ideas Oracle IBM DB to and mySQL and then
for non relational OLTP databases we've got MongoDB, Cassandra and neo4J and Hbase and
then we have analytical we've got Amazon Redshift which we'll be covering in this section.
And then you've got things like Teradata and hedge P Vertica as well.
And then for non relational analytical databases you've got Amazon EMR which will also cover in this
section and you've got map reduce.
So I know there's a lot to take in here but you really do need to know this stuff for the exam.
Make sure you understand the differences between these different types of database and also which products
fit into which category.
So one more slide to go.
And then we'll be out to start getting onto the laps this slide is just to help you understand some
typical use cases.
So it's not just the managed services like RDS and dynamoDB and redshift in some cases users might
want to install their database on EC2.
And you would do that if you want full control over the instance and database or the database that you
want is not available underaged.
Yes.
So for instance you might want to install a database like MongoDB or you might want to install a database
that has a version or maybe a licensing configuration or a configuration setting that's just not supported
under RDS or any of the other managed services.
So in that case you can install and you can launch an EC2 instance and install your database on
it and you get full control then over managing the instance in the database.
Of course that comes at the cost of the operational overhead.
We've then got Amazon RDS and this is a managed service and it's used for OLTP type of use
cases and it's SQL so it's for well-formed structured data then we've got dynamoDB.
So this is a name value pair data that's a noSQL database you use it if you have an unpredictable
data structure you get great in memory performance with persistence and later in this section we'll
talk a bit more about the performance of dynamoDB and the options available but if you need high
IO and dynamic scaling dynamoDB is a great option.
We then got one of the warehouses which AWS provides which is Amazon Redshift.
So this is a managed data warehouse solution primarily for analytics processing.
We've then got Amazon Neptune.
So this is the graph database and this is when relationships between objects are of high value you won't
see complex questions I don't think you'll see complex questions in the exam about Amazon Neptune but
you will get something with where the use case is clearly a graph database you just need to know that
Neptune is the graph database.
The next one is Amazon Elasticache.
This is an in-memory database used for temporary storage for small amounts of data so great performance
volatile data though so it's not way you wouldn't use this as your primary database but you use it to
improve the performance of your primary database.
That being said it does depend whether you're using the memcached or Redis versions because redis
does allow you to store data persistently within an elasticache but we'll get onto that later in
this section.
So that's it for this theory lesson.
Hopefully that made a lot of sense to you.
There are lots of great documents.
I'll put a few links into the course download but there's you know there's great reading to do on the
AWS Web site as well as other Web sites just to really understand some of this and a bit more detail
and I suggest you go and have a look at those documents because it is really important because it is
an architecture exam so they will be testing your ability to choose the right solution in a specific
scenario.