This section of the course we're going to talk about the elastic block store and the elastic file system.
So if you've already done the Amazon S3 section of the course at the very beginning I talked about
the difference between object based storage systems which is what Amazon S3 is and block-based storage
systems and file-based storage systems which is what EBS and EFS are.
If you haven't seen that it might be worth checking it out but I'll recap most of what I said here.
So with the elastic block store this is a block based storage system and you can think of a block based
storage system as being analogous to a drive that's in your computer so a disk drive in your computer
which would be a hard disk drive or solid state drive and your operating system of your computer would
be able to then access that disk create partitions on that disk create file systems and format those
file systems and then store data on it.
So your operating system can interact with an EBS volume in the same way and it really is a hard disk
drive or solid state drive that's sort of located somewhere else.
So it's actually accessed over the network and connected to your EC2 instance you can think of an
EBS volume then as a virtual hard drive in the cloud and your computer sees it as a device.
This is different to an elastic file system with EFS the file system is already created somewhere else
and formatted and then presented to your computer.
So in this case your EC2 instance then connects to it using a protocol over the network.
So in this case with EFS it's NFSv1 so you connect to and mount that.
So it's not a device mapping.
It's a mount point on your computer a couple of key differences between EBS and EFS as the diagram
shows what we have here is one EC2 instance accessing one volume.
Now you can have multiple volumes attached to the same EC2 instance but you can't have multiple
EC2 instances attached to a single volume so you can't share volumes between computers.
You can detach it from one computer and then attach it to another computer but they can't both access it at
the same time with EFS you can have multiple computers accessing the same file system so they can
be reading and writing to the exact same file system and you can have them across multiple Availability
Zones whereas with EBS the volume and the EC2 instance must be in the same availability zone.
You can even have an on premises client connecting into your VPC over a VPN and accessing the EFS
file system.
Now one note point is that Linux only for EFS
You can't connect a Windows instance to SFS.
You can pretty much run whatever you want on your EC2 instance with a block storage system.
So with EBS. So that's some high level information on EBS and EFS.
And now we're going to cover both technologies off in a series of labs.