In this lesson, I want to help you to understand the differences between scaling up and scaling out.
And this is all about what we call elasticity.
So you might have heard this term before or scalability.
Now the key difference between scalability and elasticity is with scalability.
We're saying that we're going to add a certain amount of resources.
So for example, if you have a hard drive in your computer and you need of some more storage space where
you can buy another hard drive, plug it in and now you have a bit more space.
That would be scalability.
Now, elasticity means that when you no longer need the space anymore, it's going to automatically
shrink back.
It's elastic like an elastic band if you stretch it and then it contracts again.
Now that wouldn't happen if you just bought a hard drive because now you've already bought it.
So it's there now with the cloud, we can automatically scale things up and out and then back in again
when we don't need as many resources.
And that's one of the key benefits of the cloud because we're only paying for what we use.
We're not paying for the underlying infrastructure layer.
You can certainly scale your resources on premises, but you're always going to pay for the underlying
layer.
So that's a fixed cost.
It's not a variable cost.
So let's have a look at scaling up versus scaling out now.
Scaling up is also known as vertical scaling.
So here we have an easy to instance.
The easy to instance has a certain amount of hardware.
Now scaling up means that we add more hardware, we have more CPU's, we have more memory, more storage
space, maybe some more network bandwidth or an additional adapter.
So that would be scaling up scaling vertically.
Essentially, we're adding resources to that instance.
It's just one instance, but it's got more resources assigned to it.
There's a bit of a limitation here in that you still have a single point of failure.
Imagine you've got a really important application and it keeps becoming more popular.
And so you add more resources, but it's just one instance.
Now what happens if that instance fails for some reason?
Well, now everything has gotten.
So you've essentially got all your eggs in one basket.
So another option is scaling out, also known as horizontal scaling.
So here are applications becoming more popular.
So we add another instance of the application and then another one and another one scaling out gives
you more resiliency.
You don't have all your eggs in one basket.
You now have multiple baskets.
And if any one of these fails, then the other ones can take over the load.
With this model, you can add almost unlimited capacity.
When you're scaling up, you can often reach a limit a ceiling as to how much resource you can assign
with scaling out.
That's not usually the case.
You can keep scaling out again and again.
So how do you do this with Amazon Resources?
Well, for example, with EC2, we might have 80 to instance, so that's a certain instance.
Type has a certain amount of CPU and RAM.
In this case, it's a two micro with one VC CPU, a one gigabyte ram, so not a lot of resources.
Now we can always change the instance type, and maybe we move it to a C five or X launch, which has
got four VC CPUs and eight gigabytes of RAM.
So now we have an instance with more resources.
It's the same instance.
We just change the instance type.
So that's vertical scaling with horizontal scaling.
We simply add more instances.
So now we've got lots of these two micro instances, which means we have more capacity.
So that's how you scale up and scale out.
And in the next lesson, you'll learn about Amazon EC2 auto scaling, which enables you to launch and
terminate instances and scale out and back in again automatically.