Hi, guys, Adewusi cloud formation is a very exciting and powerful service, and I think we're going
to have a lot of fun in this section because there's lots of demos to do and also a bit of code to play
around with.
So what is cloud formation?
Firstly, cloud formation is a service that allows you to manage, configure and provision your infrastructure
as code.
So that means that you can define in code what your infrastructure should look like and then cloud formation
can go out and build it for you.
So, for example, we have a template on the right hand side here, and this actually is for building
a lamp stack, which we're going to do shortly.
So Linux, Apache, MySQL and Python on a Linux instance.
And what it does is it gives you the option here to specify certain attributes about that instance so
we can have a parameter for the key name, the easy to keep here.
We're going to use the database name, the database user and so on.
And there'll be other parameters about what type of resource.
So the two instance, you're going to create the amid the instance type, you're going to use that kind
of thing.
So this is just a small snippet of the code.
So it gives you a common language to describe and provisioned the infrastructure resources in your HWC
cloud environment.
The resources are defined in what we call a template.
So what you see on the right hand side here is an example of the code that would be in a in a cloud
formation template.
So we can also visualize that as well.
It's not just shown to us in code form.
You can actually visualize like on the right hand side here, and we'll see that in the console shortly.
So this is an example of a high availability stack with WordPress.
So it includes a database, it includes security groups, a Web server and Albi target group there,
the actual application load balancer and a listener and then and also skiting group.
So cloud information can be used to provision a really broad range of AWB resources.
Think of cloud formation as deploying infrastructures codes.
That's a term you often hear a lot.
This is what infrastructure is.
A code really looks like.
You're defining the infrastructure you want to build like this on the right hand side here through a
template using code like you see on the left hand side here.
So just quickly to differentiate, because sometimes cloud formation and elastic beanstalk are considered
together.
Now they are different things.
And so this should make that more clear to you.
Now, Elastic Beanstalk is covered in the next section of the course.
I think the reason why they're often talked about together is because they both essentially do a level
of automation.
You can think of cloud formation as deploying your infrastructure, using code, so using a template
to deploy infrastructure.
So we're talking about two instances.
We're talking about security groups.
We're talking about load balances, all of those different things.
Now, Elastic Beanstalk is really focused on applications.
So it does launch load balancers.
It does launch all these instances.
It does launch two instances and auto scanning groups, but it's all about the application.
So it's actually attempting to give you a way to deploy, for instance, a no JS website using your
code by just uploading it and having it automate that infrastructure for you.
So there's a lot more limited in what it can do, whereas cloud formation can pretty much be used for
every service inside of us.
With cloud formation, you're using JSON or Yamal formatted template files, whereas the elastic beanstalk,
you're not describing your infrastructure in code as such, you're uploading your application code.
And then there are some configuration files as well, which we'll talk about an elastic beanstalk section.
So confirmation is actually used to deploy the environments that you create an elastic beanstalk.
So when we go into the Elastic Beanstalk section, we'll see that when we create an environment using
elastic beanstalk, we can go into cloud formation and see that it's actually doing the building for
us.
So let's just talk about some of the key benefits of cloud formation.
Why would you want to use cloud formation?
So the infrastructure is provisioned consistently, so this removes or reduces the risk of human error.
Of course, you still have to write your code correctly, but once you return it, once you can redeploy
that infrastructure over again without making mistakes, or you can use segments of that code and copy
it into different templates and know that you're reusing code that's been written correctly, it reduces
the amount of time and effort that you need to put into configuring resources, because this is automating
it for you.
You can also use version control and peer review, if you can, information templates, and it's free
to use.
So you're only charged for the resources that are provisioned by cloud formation, not for confirmation
itself.
You can also manage updates and dependencies and it can be used to roll back and delete the entire stack
as well.
So that's a bit of fairy on cloud formation.
What I want to do now is get straight into the console and let's actually start looking at what cloud
formation looks like.
So I'm in the North Virginia region, so I'm in USD one, and I suggest you for this entire section
do change to us one.
And the reason is we're going to be using some code templates and I've already got the region specified
in those templates.
So you can change that.
But just to make life easier, you might want to just change to North Virginia.
So let's head over to cloud formation, which is under management and governance.
Now, I just want to go back to the slides to discuss a few key concepts.
So firstly, there's templates.
So these are the Jason Oyamel text files that contain instructions to build the environment.
And we saw some snippets of code on previous slides.
You then have a stack.
So this is what we're going to create now.
So the stack is when you actually use your template to build out some infrastructure using cloud formation
stack sets, then allow you to do what stacks do but across accounts so you can actually create update
or delete stacks across accounts using one operation.
And then this change sets, which will cover later on in this section, which is where you can have
a look at what you what your changes are going to do to your infrastructure without actually putting
those changes into effect.
So essentially visualizing what's going to happen to make sure that you've got good code.
So coming back in, we've got we're going to create a stack now, so we choose Crate Stack and then
we have a few options so we can use a template that we have on S3 or upload a file, or we can use a
sample template or create our own template in the designer.
So let's just go to use a sample template and we can see that there's several different options here.
So we're just going to choose this one up the top lamp stack.
And what we can do now is we can click on this view in designer, and this is actually going to show
us the infrastructure that's going to be built.
Now, in this case, it's simply a Web server instance and a security group.
And you can see a few of the potential dependencies and things that are going to be associated with
that.
But what I really want to draw your attention to is down here.
So this is the code and this is in Jason format.
You can switch it to Yamal and that typically makes it quite a bit more easy to read, as you can see,
because it has less formatting on it.
So it really depends what you're most familiar with.
So in this template file, we can see the infrastructure that's going to be built.
Now we're going to go through the anatomy of these template files within the sections so that you understand
the key components of the template file.
But for now, all we want to do is just choose this option here, create stack and the template file
has been loaded for us and you can see it's from S3.
We can choose next.
Try to stack nine.
I just called this lamp stack.
And now it's going to ask us for some parameters, so I'm just going to change this to Digital Cloud
for the DB name, password, password and user.
And then we can choose the instance type, you might want to change this, for instance, to to micro,
you can specify a keeper and you can specify some other parameters as well.
You can add tags.
You can specify roles if you need to.
And then there are some more options here around STAC policies.
So this is adjacent document that defines the update actions that you can perform on resources.
There's a roll back configuration, there's a roll back configuration where you can specify alarms to
monitor.
There's notification options using essense and stack creation options.
So by default it enables rollback on failure.
So if anything goes wrong, it will automatically roll this back.
And you can also enable termination protection.
If you want to make sure that you can't actually delete this stack.
We now have an option where we can look at estimate cost and it actually brings up the calculator and
shows us what this is going to cost us.
So you can say it's going to cost eight point fifty a month.
So we now get to review all the various parameters that have been specified and we can just leave all
those details and choose create stack.
So we now get taken to this screen where we can see a list of events, so there's several different
options up here, which we're going to go through in this section.
But for now, we've just got the events shown and we can see that we have a crate in progress.
And if we had over two to, we should now see that we have this instance initializing.
So this should be our two micro instance and that's being created by cloud formation.
So that just took a few minutes to complete.
And we've now got a green create complete.
So it's all worked successfully.
Now, if you look on the resources, we can see that we have some resources here.
So it's telling us the Web server security group is being created.
So we could click on this and it will actually take us and we'll see the security group that is created
by cloud formation.
And we can also see the Web server instance.
And that's going to link us to our AC2 instance so you can see the instant side here.
So note that for the resources here, you have a logical ID and a physical ID.
So the logical ID is what's to find within the template and then the physical IP corresponds to the
actual resource in us.
You can also see the resource type here and we'll cover that off in another lesson.
We then have outputs.
So you can see here that there's been an output defined in the template that tells us the URL to go
to so we could click on this URL and it takes us to our information sample.
We can also see parameters.
So this lets us review what parameters were defined in the template and you can review the template
here as well or view it again in the designer.
So that's very simple.
Now, the other thing I want to show you is what happens when you need to remove your stack so you can
literally go in and click on delete and delete stack and it warns us it's going to remove all our resources
and this is going to automatically roll back the entire configuration.
So we should quickly find the our instance turns into a shutting down state.
So that's going to be terminated and our security group will be deleted very shortly as well.
So that just took a few moments and our deletion is complete.
And if we go back up to stacks, you can see the stacks gone.
It's often worth monitoring your stack deletion, though, because sometimes things can get stuck and
you might even have to go and remove a resource manually.
So that's it for this lesson.
And in the next lesson, we're going to start looking at templates.