Hi guys.
We're about to get started on the storage section of the course and I just wanted to talk about the
three different types of storage that we're going to be covering.
So first there's Amazon S3
The simple storage service then the elastic block service or EBS.
And lastly the elastic file system (EFS).
Now these are very different types of storage systems and I wanted to throw in a theory-based lecture
just to discuss some of the differences in the use cases so let's get started with Amazon S3
S3 is an object storage system which means you load you upload your files as objects and it uses
an Internet accessible public endpoint.
So this is a HTTP address which contains the region the bucket and the object and there's a couple of
different formats for this but this is one of them.
And what you actually use to manipulate objects.
So to upload objects to download objects to delete objects and so on is a REST API and that uses HTTP
verbs (methods) so you use the HTTP get requests which is what you normally use to retrieve a web page.
The HTTP put requests which is what you use to upload to a website and so on.
Then you've got the posts and the select and the delete so you should consider S3 as being a web service
that's accessible via a public endpoint you can connect your EC2 to it but they go out
via an Internet gateway to an Internet endpoint unless you are using a VPN endpoint which we'll talk about
later in this section and then obviously you can access it from any Internet clients as well and you
would do so through a rest api.
So the common use cases are backup application hosting media hosting software delivery so that's Amazon
S3
So that's your object storage system we'll then move on to the elastic block store (EBS) which is a block
storage system.
And what that means is that data within hard disk drives or solid state drives is accessed in blocks
which are within sectors and tracks on the disk.
So if you think about your computer whether you've got a laptop or or a desktop machine it has a hard
disk drive in it or a solid state drive and the operating system accesses that through a bus which is
typically a SCSI bus or a serial ATA bus. SCSI stands for small computer systems interface and is
usually used on server systems and then you have the serial ATA or SATA bus which is used in more
well it's used in server systems as well but it's also often used in client systems like laptops and desktop
computers and those are high performance buses within your computer which then can talk directly to
a disk drive. You then format that disk drive or you create partitions and then format those partitions
and then you can store your data on them and typically the actual disk itself is quite close to the
computer so you know whether you're using a USB drive for instance which you wouldn't typically use
in an application environment because of the performance limitations but you know that cable can only
be so long from your computer it can't be you know more than maybe a few feet I'm not sure about the
exact specifications and it's the same with the SCSI bus in the SATA so they need to be very close
to the actual computer so there's a small distance between the disk and the computer and that's why
they're typically internal to the actual computer itself.
Now in the case of the elastic block store it's actually accessed over a network.
So if you're from a traditional on premise environment you'll know that you can use the iSCSI protocol
or fibre channel to send the commands that would be sent to the disk over a network so Fibre Channel
is a dedicated storage network and then iSCSI is is where you actually encapsulate those SCSI commands
with an Ethernet header and send it over a traditional network and then you'd have a storage array
with a series of disks and some controllers which then receive that data.
And that's pretty much what the elastic block store is but it's transparent to you.
So all you need to worry about with EC2 and EBS is choosing the size and the type and the size of your
volume and then you can adjust some of the performance characteristics as well.
So in terms of use cases for EBS. firstly your operating system of your EC2 instance will be installed
on an EBS volume so whether it's Windows or Linux EBS is what's used for the operating system.
In fact you can't store an operating system on S3.
You can't install to an operating system on the EFS either.
So you must use a block based storage system for your operating system you also might use it for database
systems file systems transactional logs that kind of thing.
So anywhere where you have high performance requirements you need low latency and you need the ability
to be able to have a good granularity in how you configure your performance characteristics of your
storage system
the third type is the elastic file system.
So this is a file system that's actually created for you so you know it's actually means that somewhere
there's a block based storage system where the server that's presenting that system to you has already
created the partitions it's already formatted the file system and is now able to present that file
system to you.
So whereas with EBS you mount the block storage to a device mapping within your Linux operating system
with EFS you mount it using the NFSv1 protocol to a mount point which you can create.
And what happens then is you'll just see the file system and whatever files already exist on that file
system that you're mounting. Now with EBS your EC2 instance and your EBS volume must be in the same
availability zone.
However with an EFS file system your instances can be in different availability zones mounting
the same file system and you can actually have a large number of instances mounting the same file system
whereas with EBS it's a one to one mapping.
So only one EC2 instance to one EBS volume you can also connect and on premises clients or server
to an elastic file system and for that you need a VPN.
Note that this is for Linux only whereas you can use Windows or Linux for your EC2 instance and
connect to the EBS volume and you can have any client that has the ability to use a REST API for Amazon
S3.
So those are some of the differences between S3, EBS, and EFS.
So whenever exam questions come up just remember S3 is the object storage system and you use HTTP
verbs (methods) to access a public endpoint, EBS is for block-based storage, hard disk drives, solid state
drives, operating systems, and you must be in the same availability zone as your instance.
And then EFS is when you're looking at file systems which you might want to mount from multiple EC2
instances within different Availability Zones and even on premises clients over a VPN so use cases for
EFS include home directories, shared corporate directories, database backups, big data analytics.
Just remember you cannot issue block level commands or format file systems with NFS mounted
file system that's already being shared from somewhere else.
So that's it just an overview of object block and file storage and now we'll get on with the S3 section.