I just want to bring a few tools to your attention, which are useful if you're performing a migration.
Now, these aren't necessarily covered on the Solutions Architects exam, but I just wanted to mention
them because I thought it would be remiss not to.
And the reason being that if you're doing the migration to the cloud and your solutions architect,
you're going to need to do some calculations to work out what is the cost going to be in Adaba US and
also what is the cost of your existing infrastructure and new applications on premises so that you can
do that comparison and work out what are the cost savings on a W.S.?
So there's a few tools that you can use.
The first one is the W.S. Simple Monthly Calculator.
This has been around for quite a while and I'll show you it, but it is actually being replaced by the
A.W. as pricing calculator, which is new.
We've then got the A.W. W.S. Total Cost of ownership calculator.
The TCO calculator.
So that's the one where you can actually plug in your on premises costs and then see how much that is
costing you.
And then what are your savings going to be in the cloud?
So just a little bit more on the TCO calculator.
Because this one requires a bit more explanation.
So this is about looking at your on premises costs and then comparing those to the cloud.
So it gives you that directional guidance on what cost savings you might achieve.
So you put in your cost elements of your current or estimated on premises, data center resources.
And then you can compare those cost requirements with what is it going to cost you on a W.S.?
And you can add and modify things as you go through.
So what does it include?
Well, it includes things like the RAC infrastructure costs, your virtualization costs, your facilities
costs, because remember, these are the things that go away when you move from your own premises into
the cloud and then your networking, your data transfer and those kind of things.
Now, of course, you do pay for those in the cloud as well, but you just need to understand what the
costs are.
On Prem vs. A.W. as cloud.
And then for labor now, you know, you might have fewer admins looking after your databases on a W.S..
So you have to consider what's going on today.
And once you're using a managed service in a W.S. instead of your on premises data sensor, what are
those savings going to be?
And obviously things like data center and power and all those things that do go away once you move to
the cloud.
So that's just a basic overview.
And what I'll do now is our just briefly show you those calculators.
So what we're gonna do is just go to Google and a search for a top U.S. calculator and you'll see the
ones that come up after are Amazon Web Services, simple monthly calculators on an open that one.
And then also this is the new one here.
So the A.W. s pricing calculator.
Let's also then look for the TCO calculator.
And I going to open that one as well.
So this is the simple monthly calculator and you can see they are telling you that it's being deprecated.
So, you know, we don't spend too much time on this because they're trying to get you to go to the
Nutile now.
But this was the old tool and you went for your services and you just added those in and then you were
able to estimate the costs in a W.S..
So let's ignore that one, because that is being deprecated.
And now we have this neutral and we can create an estimate.
And then, for instance, we could put in E.S., too.
We could can we can click on Configure and then we'll be able to input our specifications so we can
choose, you know, what operating system we're gonna have, the CPA use we need and so on.
And then in reservation terms as well.
So you can choose a reservation term if you're using a reserved instance and or you can just go back
easy to savings and then it shows you how much it's going to cost.
So it's it's really as simple as that.
And you can then obviously go in and create a more advanced estimate as well, if you like, which includes
other things like data transfer costs.
And you can see add lots of different services in and then see what your costs are going to be.
So that's the pricing calculator.
And then you've got the total cost of ownership calculator so you can launch it.
So this is the TCO calculator.
You can choose whether you're on premises or co locations.
So whether your sharing your data center or whether you've got your own dedicated data sense that you
can choose where it is for geographical requirements.
You can choose virtual machines or physical servers.
And then you can add in your rows here and you can give each application a name, choose whether it's
a database or not.
Operating Systems hypervisor is the number of VIMS, the number of calls per VM and the amount of memory
as well.
And then you can put in your storage here.
So sand nasal objects and put that in and then calculate TCO.
And when you get the report, NWS break it down in quite a bit of detail, showing you the various assumptions
that have gone into it.
So that's just a basic understanding because as I say, it's not mentioned in the Solutions Architects
exam.
But if you are a solutions architect, you will be looking at these tools when you're thinking about
migrating workloads into the cloud.