Welcome to another exam, Cram, so this time it's elastic load balancing and auto scaling.
So starting off with auto scaling, auto scaling launches and terminates EC2 instance is automatically
scaling as horizontal it scales out.
It provides elasticity and scalability, and it will respond to EC2 status checks and cloud watch metrics.
You can scale based on demand, so performance or on a schedule scaling policies will define how to
respond to changes in demand.
Also, scaling groups to find collections of EC2 instances that are scaled and managed together.
Full health checks We have 82 health checks, which are the active status checks, and we have Ailbhe
health checks, which means it's going to use the Albi health checks.
In addition to that easy to instant status checks, the health check grace period is how long to wait
before checking the health status of an instance after it's been launched into an auto screening group.
Auto scanning does not act on health checks until the grace period expires.
For monitoring, you got group metrics, and those are data points about the ISG, their one minute
granularity, and there's no charge, but they have to be enabled manually.
Basic monitoring is at the instance level.
By default, it has five minute granularity and there's no charge with detailed monitoring at the instance
level.
That's one minute granularity and charges do apply some additional scaling settings.
We've got call downs, and they're used with simple scaling policies to prevent auto scaling from launching
or terminating before the effects of a previous activity are visible.
The termination policy controls which instances to terminate first when a scale in event occurs.
Some donation protection prevents auto scaling from terminating the protected instances.
The standby state is used to put an instance that's in the in-service day into the standby state for
updating and troubleshooting.
Lifecycle hooks can be used to perform custom actions by pausing instances as the ISG launches or terminates
them.
Use Case is running scripts to download and install software after launching your instance or pausing
an instance of process data before the instance is terminated by a scale in event.
Moving onto elastic load balancing an Ailbhe distributes incoming traffic across multiple targets such
as easy to instances, consignors and IP addresses, and also lambda functions.
It provides fault tolerance for applications.
EL-BAZ can distribute incoming traffic into a single AC or multiple ACS, but only one subnet per AC
can be enabled for each LP.
You need to ensure you have at least a 27 subnet.
And make sure there's at least eight IP addresses available for the LP to scale.
EL-BAZ can be configured as internet facing or internal only with incident facing EL-BAZ.
The LP nodes will have public types, and they will route traffic to the private addresses of the active
instances.
You need one public subnet in each A-Z where the LP is defined.
Even if you're routing to a private subnet with an internal only LP, the nodes have private IPS and
also routes that are private IPS of the instances.
So let's look at the different types of low balance and when you would use them.
We've got the application load balancer, use it with web applications with last seven routing.
So HDTV and HD TPS microservices architectures such as Docker containers and lambda targets a network
load balancer.
It's operating at the TCP and UDP level, so you can use it with applications that operate there.
It offers ultra low latency, and static IP addresses also can be used with VPC endpoint services.
We then got the Gateway Load Balancer.
This is layer free and lessons for all IP packets across all ports and the GOP and virtual appliances.
Exchange application traffic using the Geneive Protocol on port six eight one gateway load balances
are used with virtual appliances such as firewalls, intrusion detection systems, intrusion prevention
systems and deep packet inspection systems across town.
Load balancing is important to understand when cross-site load balancing is enabled.
Each load balancer node will distribute traffic across the register targets in all enabled Azeez when
it's disabled.
Each load balance and no distributes traffic only across the registered targets in its availability
zone.
And we saw in the lessons earlier on how that actually looks in a sort of diagrammatic format with application
load balances.
Cross own load balancing was always enabled with network load balances and gateway load balances.
Cross load balancing is disabled by default, and that's it for this exam crime.