Hello and welcome to the first exam cram of the course.
Now this is a new addition to the course.
Previously I've been giving you links to the training notes on our website and also I provide you an
e-book.
And both of those resources provide a collection of facts that you need to know for the exam.
Now it's really hard in a purely lab based course to be able to make sure that you remember every single
individual fact that you need to know.
It's very hard to cover it.
So those are really important notes to read.
But what I wanted to do is bring some of that back into the course so you're not completely reliant on
actually going out to the training notes and the e-book which we provide to you.
However I do still recommend that you definitely read those documents there is still a bit more in those
that I didn't cover in the exam cram.
But these are just a way of trying to bring in some of the key facts you need to know for the exam.
And there's going to be an exam at the end of each section.
It's relevant to that specific section and it's going to be a pretty fast paced run through of facts.
Now the other good thing about this is it means that you're ready with the information that you need
to know for the quiz which I'm adding after each exam cram.
So after every exam cram there's gonna be a short quiz.
Sometimes it's only going to be a few questions or seven or eight questions and I'm gonna add to those
over time.
But it's just about giving you some knowledge checks to make sure that your remembering the information
you need to know for the exam.
Another quick note about the quizzes.
The question format in the quizzes is not similar to the exam so they're not the same difficulty and
they're not the same format as the real exam.
However when you get down to the actual practice tests later in the course all of those questions are
exam difficulty and exam format but the quizzes are really just there to test your knowledge. So that's
it for the intro.
Let's get on with the exam cram, so Amazon EC2 or the Elastic Compute Cloud is a Web service that
provides re-sizable compute capacity in the cloud.
You have full control of the operating system with EC2 you use key pairs to securely connects your
instances.
So it's really important to remember what these are and they actually consist of a public key AWS stores
and a private key.
And that's what you store on your machine.
Now for Windows AMIs you use that key pair to obtain the password to log onto your instance whereas
for Linux AMIs the key file allows you to securely connect over SSH and user data is the data that's
supplied by the user at instance launch in the form of a script we've already used it so we're going
to use a lot more for the course.
So remember this is a way that you can run some scripts at startup time for that instance.
Instance Metadata is information about the instance so you can use this to configure or manage a running
instance.
Now remember we looked at some examples and you can find out what availability zone an instance is in
or what IP address it has in that kind of thing.
Metadata is available at this you URL and user data is available at this URL.
Now there are three key pricing models for EC2.
We've got on-demand, reserved and spot so remember On-Demand is where there's no upfront fee it's charged
by the hour or second.
The second is for Linux there's no commitment whatsoever.
So you can launch an instance and terminate it straight away.
And so that's really good for short term needs or unpredictable workloads.
Remember there's no discounts for on-demand.
With reserved you actually commit to a one or three year term and in exchange for that commitment you're
actually then going to get charged a lower amount.
So you get quite a big discount.
You can also choose to pay nothing upfront partial upfront or all upfront so you can choose how you
pay.
You can pay the whole lot upfront is going to be a bit cheaper or you can pay on a monthly basis but
just pay a small bit upfront or we can pay nothing upfront and just pay on a monthly basis.
So this is for steady state workloads and predictable usage.
So workloads that you know you're going to be running over that year or that three year term. With spot
there's no upfront fees you're charged by the hour or second as well and there's no commitment.
Now remember the spot is where you have some kind of cost sensitive workload and maybe it's very compute
intensive and you have to be able to withstand interruption because your instances can be terminated
whenever EC2 or whenever AWS need that capacity back.
So remember this is all about using capacity that's not being used so it's about taking advantage of
unused capacity and getting a cheap rates on it.
But AWS might take that back and terminate your workload so your application needs to be okay with
that needs to be able to store its data somewhere else store it state somewhere else so that if an instance
is terminated it doesn't matter.
We then have dedicated hosts and instances.
So here's the differences between the two.
Both of them use dedicated physical servers.
So you know that the physical server on which you're EC2 instance is running is dedicated to your
account.
Now with instances you get per-instance billing whereas we have dedicated hosts who get per-host billing.
Now most of the rest of these features are relevant to dedicated host so you get stuff like visibility
of the sockets, host ID affinity between a host and an instance and targeted instance placement
and you can add capacity use an allocation across.
Now these ones are really interesting so you can see the sockets and the cores and you can you can actually
place your instances on specific hosts.
So why would you want to do that.
Well you might have an application absolutely must have two components of it running on different hosts.
Maybe it's some kind of clustering or high availability or it might be that you need to do that
because of your socket base licensing for let's say a database service.
So those are the kind of things that can come up in exam question.
Now you don't need to remember all the instance types just remember that there are different instance
types for different purposes.
So that can be optimized more for compute for memory for accelerated computing for storage and so on.
So the EC2 AMI is the Amazon machine image and this provides the information required to launch
an EC2 instance.
And the AMI includes the template for the root volume the launch permissions that control which accounts
can actually launch the AMI, will launch an instance from the AMI, and then the block device mapping so
that specifies which EBS volumes should be attached to the instance or which instance store volume
should be attached to the instance.
So the volumes are either instance store or EBS. EBS is persistent storage and in this case EBS snapshots
which reside on S3 are actually used to create the volume.
So when you take a snapshot of an EBS volume it's stored on S3.
So when you create an AMI the AMI uses the snapshot and builds the volume from the snapshot. With instance
store volumes which are ephemeral so non persistent data.
And that means the instance data will be lost.
The data on the volume will be lost when you shut down the instance.
And in this case a template is stored on history and used to create the volume.
Remember that AMIs are regional.
And that's because they use S3.
So because they're stored on S3 the EBS volumes or the snapshots rather that that are backing the
AMIs are stored on S3.
That means you can launch an AMI from the region in which it's stored so into any availability zone
and you can also copy AMIs to other regions.