We're now going to talk about encryption on S3.
So there's a few different ways that you can encrypt your data on S3.
On the left hand side here you can see two different types of encryption that use keys which are managed
by even free or the key management service so they're managed by AWS.
And on the right hand side here you can see two different options for where the client your organization
actually manages the keys.
So starting from the left there the first one is we've got the S3 managed key.
So this this means that Amazon has free will actually manage those keys it creates a unique object key
for each object and then a master key which encrypts the object keys and it uses the standard AES 256
which is a very good standard the encryption decryption takes place here.
It happens actually on the bucket.
So if you upload data the data is not encrypted it gets encrypted when it reaches S3 and gets written
to the bucket in an encrypted state.
If you then want to retrieve that data it's decrypted and then sends over the wire bound to you the
next option is KMS and this basically means that AWS manages the key but in KMS rather than an Amazon
S3.
So the first one is known as server side encryption with S3 managed keys or SSE S3.
And this one is called service side encryption with a.
Excuse me AWS KMS managed keys so AWS KMS.
So in this case rather than S3 managing the keys we're using the key management service one of
the differences is you can use customer master keys you can actually supply a master key to KMS which
it then uses for its encryption and that can be customer generated so it can be one of yours or it can
be automatically generated by KMS itself.
Again the encryption is done very similarly to with the SSE S3.
It's performed at the bucket level.
We then have the service side encryption with client provided keys SSE-C.
So in this case the encryption still takes place up here in the cloud.
So data is not encrypted as it sends up or retrieved from the cloud it's encrypted by S3 as it
is written to and and decrypted when it's read from the bucket.
But the difference is the keys aren't stored at all AWS or the keys are actually managed
by the client and then the full function is where the encryption and decryption takes place entirely
on the company side of the connection.
AWS doesn't know anything about the encryption at all.
You just send encrypted data to AWS and you pull the encrypted data back down again you manage the
keys and you manage the encryption process as well.
So those are the four different types of encryption you can use with S3.
Let's have a look into the console at where we configure encryption.
So we're gonna head into our DCT company bucket and if we go to properties we have default encryption.
So in here we can specify that we set the default which means then that all data is returned to the
bucket unless it has a header which specifies that it's encryption should be different.
It will use whatever setting you use here.
So this is where we have two options we have the service side encryption with AWS managed keys, SSE-S3,
or the K M.S. option whereas key KMS managed keys or as KMS so you can set the default encryption
here.
It won't apply to existing objects.
So if you have objects in that bucket already they won't be encrypted they'll just stay as they are.
The other option we have is when we actually upload data.
So if we go and just grab a file I'm just going to grab my file here and we click next and we could
specify permissions on here but we're going to leave that as it is.
And then this is where we have a couple of options to either modify the storage class and also down
here we can set the encryption so again we see these two options the SSE-S3 and the SSE-KMS
.
And if you choose one of those options you'll then get presented with some available keys so I could
choose came as master key or S3 and if we just click next here and click upload we now have
this file and if we go to properties we can see that it's encrypted with AES 256 and if we want
to we can actually change this so we can then go in and say well now I want to use KMS managed keys
and I'm going to change to this key here and simple as that it would just change to that key.
So that takes care of these two options SSE-S3 and SSE-KMS. if you're using server side encryption
with client provided keys it's not an option that you see here in the console.
So there's a good article here which talks about how it's done and if you come down to here you can see
that this is the encryption key information that you need to put in your request headers.
So when you make a request to S3 you can specify this information to configure what sort of encryption
you're going to be using
so that covers the third option.
And then with the fourth option there really is nothing in AWS for this.
So you actually have to do everything on the client side
so that's most of what I want to show you.
But the other thing that we could do is just have a look in the KMS service.
So this is the AWS Key Management Service which you can use to create and manage encryption keys.
You can go under AWS managed keys here and you can see some of the keys that are being created such
as this AWS S3 key which is the default master key that protects S3 objects.
And then you can go to customer managed keys and this is where you can create your CMK keys your customer
manage keys that can be used with S3 encryption.
So there is lots more to KMS and we'll be using it in other sections of the course but for S3 encryption
this is really all we need to know at this point.
So just understand the four different options and have an understanding of when you might use one over
another.