There are a few different ways that we can enable cross account access, and we really need to understand
what is our use case, are we going to be using the console?
Are we going to be using programmatic access?
So let's have a look at the different methods we can use resource based policies and I am policies for
programmatic only access to S3 bucket objects.
We can use a resource based ACL and I am policies for programmatic access to pocket objects as well.
Or we can use across account.
I am role for programmatic and console access.
The key takeaway, I suppose, is if you want console access, you need to use a cross account.
I am role, so you assume the role and then you can access the data.
Alternatively, if you only need programmatic access, you have a choice of resource based policies
and I am based policies and also resource based ACLs as well.
So let's have a look at a simple scenario.
We have accounts a on the left, an account, B on the right, on the left, we have an S3 bucket.
We want our user in Account B to be able to access that bucket.
So we've created a role and attached to the user.
There's going to be an identity based policy and that policy allows the user to assume the role and
accounts a.
The user will then issue the SDS assume role, perhaps through the console.
And then the role must have a trust policy that allows the user from Account B to assume the role.
And if that's the case, then the permissions policy will then allow whatever permissions are assigned
to that particular policy in that role.
So that's the theory behind cross accounts access.
And in the next lesson, we're going to do a hands on where we're going to implement this very scenario.