Now you need to remember the three different types of IP address.
So you've got the public IP address and that's what if you launch an instance into a public subnet This
is what you're going to get by default.
It's lost when the instance stopped.
So if you stop the instance and start it again you're going to get a new address is used in public subnets
there's no charge.
And it's always associated with a private IP address.
Can't move a public IP address between instances.
You then have a private IP address.
Every instance will have one of these.
It's actually retained when the instance is stopped.
And whether you're in a public or private subnet you always have a private IP.
We then have elastic IP.
So these are static public IP addresses and you're charged when they're allocated to your account but
not actually used.
Now these can be moved between instances and elastic network adapters.
So when I want to look at the different types of adapter first you've got the ENI.
And this is the logical networking component in a VPC that represents a virtual network card.
And it includes an IP address a security group can have a mac address a source destination check flag
and a description. You can create and configure its network interfaces in your account and then attach
them to instances in your VPC.
And eth0 is the primary network interface and cannot be moved or detached and ENI is bound to an
availability zone and you can specify which subnet availability zone you want the ENI added in.
We then have the elastic network adapter.
So this is used for enhanced networking which provides higher bandwidth higher packet per second and lower
latency.
So watch out for exam questions where you need to have higher bandwidth or lower latency between instances.
You have to launch this into a HVM AMI and it's only available for certain instance types.
The last one is the elastic fabric adapter.
So this is like an ENI but with extra capabilities and this enables customers to write applications
requiring high levels of Internode communications at scale.
Now you might see this associated with use cases such as high performance computing applications using
MPI and machine learning and applications using the NVIDIA collective communications library.
You'll definitely see exam questions coming up around high performance computing especially in the SAA-C02
exam.
So some of those questions or some of the answers might include different types of adapter and you've
got to make sure you know what type of adapter to use.
So if high performance computing where you got tightly coupled applications that need Internode communication
that high bandwidth low latency might be the EFA that's the best choice there.
So just look at them again.
The ENI is the basic adapter for when you don't have any high performance requirements can use any instance
the ENA is good for use cases that require high bandwidth low inter-instance latency limited instance
types and then EFA for high performance computing, MPI and ML use cases, tightly coupled applications
as well.
So we also have placement groups.
And remember the three different types you got clustered where your instances are placed into a low latency
group within a single AZ. You got spread where the instances are spread across underlying hardware
and that can be across multiple AZs and you got the partition where the instances are grouped into
logical segments and they use distinct hardware, they're in separate racks.
You'll definitely need to remember which ones can support multiple Availability Zones.
So in this case the spread placement group can support multiple Availability Zones and the partition
placement group can also support multiple Availability Zones but the cluster cannot. So for IAM roles
in relation to EC2 instances remember these are a much better way.
So clearly accessing services and granting permissions as opposed to storing access keys and secret
access IDs on the actual EC2 instances themselves. They're much easier to manage.
You can attach them at any time and you can modify them at any time.
You can only attach one IAM role to an EC2 instance at a time and remember they are universal and
can be used in any region.
So you only have to create the role once and you can use it in any region across AWS. For monitoring.
we have the EC2 status checks and they're performed every minute and return a pass or fail status if
the checks pass the status is OK.
If one or more checks fail it's showing it's impaired the system status checks detect problems of your
instance that require AWS involvement to repair.
So that's not just something to remember that that can come up in an exam question instant status checks
detect problems that require your involvement to repair.
So just remember it has an instance status check it might be something that you can fix.
You might have to reboot an operating system you might have to stop and start your instance or you know
fix a network adapter problem or something like that whereas the system status checks are more likely
to be the underlying infrastructure that you have no control over.
You can also create cloudwatch alarms to monitor EC2 instances and automatically perform an action
if the status check fails.
And lastly we have NAT instances and NAT gateways.
So remember these are both a way to make sure that you can provide Internet access to instances that
have a private subnet.
The NAT instance is kind of the old way of doing it and NAT gateway's the new way of doing it.
The NAT instance is managed by you so you provision an EC2 instance and you have to manage it and
the NAT Gateway is managed by AWS.
So just to understand all of this information here in almost every case now I think NAT Gateway is
going to be the preference over NAT instance.
It's unlikely that are gonna see exam questions that push you to the NAT instance these days because
I think AWS would prefer to promote solutions that include the NAT gateway.
So that's it for our first exam cram.
I hope you learned some more information there.
Again remember the training notes and the ebook
we provide have even more info that you can go and review and use as last minute cramming resource.
This gave you some more information as well and you're now set up to answer a few questions in the quiz.