Let's now cover events, notifications, and the best way to do this is to go straight into the console
and if we had to properties, we've got events so we can receive notifications when specific events
occur in a bucket.
So let's have a look inside at what the options are so you can add a notification and you've got all
these different event types.
So you can have an event when somebody uploads an object, a put request or post or a copy or multiple
upload is completed and so on.
So there's quite a few different event types that you can configure there.
And then there's a few different types of destination that you can send to.
So we've got S.A.S. topic, which is the simple notification service.
We've got the simple Q service.
Ask us where you can send to a queue and then we've got LAMDA functions.
So Lambdas is a very interesting one because it's a serverless service which provides functions as a
service.
That means that you can take code and have that code run in response to events or triggers, as they're
called in lambda.
And we're definitely going to cover this in the lambda section of this course.
So we're actually going to configure an event notification and see how it works.
But an example is that you have some images that you're uploading to a bucket and then you want Lambda
to process those images.
It could be adding a watermark.
It could be changing the file type.
It could be doing one of a number of things and then saving that data to a different location, for
instance.
So lots of power with how you do that.
And we'll see the information that's sent with an event soon.
So let's get around to actually configuring an event.
But what I'm going to do for this map is we're going to send to an S.A.S. topic and generate an email.
Now, I don't have any at this stage.
So what we need to do first is head over to S.A.S..
So this is the simple notification service and what we're going to do is we need to create a topic.
So I'm just going to call this one email Neil, and we can leave the defaults except for the access
policy.
Now, in here, you can use the basic option where you can specify which accounts have published, messages,
rights you can also configure, who can subscribe to the topic.
So you could put in an account.
Top Icona allow everyone, etc., but what I have is I have some code in my clipboard, so I'm going
to go to Advanced and I'm going to delete all this Jason code and then I'm going to paste this code
in.
And so I already have the right information in here.
So I have the ayran of my bucket.
So really, you just need to change the bucket name and that's all we need to do.
Everything else can be defaults.
So now we have a topic and what we need to do is create a subscription, so I'm going to choose the
protocol and now you can see the different options for S.A.S..
You can send you can use the GPS protocol, you can use email, email, Jassam, excuse, lambda functions,
et cetera.
So there's quite a few different options.
What we want is just simple email.
And then I'm going to type in the email that I want this to go to.
And we can click create subscription.
Now, we can see here we have a status which is pending confirmation, so I'm just going to go to my
male client on another screen and I should have a notification and I do.
And so I'm going to click confirm subscription, and this is the response that I got from another browser,
just saying that I subscribe to the topic.
So that should all be set up properly now and we can go back to history and I'm just going to.
At a notification event, we'll call this one email put's, so I want an email to go out when I have
a put event and you could choose a prefix and a suffix to the prefix would be something like your folder
name.
So you only want to apply this to objects that are uploaded to a certain folder in your pocket.
And then a suffix can mean that you can have an optional suffix to limit the notifications to objects
with keys that end with matching characters.
So if all your data ends with certain characters, or maybe it's the filename, for instance, you could
configure that as a suffix.
So let's choose S.A.S. topic and email Neil and click save.
So that's been saved.
What I want to do now is come back and I just need to upload a file to my bucket, so I'm just going
to upload any fall I can.
And this is the S3 notification that I received, so I got a couple of emails, this was the first one
that came from.
There's more information in this one, so if you look at the type of data that we can see the region,
we can see a timestamp, we can see that the type of request was an object created a put request.
We can see the principal I.D. of the user.
We can see the source IP address that it came from.
So that would be my public IP address.
And then we can see request header information and schema versions, bucket names and so on.
So there's quite a lot of data and this is the type of data that can be sent to a service such as an
excuse Q or a Lamba function, which could then use this data to perform whatever processes it needs,
then needs to perform.
So that's event notifications and we will cover some more examples of how to use event notifications
later in the course, such as using security cues and lambda functions as well.