Hi, guys, in this lesson, you're going to learn about VPC flow logs, and then we're also going to
set a flow log up to see how it works and what data actually captures.
So VPC flow logs capture information about the IP traffic going to and from network interfaces in a
VPC.
The data is stored using Cloud Watch or Amazon is free, and you can create the flow log at different
levels.
So at the VPC level, at the subnet level or at the interface level surface, at the interface level,
it's associated with the Illinois that's attached to an easy to instance.
You can capture a lot of traffic, which is really useful for troubleshooting purposes and security
as well.
So let's go and create a flow, log in, etc. I still have an instance running.
If you don't have an instance running, just launch an instance, just as we have done before and put
it into your public one a subnet and it should have a public IP address.
Next, we're going to actually send our data to cloud watch logs.
So in the cloud watch service, I'm going to go to lot groups.
Create law group and create myself a law group.
I'm going to call it my subnet logs.
I consider attention setting.
For me, let's put five days, so after five days, I don't need that data anymore.
And let's create the log creep.
Next, we need to create a role so that the flow logs service has the permissions it needs in the Identity
and Access Management Service.
We're going to create a role.
So let's create a role.
Choose create role.
We're going to choose EC2 for now.
We're going to modify that scene because that's not actually the service that's going to be assuming
the role.
We're going to go straight past policies because we're going to add an in-line policy and I'm going
to call my roll flow logs, cloud watch and I remove the description and create this role.
Now let's find the role and under permissions, we're going to add an inline policy.
We're going to go to Jason and we have this JSON code here in your code Amazon VPC Directory and it's
VPC Flow Logs, JSON.
So we need to do is copy all of this.
As you can see, the service is going to be provided with the permissions to create a log group, create
a log stream, log events, described log groups and describe log streams.
So with that copied, that's come back over, right?
All of that code.
Click on Review.
Give it a name.
I'll just call it cloud watch permissions and create the policy.
Now we do need to edit the trust relationship.
It's not actually easy to that's going to assume this role.
So coming back here, the trust policy can be replaced.
We can literally just copy this piece of text here, and we're going to paste it over where it says
easy to do or Amazon US dot com.
So now the service is able to assume this role is VPC flow logs.
Let's update that trust policy.
That's it.
We're now ready to go and create our flow log back in.
Easy to do.
I've only got one instance running, so it's going to be easy to identify the network interface.
We're going to create the flow log here at the network interface level, so flick over to flow logs,
create flow log.
I'll just call it my flow log.
Let's put it for all traffic and a one man aggregation.
So we get some data nice and fast.
We'll delete it afterwards when we terminate our instance anyway, and we're going to send a cloud watch
logs.
So we've got our log creep and let's find our role, which is starts with flow.
So it's flow logs, cloud watch and we're going to leave the default formats.
And then just create that flow log.
So now let's try a couple of things.
We want to send some successful connections, so let's copy our public IP.
Go to a new window here and put that in.
And we've now generated some HTTP traffic and what refreshed out a couple of times.
And what about sending some traffic, which we're going to get rejected on?
That's another thing that we could do.
So let's come back to instances.
Check out what security creep this instance is in, and it's actually got two.
So let's go to the public web one, because I think that's the one that's got some rules which allow
certain protocols from the internet.
And yes, we can see the cessation HTP rules are in there.
So let's go and edit the inbound rules.
And I'm just going to temporarily delete my SSA rule and safe now from a command line.
I'm simply going to try without any arguments to switch to that instance.
And that shouldn't work.
It should just keep failing because we don't have the security group rules to allow this.
So that's basically it just generating a bit of traffic.
So what we can do now is go to cloud watch logs and see if some data is starting to be sent there.
Back in the cloud watch logs, I'm going to select my log group and let's see if we've got a stream
and I do have a stream that's nice and fast.
Now, don't worry if it's not there yet, you might have to wait a few minutes and it will turn up.
So let's select my log stream and see what data we have in here.
And you can see there's a few entries here we can see some rejects.
And associated with those is various information, including the Elastic Network interface, the source
and destination IP addresses.
We've got port numbers.
We've got protocol numbers.
We've got various bits of information in there that could be useful in whatever analysis you're doing.
If you want to refresh, you can click on Resume and then you should see some more data coming in over
time.
So there we go, we've got quite a few more rejects coming in as well.
And just a couple of minutes later, I've refreshed my screen and we can see some accepts as well,
says quite a few.
We can see the port no.
Airport 80.
So those are successful connections going to our web server.
So that's it.
There's lots of data there that you can use for various analysis, and it's really useful to understand
that different types of logs we've got in IWC, what data is included in them.
So you know which ones to use for your troubleshooting or your analysis.
So that's it for this lesson, and we have finished with our EC2 instance now so we can go ahead and
delete it.
Once you've terminated your instance, you're all cleaned up.