Welcome back in this lesson, we're going to implement cross account access to Amazon as free and the
implementation we're going to create is very much like we saw in the scenario at the end of the last
lesson.
In this case, account a is going to be our management account.
That's the main account we log in with using IWC organizations.
We created our production account.
So Account B is going to be our production accounts.
Now what I'm going to do is create a user called John an account.
B John will have an identity based policy attached in-line, and that policy will allow John to assume
a role in accounts in our management account.
That role will have a trust policy that allows John to assume the role and a permissions policy, which
defines the permissions that John will have to the three buckets.
So let's go over, and the first thing we need to do is create our user, John.
So back in the management console, I'm going to switch to DCT production, so I'm accessing I am in
the DCT production accounts.
Let's go to users.
And we don't have any uses in this account, so let's create a user.
I'm going to call it John.
You can call him whatever you want.
Now I only need management console access at this point in time.
I'm going to set a password, go free, no permissions and just simply create the user.
So that's it.
The user is ready.
I'm going to copy this URL.
This is the URL the user is going to use to log in.
And we have this file in code Amazon S3 cross accounts Access Dot Jason.
I'm just going to paste in this URL so I can use it later on.
Now, this first snippet of JSON is the trust policy for the role that we're going to create in our
management account accounts.
And we need the afriend for our user in account B. So back in, I am.
Let's just go back up a level, click on the user.
Copy the R.N, come back here and we'll paste it in.
So we now have the Aaron Fry user, so now we can actually go and create our trust policy.
So let's copy this code.
We need to switch back to our management accounts.
Goats rolls great role we can choose easy to.
For now, we're going to override that in a moment for permissions.
We're not going to add anything at this point.
We're going to go through and give it a roll name.
I'm going to call it cross account as free.
I'm going to take out the description, just put something in there and create this role.
So now let's find our role under trust relationships.
Let's edit the trust relationship.
Delete all of this out.
I need to come back because I already use copy, just re copy my trust policy and paste on in.
So now the trust relationship here should allow the user from Account B to actually assume this role
so that user has the allow for the action SDS assume role.
So that's the trust policy.
Next, we go back to permissions, add an inline policy, go to Jason.
We're going to delete this code and then let's go and see our snippet of code.
So here is the permissions for the policy.
Now we do need a couple of things.
We need to have the bucket name in two different places.
Otherwise, everything's okay.
We're going to be less buckets.
We're going to be able to get bucket location, get objects and put objects as well.
So let's go and get our bucket ayorinde in Amazon S3.
I'm going to use the DCT cloud storage bucket now.
I just want to check if I've left, I have left the bucket policy.
Let's remove the bucket policy.
So that's been deleted back in properties.
Let's copy the R.N.
And then we're going to come back here and place that over the top into these two locations.
Leaving the slash staff so that we apply to objects and then let's copy all of this code and then paste
that into our JASON editor for our permissions policy.
Give this a name.
I'm just going to call it free access and create that policy.
So now we have the roll sets up with the trust relationship set correctly so that the user an account
B can assume the role and the permissions assigned.
We now need to give Paul an in-line policy, allowing Paul to actually call the assumed role.
And then we need to log in as Paul once has this all out.
Now we're going to need our role.
R-N.
So looking at my role here, let's just copy the irony of our role and our third piece of code here.
We're going to paste in the role Aron.
So now we have to run for the role.
We're going to copy this code.
We're going to go to users and then switch accounts.
So now we're going to switch accounts, DCT production.
We can see John and under permissions, we're going to add an in-line policy.
Go to Jason and add this in.
I'm just going to call this assume role and let's create the policy.
So we need to log in as John now and attempt to assume the role.
We're going to need a few pieces of information for that.
Firstly, we need this URL.
So let's log in as John.
So when you enter the URL, you should see a page like this put in your username and password for John
and sign in.
So we're signed in, and what we're going to do is switch roles and to switch roles.
We need a bit of information.
Firstly, we need the account side and then we need the role name.
So back in I I'm going to go back to my main accounts and any user here I should find an R.N., which
includes the account side.
Let's just come back, pay, start in copy the account's I.D. Come back, we can paste it in.
We need the role name that was crossed.
The account free will paste it in.
I'll set the display names across the account as free as well.
Put this is green and let's click on Switch Roll.
So we appear to have switched roles.
Now let's go to Amazon is free and we can see these buckets and we don't have too many permissions,
but we should have the permissions to actually get an object.
So let's try downloading and objects, and that's worked.
We can see that just downloaded and then maybe we can upload an object as well, just a test that we
can do that.
So let's try and upload this HD html.
Click on Upload and that works successfully as well.
Now we shouldn't have permissions to delete, so let's just try and make sure that we do have all the
permissions we expect.
So I'm going to try and delete this object, and I get an access denied.
So that's how you enable cross account access.
So just coming back to our diagram quickly, we have our user ID account be in our production account.
That's John, who had an inline identity based policy, which literally just allowed him to assume a
role and account, say the role in accounts.
He has a trust policy to allow John to assume the role, and then we had some permissions to find.
So that's it for cross accounts.
Access hope that was useful.
I'll see you in the next lesson.