Welcome back.
And in this lab I'm going to cover server access logging proxy protocol and X 44 in relation to the
application and network load balances.
So you may recognize this diagram because it looks very similar to before in the previous lesson.
We had a classic load balancer in both of these places because I was trying to show you that you can
have Layer 7 and layer form of a classic load balancer and you have support for X forwarded for at last
seven and proxy protocol layer for the difference here is we've split the two between an application
load balancer and a network load balancer because as you know an application load balancer only operates
at least seven and a network load balancer only operates at four.
So for these low balances the routing decisions that they make are based on L4 data or L7 data.
So when it comes to access logging and logging the source IP addresses of our Internet clients they
both behave slightly differently.
The network load balancer actually sends the client IP by default in a format that you can see in the
log files.
You can also add the proxy protocol and that just means that you need to have an interpreter to be at
to see that information in your log files.
We'll see this in the labs for the application load balancer the source IP is forwarded using the x
forwarded for header so it's added onto the data and it's there but we have to make a modification in
Apache if we want to be able to see that information.
So what we're going to do now is we're actually going to set this up we're going to set up to load balancers
and we're going to have to see two instances of Apache and we're going to go in and have a look in the
log files and see what information about our clients we can find.
We're also going to enable server access logging on the low balances to an Amazon S3 bucket and we'll
have a look at those log files and see what information's available there.
I mean the easy to management console I know I'm going to launch two instances.
These are going to be Amazon and it's to EMI and T2 micro and move freight is quite quickly because
you've done this lots of times before and then you use my default VPC use my S3 full access I am oral
and then under user data I'm going to paste the same code that we've been using for the last several
labs and then I just need to put it in the web access security group and just launch.
So while those are launching and then go straight down to load balances and create to load balances.
So the first one's going to be an application load balancing and a call that my Alby is going to have
a hasty tepee listener I'm going to put this into my default subnet and it's going to my default VPC
rubber and it's going to have two public subnets and let's put it in the web access security group and
then create a target creep called C.G. 1 legal settings except healthy fresh all comes down to two and
four register targets I'm actually going to register one of my targets here and that's going to create
and that's all being created and let's do the same but now we're going to select a network load balancer.
So I'm going to call this my MLB it's gonna be a tepee listener before VPC and again put it in public
subnets and we're going to put this in T G to get a credit target group called TGT healthy fresh is
going to be to interval 10 seconds and I'm gonna register the other instance.
So each of these instances is registered to only one load balancer and I'm going to create and that's
that.
So those two are provisioning and let's just go back and check our instances.
And what I want to do is actually log into each of these instances.
The next thing I want to do is enable server access logging so to do that we select our low balancer.
We come down to attributes.
We select access logs and I'm just going to create a new one here called DCT labs logs and I'm going
to select the option to create it for me and then going to go to my network load balancer and I'm going
to enable access logs here we already have the logs bucket now so I'm just gonna put in DCT labs logs
and save and if we go over to S3 we should now see that that bucket is being created for us.
So here it is and it's got a directory called Dawe logs and then the account number.
And then there's a test file so we should see some files coming into here once we start making connection
requests through our load balances back up.
Looking at my instances I've labeled my instances instance one which is attached to my application load
balancer and instance to and what I'm going to do now is just log onto each of these two instances.
So I've set up a connection to each of my instances.
And before we go over there what I want to do is go to my low balances.
I'm going to take the DNS name go to a browsing tab and I'm just gonna pay start in and we get Kirsten
so we've got one of our instances there called Kirsten and then let's go back and do the same for the
network load balancer and hopefully this is up and running as well.
Sure is.
We got two here and one that does for each of these I'm just going to hit refresh a bunch a bunch of
times so I can generate some log files both using the server access logging for the load balancer but
also on the backend on Apache.
Let's now have a look in Apache and see what information is being logged.
I'm now logged on to instance one instance one is attached to my application load balancer and what
I want to do is run a command to have a look at the log files in Apache.
So what we're seeing here is a combination of health checks and we're also seeing some information coming
from you can see Macintosh I'm using a Mac so you can see that some data is coming from my machine using
Safari but if I type this to grep to search for what I know is my public IP address there's nothing
there.
So what we're actually seeing is the private IP addresses of the load balancer and my easy to instance
in the public subnet.
So these are private AWB s IP addresses.
Now what we want to see is the source IP address of the client.
But to do that we have to make a couple of modifications.
And what we need to do is edit the hasty CPD dot com file
and we need to scroll way down and keep going down the file until you see the section for logging and
some what we want to do is actually paste in some code here and I'll show you where to get this.
I'll provide it obviously in the course downloads but also I'll provide a URL for an AWP as article
which tells you all about this.
But we're just changing the log format.
So we're just adding in the X forwarded four so it's going to show the contents of the X forwarded for
header.
So now let's just save this and we just need to restart H2 TPD
and now let's go back and generate some more load on our instance.
So this is instance one and the one that's attached to my application load balancer and it is going
to hit refresh a bunch of times.
So hopefully Apache will now log some information which will include my source IP address so let's run
that grep command again.
So I'm going to open the access log and search for my public IP address of my machine.
And then we go get lots of hits.
So what we've done is we've just enabled Apache to see the export ad for headers so we know the export
ad for headers are there.
The application load balancer doesn't need to be configured it sends that by default or we needed to
do here was edit Apache to find that information.
Let's now head over to instance to which is attached to the network load balancer.
So I'm logged on to instance to let's run the same cat command to look at the log files in Apache and
straight away I can see my public IP address.
So the main difference is that with the network load balancer this IP address is actually readable in
the TTP header whereas with the application load balancer it's an ex forwarded for header which you
need to be able to interpret in Apache.
Now you can use proxy protocol of the network load balancer but that's something different.
What we're seeing here is not the proxy protocol.
It's just that the IP address is being sent in a format that's readable.
Now another thing you need to know about the network no balancer is if you specify your targets by IP
address then that information won't be present and you'll have to use the proxy protocol if you want
to be able to see the source IP.
The reason being is when you specify a target by IP address you will see the source IP address of the
packet is coming from the load balancer.
If you specify instance then you'll see the source IP address as being from the actual source client.
Let's go back over to S3 now and see if we can find some server access logs from our low balances.
I've just refreshed my bucket and I can see that I now have a folder called Elastic Load Balancing.
And if I go in here I'll drill down to the date and I can see that I have a couple of logs from my application
load balancer.
So I'll just download these or download one of these and we'll open it up and have a look.
This is the log file that was generated by my application load balancer.
You can see the protocol.
You can see a timestamp here.
You can see an identifier for the load balancer.
You can see here the public IP address of my machine on the Internet.
You can then see the address of the actual easy to instance itself and the port so this port easy on
the easy to instance.
That's obviously the private IP of the easy to instance and you can then see some more information about
what the GET GET request was.
You can see the browser version is being used and so on.
So there's quite a bit of information in there.
So that's what a server access log looks like.
So that's it for this lab.
I just wanted to show you the logging options for elastic low balances and to make you aware of the
X forwarded for proxy protocol and what information is actually sent in the packets that your easy two
instances receive and indeed which information is logged by the low balance using server access logging.
So hopefully that will make sense to you.
What we can do now is we can actually go back and terminate our instances and we can delete our load
balances and I'm going to remove both my target groups as well.
So just a final recap.
You can enable server access logging on your low balances and it logs it to an S free bucket which you
specify and that includes the source IP address of your client along with other information the network
load balance or price at lower for the application load balancer at last seven application load balance
includes the source IP address of the client in ex forwarded for headers whereas the network load balance
actually sends that information in the hasty T.P. header itself but also supports the proxy protocol.
So that's it for this lab guys.
Hope you enjoyed the course and learning lots.