Welcome to another exam cram.
There's definitely a lot to cover on databases so let's get stuck straight into it.
So with Amazon RDS
this is the relational database service.
It's a managed service for running relational databases in the cloud and you use it for online transaction
processing types of databases so not analytics databases.
This is more your sort of databases for your transactional systems. Primary use case is transactional
rather than analytical so structured relational data storage requirements and aims to be a drop in replacement
for existing on premise instances of the same databases.
So if you're running SQL on premise or MySQL on premise you can migrate that onto RDS.
It has automated backups some patching applied and they're done in customer defined maintenance windows.
Now it has what they call push button scaling but remember with RDS you do need to change the
instance type.
So there's actually a reboot required so there's a little bit of downtime.
You can also set up replication and redundancy so the different types of engines are Aurora.
That's the proprietary AWS database.
Then you've got MySQL, MariaDB, Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server and PostgreSQL.
It's a managed service and you don't have access to the underlying EC2 instance. Key exam question
here.
If you have a scenario where a database is going to be migrated onto AWS but the company needs to
be able to maybe install some software at the operating system level and managing at the operating system
level you can't put it on RDS. That might be better for EC2. RDS includes security and patching
automated backup software updates and the scaling for storage and compute.
You can also set up the multi AZ for synchronous replication and automatic failover. Read replicas
are used for scaling read not scaling write.
So there are alternatives.
As I mentioned before if we have a use case that's not supported on RDS.
For instance you need to access the underlying operating system or maybe the database engine isn't supported.
Then you can use EC2. Install on EC2.
But now you have to manage that instance.
So if you do consider using EC2 instead of RDS
remember you can run any database you like and have full control and flexibility but you have to manage
everything including the backups, redundancy, patching and scaling.
But it's a good option
if your database isn't supported. It's also a good option
if it's not feasible for some reason to migrate to an AWS managed database and that might be the flexibility
and the control that you might need especially at the operating system level.
So with encryption you can encrypt your RDS instances and snapshots by enabling the encryption
for your DB. Instance encryption at rest is supported for all DB types and uses KMS keys. When using
encryption at rest
the following elements are also encrypted.
That's the snapshots, backups, DB instance storage. Because you cannot encrypt an existing database
so if you have a database that's not encrypted and you want to encrypt it what you have to do is create
a snapshot encrypt the snapshot create a copy of it and then build the encrypted database from the snapshot.
Data that's encrypted at rest includes the underlying storage for the DB instance, it's automated backups
read replicas and snapshots and read replica of an RDS database that's encrypted is also encrypted
using the same key as the master instance.
As long as they're both in the same region if the master and the replica are in different regions you
encrypt using the encryption key for that region instead. You can't have an encrypted read replica
of an unencrypted DB instance or an unencrypted read replica of an encrypted DB instance.
So what do you pay for.
You pay for the DB instance hours, partial hours are charged as full, you pay for storage and gigabytes a
month - that's EBS storage.
You pay for I/O requests a month and that's magnetic storage for provisioned IOPS you pay for the IOPS
provisioned.
Just like you would with any EBS volume.
You also pay for egress data transfer you pay for backup storage but remember that you get up to the
EBS volume size for free.
So if you attach 100 gig EBS volume to your database then you get 100 gig worth of snapshot space for
free.
Now for multi AZ you're charged for multiple DB hours so the extra instance that you've got in the
other availability zone, provisioned storage, double the writes because everything has to be written
twice. You're not charged for the data transfer from the primary to the secondary. Oracle and Microsoft
SQL licenses are included.
Or you can bring your own or BYOL.
On Demand and reserved instance pricing is also available for RDS. In terms of scalability.
You can only scale RDS up based on changing the compute and storage.
You can't decrease the allocated storage for an RDS instance.
You can scale storage and change the storage time for all DB engines except MS SQL. With MS SQL
you have to create a new instance from a snapshot with a new config. Now scaling storage for those other
engines can happen while the instance is running without outage.
But there might be some performance degradation and scaling compute will cause downtime because you
are changing instance types and that requires a reboot.
However you can have those changes take effect in the maintenance window rather than immediately.
So in terms of performance RDS uses EBS volumes for the database and log. There are three types you
got a general purpose, provisioned IOPS and magnetic, and magnetic is not recommended except for backwards
compatibility.
Now we also have multi AZ and read replicase because these are used for high availability fault tolerance
and performance scaling so let's have a look at the difference between these two.
You definitely need to know these for the exam so multi AZ is where you have a standby database in
a separate availability zone so you use that for disaster recovery and it uses synchronous replication.
Read replicas use asynchronous replication but they're just for scaling read performance. With multi
AZ only the database engine on the primary is active whereas read replicas all of the replicas are available
to be read from and then you write to your main master database with. multi AZ automated backups can
be taken from the standby so you don't have your backups running on the primary whereas there's no backups
configured on a read replica.
By default the multi AZ spans two AZs in a region. Read replicas can be within an AZ, cross AZ,
or even cross region. with multi AZ the database engine version upgrades happen in the primary.
With read replicas because the version upgrades are independent from the source
instance. With multi AZ automatic failover happens to the standby when a problem is detected.
Now with read replicas you can manually promote a read replica to a standalone database instance
if you need to. So multi AZ again creates the replica in another and synchronously replicates.
You can choose to configure it at launch and it's recommended to use provisioned IOPS. Each AZ runs its
own physically distinct independent infrastructure.
So this is very highly reliable.
You can't choose which AZ will host the standby instance but you can view which AZ
it's created in.
Now you do get read replica support for multi AZ so that means that for MySQL and MariaDB
08:34.670 -- 08:42.030
they support multi AZ deployments and that means you can combine read replicas with multi AZ and
that enables you to build resilient disaster recovery and simplify the database engine upgrade process.
A read replica in a different region than the source database can be used as a standby database and
promoted to become the new production database in case of regional disruption.
So that means you can scale reads while also having the multi AZ for the automatic failover
between a primary and a standby.
Now this feature is not supported for PostgreSQL.
Now make sure you know this.
Make sure you understand what's on the slide here.
This was an exam question for me so I understand that you cannot use PostgreSQL in this configuration.
So read replica is when you have heavy reads on your database, replication is asynchronous. Read replicas are for
work load sharing an offloading those reads, and it provides a read only copy of the DB for DR as well. Read
replicas are automatically created from a snapshot of the master instance.
You have to have automated backups enabled and it only supports transactional databases, that's InnoDB not
myISAM. Read replicas are available for MySQL, PostgreSQL,
MariaDB, Oracle and Aurora, but not MS SQL server. You can enable automatic backups on MySQL
and MariaDB read replicas as well.
And you can enable writes to the MySQL and MariaDB read replicas. When you have read replicas
and a multi AZ configuration the read replicas are switched to the new primary when the multi AZ fails
over.
You can have five read replicas of your production DB but you can't have more than four in a replication
chain.
You can have read replicas of Read replicas so a read replica that's getting its data from another read
replica for MySQL and MariaDB.
You can promote the read replica to primary as I mentioned before.
Snapshots are user initiated and enable you to back up your DB instance in a known state as frequently
as you wish and then restore to that specific state that stored on S3 and they remain there until
you manually delete them. Backups are taken within a defined window.
That's the maintenance window and restored databases will always be a new RDS instance with a new
DNS endpoint.
You can't restore from a database snapshot to an existing DB.
So that's the same as the previous point.
It's always going to be a new database instance. For migration
you've got the database migration service and that helps you to migrate databases.
to AWS quickly and securely.
It can be used with the schema conversion tool to migrate databases to AWS RDS or EC2 based
databases. when using DMS the source database can remain fully operational during the migration so
that minimizes downtime and it supports lots of different scenarios in terms of the source and destination
database types and that includes most widely used commercial and open source databases. Schema conversion
tool can copy database schemas from homogenous migrations like the same database so MySQL to
MySQL and convert schemas for heterogeneous migration so you might be converting SQL to MySQL
or something like that.