Welcome to the exam cram for Amazon VPC, so a VPC is analogous to having your own data center inside
IWC as you get complete control over the virtual networking environment.
And if EPCs, logically isolated from other VCs on IWC BBQ's and regionwide, a default VPC gets created
in each region and that always has a subnet in each availability zone.
By default, you can create up to five APKs per region.
Public subnets Subnet STAT have the auto assigned public IPv4 address setting configured to yes, and
the subnet route table must have a route to an internet gateway.
When you create a VPC, you specify a range of IPv4 addresses for the VPC in the form of a side.
A block of VPC will span all availability zones in the region, and you get full control of who has
access to the resources inside the BPC.
The names of availability zones are mapped to different zones for different uses, so you can use the
AC I.D. to identify the actual physical zone.
So what are the components of a VPC?
We've got subnet.
These are segments of a VPC IP range where you can place groups of isolated resources and they map to
a single AC internet gateway is the VPC side of a connection to the public internet, and that Gateway
is a highly available managed network address translation service for enabling access to the internet
from private instances.
The VPC router performs all the routing functions in your VPC appear in connection connects you to enough
of a PC using private IP addresses and VPC endpoints.
Enable private IP addresses to be used to connect to services in the public zone and egress only.
Internet Gateway is used by IPv6 addresses to access the internet and its outbound only.
A hardware VPN connection is a virtual private network that you can connect to your VPC to your data
center, your home network or your co-location facility.
The virtual private gateway is the VPC side of the VPN connection, whereas the customer gateway is
the customer side in terms of the rules for your IP side of blocks.
The size can vary between 16 and 28.
The side of block cannot overlap with any exist inside a block that's associated with the VPC, and
you cannot increase or decrease the size of an existing site or block.
The first four and last IP addresses in a subnet are not available for use, and I recommend you use
the RC 1918 ranges.
A few additional considerations that ensure you have enough networks and hosts big insider blocks are
often better and smaller subnet.
So usually OK, consider deploying your application tiers into subnet.
Split your high availability resources across subnet that are assigned to different Azeez and VPC pairing
requires non-overlapping side of blocks.
Consider that in your design, and that's across all the pieces in all regions and accounts.
So in summary, avoid overlapping silo blocks as much as possible.
What about security groups versus network schools?
Security groups operate at the instance level they support allow rules only the stateful and all rules
get evaluated, and they apply only to instances that are associated with the group.
A network ICL operates at the subnet level, supports, allow and deny rules, it state less rules get
processed in order and automatically applies to all instances in the subnets that it's associated with.
Let's go through the various methods of connecting to a VPC.
Firstly, we've got the IWC managed VPN, so this is an IP SEC VPN connection over the internet.
It's a quick and easy way to set up a VPN tunnel to a VPC, and it can also be used as a redundant link
for some other connection, like direct connect and support, static routes or BGP pairing and routing.
And it is dependent on an internet connection.
So and it's also subjects, of course, to the performance and the licensee issues associated with the
incident.
You create a AWG managed VPN by creating a virtual private gateway, also known as a V.W on a WC and
a customer gateway on the on premises side.
Next, we have direct connect.
This is a dedicated network connection over private line straight into the IWC backbone.
It requires a large network link into WC.
It's useful when you have a lot of resources and services being used by corporate users in your data
center or your office.
You get predictable network performance and potential bandwidth cost reduction if you use the right
volume of traffic and you get up to 10 or 100 gigabits per second of provisioned connections and also
supports BGP pairing and routing.
Now, on the downside, it may require additional telecom and hosting provider relationships and network
setups so that can take a bit of time and cost to configure.
In terms of how you do it, you'll have to work with your data center networking provider to connect
into the AWB locations and then you create virtual interfaces for accessing services on IWC.
You can combine direct connect and a VPN connection.
In this case, you're actually using a VPN connection over your direct connect link.
Why would you do that?
Well, you get an encrypted tunnel over your direct connect connection, so it's more secure in theory
at least than Direct Connect alone.
Of course, you are adding a little bit more complexity.
And again, you'll have to work with your data center networking provider to set up the Direct Connect
connection.
Next, we got VPN cloud up.
You connect your locations in a hub and spoke manner using US Virtual Private Gateway, so it's VPN
connections from multiple office locations or multiple data centers that you might have.
So you're linking your remote offices for backup or primary when access to AWG resources and to each
other because it will route between them as well.
It reuses existing internet connections and supports BGP routes to direct traffic in terms of the downsides
is dependent on internet connections again.
And there's no inherent redundancy with cloud type.
You need to assign multiple customer gateways to a virtual private gateway, each with their own BGP
ehsaan and unique IP ranges.
Next, we have a software VPN.
Hey, you're providing your own VPN endpoints and software you have to manage by friends of the connection.
It's a software layer.
It's not a top us provided, but it's something that gives you more flexibility and manageability options.
Of course, you need to design for any kind of redundancy as well.
So that's up to you.
And that could be a downside in terms of actually deploying a software VPN as lots of different options
out there, and you can also use the marketplace to find an instance with pre-packaged software.
Next up, we have a transit VPC.
This is a strategy where you're connecting geographically dispersed the pieces in a hub and spoke manner
with us, manage VPNs.
So then you have one VPC that's configured as the network transit center for the other VPNs.
You have to define any redundancy that you need across the whole chain.
And there are some third party providers that also offer equipment that can be used with your VPNs and
help you to configure a transit VPC.
We then have APEC pairings, so this is when you need to provide connectivity between vehicles and they
need to have that connectivity via a private IP addresses.
You can use the IWC backbone without traversing the internet in this case.
There's no transdev pairing supported, and we've seen how to actually create a VPC pairing connection
in the hands on.
We then have VPC endpoints.
There's two different types interface, end point and gateway endpoints.
We have an interface endpoint.
It's an elastic network interface with a private IP that uses DNS entries to redirect traffic.
And you can use it with many services, including API Gateway Cloud Formation and Cloud Watch.
And you have security groups, which you can assign as well, so you can apply your security groups
to your interface with a gateway endpoint.
This is a target for a specific round, which uses prefix lists in the routes able to redirect traffic.
And this is for Amazon as free and Dynamo DB only.
You can't use security groups, but you can use VPC endpoint policies.
Lastly, we have flow logs.
These capture information about the IP traffic going to and from network interfaces and the VPC.
The Flow Log data is stored using cloud watch logs or Amazon free, and the flow logs can be created
at different levels.
The VPC level subnet level or the network interface level.
And that's it for this exam crime.