In this lesson, I'm going to cover nitro instances and nitro enclaves.
Now these are both part of the IWC Nitro system, which is the underlying platform for the next generation
of active instances.
It's been around for a few years, but it's been evolving over time, and more and more instance types
are now supported on the Nitro system.
That includes by virtualized instances and bare metal instances now by bare metal.
What we mean is rather than having a virtualisation layer, a hypervisor between the physical infrastructure
and the instances operating system, it actually accesses bare metal, so it's connected directly to
that physical infrastructure layer.
Now, in some cases, that improves performance.
It might help you with licensing restrictions as well.
Virtualization can impose a performance penalty.
And with Nitro, what they're trying to do is eliminate that and give you the best performance you possibly
can get for both bare metal and virtualized instances.
Now, the functions of the underlying infrastructure layer, including the hypervisor, are broken into
separate hardware modules.
We have the Nitro cards for VPC, Nitro cards for EBS and Instant Storage on Nitro Card Controller and
Nitro Security Chip.
We've then got the Nitro Hypervisor and Nitro Enclave's, so each of these functions is broken into
a separate specialized hardware module, which gives you the best flexibility in performance.
The key benefits of the Nitro system involve performance, security and innovation.
The performance is close to bare metal, even for virtualized instances.
The Elastic Network adapts and elastic fabric adaptor are both based on the Nitro system.
There's more bare metal instance types, and there's higher network performance, including up to 100
gigabits per second.
It's also optimized very well for high performance computing.
Additionally, we have support for dense storage instances, which go up to 60 terabytes at the time
of recording.
Next, we have Nitro Enclave's and this is really about security.
These provide isolated compute environments.
Your instances will run on isolated and hardened virtual machines.
There's no persistent storage, no interactive access or external networking.
It uses cryptographic attestation to ensure only authorized code is actually running on your instance.
So it's an extremely secure computing environment.
It integrates with K.M. encryption, and you can protect and securely process your highly sensitive
data for use cases like personally identifiable information protection, health care data, financial
data and intellectual property data.
So the key takeaways are that the U.S. Nitro system is the next generation of the underlying hardware
platform.
For easy to, it breaks apart various functions into these different modules, like the Nitro cards
and the Nitro security chip.
We then got the Nitro enclaves, which help you with really secure computing environments that are very
much isolated.
As I mentioned before, there's quite a lot of instance types that do support the Nitro system now.
The T2 type that we use during this course is not supported for Nitro.
It's a lower cost instance, and it doesn't support many different features.
Now, if you're interested in understanding which instance Typekit support which features, I'll add
a link to this lesson.
You don't need to know them all off by heart, but it's useful to pass over it with a quick glance just
to understand the differences between what supported for different instance types and instance families.