Hello and welcome to this lesson and this lesson, I'm going to cover the Amazon EC2 pricing options
and various use cases for those different pricing options.
So there's quite a bit of a deep dive on these subjects as they do come up quite a lot in exam topics.
So you really need to know this.
So firstly, let's look at the different types of pricing model there.
All we've got on demand on demand is just the standard rate.
There's no discount, there's no commitments.
You can use it for things like dev test workloads, anything that's short term or unpredictable.
So in that case, you're not committing, but you're also not getting any discounts.
So it's just a standard rate is very flexible.
So it's very useful when we launch instances in this course, we're just using on demand because we're
not running them for very long.
If you're running a workload for a longer period, then you've got to start thinking about some other
kind of option other than on demand because you're just not going to get any cost savings.
That's it's going to be the most expensive option.
So next up, we have reserved in this case, you are committing.
So though IWC is mostly about not having any commitments in this case, you are going to commit, but
you get a discount for it.
That discount can be up to 75 percent and you commit for even one year or three years.
And this is for things like your steady state workloads, your line of business applications.
They're not going anywhere.
They're going to keep running year after year.
It's predictable, and therefore you need to make sure that you get the best pricing model for it.
And in this case, it makes a lot of sense to have that commitment with IWC.
You could also reserve capacity with reserved instances as well.
Next up, we have spot instances.
This is where you're actually bidding for unused capacity.
So IWC obviously have huge data centers.
It's not always fully utilized.
And so there's lots of unused capacity and you can bid on the usage of that unused capacity.
In this case, you can get discounts up to 90 percent.
So really big discounts.
But there is a catch, of course, and that is that your instances can be terminated at any time and
you do get a short notification before that happens.
But in this case, you need workloads to have flexible start times and flexible enzymes.
This is used in situations such as where somebody needs a really cost effective solution to run a large
processing workload, and that workload can actually withstand instances being terminated so the data
needs to be saved or it needs to be replicated somewhere, and the application logic needs to be able
to recover from any terminated instances.
We then have dedicated instances this is where you have physical isolation at the host hardware level
from instances belonging to other IWC customers.
So we typically are using shared infrastructure.
The infrastructure, which, for instance, is run, is shared across many customers.
If you need to dedicate your instances to hosts that are not shared with other customers, then this
is the option for you.
In this case, you pay.
Per instance, your dedicated instances can be sharing hardware with other instances from your account,
but not from other IWC customers.
We then got dedicated hosts.
This is a physical server that's dedicated for your use, so you're not sharing it with anybody and
you've got a whole server dedicated just for you.
It's going to cost you a lot more.
Both of these options are going to be expensive, so you've got to think about, you know, why do you
need this?
But you might need this for things like soccer and core visibility.
So some licensing is bound to the CPU's in the physical hosts that your instance is run on and therefore
dedicated hosts means that you can have that visibility and it helps you with licensing.
You have host affinity so you can control where your instances are actually running.
Which hosts are they running on?
You might want to make sure that two particular instances are running on different hosts, and you can
do that with a dedicated host.
This model is pay per host, so you pay for the whole host rather than the instances running on it,
and it's going to be a lot more expensive than any of the other options here.
Lastly, we have something called savings plans.
This is where you commit to a consistent amount of usage, and this goes across easy to forget, which
is a container technology we'll talk about later in the course as well as lambda.
So in this case, what you're doing is you're saying I'm going to pay a certain rate and I'm going to
commit for a certain period of time, one or three years to using a certain amount of compute capacity.
Now, let's look at how you actually build.
So you actually build per second with a minimum of one minute and that's for Linux instances and the
per second billing is for Amazon Linux and a buntu in on demand reserved and spot forms.
We then have billed per hour.
This is a minimum of one hour.
And this applies to windows and applies to other distributions such as commercial Linux distributions
such as Red Hat Enterprise, Linux and Susie Enterprise Server.
Now what about the EBS volumes that are attached to your two instances?
Well, those are actually billed per second with a minimum of one minute.
So what about the EBS volumes that are attached to your instances?
Well, that build per second with a minimum of one minute.
So let's look at reserved instances in some more detail.
Remember that the term is one year or three years and you have something called a standard ROI and you
have a convertible.
All right.
The standard ROI means that you can change availability zones the instant size if it's Linux and the
networking type you use to modify reserved instances API action to perform those changes.
With a convertible, Roy, you can change the AC instant size for Linux and the networking type as well,
but you can also change the family operating system tenancy and the payment option.
And in this case, you use the exchange reserved instances API action to perform those changes.
The payment options can then be all upfront, partial upfront or no upfront, so you even pay for the
entire one or three years upfront.
And that means you'll get the best discount, but not so good for your cash flow.
Or you can pay a partial fee upfront and then a monthly payment or no upfront, which just means a monthly
payment.
And of course, you don't get quite as much of a discount if you don't put anything down upfront.
But that obviously gives you a better cash flow situation as well.
When the attributes of a instance that you've launched into your account match the attributes of a reserved
instance.
That's when the discount gets applied.
So that can include the type of instance you're running, the instance type, and it can include the
operating system that you're using.
With that instance, the tenancy is another attribute so that can be default or dedicated.
Remember that dedicated means you're running on dedicated hardware.
Lastly, it can be the availability zone and the region.
So these are all the attributes that need to match the ROI for it to be applied.
When you specify and availability zone, you can also reserve capacity in that easy but by region.
It does not reserve the capacity, but the discount does apply to all availability zones.
So let's look at these scheduled ROI schedules.
All ROI is where you matched a capacity reservation to a recurring schedule.
There's a minimum of 12 200 hours per year, and you might use this for something like a reporting application.
So if that runs for six hours a day, four days a week, that would be one thousand two hundred forty
eight hours a year.
So what you do is you just pay for one thousand two hundred and forty eight hours a year and you get
your reserved instance discount.
And you can just use that within those time frames.
Now, very recently, I've noticed this IWC seem to be deprecating this functionality, so they now
say that they do not have any capacity for purchasing scheduled reserved instances.
Now I still talk about it because it's definitely on the exam at the moment.
It will take a few months before they get rid of those questions and update the exams.
So just bear in mind, the exam may not reflect this.
Yes, if you see something mentioning scheduled reserved instances, that means the exams not updated.
Next up, we have the savings plans.
So here we have the Compute Savings Plan or the Easy two savings plan.
With the Compute Savings Plan, you choose a one or three year.
It's an hourly commitment to usage or Filegate Lambda and to any region, family size, tenancy and
operating system with the easy to savings plan.
Again, it's a one or three year commitment.
It's hourly usage again, too easy to only and within a selected region and instance family.
And you can also use any size, any tenancy and operating system combination.
Let's look at spot instances in some more detail here.
You're bidding for unused capacity and getting a discount of up to 90 percent.
You can launch a spot instance that's just one or more spot instances, or you can launch a spot fleet.
This is where IWC launches and maintains a specified number of spot.
And also, you can mix in on demand instances to meet a certain capacity.
You then have two fleets.
This is where IWC launches and maintains a specified number of spot on demand and reserved instances,
all in a single API call with Sea Fleet, you can define separate on demand and spot capacity targets,
bids, instance types and availability zones.
So lots of flexibility there.
Now you do get a two minute warning if eight of us need to reclaim capacity.
And this is made available via instant metadata and also cloud watch events.
Spot Blog actually comes up in a few exam questions with Spot Block.
This is where you can run two instances uninterrupted for one to six hours, so you're getting a discount,
but you also don't get an interruption.
So in this case, you just specify the block duration, which is anything from one to six hours.
The number of instances and then your bid price pricing is 30 to 40 per cent less than on demand.
So much better than on demand.
Not anywhere near as good a spot.
But if you need to make sure that your instances aren't terminated within that time frame, then spot
block is a good idea.
Lastly, let's look over dedicated instances and hosts and a bit more detail.
So this table just helps you understand the differences because it can be a bit confusing.
So we've dedicated instances and hosts.
It's enabling the use of dedicated physical servers.
Remember that we've dedicated instances your instances of running on hardware the other IWC customers
are not using, but other instances that aren't dedicated.
Instances in your account can share that hardware.
We then have, per instance, billing.
That's four dedicated instances per host.
Billing is for dedicated hosts and then lots of features here, which you don't get with dedicated instances.
You've got visibility of sockets, calls and the host I.D affinity between a host and an instant, so
you can choose where which instance your host is going to run on.
You can target instance placement and automatic instance placement is for both.
And you can add capacity using an allocation request for dedicated hosts.
So that's it.
For this lesson, we've covered a lot of ground and it's not the most exciting topic, but it really
is game for the exam.
There's lots of questions in the exam on EC2 pricing.
In the next lesson, we're going to look at some particular use cases.
We're just going to cover off when you would use each pricing model.
So I hope that is useful to you and I'll see you in the next lesson.