Hi, guys.
Welcome to another architectural patterns, and this time it's Amazon virtual private cloud.
So let's have a look at our first requirement.
An Amazon S3 bucket must only allow access from two instances in a private subnet using private eyepiece.
Well, in that case, you can create a VPC endpoint and configure a bucket policy that restricts access
to the VPC Endpoint ID using the condition elements.
Malicious traffic is reaching some EC2 instances in a public subnet from a few identified public IP
addresses.
Well, in that case, the best way to handle this is to use a network ICL to deny access based on the
source IP addresses.
Of course, you could use the web application firewall WAF as well, which we cover later in the course,
but that might be more costly, so this is an easy way to implement this very quickly.
A company wants to connect their on premises data center to IWC and requires consistent performance
and encryption.
Well, remember you don't get consistent performance over the internet.
That's never the case.
So you need a direct connect connection, but you can't get encryption on a direct connect connection,
so you have to run a site to site VPN over the top.
A company requires private connectivity between sees in different regions with full redundancy.
Well, you can try to VPC pairing connection between the sees, and that gives you that private connectivity
and it can be across accounts and across regions.
Several remote office locations should be connected to an Amazon PPC and to each other over the internet
with full encryption.
Well, in that case, you can create a VPN and attach multiple remote locations in a hub and spoke topology,
and that's an IWC cloud hub topology, and they get to route between themselves as well as into an ounce
of the BPC.
Micro Services app requires instance level firewall with different rules per application component.
Classic case for security groups for each application component.
And you just need to make sure you configure the appropriate rules.
A company is using IPv6 addresses with Amazon easy to a needs to enable outbound internet connectivity.
Well, in that case, rather than a internet gateway, you need an egress only internet gateway that's
for IPv6.
A subnet must be configured that allows internet connectivity using IPv4.
We've also address assignment.
Well, in that case, you should attach an internet gateway to the.
Update the roundtable table for the new subnet and then enable the auto assigned public IPv4 setting
for the subnet as well.
And on premises data center needs to establish site to site VPN connections to several VPNs and a full
mesh architecture.
Well, then you might want to deploy an eight U.S. transit gateway.
Attach the VPN connection from the on premises and then attach it also to each VPC.
And that will give you that full mesh architecture.
And it's a very simple way of implementing this topology, and that's it for this architecture patterns.