Welcome to the exam, cram for Amazon as free, so we've is free.
You can store any type of file files can be anywhere from zero bytes to five terabytes.
There is virtually unlimited storage available as free as a universal namespace of bucket names must
be unique globally, but you have to create your buckets within a specific region.
It's therefore best practice to create your buckets in regions that are physically closest to your end
users, and that will reduce latency.
There's no hierarchy for objects within the buckets.
S3 delivers strong read off the right consistency, so with buckets, files get stored in buckets and
the bucket can be viewed as a container for the objects.
It's a flat container of objects with no hierarchy, but you can use an object, key name or prefix
to mimic folders.
You've got 100 buckets per account by default as a limit, but you can store unlimited objects in your
buckets.
You cannot create nested buckets, or a bucket will never go inside another bucket.
Objects are the files that you upload as free as free supports any file type, and each objects is stored
and retrieved by a unique key.
Objects remain in the region in which they're stored unless you set up replication.
Permissions can be defined on objects at any time.
The storage class is set at the object level, and here are the storage classes.
So this is something for you to review.
I'm not going to go through them all.
We've been through them quite extensively in the course, but you need to understand the various features
and use cases for each of these different storage classes before you sit the exam.
We then have different types of policies that we can apply IAM policies and bucket policies.
I am policies, identity based policies.
The principle is not defined within an IAM policy.
Bucket policies are resource based policies with bucket policies.
They can only be attached to Amazon S3 buckets and both use the same IWC access policy language.
We then have access control lists.
These are a legacy access control mechanism.
IWC will generally recommend using S3 bucket policies or IAM policies rather than ACLs.
They can be attached to a bucket or directly to an object, and you get limited options for the grantees
and the permissions that you can apply.
Nowhere near the power of a JSON based IAM policy.
So when should you use each use?
I am policies if you need to control access to AWB services other than as free.
If you have numerous free buckets, each with different permissions requirements I am policies will
turn out to be a lot easier to manage or if you prefer to keep access control policies in the IAM environment,
use bucket policies.
If you want a simple way to grant cross account access to S3 without using IAM roles, or if your IM
policies are reaching the size limits, you might prefer to keep access control policies in as free
as free versioning.
Versioning is a means of keeping multiple variants of an object in the same buckets.
You use versioning to preserve, retrieve and restore every version of the object stored in your S3
buckets and versioning.
Enable buckets will enable you to recover objects from accidental deletion or overrides.
There are two types of actions with lifecycle management transition actions and expiration actions.
Remember the supported transitions?
I'm not going to go through each of these.
I'm just going to put them up on the screen for you to read through.
And perhaps the easiest way to remember this or to understand it is to use the diagram on the right
hand side.
We then have the unsupported transition so you can't transition from any storage class to S3.
That's a quite a simple one to remember.
Any storage class to reduce redundancy intelligence hearing to S3 Standard, i.e. one zone item, S3
Standard, IEEE or intelligent tearing.
And again, if you understand the diagram on the right hand side, that would be an easy way to remember.
Moving on to multifactor authentication delete this adds an MFA requirement for changing the versioning
state of a bucket or permanently deleting an object version.
And that's what bucket owners the X aims at MFA request header must be included in the above requests.
The second factor of authentication is generated by a hardware device or software program like a authenticator
app such as the Google Authenticator app that we've used in this course.
It does require versioning to be enabled on the bucket.
Versioning can be enabled by bucket owners.
The root accounts AWG account that created the bucket and authorised IAM uses MFA deletes because.
Be enabled by the bucket owner only, what about protected API access with MFA?
This is used to enforce another authentication factor.
An MFA code when accessing resources and not just as free.
It's enforced using the aid of U.S. multifactor auth age key in a bucket policy for S3 encryption.
We went over the options available in quite a bit of detail in the lessons.
So you remember this SC S3, that's when you're using s freeze existing encryption key for a two five
six encryption SC C is where you're uploading your own as to five six encryption key, which is free
then uses for U.
S. CMS is where you're using K keys and client side is where you have your own encryption keys and you're
managing the encryption as well.
There's no encryption happening on.
You're doing it before you upload your object's default.
Encryption is a way to set the default encryption behavior for unnecessary buckets after you enable
default encryption.
All new objects will be encrypted when they're uploaded.
The objects are encrypted using server side encryption, and S3 encrypts objects before saving them
the disk and decrypt them when they're being downloaded.
There's no change to the encryption of objects that existed in the bucket before the default encryption
was enabled.
We then have event notifications.
This is where he sends notifications when an event happens in an buckets.
The destinations include S.A., iSCSI and Lambda multiple upload uploads, objects and parts independently
in parallel and in any order it's performed using the multiple upload API and it's recommended for objects
above 100 megabytes.
And it can be used for objects from five megabytes up to the maximum file size, which is five terabytes,
and it has to be used for any objects larger than five gigabytes.
Next, we have transfer acceleration.
This is a way of improving the performance of transfers of files, and it leverages the cloud front
edge locations.
You can accelerate uploads of objects over long distances, so you're reducing latency transfer.
Acceleration is as secure as a direct uploads as free, and you're charged only if there's a benefit
in the transfer time you need to enable transfer acceleration on the S3 bucket.
It cannot be disabled after that, but only suspended.
The free copy API is where you can copy objects up to five gigabytes, and it can be used to generate
additional copies of objects rename objects.
Changed the storage class or encryption at rest status.
Or move the objects between IWC locations and regions.
You can also change the object metadata.
Server access logging provides detailed records for the requests that are made to a bucket.
The information that is logged includes the request to the bucket name, the request, time, request,
action, response status and error code.
It's disabled by default, and you only pay for the storage space that's actually used.
You must configure a separate bucket as the destination, and you can specify a prefix if you want to.
You must also grant write permission to the Amazon S3 Log Delivery Group on the destination bucket.
Calls with Amazon S3 is enabled free setting, the access control, allow origin, allow methods and
allow head of settings.
These settings are defined using rules and the rules are added using JSON files in Amazon hash rate.
The Cross Account Access Methods, Resource Base policies and IAM policies can be used for programmatic
access to S3 bucket objects, resource based ACL and I am policies for programmatic access to S3 bucket
objects as well.
If you need programmatic and console access, you can use Cross Account I roles for performance optimizations.
S3 does support at least 3500 puts copy paste deletes or 5500 head requests per second per prefix in
a bucket, so it's pretty high performance.
You can increase, read or write performance by paralyzing reads.
You can use Byte range fetches.
You can retry requests for latency sensitive applications, and you can combine S3 and easy to in the
same region for better performance.
Lastly, you can use Amazon S3 transfer acceleration to minimize any latency caused by long distances.
And that's it for this exam chrome.