Another security feature of S3 is server access logging, with server access logging, you can log the
requests that are made to S3.
So that means you can log whatever happens.
Innisfree, for instance, somebody uploads or downloads an object.
You can have an access log written to notify you or keep a record of that activity.
And that's useful for security and for access audits.
So the way you do it is you configure a source and a destination.
Buckett, the destination can actually be the same bucket, but it's recommended to be a different bucket.
Actually, if you use the same bucket, it will actually create a log entry for the writing of a log
entry.
So you might end up with more records in.
There might be a bit confusing.
So you're better off having a separate bucket.
Ideally dedicated specifically to that purpose, so we can do a couple of ways, we can enabler for
the console, you can enable it programmatically and it gives you a bit of information on the page here
about the format of the logs.
Another interesting thing is that his best efforts, server log delivery, so pretty much says here
that you will get a log or you maybe won't get a log.
It's it's not even guaranteed.
And if you do, it could be some hours after the event actually happens.
So let's just go to the console and have a look where we can implement this.
So we're in a bucket on the properties tab and we've got this entry here, server access logging.
So if I enable this, this will be the source packet.
So this is where the log logging will take place based on activities that happen within this bucket.
So I can choose my bucket and I'm going to follow the recommended advice and use a different bucket
for the destination.
And I can then put a prefix in as well so I could say deliver it to logs and that will mean that I can
separate out those logs and identify the more easily.
So we can click on Save.
The other thing that needs to be done is on the destination bucket, we have to assign permissions for
an access control list to the S3 log delivery group when you enable server access logging for the console.
It actually already creates a couple of these permissions for you.
So hopefully that will work.
OK.
So what we want to do now is just go back and actually generate some activity on our bucket, so let's
just upload a couple of files.
I'm just going to.
Choose a couple of these files I've got here, and then we'll just delete those files and that just
gives us a bit of activity happening.
As I mentioned before, it can take some time to actually generate the log files.
So you might want to just give it a bit of time and then come back in an hour or two and just see what
log files are being generated.