So moving on to auto scaling, auto scaling dynamically and automatically ensures the correct number of
instances for your application.
And it does so through what are called auto scaling groups so you create a collection of EC2
instances in an auto scaling group and it automatically horizontally scales your instances, launches
and terminates instances that's scaling out launching, and scaling in terminating. Auto scaling is triggered
by events and performance scaling actions.
It's a region specific service and it can span multiple Availability Zones within the region.
There's no cost to using auto scaling.
You just pay for whatever EC2 instances get provisioned. You can attach your ALBs to your ASGs.
You can attach target groups to your ASG and that means you can include instances behind an ALB.
and also in an NLB as well.
The ELBs have to be in the same region as the auto skaling groups.
The launch configuration is the template that you use to create new instances so it defines the instance
family and type the AMI to use, the key pair, the security groups to use when an instance is launched
from auto scaling.
You can't edit a launch configuration.
Definitely an exam question.
Just watch out for where you need to make some kind of modification to the instances in your auto scaling
group.
And remember you can't go in and change the launch configuration.
You've got to create a new one.
You can also use your launch configuration with multiple auto scaling groups.
Now these are the scaling options so you have maintain you have manual scheduled and dynamic the maintain
ensures the required number of instances of running.
So you might say I want four instances to be running at all times and it would just make sure that
four instances are running.
You then have manual where you can just manually change the desired capacity, scheduled adjusts the amount
of instances for specific dates or times.
So watch out for exam questions where they say for instance an organization has noticed that when people
log on at 9:00 in the morning or the system slow down.
Well you can then schedule that just before 9:00.
You can boot up or launch a series of EC2 instances to make sure that the load is catered for in
that busy period at the beginning of the day and then terminate them later in the day, and dynamic is
where it dynamically responds.
So there can be a bit of a lag which is why for instance you might want to use a scheduled.
In that use case I just mentioned because with the dynamic it will only respond when the systems are
already slowing down and a threshold perhaps to see utilization has reached a certain threshold.
We then have the scaling types that you associate with a dynamic scaling policies so you have target
tracking.
In this case it's where you want to keep your CPU usage or your memory usage or your network usage at
a specific level.
So you say well I would like to see that my instances are being used properly so I want to make sure
that 70 percent CPU across all my instances and so a target tracking will try and keep that utilization
at that level.
Simple scaling is more where it adjusts to a specific event that happens so you reach a certain threshold.
The CPU hits 80 percent right now launch a new instance when it drops down below a certain percentage
in the in the aggregate usage of your EC2 instances.
See then it might terminate an instance and the step scaling policy can make different adjustments
based on the size of the alarm breach.
You can also scale based on the number of messages in a simple queue service (SQS) queue.
Now this is something that can come up in an exam question for the SAA-C02 and what you do actually
to configure this is you create a custom metric that's sent to cloudwatch that measures the number
of messages in the queue per EC2 instance.
So you say if a certain number of messages are in the queue and you kind of divide that by the number
of instances you've got available then you know that you can work out a kind of threshold which is a
level at which you feel you need to launch an additional instance to handle the amount of messages in
that queue and you do that for a target tracking policy that scales based on that custom metric.
So for instance AWS recommend that you can create a custom metric called a backlog per instance and
that tracks not just the number of messages in the queue but the number available for retrieval.
The actual metric that you can base this off is SQS metric approximate number of messages.
So the termination policies these are the policies that control how your instance is terminated.
So which instances are terminated first when a scaling event occurs.
There is a default policy and their options are configuring your own customized termination policies.
The default policies designed to help ensure the instances span the availability zones for HA and
it's kept very generic and flexible.
Now what do you just look on the AWS Web site search for EC2 auto scaling termination policy and
just try and understand the logic behind the default termination policy and what the other termination
policies are that are available with easy to auto scaling. You can also define instance protection and
that stops auto scaling from scaling in and terminating specific instances. Auto scaling performs rebalancing
when it finds the number of instances across sizes are not balanced so that's something that it will
do automatically when auto scaling rebalances it launches new instances into the AZs that have the fewest
instances first and then it starts terminating instances in AZs that have more instances.
So that means it launches instances first then it terminates so it tries to make sure your application
is available rather than ensuring that it's the most cost effective by not having too many instances
running an imbalance may occur due to something like you've moved a availability zone a subnet you've
terminated instances there are capacity issues on AWS or spot has terminated an instance.
We then have health checks by default EC2 Auto Scaling uses the EC2 status checks.
You can also choose to use ELB health checks and custom health checks when you use ELB health
checks these are in addition to the EC2 status checks so you'll always use status checks but you can additionally
use health checks when you configure that and it's a best practice that you use.
ELB health checks as well.
Any health check failure will return an unhealthy status and the instance will be terminated.
So when you have ELB health checks it means that an instance is marked as unhealthy.
If the ELB reports it is out of service a healthy instance is entering into the in-service date and
when an instance is marked as unhealthy it gets scheduled for replacement.
If connection draining is enabled auto scaling waits for in-flight requests to complete or time
out before terminating instances.
So there's a grace period to make sure that open connections are completed before the instances of the
terminated. So unlike AZ rebalancing when instances are terminated because they're unhealthy.
It happens first.
So remember with the AZ rebalancing it will add additional instances and when they've been added successfully
it then terminates the instances in another availability zone to try and keep you at the number of instances
you want.
However with unhealthy instances they're just terminated immediately and then also scaling attempts
to launch a new instance.
You can suspend and resume scaling processes for your auto scaling groups and you might do this when
you need to investigate configuration problem or some kind of issue so that the screening process isn't
invoked because otherwise you might find that auto scaling is trying to replace the instance that you've
taken off line to work on.
You can also manually remove instances from the ASG and put it into a standby state that's used for
performing updates changes troubleshooting and so there's a thing called the cooldown period and that's
a configurable setting for the also scrolling group that ensures that it doesn't launch or terminate
additional instances before previous activity has taken effect so previous scaling activity and the
default value for that is 300 seconds.
The warm up period is the period of time in which a newly created instance launched by ASG using step
scaling is not considered towards the ASG metrics onto monitoring basic monitoring sends metrics
to cloud watch about EC2 instances every five minutes and that's free and then detailed can be enabled
every one minute and that's chargeable.
Now if the launch configuration's created from the console.
Basic monitoring is enabled by default.
However if you create the launch configuration from the CLI detailed monitoring of EC2 instances is enabled
by default.
So that's it for this exam cram.
There's a lot of information there but I hope that you've retained some of that because this is definitely
a big subject for the exam.
Both ELB and auto scaling are definitely very prominent in the exam.