This lesson, we're going to cover some architecture patterns for Amazon S3.
The first requirement is a company is concerned about accidental deletion of Amazon S3 objects.
Well, they might want to mitigate this by using S3 versioning.
Data stored in S3 is frequently access for 30 days, then is rarely accessed, but must be immediately
retrievable.
So this is all about which storage class is best, where you could use a lifecycle policy to transition
objects from S3 Standard to S3 Standard infrequently access after 30 days, a backup of S3 objects within
a specific folder in a bucket must be replicated to another region where you could configure cross region
replication and specify the folder name as a prefix.
Previous versions of objects in a versioning enabled S3 bucket must be stored long term at the lowest
cost.
Well, for this, you could create a lifecycle rule that transitions previous versions to S3 Glacier
Deep Archive, and that's the cheapest option for storing that long term.
A company wishes to manage all encryption of S3 objects through their application with their own encryption
keys.
In that case, you should use client side encryption with client managed keys.
Unencrypted objects in an Amazon S3 buckets must be encrypted well, to do this, you need to re upload
the objects because they're already there and you can't encrypt existing objects, and when you upload
them, you can specify the encryption to use and the encryption key.
An administrator requires a notification when objects are deleted from an S3 buckets.
Well, for this, you can simply configure an event notification that uses the same service.
A group of customers without IWC credentials must be granted limited access to a software update that
is stored in an S3 bucket.
For this, you can generate a precise URL and the users won't need a night up U.S. accounts and it will
be time limited.
Solutions architects require both programmatic and console access across IWC accounts.
For that, you can configure cross account access using IAM roles.
And that's it for this architecture patterns.