And this architectural patterns lesson, I'm going to cover Amazon EC2.
So the first requirement is a company needs to run a short batch script to configure Amazon E2 Linux
instances after they are launched.
So what could you do here?
Well, it's a short script, so hopefully it's under the 16 kilobyte limit for user data.
And if that's the case, you can add the patch script to the user data of the two instances, and then
it will run as they boot up as a launch for the first time, a tightly coupled HPC workload, high performance
computing requires low latency between nodes and optimum network performance.
So what's the best architecture here?
Well, you should launch the active instances in a single A-Z and a cluster placement group and use
an elastic fabric adapter.
And that's a standard pattern for this type of workload that needs very low latency communications between
nodes.
A line of business application receives weekly bursts of traffic and must scale for short periods,
and you need the most cost effective solution.
In this case, you could use reserved instances for the minimum required workloads, so that's going
to give you a big discount from the standard rates.
And you know that they're going to run all the time anyway, because it's a line of business application
that means it's an important production application for the business.
It's not going away any time soon.
And then you can use spot instances for the occasional bursts in traffic because, you know, those
are short lived, and that means that you can get some cost savings there as well.
A single instance application uses a static public IP address.
In the event of failure, the address must be remapped to a fellow, for instance.
In this case, you can attach an elastic IP address to the instance, and you can remap the IP address
in the event of a failure.
And that can be done programmatically, so you might have some kind of automated way of deploying that.
A fleet of Amazon EC2 instances run in private submarkets across multiple aces.
Company needs a redundant path to the internet.
Well, in this case, you could use NAT gateways so that your instances in the private subnets have
internet access and you can put them into multiple A-Z.
So you've got that high availability because it does ask for redundancy here, and then you need to
update the root tables to point them to the NAT Gateway.
A team of engineers must administer EC2 instances in private subnets from remote locations using SSA
edge to secure shell protocol.
Well, in that case, you can deploy a bastion host in a public subnet and instruct the engineers to
use the Bastiaan host to jump to the instances.
In private subnets, an application uses several active instances the architect must eliminate the risk
of correlated hardware failures.
Well, in that case, he could launch the instances in a spread placement group across distinct underlying
hardware.
This means that each of the instances in the application is essentially in a separate rack of servers
in the IWC data center with separate power supplies and so on.
And that means there shouldn't be a correlated hardware failure.
An application requires enhanced networking capabilities.
We can choose an instance type that supports enhanced networking, and you need to ensure that the INA
module is installed in any support is enabled.
Some allies, like the Amazon Linux two IAMAI, are already configured with the in-a module when it's
enabled, so you already get that support.
For others, you do have to complete these extra steps.
An instance needs close to bare metal performance EFI, the elastic fabric adapter and high performance
networking.
Well, in this case, you might want to use an IWC Nitro instance type, and that's it for this architecture
patterns.