Hi guys.
In this lab we're going to be creating another Amazon CloudFront distribution.
This time we're going to be using a custom origin with EC2 instances in an auto scaling group behind
an application load balancer.
This time we're going to be creating everything from scratch.
So let's get over to the console before we get started I just wanted to show you that the two distributions
that we set to disable on in the previous lab are now disabled and can be deleted.
So you do have to wait for those for a while so easy to forget them.
Don't forget to come back in and then just delete.
So that's done.
Let's head over to EC2.
And what I want to do is firstly I'm going to create a load balancer so let's create an application load
balancer and I'm just going to call this myalb.
It's going to be an Internet-facing load balancer and I'm going to use HTTP.
I'm going to use my custom VPC and I'm just going to go in and select a couple of public subnets
and let's click next going to choose my web access security group and then I'm going to create a new
target group called TG1.
We're going to leave all the defaults here and we're just going to change the healthy threshold to two
don't have any targets to attach yet.
So let's just click Create. So that's creating let's go to auto scaling groups and I wanted to do all
this just to make sure that you guys are getting more practice because it's easy with a long course
as well to forget a few things that you learned earlier.
So let's just keep our our skills sharp by re-using the skills that we learned. I now need to create
the launch configuration for my auto scaling group.
Just gonna call it LC1.
I'm going to use my S3 full access I and I'm going to then paste in some code for the user
data.
If you've done the EC2 section in the course and the ELB section of the course you'll recognize
this code.
Essentially we're installing a web server and we're then giving that web server a name.
So when the index.txt file is displayed it will say "this is" and it will have a name.
And that way we can see that where our load balancer is working and we're cycling between different
servers.
It does rely on a couple of files.
These are in the course downloads and they need to be in the path to your bucket here.
And then need to choose assign a public IP address to every instance click next going to choose the
web access security group and then click review and create launch configuration.
Choose my key pair and then I'm going to create my auto scaling group and this is gonna be ASG1 I'm
going to have two instances, custom VPC again and I want these to be in a public subnet.
Course you could use a private subnet but you would then need a NAT Gateway and what I'm gonna do is
I'm going to say receive traffic from one or more load balancers and choose my target group and I'm
going to leave the health check setting at default.
I don't want to set instance protection so let's just go straight for now and click Create auto scanning
group so that should take a few minutes.
We can always go into our target group go to targets and shortly we should see our targets registered
so that's working I can see that my targets are being registered and they're in the initial state while
that's happening.
Let's go back over to CloudFront and create our distribution because it will take a few minutes
to create the distribution we click Create distribution.
We choose web and Origin domain name.
We're going to come down and here's the elastic load balancer and myalb.
I don't need to specify any settings there and in fact I think we can leave pretty much all these defaults
and I can click Create distribution and that's now in the states as in progress is being created and
that could take a while sometimes you know it could be 15 minutes or more so let's just leave that going
and let's go back and check how our target groups are and then hit refresh and they're healthy so that's
awesome.
Let's go to load balancer.
I'm going to get the DNS name and copy that's in my clipboard and let's just go and paste this into
the browser.
And so here we get our index.html page and it says "Hi this is Joseph".
And if I hit refresh I've got Sharon as well so that that means I've got a different index.html
file on each of my back end EC2 instances and because this is a load balancer I can just
hit refresh and I'm just going to cycle between those. We don't actually have to wait until this is
completely deployed what we can do is just grab this domain name copy it to our clipboard and let's
then go to another tab and put it in.
And sure enough it is up and running so I can see I've got the index.html file from one of my
instances.
Now if I refresh of course I get the same one because the content has been cached so obviously this
is not an ideal solution when you have what we have in our lab environments. In our lab environment we
have to different EC2 instances that have different content. Now that isn't the way that you would normally
define your instances behind an application load balancer you want your instances to have the same content
so it doesn't matter which instance the connection goes to but it's an interesting point to point out
because this is where you have a use case then for multiple origins and setting up behaviors.
So if you remember what we can do is go into our distribution we can select another, we can create another
origin.
And so if we had multiple application load balancers we'd be able to select a different one now and then
we could create a behavior rule that says that traffic that's destined for a certain path like a /images
or a /checkout or whatever, whatever it might be, goes to a different origin.
Now we finished what I wanted to show you in this lab but one of the other things that I wanted to cover
is Lambda Edge so if we come down to if we create a new distribution here we just scroll down to here
it is Lambda function associations and we can actually just click on learn more.
And it tells us about adding triggers for a Lambda Edge function.
And what this means is you can create AWS Lambda functions that
execute closer to your users and say you know the example that says here is you can create a trigger
that causes the function's execute when CloudFront receives a request from a viewer for a specific cache
behavior you set up for your distribution.
So this is another way of getting your logic closer to your users as well as your content.
This is definitely something that can come up in the exam so it's worth just reading up on Lambda Edge
just to understand exactly what it is.
Another thing that I said I'd show you is the log files that are produced by CloudFront.
So let's go back to S3 and this is actually from the previous lab where we had a bucket.
We didn't configure logging this time but let's go into dctlabs.com and I had this SIF f logs prefix
and we've been here we have a bunch of zip files so I can download these and so you can see some of
the information that's been logged here and there isn't too much, we haven't sent many requests but
one of the things that stands out is the source IP so you can see the IP you can see something that
obviously relates to Sydney the region.
You can see the CloudFront distribution name and you can see some information about the browser and
even the computer and the processor type that's being that's on my client that I'm connecting from.
So that's it for there.
Now don't forget to go back and delete your resources.
You can delete your load balancer.
You can delete your target groups and you can go to auto scanning
delete your ASG and if you want to you can go also and delete your launch configuration
and just check that your instances get terminated.
The IEA should do that but sometimes I just go in and do it myself anyway just to be sure.
And then that's everything cleaned up there.
We just then need to go back to CloudFront and again you've got to disable and then delete so I can
hit disable and then I'm gonna have to come back in 10 or 15 minutes and just delete this distribution.