Welcome to the exam cram for Section seven.
We're starting off with Amazon S3.
So entries are distributed architecture and objects and redundantly stored on multiple devices across
multiple facilities in an Amazon S3 region.
It's a simple key based object store and uses a standard rest based interface.
Your files can be zero bytes to five terabytes in size and the largest object that can be uploaded in
a single put is five gigabytes if you use objects larger than one hundred Meg it's recommended to use
the multiple upload the capability. Event notifications are a way that you can send triggers or alerts
based on specific events that happen event notifications can be triggered for specific actions to send
alerts or trigger actions in another service and they can be sent to SNS topics SQS queues, Lambda
functions and you need to configure SQS queues and Lambda before you configure S3.
There's no extra charges but you do pay for SQS queues and Lambda. S3 provides
read after write consistency for puts of new objects and eventual consistency for overwrite puts and
deletes so because the data is replicated across multiple Availability Zones.
The eventual consistency just means that there's a little but a time delay where the data must be synchronized
across those different copies of the data.
So remember eventual consistency when you overwrite an object with a put or you delete an object as
free data is made up of a key.
That's the name of the object and then you have value which is the data version i.e. metadata and an
ACL.
There's a few extra capabilities about S3 that you need to know about so transfer acceleration
speeds up uploads using cloud front so it's uploading data and it makes it faster to upload that data
request space means that rather than the bucket owner paying for the requests and the data transfer
the requester pays and that means another AWB account.
You can assign tags you can trigger events as we talked about before and you can create a static website
on S3.
You can even use the BitTorrent protocol to retrieve publicly available objects.
Now I don't go into these in more detail here because ESRI is a really big subject and go into detail
on all of these would take us a long time but there is more information obviously on the IWC website
but also on the training notes typical use cases for S3 include backup and storage application hosting
media hosting software delivery and static websites.
So an S3 bucket remember your files or your objects are stored in a bucket so it's a container for the
objects.
It's a flat container.
You don't have a hierarchy so you have a single bucket and that's it.
And then you put your objects inside the bucket but you can use a folder and that's essentially it.
It's actually an object key name or prefix but it looks like a folder so it looks like you're creating
a hierarchy as you would file system.
You can have 100 buckets per account by default and you can store unlimited objects in your buckets.
You can create folders as mentioned before.
This is only available through the console.
You can't nest buckets so it's just one bucket at the top level.
You could also create lots of buckets but you can't have a bucket within a bucket and each bucket is
created in a region.
Again remember this one very important for the exam.
S3 as a global service.
So when you administer it you don't select a region it's just global.
But when you create a bucket you specify a region and your data is held within that region and it's
never replicated out of that region unless you create a replication configuration yourself.
So each object is stored and retrieved using the key name.
And so you can identify and connect to your objects using a service end point the bucket name the object
key name and then potentially the object version as well.
As mentioned before objects stored in a bucket never leave the region in which they're stored unless
you move them to another region or you enable cross region replication.
You can define permissions and objects when you upload them at any time afterwards using the console.
Some resources.
This is another one where I've got a lot more information in the training notes I don't go into too
much detail right here.
You do need to understand these though you need to understand lifecycle rules so make sure you understand
lifecycle management.
You need to understand that you can use S3 as a static website that you can enable versioning to
keep multiple versions of an object access controls which control permissions to access the bucket.
You need to understand those as well for the exam and then bucket policies which are more like an I
am policy with Jason code and you apply those two buckets and control access then have cross origin
resource sharing which can be enabled or restricted and logging.
So definitely as I mentioned before.
Check the training notes and our e-book.
We've got lots more information about each of these so you can understand them at a deeper level.
It'll be quite tedious to sort of go into it now.
So I'd rather that you just go and have a look at the training nights and just read up on these and
understand what they are for storage classes.
There are six storage classes you got the standard the intelligent tiering which automatically moves
data to the most cost effective tier you've got standard infrequently accessed you've got one zone II
which is one zone infrequently accessed so only stores data in one availability zone.
You've got glacier and then you've got deep Archive which is the version essentially is the original
glacier.
It's the one where you get the lowest cost and it takes at least 24 hours to get your data back whereas
with S3 glacier it's a little bit more expensive but you can get your data back faster.
This is a table from the AWS website and there's a few things you definitely need to know.
So these are the different storage tiers.
One thing that's easy to remember is that the durability is 11 nines for all of these tiers.
So that really equates to the likelihood of AWS is actually losing an object so it's very low.
It's very very resilient and then you have availability so this is really more about you being able
to access your objects so not whether they're lost or not they're still on AWS but can you actually
connect to them.
And in this case we can see we have some differences so we have four nines for S3 standard for it.
Also for S3 glacier and deep archive then we have three nines for these to the intelligent tearing in
the standard infrequently access and we have ninety nine point five for one zone IA.
There's even an SLA the availability zones is free for everyone except one zone IA.
And then you do need to understand that there is a minimum capacity charge for some tier so for these tiers
a minimum storage duration for those tiers.
So basically for everything except S3 standard and there's also a retrieval fee that's associated
with these four tiers here.
Make sure you know those because they can come up in exam questions.
There are quite a lot of exam questions on S3 so it is quite a big subject and you do need to really
understand it well.
So again multipart upload is where you have bigger uploads or bigger files that you need to upload and
it will upload the objects into different in different parts in parallel and in a specific order and
it's performed using the multi-part upload API. Recommended for objects of 100 MB or more and can be
used for objects from five MB up to five terabytes.
You absolutely have to use it if your objects are bigger than five gigabytes.
Then we got S3 copy so this is for creating a copy of objects up to five given size in a single
atomic operation for files bigger than five gig.
You have to use multiple upload so you can copy files up to 5 gig but you have to use multipart upload
for bigger than 5 gigabytes and for this you can use the SDK or the rest api so you can use the copy
operation to create copies of objects rename objects change the storage class or encryption at rest
status move them between locations or regions and change the object metadata so a bit more and transfer
acceleration.
This enables fast easy and secure transfers of files over long distances between your client and the
S3 bucket and it does not using cloud front.
So think about latency here and accelerating uploads.
There's no difference in the security is just as secure as uploading directly to S3 and you're only
charged if is a benefit in transfer times compared to just uploading straight to S3.
You have to enable this on the bucket and you can then disable it you can only suspend it.
Let's have a look at encryption.
There are four key encryption options.
You've got the server side encryption S3 the server side encryption with client provided keys the
server side encryption with KMS provided keys and then the client side where everything's encrypted
outside of AWS. For S3 performance
AWS recommend that you measure your performance that you scale your storage connections horizontally.
You use byte range fetches and you use retry of requests for licensee sensitive applications and you
can combine S3 and EC2 in the same AWS region so that's what you should do.
Also it's recommended to use transfer acceleration to minimize latency caused by distance.
Now again this is one where there's quite a lot of information to read up on here to understand the
difference.
Best Practices for performance.
Please check the training notes and the AWS documentation.
I'll put a link in.
There's definitely exam questions coming up asking about bite range fetches or where the answer is to
use byte range feature.
So you need to understand what that is.
It's really just a way of creating multiple parallel requests for your data to improve performance.