Hi, guys, in this lesson, we're going to create an IWC organization and add an account using the
organization, so it's going to look like this.
We have our management account, that's the account that we've been using so far.
In this course, it's going to become our management account because that's where we're going to actually
create the organization using the management console.
So once we've done that, we have our organization, our management accounts is at the roots of the
hierarchy now will then create a production account, and that production account is then going to get
organized into a production a year and later on, we'll be adding a service control policy to our own.
But we're not going to do that in this lesson.
So how do we access the accounts now?
When you create an account through organizations, you don't actually set a password for the root account.
You have to go through a process to get access via the root account, which we're not going to do.
Instead, what you do when you create the account is you specify the name of a role.
That role gets created in that account.
We're going to call it organization account access role.
That account has full permissions in that account.
So important to understand that when you assume this role, you get full permissions in that account.
Then we've all user in our management accounts will be able to assume that role.
And when we do that, we're using the SDS Assume Role API.
This can be done through the command line or through the console.
We'll do it through the console in this lesson in the management console.
Let's go to services and under management and governance, you'll find IWC organizations.
If you don't already have an existing organization, then this is the page you'll see.
And to create an organization is really, really simple.
All we have to do is click on this button, create an organization, and that's it.
The organization has been created, and as you can see, we have the route here.
That's the root of the hierarchy.
And this is the management account.
That's the account we're already logged in with, which is now the management account because this is
where we created the organization.
So the billing for consolidated billing will take place from this account.
So the credit card linked to this account will pay for all the resources in the other accounts that
are linked to it.
So how do we create an additional account?
Well, we simply click on add an IWC account.
We need to give it a name.
I'm going to call my DCT production.
We need to give an email address that needs to be unique.
It cannot be the same email address you used for the route account.
Next, you need to specify the I role name or accept the default.
We can accept the default organization account access role.
This is the role that gets created in the account that's being created now.
So the role will have administrative permissions and we'll be able to assume the role to be able to
access this particular account.
Now, another thing you can do is invite an existing IWC account.
So, for example, maybe you have some developers and they have their own accounts and you've decided
you want some kind of centralized governance management control.
Maybe you want to apply service control policies to them.
So you'd invite them to your organization and then an email is sent to the account owner of that account.
And if they accept it, their account gets joined to the organization.
Now, in this case, we're creating an account, so let's just go down here to create a WC account.
Now, while this is happening, one thing you'll have to do is go to your email and just check if you've
received a verification email for your organization.
You will need to verify your IWC organization, and once you've done that, you can sit back and relax
and wait for your new account to be created.
I just refreshed my screen and I now have my new account.
So I now have two accounts the management accounts and then my DCT production accounts.
The next thing I want to do is create an organizational unit that I'm going to put my production accounts
in.
So if I click on route, go to actions and under organizational unit, create new and I'm going to call
this one production and create organizational units.
So now we have a child 0U called production.
And what we can do is take our DCT production account and we can move it into the production organizational
unit.
So now we can see the under production, we have our DCT production account.
So what will next be able to do is add service control policies to the production.
Are you to apply some constraints on the permissions available in that account and more on that in the
next lesson?