Hi guys it's time to get hands on.
And in this lab we're going to cover Amazon relational database service. I'm in the AWS management
console I'm going to go to services, database, and choose RDS.
This is a managed service and we can choose from one of several different engines.
So what I'm gonna do is we're just gonna go through the wizard here.
You can just click Create database or go to databases and then create database and by default it always
comes out with Amazon Aurora.
Now I'm going to cover RDS in this lab but we're going to push Amazon Aurora out for a few labs
because it's a whole different beast.
And I want to tackle that independently.
So first off I just want to show you the options associated with these databases so let's choose mysql
you could also choose then MariaDB, PostgreSQL, Oracle or Microsoft SQL
server.
Now when doing your labs you can choose to select this option here which will ensure that you
only use options which are within the free tier.
I'm not going to do that for now and you can see by the way that a row gets greyed out straight away.
So you can't do Aurora.
So you don't get any free tier credits with Aurora but let's just click next and we now have an option
to choose our use case so let's say this is a production database which means I'm going to get some
defaults for provisioned I up storage high availability and fast and consistent performance I click
next.
And here you can choose your licensing model and then your engine version you then get an instance class.
So if you look here what you're basically looking at is the EC2 instance classes that are associated
with this database so you can choose your instance class here and this essentially means that your database
is going to get installed onto an EC2 instance and that's going to happen in your subnets as well.
So for instance we can choose, let's go for an  extra large instance
you then get an option to choose multi AZ.
You can choose no here if you don't want a redundant deployment we're going to go through multi AZ
in a lot more detail and another lab.
RDS uses EBS for storage.
That's why you recognize general purpose and provisions IOPS.
These are types of EBS storage and you can enable storage auto scaling so the storage allocation will
increase as your database increases in size.
We then get our estimated monthly costs.
So clearly this is not a free tier ones is going to cost sixteen hundred US dollars a month.
You then have to put in your settings so we can put in our database identifier.
Let's just call this digitalcloud and I'm just going to paste this into the master username and password
sections as well and then click on Next
we now get an option to choose our VPC.
So I could choose my custom VPC and then we get to choose a subnet group a DP subnet group is a collection
of subnets in which your database instances are going to be launched.
You can then choose whether you want them to get a public IP address and be publicly available or not
and you can choose the availability zone within this VPC that you put them in can choose a security
group or allow it to create one for you you can then put in your database name the port of for mySQL
is free for you 06 and you can then enable IAM DB authentication as well so if you leave this disabled
you'll just use your traditional method of using the username and password to connect to the database.
If you enable IAM D.B. authentication you can then use authentication tokens that can be associated
with users and roles you can enable encryption for your database and you have to do that at this point
in time so you can enable it at a later point in time.
There is a way around that and we'll go through that in a second but basically you need to ensure that you
enable this at the time that you create your database if you want an encrypted database.
So let's just click learn more because there's a great article here which can give you a bit more detail
let's just scroll down to the bottom and what I want to point out to you are the limitations of RDS
encryption.
So the first thing to note is you can only enable encryption for an RDS DB instance when you create
it not after the DB instance is created.
So that's an important point.
But because of this is using EBS storage and you can take snapshots of your database and you can then
encrypt that snapshot and what you can do then is you can restore the encrypted snapshot to a new DB
instance. It has to be a new one, it can't be the same DB, instance but you can create a new DB instance
from that encrypted snapshot and now you've got around the problem where you wanted to encrypt an existing
database.
The next point is that DB instances that are encrypted can't be modified to disable encryption so again
it all comes down to you get the choice when you first deploy your database to encrypt or not encrypt
and you've kind of got to live with that except where you might be out to use the encrypted snapshot
option to create a new encrypted database but you can't do it the other way around.
You also can't have an encrypted read replica of an unencrypted DB instance or an unencrypted read replica
of an encrypted DB instance and we'll talk more about read replicas and I'll show you how to configure
those within this section.
Also note that encrypted redirect because must be encrypted with the same key as the source D.B. and
you can't restore an unencrypted backup or snapshot to an encrypted DB instance.
So this comes back to this first point here where sure you can encrypt a snapshot but you can't restore
it to an unencrypted database you have to create a new database restore the encrypted snapshot to that
database and then you've got you encrypted database
and also when you copy encrypted snapshots between regions you have to specify the came as key identifier
of the destination AWS region.
So what what RDS will do is it will re-encrypt your data with the same key from the destination
region.
The next section in the configuration wizard is backup and the default is that you retain your backups
for seven days.
You can choose 0 which means nothing is going to be retained or you can go up to 35 days.
So I just put that back to the default and you can choose a window in which the backups going to be
taken.
So obviously if you want to ensure that any performance implications have taken the backup out within
a time when your users aren't using it then you can select your window there.
You can also enable enhanced monitoring which will cost you a bit more that uses cloudwatch by default
it would be disabled except in the scenarios where you're choosing this production workloads so it's
automatically enabled that under maintenance you can define a maintenance window and that means that
when patches or security updates need to be installed it will happen within this time frame and it might
mean in some cases such as for security updates that your easy to instance on which your database is
running needs to be restarted.
So that means a database outage so you can choose the window here.
And if you've got multiple AZ then you can ensure that your database stays up by using the replica copy
of your database.
You can also choose whether minor upgrades are automatically installed or not.
You can also enable deletion protection which just means you've got an extra layer of security to stop
your database accidentally being deleted.
Now I'm not gonna click
Create database here because obviously this one is gonna cost lots of money.
So what I'm gonna do is just cancel out of here and in the next lab we're going to install Wordpress
on an EC2 instance and use RDS mysql
as the database backend.