Hi, guys, in this lesson, I'm going to teach you about the Amazon Virtual Private Cloud or VPC.
Now obviously, you've already been using VPC quite a bit in this course, and that's where you've launched
EC2 instances and you choose a VPC to put them into.
And then within the VPC, you choose a subnet.
Well, sometimes we just allow it to auto assign both HPC, incorporate several different concepts,
and what we're going to do in this section is go into them in much more detail.
So first, we'll start off with the core knowledge around VPC itself.
So within a region we have of Epix's and they are always within a region they can't span across regions.
A VPC is essentially a logically isolated portion of the IWC cloud that you can then use to deploy your
resources inside it.
And that's different to the public space outside of the VPC, where services like Amazon has free set.
This is a private space and you have full control over how you configure your VPC.
Now, as you know, within a region, we have availability zones and you could use those within your
VPC by creating subnets and assigning those subnets to an availability zone.
A subnet is always assigned to one availability zone.
It can't span across multiple axes, but you can of course, have multiple subnets in the same A-Z.
We then deploy our resources, such as Easy two instances, into our subnets.
Now there's a thing called the VPC router.
You don't really see the VPC browser, but it exists and we interact with it by configuring roundtables.
Now, the VPC router takes care of all routing for connections that are going outside of a subnet.
If you send data out of a subnet, it's got to go somewhere else, maybe to another subnet or maybe
out to the internet or some other network.
So the router takes care of making sure the data connection is sent to the right place.
Now, as I said, you don't see the VPC router.
All you do is see the root tables and they are configuring the VPC routes are for you.
So we need to specify the destinations and the targets for certain networks, and that's how it then
knows where to send those connection items.
If we want to access the internet, we also need an internet gateway.
The internet gateway is attached to your VPC.
You only ever have one per VPC.
The Internet Gateway is used for sending data out to the internet.
That's egress, traffic and in from the internet.
That's ingress traffic.
And we configure a roundtable with a route to the Internet Gateway I.D. that tells it to send all traffic
that doesn't fit one of the networks in the round table before it to the internet gateway.
Now you can create multiple VPNs within a region.
You have a limit of five by default, but you can request an increase on that amount.
Each VPC has a side, a block.
That's the overall block of addresses from which you then create the addresses you assign to your subnet.
So it's kind of like a master block of addresses.
Each VPC has a different one of these.
So in this case, we got two pieces and they have different side blocks.
As you learned in the last lesson, cider stands for classless into domain routing from the overall
side to block.
We can then create the network IDs for our subnet, and they fit within that overall cinder block.
But they have a different subnet mask so that essentially a subset of the overall available addresses.
And this is why it's really important to make sure we specify our side of blocks correctly.
So we have enough networks and enough hosts per network will cover that.
And another lesson so here we have two pieces each with different side blocks and then each with different
subnets that come from those side of blocks.
Now we're going to cover a lot of these components within this section, but I just want to cover them
at a high level now.
So you know what a VPC is and what subnet saw.
You know what an internet gateway is as well.
Now, an egress only internet gateway is when you're using the IPV six protocol, and it allows traffic
outbound only, whereas an internet gateway is the IP version four, and it allows both egress and ingress
traffic.
As you know the router, the VPC browser takes care of routing connections to the right places.
Now, a pairing connection is something where you can connect multiple VPNs and have private routing
between that would cover that in detail later on in the section VPC endpoint.
Allow you to connect using private IP addresses to public services on IWC, again, we'll cover that
in detail later on now, not instances and gateways.
We covered these earlier in the course.
These are both ways that you can enable internet connectivity outbound only for your instances in private
subnets.
The next two components the Virtual Private Gateway and the Customer Gateway are both related to creating
virtual private network VPN connections to our company offices or our company data centers.
So that's a virtually private network, an encrypted tunnel over the internet.
We then have direct connect that avoids the internet by using private connections right the way through
to your data center or office.
And security groups and network cycles are two different types of firewall.
We'll cover them in a bit more detail in this section.
We've used security groups quite a lot so far.
They are what we call a instance level firewall because they operate at the level of the network interface
attached to all two instances.
Then we have the network ICL.
That's a subnet level firewall, so it only sees traffic going in and out of the subnet.
So just to summarize that core knowledge, a VPN is a virtual network dedicated to your IWC accounts.
It's similar to having your own data centers inside IWC because you're able to have full control over
what you do with defining your side of blocks, creating your own subnet, setting up your security,
your routing, and so on.
You have lots and lots of control.
It's logically isolated from other virtual networks in the US cloud.
And as I mentioned before, you get full control over lots of the configuration items in your VPC.
And if VPC is a place where you then launch your resources, such as Amazon EC2 instances, when you
create a VPN, you must specify your side a block.
So that's the overall block of addresses.
Now we'll see how to select the best cyber block for our use case.
And another lesson a VPC spans all Azeez within a region that essentially means if there's three or
six or whatever number of aces in a region, you can create subnets within your VPC on all of those
aces.
But remember, each subnet is always within one A-Z.
It can't span disease, but you create multiple subnets if you want to.
In an availability zone, you get full control over access to your resources inside a VPC as well.
And by default, you can create five per region, but you can extend that if you submit a request.
A default VPC is created in each region with a subnet in each availability zone, and that's always
a public subnet.
So whichever region we change to, you'll find, is already a default VPC, and it already has a number
of public subnet in it.
Now that's it for this lesson, and the next lesson will have a look at how we can work out a suitable
site, a block for our use case.