OK, guys, let's get into the Amazon simple queue service, excuse us, excuse us is a fully managed
message queuing service.
So excuse messages that are received from one application component ready for delivery or consumption
from another application component.
So in this case, we've got a website where the website places messages on a queue and then the app
to keep track in the queue.
So it's polling in the queue and it checks and then eventually finds messages and then it processes
the messages.
So the queue is a temporary repository for messages that are awaiting processing and they're highly
scalable.
So you don't have to worry about how much space there is to store your messages.
The queue acts as a buffer between the component producing and saving the data and the component that's
receiving the data for processing so the queue can resolve issues that arise if the producer is producing
work faster than the consumer can actually process it, or if the producer and consumer are only intermittently
connected to the network.
So there's lots of use cases where you might want to do this because you can't rely on the fact that
your processing is going to be able to process the messages quickly enough for the Web to or they only
periodically check in.
So this means you don't need a direct connection between your application components.
So it's known as decoupling or loose coupling, and it enables you to elastically scale your application.
Now, ask us, is Paul based, not push based?
So like back on the diagram here, you see that the easy two instances are polling the cues, the arrows
going from the easy to instances to the queue.
The producers put it on the queue and then the consumers pull the queue and take it off.
So that means it's poll based and that's the opposite of S.A.S., which is push based.
Now, messages can be up to 256 kilobytes in size and they can be kept in the queue from one minute
to 14 days.
And the default retention period is four days.
Escalus will guarantee that your messages will be processed at least once.
So that's a basic overview of what excuses.
And in the next lessons, we're going to go into more detail on some of the components, starting with
queue times in the next lesson.