Hi guys in this lesson we're going to talk about the key management service - KMS. So this is used for
creating keys that are used for encryption and it's a way that you can use a managed service for
creating or uploading existing keys into that service and then being able to use those for encryption
purposes.
Now there's a couple of different types of keys so I'm just gonna head over to a slide to talk about
that a bit more so we have these three different types of keys and these are called customer master
keys.
You've got the customer manage CMK key, the AWS managed key and then AWSs own CMK key.
So with the customer manage CMK this is something that you have control over and it's dedicated to
your account and you must manage it with the AWS.
You can see it and it is dedicated to your account so you wherever you see a Key you'll note that key
is only used for you within your account.
However you don't have the option to manage it.
These are created for you and managed for you with the AWSs own CMK key, you don't have any control.
You don't see them, manage them, and they're shared across multiple accounts so we just head back into
the console on the left here you can see the AWS managed keys and the customer managed keys. So if you
head into here for instance under AWS managed keys you can see these keys that have been created automatically
for us when we've used these services.
And if you head in you can see some information about those keys and customer managed keys you can create
your own.
Now I created one earlier and then deleted it and you can see here it's pending deletion.
You'll see in a minute what that means.
So if we go and create a key, create key, just call it new key and you can then choose a few options
as to where the key material comes from.
So even it can be generated by came as it can come from an external source or it can come from the cloud.
Your HSM is a hardware security module you choose external.
You've then got to upload your own information.
In this case I'm just going to choose KMS and you can add tanks you can define the administrators
for the key and in this case I'm just going to add myself you can then specify if the key administrators
are allowed to actually delete the key because remember this is a really key thing if you if you delete
an encryption key you may not be able to decrypt or you won't be at the decrypt the data which has been
encrypted by that key so it's a very important operation that you want to protect you then click on
Next you can define the key usage permissions.
So this is who is able to not just administer but to use the key to encrypt and decrypt data.
And in this case you might choose a user account or you'd often choose a role as well.
So in this case I might want to Elastic Beanstalk to be able to encrypt and decrypt data on my behalf
you can then also specify other AWS accounts, click next.
We then see the key policy so you can see this policy written in here which is based on the configuration
options that we just chose.
And then if you click on finish it just creates the key for you.
And if you go into this key you can see some information you can add key administrators you can change
some of the options here and add the key users and you can also add overwrite AWS accounts at this
stage as well you had under key rotation there's an option here to rotate the same keys every year
and if you click on the learn more link, there you'll get a bit more information about that.
So that's basically saying that it's going to change the backing key for the customer master key once
every year to go back up and look at these keys what you'll see here is if you then want to delete a
key you actually don't have an option to delete it but you can schedule the key for deletion and you
can enable or disable the key as well so that will stop it from being used but if you schedule for deletion
it actually lets you know that they enforce a waiting period and this is between seven and thirty days
so I could reduce this down to seven and then so confirmed that I want to delete the key in seven days
and I click on schedule deletion it then goes to pending deletion just like my test one up here the
other option on the left is custom key stores and this is using CloudHSM so you can choose to create
a custom key store in CloudHSM and actually store your customer master keys there instead and
to do that you would need to first create the CloudHSM cluster and that's what we're actually going
to do in the next lab.