I just want to quickly cover off a couple of ways that you can both connect with me and also get support
as you go through the course, the Q&A forum is a good place to ask questions.
We do have a team of teaching assistants who were there to make sure that all the questions do get answered.
We have a Slack channel, which is a really great place to both connect with me and ask questions of
the group.
There's quite a few people in there, so there's always answers coming in for whatever question gets
asked.
Another way to get support is to join our Facebook group IWC Certification Kua.
We've got well over 50000 members in that group and it's a very active place to go and get your questions
answered.
Lastly, please feel free to reach out over LinkedIn.
It's great to connect my students and I love to see your certifications, so please share them on LinkedIn.
Thank me.
And that way I can share in your success.