Hi guys.
In this lesson I want to compare and contrast the differences between some of the different compute
models that are available in AWS so on the left hand side of this diagram we have infrastructure
as a service and the best example of this is the Elastic Compute Cloud.
EC2.
We then have containers as a service and the example is the elastic container service using either the
EC2 launch type or the Fargate launch type and then we have functions as a service and the best
example of this is lambda.
So what are the differences.
Well what I'm trying to show you here is an end to end stack.
So at the very bottom you have the physical hardware and then you have the various software layers with
the applications and the functions sitting on top.
Now functions are more applicable to Lambda but you can also use the same terminology with the way that
an application functions and interacts with other applications.
So this is the stack and the key thing to point out here is what is managed by the consumer.
In other words the AWS user with all of these options in AWS is the physical hardware layer is completely
taken care of for you on EC2.
We then have a hypervisor and that's also managed by AWS.
But what you're responsible for is the guest operating system and anything that you put on top of it.
So you have complete control but also complete management responsibility for everything from here upwards.
With containers as a service
there's a bit more of an abstraction for you so you don't have a guest operating system you don't have
Windows or Linux to to run. The container engine is largely taken care of for you and this really depends
which launch type you're using with ECS but you're really concentrating on a bit of a higher level. And
then with functions as a service everything is abstracted from you.
So all you have to worry about then is code.
So here you're managing at the VM instance level, here you're managing at the container level, and then
with Lambda you're literally just taking care of your code. I have another table here which just helps
us to understand the differences because it's really key for you to understand in the exam and for your
career to try and work out for any given solution
which of these is the best option and the way that the solutions architects exam is constructed is they're
very much looking to test you on your ability to choose the right service for the right solution and
they might ask you what is the most cost effective solution.
What is the most scalable solution.
What is the most operationally efficient solution.
These kind of things.
And by knowing these differences that are on the screen now you can work out what the differences between
these different compute options are. And you know if for instance.. if operational efficiency is the key for
this question, then you wouldn't want to go with EC2 because that has a much higher operational overhead
because you have to manage the operating system, whereas lambda you only have to manage the code. So just
going through this table in the middle here you have the EC2 launch type where you manage the container
instances so you have to remember that with the EC2 launch type you're still managing an EC2
instance you're also then managing the containers and the tasks. With the ECS Fargate launch type
you no longer have to worry about
EC2, you don't have to manage the container instances on which your container runs.
Instead you literally just create the containers and they run, and then with lambda that you just implement
your code and the function runs for you.
So how do you scale these solutions, well with EC2
you can scale vertically and that means that you can change your instance type or your instance families
so that you have more you more RAM, more EBS storage, or you can use auto scaling and that can be automatic
obviously, and you can then scale horizontally by adding more instances to your application so that will
work for some applications but not others. With ECS
what you have to do is add container instances.
So in other words you have to add more of these EC2 instances that run your containers and you add
those to your cluster even manually or you create an ECS service and use auto scaling and that's very
much the same auto scaling you are using here.
Just looking at certain cloudWatch metrics and if your performance gets to a certain point for instance
you'll see you had 80 percent then it adds additional instances. With Fargate
you don't have to worry about that.
So ECS will scale your cluster automatically and with Lambda you can automatically scale your concurrent
executions up to the default limit of 1000 concurrent executions.
And that's an account limit which you can change by contacting AWS and putting in an application.
So what are the use cases for these different compute options?
Well EC2 is more for traditional applications maybe applications that either aren't micro service or
service oriented, they might not be able to run in a container and they might be the sort of stable
applications you run for a long time or they might use certain languages frameworks and so on that aren't
compatible with containers.
So there are definitely use cases for using EC2. And then with ECS we're looking at micro services and batch
use cases so much more micro services architectures and then with the different launch types you then
need to work out for your use case do you need management or do you want management of the underlying
platform or would you rather have all that taken care of for you. With Lambda
there's lots of use cases such as extract transform load infrastructure, automation data validation,
mobile back ends, so Lambda is very much custom code, with EC2 is it could be more commercial off
the shelf applications, and with containers it can kind of fall somewhere in the middle.
With the next line
I just wanted to point out the limitation of nine hundred seconds in execution for lambda because that
could be an issue and if that is an issue then you could even look at going to containers always see
two and probably the next step would be to look at whether containers are compatible with your application.
Now these these timeout issues don't obviously apply to these other compute types. In terms of how you
pay for these resources with EC2 you pay for the instance runtime and that's based on the family and
the type of instance you're running that's the same with EC2 launch type on ECS because you actually
just pay for the EC2 instances you launch you don't pay for the containers you run on them. With
ECS Fargate launch type you pay for the container runtime you don't know how many underlying EC2
instances your containers are running, on that's completely abstracted away from you so you don't have
to pay for those you just pay for the number of containers you're running, the configuration of those
containers based on the amount of resources that you've allocated to them. And then with Lambda you just
pay for execution time and the amount of memory that's actually allocated to that function.
So that's just a quick overview of some of the differences.
Definitely worthwhile going to the FAQs for each of these services and then just try and understand
these differences in a bit more detail.