Before we get stuck into the labs on EBS I wanted to cover off instance stores and just outline the
differences between an EBS volume and an instance store volume so instance store volumes are ephemeral
storage and they're based on NVME technology which is local to the actual server where your instance
is running.
So EBS is actually accessed over a network whereas NVME is local to the actual server itself so it's
higher performance.
However being ephemeral that means that the data is not secure.
So when you switch off when you shut down your instance your data is lost so let's launch an instance
and see where this is.
So if we click on select we're just going to we need to scroll down here actually and find a different
instance type so we won't be able to find an instance store there.
But we should be out to find one here we can try.
Well let's just go right down to the bottom actually go to storage optimized.
This is this is a huge server and I'm pretty sure this comes with a whole bunch of instance stores so
if you go to add storage so you can see here that we have the root device which is always going to
be an elastic block store volume and then you have all these ephemeral disks and these are local devices
and NVMW technology and you can see it says here that it's an SSD
so ephemeral means that the data will not be persistent.
In other words when you shut down your instance if you stop it you will lose that data.
So there are some use cases where people do want to use these you can use them for some kind of temporary
data data that's perhaps distributed across instances and replicated in some other way and where you
need that high level of performance.
So with an ephemeral volume you can't stop your instance so you'll lose your data you can restart your
instance though.
And you can't detach an ephemeral volume from one instance and attach it to another like you can with
an EBS volume.
So those are just a few facts about ephemeral storage.
You will see it occasionally coming up.
I don't think they use very much anymore.
There's some fantastic performance coming through on EBS so it probably doesn't matter as much nowadays
but there are still use cases where some organizations will use it and you just need to be sure that
you understand from an exam perspective that if you see ephemeral that's an instance store and that
means that the data is not persistent.