Hi, guys, before we get stuck into the labs, I want to just teach you a few of the concepts around
elastic load balancing.
So some of you might come from a background where you're not that familiar with load balancing.
So we're just going to start at the basics here to just understand what it's all about.
So with a plastic load balancing, what we're trying to do is we might have an application like a Web
application that runs on multiple instances.
So the applications that are compatible with load balancing must be applications that you can run across
multiple instances.
So Eva, for instance, with a Web application, it could be a static Web application or it could be
using a shared file system.
So there could be an FSR system or S3 so that all of these instances can actually load the same data.
So they're all identical and any one of those instances can actually service the load.
So what we then do is whip and load balancer.
We have a single endpoint now that could be a public DNS name like this one, a custom DNS name, or
it could be the one that you actually get from Amazon, which is a bit of a longer DNS name.
And we'll see what that looks like in the labs.
But you have a single endpoint.
So when a client connects to DCT labs dot com, he's going to hit the load balancer and the load balancer
has a number of what it calls targets.
And these are all instances that can service the request.
So perhaps client one then gets directed to the instance at the top here, and then the second client
wants to access DCT labs dot com and it might get low balance to another instance in a completely different
availability zone.
And you can have two instances spread across as many availability zones as are available.
Now, this is within a region, so you can't load balance between regions, but you can load balance
within a region across multiple availability zones.
So then maybe the third client would get sent to another instance and it's going to try and spread the
load between the availability zones.
Now, the whole idea is that you're going to have high availability and fault tolerance.
So what happens then is health checks are used to determine whether these instances are available and
if, for instance, an instance becomes unavailable for some reason, it's going to fail its health
check and then the connections are going to get dropped and the load balancer is then going to reroute
that client to a different instance.
So that way you don't have to worry so much about your instances failing, because as long as you've
got enough instances to service the load, the load balancer will take care of making sure that your
clients are able to access your application.
So that's basically how it works.
And with auto scaling, which we'll see later in this section, you can then ensure that you've got
a certain number of these instances running.
So when this one fails, another one will get launched and replace it.
But more than that, a bit later on with Amazon elastic load balancing, there are three different types
of load balancer.
So apologies for having lots of information on the screen, but we are going to go into each of these
low balances in detail.
So you're going to learn all of this and a lot more detail and more.
This isn't everything, but these are the key differences that I just want to talk about.
So let's start at the bottom with the classic low balance.
The classic low balance has been around for a long time.
So this is considered to be old generation.
And Amazon don't recommend using it for new applications.
They only recommend that you use it for existing applications running in what's called easy to classic.
Now, we're not dealing with easy to classic now, but it's basically the predecessor to VPC.
It won't be covered in the exam anymore.
Now, the classic low balance operates at layer four and last seven.
So here we're talking about the Open Systems Interconnect or Owosso model, and the layers represent
the transport layer, layer four and the application layer at last seven.
So what that means is it deals with protocols such as TCP and SSL, which operate at Layer four and
HTP and https which operate at seven.
So it operates a both layer four and seven.
So you can have your low balance of protocol, which is the protocol which your load balancer accepts
connections using and is able to rout based on information in the protocol.
And then the instance protocol is the protocol, which you're easy to instances listen on so they can
be listening on ports using these protocols.
We then have the two newer generation load balances, the network load balancer and the application
load balancer.
Now what's happened here is these operate at different levels.
So rather than doing four and seven, we got the network load balancer, which operates at layer four,
and we have the application load balancer, which operates at least seven.
So they're specialized for different use cases with the network load balancer, it operates at the connection
level.
So that's all this TCP tearless UDP and so on.
And it rousse connections based on information within their support numbers, for instance, it's especially
designed to offer ultra high performance, low latency and to be really good for running, tearless
connections.
So tearless, offloading, meaning that it's offloading the processing of encryption from your application.
You can also have static IPS unless the clips on your load balancer.
So you can so you can define the IP address that your low balance uses, which you can't do with an
application or a classic load balancer.
It also supports UDP and static IP addresses as targets so you can have static hippie's on the back
end as well.
The application load balancer operates at the request level, so that is the application level.
So it's last seven is routing based on information within HTTP and https packets.
So what you can do with it is things called path based routing and host based routing.
There's a couple of others as well as you can see here, query string parameter based routing and source
IP address based routing.
But perhaps the most commonly used are path based routing and host based routing.
What this means is you can specify that you route to specific targets based on what the DNS domain name
in the HTTP header is.
So it could be DCT labs dot com.
It's going to send it to one set of instances.
If it's DCT applications dot com, it's going to go to a different set of instances.
So rounds based on information in the header with that's how Spanish routing with path based routing
it can be.
What's after the slash.
So you might have DCT labs dot com slash images and that will send it to certain instances.
Or it could be Check-Out and it'll send you to the checkout instances with an application load balancer.
You can also have IP addresses, lambda functions and containers as targets, so as good for use with
micro services applications.
So that's just a really quick overview of the load balancing.
And what we're going to do now is we're going to have a series of lamp's and we're going to focus on
each of these types of load balancer so that you see it in action and learn how to use them.