I just want to give you some pointers as to how you can get help and support as you go through the course
now if you have any problems with the YouTube platform itself.
So, for example, video playback problems or performance problems, please take these up with you to
me directly as instructors, we don't have any access to the platform and we're unable to submit support
tickets on behalf of our students.
So please just go to the help and support menu and submit a support ticket to you to meet directly.
If you're having trouble with a hands on labs, the best thing to do is if you can't find a resolution
to your problem by working through it, then just row yourself back to the beginning, change your environment
back to the state it was in at the beginning of the lab, and then just go back through it again, following
the instructions very carefully to make sure you don't make any errors.
There's a Q&A form that you can submit questions to as well.
The Q&A form is a great place to submit questions, but I would urge you to please search the forum
first to see if your question has already been asked and answered previously.
Also, please try finding an answer to your question by using Google search.
Often a simple search will turn up.
A great answer to your question, Awista.
Do a great job of writing some detailed articles and tutorials on their products.
So they're a great place to find information and get your questions answered.
And often that will be faster than waiting for somebody to respond on the Q&A forum.
Another great place to get assistance is on our workspace.
We have channels for each of the certification courses that we have and there's also a general channel
for general questions.
Now, why hang out there quite a lot?
And there's also lots of engagement from other students.
So that's a good place to look for assistance and to ask questions and share your knowledge with others
as well.
Between those resources, there's lots of ways to get help.
So you shouldn't find that you get stuck on any questions throughout the course.
Please make sure you use all those resources that are available to you and I'm sure you'll get on just
fine.
One last thing before I go.
At some point, Udemy is going to ask you to leave a rating and review on the course if you're not ready
at that point in time, because it can be quite early in the course sometimes.
Then you can always do it later on.
But if you're ready to leave a rating, it would be really appreciated.
It really helps us as instructors and it also helps other students when they're making decisions about
which courses to enroll in.
So I would really appreciate it if you did.
Thanks for doing that.
And I'll see you in the next lesson.