Hi, guys.
And this lesson I'm going to discuss or fence occasion methods, so what you can use to authenticate
to a W.S..
So firstly at the very top here we have what is perhaps one of the more difficult concepts to understand.
The access key, an access key is composed of an access key I.D. and a secret access key.
So there's two parts to it.
And you use this for programatic access to a W.S..
So, for example, if you're using the command line interface to launch a service on a W.S., you would
need to have an access key to be able to offensive code.
It's also used for the API.
And when accessing a W.S. by the software development kit.
Now you can add multifactorial fanfiction protection to your API calls.
We'll talk about MFA in the next lesson so you'll fully understand what it means.
Then the next stop is probably what you're most familiar with.
So this is a typical username and password.
So you'd have a user account and then use your account as a password, which is hopefully nice and strong,
like this one.
And you use a username and password to access the management console.
So this is the visual interface in which you can interact with a W.S..
You can come in here and you can view your services and you can launch services.
So you use a username and password to you to access the management console.
And again, this can be also protected with MFA.
We then have a signing certificate.
This doesn't come up much on the exam, but I'll explain to you in this lesson what it means.
So an access key is a combination of an access key I.D. and a secret access key.
And you use these for programmatic calls when using the API and you can put them in program code or
at the command prompt when you're using the command line interface or the PowerShares tools.
You can create, modify, view or rotate access keys.
And you can do that through the console as well as programmatically when created.
I am returns the access key I.D. and secret access key.
Now these secret access key is returned only at creation time.
And if it's lost, a new key has to be created.
So we'll see this later in a section where we create an access key and we get to see the secret access
key.
But only once.
If we lose it, we have to destroy the access key and create a new one.
You need to ensure the access keys and secret access keys are stored securely because whatever privileges
are associated with your account.
Anyone who has access to your access keys will be able to assume those privileges programmatically.
Now users can be given access to change their own keys, fruit and policy, but not for the console.
And you can disable a user's access key, which prevents it from being used for API calls.
So that's really important.
If somebody loses their key or they thinks it's being it's being compromised, then you can disable
it and create a new one.
Next up, we have the console password.
So this is a password that the user enters to sign in interactively using the AWB management console.
You can allow users to change their own passwords.
And you can allow selected I am users to change their passwords by disabling the option for all users
and then using a policy to grant permissions for selected users.
That's something that can come sometimes come up in the exam.
Lastly, we have a service director, also known as a signing certificate.
So this is a SSL tearless certificate that you can use to authenticate with some A.W. services.
Now, you can actually provision these using a service called a W.S. certificate manager and that can
provision, manage and deploy your service defecates.
You can also use IAM and you do that when you need to support Heggarty G.P.S. connections in a region
that's not supported by ACM.