OK, so let's look into some more details of users group's roles and policies in the identity and access
management service.
So we have an account here and within an account.
We have these various principles.
We have users groups, rules and policies.
A group is a way of organizing users.
So we create a group and then we can assign our users to the group and we can then apply permissions
to these users and we do that through a policy.
So the policy defines what the people in this group are allowed to do.
So this is a great way to organize, create a group for everybody in that group that has similar job
responsibilities and therefore need similar permissions and then apply a policy to them.
So the policies to the permissions for the identities or resources they're associated with and the user
will gain the permissions apply to the group through the policy.
There are different types of policies.
One is called an identity based policy, and these can be applied to users groups or roles.
So what is a role?
A role is a little bit of a more difficult concept, one to stand.
Roles are used for delegation, and they're assumed.
Now, if that doesn't make sense, don't worry.
In another slide, it's going to make a lot more sense when I show you graphically how it works.
Let's first go into some more detail on users.
So 9:00 a.m. We have all account route user.
Now the route user is the account that we created when we logged in sets, the email address that we
used to sign up for our U.S. accounts.
The route user has full permissions, and it's a best practice to avoid using the route user accounts,
and you should also enable multifactor authentication for the route user accounts.
Then we have our individual users.
You can create up to 5000 individual users in IAM and users will have no permissions by default.
That's really important to remember.
So you can create a user account and that user is able to log in to us, but they can't do anything
because they don't have any permissions.
So what you then have to do is give them permissions.
Now each user will have a friendly name.
In this case, the user account name is Andrea.
So this person can log in with the username Andrea.
There's also something called an Amazon resource name, and Aaron and Aaron's are assigned to resources
within IWC.
They're a bit harder to remember, as you can see that quite long they contain the account number for
the IWC account.
And as you can see, they tell you the type of resource a user account and then the actual friendly
name is on the end.
There's a few ways that all users can actually offensive to IWC.
You remember that you can access IWC through the management console, the command line interface and
also the API and authentication to the console is enabled through a username and password.
And for the Clia and the API, there is something called access keys, which will explore in more detail
a bit later on.
Next up, we have groups with groups we can create on different groups for different users.
So here we have an admin group, we have a development group and we have an operations group.
So these are job role specific groups.
We can then place our users into these groups as is appropriate.
Groups are a collection of users, and you can have a user be a member of up to 10 groups.
The main purpose of using groups is not just to organise the users, but to organize them and then apply
permissions to those users, and we do that by assigning policies to the groups.
The user will then gain the permissions apply to the group through the policy.
Next, we have I am roles and I am role as an identity that has specific permissions assigned to it.
The roles are assumed by users applications and services.
So we have some user accounts and maybe you have an application or a service running somewhere else,
and we're able to assume the role.
So each of these is able to then assume the role and then gain the permissions that's assigned to that
role.
So once assumed, the identity actually becomes the role.
So in other words, you have a user here and the user assumes the role.
At that point, the user is no longer acting as the user.
They're acting as the role and they have the permissions that are assigned to the role.
And in this case, that might mean that they can access an S3 bucket.
Lastly, we have policies we've seen in this lesson that policies are a way to assign permissions.
They're actually documents that define the permissions, and they're written in JSON.
That's JavaScript object notation.
They look something like this.
And as you can see, there's a bit of code here.
This is JSON code, and this one essentially says the effect is to allow any action on any resource.
So this is one that you might assign to an administrator who needs to be able to do everything in the
account.
We then have a bucket policy here.
A bucket policy is another type of policy that's just assigned to a resource, and it defines who is
able to act on that resource.
What they're able to do or permissions are implicitly denied by default in U.S..
Now what that means is that if you don't assign a permission to allow something, then it's just denied.
Everything will be denied unless you explicitly allow it.
The policy at the top here is an identity based policy, and it can be assigned to users groups and
roles.
The resource base policy at the bottom here can be assigned to specific resources such as an S3 bucket,
which is a container for storing data or a dynamite DB table, which is a type of database.