Hello and welcome to this lesson.
So you may have noticed that the AWB Management Council has been changing for a while now, so it's
an ongoing process.
AWB are modifying the console for quite a lot of services, not all services yet.
I presume that they'll roll out all services eventually, but they're making some ongoing changes.
And these are happening all the time.
In fact, as I'm recording courses, they're changing.
So it's a bit of a moving goalpost at the moment.
So what I'm doing is I'm recording some orientation videos to help you to get a feel for the new console.
And that's what I'm going to do here for the easy to management console.
And in the next two videos in this section, I'll also provide some videos showing you how to create
and launch instances, how to connect to instances, all using the new management console.
The remainder of the videos in this section are still using the old console.
But I'm going to help you to understand the differences.
Really, it's mostly cosmetic.
Now, you might be wondering, why don't I rerecord all videos?
Well, partly it's because it's a big job.
And so I need to schedule that time in.
But also it's because at the moment the changes are ongoing.
So I don't want to rerecord the course and then find that when I'm finished, students are asking me
why the console looks different to what they're experiencing.
So I'm going to wait until eight of us have got the vast majority of the most significant changes done.
And then I'm actually going to rerecord lots of videos throughout the course.
So as I mentioned, the key thing to note is that mostly we're talking about cosmetic changes here.
So it's really the look and feel, the features and the settings are the same.
It's just a better way of working with us.
So let's have a look.
So on my screen here, I have the new management console.
At this point in time, you can turn the new experience on or off by flicking the switch up on the top
left hand corner.
Now, on another screen here, I have the same HWC account in the same region using the old console.
So I've turned off the new easy to experience.
So let's have a look at some of the differences.
Now, one of the first things to note is that up in the top here, we have different menu.
So let's select one of these instances.
This is a Windows instance and you'll notice we've got a connect instance, state and actions, whereas
in the old console we only have the actions and the launch instance here.
So coming back over, if I go to instant state, this is where you stop, start, restart, hibernate
or terminate your instances.
And then we have a separate actions menu in the old menu, the instant state is here and actions.
So they've just broken that out into a separate menu.
So coming back here, that's instant state covered.
We've then got actions now.
A few things to note and actions.
Firstly, we have security here.
This is a new tab where you can change security groups, get the Windows password and modify the erm
roll.
Now, the key thing to note is that in the old console you would actually have to go into networking
to change security groups and instant settings to attach or replace an item roll.
So they've changed the layout a bit here.
So coming back onto the new menu, just note that security is where you go to change security groups
to modify your IAM role and also to get the Windows password for Windows XP instances.
The remainder of the settings are just as you would expect.
This is the networking.
We have the general to instant settings here.
We then have images and templates and there's some monitoring and troubleshooting tools.
The other thing to note is the connect menu has changed as well.
So when you go into the connect menu, if you're using a Windows instance, you can then either use
session manager to connect or you choose RTP clients.
If you want the Windows password, this is another place to get it.
You can download the settings for remote desktop and you can get a password here.
So this is again, slightly different to the old console.
Let's head back over there.
In this case, you just go to connect, get a password.
So the only real difference is you have to change to this IDP client menu.
So then let's have a look into the bottom part of the console.
I have one of my instances selected, and what we had in the old console was status checks, monitoring
and tags.
So you can see those here on the new menu.
They've also given us security, networking and storage.
So on the main details page, you get a lot of this information, but then you can get a bit of a drill
down on each of these tabs.
So that's slightly different.
Let's now have a look at security groups on the left hand side here.
So, again, this is just a slightly different look to the very same functionality.
Let's go into the old console.
Security groups and let's select this Web access security group now actually need to add an inbound
rule for my Windows instant's.
So let's see how you do that.
If you click on edit add rule and then you add a rule and you have to specify these particular settings.
Now those settings are the same on the new console.
Again, it's just a slightly different look.
So let's add RTP into here, for instance, choose to allow it from anywhere and then save rules.
So really no different functionality.
Just looks a bit different, looks slightly better, if anything.
That's it for this orientation video on the new management console for two.
The key takeaway is that overall it's mainly cosmetic changes.
It's really just about a different look and feel.
The settings are pretty much all the same, but you just need to work out where things are now.
It's slightly different when you work with the console.
I've also added some orientation videos for other services as well to help you work out the differences
between the old and the new console.