Before we get started with the labs there are a couple of things we need to do to get set up.
Firstly we need to install the Amazon ECS CLI.
So there are two different types of command line interface for ECS.
There's the AWS CLI and then there's the ECS-CLI and we're going to use both in this section. What
you need to do, and its operating system specific, is follow one of these.
Now I've already done it but you'll need to choose for your operating system anyway so follow one of
these commands depending on your operating system and then there's some verification stuff you can do
as well.
And the other essential thing you need to do is come down and apply the execute permissions to the binary.
So again operating system specific go ahead and do that should be very simple.
The other thing we need to do is create an ECS container instance
IAM role.
There are two different types of IAM role that we use with ECS clusters.
Firstly there's the IAm instance role and this is at the container instance level.
So this is attached to your EC2 instance just as you normally attach a role to your EC2 instance
to provide access to AWA services.
The other level is at the task level.
So here you're allowing your task specific permissions to interact with other services on the Fargate.
So there is no EC2 instance that you have control over.
So the only place you need to worry about is the task role. AWS recommend that with the IAM instance
role you limit the permissions to only those that are necessary.
And the reason being is the tasks can inherit some of the permissions from the container instance at
the task level.
You can give the IAM permissions that you need to assign to an individual task so you have some granularity
there in how you assign permissions to tasks.
We're going to go ahead and do this now and I'm just going to scroll down this web page.
The instructions are actually here so to create the I guess instance IAM role we're going to go to the
IAM console and we're going to create a role.
We're in the IAM management console now and I'm gonna head down to roles create role and then for the
AWS service type we want to choose elastic container service and then EC2 role for elastic container
service.
So we're trying to allow EC2 instances in the cluster to access ECS. We can click next
and it's already selected the policy for us so we can click Next again and go to review and you can
call this whatever you want but it's better to call it ECS instance role and try and capitalize the
same way.
The reason being this is actually picked up in some in the console sometimes when you're creating clusters
and tasks in the console
will leave the role description and click Create role.
If we now go into the role and have a look at trust relationships we can see that this provides EC2
to Amazon the AWS.com.
So an EC2 instance the ability to assume a role so we're allowing our EC2 instance to assume
a role and then the permissions that we're providing are the permissions in this role.
So have a look at this.
So we can describe tanks on EC2 and then a whole load of different ECS and elastic container registry
permissions.
Another policy that we might want to attach is S3 read only access so let's have a look at S3 read. We
just type S3, actually we should find it.. there it is, read only access and this will give all instances
the ability to pull data from history and that's all we need to do.
We're now set up and we can continue with creating some clusters in the next labs.