Hi guys.
We're gonna start this section on Amazon S3 with an overview of what the service is so Amazon S3
is the simple storage service and it's an object storage system that is accessed over the Internet through
a public endpoint.
Now S3 is an object storage system and that means you upload your files as objects and objects
are stored in buckets and a bucket is just essentially a container for objects.
Now it's a flat namespace but you can mimic what you would typically think of as folders in a file system
by creating folders within the bucket which essentially just changes the URL so it's a public service.
You can access over the public internet and if you have two instances they will also go out via an Internet
gateway to the public end point for Amazon S3.
The exception to that is if you configure S3 Gateway endpoints.
If you remember from our VPC section we talked about VPC endpoints and S3 Gateway endpoint is one of
those types of endpoint where you can create an entry in a route table to an interface which takes you
out to Amazon S3 over a private connection.
So that's the other way that you can access S3 which is useful for if you want to protect your
traffic from the public Internet or if you want instances in subnets which don't have Internet access
to be able to access S3 as you know you can do that for other services as well.
So back over two buckets there's a couple of different types of URL that you can use to access your
buckets.
So the first one here is known as a virtual hosted style you are ill in which you actually have the
bucket as part of the URL.
Now there's some slight variances in the year or else depending on the region so you should look up
this on the Amazon Web site to identify a couple of variations that you need to know in case you get
some kind of tricky question on the exam.
Now the other format is known as a path style your URL which instead it starts with S3 and then you
get the region.
You have the region in both your URLs.
Here it's at the beginning and then you have slash and your bucket name and then your objects names
will come after that in the first type of your URL.
The buckets at the beginning but then you'd still have slash in the object name at the end.
So an object is made up of a few attributes.
There's the key which is the name that you assign to the object.
The version I.D. a value which is the content that you're actually storing some metadata some resources
and access control information and we're going to go over each of these in more detail later within
this section.
So for now I just want to head over to the console and we're gonna have a quick overview of S3.
So I've recently visited it so I just selected S3 from my list there and I already have one bucket
here.
So if I head into that bucket we can see some of the objects that we've previously uploaded and we can
easily just go in and choose another file to upload.
We can also see the properties where you've got versioning and access logging.
You can create a static website out of S3 and you can configure logging and encryption and we're going
to go over all of this stuff within this section.
You can also prevent objects from being deleted.
You can configure tags, you can enable transfer acceleration for faster uploads, and then you can configure
event notifications, and you can even configure that the person who requests access to an object actually
pays for that request.
We then have permissions and in here we can see that there's an option to block public access
and then there's the access control list bucket policies that you can configure and then cross origin
resource sharing configurations.
And again we're going to go over all this within this section.
I just wanted to show you around a little bit before we get a bit deeper into S3.
So backup in the console here you can just create new buckets.
Now remember that S3 is a global namespace and this is somewhat something which people often get confused
about.
So it's a global service which means you see global up here in the top right hand corner.
You don't see a region and you can't select a region.
However when you come to create a bucket you'll notice that there is an option for a region.
And that's because your data will be stored within a region so the namespace is global.
So if I try to type a bucket name I know that that bucket is likely to.
So if I just try to call it you know bucket1 and click next.
There's no chance that I'm going to get that bucket and that's not just because someone's got it here
in Sydney.
That means that someone could have that name somewhere in the world.
So it has to be you the name has to be unique globally but the data is stored within the region that
you specify.
So I could then try and find a bucket name for instance DCT bucket 29 saying let's see if that's available
and that's okay so I can create a bucket and you can configure these various settings and we're just
gonna be free of these for now and create the bucket.
And it's as simple as that and then you can go into your bucket and upload so to upload an object you
just click on Add files and then you can choose your file and click next to go through and see some
of the options so you can specify permissions access for other accounts.
Again all of this is going to be covered in detail later on and then you get the storage classes so
you can see that there are several different storage classes available here and it's a good thing to
go and click on the learn more link and if you scroll a bit further down this page we get to see all
these different storage classes.
So in this chart you can see the durability.
So this is really the likelihood that an object is going to become corrupted or lost.
So very very high durability This is 11 nines durability here.
Then you've got the availability.
So this really corresponds to the uptime of the system in other words access to your objects and then
you can see the number of availability zones which your data is replicated across so your data is replicated
within Amazon S3 into multiple facilities within a region and in this case three facilities for the
standard storage class.
And then you can see in some cases there's a minimum storage duration a minimum billable object's size
and other attributes.
So have a look for these classes.
This seems to be more than all the time Amazon is introducing different options for different use cases
and you can see the use cases under designed for here.
So there's obviously the standard here which if you are frequently accessing data may work out well
if you want to lower costs then you might go to infinite frequently accessed which then means that you
get slightly less availability but for a slightly lower cost and then there's some more options there
are even going down to where you only have one availability zone and intelligent tiering is interesting
because this is where you don't know the use cases for your data.
So it means that it's going to move it really between different tiers and so you're going to benefit
from different tiers of storage depending on how you start accessing that data and that might change
over time.
Then further down we have glacier and deep archive and deep archive is really what glacier used to be
where you could only access the data in it within a treat with a retrieval time of about 12 hours whereas
now you can actually access it much more quickly but you pay a bit more so.
Think of glacier as the archive service and will cover in more detail later in the section.
And then the last one here which is even gone to not recommended sign on it is the reduced redundancy
storage.
And this has sort of lowered your ability as you can see than any of the others and it looks like that
sort of phasing that one out
so back in the console.
Once you've configured all these settings you can then just go down you can choose encryption you can
select you can add metadata to this object so you can say that's going to expire into certain certain
timeframe.
You can put content type in there.
You can add tags so then you can just click upload and that will upload your object
so another way that you might want to access S3 is via the command line.
And if you don't have the fly installed on your machine you can just go to search for a W.S. Klein install
and I think that should bring up the link so installing the AWS CLI so I going to
follow the procedures for Mac.
You might be on Windows or Linux so just go through and install the client.
And once you've done that we can go over to a command prompt and we can actually run the AWS CLI tools.
So if you if you just run aws it will tell you that you need to specify some some more information.
You can do aws help and it will list lots of the come up come online options that you can use
and then you can do aws S3 help and do the same.
And we can starts going through the help file and seeing the options that are available to us so we
can see available Command said the cp for copy, ls for list and so on.
So you've got all these different options and I'll just hit you to get out of there and what I want
to do now is just list the files in my bucket naturally before I do that.
I just want to remind you that if you have just set up your command line you're going to have to run
aws configure.
So this is where and we've done this earlier in the course.
You remember you ran aws configure you need to put in your access key I.D. your secret access
key and then even you can specify your region that's optional.
I'm just gonna come online out of that because I've already configured mine so we can now run AWS
s3 la and we'll see our buckets and then if I want to see inside the bucket I can do a
aws s3 ls and then I do s3:// and the bucket name and now we can see the objects
in the bucket and if we want to copy something into the bucket so I've got a file called cookbook on
my machine here and I just want to copy that up into S3 and let's put it in our new bucket
so this is a maybe a 30 MB file it's taking a few seconds to copy that one up and we can see some
status information
so the files are loaded and if we now do an aws s3 ls and I'm gonna put in the name the bucket
now we can see we've got the cookbook file and if we want to we can quite easily just remove that file
and if we want less command again now it's gone so that's it guys for the overview.
I just wanted to show you around S3 and we're going to go into lots more detail and lots of the
options you saw in the console there and more throughout the rest of this section.