So you should be quite familiar with stacks by now, but we're also going to talk about tax sets and
nested stacks in this section.
So just as a reminder, the stack is the deployed resources based on a template and you create update
and delete stacks using your templates and you can deploy them through the management console, the
Seelie or the APIs.
Now, if any errors do occur during stack creation by default, automatic rollback is enabled.
And just to understand, you do get charged for resources provisioned even if you roll back.
So understand sets, stack sets allow you to create update and delete stacks across accounts and regions.
So that means you can have multiple accounts across multiple regions and you can still using a single
template, actually update stacks across those accounts and regions.
And you can do that with a single operation.
So you use an administrator account and you define and manage your cloud formation template and then
use that as the basis for provisioning stacks into target accounts across different regions.
The administrator account is the account in which you create the stacks and stacks is managed by signing
in to the administrator account in which it was created.
The target account is then the account into which you create update or delete a stack in your stack
set.
So moving on to nested stacks.
So this is a way that you can allow the reuse of cloud formation code for common use cases.
So, for example, you might have a separate stack for your load balancer, your web server and your
application server, and then you join those by using references between the stacks and build them into
a hierarchy.
So that's it for nested stacks.
In the next lesson, we're going to look at change sets.