Hi, guys.
There's another way that you can import virtual machines into the W.S. Cloud.
Now, I didn't put this on the original slide at the beginning of the section, but this is definitely
another way.
And this can come up in exam questions.
So you need to understand this now.
It's basically importing and exporting virtual machines.
So let's say on premises you've got a virtualization stack.
So this could be a Windows or Linux for MS.
The virtualization stack could be VM where ESX.
It can be marks of type of V, it could be Sitrick, Xen, and you got your virtual machines running
on there.
Now, what you need to do is export your virtual machines.
And typically that would be in an ovie, a file and then you upload your A file to Amazon estuary's.
You might use to see Allai upload your files to Amazon as free and then you can run a CLIA command to
import the image and create of a AMISOM C.
And I am I will be sort of registered against E.S. too, but it's also backed by S3.
And then what you do is run another command to use the EMI or just go in through the console.
The point is you've now taken your on premises virtual machine, turned it into an ovie, a file imported
into a W.S..
So it becomes an am I.
And then you're able to use that EMI to launch instances in your VPC.
So that's the import piece for export.
You're kind of doing the reverse.
You might take your easy two instances and you need to move them back on premises so you can export
them from a W.S..
And the process is a little bit different, but it's the same sort of thing.
And then you export them back to on premises.
Now, most likely, if this comes up and exam is going to be the other way around because it's going
to be organizations who want to migrate into the cloud.
So that's B.M. import export.