Let's go into a hands on now.
Create a launch template and launch an auto scaling group.
I'm in the easy management console and I've selected the North Virginia region.
Now, on the left hand side here under instances, I'm going to just scroll down to launch templates
and I don't have any at the moment, so I'm just going to create a launch template.
I'm going to call it LC one.
I don't need to give it a version description.
You can choose to have it provide guidance to help you set up a template that you can use with auto
scaling and that will just filter out some options.
Now I know what to do there, so I'm just going to leave that unchecked now for Amazon machine image.
What we're going to do is select the first option in the list here for the Amazon Linux two Amy, for
instance, type.
I'm going to select to Micro and then for Keeper, I'm going to select the keypad I have for this region,
which is Cloud Labs Dash and V for VPC.
We only have one VPC, but we do have a security group called Web Access, and I want to make sure my
instances all have the web access security group applied to them.
So I'm going to select that option for storage volumes.
I'm going to leave the default.
It's just going to create an eight gigabyte EBS general purpose SSD volume.
I'm not going to tag and I'm not going to add a network interface.
It will do that automatically for us.
Then I'm going to click on advanced details.
And this is where you can see there's quite a lot of different options here.
You can request spot instances, add an instance, profile or change the shutdown behavior and so on.
The only thing I want to do is scroll all the way down to the bottom here where we have user data.
Now what I've got here is I've opened up Visual Studio code and I've opened this file, and now this
is in the course download.
So what you should do is go to the last lesson in section one.
If you don't already have this ready, you'll find a link there to download the course.
Download materials.
Once you've unzipped your file, you'll have a code directory in that auto scaling and LP and then user
data easy to assuage.
This user data is going to run as instances launch.
And what it's going to do is it's going to install a web server.
It's going to enable the web server and then it's going to actually find out through the instance metadata,
what availability zone the instance is actually running in.
Then it's going to echo and it's going to take that variable and put it into the results of what will
actually see is will have an index HDR html file in a bathtub topped up email directory.
So that means all web server is going to display this whenever we connect to the website.
And that file is going to just say this when we display it on the page, it's going to say this EC2
instance is located in availability zone and then whichever AC is actually located in when we add a
load balancer later on in this section, this will help us to see how we're cycling through these two
instances.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to copy all of this code to my clipboard, come back, paste
to enter the user data and then create launch templates.
And that's done.
So now let's go back up to the EC2 level, come down to the bottom of the page, and here we can see
launch configurations and also screening groups.
Now, like I said, launch configs are very becoming deprecated over time.
The launch template is a bit more powerful, so we don't need a launch config.
We just need to create an auto scanning group with our launch template.
So let's create an auto scaling group.
We're going to give this a name.
I'm just going to call it ASG one.
We're going to select our launch template and we can see a summary of the configuration of that launch
template.
Let's click on next and we can choose the instance purchase options.
We can either adhere to whatever's specified in the launch template, for instance, on demand versus
spot, or we can combine options here.
Now there you can see you can blend the amount of on demand versus spot instances.
Now we're just going to adhere to the launch templates under VPC.
I'm going to select subnets now.
I want to use public subnets and I'm going to select Availability Zone 1A, 1B and 1C and then click
on next.
Now we could add a load balance, but we're not doing that yet.
We're going to do that later on.
And you can enable LP health checks, but we don't have a load balancer applied at this stage, so that
doesn't make sense.
And if we wanted to, we could enable that group metrics collection as well.
So let's go ahead and do that.
There's no charge for that.
And you get the ISG metrics displayed with one minute granularity.
Let's click on next.
And now we can specify our desired minimum and maximum capacity.
I'm going to specify the desired as to the minimum as to so I don't want to go below two and the maximum
is going to be four.
And later on, we'll see how we can scale elastic and dynamically in response to performance data.
For now, it should just launched two instances.
Let's go down to scaling policies.
We're not going to do this yet.
So we're going to leave it as none.
And let's click on next.
I don't want notifications at this point or tanks, so I can just scroll down to the bottom here.
This is just a summary of what we've configured.
And let's create auto scaling group so we can see it's gone to the status of updating capacity.
And it's showing us the desired is to minimum two max full and we can see the availability zones, which
instances will be launched in see?
Now we've launched two instances here, so it should put them into different availability zones.
If we had over two instances now and we can straightaway see that we have two instances in a pending
state coming back to our auto scaling group.
If you click on the auto scanning group name, you can then go to activity as well.
And here this is a really good place of seeing what's going on so we can see that we have one instance
successfully launched and one is pre in-service, so it's on its way to being in service at the top.
Here we can click on automatic scaling.
And this is where we can enable policies.
Now we're going to talk about these in more detail and implement them a bit later on in this section.
But we have dynamic scaling policies, predictive scaling policies and also scheduled actions as well.
On this page, we can perform actions on other instances, such as setting them to stand by detaching
or setting scaling protection.
We can configure lifecycle hooks and we can configure what's called a warm pool.
These are pre initialized instances that are sort of ready to go into action when they're needed back
up to the top here under monitoring.
We enabled auto scanning group metrics collection.
So we should see information about the auto scaling group itself here.
Over time, we'll start seeing some data populates it under two.
These are the metrics from you'll see two instances, so they're not actually doing much at the moment.
So we're not going to see a huge amount of data, but we will later on the last tab at the top here
allows us to refresh all instances.
So that means that we can actually completely replace the instances that are actually in operation at
the moment.
This will reduce the capacity of the auto scanning group, but you can also set a minimum healthy percentage
as well.
So let's just come back up to instances and see how things are going.
These are both now running.
So we should also see under activity in our auto scaling group that we have two successful launches.
Now that's all we're going to do at this point in time.
But please leave your resources running.
We're going to work with some of these resources throughout this section.
So it's better to leave them running and continue where we left off.