In this lesson, I'm going to show you how to connect to your Linux instance using the secure shell
protocol and also a utility called Instance Connect.
So let's head over to the console back in the management console.
I have my Linux instance selected now.
As you can see, each instance has an instance I.D. You can see the state which is running tells you
the instance type, and it shows that it's still initializing.
In fact, if I refresh that, it should be ready.
So yes, it is ready, and it's telling me that the status checks have passed, which means it's in
a good state of health.
You can see the availability zone and you can see some information about the public and private addresses
that the C2 instance has.
Now there are a couple of ways that we can connect to an instance if we click on the Connect button
up here with the Linux instance selected.
We'll see a few options.
There's easy to instance, connect session manager SSA clients and then easy to serial console.
Now the two that I want to show you in this course are easy to instance connect and switch clients.
So let's start with easy to instance connect.
Now, the great thing about this is you don't need to do much at all.
Everything is filled out for you, including the username.
And easy to dash user is the correct username for the Amazon Linux Amoy.
So all you have to do is click on Connect what you'll then find as you get this command prompt.
Now what we're seeing here is that we're logged into the Amazon Linux two Amoy, and it's actually prompting
us to run the Sudo Yum update command.
And what that does is it updates the software on the Linux instance.
So I'm just going to run that just to show you that we're doing things on this EC2 instance where locked
into its console and we're actually able to run commands.
So that just took a few seconds, and you can see how easy this is to be able to get access to your
instance.
Now, backing the management console the other way that we can connect is the sage client.
So if I select this option, you'll see that it actually tells me the command that I need to run.
So we can see that we need to run an S-H command Daschle.
And then this is the name of our keypad file that we created when we launched our instance.
And then it pre populates the DNS name of our instance.
Now let's just go back and be clear what that means.
So our instance has a public IP.
It has a public IP v4 DNS address.
So this is a domain name, and you can see it actually includes the IP in the domain name.
Now, either of these can be used to connect, for instance, from the internet.
It also has a private domain name and a private IPv4 address.
These are for internal use only you can't connect from the internet to the private IPv4 address or DNS
address.
Now, if we go back to the Connect and Associates client, we can see that we already have all of this
filled out.
So I'm going to copy this to my clipboard and then go over to a command prompt.
Now, back on a Windows desktop here, if I go to start, just type CMD and open a command prompt.
Now, if you're on a Mac operating system, you can open a terminal on a Mac OS desktop.
If you click on Launchpad and then go to other you'll find terminal.
Now Terminal will give you the site's utility that we need back on windows.
We should also have that same utility here.
Now, if you don't, then for Windows 10 you can install it.
Just do a quick Google search for install open source h windows and you'll find how to do it.
It's very simple now that we know we have the utility to run such commands.
I just need to check that I have the file in my directory.
So on windows, I need to run, dial and make sure that I have the file in the directory I'm in.
If not, you need to change directories.
So let me clear my screen just to make this clearer for you, and I'm going to paste in the command
that I copied from IWC.
So now I can just run this commands, and what we should find is we get straight access into our Linux
instance.
So that's how we connect from Windows.
Now there is one extra step.
If you're on a Linux or Mac OS machine, so let's go back over and I'll show you that back in the terminal
on my Mac OS machine.
What I need to do is run less just to check that I'm in the correct directory.
And sure enough, I have my file here and now I need to run the command mode 600 and put it in the name
of the file, and that's going to change the permissions.
We have to do that.
Then we can paste in the command from IWC.
The exact same commands hit.
Enter, we need to type yes and hit enter again.
And now we should be connected.
And sure enough, we're connected to our Linux instance.
So that's how you do it using the S.H. clients.
As I said, the Instance Connect is a great feature, so it's certainly one we'll use when we can in
the course.
But if you want to connect for remote administration, this is how you do it.