Let's have a look now at some of the key terminology and concepts associated with Cloud Watch.
So firstly, you have what's called a namespace and the namespace is a container for your cloud, which
metrics and metrics and different namespace spaces are isolated from each other.
So they cannot be mistakenly aggregated into the same set of statistics.
So this is what namespace is looked like, and this is just a few of the name spaces that are available.
So, for instance, the format is Awassa and then the name of the service like API, Gateway or Cloud
HSM or Dinamo DB.
We then have metrics themselves.
So metrics are the fundamental concepts in cloud watch.
They represent a time ordered set of data points that get published into cloud watch.
So your services will send metrics to cloud watch and you can also send custom metrics to cloud, which
will see how to do this a bit later on.
And we'll actually do this in a hands on lab as well.
Metrics exist within a region, so they're regional and they cannot be deleted, but they automatically
expire after 15 months.
Metrics are uniquely defined by name, a namespace and then zero or more dimensions.
So you can see an example here of a few different AWASSA services sending in different metrics.
So we got CPU utilization and discrete ops and then we got four EC2 and then we've got consumed rate
capacity for Dynomite eBay.
We might have bucket sized bytes for as free and read latency for ideas.
Next up, we have dimensions.
A dimension is a name value pair.
That's part of the identity of a metric you can assign up to 10 to each metric.
And they're basically categories for the characteristics of each metric.
So let's look at that visually.
So, for instance, here we have the two namespace.
And then if you clicked on that AC2 namespace, you'd then see that you have a series of metrics and
they're organized by dimensions.
So you have by also scanning group as a dimension, per instance, metrics.
That's a dimension.
And within each of those, you then have a number of metrics.
Next up, we have statistics.
So statistics are metric data aggregations over a specific period of time and cloud, which provides
statistics based on the metric data points provided by your custom data or provided by other services,
the cloud.
So let's just have a look at what the statistics might be.
So, for example, you have minimum, which is the lowest value observed during the specified period,
maximum, the highest value in a specified period.
Then you've got the sum all values submitted, the average, which is the sum divided by the sample
count and the sample count, is the number of data points used for the calculation.
And then you have percentiles at the bottom there.
Next up, we have alarms, so we've used alarms a couple of times in this course already and we'll use
them again in this section and use an alarm to automatically initiate actions on your behalf.
So it's configured to watch over a metric and look for a specific threshold and then it will trigger
some kind of action based on that metric.
And we did this earlier in the course where we had an auto scaling group configured with an alarm,
that when the aggregate CPU usage went over 80 percent, it triggered a action to then launch a new
instance.
And action is a notification sent to an SRS topic on auto scaling group.
You can also add alarms to dashboards and alarms, invoke actions for sustained state changes only.
They don't invoke actions simply because they're in a particular state.
So in other words, the state must have changed and been maintained for a specific number of periods.
So, for instance, your metric needs to go over 80 percent CPU aggregation for a specific period of
time, not just for a very short period of time.
So remember this diagram from earlier in the course?
In this one, we have an auto scaling group with four Ekta instances.
We have Amazon cloud watch here.
Now it is two status checks are different to cloud watch.
But what we showed before was that an AC two status check might fail and then auto scanning group would
initiate a new instant replacement.
However, what we want to cover now is that we have also an alarm monitoring when the CPU utilization
is greater than 80 percent and that's aggregated across the auto scaling group in that case, cloud,
which notifies IHG to scale.
So we have an alarm wheel on cloud watch.
It's monitoring the incoming metrics from all of these different instances.
And then when it sees that the aggregate CPU is over 80, it sends a notification to the ASG to scale.
And in this case, another instance can then be installed.