This is a fairly basic overview of Route 53 hosted zones.
So let's have a look.
Firstly, we have Route 53 and we have a hosting zone and this one is called example dot com.
And in that hosted zone, that's where we can create all DNS records, things like an AA record here,
for example, dot com that resolves to an IP address and has a time to live associated with it.
So 60 seconds is how long your browser is going to cache.
The result before ends up actually going out and asking DNS again to give it a new record.
So always important to make sure you set your titles properly.
If that's too long and something changes, your clients are still trying to connect to the old address.
So we have a hosted zone, which is essentially a file that contains these DNS records, and those records
all belong to the domain in this case, example dot com.
So in this case, we have a client who's trying to resolve example dot com that computer asks the Route
53 DNS service Rule 53 responds with the address is 8.1.2 Dot one, and the client can then perform
an HTP get to a web server that's running on that address.
So this is how we have a public hosted zone working for public addresses.
Now what about the private hosted zone?
Well, in this case, it can be any domain name you want because it's not in the public space.
So you might choose something like my company dot local, whatever your company name is.
We then have our resources in our public subnets and our private subnets.
And what we do is we associate the private hosted Zone two of APEC, and then we need to make sure that
we've enabled DNS hostnames and DNS resolution.
And that means that all instances will actually receive a DNS hostname and the DNS resolution will work
now by default.
Using the standard DHCP options your computer.
Your instances will pick up a DNS address, which is the Route 53 resolver, so Route 50 free will result
in these names.
You can always change that if you want to use your own DNS service, but then you might want to have
a forwarder and the forwarder would forward any requests for US services to rule 50 free.
So let's say in this case, we have DNS resolution working using Route 53.
We've got our records created in this case for our app.
My company, Dot Local and our DP.
The app server asks Root, 53, for the address of the database.
It responds with the IP address and then the connection can be made.
So that's an example of a private hosted zone.
Now you can migrate your hosting zones to Ralph, 53 or from Route 53 to another provider so you can
migrate from another DNS provider.
And you can import records so you can export a file with your records from another provider and then
import that into Route 53.
You can also migrate a Route 50 free hosted zone to another AWB account.
You can migrate from Ralph 50 free to another registrar, so that's another DNS registrar, an external
third party service.
And you can associate a round 53 hosted zone with a VPC in another account.
And as a tip, this is something that comes up in an exam question.
The way you must implement this is you authorize an association with the VPC in the second IWC accounts.
You then create an association in the second account.
And that means that resources using Route 53 in that second IWC account are able to resolve records
in the hosted zone in the account that you've just associated.
Those are the core facts you'll need to know for Route 53 hosted zones.