In this lesson, I'm going to give you a very brief overview of what an AWB account is in the next lesson.
We're going to get started with a hands on and actually create a free to air account that we're going
to use throughout the course.
So before I do that, I want to give you a little primer on what made up U.S. counties and how we go
about setting one up.
And all of the concepts I explain in this lesson will be explained in a lot more detail later on.
So firstly, what we need to create an account is a credit card.
We also need an email address, and that has to be a unique email address.
In other words, it's not being used with another eight U.S. accounts.
So as long as you have these pieces of information, you can then create an IWC account.
And when you do so, a root user is created.
The root user is the only user in the account at this stage and has full control over the accounts.
The root user signs in with the email address that you supplied when you created the account.
We can then use a service called Eight of US Identity and Access Management, or IAM.
That service is used to create additional users groups that we can put the users into roles that we
use for services and policies, which define the permissions that we assign to the users, the groups
and the roles.
So that's something we'll do a bit later on.
We're going to create users groups, roles and policies using IAM because the user account is so privileged.
It's one that you don't want to use unless you really need.
So it's much better to create individual user accounts for the people in your organization, including
yourself, and use those for logging in.
Now, when we log ins, IWC will initially be logging in using the IWC management console, and that's
a web based console that you can access through a web browser.
The Identity and Access Management Service is the services used for authentication, so logging in.
So when we create our own individual user accounts and log in with those, we'll be using the IAM service
to log in to the console or the API or the command line interface, all of which you'll learn about
later on.
Once a principle such as an IAM user has logged in, they're then able to create resources in different
IWC regions around the world.
So, for instance, you can launch EC2 instances, audience databases as free storage buckets and elastic
load balances as well.
And those are all resources that you'll learn a lot about in this course.
So that's a very brief overview of IWC accounts.
And in the next lesson, we're going to create a free to air account that we can use for the course.