If you're migrating a database into a W.S..
Then the database migration service is the tool.
You might want to use.
So there's not gonna be hands on in this, I'm afraid, with a lot of these migration tools.
I just need to give you the feary, because setting them up means, you know, you've got to set up
a source database somewhere and a destination and it won't be that exciting, really, once you get
it set up.
But, you know, if you've got the time, then by all means you can play around and try and use these
tools.
Might be a good exercise to understand and deeper.
If you're planning to use them.
But for the purposes of the exam, you really just need to know the high level.
So what you can have is you might have your on premises data center or you might have some workloads
that are in easy to or even an RDX already.
So they might already be on the A.W. as cloud, but you want to move them to a different destination.
So that could be you're moving them from east to into RDX or you're moving them from RDX.
Parkin's easy to that's possible as well.
So lots of different source and destination options you can see here.
Destinations include a Rora Redshift dynamo, DP and document DP as well.
And DMX will actually manage the entire migration process for you now at your source database can stay
on line and see your application can stay on line throughout the entire process, which will minimize
the disruption.
So there's a lot there's not much downside.
You just got to work out how to cut over at the final time.
But during the migration, while your data is migrating, there's no actual downtime.
So that's a really good thing.
Now, you can also not just do homogeneous.
So, for instance, my ask you all to a minus QOL compatible database, but you can also do heterogeneous
migrations so you can take, for instance, an Oracle database and put it into redshift.
And there's quite a few different options.
And to do that, you use something called the schema conversion tool.
So the key thing to remember, you've got the database migration service.
And if it's a homogeneous migration, you don't need to use the schema conversion tool.
But you do if you're moving between different types of schema.
And so just remember also that the source can be in the A.W. as cloud as well as on premises and the
different destination options.
And that should have you covered for the exam.