Hi guys.
In this lab we're just going to go and use the console to create a couple of streams.
So we're going to create a data stream and a Firehose delivery stream so going to click data stream
and I'm just gonna call this my data stream and then we get to choose the number of shards and you can
even use this option to put in your record sizes and the number of consumer applications you're going
to use.
And then you can provision your shards.
So it says here you can provision up to 200 more shards before heading your account limit of two hundred.
So let's just put in two.
I don't need two hundred and that's it.
That's the only option that you need to put in and then you just click Create a stream
so that's being created.
What I'm going to do is just go back to the dashboard and we're going to have a look at what the options
are with Firehose.
So I'm going to call this one my delivery stream and then you get to choose your source.
So it's even a direct put.
And it says choose this option to send records directly to the delivery stream or to send records from
eight of us IO T cloud which logs or CloudWatch events.
And the other option is to use a can ease stream.
So now I could choose my data stream and then I can click next.
We now have this option to transform records with AWS Lambda.
So if I enabled this I could go in and I could choose a Lambda function and then whatever I can do with
my code in Lambda i can use to transform these records in some way.
Let's just leave that disabled.
You can also then enable this option to convert the record format and you can choose to use the glue
service
and you can choose between the output formats Apache Park or Apache org.
So we'll just disable those options and we'll just click on Next.
And now you get the option to deliver to a destination and the wizard changes depending obviously on
what you're going to use as a destination if I choose an entry destination I get to put in my bucket
name but choose redshift it's going to ask me for a cluster and then the same with elastic search to
specify the parameters there and then you can also use Splunk as a destination and it has the details
here to lead your Splunk configuration.
And as we'll see you then have this option to back up.
So I'm just gonna go back up here choose Amazon S3 and choose one of my buckets.
I think I'll leave it there.
DCT company you could then choose a prefix and even an error prefix and then you click next.
So now we have the option to set the buffer conditions.
It says that Firehose buffers incoming records built before delivering them to you as free bucket.
So you choose your buffer size and your buffer interval and you can then enable encryption so you can
choose how you.
Excuse me compression and encryption so you could choose how to compress your data and you could choose
to enable encryption and choose the CMK then have logging which will go to CloudWatch Logs
and you can enable tanks and then I am wrong.
Let's just click next and we have to choose the Role
and yeah we don't actually have a role for this now so let's just see what it's configuring and it's
enabling glue.
Get table versions.
That's just leaves the default options here and click allow
and we've now chosen all wrong and as click next and we can review and then create the delivery stream
so that's just to show you a brief overview of the console and what's here.
We don't really need these.
We're just going to delete.
We go in to data streams as well and just select my stream and delete.
And what we're going to do in the next lab is create a Kinesis stream and have Lambda consume events
from the Kinesis stream using an event source mapping and then log events to CloudWatch Logs.