And this lesson, we're going to look at what we need to do to to find the side of blocks, we're going
to use a few of the rules and guidelines and best practices.
So first, with the rules and guidelines and these come from IWC, these side a block size can be between
a slash 16 and slash 28 subnet mask.
It cannot overlap with any existing side, a block that's associated with the VPC.
And you cannot increase or decrease the size of an existing site a block, so you must get it right.
From the beginning, the first four and last IP address are not available for use.
So you've got to account for that when you set the size of your subnet because you want to make sure
you have enough addresses for your instances that you deploy.
IWC recommend that you use sider blocks from the RC 1918 Rangers, remember these are the private IP
ranges and that's these addresses.
And of course, these give you plenty of scope, so that shouldn't be a problem.
Now let's have a look at an example.
So let's say I have a BPC side, a block that looks like this.
It's 10 zero zero zero with a 16 bit subnet mask.
So that means it looks like this 10 000 slash 16.
So that's the overall block of addresses.
But now we want to create a subnets.
So what we need to do there is we're going to take some of the bits from the host portion here and assign
them to the network portion.
So maybe we're going to have 10 zero one zero slash 24, and that means we borrowed all eight bits from
that third octet for the network side.
So your VPC subnets will have a longer subnet mask than the slider block that they come from.
Now, in this case, it's a 24 bit subnet mask.
Now what's the next network?
The next network is 10 zero two zero slash 24, and then the next one is 10 zero three zero slash 24.
So each of these subnets is going to have up to 254 potential hosts.
But of course, you have to take away a few from that number, so take away five from that number.
And that's how many addresses you have remaining for your active instances.
So as long as you're happy with that number of instances per network, which is quite a big number still,
then this is a good and very simple range to use.
Now let's go through a few additional considerations.
You got to ensure you have enough networks and hosts.
You really don't want to mess this up.
You only get to set this side a block once and then you're stuck with it, so make sure you plan correctly.
Bigger slider blocks are typically better.
It gives you more flexibility down the road.
Smaller subsets are OK for most use cases.
You don't need thousands of instances per subnet.
Consider deploying application tiers per subnet.
So if you have a free tier application, you might have different subnets for each tier and you might
have it as highly available across multiple availability zones as well with a subnet in each A-Z.
So that's a good way of getting that high availability and resilience into your workload.
Now VPC pairing, which we're going to cover a bit later, is where you connect your VoIP sees so that
you can route directly between them using private IP addresses so you don't go out to the public internet.
Now it's really essential that you don't have overlapping side blocks.
So in other words, you can't have the same side a block in to VPC and connect them with VPC pairing.
So even if you're not doing pairing now, just remember this because you might need to do it in the
future.
You want to make sure your site blocks don't overlap, and this is across all the and all regions and
all accounts.
So make sure you get it correct.
So in general, just avoid overlapping sites blocks as much as possible.
Make sure you consider this when you're designing your IP address ranges.
So let's go back to an example.
Let's say we have 10 zero zero zero slash 16, so that's outside a block and we create a series of subnets.
Now each of these subnet has a 24 bit subnet mask, and as you can see, we're separating them into
public and private subnet in different availability zones.
The private subnet to have a private round table and the public ones have a different round table.
Of course, the main round table for the public, Subnet said, will have an internet gateway, and
those subnets will also assign public IP addresses to the instances that are launched in them.
So that's a bit of fairy behind it and some practical examples here.
I also want to show you a very useful tool that helps you to plan out your side of blocks and your subnets.
I'll attach a link to this tool to the lesson.
Now what we can do with this tool is specify our side of block and see the subnets and we can actually
the tool will help us to work out which subnets to use based on the number of networks we need.
Subnets or the number of hosts per network.
So let's stick with the example and put in 10 zero zero zero and then subnet mask.
We're going to scroll down to slash 16.
Now I want to have subnets with at least 250 full hosts.
So that would be a standard Class C network.
Now let's have a look what we get.
So let's click on Create.
And it gives us all the subnets with a 24 bit subnet mask that fit within the side block.
So we've got the zero subnet here.
And then all the way down, we get to the very last subnet, which is two five five.
So that's two hundred and fifty five subnet so that we can have and each of those subnet can support
up to 254 hosts.
Of course, the VPC will actually reserve a few addresses so you won't get that many, but you'll still
get close to 250.
So that's a really nice tool to use to help you to work out what your subnets are going to be within
your a block, and that will also help you to determine the best site of block as well.