So we can have a look at EBS volume types now.
So EBS can be found within the EC2 dashboard and you can attach EBS volumes to an instance when
you launch it or you can create them independently here and you can also do this via the command
line.
So we can go in and click Create volume and the first thing that we're asked to do is to choose the
volume type and we can see that there's a few different options here.
And if you hover over the little information icon it tells you a little bit about the different
volume types.
So general purpose SSD is the default volume type that will be selected when you launch an instance
for your route volume.
And as it says it can burst up to 3000 IOPS per volume and delivers a baseline of three IOPS per gigabyte.
So if you have a look here we've got a 100 gig volumes with 3 IOPS per gigabyte so 300 IOPS
.
And if we change that 200 then it would just adjust it automatically and then it can burst to three thousand
if it needs to.
The next one down then is provisioned IOPS and provisioned IOPS can go up to 20000
IOPS per volume and actually delivers 50 IOPS per gigabyte.
So if we choose provisioned IOPS you get another little information icon here where it gives you a bit
more information where it says you can provision up to 50 IOPS per gigabyte so we have our volume size here
of 100 gigabytes.
We can therefore choose up to 5000 IOPS and if we try to go over and go to let's say 5001 then
it tells us that the ratio is 50 to 1.
So 50 IOPS a gigabyte.
So we have to drop it back to 5000.
So that's the maximum.
And then we can go up to 16384 about sixteen tibibytes and
then we would be able to increase this to up to 64,000 IOPS not 64001
.
But up to 64,000 again with that same ratio.
Now don't try and create this because this would cost you a fortune but that's just to give you an example.
So let's be safe and just drop this way back.
So the other type of volumes that you can choose here are the hard disk drive type.
So General Purpose and provisioned IOPS are solid state drives.
And then you've got the hard disk drive type.
So you've got throughput optimized and magnetic it used to be the default for root volumes
but now it's been changed and I think it's just been deprecated away whereas these two might stick around
a bit longer.
Now one of the things you'll notice here.
Well firstly it's just over availability zones so your EBS volume sits within one availability zone
and I'll show you how you can move UBS volumes between availability zones but you have to create it
within a specific availability zone.
The next thing I wanted to show you is the throughput megabytes a second you'll notice that there's no SLA
here.
It doesn't specify anything.
And that's the same for any of these SSD types.
But when we come down to the hard disk drive type volumes then we get a SLA here and the throughput
optimised is is the best out of those two
so those are your volume types and then you can select a snapshot.
And this will just show you a list of publicly available snapshots or these are just snapshots that
other people have created.
And if you chose one of those then it would basically just create your volume from that snapshot which
would mean that whatever was installed on that snapshot will be available to you you can then choose
to encrypt the volume and we're going to cover all of this in detail throughout this section.
But this is just to show you how you can create a volume and a few of these variables.
The other thing I want to show you is this web page because this also gives you some more information
that you need to know.
So you do need to know this stuff for the exam.
So here's our hard disk types and our solid state drives.
The general purpose SSD and the provisioned IOPS so we can see that the use case for the general purpose
SSD is most workloads so they said this is a good balance of price to performance, recommended
for most workloads it's good for system boot volumes good for virtual desktops and low latency interactive
apps and dev test environments.
On the other hand your provisioned IOPS is about mission critical low latency so this is really high
performance.
So it's more about business critical applications large database workloads that kind of thing then you
have throughput optimized hard disk drives you are looking here at lower cost and the lowest cost is the
cold but that's very low performance so you really only use it for some very specific scenarios where
all you care about is cost something is not very important to you
with the HDD one rather than the SDD one.
So this is more about throughput so low cost but pretty good throughput.
So there might be some use cases that you want to use this for.
And again you you might want to just have a look at what's the cost differences you can come down and
see that it gives you 500 megabytes a second there vs. a thousand for general purpose and provisioned IOPS.
So there's quite a bit more performance in the provisioned IOPS SSD drive in terms of throughput
but then again the cost of this is going to be so much lower and you could even potentially bundle a
bunch of these disks together in a raid volume to aggregate the throughput.
And we'll talk about that later in this section.
So just familiarize yourself with this table and understand the different use cases and also the limitations
so you can't use even these as a boot volume.
Now you remember back here we did have an option magnetic standard which could be a big volume so you
can still use that but it's not even on this table anymore.
So really it's just being deprecated away.
Another thing to note maximum volume size is the same across all of these 16 tibibytes whereas the
max IOPS is significantly different so much higher on these SSD than it is on these HDD.
Another thing that you might know is the minimum size is so a gigabyte or gigabyte for here 500 here
and 500 here.
So just understand those because those can come up in exam questions.
So that's it for this lab.
We're not going to create this volume and we're going to go into a bit more detail about some of these
other parameters in the next labs.