We're going to talk a bit more now about hosted zones.
So let's go to the console and I mean the round 53 dashboard and I have one hosted zone.
Now if you watch the lamps from Section two you'll see me create this and you might have even created
one of your own.
So I actually went and registered a domain name on the video.
So I have this one public domain name.
This one hosted its own excuse me and within there the only records I have at this stage are the start
of authority record and the name server records.
And then we can then go and import records or create records sets.
So simply it is a hosted its own is a collection of records.
Now if we go back to hosting zines we can actually create hosts of songs from here.
And what I'm going to do in this lab is I want to show you what a private hosted zone is.
So this is used with VPC and what I'm going to do is I'm just going to call this DCT private dot com
and what I need to do now is choose my region and your VPC will need to be enabled for DNS host names.
So it tells us here you have to have enabled DNS host names and enabled DNS support configured on your
BPC.
So I already have that which is why those two pieces are showing.
So let's click on Create
and so I now have these records.
So what I want to do now is go to easy too and I'm actually going to launch a couple of instances and
then create some records for them in that private zone.
So I'm just going to choose to launch two instances and I'm going to put them into
my custom BPC and they're going to go into a public subnet and that's really all I need to do.
I just want to click free to the security groups choose my web access so I can access H into one of
these instances and then launch.
And while these instances are launching I just want to copy that public IP addresses and I'm just pasting
them somewhere.
And what we'll do then is create a couple of records
right.
So let's go back over to round 50 free
and I'm going to go into my private Hastings zone and create a record set and the first one I'm going
to call app and I'm going to paste one of my IP addresses in there.
So it's just Apple DCT private dot com and I'll click on Create the second one I'm going to call D.B..
So let's consider that these are DB servers and our app service
and I'm going to click on Create.
So what I want to do now is just secure a shell into one of those instances and we're just going to
see if we can resolve these domain names
so I'm at a command prompt now and I'm going to SSL each into one of these instances
and then what I'm gonna do is I'm going to I don't know which one this is but let's just ping DCC DB
the DCT private dot com and we'll get a response.
Of course we're allowing ICMP within the security group.
So that's why this works.
And then let's just change that to app and we get a response again.
So very very simple.
We could also run Digg and we could do app or DCT private dot com and we'll see that we have in the
answer section here the IP address and we could do the same for D.B.
and we get the IP address of the DB server.
So very simple guys just wanted to show you hosted zines.
I want to go.
We will kill these off because we're going to launch some other instances with a different configuration
seen for the rest of them for the exercises in the rest of the lab.
And I'm also going to go back to around 50 free.
Now you do pay a small charge.
It's not much.
It's like 50 cents a month or something for a private for us for our hosted zone in general.
So you might as well get rid of your private hosting zone if you don't need it anymore.
And I think it's going to warm up before I get there I'll just go and delete the records say it will
tell you that you have to delete your records and that is your records other than the NSA and SLA.
So you have to delete your records.
You can go back at that point and delete your hosting zone
so that's it for this lab in the next lab we can talk about DNS records.