I am instance profiles are something that you definitely need to know for the exam.
They come up in a few questions here and there.
So we've used Encinas profiles quite a lot in this course with our AC two instances to give them the
permissions they need for certain scenarios.
Now, an instance profile is a container for an I am role that you can use to pass roll information
to an easy to instance.
When the incident starts, an instance profile can contain only one I am role and are although a role
can be included in multiple instance profiles.
Now this is what it looks like.
So you have your easy to instance and there's an instance profile within that instance.
And that's what has the I am role attached to it.
So when your application needs permissions, for instance, to talk to S free, it speaks to the instance
profile, gets the keys that it needs to then access asri.
Now you can use some CLIA commands to work with innocense profile.
So we're going to do that in this lesson.
So we've got the crate instance profile command at a role to an instance profile.
We can list our instance profiles and so on.
So let's head over to the console.
And first off, I just want to show you where instant profiles are in the EU management console.
So I'm on the AWB management console.
I said, oh, it's easy to.
I'm going to launch an instance where I'm gonna start the launch.
Wizzit click, select, click next.
And then here we have I am wrong.
So if I click the arrow, then I can see that I have several roles here.
So these are instant profiles.
And what happens is each of these has a role attached to it.
And so this is an instance profile.
It has a role attached to it.
And then you attach the instance profile to the instance.
So let's go to the command line and we're going to create a new instance profile from the command line.
So before we head to the command line, I just want to show you a file, which I've got.
And this is the commands that we're going to run.
So we can run each of these commands, create instance profile, add roll to instance profile and then
to delete it.
You have to remove the role from the instance profile and then delete the instance profile.
So let's head up into the command line.
And actually the first thing I can do is run a W.S., I am list instance profiles.
And so we should now see a whole list of profiles and you'll see the name of these actually matches,
the instance profiles that you saw in the console.
So we've got each of these instance profiles.
We've got the ones you're very familiar with, the S3 full access, the S3, READ-ONLY and so on.
So those are the profiles that exist at the moment.
So let's take our first command and it's going to create a profile called my test instance profile.
So let's head over and paste it in and hit enter.
And that was very quick.
So now let's go back to the console.
And if we just reopen so refresh the wizard, we should now see that we have my test instance profile.
So that's great.
But it doesn't actually have a role.
So you can see if you try and use it, it says that it doesn't actually have an associated I am wrong.
So back in our commands, I'm going to copy this next command, which is going to add an I am role and
it's gonna be the S3 read only access role.
So I paste that in and that's been created.
And now if we head over and I'll just refresh by starting the wizard again and this time I should be
at a select the my test instance profile and I don't get an error.
So we actually now have an instance profile with a role attached to it.
So that's great.
But now that I finished with it, I want to delete it.
So what you can do then is you have to come in and remove the role from the instance profile.
So you run this command and that's complete and then you can come back and delete the instance profile
with this command.
So that should now be deleted.
And if we go back in and have a look again.
And now our instance profile is gone.
So that's just to help you understand incidence profiles a bit better because they can come up in the
old exam question.