Hi and welcome to this lesson.
So in this lesson, what we're going to do is we're going to do some hands on, we're going to launch
an easy instance in a public subnet.
So let's just have a look at how this works.
So remember, Ishita is a regional service, so we're going to deploy within a region.
We need to choose the region where we want to deploy are easy to instance.
We're in a region.
We have a VPC, which, as you know, is a logical boundary in which we can create our own resources,
we can create our subnets within a VPC and then launch our resources within those subnets.
So that's the next thing.
Now, in this case, just depicted here, you can see one availability zone with two subnets.
Of course, there are multiple availability zones in every region, but this is just to make things
simple.
So within our availability zone, we have a public subnet and we have a private subnet.
So remember, the key difference being that with a public subnet, instances receive public IP addresses.
So we're going to launch an easy to instant's into a public subnet because it's a public subnet.
That instance will pick up a public IP addresses, so they're automatically assigned to instances that
are launched in the public subnet.
Now, the other thing, remember the key ingredients for a public subnet.
You need to have a public IP.
You also need an entry in the round table for the public subnet that points to an Internet gateway.
So let's see, how do we connect from the outside world?
That's what we want to do.
We're going to launch an easy two instance.
And then from our own PC's, we're going to connect into our AC2 instance.
So the way we would do this is the Internet client that's our computers is going to connect to the public
IP of the instance, and it does so via an Internet gateway.
So we need to have an Internet gateway and those devices are attached to the VPC.
So you have one Internet gateway attached to each VPC that you want to enable Internet access for.
And then via the Internet gateway, we can connect to our ACSU instance.
So that's what we're going to do now.
We're going to launch an easy to instant's running the Linux operating system.
That's going to be the same for everybody.
Now, depending on what client you have, the instructions are slightly different.
I'm going to show you both ways.
So there's two ways.
One is for Mac and Linux users.
That's what we're going to do first.
And then the second way is for Windows users.
If you've got a Windows computer, it's a slightly different way of connecting into your instance.
But once you're connected, everything's the same.
So let's head over to the console now and will launch an initiative instance.
I'm on the AWB management console and on the services.
We can click the dropdown and then choose easy to underneath compute.
Now note that I have a region specified.
I've got the region specified as Sydney because that's the closest region to where I am.
You can choose whichever region you want for this exercise.
Typically you just choose one that's closest to where you are physically.
So I have my region selected.
Now let's just have a quick look over the console here.
Now, the first thing to note is you'll notice up here we have new easy to experience.
If you flick this off this little switch here, it takes you back to the old console.
We're actually in the process at the moment.
We are in the process at the moment of changing from the old console to the new one.
And really, this is a layout difference.
There's nine different features or functionality.
It's really just how everything is presented to you.
So, for example, if we go under instances here, this is where you will see your instances and this
is going to look a bit different in the new console.
So the actions menu here has several different functionality underneath it.
And when we go to new experience, you'll see the layout is slightly different.
So let's go back to the new experience.
We are going to use the new experience.
Now, one other thing to note, this is still changing as I record this course.
It's changing daily almost at the moment.
So it's been going on for quite a while.
So it's hard to actually keep up with the changes.
But when you look at the interface, there might be some differences.
If there are, just be patient and look through and try and find what you're looking for.
The layout might be slightly different, but overall, the functionality in the features and the settings
should be the same.
So you can see that the layout has changed a bit.
Now, I'd like to draw your attention to a few things over on the left there.
So we've got instances that's where we are now.
You can go to instant's types and this shows you the various different types of instances.
Talk about more about that in a moment.
We then got something called launch templates, spot request savings plans.
There's lots of stuff here.
We're going to talk about this throughout the course.
I'm not going to go into detail now.
We got Amazon machine images.
These are images of the Ebb's volumes, the volumes that are actually attached to the easy to instant.
So.
I worry about that we're going to actually gets Ebb's volumes a bit later on, of course, and you'll
understand in more detail, but essentially think of this as the operating system so you can actually
have a package that includes the operating system and you use that when you want to deploy an instant
so you can pre configure them and you can also find some that are public.
So here we can look at public images and people have already created these.
And for instance, they might have some software installed on them.
We then got Ibbs, as I mentioned, this is the volumes, the disks.
Think of them as virtual hard drives that are attached to the E2 instance.
And we'll talk about more about that in another section.
We have networking and security here.
Now, security groups are really important.
These are essentially firewalls that are attached to our computer, to our easy to instant's.
So they're an instant level firewall.
Really important to understand these and you'll actually see them in use very soon.
We then have elastic IP addresses.
So these are static public IP addresses, placement groups beyond the scope of what we need to talk
about now and then.
We've got key players here now.
Keepers are a public and private key pass.
So it's using what's called public key cryptography.
Now, we do need to actually use these to connect to our instance.
When you create a keeper, it creates a public key and a privately the public is on Adewusi.
The private key is something you download to your machine and then you use that when you want to connect
to your instance.
Now, you can see here that there are two different types.
If you're using windows, then you can choose PPK and it will create one that you can use with Putti
if you're using Linux or Mac or your computer has an open access client.
So you're going to use a secure shell program to connect in.
Don't worry if you don't understand this yet, we're going to do this soon.
So you'll understand it then.
But then you can use a PM now, a profile can be converted to a PPK file.
So don't worry if you choose this option and then realize you want to connect from Windows and we'll
see this in the hands on very shortly.
We then have low balancing down here and also scanning big subjects that we're going to come a bit more
later on in the course.
So let's go back up to the top now.
Let's go to instances and we're going to launch an instance.
When you launch an instance, the first thing that you need to do is choose the Amies.
Remember, I mentioned this is a pre configured package, including your operating system.
So you can see here we have several options.
Now, three tier eligible just means that it is a part of the free tier.
So if you have a free tier accounts, then you can run these instances without paying up to a certain
limit.
So, for example, we can run one of these constantly for throughout the month in the freezer.
If you run several of them at a time, then you might end up paying.
We're going to choose Amazon, Linux to Amite.
But I just want to show you, you can have your own Amies.
We don't have any.
Now, there's also a marketplace.
So in the marketplace, you can find Amyas to have software preinstalled, stuff like Trend Micro here
at Juniper Networks.
So these are going to be networking and security devices, open VPN and so on.
So you can actually go into the marketplace and you'll pay a little bit more for these because they
actually have the software licensed within them.
So let's go back to QuickStart.
We're going to choose Amazon, Linux to Amoy, click on Select.
We now need to choose the instance type.
Now again, we want to make sure we're in the free tier.
So we will use this to micro.
It only has one CPU and one giga ram.
So it's a very basic system, but it's good enough for what we want to do now.
Know that there are lots and lots of different types of instances.
You don't need to understand all the differences for this particular exam, but it's worth having a
look at these just to understand, you know, what you can do.
You can see here we have some instances that have very large amounts of CPU and also RAM.
And as we go down in fat, it gets much, much bigger than that.
So you'll find that there's some absolutely huge instances, 498 giga ram here.
So they are also optimized for different use cases.
So if I just scroll back up here, the ones we've seen in front are what are called compute optimized.
So the ratio between the number of CPUs and RAM is a bit higher and then you might have storage optimized
where it's optimized more for storage throughput.
So that's a bit beyond the scope of what we need to do now.
But I just wanted to show you, we're going to choose to micro click on next.
Now in here, you can choose the number of instances.
We're going to keep it as one.
You can choose to use spot instances, if you like.
That's another method of using unused capacity on AWB at a much cheaper right.
We're going to choose our network.
In this case, the default VPC is selected.
The subnet says no preference.
It's just going to use one of the.
Subnets in an availability zone, and it's also going to enable public IP.
So this means we're going to deploy our instant's into a public subnet with a public IP.
We don't need to change anything there.
Now, most of these other options are things that we're going to cover a bit later on in the course.
So I'm just going to click straight through here and go to add storage under add storage, you can see
a single volume is selected.
This is what's called the root volume.
Now it's eight gigabytes in size, which is fine for what we need to do.
Now there are several different types of volume and these have different performance characteristics
and different costs.
We'll talk about that in the storage section of the course.
For now, we can leave it as the default volume type, which is general-purpose SSD.
And note that by default, when you delete your instance, the volume will be deleted.
If you deselect that, it means that the volume will be stored so you can delete the instance, you
can terminate your instance and the volume will always be there.
So you can actually use that then to restart the instance at a later time.
You can also enable encryption, if you like.
We're not going to do that for now.
And if you wanted to, you could add an additional volume that's just delete that one.
We don't need any more volumes for now.
Now, under Tagg's, this is where you can enter some metadata associated with this particular instance.
So, for example, we can write in here department and then we could say that this is perhaps I.T. and
that just adds some metadata that you can then use for various purposes.
We'll talk about that again later in the course.
Next up, security groups.
So here what we need to do is create or attach a security group to our instance.
I'm going to create a new security group because we don't have one yet.
And I'm going to call this Web access.
I'm going to copy that and paste it in the description.
We then need to define the rules for the network traffic that we need to allow to reach our instance
by default here because it's Linux, it's come up with S.H. and that means the SNH protocol is going
to be allowed, which uses what's called Port 22 on the TTP protocol.
And the source can be any source.
This IP address means any source.
Zero zero zero zero zero means it can come from anywhere if you want it to be more secure.
You could change this to my IP and it will identify your IP address and now only you can connect to
this instance for our purposes.
We'll leave it on anywhere which puts it back.
So this zero zero zero zero last year.
And note that what it's done now is it's also added this other address at the end.
Now, that's actually the same as this first part, but using a different protocol, IP Version six
rather than IP Version four.
That's all good.
So let's click on review and launch.
And here you can see a summary of what you've configured.
If you click on launch, it now needs a key piece.
Remember I mentioned these are public and private keeper.
Adewusi stores the public key and you download the private key and you need that to connect to your
instance.
Now, we don't have any, so let's try to keep it.
I'm going to call it Sedney Dash Kipen and I need to click on Download Keepa, so now I've got to copy
that which will need shortly.
So last thing to do is just launch our instance and that's it.
Now if we click on view instances we can see our instances launching here.
Let's just click on View Instances and that takes us to this screen.
And if we select this button on the left, it will now get all this information.
We can see that our instant state is pending.
We can see the instance type.
We can see the status checks here.
There's no information yet.
And then we get lots of details so we can see lots of information about our running instance.
And then there are several times.
So you got security information, networking, storage, the status checks, which in this case appear
to be running now.
So things are looking good.
We've got monitoring here where you can see some operational information about your instance and then
you can see the tags that are assigned to the instance.
So that's it for this lesson.
What we need to do next is actually connect to our instance and we're going to do that in the next lesson.