I just wanted to take a few moments to talk about ways to keep in touch.
I really appreciate having you as my student.
It's one of my great passions to be able to teach and to do so for so many students around the world.
It's a great privilege and I would really appreciate it would mean a lot to me if you connected.
There are several ways we can keep in touch.
But before I share those, I would just like to tell you a little bit about myself so you get to know
a bit about who I am.
I originally come from the U.K., but I'm now very lucky to call Australia my home.
I've worked in I.T. for well over 20 years working as a consultant in the systems integration space
for a large part of that career.
I've also got lots of certifications from many different vendors, including IAC, Compter, Cisco,
VMware, Microsoft and of course, Awadi.
I've always enjoyed learning, which is why it's such a great privilege to be able to do this full time
now and learn and teach others as well.
I.T. certification has changed my life in many ways.
It's helped me to develop a great career and it's also helped me to travel the world and end up where
I am today.
So it'd be great to connect.
And there are several ways you can do that.
I'm on LinkedIn, so please connect with me on LinkedIn and share your course completion certificate
or share your Awista vacation.
I love to share in my student success, so please tag me and I would be sure to congratulate you on
your achievement.
You can also find me on Facebook.
We have a group called Awista Vacation Kuai.
It's got many thousands of members and there's tons of engagement on there.
So it's a great place to hang out and ask questions and share knowledge with other students.
I also have a YouTube channel for digital cloud training, so there's lots of free videos on there and
I'm adding new ones all the time.
So great place to get some free content.
Last but not least, there's the slack workspace.
That's a really good place to find me.
I like to hang out in slack, so please feel free to pop in and ask questions.
So I really hope you'll get in touch.
I look forward to hearing about your success and I hope you enjoy the course.