We're now going to talk about network AC ls so network access control lists known as network AC Ailes
or Nichols for short are different to security groups in several ways.
Now we've used security groups extensively up to this point in the course but we haven't modified the
network AC yells at all but we've been relying on the fact that the default network ACL allows our traffic
between subnets.
So let's explore that in a bit more detail.
A network ACL functions as a firewall at the subnet level.
It's actually hosted on the BPC router so you remember that we have a VPC router which is responsible
for routing traffic between our subnets so any traffic that leaves one subnet goes through the VPC router
before it goes into another subnet.
So the network ACL is hosted on the BPC router and logically is associated with the subnet networK AC
yells filter based on ingress traffic.
So traffic coming into the subnet and egress traffic traffic going out of the subnet so inbound and
outbound essentially
and network ICL is associated with a subnet not with an instance.
So that's one of the key differences between a security group and a network ICL.
Another is that your network ACL has allow or deny rules so you can specify allow or deny rules.
Whereas with you remember with a security group you only have permit rules or allow rules so you specify
the traffic that you want to allow and that traffic is then accepted.
And if you don't have a rule allowing that traffic it just gets dropped by default which is what we
call an implicit deny so of a network ACL instead you have a list of rules and the rules are processed
in order from the first to the last and you'll see when we go to the console that they're actually no
I don't show it in tables here but they each have a number.
So you might have one hundred and then one hundred and one or two hundred two hundred and one and so
on.
And I'll tell you a bit more about how eight of us recommend you.
No.
Your rules shortly so they're processed in order.
And what happens is as soon as a allow or deny is reached.
That's basically the end of the processing the traffic is either accepted or it's dropped.
And we'll see how this works.
So just to compare two security groups again if you remember if we have a security group a it really
doesn't matter.
These these are VPC levels so it doesn't matter where you instances reside if you have a permit rule
in that security group that says that the instances can talk to each other then they can communicate
directly whether they're in the same subnet or in different subnets now as they do that they're actually
reliant on the fact that the network ACL is set up correctly because otherwise the traffic which goes
between subnets must exit via you through the network ACL that's hosted on the to and then into and
be processed by another network ACL as it comes into the other subnet so you do need a rule to allow
that traffic of course with security groups if instances communicate directly with one another within
the subnet then nothing ever goes to the network ACL so it really doesn't matter what you have configured
here these these two instances will be either talk to each other
now before we head out to the console let's just have a look at the default network ACL so just as with
security groups your VPC will come with a default knuckle and you can then create custom knuckles and
the key difference is this.
So with a default on that there is an allow rule for any protocol from any source and if you have IP
six enabled you will have two rules one for IP before one for IP B6 and this is inbound and outbound
however custom natural if you just create it and save it.
This is what you're going to get.
You just get a deny.
So as soon as you associate this with a subnet no traffic will be able to go into that subnet or out
of that subnet so that's very important to note.
Now each subnet can be associated with one network ICAO only.
However you can have multiple subnets associated with a single network ICAO.
Now let's just before we go to the console we're going to look at one more slide.
So I just want to make it very clear to you the differences between security groups in network AC ls
so security groups they operate at the instance level and that specifically at the network interface
level whereas a network ACL operates at the subnet level with security groups you have allow rules only
and with network ACLU you have allow and deny rules a security group has state full whereas a network
ACL is state less and we just go back over to hear what that means is that if you have traffic coming
into your subnet and the network ACL allows that that the return traffic going back must also be allowed
there has to be a rule in the network ACL that allows the port protocol to go back out again that's
different to security groups where as long as it's allowed inbound whatever outbound connections go
back or allow by default
a security group evaluates all rules whereas a network ICAO processes the rules in order until it reaches
a permit or deny and a security group applies to instances only if they're specifically associated with
that group.
Whereas a network ICL applies to every instance that's within a subnet that that network ICL is associated
with
so let's go to the console and what we're gonna do is we're going to just head over to easy to and we're
also going to bring out the VPC console so it's kind of easy to and what we're gonna do is we're going
to launch a couple of instances
and the first one I'm gonna go to.
I'm gonna put this into my VPC so this is the custom BPC we created in this part of the course and I'm
gonna put this instance in public to a I'm gonna select my I am wrong and then I'm going to take the
code and hopefully you followed through this course from the previous section.
If not you'll find this code within the course downloads and what it essentially does is cause the bash
interpreter updates packages installs and enables Apache and then it uses a couple of s free for objects
that we upload it to a bucket and it essentially just updates an X indexed or hasty metal file with
a name that it pulls at random from this file.
So let's continue.
We're going to configure security group choose web access which gives us access H and we're going to
launch
and we're going to do the same thing now in to be.
So we're going to just put this instance into TV and actually we we don't need to install Apache on
this one so let's just put this one in public to be and we don't need to change that rolls or add a
new user data
so we can choose web access again view and launch and launch.
So while those are launching let's head to the VPC management console and have a look at network AC
sales so you can see here the default network ACL and this top one is the one that's associated with
the custom BPC we created.
And you can see it's associated with all six subnets
and you can see that allow all that I talked about and it's rule.
So the format the IWM suggest is that you leave big spaces between your numbers so that you can I suppose
fill them in with other rules later down the line so they suggest that you start with 100 and then you
do 200 and 300 and then the patent seems to be that you then use the next number for the IP B6 version
of that rule.
So you have one hundred one then two hundred and two hundred and one and we have the same of outbound
it's identical you have allows and then there's explicit denies at the end.
So the rules would be processed in order until they reach a deny.
And in this case the traffic will be allowed because it says any protocol any port any destination and
we can associate administrator here.
So let's go ahead and create a test and ICL just gonna call it that and put that in the VPC and let's
have a look at the rules associate of this.
So as we can see you only have to deny rules there are no allow rules and the same of outbound.
Now what I want to do is go over to the council and I want to take the IP address of my instance that's
in to be.
So not this one that's into wireless connect to the instance into B so I'm in the console and I'm going
to SSA into this instance
and we're in and I'm now going to go back and get the private IP address of this other instance which
is the instance that's in to a I remember it's the instance into why that actually has a patchy install.
So what I should be able to do is what I want to be able to do is to ping this instance.
But first we need to go back and allow it us in the security groups.
So let's just head back over to the VPC management console and that's choose our security group and
we only have association this one at the moment so I'm going to create one that says all ICMP V4 and
another one that's allowed HDTV which is there it is.
So we're just going to allow any address range.
So going to save those rules head back to the console and that's try to ping the private because I'm
going to go back and copy my IP address again.
So let's just go in and copy the IP address and then we're going to ping the IP address of the other
instance which remember is in a different subnet and that's fine.
And then we should be able to curl that instance and you'll see that the index or hasty mail file displayed
at the bottom there we can see that the names we've got.
Hi this is colony so that's the name that was given to that instance.
So that all works fine.
Now let's go back to VPC management console and we're gonna go to network AC yells.
And so what I want to do is I'm going to associate this network ACL with to a subnet so that's where
our web server is sitting and I click on edit.
So now we only have five subnets associated with the default ACL and we have one subnet associated with
the new custom ACL.
So remember that's what happens when you Associates a network ACL because you can only have one network
ACL associated per subnet.
So we don't have any allow rules so the expected behavior would be if we tried to rerun those commands
it doesn't work and sure enough we're not getting any response.
So let's go back over and what we're going to do is we're going to edit the inbound rules and we're
going to allow and let's choose all ICMP and we're going to put that as well 100 from any source and
then we're going to allow HDTV
and we're going to put this one is following the protocol.
Let's put those two hundred and again that's any source.
So let's go by we've created those rules.
Let's go and try again and we're not getting any response still.
So I've tried the ping I've tried the curl and we're not getting any response from our web server.
And of course that's because this is a state less firewall.
It's not a state for firewall like a security group.
So we have to go to outbound rules and we need to add the rules in here.
So let's put in rule 100 ICMP before and allow and then rule one hundred and paste ETP and that is being
allowed as well.
Excuse me I need to change up to 200 click on save.
And now let's go back and see what happens.
So we'll run the ping and that's great.
So we've now got traffic going in both directions and let's try running curl.
And that's not working.
So the reason being if we go back to our rules we have an inbound rule and that allows ICMP V4 and an
outbound rule that allows ICMP V4.
Now this is a protocol level.
It's not a port level.
So it doesn't matter what port the traffic comes back as as long as it's in ICMP packet.
It's allowed now with haste ETP we're sending data one direction to our Web server and it's heading
the web server on port 80.
But the return traffic doesn't come back on port 80.
It comes back on an ephemeral port and a federal port is a high number port.
So we're going to put in a custom DCP rule and we're going to put in 10 24 to sixty five 5 3 5.
And that's that's the range which most federal ports sit in.
And it really depends on your operating system.
But we're going to use this and I think this will work just fine.
So we.
So what's essentially happening is the traffic hits your web server and port 80 but the return connection
that comes back is on a port somewhere within this range.
So we just need to allow that return traffic and we can come back here and hit kill and now it works
just fine so another thing you can do.
Network ACLJ is you can apply the new rules and what we need to do for a deny role is make sure that
the rule is reached before and allow rule because these are processed in order and the first allow or
deny that's reached is process and nothing happens after that.
So what we need to do is we need to make sure that our deny rules if you want to deny a specific source
for instance are higher in the list of rules than ours open allow rules and I'm going to show you an
example of that.
So let's just go over and to our instances and I'm going to take the public IP address of our instance
into a which is this one
and I've opened a new terminal window and what I'm gonna do is just ping that instance from my clients.
So I have a I'm going to Mac working at home and I can ping this instance by the Internet.
Now what I want to do is I want to block traffic from my IP address.
So the way I can do that is I can come in here and I can add a rule.
Let's just put this is 300 that says all I see NPV for now.
I could specify my source IP address here but if I did it there the allowed rule would still be reached
first.
So let's just try that.
So we put in the IP address that I have on the Internet click on site.
And let's go back and ping and sure enough that traffic is allowed because the rules are being processed
in order.
So let's just go back and what I'm gonna do is I'm going to copy this
up into the one hundred rule.
And so what I said is that this IP address and the slash 32 means this exact IP address you could put
in a range if you like.
So we've put in our source address with our slash 32 to to say this exact type pay address and what
we want to do now is change this to deny and click on save.
And so what I want to do is try and ping that address and it's a file and let's try again to reach that
address via curl.
So this is trying to reach the web server in port 80 and that's fine so that works okay.
Whereas pinging doesn't.
And of course that's because we have a deny rule for ICMP but we have an allow rule for port 80 TCB
so that's it for network AC ls what we're going to do is we're going to go back into our default network
ICL here.
I'm just going to re associate public to a and then we now have no associations and we can delete that
network ICL and the only other thing to do is just delete instances.
So let's just terminate our instances.
So go back to the slides you know key things to remember BPC rounds are actually hosts the network AC
ls but they're logically associated with subnets they process traffic that's coming into ingress or
out of egress the subnet so they don't affect anything it's within the subnet.
So if you see questions around around blocking access for instance between instances within a subnet
then that's a security group it can't be a network ICAO again after exam questions you might get say
that you want to deny a specific IP address from sending data.
So I remembered the nine rules are allowed to network ICL but there's no such thing with security groups.
So you've got to work out the differences between how you might be able to implement that solution.
So that's it for this now guys.