Hi, guys, this is a quick orientation video to show you around the new S3 management console.
Now, at this point in time, the changes are ongoing, but I wanted to record this video just to help
you to navigate around the console.
So I'm in the console here.
And what you'll notice, I've got a bucket and this one is a public bucket.
Let's just go into the bucket.
Now, here you'll find that things are very similar and other properties you can enable versioning.
It's enabled for this bucket.
Select tags, set your encryption.
I've enabled encryption for this bucket, set up intelligent sharing server access, logging cloud data
events, event notifications, transfer acceleration, object log request lipase and static website
hastings'.
And that's all under this menu properties.
You've then got permissions.
So here we've got block public access.
In this case I've turned blocked public access off.
So this is a public bucket.
You apply your policies here when you apply a policy.
An interesting thing to note is there's now a nice little tap there where you can just copy your ayran
so that you can then paste it into the policy edits at all.
You can get some policy examples and use a policy generator as well.
Under the bucket policy, you can set objects ownership, configure Ackles, in this case, openable
public access for list and read and you can set course settings as well.
On the metrics page, you can see some information about the bucket.
This is a brand new bucket, so there's no data to see here.
Under management.
We then have the lifecycle rules and the replication rules.
So lifecycle would be, you know, what you want to do in terms of moving your data between different
storage classes.
Replication rules are where you then create your replication between buckets.
So Eve across region or single region replication.
And this particular menu is fairly straightforward to follow.
And we'll be doing this later on in the section.
Now, let's go back to the main page.
And what I want to show you is what it's like creating a bucket now because the menu is slightly different.
So when we create bucket, we give it a name.
I'm just going to call this orientation test DCT too, and then you select your region as normal.
Now, this is a new feature.
You can now choose a bucket.
And so what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy the settings from this other bucket.
Now, note before I do that, that block public access is off, versioning of encryption is off.
But I want to copy the settings from my other bucket, so I'm able to do that here.
So that's quite a handy little feature and that's changed the settings for my bucket.
And that's all.
We can then go down and make an override the settings if we like, or just accept those and create the
bucket.
In this case, I have to acknowledge that the settings are going to enable public access and then create
a bucket.
So that's bucket creation.
Now let's go into a bucket and we can upload an object.
You can actually drag and drop files straight onto this interface or click add files or add folder.
Let's add a couple of files and we can see a summary of where the objects are going to be uploaded.
So this is the destination bucket and then what the versioning encryption and object lock statuses.
You can then also expand for additional options where you can choose storage class, service side settings,
ECLSS settings, object lock tags and metadata.
So, you know, these aren't new settings.
These are the same settings that we had before.
It's just a slightly different interface.
So it's click on upload and those files are now uploaded.
At this point, it's sometimes not obvious, but you have to go up to the top right hand corner here
and click on exit and then it takes you actually back to the bucket and the main navigation page.
That's all I wanted to show you in this video.
There are some new features, but mainly it's just different menus for creating buckets and uploading
objects.
So I hope that is useful.
I'll see you in the next lesson.