We're almost ready to get stuck into the labs guys but we need to set up a few things ahead of time
open up a browser and what we're going to do is install NPM.
So if you just type npm install if you don't have this installed already you can follow this link.
And so this is what they call the neatly packaged modules.
And this is for node.js.
Yes you can click on the download link and it should take you to the right download for your operating
system.
In my case it's MacOS and I just chose the current version and it's a very simple install.
The next thing we need to do is create a couple of IAM roles.
So we're in IAM.
We're going to click on Create role.
We're going to choose Lambda and then under permissions we need to search for AWS Lambda executes
and it's this one here and just select that option go to review and then you want to call this Lambda
d-s3-role and you can click right roll we can then do the same thing again.
We're going to choose lambda again and this time we're going to search for AWS Lambda
DynamoDB.
And there we go.
We got the DynamoDB execution role.
So I'm going to check that box.
Go to review and this one we're going to call lambda-dynamodb-role and click on Create role.
The only other thing we need to do is just create a couple of directories.
So let's go to a command line and what I've done is I've changed to a directory where I'm going to store
my documents and I just want to do make directory lambdaS3 and make directory lambda-dynamodb
and that's it and we're just gonna use these tools and these directories for some code in the subsequent
labs.