Service control policies or steps are a way that we can control using chase on policies, the permissions
that are available in an account.
So let's have a look at how this works.
We have our IWC organization, we have a management account and that's under the roots of the organization.
You can apply a policy here.
And by default, there's a policy here, which is an ACP, and it has this statement which essentially
says effectors allow action star resource stock and those are wildcards.
So what this does is it allows any action on any resource, so steps will control the maximum available
permissions.
They don't grant you permissions.
You need to have permissions assigned to you through IAM.
But what this will do is limit what's available now in this case.
This ACP allows all action, so it's not limiting anything.
Users in the management account are not restricted.
So these policies are not applying to the management account, but we can apply them to organizational
units and then accounts underneath the management account.
Now here we've got a TAC policy.
This enforces TAC standardization and then on the right hand side, here we've got another O.U and we
have a development accounts in it.
And here we have another you underneath the Devah use of a forming a hierarchy with children underneath
children.
And we have a production account attached to that O.U and we can apply service control policies.
Now this service control policy essentially denies the easy to run instances API action, for any instance.
So the resources just EC2 instance, start with a condition, and the condition says that the string
does not equal to Mike, right?
So what this is saying is it's denying the ability to launch an easy to instance unless the two instance
is a T2 micro.
So you can only launch T2 micro instances.
So deaf users can only launch a T2 micro now because of the effects of policies in that they actually
flow down to child organizational units.
The production users also cannot launch any instance other than T2 Micro because it's been denied an
MCP at a higher level.
So these permissions will flow down through that hierarchy and apply to any accounts underneath.
A really important thing to remember is that steps do not grant permissions.
They limit the maximum available permissions.
So, for example, if you're your user in this development account, you do have or you're not constrained
through the step from launching to micros, you can launch a T2 micro, but you do need to have the
I Am permissions for easy to to be able to do that.
So what you need to understand is first, you need to grant people permissions and then you can control
the permissions that are available in an account.
Now these constraints will apply to everybody, including administrators.
So if you're an admin in the developer account, you have full U.S. access.
You still won't be able to launch anything but T2 Micro SD two instances.
So that's the ferry.
In the next lesson, we'll do a hands on and test applying an Sep policy to our production account.