Hi guys.
In this lab we're going to cover AWS WAF and AWS Shield.
So before we go on with AWS WAF which will take a bit more explanation we're gonna start with AWS shield.
So let's just go to AWS Shield and what you can see here is the AWS Shield is a service which provides
protection for Distributed Denial of Service protection for your applications.
Now there are two different versions of AWS Shield.
We've got the standard and the advanced and as it mentions here the standard comes with AWS WAF and
your other services so you're not actually paying anything extra for this.
Whereas with the advanced plan which has a lot more features you actually have to pay quite a bit of
money.
So we're not going to enable advanced.
This is enabled by default whereas the advanced requires you to pay your three thousand dollars a month.
But as you can see if you need that level of protection there's lots of extra features.
Now just to talk a bit more about the distributed denial of service.
This is an article that you should definitely have a read of.
You may be asked questions in the exam about which services you can use in an architecture to protect
against distributed denial of service.
So if it's a specific service like AWS Shield that's great but it might be that it's part of your holistic
architecture and you need to understand which services help in mitigating DDOS attacks.
So for instance these services include Route 53, CloudFront, Elastic Load Balancing, as well as IAM
as well.
And it gives you a bit more information in this article about how that is.
Now what are the best practices.
So firstly it's all about being ready to scale you want your architecture to be able to scale so that
if your resource usage does go up you can absorb those spikes.
It's also about minimising the attack surface area and safeguarding exposed resources.
So this might be using a more distributed decoupled application architecture so that only the resources
that really need to have Internet exposure are actually exposed to the internet then there's know what
is normal and alert on what is not.
So this is really about understanding your environment monitoring it and being able to understand what
normal looks like and being able to have alerts generated when something changes from that normal.
You also need to architect for resilience so that's about making sure that whatever happens your architecture
can recover or absorb spikes or keep running in the event that something fails.
So there's a few best practices there and then they go on to talk about the different services and how
they actually assist with these best practices.
So I recommend you have a look through that and have a look at the different options that they give
you here all the different patterns that they talk about as you will often have exam questions coming
up that might question this knowledge.
I'm just gonna close that now.
Let's go back to shield and I'm just going to go back up to AWS Shield and we're going to continue
this discussion with AWS WAF as well.
So AWS WAF is a web application firewall.
Now let's just go over to the console and get started with AWS as well if you can monitor HTTP
and HTTPS requests that are forwarded to Amazon API Gateway APIs, Amazon CloudFront or application
load balancers. So it's protecting your API and it's protecting your applications that sit behind CloudFront
or an application load balancer. You can control access to your content and you can do so based on conditions
that you specify so you can see on the left here we have all sorts of conditions.
For instance if you go down to geo-match you can go in and create a condition here for location so you
can say country is American Samoa, or country is Barbados, and you can have then a list of countries and
then you can use that list of countries for your filters to either deny or allow access from those countries.
Similarly you can do the same with IP addresses you could even do size constraints so you can come in
here and say well I want my HTTP method to equal no more than 20 bytes.
And so let's just cancel out of there.
You can also protect against sequel injection string and regex matching and do cross site scripting
as well when you've created your conditions.
You can then choose one of the following behaviours so even you can allow all requests except the ones
that you specify you can block all request except the ones that you specify or you can count the requests
that match the properties that you specify might do that so that you can monitor and understand if you
set up your rules correctly before you actually implement them in allow or block rules.
Let's have a look at creating a Web ACL. We can click on configure web ACL and then we get a page here
which shows us some of the concepts.
So you can see the conditions which we just talked about where you got things like IP match string match
or secret injection match.
You've then got your rules and you've then got your web ACLs.
So if you look in the middle here what it mentions is that we have rules if you add more than one condition
to a rule the request must match values in all conditions to be allowed or blocked.
So you've got to bear that in mind when you're actually creating your rules.
If we click on Next we can now choose a name.
I'm just going to call this my web ACL and you can then choose a region so you can say global cloud
front or you can choose a regional life resource and you can choose your local region.
I'm just going to leave it at look at region global.
Now we don't have any resources to associate at this stage so we can click on to next and we now get
to specify our conditions.
So let's go in and create a geo-condition and I'm going to call this include US and you can then choose
country and you can go in here for instance and put in United States and at that location and choose
create so we can now choose to set up a rule that allows or denies access to people from the US.
And as you can see you've got all these other options as well.
Let's click on Next.
And there's a couple of things on this page.
Firstly you need to create a rule.
What we're going to do is create a rule to allow and we need to change this dropdown box here to originate
from a geographic location in and then we can choose our include us.
So this is context specific.
We need to change that so that we pick up this rule and then we could choose to add an additional condition
or just choose create.
And now that we've created that rule we have an option.
So in this case I want to allow people from the US so I can choose allow and then I can set my default
action to block all requests that don't match any rules which means everybody else will be blocked.
And then we just go in and choose review and create and confirm we have our rule now and what we could
do is actually go and use this somewhere.
So for instance let's head over to CloudFront and let's create a new distribution and then choose a
Web distribution.
And I'm not going to actually fill out any of these details because we're not actually going to create
this cloudfront distribution.
But if you just scroll down to distribution settings you can now see your web ACL.
So by selecting that web ACL if I created a cloudfront distribution now it would only allow users from
the geographic area of the United States.
So I'm just going to cancel out of that head back over to AWF and I want to delete this web ACL but
before I can do that I need to head into the web ACL and I need to delete the rule and click on updates
and then we can go in and actually delete the web ACL.