Hello and welcome to this lab on application low balance a path based routing.
There are two different types of routing that we're going to cover in the next two labs.
The first is path based and the second is host based.
So what I'm going to show you is how to create this configuration where we have an application load
balancer that forwards to different target groups based on conditions in roles.
So you'll remember from the slide that shows the different types of low balances that the application
load balancer operates at the request level.
So it routes based on the content of the request that Layer 7.
That means it looks at what's in the DTP and hasty CPS protocol information.
So that is the header and the path in the URL.
So we can then support path based routing host based routing query string parameter based routing and
source IP based routing.
So we're going to concentrate on path based routing for this lab and then host based routing.
So what this means is we're going to create this configuration we're going to have a default rule which
just forwards all traffic to target group 1 but we're then also going to have a rule which says that
if the U.R.L. includes slash orders and then as that you're gonna be a wildcard a star then forward
to target group 2 which is also going to have two instances in and we're actually going to have names
on these instances through the code that we're going to use in the user data.
So we'll be able to see ourselves cycling between the different instances in each of the target groups.
So it sounds like a lot of fun I think.
Let's get into the easy to management console and start building this out someone that easy to management
console let's click launch instance I'm going to choose the Linux 2 am I T2 micro I'm going to change
my number of instances to 4 I'm going to choose my S3 full access roll and then I'm going to go down
to advance details and I'm going to paste in my code.
Now we've used this code before I think the only difference is at the very end I've got a command that
copies the index or hasty amount to orders not H2 email.
So what it does is it picks up a name from this file which is on as free and then it puts that name
into the index or a hasty email far so we actually have a name for instance.
So I'm going to click on Next go through to security groups choose web access review and launch and
launch.
And while those four instances are launching Let's go down to target groups and we're going to create
our target groups.
So I'm going to create two target groups.
The first is t g 1 and as you can see for a application load balancer you can actually choose a lambda
function as well as an IP we're going to choose instance we're going to leave the protocol as page DTP.
Now you can see all the other protocols like the laughable ones but that's because we're just creating
a target group.
So this is generic.
If you chose DCP you wouldn't be able to attach this target group to an application load balancer.
So we have to choose like a seven page TTP.
It's going to go in my default VPC.
I'm going to leave the other settings as default except the healthy threshold is going to be to and
then I'm going to do exactly the same and create my second target group T G two and use the same settings.
What I'm going to do now is go back and I'm going to name my instances so I know which ones are which.
So let's do instance one instance to instance free and instance for and I'm going to go back to my target
groups and in target group one I'm going to register instance one an instance two and then in target
group two I'm going to register instance free and instance for and now I can create my load balancer.
So let's choose crate load balancer and we can see the application load balance on the left here which
is hate TTP and hasty tepees.
So as it says you use this for web applications with haste ETP in haste G.P.S. s traffic and it tells
you that it operates at the request level Albee's provide advance routing and visibility features targeted
at application architectures including micro services and containers and we're actually going to do
a lab on containers in section 9 where we attach an elastic load balancer.
So let's choose create.
I'm going to call this my Alby.
We're going to keep the protocol as TTP and then we're going to specify multiple Availability Zones
and subnets already predefined for us and then go to choose the web access security group and underwriting.
I can choose an existing group and I'm going to choose one so that's going to be the target group for
my default rule.
Now you can say it finds the instances and tells us that they're already going to be registered.
So let's go create and our load balance is being created so our low balance is being created.
But all it's got is one rule which rules connections to target group one and you can see that under
listeners here.
So it says default rule forwarding to target group 1 but we've got to target groups.
So what we can do is edit rules click the plus insert rule add condition and this is where you select
the type of condition you want to use.
So I'm going to select a path based condition and I'm going to put slash orders and then a staff or
a wildcard click the tick mark and then action forward to target group 2 and click on say.
So we now have two rules.
Got the default rule at the end here which says that all traffic will be forwarded to target group one
but the number one rule here is that if the path is slash orders then forward to target group 2.
So that's all looking good.
Let's go back and check if our instances are healthy.
So they're actually in the initial stage in target group 2.
It's got a target group one they're also in the initial stage so we need to wait a couple of minutes
until our instances show as being healthy.
So it's been a few minutes and I can see my instances in target group one are healthy and in target
group 2.
They're also healthy.
So that looks great.
Let's go to load balancers description and we can copy the DNS name and I'm going to go to a new tab.
Put it in.
And here we go.
We've got this is Brett.
And if I just hit refresh.
We've now got Joe Len as well.
So we should cycle through Brett and Joe Len.
Now these instances are in target group 1 because we've gone straight through the default rule because
we didn't put slash orders in.
So let's go back and put in slash orders into the path and see what happens.
So I'm going to type in slash orders dot hasty email because that's the file on our instances.
And now we've got Sandra and Alicia so you can see we're now cycling through Sandra.
Alicia these are the instances in target group 2 because we've used a path that includes slash orders
so our rule has triggered on a condition and forwarded traffic to target group to so that's how it works
we've got Lisa and Sandra there.
And if we remove it slash orders straight away we go back to Brett and Joe Len.
So that's if a path based routing we set up this configuration.
And if you wanted to apply a bit more you could add in additional rules with different conditions.
Now we're going to keep our configuration running because we're going to focus on host based routing
in the next lap.
But what we can do is just go back to our load balancer to listeners view and it rules and let's just
delete this rule.
So you click the minus select one and then delete and that's put us back to just having the default
rule.
And then in the next slide we're going to look at host based routing so leave everything running and
go straight onto the next lap.