Hi, guys.
So next up, we have these surfer migration service.
So this is what you would use to migrate your virtual machines from on premises into the W.S. Cloud.
Now, the source can be VM where Hyper V or as you're at this stage.
So the source has to be one of those different providers.
And then what you do is you install something called the Server Migration Service Connector.
So that's actually an overlay appliance.
So a virtual appliance which you install on your farm.
And then once that's installed, that then communicates with the server migration service.
Now, the great thing about estimates is it does automated and incremental migrations and it can also
you can use it to schedule your migrations as well.
So you can specify when they're going to be migrated.
Now, this means that you can sort of incrementally migrate your services.
Now, if you've ever done a server migration like this, I've done lots of them in the past.
Same with databases.
You know, you don't want to have to take your database or your server down while you're migrating,
because sometimes that can be very large quantities of data.
And the network pipe into a W.S. might not be fast enough to do it quickly.
So you want to try and do it automate in an automated and incremental manner.
And that means you can do a lot more testing so you can test the code over process.
You can cut over to E.S., too.
You can see what you need to do to modify those instances to make them run properly and make sure your
application works.
And and then you can sort of repeat.
And you can keep migrating.
You can keep replicating the data until the point in time when you're ready and confident that you can
cut over your application successfully.
So this can be running sometimes for periods of, you know, days or weeks while you're slowly getting
ready to that point where you're ready to actually cut over your application and go live on a W.S..
So that's a really cool tool.
So it does these scheduled automated incremental migrations of your life servers from VM where Hiep
of yours, you're and what it will do is it will create an am I for each of your migrated servers and
then you can launch instances from those itemise.