Hi, guys, this lesson is going to be a hands on lab, where I'm going to show you how to create and
publish custom metrics from an easy to Linux instance.
Now, I'm going to be following Loosley with this article here, so I'll provide this in the course
download.
And by all means, you can follow this article if you want a bit more detail, because this has a few
different metrics that it's actually going to publish.
Whereas what I'm going to do just to simplify things is just use memory.
Now, why have I chosen memory?
Because memory comes up on the exam quite a lot.
And the reason is because when associated with Cloud watch, what you'll find is that memory is something
which is not recorded by default using cloud watch.
Now, let me just go back over to somewhere.
I've actually got a bunch of metrics, so let's go to the Sydney region.
And if I go to metrics and if I choose to, per instance, and then I'm just going to copy one of these
instant sightings just to bring down the lists, I'm going to filter the list.
So we just see one instance and you can see there are 17 metrics.
That's the default and none of those are related to memory.
So if you look on the right here, there's none that are related to memory.
A CPA, we got desk, we've got network and so on.
But there's no memory metrics.
And that is something that's been coming up on exam questions and different certifications for quite
a while.
So they still get thrown in every now and then.
Now, I'm going to go back to you southwest Oregon, because this is a bit of a blank slate.
So I don't have metrics here.
If you have a look on the metrics and go to it's clear those filters, I've only got one metric.
So there's nothing going on here.
So the first thing I need to do is go to two and we're going to launch an instance.
It's going to be Lennix two.
Am I?
It's going to be a T2 micro.
All of this can be defaults.
We just need to put it into a security group for S.H. So I've got my Web access reports.
We need to open to any source, address this change, review and launch and launch.
And that's on its way.
Now, you'll find in the course download that you've got this mentor, S.H. Shell script and it's under
code cloud.
Watch Memmel S.H..
And what we're going to do is we're going to use the first two lines here.
But the first thing we need to do before we can use the script is change the instance side here.
So make sure you delete the instant.
Let's come back, find our instance and I'm going to copy the instance ID here and then just paste that
in.
So the next thing we need to do is copy our public IP.
Just going to check what my keeper is called.
So that's dash copy.
So I'm on the command line now.
I'm going to tie S.H. Dash.
I put in Oregon Das Kapital primness my keeper and then easy to dash user adds and then the IP address
and that should be running now.
So let's hit enter and type.
Yes.
And now we're on our new Easy two instance.
So what I need to do first is I'm going to create a file called Memmel S.H. and we're going to go back
and we're going to copy these first two lines here and we'll paste that in.
And then I'm going to save this file.
Now we need to have permissions for the Shell script to actually publish data to cloud watch.
And for that, I'm going to go back over to the console and we're going to head over to Iame and I'm
going to head down to roles and search for cloud watch.
Now, I actually have a role, so I've got one called Cloud Watch Agent several.
So if you just create a role, choose EC2 as a trust type and then for permissions, what you'll find
is this cloud watch agent server policy and that policy gives us the actions we need.
So we've got the metadata action and there's got some other ones around logging and describing volumes
and tags.
So I already have that policy.
So I'm going to head back to to choose instant settings here, attach, replace Iam role and then choose
my cloud.
Watch Agent Severo and Head apply.
So we've now got our roles, so we should have permissions, what I need to do now is I want to test
my script and to do so I first need to run it plus X to give execute permissions to the file.
So Ashmont plus X, Mendoza, which we now should be able to run Mandorah S.H..
So let's see what happens now.
We get a message saying that we need to specify a region.
Now I know that the command line we're using doesn't accept a region variable.
So instead what we can do is just type Athabascan figure.
We won't put it in an Axis Kiddi or secret axis K and we'll just type us W two for the region name and
just put in whatever your region is.
And then I'm going to hit enter a couple of times.
Now let's try and run this command.
So appearance and appears to have run.
Now if we head back to cloud watch, let's have a look at what metrics are already there.
So back in cloud watch.
We have one metric, but let's refresh this page.
And if that doesn't work, refreshed the entire page.
So just refresh your browser window and then sometimes that makes the difference.
So now let's go back to all metrics and we can see that we've got the standard metrics.
So we've got the EBC two metrics and some usage metrics and then we've got a custom metrics.
If we go in here, we can see that we actually have our custom metric.
So that's how we create a custom metric.
Now, if you want to take it a bit further, the next thing we can do is in this file we can run this
command.
So we're going to try to crosstab so that it runs on a schedule.
So just copy from the start until the end of the script.
Now, then a copy that come back to the command line and we'll type crosstab Dashi hit ensa paste in
and then type Kolon WQ.
So in the bottom corner there you can see Kolon WQ and that will save the file and then it should stay
say installing new crosstab.
And that means that the crosstab is going to cause the Shell script to run on the schedule that we just
defined.
Now another thing I want to do is actually install the stress utility.
So I'm going to copy this command, post this command in and hit Enza and that should install these
libraries.
And then let's come back and install the stress dash and G utility.
So I'm going to pass that command in and that should install and then I'm going to run this command.
So I'm going to take all of this code here.
Copy that in.
And then once this is finished installing, we can just put that into the command line and run the stress
utility.
So I'm going to answer I missed the V on the end there and then head enter.
And so that's going to start a series of these VMS with a certain amount of CPU and memory utilization.
So what you can do now is just watch what happens in cloud watch.
So over a period of time, we should see some more statistics coming in from memory usage in the graph
at the top here.
So that could take a few minutes before you start seeing some good data.
So just go and have a cup of tea or something like that and then come back and have a look at your graph
in a few minutes time.
I've waited a few minutes and now I've got a bit of data.
And you can change the resolution, by the way, under period here.
So if I change that to one minute, then we'll see a bit of a line here.
So it goes up, it peaks, and then it drops down and kind of stabilizes.
And you can see the increments here.
So you can see where the data points were actually received.
So that's all I wanted to do in this lesson.
And what I'm going to do, I'm going to leave this running.
And in the next lesson, we're actually going to create an alarm and try and trigger that alarm.