Hi guys.
In this lab we're going to create a Kinesis stream and then what we're going to do is we're going to
create a Lambda function and we're going to create an event source mapping such that when we put items
into the stream, Lambda is polling the stream, and it finds that there's a new entry and then it runs
the function and the function will simply write an event to CloudWatch logs so if you'll remember from
the Lambda section of the course when it comes to stream based services like Kinesis and DynamoDB
the event source mapping is configured on the Lambda side not on the stream side.
So that's the opposite to a bucket for instance in S3 where you configure the event source
mapping on the bucket.
So it will be the Lambda function that does the polling and we're going to upload some records into
a stream.
Lambda is going to execute and write in events CloudWatch logs.
So let's get over to the console.
Now what we're going to be doing today is following a tutorial from AWS.
So again guys this is to make things easy so that you guys can recreate what I'm doing.
I don't want things to be too complex and you guys have problems.
So what we're going to do.
First thing we need to go to I am and we need to create the execution role.
So let's just open up.
I am so I'm in.
IAM.
I'm going to go to roles create role.
We're going to choose Lambda and then we're going to choose next
and what we want to find is the AWS Lambda Kinesas execution role.
So there we go.
We can just attach this row let's click next and what I'm going to do is I'm just going to paste in
the name for the role which AWS suggested.
So that's Lambda Kinesis - role and we're going to create the role.
And what we're going to do now is go over to the command line and the first thing I need to do and by
the way I've just created the directory called Kinesas.
So I've just created it in my documents folder just create yourself a directory so you can put your
files in here.
And what we're going to do is we need to create an index.js file.
So I'm gonna do nano index.js and I now need to paste in some code and I can say I've missed a
letter at the beginning there so let's just put that in shouldn't be capitals just backspace that console
and I'm just going to save this file so I now have my index.js file.
I then need to run zip function.zip and then supply the name of that index file so we now have our
function.zip in our index.js.
The next thing we need to do is run a command that's going to create our function and to do that we
need to get the ARN of our Lambda role that we created.
So let's just go back and we can choose our role.
And I'm going to copy the IRS on my clipboard.
I'm now going to run this command which is AWS Lambda create function.
I'm gonna give it the name.
Process can e as records.
I'm gonna supply the file the zip file that we just created function.zip.
The handler is indexed or handler.
This is a node.js function.
And then I'm giving it the role.
So let's just hit enter
and now let's head back over to the console and let's go into Lambda and see if we've got our function
created
and that's our process can these records function.
We now want to test our function.
So let's head back over to the console.
We're going to create a file called input dot t 60.
So I'm gonna run nano input dot t t I'm going to paste in my code and I'm going to save the code we're
now going to run a command to invoke the function with the file with the payload false of the input
test file that we just created so we've got a status code of 200 that looks good.
The next thing we want to do is create our Kinesis stream so we can run the command AWS Kinesis
create stream stream name and we're giving it the name Lambda that's stream and we're just going to
have one shard if we want to see the stream details we can run this command AWS Kinesis describe
stream and we give it the stream name and this will also give us the ARN which we're going to need shortly.
Let's just have a quick look in the console to see our stream.
I'm gonna go to Kinesis
and under data streams sure enough we've got our Lambda stream so that all its good we now need to create
our events source mapping and there's a rather long command to do this.
So it's AWS Lambda create dash event dash source dash mapping.
We supply the function name events source which is the ARN for our Lambda stream which we just got from
this output up here and then given a batch size of one hundred and the starting position of latest.
So let's hit enter you may have noticed an error there.
So let's just head back and what I need to do is I haven't copied the full ARN so I'm just going to
backspace away here
and what I need is the full ARN and so I missed out on that first bit.
So let's copy that and then paste that in and hit enter and let's head back over to Lambda
and have a look at our function.
And sure enough we now have an event source mapping here and we can see we have a problem here.
It says the function is not found in the database.
Now I think this is because I've created this before while I was preparing for this lab.
But let's have a look at how we can troubleshoot this so we can see that the output here actually said
mapping already exists.
Let's run AWS Lambda list dash event bash source bash
mappings and we can see that there's a couple of events source mappings here.
And what I want to do I don't need either of these and there's been a conflict.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to delete these events source mappings and I can just run
the command delete prevent dash source dash mapping and then I need to give the IDs.
So I do dash dash UUID and I'm going to copy this one here and paste it
and then I'm going to do the same for the other UUIDs I'm just going to backspace out copy this one
and let's go back and list event source mappings and we don't have any anymore.
So I'm going to go and see if I can rerun.
Now before I do that I'm going to run the command but before I do that I just want to go over to Lambda
and let's go outside of this function and just want to go back in and see if it's gone.
So the trigger has gone so that's good.
Now let's go back and try and recreate event source mapping okay.
Now that looks a bit better.
So let's head over to the console and again I'm just going to refresh and we've got our event source
mapping and this time we don't have any issues it just says loss processing result.
No records processed.
So we're back on track.
So let's head back over to the console and what we're going to do now is actually put a record into
the stream.
So we're in the console and I'm going to run this command AWS Kinesis put record and then I'll give
it the stream name the partition key and some data and it just says hello.
This is a test so we're going to run that and then let's just go in and change this too.
This is another test.
So we've sent a couple of records into the stream.
So what should happen now according to our diagram is we've uploaded those records.
They've gone into the stream Lambda should have pulled the stream and then written an event to cloud
watch logs.
So let's head over and we're gonna have a looking CloudWatch logs back in the Lambda console.
Let's go to monitoring and view logs in CloudWatch.
And so we've got this log stream.
Let's open it up and there's a few messages in here and we can see here the payload.
This is a test and we can see here.
This is another test.
So that was a very simple lab just to show how you can integrate between Lambda and concussive streams
and of course with those functions you could do all sorts of things to your data.
All we've done is written a log to cloud watch logs.
So let's close this lab down and what we can do is go into Kinesis streams and delete our stream and
we can go to Lambda and delete our function and that's it.
Guys hate we had some fun.
See in the next lab.