Hi guys.
What we're gonna do in this lab is we're going to enable multi AZ for the database that we configured
in the last lab.
But before I do that I need to explain to you what multi AZ is and also how it compares to
read replicas as these are two ways that you can enable high availability and also offloading of performance
from your master database.
So let's look at the two, multi AZ
What this means is you enable multi AZ on your database and it creates a standby copy of your database
in another availability zone within the same VPC.
So it's within the region within the VPC.
It's just in a different availability side.
It's always going to be in a different availability zone and the replication is synchronous.
So synchronous means that before
before a replication event came complete it needs to the database needs to check that it has successfully
been written to the database.
So that's different to asynchronous where there's no checking so the data is replicated but there's
no check to prove that the transaction has been committed before carrying on.
So with a read replica you have asynchronous replication. Now read replicas are a different use case.
So multi AZ you have a primary database and a secondary database.
Let's have a look at a diagram.
So you've got your RDS master.
You create an RDS replica of it not a read replica.
This is a standby copy of your master database your application servers will then connect to the master
instance and synchronous replication happens to the standby.
Now there's no endpoint address on that standby.
So you'll remember from the previous lab we get a long endpoint address like this.
And that's the address that your app server connects to.
But the replica doesn't have an endpoint address because what happens is when you failover the same
address is mapped to the standby instance.
That means that you can't use this instance except for in a scenario where you failover from the master
and that can be an unplanned event or it can be a planned event so read replicas are different because
with a read replica
what happens is you create a replica copy of your database but it has a separate endpoint.
So with a read replica.
What happens is you have this separate copy with its own endpoint and you can have different application
servers connecting to that database but it's only four reads.
So what this is doing is it's off loading reads from your master database or in this case in this diagram
the one on the bottom is the master.
So you can read and write to your master database.
You can't write anything to any standby copies of your master database multi AZ copies but you can
read from an RDS read replica.
So if you've got a lot of read traffic and your master database is having a performance implication
it might be worthwhile a neighboring read replicas
so as I mentioned only the database engine on the primary instance is actually a multi AZ whereas
with read replicas all read replicas are accessible and can be used for read scaling. With multi AZ
backups are taken from the standby.
And that's good because it means that your primary production system that's live isn't getting any performance
implication from actually performing the backup.
There are no backups configured by default for a read replica.
So a multi AZ deployment always spans two aces within a single region whereas a read replica can be
within the same AZ it can be across different AZs or it can even be across regions with multi AZ
the database engine version upgrades happen on the primary whereas with a read replica the database
engine version upgrade is independent from the source instance.
With multi AZ failover to the standby is automatic, if a problem is detected then you can do it manually
as well.
Read replicas can be manually promoted to a standalone database so you can promote a read replica to
become a writer or database.
So that's the theory.
Let's get on with the lab.
So what we're going to do is we currently have our EC2 app server which in this case it's a wordpress
server and we've got a database but we don't have a replica.
So we just have what's going on in the top here.
Let's go over to the console and we're going to head into RDS
and if we just choose our database here we can then click modify and all we need to do is specify yes
under multiple deployment and we can leave everyone else's defaults and it's going to warn us that you
may experience a significant performance impact when converting this database instance to multi AZ.
This will impact, this impact will be much more noticeable on database instances with large amounts of
storage and write intensive workloads.
So of course the data needs to be replicated.
So it's going to have a performance implication because it needs to be read from the current master
database and transferred to the new one therefore you can leave it as the default which is to apply
the change during the next scheduled maintenance window.
In our case we want to choose apply immediately.
So we just collect modified DB for instance and if you just go back to databases and we refresh our
and it now says modifying so I got to leave that a few minutes until it becomes available again.
So that took 10 minutes or so but it's now available.
So I'm going to go into my DB and we now have multi AZ enabled.
What I want to do is simulate a failover and the way that we can do that or actually cause a failover
and the way we can do that is we can choose reboot and then we'll reboot with failover.
Now let's just check.
So we've got our WordPress sites.
And if you remember from the diagram we have our master database server.
We have our WordPress instance connecting to it.
And what we've just done is we've created a replica.
So this is a standby replica.
And the endpoint is currently mapped to our master.
So what's going to happen is when we click reboot and cause a failover, the endpoint address will be
remapped to the RDS replica.
And this will then become the master and things flip around.
So this then becomes the standby in the synchronous replication goes in the opposite direction so let's
head back and let's do it guys.
RDS we're going to choose the option reboot with failover and hit reboot
and now let's go to our WordPress database or WordPress site and click refresh and you can see that's
not working and if we open a new tab we'll get the same thing so that's timing out and it's going to
take a little bit of time while the address gets remapped to the new RDS instance.
And that didn't take long.
I just hit refresh again and this time I got the results.
And this one appears to be hanging but let's just hit refresh and there we go.
So that really didn't take more than a minute or so maybe two minutes.
So it's quite a fast failover and that's all we're going to do in this lab and what we've done now
is we've got our RDS master in this other availability zone and we've got our replication going
to the availability zone where the master used to be and what's happened is our server is now just connecting
to that endpoint over here and what we're going to do in the next lab is we're going to create this
configuration.
So we're actually going to create a read replica.