In this lab we're gonna create an ECS cluster using the EC2 launch type and we're also gonna create it
using the ECS-CLI in this course. I want to show you how to use the ECS-CLI as well as the AWS CLI.
And also how to create ECS clusters through the console as well and that will give you a better more
rounded experience and knowledge of ECS.
The configuration that we're going to create is going to be very similar to the one that you see on
the screen here.
We won't be using the elastic container registry but we will be using its task definition that uses
WordPress containers and mySQL containers and those images will be pulled from the Docker Hub.
We'll have two container instances and we'll have an ECS cluster.
We're going to use the docker compose method of creating our cluster.
And that means we need these two files docker-compose.yml and ecs-params.yaml.
So you do need to use these exact file names and you'll find these files in the course downloads if
you want to change the cluster name and the region
you can do so within this file and you need to do so both the WordPress and the mySQL images.
other things you'll notice that there's the host port and the container port here and you can see that
we've got the WordPress image and the mysql image and that there's a link so that the WordPress
image is linked to the mysql image.
There's also a place where you can specify a password in the acs-params.yml file.
Here we specify CPU shares and memory limits for each of our services: Wordpress and mysql.
So you'll need to copy these files into a directory make any changes you need to make around your region
and cluster name and then open a command line and change to that directory.
Now I'm already in the correct directory so I can just type ls and I can see that I have those files
so you need to make sure that you're in the correct directory and you can see these files and then going
to paste in this command.
So this is the ecs-cli configure command and we specify a cluster name and we're going to call it
DCT ECS cluster. A region
and I'm using ap-southeast-2 you can change it to whatever you want.
You can change the cluster name as well.
And then we've got a default launch type which is EC2 and the configuration name which is the same
as the cluster name in this case.
So I'm going to have to answer and it's safe.
The cluster configuration we now need to run this configure profile command says ecs-cli configure
profile.
We need to provide an access key and a secret key and then a profile name which is DCT ECS cluster.
So that's now being saved the next command brings the cluster up.
So as ECS comes up we provide a VPC I.D. So this is my custom VPC I've copied the ID and pasted
it here.
We then specify a key pair.
So I'm using my Sydney-KP, we specify the number of instances I've got to add the instance type
which is t2.micro we then specify the cluster config which is DCT ECS cluster and we specify two subnets
with a comma in between.
So you can take these IDs from the VPC management console and we're going to press enter and what's
happening now is cloudformation will create this stack for us so it's going to bring up the cluster
and if we head over to the cloudformation console we can see the ECS-CLI setup and our cluster name
and as it's "create in progress" and we could go here and see what's happening if we go to East yes we
may have a cluster yet we've got a cluster.
So you can see the cluster but nothing is going to get started yet.
So we're actually bringing up the cluster configuration and any supporting infrastructure but we won't
be running a service or a task through this command.
I paused the video for a couple of minutes and we can now see that our cluster creation has succeeded
and if we head over to the ECS management console we can see that we have two instances running.
So these are the ones that have been created by cloudformation and if we had over to ECS we've got
a cluster.
And if we have a look at instances we can see that we've got these two instances but we don't have any
tasks running yet.
So what we need to do is come back over here and run another command and this is going to deploy our
compose file so the file that's the docker-compose.yml and the ecs-params.yml.
These are both going to be used now.
To create our tasks the command ECS-CLI compose up create log groups and then cluster config.
And the name of our cluster
so it's starting now we can see it as a failed to create log group because it already exists.
That's okay.
But the containers are appearing to stop.
So let's have a look.
While this is in progress.
Let's head over here and hit refresh and sure enough we've got our WordPress task definition running
and the last state was in pending, desired status is running, so we should see these both be running
soon and it will go, it will turn green as well.
And we can see that this is still working at the moment creating the second task definition as well.
So that's completed.
Let's head back and we have a running task.
And if we go into that task we can see some information about it.
And if we head down to WordPress we can get the external IP.
So this is the public IP address that we're going to use.
So just before we go there you can see the instance say that it's running on.
You can see the container instance ideas as well.
I can see the task definition has been launched from and then what you're saying here is then can the
information that you can associate with a container.
So there's lots more information that's not being configured.
And then under mySQL again here there's not much information is being configured in this other
than the password.
So let's take this IP address and I'm going to open a tab and here's our WordPress site.
I'm just going to call this site one.
Give it the user name of digitalcloud.
I'm going to use that for the password as well confirm that it's a weak password.
I'll give it a fake email address and let's just install Wordpress and say That's it.
We now have a working WordPress instance running on a container back on the command line.
We could also use ecs-cli ps and then give it the cluster type that currently and this will also
give us some information about what's running on the cluster so we can see that we have a single instance
of this task running Wordpress and minus Q Well and you can see the public IP address.
So that's all we're going to do in this lab.
We're going to leave the resources running and then in the next lab we're going to see how we can scale
our cluster.