Hi guys we're going to create a wordpress stack now using CloudFormation and what I'm showing you
on the screen is the PNG that was exported from the designer.
So I used that template and just clicked on the export button and this is what you see.
So you can see on here we've got a DB instance we've got a load balancer.
So there is running an ideal spot away.
We have a load balancer with a target group.
We have a couple of security groups an Auto Scaling group which will have instances running in it
an ALB listener here
and the launch configuration.
So that's the infrastructure that's gonna get built now through the designer.
You can see all these different mappings and how they relate to each other.
So let's head into the console and have a look at this.
So I'm in the CloudFormation management console and then choose create, use a sample template and
choose the multi AZ simple wordpress blog.
And what I want to do is view in designer and we do need to make the same changes that we made in the
last lab.
So I'm going to go in here and I'm going to search for PHP and it's not that one is this one here.
And I just need to change this to PHP 70 and then PHP 70 dash mysql and HTTPD24.
So I've made those changes and what I can do rather than sort of export in the fall and uploading it
which I wanted to show you last time is we can just go and create this stack
so the stack is ready to create we click on Next.
And I'm going to change again to use smaller instances try and keep us in free tier so I'm going to
use this t2.micro I'm going to just copy and paste the passwords again change the instance type here
which is for our web server and she's my keeper.
Now we can create multi AZ if we want I'm not going to bother for this lab because we're not going
to test failover or anything like that but you could just change false to true if you wanted to choose
multi AZ as well.
And now we can choose our subnets now and then I choose my default subnet.
I did notice in testing that if I chose the other VPC CloudFormation put my instance into the correct
VPC but it put the database into the default VPC so that's clearly not the code written into the
template to update the ID since to be deployed into the same VPC.
So I would just leave it as default if I were you or you could use it as an exercise to sharpen your
skills on creating CloudFormation templates.
Now I've just added my subnets and I click on Next.
And of course I need to give it a name.
So in this case I'm going to call it multi AZ WP.
So again we don't need to make any other changes here,
I'm just gonna go through.
You can see everything set up correctly.
And I'm just gonna head through and click Create stack.
So that took about 15 minutes or so for me.
And it looks like things that have been created and it's all complete you can see in here application
load balancer.
The target group the listener you can see the web service security groups being created, the database
security groups, the database instance itself.
And then the launch config and the web server green.
So that looks really good.
Let's have a look into resources here and you can sort of see some information about your resources.
Now one of the things to note logical ID refers to these attributes that are within the template
file.
Whereas the physical ID actually represents the resources outside of the template file.
So anything like the Rand you can get IP addresses here sometimes URLs that kind of thing if you
look on the outputs we've got the Web site url.
So let's quickly just click on this link and see what happens and sure enough it works.
So we've got our wordpress installation ready to log in and create our sites.
So that's really it.
But I want to show you the other things that are being created so let's have a look into instances here.
And so we've got our instance.
This is the one that was just created.
We've then got the security groups.
So we've got a couple of security groups one for the web server one for the database server and we've
got a load balancer so that's being created and a target group and then we've got our launch configuration
and Auto Scaling group.
And then we've also, if we go over to order, yes we should also have an RDS database so the database
backend for this wordpress installation is actually going to be this database instance
so we've automated the entire installation.
We've set it up and through the file it's not just installed WordPress but it's configured the
the wordpress installation to speak to the database backend.
And so the whole thing has been automated so that's really really cool.
Now what we want to do now we've finished with this one but we're not going to delete it yet.
What I want to do is just show you a couple of other things about CloudFormation.
If we head back to stack info here one of the things you can see here is drift status and it says not
checked.
And what we can do is you can click here and say detect drift.
And what this does is it checks that your infrastructure is built according to your template.
So you've built your input for structure based on this template file here.
So if anything's changed then it will pick that up and report it back to you.
Now to go in that now it says drift status is in sync.
So that's great.
Let's head over to it.
Let's head over to EC2 and find security grapes.
And what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go in and... let's in fact, let's go into this one.
And what I'm going to do is I'm just going to remove one of these rules so let's remove this as the
site rule.
So what we've done now is we've changed the security group and this security group was built using the
template file.
So the definition of the security group and how that security group should be configured is different
in the template file than it is now actually is here.
So let's go back and click on detect drift and straight away we have address status it says "drifted".
And we can go up to here and we can view drift results and it's just refresh this page and sure enough
down here we can see that the web server security group has been modified so this is a really good way
to make sure that your infrastructure is configured according to the way that you need it to be.
And for instance you know somebody has changed one of those security groups.
They might have added a port in that they shouldn't do or protocol or they might have changed the configuration
in a way that could lead to instability, could lead to performance problems, could lead to security problems.
So that's why CloudFormation is a good tool for securely and consistently deploying infrastructure and
you'll sometimes see exam questions that refer to that.
So they might say that a team of developers need to find a way to repeatedly build infrastructure. Maybe
they're building the same sort of infrastructure for different clients or something like that, and they
need to be able do it efficiently but also securely, and repeatably without having any error.
So that's where things like CloudFormation can be really really useful.
The other thing we want to exploit are change sets.
So what a change that is is it's a way of looking at the changes that you want to make to your stack
before you actually make them.
So I'll show you what that means.
We'll click on Create Change there and we're going to use the current template and click on Next.
But what we're going to do is we're going to change the DB class to t2 small and that's all in a day
and it looks just like you're gone through the wizard at the beginning with first deploying a stack
so go through and create the change sets and it tells us here that a change is a preview of how this stack
will be configured before creating the stack which allows you to examine various configurations before
executing the change set.
So what we're going to do is just create this change set and you can give it a name and you can set
a description and we can see what is going to be modified so it shows us that the DB instance is going
to be modified. Not sure why the launch config is going to be modified..
But anyway the DB instance is what we're looking at here.
And if you go over to JSON changes you'll then see the code that is being modified and you can see
in here that the DB instance is going to be changed so what we can then do is you can then choose to
delete or execute your change set.
So let's just click on execute and now we can see that the same stack is being updated
and let's head over to RDS
and have a look at our database and we can see that our database is now in the state of modifying.
So it's now going to be shut down so that it can change from a t2 micro to a t2 small.
So that took a few minutes and we can now see that the database is modified to a t2 small so let's
head back to CloudFormation and this has had a refresh and it's still showing it's in progress.
I think there was still some stuff outstanding and we'll actually have to wait a few minutes until the
stack is completed before we can then go and delete asked at the stack updates have completed now and
we're done for this lab.
So all I'm going to do is go in and click delete and delete stack.
Now you want to keep an eye on this because you will find sometimes that CloudFormation doesn't successfully
delete your resources and it's usually quite easy to have a look in the events and work out what's going
on sometimes it might be that a security group can be deleted.
And I found for instance earlier that my security group couldn't be deleted because there was a network
interface that had been looked like it had been detached but not deleted.
So I had to delete the network interface manually in EC2 and then go and delete the security group
and then everything else just was it was deleted automatically by CloudFormation.
So just go and make sure that all your resources are properly terminated and delete it and make sure
that you don't end up with any charges.