Guns covered DNS record types.
Now the list on the left hand side of the slide is the list of supported DNS records in round free.
So I'm not gonna cover all of these but a few of the key ones and a record just resolves the hostname
to an IP address and a record does the same but it returns an IP vs 6 address a C name is a canonical
name record and that returns.
That means that you resolve one domain name to another domain name and an alias is a similar is very
similar to a C name but it's around 50 free specific record that has some extra capabilities which we
will cover in more detail.
So a few of the others say you'll recognize mail exchange records and pointers which basically the reverse.
They resolve IP addresses back to host names and we all talk about the start of authority and just just
be familiar with this list of records for the exam because occasionally something might come up on the
exam that asks what are supported record type is or you might be us so eliminate an answer because you
know.
So let's go in to see name and Alias and a bit more detail because this is definitely something that
comes up in exam questions.
There's more differences to see names and aliases than in this table but these are some of the key ones
that you need to know.
So one thing is round 53 charges you fancy name records whereas aliases.
There is no charge.
Another one is that you can't create a C name recall that the top note of a DNS namespace.
So this is also known as the zone Apex record.
So if you take the domain example dot com example dot com is the DNS root namespace or the zone apex.
So you can't create a C name record for example dot com but you can create one for apps dot example
dot com something like that.
So that's no longer the zone Apex because it's a subdomain with alias records you can do that so you
can say example dot com and you can resolve that using an alias record to a an easy to instance or a
load balancer or something like that so another one is see names can be used outside of around 50 free
so you can actually resolve to records that are hosted anywhere else.
So remember A C name resolves to another hostname so that it needs to in turn be resolved to an IP address
so that you can connect to that resource.
So what it's saying is that with a C name you can point to another domain name that's in another DNS
server outside of around 50 free.
You can't do that with alias records which are actually designed to point to cloud front distributions
beanstalk environments low balances S3 Buckets and so on.
So it's a bit more limited but it's also very powerful within a W.S. so let's just have a look in the
console and I'm going to go into my hosting zone.
And so this is what we're talking about and here we have named server records and start of authority
records by default.
And then we can go and create our own records.
And this is the dropdown where you can choose the type of record that you want to create a record for.
So for instance you can create an A record now an alias is another capability of record so you choose
a record and then you choose alias and then you find your target which could be a light balancer or
a cloud phone distribution.
You could also choose C name if you do that then you can use an alias but you have to resolve to another
C name the record type has to match.
So very simple.
You then just need to enter the value.
So in the case of an alias you choose your target.
In the case of a regular DNS record you choose the value.
So you'd put the IP address of the server in here.
You can then choose the TTL.
The default is five minutes free hundred seconds and you can change that.
So that's the time to live.
And that means that when you query around 50 free and it returns an answer the answer contains a TTL.
And that tells the cash on your machine how long to store that record for.
And so you can change that and if you change it to a lower value say 60 seconds it means you're going
to have to query Rhapsody free more regularly.
So once every minute rather than once every five minutes.
So that means more traffic but it also means if your records are changing then you pick up those changes
more quickly whereas if you have it set to a day then if you change your DNS record whoever is cached
the previous the old record in there or the response from the old record in their browser or on their
machine or in your application or wherever it's stored it's not going to change now for a day.
So they're not going to be able to connect to your service anymore.
So you definitely need to consider carefully what you set the TTL value to now you'll say down here
routing policies and we're going to cover each of these in detail in the section.
So you have these different types of routing policies where you can for instance file over between primary
and secondary records.
So lots of intelligence there so that's it for this lab.
Just wanted to cover DNS record types and as a reminder make sure you know the differences between C
name and Alias records and there are more differences than in this list.
So look it up there's some great information in the FAA Qs.