Hi, guys, in this lesson, we're going to create a free two accounts on IWC.
So let's first clarify what it is you're going to need.
Firstly, you're going to need a credit card for setting up the account and paying any bills.
Now it is a free tier account, but you always need to have a billing method, so you have to have a
credit card assigned to the accounts.
Now we are going to try and make sure that you don't run up any bills, so it's important to follow
my instructions.
One of the things we'll do is create a billing alarm so that if you do forget to terminate an instance
or you leave something running, you shouldn't have done.
Then you'll get a warning to let you know that you might exceed your threshold so you can keep that
threshold very low.
You'll also need a unique email address for this account, so an email address that hasn't been used
with any other IWC accounts.
Now check if you can use a dynamic alias with an existing email address.
If you already have other IWC accounts, say, for example, if your email address is John at gmail.com,
you can use John Plus and then put in some kind of alias for your accounts at gmail.com and it'll still
come to your email inbox.
Then when you have another account, you can have John Plus account alias two at gmail.com.
Now, Gmail does support dynamic aliases.
You'll just have to check if you're using a different email provider, whether they do as well.
But it's a good way of getting around, having to set up multiple email accounts.
You'll also need to create your own account, name an alias, and you'll see how to do this shortly.
Lastly, you will need a phone to receive an SMS verification code.
That's part of the process of opening the account.
So that's it, really.
Let's go over to a web browser and we're going to start setting up our free tier accounts.
I mean, Google here and I'm just going to search for eight U.S. free tier.
And the very first result here, IWC Free two is what I want.
This page helps you understand what a free tier account is and what you can use in a free tier account.
So, for example, there's always free, there's 12 months free and there's free trials.
Now, if you scroll down a bit, you'll see, for example, you get 12 months free of Amazon EC2, and
the limitation on that is 750 hours a month.
And you've got to choose the right type of EC2 instance.
Easy two is where you're running.
Virtual servers in the cloud is something you're going to learn very early on.
In this course, with as free, you get five gigabytes of storage space and with the island's database
service again, 750 fifty hours a month as long as you choose the right type of database.
Now what we can do is scroll back up to the top and choose Create a free account on this page.
Choose this button down here that says Create a new AWG account.
You'll then need to supply your unique email address.
You'll need to supply a password, confirm the password and then choose an account name.
The account name can be changed later on, as well as the alias we're going to use to log in.
So let's continue to step two for the first question How do you plan to use IWC?
Just choose personal.
You'll then need to supply your name, your phone number, your country or region address and then accept
the terms and conditions and continue to the next step.
Next, you need to supply your billing information, so enter your credit card number, expiration date
your card holders name and confirm your contacts, address and then continue to step four.
You may be asked to confirm your identity.
So again, you'll need to enter your phone number.
Answer the security check and then get it to send you an SMS and enter the code that you're sent.
I've answered my verification code and I'm going to click on Continue.
And then for support plan in this case will choose the basic support.
So that's completely free and only really gives you help if you have a council billing issues.
And then we just collect complete sign up.
And that's it, we can now go to the IWC management console, so let's click on the button in the middle
of the screen here.
And it's going to ask us for our account's I.D. or our accounts alias.
Now at this point, we haven't specified an account alias, and I don't even know what the accounts
ideas yet for this account.
We also don't have a username because this is an IAM username.
What we do have is the root user email, so we have to choose sign in using root user email supply the
email address you just signed up with.
Enter your password and click on Sign In, and that's it.
We are now logged in to the IWC management console and that's all I wanted to cover in this lesson.
And the next lesson, we're going to configure a few attributes of our accounts.
So make sure you stay signed in.