Before we go any deeper into Amazon S3
I wanted to just talk a little more about access methods.
So as we've already learned Amazon S3 is a public service and you access it using a public endpoint.
So the U.R.L. is a publicly resolvable you URL.
And what that actually means is if you're in a VPC which is obviously a private environment and you
want to connect to S3 you have to go out to the Internet.
So there would be a Internet gateway and you'd need to go through that Internet gateway in order to
access the public service.
And that's the same for any public services.
So the way around that if you don't want to go over the public Internet and there could be several reasons
for that you might want to use an endpoint.
And we talked about these in the VPC section of the course and specifically we're talking about S3
Gateway endpoints and what this means is that your instances in your private instances then don't need
to have any kind of internet connectivity enabled for them.
They can connect directly to the Gateway endpoint which allows them access to S3 without having
to use the Internet.
So what I've done here is I've just created a lab where we're going to come in through SSH each into
a public EC2 instance.
From there we're going to jump across to a private instance which doesn't have any internet connectivity
and we're going to access as free through a gateway endpoint.
And the other piece to this is that what you'll see is when we create a gateway endpoint route table
entry is created and it looks like this has got nine days and then it has some some more information
about IP ranges
and then a target which is the actual Gateway endpoint itself.
So let's head over to the console.
And the first thing I'm going to do is we're just going to head over to see to and I've got 2 instances
one is in a public subnet and we're going to SSH into this one.
In fact we're going to SSH with the -A so that I can send my key across and be able to authenticate
across to the private instance.
So we come back now and we take the IP address of the private instance
so we're now in the private instance.
And I can do a I can show you that I don't have Internet connectivity I can ping Google and I do have
a security group which would allow ICMP and that's not working.
And then I could do an AWS S3 at last so I'm going to specify the region just to be consistent
because you do need this with the gateway endpoint
so I've looked to run that command as you can see it's kind of timed out.
So it doesn't actually have a path to S3 at this stage.
So we can just kill that off and let's go back to the console and get this working so we had to VPC
and we're going to go down to end points and create an endpoint.
We can then go down to here where you see the S3 service and as a gateway type of interface types
those a few which are gateway types and this is where a gateway is different to an interface in that
it's the one where you do need to update the route table though it does let you do that for you so we
select the VPC and we have to choose the round table.
I know this route table which is not the main route table is the one that's associated with my private
subnets.
So that's the one I want and I'm going to click on Create.
So now we can head over it and round tables and I'm going to select my private routes table and if I
go into routes there's nothing there but there will be seen and sometimes it takes a couple of minutes.
So I'm just going to pause the video until that comes up so I took a few minutes but we now have this
entry at the bottom of the screen here in our route table which is pointing to our endpoint.
So what we can do now is we head back over to the console and we're just gonna rerun that command which
should list the buckets in the AWS S3 account
so that's great that's proved that we can access S3 from an instance that's in a private subnet which
doesn't have any access to the Internet so we know that rather than going to the public namespace for
S3 it's actually being routed internally on the private secure backbone into the S3 service.