In this lesson, we're going to have a look at access control lists on Amazon S3 and the S3 console.
I'm going to click on my Buckethead DCT cloud storage and under permissions, we can see the access
control list just a bit further down here.
Now, as you can see, there's a warning telling me I can't actually enable public access because it's
disabled at the bucket level.
So the first thing I want to do because what I want to do as an exercise in this lesson is actually
enable public access for my objects.
So what I'll first need to do is unlock public access.
Now let's just check the behavior at this stage.
Let's go to one of our objects.
Copy the URL and then put it into a browser window.
And I get an access denied message and that's completely expected.
So what I need to do is go back up to my bucket level here.
Choose permissions, click on edits under block public access and d select this option.
Click on Save and then confirm.
So now it's been confirmed if we just scroll down to Access Control List and let's edit the access control
list.
Now, note that there's a few different options here for the grantees, so a grantee is either the bucket
owner, everyone or authenticated users.
So anyone with an IWC account who has authenticated or the free lock delivery great for storing log
files.
So those are the only options and then we have list and read and so on.
So there's a few permissions and a few options for grants.
It's not hugely powerful, like a bucket policy or an identity and access management policy.
Now this is the ACL at the bucket level.
Remember, there's also an ACL at the object level, so I actually don't need to enable list access
to my bucket to enable direct access to my object.
So in fact, I'm going to leave this as it is.
Let's click on objects.
Choose one of my objects.
Go to permissions and then edit here.
Here I can enable read access for everyone.
That's public access for my objects.
I have to click on a checkbox here to understand what the impact is of this change and then click on
Save.
Now, let's go back and refresh our screen, this time I can see the object, so it's now public.
Now another way you can achieve the same outcome is you can select an object, go to actions and make
public.
Click on Make Public.
And that's done.
So now if I go into this object, what you'll be able to see under the Permissions tab is that we've
given Reed access exactly the same thing.
So just as with the other file, we should now be able to access this one and we can see the image.
So that's how you work with ACLs.
Now let's just go back up to our bucket level and permissions.
And another thing which is worth noting is the cross accounts access.
So let's click on Edit.
And at the bottom, you can see access for other IWC accounts, this is a common use case for using
an ACL.
In this case, you can add the guarantee and you can enter the canonical I.D., which is essentially
a form of the account's I.D., and then give some basic permissions to anyone within that account.
So that's all I want to show you for this lesson.
One thing I am going to do is just go back up and put the block public access back on again.
And now the configuration of our pocket is back to the way it was at the beginning of the lesson.