Guys, I told you before that there are two different types of Q the standard Q and the FIFA.
Q There's also something called a dead letter.
Q.
Now this isn't actually a type of.
Q So there are only two types, but it's actually a configuration that you apply to either a stand a
Q or FIFA Q to configure it for a certain purpose.
So what is that purpose?
Well, we have our website here and it's putting messages onto a Q and then we have our consumers in
the application to and they're processing those messages.
So they're polling the Q and then they're receiving the message.
Now they may occasionally not process that message successfully.
And in that case, we can specify a max receive count.
So that's the maximum number of times a consumer can receive an individual message.
And if that's exceeded, we can configure a dead letter.
Q So that that message then gets put into the dead letter.
Q And we'll do that so that we can then analyze what happened.
So in this case, Message four has failed to be processed and therefore it gets moved into the dead
letter.
Q So a dead letter.
Q is used for handling message failure.
And it lets you set aside and isolate messages that aren't processed correctly so that you can then
analyze why that happened.
So it's not actually a cute time.
It's a standard or FIFO queue that specified as a dead letter.
Q In the configuration of another queue.
So, for instance, we have our standard queue and in our standard queue we can set what's called a
drive policy.
And then we can specify another cue called middle cue and specify the number of times that any message
in my standard cue can be received before it gets pushed into the dead letter.
Q So let's go over to the console and have a look at how this works.
And back in the console and what I'm going to do is create a new queue and I'm going to call that my
DL.
Q And just choose quick.
Right.
Q And then I'm now going to go into my stand.
Q And I'm going to go configure Q.
And specify a drive policy, and I'm going to tell it to use my DL cue and I'm going to say maximum
receives is free and that's click save changes.
So now let's go to our standard queue and send a couple of messages.
So I'm going to send a text message and then I'm going to send another one test, too, and then click
close.
So now we have two messages in our queue.
I'm going to poll for those messages and now I've received them once so you can see there's a receive
count of one.
I'm going to click stop and then start again.
And now I've received it twice and I'm going to click stop and start again.
And now I've received it a third time.
So what's going to happen now?
Let's say we click on Stop and start and this time they're gone.
So what's happened is those messages have disappeared from our standard queue and they've gone into
the DL queue.
So the dead letter.
Q So just to recap, messages are moved to the dead letter queue when they receive count for message
exceeds the max receive count for the Q and also a dead letter.
Q should not be used to stand accused when your application will keep retrying transmission and they
also shouldn't be used with FIFO queues if you need to maintain the order of messages because it will
break that first in first hour order.
So that's it for dead letter queues.
And in the next lesson, we're going to talk about delay queues.