Hi guys.
This is a relatively short lap to cover transit gateways so we've got a slide up here which is from
the previous lab where we're talking about VPC pairing.
And you'll remember that pairing connections are one to one relationships between pieces.
So in this case where we have free VPC is we actually have to have a pairing connection between each
VPC.
So here we've got a VPC or between each VPC pair.
So the top left and the bottom have to have a VPC pairing connection the top two have to have one and
the top right in the bottom VPC you need to have a connection so to connect these VPC you need free
VPC parent connections.
So obviously this can get quite complicated and cumbersome when you have a lot of these pieces.
And that's where transit Gateway comes in.
So I've just got the IWM transit Gateway web page open here and it just tells us that transit Gateway
is a service that enables customers to connect VPC pieces and on premises networks to a single gateway.
So that's the key thing.
It's not just about BPC but it's also about on premise networks
and it goes on to say we're very WS transit Gateway you only have to create and manage a single connection
from the central gateway into each VPC on premises datacenter or remote office across your network.
So it acts as a hub that controls how traffic is routed among the networks which acolytes spike.
So it's a hub and spoke topology now if we just go down the page here we've got this kind of before
and after image where without transit gateway on the left here and we can see just what we had in that
slide we've got a VPC here one here and here and here and to connect all those four together you have
to have all these different peering connections and then you've got a VPN connection from a customer
Gateway which is a VPN connection from a customer site.
And on premise network and so on and so that that's already looking quite complicated and that's only
a few pieces in a couple of office connections.
So on the right hand side here we've got the transit Gateway and it acts as the hub and then you have
the spokes which are direct connect gateways and VPC and VPN connections so you can interconnect all
of these things with transit gateway in the middle so really it's quite a new service.
It was released around November 18 and it takes about six months for new releases to actually make it
on to the exam.
So we should I mean June late June now so I'm expecting to see some questions popping up now if not
in the near future on transit gateway.
Now let's just head over to the console and you can find it in the VPC dashboard.
Head to the bottom.
You've got transit gateways and you can select create transit gateway.
Now another right one now because it does require some things like a BGP ISDN which I don't have and
so I'm just going to sort of show you through the console here What what where to find this information
so you can come in here and this is where you create a transit Gateway.
You then have transit Gateway attachments.
So this is how you connect to your hub your transit Gateway hub.
And then there are round tables which are curated so you can always go up and hit the question mark
to get more information.
And this there's lots of stuff on the obvious Web site.
So have a look over the FAA queues.
Have a look over the about pages here and just try and understand what the use cases are for transit
gateway.