My guys in this lab were going to go into the console and have a quick look at Amazon EMR.
Now EMR does feature on the exam.
However usually it's doesn't come up very often and when it does the questions are typically quite basic
so you won't need to go into all the details.
There's a lot of open source technologies that are associated with them and you don't really need to
know the ins and outs of all of those.
You just need to know what it is what it's used for and a few key facts which may be tested on in the
exam.
So what is Amazon EMR.
Well it's the leading cloud native Big Data platform so we've all heard of big data and what this does
is it allows you to process vast amounts of data at pretty much any scale.
So it's highly elastic.
It can scale to thousands of nodes and it uses or you use open source tools with it such as Apache Spark
Apache hive H base flank Presto all these open source tools that you may or may not have heard of but
those are the tools that you would use to analyze data on Amazon EMR. EMR uses the concepts of clusters
and in each cluster you have one master and then a number of core nodes and the core nodes do the processing.
You can have up to thousands of core nodes and you always have the one master per cluster and you also
have the option of scaling by adding additional clusters so you can even resize your cluster or you
can add additional clusters.
Now the way that you provision EMR is through two methods. Either you use a cluster and then you have the
options of core Hadoop each base Presto or SPARC or you create a step execution we'll see this in the
console and in this case you have a few different options.
One of the things often comes up in the exam is root access to the cluster instances.
So these instances are based on EC2 so your nodes are all easy to nodes and you have full root access
to those nodes.
So that's very important for some of the tools the open source tools that you would use with EMR data
comes from a number of sources so you can use S3, Glacier, redshift, dynamoDB, RDS or the Hadoop file system
HDFS. Typically the nodes are provisioned with instance stores if you might remember from the section
of course where we cover EBS and you may remember that instance stores are ephemeral storage so that
means the data is lost when you shut down your instance. Not when you reboot it, but when you shut it
down so you can't store data long term but it's very high performance which is why it's really useful
for analytics but you can also attach EBS volumes. Now typically EBS volumes have persistent data however
with EMR when you shut down your clusters you do lose it.
So the data is actually scrubbed from the EBS volume.
You have an option with EMR to not just load data but to access data directly in S3.
So you could have multiple clusters actually pointing to the same S3 Buckets and analyzing the same
data.
Alternatively you can load data in through one of these services and you can use data pipeline.
Another AWS service to help you migrate data.
So let's head into the console and we're just going to provision and EMR cluster. So I'm in the AWS management
console.
I'm going to go to services, analytics, EMR.
So on the splash screen we just want to go and create a cluster.
And I'm just going to leave the default name.
We can say that it comes up with a default location for logging and then we have these two options.
So the cluster.
And it tells us we have cluster EMR creates a cluster with a set of specified applications so these
are the applications core Hadoop.
Each base Presto or spark.
So you need to choose one of these options.
I'm just going to leave it on core Hadoop alternatively you step execution and in this case a cluster
is still created but the steps are executed and then the cluster is terminated once they're complete.
So if you two step execution you have these options here streaming program, pick SPARC application
or custom jar and then you have to fill out a few of those details depending which one you choose.
So let's go back to a cluster.
We're going to leave it selected as core Hadoop.
We're going to leave it on the latest release of EMR and then you get to choose your instance size.
Now note that you have one master and two core nodes.
If I just up this amount you'll notice that you still have one master and they have two hundred ninety
nine core nodes.
So wherever you include there's always gonna be one master.
You can even put that at 3000 and it's still just going to add core nodes.
So we'll leave that it three and let's go and choose the smallest instance so we can reduce our costs.
And in this case are going to see one medium.
Again this is not a free to air incident so be careful.
I understand that you will incur some costs if you run this instance and because this is easy too and
we have the option of actually accessing it via route we can choose our keeper and you could then choose
a role for EMR or if you like as well.
We're just going to leave this on default and we're going to choose create cluster and so interestingly
I got a message terminated of errors and in this case it says the instance type C one medium is not
supported.
So let's go back.
I'm just going to try and create a cluster again and this time I'm just going to choose a different
cluster.
Let's try a C three extra large of compute optimized instance, still and leave the other settings as
defaults and choose create cluster.
I'm going to need to change the name on here.
So just call my cluster 2 and create the cluster
don't get to choose your key pair.
So my cluster's in the starting state and we don't need to wait for this to complete because we're not
actually going to be doing any work on the actual cluster itself but we're just going to have a look
around and see what's what.
So what I've done is I've opened up the east to management console as well because I want you to see
that we now have these free instances.
So clearly this is not like one of those managed services where you don't see the underlying infrastructure
you can access this infrastructure.
Now if you do want to access it you don't need to think about the security groups.
Let's have a look at one of these instances and go to actions networking and change security groups
and we can see that there's a couple of groups here that were created automatically for us.
So we've got the elastic map produced slightly so we know that this must be a slave no because this
was selected and then we had the elastic map reduce master.
So that will be for the master node obviously.
So let's look at the next one and try and work out which ones to master so we can see that this one
is the master because it's using this security group.
Now let's go down to security groups and just see what the rules are so we can see some rules here for
inbound access to the slaves and this all DCP and UDP rules and they come from different security groups
and we can also see ICMP rules to allow the ICMP protocol to work for communication and then if we go
to the master we can also see some rules here that are locked down to specific security groups and then
it's a bunch of IP addresses here which are Amazon IP addresses that allow the cluster manager to communicate
with the master node.
So one of the things that's missing is Port 22.
If we did want to connect into these instances we would need to have port 20 to say let's just add an
additional security group to our slave instance.
So we'll go about we've got two slave instances I'm just gonna choose one of them go to networking change
security groups and I'll just add in web access.
Let's now head over to a command line with the IP address of the server copy to our clipboard.
So I'm at the command line.
Let's SSH.
Into this instance
and sure enough we're logged in and we can see EMR written on the screen in big letters here.
So we know we have access to log in and work on this server.
Let's head back to the console and have a look at a few more features of EMR some back in the AWS console
for EMR.
Let's just refresh waiting cluster ready so this cluster is now ready to perform operations on its actually
start loading some data and running some analytics.
And you can see some information about the master and the core nodes.
You can choose to view the cluster details and look at the applications that are being used.
You have lots of monitoring information here from cloud watch and the hardware you can now see the instances
that are running so gives you a bit of a breakdown and you could go in here then and actually resigns
these instances so you can go in and choose the amount of instances that you want to run.
You then also have events can see what's going on.
And you also have steps.
So here you can add additional steps now a step is a programmatic task for performing a process on the
data.
So if you wanted to count the words in your data or perform an operation to modify data you can add
a step to perform that operation under security configurations you can go in and create a security configuration
you can enable encryption at rest encryption in transit authentication using cobras and you can also
use IAM rules for the EMR file system the EMR file system is what is use when you want to access data
directly from S3 just going to cancel on there under VPC subnets.
This is where you can configure your subnets so that you can add an S3 endpoint or access to S3 or net
instance.
So your instances are running in subnets within your VPC.
You may have noticed in the diagram that all of our clusters here are running in a single availability
zone.
Now you can run them across different availability zones but all the nodes of your cluster will be within
one availability zone.
So if you actually want your EMR instances to be able to access data on a S3 you need to add your
S3 endpoint to that subnet.
And if you want them to access public AWS service endpoints then you need to enter a NAT device and
you'll see it here.
If you actually have one present.
So for these subnets we don't have that but we're not trying to enable any outbound access at this stage
anyway so we'll give that a miss.
Again we can see events across all our clusters under notebooks you can create multi-user notebooks
and these are used by data scientists analysts and developers to prepare and visualize data and also
collaborate with their peers.
So you can head in here and you can create your notebook and specify your cluster your security groups
and the location where the files for this notebook are actually stored so that's just a very quick overview
of EMR.
What we're going to do is we're just going to terminate this cluster
and don't forget to do this if you have run it up because remember these are not free tier so you
will pay something for running these instances.
And if I were you I'd make sure that once this is terminated just go into your instances and
just make sure that nothing is running that everything's gone.