So we're back in EC2 and I'm actually going to launch another instance and what I'm gonna do this
time it's going to be the same configuration apart from we're not going to add that extra volume as
part of the launch so we're going to stick to the same Availability Zones, keep clicking next go through.
I should change my security group because it keeps created at launch ones and then we've got
to review and launch. That's been a couple of minutes
It's still initializing but let's go down to EBS volumes and so we have our additional volume that we
left from before and that's available which means that you can attach it to an instance.
So what we're going to do is go here and we'll click on attach volume and then it will actually come
up with the instance ID obviously if you've got a lot of instances you need to search by instance
I.D. but in this case we can easily select it from the list and we're going to just leave the default
device mapping here and click on attach.
So while that same process let's head over to the command line and I'm going to secure shell into
this Linux instance
and say I'm going to run the command LSP L K and we can see that that additional volume has been attached.
So I'm just going to switch the root user and I'm gonna run the command file DASH Yes and then Dev x
d f and so this time we can see that there's already a file system because we created it on the instance
in the last lab and I'm going to do the same thing as before I'm just going to do I can get rid of the
pseudo again and get rid of the do and make directory slash data and then we're going to mount slash
Dev slash X VDI F to the slash data directory.
And now that's changed to slash data and run ls and sure enough there's our files so we've now just
mounted the same EBS volume to a different instance but we have actually done that within the same availability
zone and that's all we're going to do in this lab we can come back now and just terminate this instance.
And then what I'm gonna do in the next lab is show you how you can then take used the snapshot that
we created before to actually create an API volume in a different availability zone and attach that
to another instance.