Hi guys it's time to get started with AWS Elastic Beanstalk.
So as I mentioned to you at the beginning of the section in the overview lesson Elastic beanstalk is
a platform as a service.
Now what that means is that developers can take their code and they can basically put it on top of the
platform and the code just starts running.
Okay.
So they don't have to...
They don't have to worry about any of the stuff that's underneath their code.
They have to worry about their code.
Put it on the platform. Obviously, choose the right settings for the platform which will go over now but
the actual platform is provisioned for them, and it's run for them.
So it's very very easy way to get your code running.
Now what we're going to do now is we're going to create a couple of environments within Elastic Beanstalk.
It's just gonna be very simple stuff I'm just gonna show you around so you're familiar with the console
will create a couple of environments and then in the next lab where you're going to then take it to
the next level we're going to actually package our own code.
We're going to set up a HA wordpress with Elastic Beanstalk and RDS as the back end.
So that should be a lot of fun.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to just choose get started.
We're going to put in a name.
I'm just going to call this simple Node.js
in there and then we can choose our platform.
So you need to know for the exam what the support platform options are.
So you have these generic container options up here Docker or multi container Docker.
You then have the pre configured and these are the supported environments and then you have the pre-K
and figure Docker glass which go in Python.
So make sure you know what the supported options are for this option we're going to choose
Node.js and we're going to just leave application sample application selected.
Now normally this is where you would upload your code but we're not going to do that in this lab we're
gonna do in the next lab.
So we just choose sample application and choose create application.
Now you'll notice there's an option to configure more options we're going to do that later on in this
lab but defaults are okay for this option.
So you can see now that we have the environ being created and is getting a hostname or excuse me it's
getting the bucket name for where it's going to store some information in S3.
And I want to show you a couple of things that are going on in the background.
So let's go to CloudFormation and let's also open S3 and let's also open EC2. So in CloudFormation
we can see we have a create in progress.
So what this means is that Elastic Beanstalk is leveraging CloudFormation in order to build out the
infrastructure for your application.
So if you go into events you'll then see what's happening we've got an auto scaling group being created
and see an elastic IP is being created and a launch configuration and so on... security groups all that
kind of stuff.
So that's all happening and you can see the resources that are being created here.
If we go to S3. This is the bucket that's being created in fact this one already existed because I've
created some environments previously but it does have a bucket which you can then store information
in and there's just a couple other objects in there.
If we then go to EC2 and let's see what's happening now the one at the top is an environment which
I already have and this one here is our simple Node.js environment that's just been launched so we can
see that's initializing we come down to auto scaling groups and we can see that it's being launched
through an auto scaling group. That gives us that redundancy that we know if
the instance goes down for some reason we can have a new instance launched.
So all that's going on let's go back to our create environment and we can see this is still happening
Here we go we've got some more options coming up now we can see the elastic IP that's
being created we can see that the instance has been added to the environments and that just took a few
minutes and we can now say that the environment has been successfully launched.
So what we can do now is let's go back up to our application and we can see the application running
here and we can choose this URL and what it does is it loads this page with some information we can
see the health status we can see some information events here we can see the version that's being run
you could actually upload some code to here if you'd like and we can also open this link here and a
new tab and this just gives us a sort of splash screen for Node.js.
So it's just telling us that congratulations your first beanstalk Node.js application is now running
on your dedicated environment in the AWS cloud.
So that's great.
That's that's just running and that was very very simple.
Now of course you can imagine if you've got your application packaged or you to done is instead of choosing
sample application you to just uploaded your zip or WAR file.
And right now you'd be seeing your application running.
So you didn't have to worry about any of that underlying infrastructure provisioning it was all done
for you.
So that's really the key use case and benefit of elastic beanstalk.
Let's go back to our environment here.
Let's now go up to all applications and we can see the only application we have is a simple Node.js application.
So what we can now do is create environment.
Now if you do this what you're doing is you're creating additional nodes as part of this application.
So let's have a look at what happens here.
We can choose create environment and we get two options you get to choose one tier or another web server
or worker.
So the web server is your HTTP Web site running over port 80 and your worker is your specialized
application running background processing.
And the message buses between your web server environment and your worker environment is SQS.
So what we want to do for now I'm just going to add a web server environment that's just look at how
this is done and you can put in a domain name here and check the availability and again you have these
options to choose your code or your sample application.
You could then configure more options we'll do that in a second or you can just create environment.
Let's just choose create environment what we're gonna do is just choose Node.js again, choose
a different one as choose Java so we can see if that will run in parallel within the same application
and we just choose create environment.
So that's starting up.
Let's head over it's CloudFormation and just gonna give this a refresh and you can see that we now
have a new create in progress and if we head over to events we've got a lot of similar stuff happening
as we did before.
Let's just have a look at the outputs from our previous one there were no outputs actually.
That's interesting.
So we can go to resources and we could see these auto scaling group and the elastic IP being created
and that's just going to take a few minutes to complete.
So that just took a few minutes and automatically took me to this screen and that environment is now
running.
So let's go back up to our application here.
So with all applications of a simple Node.js and you can see we now have these two environments running
within a single application.
So I wanted to show you that relationship where you have your applications and then within it you have
these environments.
So this is our new one if we click on this link it takes us back here and then we could open this in
a new tab and we now have this.
Congratulations.
This message which looks very similar to before but this is running on Java rather than
Node.js
So that's what that looks like.
Let's go to EC2 and let's just give this a refresh and you can see now that we have two auto scaling
groups one of the things to note here is because this is a good use case for auto scaling.
We have a desired min and a max of one.
And what that means is a good way of making sure that your instance runs.
So you might do this you might have a single instance that runs an application on its own.
It's not part of any HA architecture but you just need to make sure that it runs.
So what you can do with this is just ensure that if that instance goes down you get no one back up again.
So you know you don't actually pay for auto scaling you only pay for the resources you create so it's
a great way of ensuring that your instance is always going to be available. If we go back to CloudFormation
we can see both our stacks are complete.
So that's great.
Now let's go back up to the all applications level I want to show you how to create a new application.
So in this case you hit the create new application button right up here on the right hand corner so
let's call this one custom PHP and click on Create and we now get the option to create some environments.
So let's create an environment and then choose web server.
Click on select and I'm going to choose pre configured I'm going to go down to PHP and I'm going
to create a sample application but I'm just going to configure some some of these options now.
So that's the way I'm going to customize this application.
So as you can see you can go through each of these areas here and choose modify.
So for instance we can go into instances modify and we could change it from a t2 micro to t2 small
for instance and we can select the security groups we want it to be part of.
So I'm going to put it in my web access security group we can choose to change from a single instance
to a load balanced environment
and we can select which ones of these availability zones to use.
In this case it's just set to any well we can choose any one.
Let's just leave it on any for now and then you can set up your metrics and statistics and so on.
We're not gonna create a load balancer right now but you can do that and you can see options for
how updates and deployments are configured the security keys.
So if you want to be able to SSH into your instance you're going to need to choose your EC2 key pair.
So you do actually have access to the underlying resources where that Elastic Beanstalk creates.
It's not like ECS for instance where with Fargo
you don't actually see the underlying resources, you can't connect to them.
In this case you can.
You can SSH into your instance but it won't have the key pair. If you want to use a key pair to SSH
into your instance you're going to need to select your key pair here and you could update the instance
profile if you wanted to as well.
So let's just save that option and we could then choose to put it in a VPC so this is an important one.
You could choose a custom VPC let's put it into my custom VPC where my public 2A subnet
and you could add a database here as well.
So we haven't got any code that's gonna use a database in this instance but you could put your database
here and you can choose one of these options.
So let's just cancel out that one and you can use tags and notifications.
Let's just choose create environment
and again it's going to go through exactly the same process.
Using CloudFormation to build out our environment and it looks like that environment is pretty much
there.
Let's go to instances and we can see that we now have our custom PHP environment running here as well
so we've got all these three environments.
Just wanted to show you in back in S3 if you go to this elastic beanstalk bucket which is being
created for us and then you go to resources and choose environments you can then see these three different
folders and each of these corresponds to one of the environments that we've just created and if you
go inside you can see got runtime and then you've got some sub folders and if you go in you'll then
find these files so this is the way the elastic beanstalk can store your code.
We have a looking CloudFormation we can see you've got all these three stacks complete and this is almost
there.
What I'm going to do now is I'm just gonna go up to my environments and I'm going to delete my simple
Node.js application and you just need to copy the name of the application and paste it in and confirm
and I'm gonna do the same with this one as well and if we head back over to CloudFormation now we should
see all of these delays in progress.
So as always a CloudFormation just monitor go back and check that it's definitely deleted all the resources
the elastic IP is you know it's shut down your instances properly that kind of thing you should be at
a tell if that's happened.
I like to go in to make sure that everything looks good here.
And if you have any doubts go over and look into EC2 for instance and make sure that your resources
have been deleted properly so that you don't pay any extra costs.