Hi guys and welcome to the first practical lap of the course.
I'm going to guide you through creating your AWS free tier account.
Now this is a practical course.
So I'm actually going to guide you through over 20 hours of practical exercises through hands on labs.
That means an AWS Free Tier account really is essential if you want to follow along with the exercises
and really gain that hands on experience which I think is the best way to learn.
And it's also the best way to get the knowledge so that you can really understand how to work out the
answer to a question.
So I do highly recommend that you create an AWS free tier account now for this.
You will need a credit card and you'll also need a mobile phone number.
Some people will be worried about bills.
Now with the AWS free tier account I'm going to show you through it in a second.
You actually get quite a lot for free.
So for most of the exercises throughout this course you're actually going to be able to stick within
the free tier and not pay anything.
However you can accidentally leave something running or provision a service which isn't within the free
tier or just exceed the limits in some way.
So it is really important that you follow my advice through the course that when I tell you to clean
up resources you go and clean them up.
I'll give you warnings where things aren't within the free tier and also within the section we're
actually going to set up a billing alarm which will notify you if you're going to exceed a certain amount
on your bill.
Let's get started and actually create our free tier account.
I'm on the AWS Web site here and you can easily find this page by just going to Google or typing this
into your search bar.
Just type in AWS is free tier and you're going to see the very first link here.
So I've already opened that page and we can just go to create a free tier account.
Now what I want to do first is just scroll down and have a look at some information here.
So it tells us that there are more than 60 products available within the free to air and you can see
that there's the always free and these are free to offers that don't expire after the first 12 months.
So in other words you get a certain amount of resource available for free forever as long as you have
your account.
You've then got the 12 months free.
And this just means that for 12 months you'll get a certain allocation of resource that you can consume
without having to pay.
And then there are the trials which are short term free trial offers which are available for certain
services and there's probably fewer of those.
What we're going to concentrate on mostly in this course are services that are either always free or
12 months free.
So just have a look at the examples of what you can do under compute here you get Amazon easy to for
750 hours a month.
Now what you have to make sure is that you choose the T2 micro instance which is a certain size of instance.
And that means you can run this for 24 hours every day of the month you've then got storage free tier
and you can see that for Amazon S3 which is an object storage system.
You can get five gigabytes of storage a month and you get a certain amount of requests for retrieving
or uploading objects and you've then got the database service over here.
RDS.
Again 750 hours another popular service on Amazon is dynamoDB which is a no SQL database and you
can see here you get 25 gigabytes.
So it's always worth having a look and just seeing what you can get.
You can filter on the left hand side here you can see we've also got AWS lambda an elastic container
registry Elastic Load Balancing and lightsail.
If we go down to database you can see There's RDS dynamoDB, Eelasticache, Redshift and database migration
service if we go down to storage we can see in addition to S3 we've got cloud front, elastic file system
elastic block storage and so on.
So there's quite a lot available.
Now let's just scroll back up again and choose create a free tier account.
What we need to do here is put in our email address.
We can put a password and confirm the password and then we've got to choose an account name which can
be changed later on.
Once we filled out that information we can just choose to continue on the next page you need to fill
out your contact information.
However before you do that you need to choose the account type.
Now if you hover over the information icon here it tells you that you should select professional if
the account is intended for company use educational use or for an institutional organisation.
Otherwise select personnel.
So in most cases you're going to use personal.
So just select that option and then fill out your contact information.
And once you've done that click Create Account and continue you'll now need to enter some payment information.
So you'll need your credit and debit card and then just put in your details and click on secure submit.
You're now asked to confirm your identity.
So you have a couple of options here.
You can choose to receive a text message or you can choose to receive a voice call if you receive a
voice call.
You'll actually get called by an automated service.
But from a AWS and they'll ask you to verify some information.
I'm just going to use the text message service and all I need to do is choose my country and my phone
number.
Obviously put in the security check and then click send SMS.
You should then receive a verification code and you just need to type that into the box.
My case is 6 8 9 2 and then just choose verify code and that's it.
It says that my identity has been verified successfully and I can continue.
You then get asked to select a support plan and there are free options here.
The basic plan which is free to the developer plan which is about $30 dollars a month and then the business
plan at $100 dollars a month.
We don't need to choose any paid plans there for the purposes of training and the labs that we're going
to be doing in this course the free plan is just fine.
So I'm just going to select that option and that's it.
So we've now gone through the whole process and we get a welcome to Amazon Web Services message and
they let us know that they're activating the account which might take a few minutes and then what you
want to do is check your e-mail to see if you've received the confirmation.
So let's just head over to my e-mail accounts and see if we receive those messages so here I am in Gmail
and I've got this welcome to Amazon Web Services message which is telling me that for the next 12 months
I'll have free access to multiple services within the free to air and you can click on this link and
see a bit more information about what's available to you I also received this email which lets you know
that you've signed up for the basic support plan.
I also received this email which gives some links to tutorials and articles that you might want to have
a look at.
Let's head back to the AWS Web site and we should now be able to sign into our account.
I'll just choose sign into the console and on this log in screen we can see that we need an account
I.D. a username and password.
Now we don't actually have those yet.
These are part of the Identity and Access Management System and we'll be creating an IAM user shortly
but for now you have to choose sign in using root account credentials.
You'll then be asked to supply the email address that you just signed up with.
You can then choose next and put in the password
and that's it.
Guys we're now locked into the AWS management console with our new AWS free tier account.
So that's really exciting you're now set to actually build some services on AWS. What we're going to
do in the next lab is modify the sign in link so we have a more user friendly link that users can use
to log in with and then after that we're going to have a lab on setting up billing alarms so that you
can get notified if you reach certain billing thresholds that you assign.
Hope you're having fun guys see you in the next lab.