We're now going to create an RDS
read replica of our master database and that means we'll have some asynchronous replication coming
from the RDS master to read replica.
And we could then serve reads using you know other apps service to connect and just read data from the
database.
We're not actually going to create an app server and connect to the database.
We're just going to go into the console and create the read replica.
So I'm back in the console.
I'm going to go into my database and then go to actions and I click Create read replica.
And we now have some new options available to us for the read replica so we can choose where we want
this to be.
So remember that read replicas can be in different regions.
So I could choose another region.
I could say well I want to put this one in Singapore and this subnet groups there I could choose
an availability zone I could choose to make it publicly available and so on.
Now I'm just gonna leave this one in Sydney and we can then choose encryption for the database.
Remember though that that's not going to work.
So there's gonna be a problem if you try and do that because you can't have an encrypted replica
of an unencrypted master database. We could then choose a different DB instance class for our read replica.
And as it's not a writable database you can't create a multi AZ deployment of it.
So the option is there but it doesn't work.
We now need to give it an identifier.
So what I could do is call it a dash digital cloud read only and we're going to leave this ports the
same.
We're going to leave the monitoring as defaults and we just click Create read replica.
So if we come back to databases now you can see we've got two databases the original digital cloud and
now we've got the read only digital cloud.
And that's going to take a few minutes to create let's go into digital cloud and go to maintenance and
backups and if you come down here you can actually see that a snapshot is in the creating stage.
And the reason for that is because what happens when you create a read replica is ideas will take a
snapshot and then the snapshot is then transferred over to create the read replica from the snapshot.
So that's just the process.
Let's have a look at a couple of other things while we're here.
If you go to monitoring you can see some information here so you can see the CPU utilization over the
last hour or the timeframes.
You can see the DB connections.
Free storage and megabytes free of memory write IOPS and read IOPS and then there's more.
So you can look at queue depth and read free.
What usage and so on.
And you know there's this quite a lot of information here so plenty of data to use if we go to logs
and events we can see some events there.
And if you go down to logs you can then see some logging information here which you can then download.
So we're not going to do that.
Let's just go back and give this couple of minutes until this is complete.
It's been about 10 minutes or so and now I have both of my databases available and if I go into my RDS
dash digital cloud you'll see that we have a different endpoints.
That's the one thing I just wanted to point out.
Don't forget you have a different endpoint from Read replicas.
And if we just head down to the bottom here you can actually see that we have our master and our replica
and the replication state is replicating if we go back to our main database our master database.
Again you can go down to replication and you can see the master and the replica.
So that's it for this lab.
And what we're going to do now is we're just going to delete our databases and you need to confirm by
typing delete me and then for the master database we need to also delete.
And in this case I'm just gonna deselect that option.
So by default it will create a final DB snapshot
and I actually need to acknowledge that the all the backups are gonna be deleted so there's
no way of recovering this database.
So I said that both deleting we can also then go back to instance and we can terminate our instance
and that's everything cleaned up and that's the end of this lab.