Hi guys.
In this lab we're going to create an AWS Lambda function that pulls data from a DynamoDB table.
And then when it finds updates it writes some events to CloudWatch logs.
Now I appreciate that we haven't covered DynamoDB yet. DynamoDB is a noSQL database service
and it's gonna be covered in the next section in this course.
But that's okay because we're really going to create a very simple configuration and we're going to
cover DynamoDB in a lot more detail in the next section.
So please notice something here.
The poll based services.
So when I say poll based, what I mean is that AWS Lambda is polling DynamoDB. So this is the complete
opposite of the last lab where you had S3 and S3 was sending an event notification when something
happened in a bucket.
So it was S3 that was responsible for triggering Lambda to execute its code.
In this scenario DynamoDB is a stream based service as is Kinesis and SQS. And so Lambda polls DynamoDB
.It would poll Kinesis, it would poll SQS, so the same thing for those three services.
and what this means is the configuration for the event source mapping is on Lambda not on the service
itself.
So this a key exam question you need to know that difference.
Now let's just head over to a web page and I have this tutorial open that I'm going to be following.
Now we're going to want to use these AWS tutorials because it's very simple way of ensuring that you
guys can run through these labs successfully.
And if you do have any problems of course you can come and message me or you can ask in the Q&A
forum but I'd prefer that you guys just are able to complete these exercises easily without getting
sort of hung up on any coding problems or anything like that.
Because this really isn't the exam where you need to know those kind of things.
So what we do is we come down here and we're going to copy this code and we're gonna create our index
JS file and I'm over on the command line now and I'm going and I'm in my directory so just make sure
you've changed your Lambda DynamoDB directory and we're going to put star code into nano and I'm then
going to save this as index.JS and we can now run zip function.zip and then we write index.js
and so if we look in here now we've got our function.zip file and we can now run the following
command to create our function.
So it's "aws Lambda create function" and we've given it the name and it's process DynamoDB records
we're giving it zip file name we're giving it the handler that we want to use the runtime which is node.js
and then the role.
So just make sure that you get the ARN for your role and paste it in here. We're now in the Lambda console
and if we click functions we should find yet we now have our Lambda function process DynamoDB records.
So let's go in and have a look, and in the center here we can select our function and that will then
display the code underneath so we can see the code which we pasted into nano before to create our index.js
and that's been packaged up and uploaded into our function.
You can see the runtime selected just as we expect it to be you can see there are no layers here layers
are a way that you can pull in additional code and contents that are actually zip archives which contain
the libraries custom runtime and dependencies that you need for that code.
We've then got CloudWatch logs so we can see the permissions here and the actions and we can see DynamoDB
again you've got the resources there and the actions here so that all looks good.
Now one for your note is we don't have a trigger yet so we're going to need to add a trigger soon but
before we do that we can test the function as it is so we can come back to here and what we're going
to do is just copy this code and I'm just gonna go over to an editor because I've noticed that we've
got some regions in hand I need to change us-east-1 to ap-southeast-2, that's my region.
I'm just going to copy that.
I think there's a couple of instances in here where I noticed that.
So here we go got to change U.S. East one again.
So just update this to whatever region you're in, and another one here,
and I think everything else looks okay.
So let's copy this and we're now going to use nano again.
I'm going to paste in that code and I'm gonna save the file as input.txt
and we've, so we've got that file now and we can now run the following command.
So it's aws Lambda invoke we're supplying the function name the payload which is the input.txt
file and then we've got an output field up to 60 for the output.
So we just hit enter on that status code to hundreds so that's okay.
And what we can do now is if we cap the output file we should see we've got this string message which
just says message and that's good.
So that's a success.
Now let's go back to the console and if we have a look at monitoring and view locks and logs in cloud
watch logs we can now go into here and we should see some records and these would have been generated
by our test.
So if you go in you'll see some messages new item.
So that looks good and our test has worked.
So what we want to do now is actually create our dynamo DB table.
So there's some instructions here.
I'm just going to copy the table name and then let's go to DynamoDB which is under database
and it's very simple to create a database and DynamoDB. Like I say, in the next section of the course
we're going to go into this and a lot of detail, but all I need to do here is supply the table name and
I.D. as the partition key.
And then we have string and we'll just click Create.
So it should only take a few seconds to create this but the next thing I want to do is click manage
stream and we just leave the default selection here click on enable and you'll now want to take the
ARN in and copy that to your clipboard.
So as you'll remember from a few minutes ago we don't have a trigger.
Yes if we go back to the configuration here there's no trigger.
So what we're going to do is we're going to run a command and this is to create the event source mapping.
And if you remember from the diagram the event source mapping in this case is taken is configured on
aws Lambda.
So because this is a stream service.
Same for Kinesis, the same for SQS, is the configuration is here on Lambda and not on the service.
So this event source mapping creation we supply the function name again.
It's a couple of other parameters.
And then the big one that you need to be sure that you change is the event source ARN.
So that's the ARN that we just retrieved from DynamoDB.
It says this value here just copy this value make sure your function name is correct paste in your ARN
and then let's hit enter.
So that looks like it's in the state of pending.
And let's head over to the console and let's just refresh this function
and just open up the design there.
And now we have our triggers if we click on that trigger we can see it says no records have been processed.
So the way we can test that this is all working now is we go into DynamoDB.
We go to items and we create items.
So let's just call these items I've got my test add another one.
You just put in the string value let's call it mytest2
mytest3 and click save.
So what should happen according to our diagram is that Lambda should be polling DynamoDB, it should
find that some items have been updated, and then it's going to write a record to CloudWatch logs and
that record should mention the name of the items that we added in here.
So let's go back to CloudWatch and I'm going to refresh.
So we've got a whole load of new entries here let's have a look at some of these and you can see the
build duration memory size Max memory used then you've got to start and then you've got some of the
payload in here so you can see how we've got my test free
and that's all that one so if we go back a bit we should find mytest2.
So we can say this is definitely working we've got Lambda polling DynamoDB and then taking some information
about the updates to the database and writing them to CloudWatch log so you can imagine this this content
and the information that's in it what you could do with that.
So clearly here we're just writing a log but you can imagine the many applications that you can design
which use this information in some way.
So that's it for this lab.
What we can do to clean up.
We can very simply go in select our table and delete table in DynamoDB and that's done.
And then we can go into Lambda and if we just head back up to functions and selects our function and
go over to actions and delete and that say and what we're going to do in the next lab is I'm going to
give you an overview of API Gateway and then we're going to create a simple micro service application
that uses Lambda as well as API Gateway and also DynamoDB.
So that should be very interesting I'll see you in the next lab.