This is the exam cram for IWC organizations with IWC organizations, you can consolidate multiple IWC
accounts into an organization that you create and then centrally manage.
It's available in two feature sets consolidated billing and all features.
It includes the root accounts and organizational units, policies get applied to root accounts or use,
and consolidated billing includes a paying account, which is independent and can't access the resources
of other accounts and then linked accounts and all linked accounts are also independent of each other.
We've consolidated billing.
You get a single payment method for all the IWC accounts in the organization.
You get a combined view of charges incurred by all accounts and you get pricing benefits from the aggregated
usage.
There's a limit of 20 linked accounts for consolidated billing by default.
It can help with cost control through the volume discounts with consolidated billing.
Unused reserved instances are applied across the group, and paying accounts should be used for billing
purposes only.
Moving on to service control policies, these manage the maximum available permissions.
You must have all features enabled in the organization and that can be applied to accounts or IOUs.
Policies can be assigned at different points in the hierarchy, and KPIs affect only IAM users and roles,
not resource policies and KPIs affect the root accounts in member accounts.
CEPS do not affect any action performed by the management accounts.
We then have the different strategies.
The denialist strategy uses the full US access CPA that's attached to every IOU and accounts and overrides
the implicit deny.
It explicitly allows all permissions to flow down from the roots that grants full access to all permissions.
You can then create additional steps to explicitly deny permissions anywhere in the hierarchy.
You then have to allow less strategy.
In this case, you removed the full IWC access MCP.
No APIs are permitted anywhere unless you explicitly allow them, so you have to create steps to allow
those permissions.
The steps must be attached to target accounts and every IOU above it, including the routes.
Full migration accounts can be migrated between organizations.
You must have Root or IAM access to both the member and management accounts, and you can use the organization's
console if it's just a few accounts or use the API or see a line if there are many accounts to migrate.
And that's it for this exam crime.