Hi, guys.
Another important topic for the exam and just one that you need to know in general for working with
A.W., US is the I am best practices.
So these are really important to know, not only because they're good Praksis, but in this case because
they're good for the exam as well as something that can come up on the exam.
So you do need to understand them.
Now the Linkous in the course downloads or you can just search for I am best practices.
And what I'm going to do now is just go back to the slides and go through each of these one by one.
But it's worth having a read of this whole article because there's a bit more context here that you
need to understand, I think, for the exam.
So I would just give this a quick read through.
Shouldn't take you too long.
So the first I am best practice is to lock away your A.W. s account route, user access keys.
So really important.
Remember, you've always got to lock those away.
They are the keys to the kingdom.
You do not want people accessing your account using route user access keys.
If they're compromised, the whole account is compromised until you delete those keys.
Great individual IAM users.
So remember, this is all about not creating a user account and giving the credentials to multiple people.
So everyone should have their own individual IAM user account.
And then you give them the permissions they need to do their job.
So use groups to assign permissions to users.
So this means don't apply permissions directly to users.
What you should do is group your users by job rule and then apply the permissions and a policy applied
to the group.
That way, it's much more easier for organization.
Grant Lee's privilege.
So this is obviously something that you should know, working in I.T. in general.
Never give people more permissions than they need to do their jobs.
Get started using permissions with a W.S. managed policies.
So we talked about that earlier in the section A.W. US manage policies are standalone policies that
are created by a W.S. there in your account already when you create your account and they're pre configured.
So this is an easy way to get started with a W.S..
It means it's less likely that you're going to make a mistake when creating policies, if you're new
to creating policies.
And that caused that mistake could lead to providing more access than you want to.
You should use customer managed policies instead of inline policies.
So remember that the A.W., US managed policies and customer managed policies are standalone policies.
So that means they exist independently of the identity.
The user role or group you attach them to an inline policy is attached directly to an entity like a
user.
So you should avoid unionise as much as possible because it's going to make administration difficult
to use access levels to review IAM permissions.
Basically means that you just need to keep reviewing your account and making sure that the permissions
you've assigned to your users, groups and roles are correct, that you're not giving too much access.
Configure a strong password policy for users.
That's quite self-explanatory.
You should always try and use a strong password policy so that the passwords aren't easy to guess.
Enabling multifactor authentication is important.
They used to say just for the rude account.
Then they said just for privileged users.
Now they just say enable Amethi.
So very simple, enable it for everybody, use rolls for applications that run on easy two instances.
So we've seen what happens if you use a W.S. Configure to create a credentials file on your AC2 instance.
The access key I.D. and the Secret Access Key are stored in plain text on your AC2 instance.
So that's not very good from a security perspective.
Much better to use a role to give your AC to applications the privileges they need.
Use rolls to delegate permissions.
So that's exactly what we're talking about there.
You should use roles to delegate permissions rather than embedding things in your E.S. two instances
or in your code somewhere.
So don't embed access key I.D. and secret access keys in your code.
Use rolls instead because they use temporary security credentials.
So it's much more secure.
Never share access keys.
So again, that's quite self-explanatory.
It's basically saying these are very security sensitive things.
Don't share them around and rotate your credentials regularly.
So those access keys.
Make sure you regularly rotate them in case I compromised and always remove unnecessary credentials.
So I don't have any more credentials than you actually need.
Use policy conditions for extra security is about adding conditions into your policy.
For instance, we saw a policy earlier in the section where there was a condition for the source IP
address, and it basically meant that the policy would only apply if the IP address that you were connecting
from was a certain value.
So if you weren't using the machine that had that IP address, the policy would deny your access monitor
activity in your A.W. account.
Again, quite self-explanatory.
You just need to monitor what's going on in your account to see if anything is happening that shouldn't
be.
So that's it for that I am best practices.
Again, I would recommend that you go back to that Web page that I showed you and just read through
these and make sure you understand them.