Welcome back in this lesson.
I'm going to show you how to use user data and metadata with two, I have a file open here with some
code in it.
Now don't worry, you don't need to understand too much about this code and you don't need to change
anything.
This is in the code directory.
So when you get your course, download your course.
Download is in the last lesson of section one of the course.
You can download a zip file once you unzip the zip file.
You will find a code directory within there.
You'll find Amazon EC2 and then you'll find this file user data.
That's metadata, though ask.
Now I'll explain to you quickly what this is doing.
This is going to update the operating system with patches and then installs a web server called FTP.
A very simple web service.
Then what's happening is it's actually going to use the metadata of the instance.
So it's going to find out what the instance ideas.
So remember this URL we saw in the last lesson?
This URL is actually going to find out what the instance side is for this particular instance.
And it's going to record it in a variable.
And then it's going to take that variable and put it into some text.
And so what should happen is the web page should say the instance side of this Amazon EC2 instance is.
And then it should have the correct instance side.
And the way it does that is it changes the variable and saves it to the indexed on HTML file, which
is the web page that we're going to see when we connect to the instance.
Now the good news is you don't need to change anything.
This file is going to be supplied as user data to our S2 instance when we launch.
So we're combining metadata to find out the instance, IP and user data in terms of supplying this code
to the operating system when it boots.
So let's head over to the management console back in AC.
I'm going to choose launch instances.
I'm going to select Amazon, then it's two am, I will keep it as a teacher in my crew.
Choose configure instance details, and this time we scroll to the bottom and we have two options here,
we could put the code directly in here or we can choose the file.
So I'm going to choose the file, select choose file and in my code directory, I'm going to go and
find that file and choose for upload.
So now the file is being supplied.
Nothing needs to be changed.
We can choose next.
Go for it, a security group.
We can choose our security group and then go forwards.
Now there is another thing we're going to need to do once we launch this instance.
Remember, we have two protocols that we can connect to an instance with the secure shell protocol or
DP.
Nothing else is allowed in our security group, our firewall.
And we will need to allow Port AC because that's the port that a web server runs on.
So that's change review and launch and launch.
I just need to acknowledge and launch instances.
So while that's launching, let's come back to the console, choose security groups.
I'm going to go back to inbound rules.
Edit inbound rules.
Click on ads.
And this time I'm going to type FTP, select FTP and it automatically chooses the port range as 80,
and we're going to allow from anywhere.
I'm going to just use IP version four and save rules.
So that's done.
Let's go back to instances, and we just need to give this a couple of minutes to make sure that it's
booted up.
And then I should be able to copy this IP address and put it into a browser window.
So just give that a couple of minutes and then we'll give it a try.
OK, so it's been a couple of minutes.
I'm going to copy the public IPv4 address, or you can choose the IPv4 DNS.
I'm going to open a new tab in my browser, paste that in and hit Enter.
And sure enough, we get a web page and the web page has the text that came from our file that says
the instant side of this Amazon EC2 instance is and then we can see it's filled out the instant side.
So that should correspond with the instant side here.
So that information was found in the metadata for the S2 instance.
So we used the user data to install a web service, and we used metadata to find out the instance IP
and then we put it on this page.
So that's how we use user data and metadata.
Now I'm just going to go back and terminate my instance.
So again, just select your instance, go to instance, state and terminate instance.