In this lesson, I want to cover off multi aisi read replicas, so you've already learned a couple of
key concepts you understand about multiuse.
So here is a classic example of multiuse.
We have our OD's master.
So this is our writable instance that's active.
We then have a standby and another availability zone and we have synchronous replication happening to
that STAMBAUGH.
Now, our application will be pointed to this end point address.
And if for some reason the availability zone or the database instance fails, this instance then becomes
active.
So that's just classic multi-asset ideas.
And when this happens, the endpoint address will contribute to the stand by.
So remembers one end point address, which gets cut over from your master to the standby, which then
becomes the master and the original master will become the standby once it's available again.
Now, you also know that you can create a red replica from a master, maybe not this one, because it's
failed.
But you know what I'm talking about.
So you create a red replica from your ideas, master.
Now, in this case, you can see I've called this a red replica master.
And the reason is what you can also do is enable multi-asset for your red replica.
So in this case, we've created a rich replica stand by and another availability zone.
And we have an end point address in this case, it's digital cloud, there are all sorts of different
endpoint address to writable end point.
This is only read only endpoint.
And we can then direct our application to do raids here and rights to this End Point address.
But we might have a problem if this instance fails, because then our applications are unable to perform
reads.
Now, you might have logic that fails it either, but you can also do it through A.D.s.
So in this case, what happens is your master files over to the stand by and your end point address
now cuts over to the Reed replica.
Stand by.
So hopefully that makes sense.
Let's just go over to the console and I'll show you how you do this.
So I'm in the console, I've already created a MySQL database called Digital Cloud.
I'm going to select my database.
I'm going to click actions, read replica.
And straight away, you can see I have an option for multiuse deployment, so I'm just going to select
that.
I'm going to come down, I'm going to call this.
Don't that's the source, so I'm going to call this one digital cloud dash.
Ah, and that's all I need to do.
So now I've created that configuration and it's going to take a few minutes.
So it will take a little while.
But eventually what I'll find is I have this replica, which will be it could be in the same availability
zone as the master here, and it will have another replica, which you can't see in the console here
because it's a standby instance.
But that will be in a different availability zone to this instance here.
So I'm not going to hang around and show you that one, I just wanted to make sure you understand the
concepts.
So just remember, you can have a multi-asset master and stand by for your rideable database instance,
but you can also have multisite if you read replicas as well.
And in that case, the end point address for the read replica gets filed between different reach replicas.
Now, you can also pair this as a D.R strategy, so you could also promote a read replica to be a writable
instance.
And if it has a standby, that will also become a standby for that writable instance.
You might have a couple of exam questions coming up around these topics.
So hopefully now you have everything you need.