Welcome to the architecture patterns lesson for IWC organizations.
So let's have a look at our first requirement.
A company needs a method of quickly creating IWC accounts programmatically.
Well, in that case, they can use the organization's API to create accounts programmatically.
Remember, if you're just doing a single account through the console or one or two accounts, then the
management console is fine.
Otherwise, you might want to do it programmatically, and that's where the API comes in handy.
Users in a member account in eight U.S. organizations should be restricted from making changes in IAM.
Well, of course, in this circumstance, you would use a service control policy and stop to deny access
to IAM actions and IWC account must be moved between organizations.
For that, you can migrate the account using the IWC organization's console.
Again, you can do that for a single account.
If you have lots of accounts, you want to move again, you can do that through the API as well.
A solutions architect created a new account through the organization's console and needs to log in to
launch resources.
So how do you do that?
Well, the architect should switch roles to access the new accounts.
Multiple member accounts in eight U.S. organizations require the same permissions to be restricted using
space.
In that case, you can create an IOU and add the member accounts and then attached to you.
That would be the least administrative overhead for implementing this solution.
The developers in a company each have their own IWC accounts for testing the security team wish to enable
centralized governance.
Well, in that case, they could create an IWC organization and send an invite to each developer's IWC
account to join the organization.
And that's it for this architecture patterns.