I'm in the AWS Management Council and we can find AWS Organizations under management and governance.
If you don't have an organization already created then you just see the splash screen and you just choose
create organization and there's really nothing else that you need to do here.
You just choose create organization and it'll create the first organization for you.
And I actually have the accounts in the console here so you can see digital cloud training labs.
Now if you choose organize accounts this is where we can see a hierarchy.
Now in this case we don't have anything.
We've just got the root.
But you can now create your hierarchy in here and you can also see policies.
So we've got service control policies and tag policies.
And if we choose each one of these we need to enable it first so enabled service control policies and
then I'm going to go into tag policies and enable tag policies.
Now what I want to do now is we're going to add another account.
So the way we do that is we actually going to invite an account.
You can say you can create an account as well but we're just going to invite an account and I'm going
to put in the account number and just choose invites.
And what will happen is the invitation now gets sent and we need to go to the other account and accept
that invitation now what'll happen is you'll be emailed a invite to the e-mail account that's associated
with that account that you've just invited.
Now I've looked into that account on a number private browsing window and I'm just pasting in the
URL that I was given in the email I received.
So you could just click on the link and the email and what I need to do is I've got to log into this
account.
So this is DCC labs 2.
And now that I'm logged in.
We can see that I have an invitation from another account that DCT training labs.
And so now that I'm logged in we can see that we have an invitation to join an organization from digital
cloud training labs.
So I'm just going to choose accept and confirm.
And now the DCT labs 2 account is also associated with the same organization.
So if I come back over to here and let's go back to accounts and the screen's refreshing and we can
now see that we have two accounts and they both have the same name.
But these are definitely two different accounts.
So what I want to do now is set up the organization with an organizational unit that I'm going to put
the DCT labs 2 account in seeing and the service control policy here.
So first off let's go and create the organizational unit.
So we're going to head to organize accounts to click on the group and then you can create a new organizational
unit.
And I'm just going to call this OU1.
So now we have the you I'm going to choose the second account and I'm going to move it into a new one.
So if we now go into that OU we can see that we have this second account.
So that's the structure set up we now need to create a service control policy that denies people from
the ability to launch instances other than the T2 micro.
So I'm going to show you where to find some service control policies.
So let's just search for service control policy examples.
And here we have some example service policies.
Now you'll see there's 13 different examples there.
And the one that we want to use is this one example 10, require Amazon EC2 instances to use a specific
type.
So if we click on that will come down and this is the service control policy that we want to apply so
you can copy that or you can click on the little button up here and this SCP enforces that
Any instance launch is not using the T2 micro are denied.
So what we can do now we can come back.
We can go to policies, service control policies, we can create a policy and I'll just I'll go back and
let you know about that's the policy that exists there already that's created by default and we can
just call this allow only T2 micro.
And what I'm gonna do is just override this policy.
I'm just going to paste in the JSON code and we can now choose create policy and that's being created.
Now let's just have a look at this one here.
So we've got the full AWS access policy.
This is created by default.
And let's just have a look at the policy.
This is the one we saw in the slide that allows basically every action on every resource.
So now that we've got the policy we need to apply it to our organizational unit so we can choose the
OU, go to service control policies, and we're going to attach the allow only T2 micro so you can see
because it's in a hierarchy the full AWS access is attached to this OU.
But because the most restrictive policy will be applied applying this allow only T2 micro will restrict
access to to ensure that we can only launch T2 micro instances.
So the most restrictive policy will apply.
So what we can do now that we've applied that is let's go back to our other organization.
So this is DCT Labs 2 and I'm going to go to EC2 and let's try and launch an instance.
And what I'm gonna do is I'm just going to go in and let's just choose a T2 large and just try to
configure a security group so it doesn't try and create one for us.
But this shouldn't work anyway so let's just have a look and see what happens.
So let's click on launch and we've got to create a key pair for this region.
So let's just go in and create a key pair.
I was going to call it my new key pair download and let's launch and there we go.
We get the launch failed so it says you're not authorized to perform this operation.
So obviously that's because of that policy.
Now I'm logged in with an administrative account so I have full privileges to AWS but I'm not able
to launch that instance. Of course I can go in and let's just try and launch another instance this just
choose a T2 micro and this should work fine.
And we just go back and stop it from creating new security groups and I'm just going to launch that
instance.
And that's no problem.
So we can launch T2 micro instances but we can't launch anything else.
So that's exactly what we wanted to achieve.
So coming back and looking at this diagram we have a master account DCT labs.
We have our DCT labs 2 account within an organizational unit.
And we've applied a policy and we've only allowed people to launch T2 micro instances.
So that's it for this lab.
Let's just go back and what we're going to do is just clean this up.
So I'm going to terminate this instance and then go back to my master account and what I can do here
is I can detach
that service control policy and
I can quite easily go in and remove this account as well.
So I'm just going to go ahead and do that going to remove the account and I'm going to leave the organization
set up.
But you can also just delete your organization if you need to.
You could do that by going into settings and choosing delete organization.
Now I'm aware that many of you won't have two accounts so might not have been able to follow along but
at least through viewing this lab you'll have a good understanding of what AWS Organizations are.
And also the key thing for the exam is just to understand how the SCPs are applied and what takes
precedence.
And remember the most restrictive policy takes precedence.