Hi guys this is gonna be a great lab.
What we're going to do now is set up ECS services within an ECS cluster and the way we're going to
do it we're going to create multiple services and we're going to attach an elastic load balancer and
application load balancer to those services.
Now the services will run tasks and those tasks will be patchy on one service and nginx on the other.
Now one of the things you may have noticed is that Apache and nginx both run on port 80 and what
we actually have here underneath this is a single EC2 instance.
So we have one EC2 instance in one subnet and another EC2 instance add another subnet so the
problem is when you have multiple services or multiple containers running on the same port we have an
issue where you can't share a port a port on the host.
So you need different ports on the host and the way this is achieved is the container instance creates
dynamically a port for that specific task and it communicates what that port is to the application load
balancer.
And this is a particular capability of an ALB you can't do this with NLB or an CLB.
So the host port is generated on the instance and the ALB gets to find out what it is that's communicated.
So when you look in your target group you'll see the port and the ALB then sends traffic on that ports
to the instance and then the instance forwards it to Apache.
In this case or if it comes in on this other point it's forwards it to nginx.
Another problem we have to solve is we have a single listener running on port 80 here.
Now we have two services on the back-end.
So how do we forward traffic to the correct service.
And we're going to do that through path based routing.
So we've path based routing and dynamic HOST PORT mapping.
We're able to set up this configuration
in this lab.
We want to create this as a secure configuration so much again to put the ECS containers into private
subnets and we're going to use a NAT gateway in a public subnet so that they can access the outside
world to pull down these images from Docker Hub.
We're also going to set up the security groups to restrict access so that the application load balancer
consort to the ECS clients securely on specific ports.
So what we're gonna do now is head over to the console and start building this out.
Now what I've done in advance is set up a couple of these security groups so we have the ECS clients
security group and that security group allows traffic inbound from the ALB security group.
So that's this one here.
And it does so on the port range 32000 to 33000 which is where I've seen the dynamic ports being created
for outbound.
We have all traffic is allowed out.
Now we do need we could restrict this further but we do need a couple of things we need to be able to
pull the images from Docker Hub and we also need to be able to setup the ECS end points on the
ALB security group.
We have an outbound rule which allows traffic to the ECS clients security group on that port range.
So that's the traffic pool and that's also going to be where the health checks go.
And for inbound it just allows from any source on the DP port.
The other thing I've configured as a NAT gateway if you haven't got one already you need to put one
into the correct VPC and you need to make sure it's in a public subnet.
So this will enable your private subnet instances to access the internet but the actual NAT gateway
sits in a public subnet.
And then you'll select an ill and elastic IP or just created new elastic IP.
So I've already got one.
It's available.
And once you've you've created you in that Gateway you then need to go to round tables choose the round
table for your private subnets and you need to go in and put a round out to the outside world so or
any destination and you need to put in the idea that Gateway and you'll be notified that by dropping
down in this box and choosing it that gateway.
So that's already set up.
And what we're going to do now is head over to the command line and start creating our cluster.
So I've opened the command line and I'm going to run the command AWS ECS create cluster
dash dash cluster dash name and then we're gonna give it a name and I'm going to call ECS dash cluster
dash B.
And that was created.
That's just an empty cluster now.
If we actually head over to the console refresh we can now see that we have a cluster.
There's nothing running in it we could also view our cluster here by doing AWS ECS list clusters and
you can get the air in there.
We're actually going to add our instances manually by going into the console.
So we have the cluster and we want to go to EC2 choose community and.
And you can actually then go in and search for ECS optimized and find the ECS optimized AMIs.
I know the my I.D. I want to use.
So I'm going to put that in I'm going to click next I'm going to choose the VPC.
I want these in a private subnet.
You need to select your instance row and we then need to put it in the cluster configuration.
So in order to ensure that this connects to your cluster you need to put in the ECS cluster equals cluster
name.
And that goes into that ECS config so this short bash scripts will perform that for us
we can then put this instance into the ECS clients security group
and that's launching.
And what I'm going to do now is and then go back in and I'm going to do exactly the same thing.
The only difference is this time I'm going to put it into the private subnet to be.
So it's going to be a separate subnet those instances are now launching and let's go and create our
load balancer.
So we're going to use an application load balancer.
I'm just going to call it my ALB.
We're going to have a single listener in port 80.
We're going to choose VPC our custom VPC and then we need to select a subnet.
Now remember when you have an Internet facing elastic load balancer even if your clients are in a private
subnet you need to put the LBO you need to connect the ELB to the public subnets.
So if we just go back over to our diagram we have a public subnet in each availability zone where our
private subnet is.
That's essential you must have a public subnet in the same availability zone as your private subnet.
And then you attach the public subnet to the ALB.
It will then be able to register the clients in the private subnet.
But that's the way you set up and I'll be or any you'll be for that matter so we collect next.
We choose the L.B. security group and now we're going to try to target group the first ones it's going
to be called one and are going to change the healthy threshold down to two and everything else can stay
the same and we're not going to register the instances now that will happen through the service that
we create any C.S.
that's being created and is currently provisioning.
Let's go over to well let's have a quick look and see how our instances are where they're running one's
definitely completed.
So let's go into our cluster and go to ISIS instances and sure enough both our instances are here now.
So that's great.
The next thing we need to do is we need to create our task definitions.
Now I'm going to first create one for nginx. We'll go to EC2 we're just going to call this engine
X we don't need to fill out any of these details here we're going to put in 50 megabytes and 128 for
CPE and then we add a container definition and this will be nginx and then this is nginx again
and this is the actual image that's gonna get pulled from Docker Hub so make sure that that's correct.
You can change the names but this one is essentially this one needs to be the same and then we then
put the host port 0 container port is 80 so back on our diagram the host port is the port on the ECS
instance the EC2 instance when you set it to 0 that allows the EC2 instance to be able to
then create this dynamic port that can be used for this dynamic port mapping to the container port and
then the container port is this one eighty.
So that's the actual service port there's lots of other stuff you can put in here but we don't need
to put anything at this stage so we can just click Add and create
and that's our task definition at the end.
There's a revision.
No because I've played around with this quite a lot and deleted task definitions it's now up to six.
So even if you delete your task completely your task definition completely you will still see this number
increment
the next thing I want to do is I need to create a task definition for hasty TTP demon.
So Apache and let's go into this first one because this one actually does do this for us.
So if against this sample at
this installs the hate TTP demons.
This is Apache 2.0 point for and also runs a commands.
This is a docker CMD command where you can actually output some information.
So we're gonna do this and we're actually going to modify some of this code.
The thing that we need to change as well is that the host port here is 80.
So remember for dynamic port mapping we need zero and 80 for the container port to do that or create
a new revision.
And we're going to rename this task definition to Apache Dash.
Alby and we need to change the network mode to default and change the compatibility is to EC2.
We're going to go to sample app.
We're going to change the host port to zero and then we're going to come down to this code here and
I'm gonna change this message here to read.
This is the container running on service dash Apache.
And then we're going to change the file that goes to from index or hasty mail to service dash patching
and we can click updates and creates and if you go back to task definitions we now have the two task
definitions that we need.
So let's go to our cluster and start creating services.
The first one we're going to create is going to be the nginx and we're going to call this service
dash nginx and put two tasks in there.
We can leave the defaults there and we can disable the service discovering and we can choose an application
load balancer.
Note here that it says that the application load balancer allows containers to use dynamic host port
mapping multiple tasks allow per container instance and then it says multiple services can use the same
listener port on a single load balance of rule based routing and paths.
So there's two things there.
Remember the Dynamic Host port mapping is where we're able to share container ports on the same post.
So we've got multiple containers running on the same ports in different services on the same EC2
instance of the container instance a single EC2 instance in this case.
And we're able to do that because of this dynamic port mapping.
The other thing is we have a single lesson.
So all traffic is coming in on port 80 but it's going to two different services.
And that's why we're using path based routing to enable traffic to reach the destination.
And you can't do that with network load balancers or CLB and you have to do static host port mappings
for a CLB.
So nowhere near as good.
We can then click Add to load balancer of and it tells us the container name the host port and the
container port choose our listener choose our target group and everything else is done for us we can
set up auto scaling here but we won't do that in this lab we're going to do that in the next lab so
we can create that service and that service is being created that's view the service and we can see
the tasks here and they're already running what I want to do now then is go to my load balancer get
the DNS address.
Copy that to my clipboard.
And let's go to a browser window
and there we go.
We can see our service and we're probably cycling free both availability zones but it's the same screen
so we can't see any difference.
But that's our first service working.
What we want to do now is go and create our second service.
So let's go in and EC2 launch.
And we're going to choose the Apache.
I'll create a task definition and this time we're going to call it service dash Apache...
click Next disable the service discovery choose our application load balancer same thing again add to
load balancer choose the same listener and this time.
Now we could've created a target group ahead of time but I'm just going to let it create one for me
and it's already created the name and it's already set up the path pattern for me as well based on the
name of the service.
And that's exactly what I want because I called my HTTP default.html file service dash Apache
.html and let's put this valuation order 1 and click on Next click on Next and create service.
And that's now being created so let's click view service and if we go back to services both services
are active now before we check this one out I want to show you in low balances so let's go to target
groups and we can see our t one target group so you can see that this is the portal on the container
instance and that's the one that's been dynamically generated and the health checks go to the traffic
ports.
So that means they go to this port and they're healthy.
And then if we go to this other target group the same thing is happening in this case they're in an
initial state.
Let's refresh that they should shortly change to healthy Oh no.
These ones have gone to unhealthy so let's just have a quick look and try and work out why that is okay.
So a health check port is slash service slash Apache now.
There is a hasty email file there but we haven't specified the file name so let's just remove that and
leave it back to path and change the healthy thresholds to speed things up and sure enough that was
the problem.
So what we can see is that the port which was originally used went into the draining state and then
we have a new container instance actually starting on 3 2 7 7 1 and that's now become healthy.
So if we go back to our tasks and we'll go into that with the Apache task and look at events we'll see
that targets were deregistered and stopped and then started new tasks and then they've reached a steady
state.
So you can actually see the lifecycle happening here.
Now let's go to our target group now let's go to our load balancer and in fact we've already got the
DNS name here.
So what we should be able to do is put in service dash Apache.html.
And if we hit enter.
Sure enough there are application running.
And it says this is the container running on service Apache.
So that's great.
That means we have the dynamic host port mapping working.
And we also have this path based routing working as well.
So that's it for this lab guys.
Hope you had a lot of fun there.
And in the next lab we're going to look at how we can scale using auto scaling so we're going to leave
the resources running.