Hi, guys, I'm now going to cover cloud watch logs, so this is another one that we've used a few times
during this course and mainly with lambda functions, but also with other services as well.
But we've seen that when we create a lambda function, we can send logs to cloud, which logs actually
does it by default.
We then have Amazon EC2.
So, as you know, easy to sense metrics, the cloud watch, but it doesn't send system logs or application
logs by default.
So if you want to do that, the best way is to install the cloud watch agent.
Now there is another way where you can use some Perl scripts and there's also a cloud watch logs agent
and that's different to the cloud watch agent.
And we'll talk about that a bit more in this section.
But by installing an agent, you can then capture application and sys logs and you can do the same thing,
installing the agent on an on premises server as well.
And again, you can capture application logs and system logs.
I'm going to head over to the console now and just give you a refresh on LAMDA and how it does logging.
So I'm in the lambda console.
I'm going to create a function.
I'm just going to call this test cloud watch logs and I'll leave it as no JS and then just choose one
of my existing execution roles, my lamda basic execution and create function.
Now one of the things to note is there's no destination for cloud watch logs or for cloud watch at all.
So they used to be used to create your function and it would by default have cloud watch here.
Now you don't need to do that anymore.
It's integrated by default.
So you don't need to go and add a destination and actually add cloud watch.
Now, with our default code, we're still going to get a log entry, but we're not actually writing
anything specific.
So if you do want to write something specific into your code or into your log entry, rather, then
you are going to need to put some code in there.
So if you had an incoming event that invokes your lambda function and there was some data in the event
and you want that written into cloud, which logs, then you would need to write down your code.
And we've done that a few times in this course.
So all I'm going to do now is click on test scores so I can generate a single event.
Just call it T1 using the Hallowell template, click on Create and then Choose Test.
And so that's executed successfully.
Let's go to monitoring and view logs and cloud, which logs.
Now that takes us into a log group and a stream for us.
Lambda test cloud watch logs and we can see in the stream we have a single execution event, so I start
an end and then a report.
And this is a bit of information here, the build duration, the memory size and how long it took and
that kind of thing.
So that's what Lambda looks like.
Now, we've run some Ekta instances recently, so let's have a look into log groups and we can see we
don't have anything here for SETI.
So we have some excellent groups and we have LAMDA, but there's nothing for you to do.
So again, for that you would need to install the agent or use the API or the postscripts.
So Cloud, which logs, enables you to centralize the logs from all your systems, applications and
services.
A few of the features are you can monitor logs from EC2 and that's application and sys logs and you
can then also trigger notifications.
You can monitor cloud logged events and so you can actually create an alarm in cloud watch based on
API activity in in cloud trail.
So, for instance, you've got API activity happening in creating a logged event in cloud trail and
then you can use cloud watch alarms to send some kind of notification in terms of log retention by default,
they're retained indefinitely and it's configurable per load group from one day to ten years.
The logs agent.
So this is the cloud watch logs agent provides an automated way to send log data to cloud watch logs
for AC2 instances.
And then there's what's called the cloud watch agent.
So this is a unified agent.
So this actually isn't just about logging, it's about metrics as well.
And the Unified Cloud Watch agent includes metrics such as memory and disk utilization.
So this is another way that you can have some custom metrics generated by your two instances.
So let's have a look at a bit more detail about the cloud watch agent.
You can collect system level metrics from easy to instances across our operating systems.
You can get in guess metrics in addition to the standard metrics for you, and you can collect system
level metrics from on premises servers.
And they can be servers in a hybrid environment as well as servers that are not managed by us.
You can also retrieve custom metrics from applications or services using the stats d and collect the
protocols.
So that's it for this lesson.
And in the next lesson, we're going to have a look at cloud watch events.