Guys, in this section we had a bit more information on I am.
So the Identity and Access Management Service.
So just some key information you need to understand as it could come up in exam questions.
So remember where the access keys are stored and these are the combination of the access key I.D. and
the secret access key.
And you can have multiple profiles as well as the conflict file gets stored with the access keys in
the same directory.
And you can do stuff likes select the region and other parameters as well.
We then have policies.
So remember the differences.
The A.W. managed policy is a stand alone policy created and administered by a W.S..
It has its own MRN and they're designed to provide permissions for common use cases.
And you can't change those permissions.
Here's a series of A.W. Yes.
Managed policies.
As an example, there's many more.
Some manage policies also designed for specific job functions such as these job functions.
So it might be useful to use a managed policy, especially if you've got a scenario where it's a new
account and the administrators have it work with A.W. as much.
So it's an easy and perhaps a safer way to apply permissions if you don't know how to create the sort
of complex policies that might really sort of lock things down.
Customer manage policies are when you create a standalone policy that you administer and own and you
can attach them to multiple principal entities in your account.
When you attach a policy, the entity gets the permissions to find in the policy.
So that's an example of an easy to action hand for allowing any action on all resources but restricting
to a certain IP address.
The evaluation logic is something you need to understand.
We have our density based policies which get attached to an I am identity such as a user group or role.
We then have resource based policies.
These can be applied to resources such as S3 buckets and then you have the permissions boundaries,
which are an advance feature that sets the maximum permissions and identity based policy can grant to
an AI entity, user or role.
Now I mentioned in the section, I don't see this coming up on the exam, but it's just to help you
understand the chance I'm going to show you in a second.
The same applies to SICP as well.
I don't think they're coming up in the developer associate exam at this stage, but they're probably
more likely to, if anything.
So it might be worth doing a bit of background reading on organizations than we have session policies
which were advanced policies that you pass as parameters when you programmatically create a temporary
session for a role or user.
So by default, all requests are implicitly denied and explicit allow will override that default.
And then you've got some constraints around permissions, boundaries, organization escapee's and session
policies which might override with an implicit deny and explicit deny in any policy will override any
allows.
Now this is the chart from A.W. s, which shows you the logic for how policies are applied.
So I'm not gonna go for it in detail again now, but I would just read through that and try and understand
it is logical.
So once you've been over a couple of times, it does make sense.
We then have instant's profiles and an instance profile is a container for an item role that you could
use to pass RHOA information to an easy to instance when it starts an instance profile contains one.
I am wrong, although a role can be included in multiple instance profiles.
So it's basically like this.
You've got your AC2 instance running an application.
It has an instance profile with an I am role attached to it and that allows it to get temporary security
credentials, which it can use to access as free.
In this example, you can use these commands to work with instance profiles using the CLIA.
And we went through these in the section where I showed you how to create and delete an instance profile.
Next stop.
Cross account access.
Useful where you have multiple accounts.
So you might have a development and production resources and you want people to be able to access multiple
accounts without having to log out back in again.
So you can then switch roles, which is much easier, and you can sign in using your IAM username and
then switch to the other account instead of having to log out and log back in again.
So all about allowing users from one account to access the resources in another one to make a request
in a different account.
The resource in that account has to have an attached resource based policy with the correct permissions,
or you have to assume a role using an identity based policy within that account that has the permissions
you need.
So quick run through of the IAM best practices, lock away those route user access keys, create your
individual IAM users, don't share them.
Use groups to assign permissions to multiple I am users at a time grant list privilege.
Get started using permissions with a W.S. manage policies, just as I mentioned earlier in the exam.
Cramb.
That might be a better way in some.
Cases of getting started with a W.S. rather than creating complex policies where you might accidentally
give too many permissions but use customer managed policies instead of inline policies.
So remember, in line is when you attach it directly to a user or a roll, use access levels to review.
I am permissions just means that you need to review the permissions you've got assigned to make sure
that you are following the principle of least privilege.
Configure a strong password policy.
That's quite self-explanatory.
Enable multifactorial fence creation for extra security and use rolls for applications that run on E.S.
two instances instead of using access keys.
Also use rolls to delegate permissions.
Don't share your access keys.
Rotate your credentials like your access keys and your passwords, and remove unnecessary credentials
so that there's less chance of somebody maliciously using them.
Also, use policy conditions for extra security, such as the source IP address might be a condition
so that you specify exactly where people are allowed to connect from in order to administer and monitor
activity in your W.S. account.
So keep an eye on what's going on.