So in this lab we're going to cover identity based policies and we're going to focus on user policies
and policies that are applied to groups.
We're also going to have an example of a bucket policy in this lab.
So let's head over to the console.
Now I quickly want to show you this article and I'll provide a link in the course downloads.
This gives you some instructions on how to do a very similar scenario to what we're actually gonna go
through now and use some of the code snippets from this web page
so heading into the IAM management console I created a couple of users Paul and Sam and if we head over
to groups we've got the developers group.
And as you can see back on the user's page Paul is a member of the developers group.
I've created a bucket called DCT company and within DCT company we have a couple of folders to organize
some objects.
You can see a file which is up on the root of the bucket.
And then within each of these folders you'll also find a file.
So this is the set up we're going to use to show how we can use policies to restrict and provide access
to users.
So the first we're going to do.
I have some code here in text Wrangler and I'm going to copy this first piece of code and we're going
to come back to IAM and I'm going to go to policies create policy and we're going to choose JSON and
we're going to override this JSON here and we don't need to make any changes to this code.
What this will do is will allow the list or my bucket's privilege on any resource in S3 on this
account.
So this is a wildcard within S3 so we can click review policy and we need to give it a name
and we're going to call it allow LIST BUCKET.
Now we can click Create policy
we then kind of go to our group access the developers group and go to permissions and we can attach
a policy and I'm just going to start typing and there's our policy.
And so what we're going to do now is head over to a private window and I have Paul logged in.
Now Paul doesn't have any other privileges so he shouldn't be able to see anything in S3 but let's go
there now and what we should find is that he's able to list the buckets in the account and sure enough
we can see the buckets.
We can't see the file because the privilege which we provided only gives access to list the buckets
not any objects within the bucket.
So what I want to do now is provide this use of the additional capability to be able to view objects
within the roots of the bucket.
So coming back to I am I'm gonna head over and get my next piece of code
and we're going to go back into this policy allow this bucket and click on edit and JSON and I'm going
to remove this code and replace it with this piece of code.
Now what we need to do is replace the resource here with the correct ARN for our bucket.
So if we just go into S3 check the box next to our bucket and we can now copy the bucket either
and so I've copied that.
So the clipboard and if I come back here I can paste it in.
Now I've done this for all the other codes so we won't need to do it again.
But I wanted to show you where that's done we can now click on review policy
and save changes
now just to understand this code.
What this does is we have the resource still set to the bucket name but we now have a condition which
also allows us to access the prefixes and delimiters and a prefix would be a folder within the bucket
and the delimiter is the slash which allows access to objects beneath the root of the bucket.
So let's head back over to the private window and let's hit refresh
and we're not able to see any changes.
So let's just log out
and log Paul back in again.
So we'll log back in as Paul.
Let's head back to history.
So now I can say that not only can we see the photos but we can see this file object in the root of
the bucket
if we try to open one of these folders.
We'll find we get an Access Denied message because so far we've only allowed the list buckets and we've
now allowed objects within the bucket as well.
The same with the Department photo.
So what we want to do next is we're going to head over and get this next piece of code which is going
to allow our user to view the department folder contents and we're going to flip back to where I'm logged
in with my administrative account head to users.
And we're going to attach this one directly to Paul.
So in this case we're going to add an inline policy we click review we choose JSON we delete these
contents and then we paste this in.
Now what we need to do again is to change the IRS and here to the IRS about bucket
and then we need to change the folder name to department and we can click review policy.
We have to give it a name.
I'm just gonna call it allow department folder
and then we click Create policy so let's head back to our private window with Paul logged in and try
to access the department folder and let's just give it a refresh.
And sometimes this will work.
Sometimes we'll have to log back out back in again.
So I've looked pulled back in again.
Let's head into history.
We're going to go into our bucket and we're going to choose the department folder.
And so now we can see the contents of this bucket.
So let's try and download one of these files and I click on download I get an access is denied and let's
go back and try and upload a file.
So I'm just going to choose any file from my drive and click upload and we can see the file uploading
and then we'll get an error and we can view the details of the error as options request denied.
So we now want to give some additional permissions to this user so that the user can upload and download
objects.
So get and put objects so we're going to come back to our code and choose the next snippet and I'm going
to copy this back change to my minister to change to my administrative window and I'm going to go back
into this inline policy
click on edit policy Jason again and again and we're going to completely override this.
Let's just delete that code and place this back in.
Now in this case I've already updated the code.
So we already have the I ran for the bucket.
However it looks like I do need to copy it down here as well
so we have our eye around for a bucket.
We've got the Department folders set here.
And here we have the IRS for the bucket slash department slash staff.
So this should allow us to get objects and put objects in other words download and upload objects into
the department folder
so we click save changes and let's flip back to Paul's console.
And again we're going to log Paul out and back in again.
So we'll look back in as Paul and we're going to head back into S3
we're going to choose DCT company and department and so we can see the files but let's try and download
those one of these files.
So then a click download and sure enough it pops up on another screen.
That's the file which I wanted to download.
And now let's try and upload a file
and I'm just going to choose one of these text documents and click upload and strangely it's saying
I've got an actually I can see that the file is uploaded and here it is
so we're now able to get and put objects into this bucket.
But if we go up a level we still can't get into the confidential bucket.
And what I'm going to do now is a match going to let it create a bucket policy which allows us to act
to access this confidential folder.
So let's go a bucket policy
and let's grab this snippet of code and place this in.
Now what this does is it specifically calls out the ARN of Paul.
So this this applies to Paul only it allows Paul any action on the resource DCT company with the prefix
confidential slash star.
So in other words Paul gets it explicitly allowed to do any action he wants on the confidential folder
and its contents.
So let's click save and we're going to head back and click on refresh and sure enough straight away
we can see the confidential information in this bucket what I want to do now is show you how we can
explicitly deny access to the confidential folder.
In other words we're going to override the bucket policy.
So to do that I'm going to come back and I have a bit of a longer piece of code here.
But what this does is it's going to allow us access to the Department folder whilst explicitly denying
access to the confidential folder.
So let's come back to I am and we're going to apply this to our user Paul by overriding this JSON code
here
and it's click review policy and save changes and we can just quickly look at this code.
We have the allow permission on the bucket route and the string for that apartment folder slash star
and then we allow gets and puts object to the Department folder and then we have a explicitly deny any
requests statement which says let's bucket deny and we apply it to anything that isn't department.
So we don't explicitly state the confidential folder but we say that this user cannot access anything
other than the department folder so we've applied that.
Let's come back and click on confidential.
Now we've already seen this before so it actually shows the listed object but we also get the access
the night message so we can tell that this policy has taken effect so that's it for this exercise.
And if you want to remove the configuration you can simply go in and delete the policy that's attached
to Paul
can go into policies search for the policy that we created and delete and then the only other thing
you need to do is come back to the bucket access the bucket go to permissions bucket policy and you
can just click on delete
and that's it for this lab.
Hope you had some fun.
It's quite a complicated subject but worth going through a few practices and just getting yourself completely
comfortable with these techniques of applying policies that the bucket level as well as at the resource
level.