Hi guys.
If you followed through the previous lab you should be logged into the AWS management console with your
new AWS free tier account.
Now what we're going to do in this lab is going to be very very simple quick lab just to modify the
sign in link and that is the U.R.L. that users will use to log into your AWS account and you can modify
that to be a bit more user friendly.
Now the way we find services in the management console is even you can choose the fine services option
here and you can put in the name of the service or just click with your left mouse button and then you
can scroll down and see all the different services.
Alternatively you can go to the services menu at the top here and then you get a list of all IAM services
organized into categories.
You can also search again in the bar at the top end.
Now the service that we want to use is called Identity and Access Management or IAM often known as
"I am" and this is under the security identity and compliance category.
So I'm just gonna choose IAM.
We're now in the IAM dashboard and you can see at the top here we have the IAM users sign and link and
this is composed of the account number dot sign in dot AWS dot Amazon dot com slash console.
So users can use this to log in but what we can do is we can actually modify this sign and link so that
this section the account number is replaced by another value that we want to assign.
The way we customize this is by choosing the button customize.
And then we just type in the alias that we'd like to use.
I'm going to call this DCTLabs and I choose yes create.
Now this does need to be unique.
So you need to make sure that you've chosen a name that isn't already used and that's all we need to
do for now when we create an IAM user.
And we actually log in with a user account rather than the root account we'll actually be able to assign
this alias as the account name when we sign in.
So that's it for now guys.
In the next lab we're going to set up a billing alarm to make sure you don't get any surprise bills.