In this very quick lesson, I'm going to show you how you can create your own custom password policy
for your U.S. account.
So back in the Identity and Access Management Service, on the left hand side, I'm going to choose
account settings and here I can choose to change the password policy.
Now, note that there is a default password policy.
So even if you don't have your own custom password policy, IWC will still enforce the default password
policy.
And that says that your minimum password length is eight characters.
You must have a mixture of different character types, and it cannot be identical to your U.S. account,
name or email address.
Now, if that's not good enough for you, you can then change the password policy and change it to whatever
settings you want to apply.
So you can increase, for example, the minimum password length you might want to enable password expiration.
You might want to grant the permission for users to change their own passwords and prevent password
reuse.
So that's very simply how you are able to create your own custom password policy.
Now, it's important to note that the ability to change your own password is something that's supplied
through IAM permissions.
So here we have a permission to allow users to change their own password, and that will apply to everyone.
If you don't enable that, you can selectively grant permissions for individual groups of users to change
their password.
You would do that through permissions policies that you attach to a group or two users.
Now I'm not going to apply a password policy, I'm just going to cancel out of here.
I'm quite happy with the default password policy for my accounts.