Hi, guys.
This is just a very quick lab to actually show you around the eight up U.S. migration hub.
So under migration and transfer, we've had a look at these services.
And what I want to do now is just show you the actual migration hub itself.
And you can see, you know, what it does and what it integrates with.
So we're on the migration hub and you can see you've got the option here to discover.
So you can import data, deploy discovery tools and then group your servers as applications so you can
find, you know, groups of servers that are related in their application architecture and group them
together so that you've got a better understanding of what you need to do with them.
You can then assess so you can get recommendations.
And then you can migrate.
So you can connect your migration tools and then actually migrate your servers and your applications
and also your data.
And so at the bottom here, you can see what it's integrated with.
So we've got the A.W. as discovery connectors, the IWC discovery agents.
Then we've got the actual migration tools, the DMSO, the estimates, the cloud and GM migration and
this eighty-eight data, A.S.A. motion.
And then there's just a mention of some of the migration programs that are available and the documentation's
of Paul.
So you can on the left hand side here, find the integration's with the different tools, so you got
service here where you could start importing some service to migrate.
You've got applications.
You've got your data coaxes.
So if you had some connectors out there, then you might be out to see your connectors and their status
here.
And then you've also got some tools where you can import and you can connect your discovery connectors
and deploy your discovery agents.
So that's all in discovery.
Then you've got the access.
So this is where you can actually look at your US assessment tools so you can rightsize your instances,
try and work out, you know, what type of instance types you should be using.
Look at some recommendations and export those details.
And then down here, we have the actual migration.
So now we can actually use these services to migrate your applications.
And if you just head down to tools here, you can see this is where you can then connect in the server
migration service and the DMSO Database Migration Service as well.