This is a fiery lecture on Amazon A.D.s encryption, there can be some exam questions popping up, and
I want to make sure you're armed with all the facts you need.
So encryption at rest can be enabled for your Amazon A.D.s instance, so Buy-Out rest, we're talking
about the storage.
So your Ebb's volumes, any backups that are taken.
So point in time, backups, read replicas are also encrypted if you encrypt the master database and
then snapshots, which are obviously the snapshots from your Ebb's volumes, it uses IIS two, five
six encryption.
It's transparent.
So the process is transparent, meaning it happens in the background.
And there's minimal performance impact, so you shouldn't notice a performance impact on your database
now, it absolutely must be enabled at DB creation time.
So remember that one really important.
You cannot enable encryption for your database instance at a later point in time with ideas for Oracle
and SQL Server.
You can also use transparent data encryption.
Now, this is encryption and the database layer.
So it's not A.D.s performing the encryption and it may have a performance impact.
Adewusi KMC is used for managing the encryption keys associated with the encryption here.
Now from Read Replicas, if you create a read replica of an encrypted database, it will also be encrypted
if the replica is in the same region as the master database, you can use the same encryption key to
encrypt the Reed replica.
If the replica is in a different region than a different key must be used.
So remember, you can only enable encryption for instances when you create it, not later on.
Now, I'm going to show you a workaround in a second, and that's really important because it comes
up in exam scenario questions.
So DBI instances that are encrypted can be modified to disable encryption, so once you've enabled encryption,
you can't then later on decide that you want an unencrypted database.
You also can't have an encrypted replica of an unencrypted DB instance or an unencrypted replica of
an encrypted DB instance.
So just to simplify that, if your databases encrypted, your marriage replica is encrypted and that's
the way it has to be.
And if your databases unencrypted, your read replica is unencrypted, there are no other options,
they're encrypted replicas must be encrypted with the same key as the source DBI instance when they're
in the same region.
You can't restore an unencrypted backup or snapshot to an encrypted DB instance, so if your database
instance is encrypted, your snapshots are encrypted, and if your database is unencrypted, your snapshots
are unencrypted and you can't restore an unencrypted backup to an encrypted DB instance.
So I mentioned that there's a workaround.
So let's say you created this database up on the left there.
So this instance is unencrypted and you want to encrypt that database.
So as you know, you can't do that.
You can't go into the arts management console and enable encryption.
So remember all this for the exam.
You might have an exam question that poses this scenario.
One of the answers is likely to be that you go to the management console and just simply enable encryption.
So remember, you can't do that now.
This means that your this is unencrypted.
So the Ebb's volume for this database instance is unencrypted, and that means the snapshots you take
from it are unencrypted.
But what we can then do is create a copy of the snapshot and encrypt the copy of the snapshot.
So now we have an encrypted snapshot from unencrypted database.
We can then restore that database.
So we're actually going to create a new instance and that has a new end.
So that's important to understand.
It's not going to be the same.
One is going to be a new instance.
But now you've taken an encrypted snapshot and created an encrypted database instance.
So that's the way to get from unencrypted to encrypted.
And it does mean you're going to create a new instance with a new endpoint.
So you need to consider how to then cut that over in your application.