Hi guys.
In this lab we're going to create an auto scaling group and application load balancer and we're going
to attach the auto scanning group to the load balancer.
So let's head into the console and build out the architecture that you can see on your screen here.
I mean the easy to management console and what I need to do is go down to auto scaling and auto scaling
groups.
Now you need a launch configuration but if you go to the wizard for creating an auto scaling group it
actually just starts you off anyway.
So it says step one is to create or select a launch configuration and then step two is to create the
auto scaling group.
So if you choose get started you then have to choose your Amazon then it's 2 am I and you then have
to choose your instance type and we're going to choose the T micro and you need to call this something
so I'm just going to call the LC 1 I am going to use my I am wrong and I am going to specify some user
data so as with the previous lamps we're going to paste this user data in.
That actually gives our instance a name.
Now you'll notice under IP address type the default is to only assign a public IP to instances launched
in the default VPC in subnet.
Well in this case that's what we're doing we're going into the default VPC as it's the only one we have.
So I can leave that as it is.
I can then go to security groups and choose my web access security group.
And if that's I do have a custom BPC so I'm going to choose this one here which I know it's the web
access security group in my default VPC we can then choose review and we can then create the launch
configuration so you can see that the launch configuration defines the EMI you use the instance type.
And then some additional details such as the IAM role the tenancy and the IP address type and also storage
and security groups.
So you define this stuff in your launch configuration.
Now you can't change your launch configuration you can always delete and create a new one but you can't
actually modify it.
So let's choose create launch configuration and we have to specify the keeper.
And now we get thrown straight into the wizard for tracing the auto scaling creep.
So I'm going to call this ASG one and we can specify the amount of instances we want to start with.
I'm going to choose two.
We can choose our VPC and then we can choose our subnet.
So I'm just going to choose two subnets in my default VPC.
If you wanted to you could then go down to advance details and you can attach a load balancer.
We haven't created our load balancing yet so we can't do that.
You can specify the health check grace period which is the amount of time auto scaling weights before
checking in instances health you can see information about monitoring.
And it tells us that we're basic monitoring is going to be enabled and we can have incidence protection
if we want to protect certain instances from scale in events where instances are terminated.
So we don't need to change any of that at this stage.
Let's choose next.
And you now get to configure your scaling policies so you can even keep this group at its initial size
and what that will mean is we specified two instances.
If an instance becomes unhealthy it will be replaced.
So there'll always be two instances or you can use a scaling policy and you can say well let's scale
between 2 and 4 instances and let's do it based on CPC utilization and other options include the network
in and out and the request count per target.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm going to specify a value of 70 percent and what that means is auto scaling
will try and keep the utilization at or close to the target value of 70 percent.
You can also use different types of scaling policies such as step policies and when you use these you
have a bit more granularity in how you can scale out and scale back in again.
And in this case you can create alarms and you can choose from several different metrics so you can
include disk Io network and CPE utilization.
Let's go back to our target tracking policy.
So let's go forward and we can configure notifications.
I'm not going to send one.
We can add tags.
I'm not going to do that even.
So let's just go to review and create auto scaling group.
So the auto scaling group is being created.
We can see here that we have a desired capacity of two instances a minimum of two and a maximum of four
and you can look through the activity history here you can see that it's telling us that two instances
are being launched and those instances are not yet in service.
You can look at your scaling policies here and you can edit them.
You can have a look at the instances that are being launched.
There are a whole series of metrics which you can monitor and you can configure notifications as well
using the simple notification service.
So just cancel on that one.
There is also scheduled actions where you can create scaling policies that happen at specific times.
So you might want to scale just at the time that you know load is going to be increased so if you have
an event that's happening and you know a specific time that you need to be able to provision or launch
new instances you can use a scheduled action.
So let's go up to instances and we should see are two instances being launched there we go and they're
already in the running state so we can now go and create our load balancer I'm going to create an application
load balancer it's gonna be called My Alby I'm gonna specify two subnets in fact and then specify free
just because I'm not sure which subnets might instances were launched into so I'll specify all to make
sure and let's go to security groups choose web access and for routing I'm going to create a new target
group called T one we're gonna use the instance target type and we're going to leave our settings except
with healthy threshold will be reduced to two and we're not going to register our targets because we
don't want to add the individual targets in we want to connect the auto scaling group and that means
that when additional instances are added to the auto scaling group by auto scaling the low balance it
will automatically know about them you don't have to manually add the men so let's go to create and
our life balance is being created we can now go back to our auto scaling group choose actions.
Edit and under target groups we can choose target one target group one so that will connect us to our
load balancer.
Classic low balances can be found here or target groups can be found for network low balances and application
load balances while we're in here.
You can see that there's a health check type and it's easy to.
You can also have a health check type of EOP which means that the low balance is going to perform the
health checks and we're going to have a lab and go into the details of these and how they work a bit
later on in the section so I'm just gonna choose safe and let's have a look at our instances so we can
see that these are in service and they're healthy.
So from the auto screening Group's perspective it sees these as healthy instances they've passed their
easy to status checks and let's head over to low balances.
In fact what we want to do is go to target groups targets and we can see that our targets are in an
initial status so they're going to need a few minutes to become healthy.
So that didn't take very long.
The instances are now both in a healthy status so if we go back to load balancer and get our DNS name
we should find that we're able to connect all our instances and we've got Frida and Mammy.
So there we go we can cycle between these two easy two instances.
So that is our architecture set up it's quite simple really.
We've got our auto scaling group.
We've actually only got two easy two instances at this stage but we could have a maximum of four.
And we have an application load balancer that's connected to the auto screening group and distributing
connections.
What I want to do in the next lab is just explore the scaling policies and a bit more detail and actually
put it into action and show you what happens when we generate some load on the easy two instances and
cause a skating event.