Hello and welcome to another exam cram.
This one's for section 14 on CloudFormation an Elastic Beanstalk.
And again I'm going to give you the key facts
I think you need to know for the exam so starting off for CloudFormation. CloudFormation is
a way that you have a common language in which you can describe and provision infrastructure resources.
So remember that it's about infrastructure.
It's not the application it's the infrastructure so CloudFormation can be used to provision a broad
range of AWS resources.
I think it pretty much works with every AWS service.
So it's very broad in scope.
Now a CloudFormation we're talking about infrastructure as code and that means that you can write some
code that describes the infrastructure you want to provision and CloudFormation will go and use that
code to actually create that environment for you.
Now Elastic Beanstalk is more focused on deploying applications so you really need to understand the
difference between these two.
So think of beanstalk as being a platform service and that's creating an application environment whereas
a CloudFormation is creating the infrastructure. CloudFormation can actually deploy an Elastic Beanstalk
environment we saw this in the labs when we actually create an Elastic Beanstalk environment.
If we go in looking CloudFormation we can see that actually it's CloudFormation that is creating that
environment but you can't do it the other way round.
So Elastic Beanstalk can't do any CloudFormation provisioning. You have something called a logical ID.
And these are used to reference resources within the template and then you have the physical IDs
and these identify resources outside of the template of the resources of being created.
So we've seen this in the console when we have created some resources and we can actually go and have
a look at what resources have been created.
So a few of the components of CloudFormation. We have templates.
These are the JSON or YAML text files that contain the instructions for building the environment.
Then we have a stack so a stack is the actual environment.
So when we've gone and created something in CloudFormation what we're actually doing is creating a
stack and that stack then uses the template and creates the environment we then have something called
a change set and this is where you can create a summary of the proposed changes to your stack and have
a look at how those changes are going to actually impact the resources before you actually go live.
So for updating the stacks there's two methods you can either directly update or execute a change set.
If you directly update the stack you submit the changes and CloudFormation immediately deploys them
so their live, they've updated your live environment.
You might want to use direct updates when you need to really quickly deploy some kind of change to your
environment.
However with the change set as I mentioned before you can preview the changes that CloudFormation is
going to make without actually applying them to your life environment.
So we then stack sets. Stack sets
extend the functionality of a stack by enabling you to create update or delete stacks across accounts
and regions with a single operation so you can't create a stack that's cross region but you can create
a stack set and that means that you can then create stacks in different regions.
So that means using a single administrative account you can then define and manage the CloudFormation
template and use the template for provisioning stacks into different target accounts and across different
regions.
So moving onto Elastic Beanstalk.
So this is where you're deploying and managing applications in the cloud.
And the key use case here is that you have developers for instance and they want to upload some code
and they want to put that code on to some kind of application framework might be nodeJS might be .NET
or some other framework and they don't want to have to launch EC2 instances and set up load balancing
and set up auto scaling and all that kind of stuff they just want to upload their code so beanstalk
means that you can very easily create that underlying environment so all you have to do is upload code
it will leverage Elastic Load Balancing and auto scaling so that you can scale your application in and
out as you need to and you can deploy it to multiple Availability Zones to have your resiliency and
reliability.
So again Elastic Beanstalk is considered to be a platform as a service solution and it supports these
different frameworks of Java, .NET, PHP.
NodeJS, Python, Ruby, Go and docker. So Elastic Beanstalk can provision most database instances
and it allows you to have full control of the underlying resources.
So even though it's managing and creating that environment for you you still have full access so you
can SSH into the operating system of your EC2 instances or manage your databases.
You can store your application files and also server logs if you need to in Amazon S3 and your application
data can also be stored onto S3.
It supports multiple environments and you can enable versioning for your environments and you can also
replicate changes from get repositories.
So finally just comparing the two again.
So CloudFormation and Elastic Beanstalk think template driven provisioning for CloudFormation think
web apps made easy for Elastic Beanstalk.
Now you'll see use cases for CloudFormation where people need to consistently, repeatedly, securely, deploy
infrastructure.
So maybe you've got a systems integration company and they need to build an environment for customers
and maybe they build a very similar environment for different customers in different parts of the world
and they need to make sure that they can very easily and repeatedly deploy that environment.
So using something like CloudFormation means that they can write their code once and then repeatedly
use it.
That reduces administrative effort.
That means that if you set that environment up securely through the code then every time you set it
up it's gonna be secure.
And again the key use case for Elastic Beanstalk is where you just have some application code using
one of those frameworks like Java or .NET or PHP and you just need to upload that code and have an
environment ready to run so you upload the Zip or WAR files.
In the case of Elastic Beanstalk and use JSON or YAML template files with CloudFormation.