Hi, guys, in this lesson, we're going to cover three somewhat related features of free called versioning
replication and lifecycle rules.
Starting off with versioning, this is a means of keeping multiple variants of an object in the same
bucket.
So in other words, you upload an object like a file and then you edit that file somewhere else and
you upload a new version of that file to as free.
Now what as free will do is will keep multiple versions so you can see the old version and the modified
new version, and you can restore the old version if you need to.
So use versioning to preserve, retrieve and restore every version of each object in your pockets.
Burgeoning enable buckets will enable you to recover objects from accidental deletion or overwrite.
So remember those two because they can come up as exam topics and make sure you remember that these
are a couple of the key benefits of versioning.
Next, we have free replication.
Now we have two forms of this one is called cross-regional replication C Ah, and this has been around
for quite a long time.
We have a bucket in one region here and another bucket in a different region, and we simply set up
replication so that any data that's written to the bucket in the region on the left is also replicated
to the bucket in the region on the right.
Next, we have same region replication and this is just the same thing, but within a region that was
added a little more recently.
Now, in both cases, this can not only be across buckets, but also across accounts.
So whether you're using the same region replication or cross region replication, you can also have
different accounts for the source and destination buckets.
Buckets must also have versioning enabled.
You will not be able to set up any kind of replication without having versioning enabled first.
We then have a lifecycle management.
This enables you to achieve two things ever transitioning an object through to a different storage class
or exploring the objects, in other words, deleting the objects.
So those are transition actions and exploration actions.
So what are the options?
Well, this kind of waterfall visual here on the right hand side shows you what the possible transitions
actually are.
So we've got standard at the top then standard i.e. intelligence sharing, one zone glacier in glacier
deep archive and you can see how you can transition objects.
So what you can do is from the standard storage class to any other storage class, any storage class
to glacier and glacier deep archive.
Standard idea to intelligence sharing or one zone, i.e., intelligence sharing to one zone idea and
glacier to glacier deep archive.
Now what can't you transition?
Well, you can't transition from any storage class to see free standard or from any storage class to
reduced redundancy.
Remember, as legacy, it's kind of still possible to use it, but it's not something that comes up
very much anymore.
The intelligence sharing storage class to S3 Standard I.a and one zone idea to S3 Standard IEEE or intelligent
sharing.
So useful just to remember these.
We do get scenarios in the exam where they give you some specific requirements for keeping data and
perhaps deleting it or archiving it, or retaining it for compliance reasons for a certain period of
time.
And then you've got to work out from the answers which storage classes and which sort of transition
actions you would use.
So that's it for the ferry.
In the next couple of lessons, we're going to see how you can put all of this into action.