Hi, guys.
Security groups and network access control lists, ACLs are two different types of firewall that we
can apply in our IWC environment, so let's have a look at how they work.
So here we have a VPC with two availability zones, and we've got a couple of public and private subnets,
and we've got a few easy two instances that have been launched into different public submarkets and
private subnets.
So let's see how we can control traffic.
Firstly, we can apply something called a network access control list, a network ICL.
Now these are applied at the subnet level, so you can see that they're sitting here at the edge of
the subnet.
Now, all traffic that goes into and out of a subnet will go through a network scale.
So you're essentially filtering traffic as it enters or exits the subnet.
So ingress and egress traffic, a security group is different.
A security group actually applies at the instance level of an S2 instance, actually at the network
interface level of the active instance.
So that means we can have a security group that is applied to issue two instances in different subnet.
So this is the same security group security group A, and it's been applied to instances in several
different subnet.
So remember that this is the instance level that means it's going to filter traffic going between instances
in the same subnet or across different subnets.
We could then have security group B that's attached to different instances.
So security groups can be applied to instances in any subnet.
Now what happens here with these security groups is the same basic thing as a network scale.
They are looking for traffic that's going in and out of the security group.
So if you send traffic from an instance in security group A to an instance in security group B, it's
going to check that there's a rule to allow the outbound traffic.
And then it's going to check here the security group is going to check.
Am I going to allow the traffic from security group A?
And you can do that by IP address, or you could actually do it by the I.D. of the security group itself.
We'll look at all this in detail in the hands on as well.
Now I want to talk to you about stateful versus state less firewalls because the security group is a
stateful firewall and a network.
ICL is a stateless firewall, and it's really important to understand the difference.
So let's look at an example.
We have a client here.
So this is a computer that wants to access a service on a web server and we've got a firewall in the
middle.
So what happens is the client is going to connect to the server, the servers, a web server, it's
listening on Port 80.
The source port is the port that's assigned to the connection by the computer and is what's called a
high number port, it's a port above 1024 and is dynamically assigned for every connection.
So we have a source port and a destination port and we have a source and destination IP as well.
Now the return traffic has a source port of Port AC because that's where the web service port runs and
the destination port of six five one eight eight.
And of course, the ships are switched around as well, so the destination IP will be the client.
The source IP will be the web server.
Now what do we need in the firewall rules able to allow this to work?
Well, what we need here is we need a rule for GCP that allows the source IP ten point one one point
one to talk to the destination IP send up to the 1.10.
And it has to have the source port and the destination port specified.
Now, of course, this is a dynamically assigned port, so we don't know what that is ahead of time.
So what you would most likely have here is any.
So rather than having this source port specified, we'd have the any specified so any source port is
acceptable.
And then rather than a specific source IP, we might have any because it's an internet based connection.
So those are things that we can play around with in our rule tables.
But the destination port will always be AC because that's where the web server runs.
So we want to make sure that we don't allow connections to any ports on the web server.
Now that's the traffic coming inbound to the web server.
What about the return traffic going back?
Well, in that case, things are swapped around, so we've got the same protocol the source IP of the
web server, the destination IP of the client and the source port of Haiti and the destination port
of the dynamic for the clients.
Now again, you'd probably have the destination port and the destination IP is any because you want
to allow traffic coming from any client on the internet.
If you're running a public web service, but you still might need a ruleset for the outbound traffic.
And this is where the difference comes in between state full and state less firewalls, so a state full
firewall will allow the return traffic automatically.
Now this is what a security group is.
What that means is with a security group, you only need this role at the top here.
You need a rule that says that you're going to allow the traffic from whatever client, whatever port,
but you're going to allow inbound to port data on your web server.
And then the return traffic is automatically allowed so you don't have to worry about the return traffic.
It's going to just go out automatically.
It's going to be allowed because the firewall is clever enough to know that that's part of the connection.
And so it just allows that return traffic.
Now, a state less firewall checks and allow rule for both connections.
Now this is what a network ACL does.
So if a network ACL, you need both the inbound rule and the outbound rules, so you need to make sure
that you have the inbound row for traffic coming in.
And the outbound rule for traffic going back, even if it's the same connection, it doesn't understand
that that's part of the same connection.
It treats them separately.
So really important to understand those differences when you configure your network cycles.
Now, let's have a look at a security group.
This is what a security group ruleset looks like.
So here we have separate rules defined for inbound and outbound traffic.
What we're looking at here is the inbound traffic.
Now, again, because it's stateful, we don't have to have a rule for the return traffic, but we still
might need an outbound roll for traffic going out from our instances.
So when are instances that are attached to the security group initiating connections outbound?
So here we can see we have several rules using different protocols and we've got the protocol specified,
the port range and then the source and the source.
In many cases, might be either an IP address or IP address range, or it can be a security group I.D.
as well.
Security group support allow rules only, so there's no such thing as a deny role in a security group.
Essentially, there's an implicit denial at the end of the rule set, and it's going to check for an
alarm.
And if there is no allow, then by default it's just going to deny the traffic.
As I mentioned, a security group can use a source of an IP address and IP address range or the security
group de of itself or another security group.
Now, let's have a look at a best practice configuration when using security groups.
What we have here is a public subnet and a private subnet.
And we've got an internet facing load balancer, so this is going to distribute traffic to our web servers.
So we have a load balancer.
We have a web server frontend.
So this is the one that's actually uses a connecting to from the internet.
And then there's an application layer that's going to process data.
And this could have multiple servers.
So we have a load balancer and we need a connections to be able to come from our clients on the internet
through to the application layer.
It might then write to a database, so haven't shown that in this diagram.
So let's see how we set this up.
Firstly, we create a security group for the public Albi.
It allows traffic on Port 80 for the web service from any source on the internet.
Now outbound, it has because it's going to now create a connection to the web front end.
It has a rule that allows outbound access to Port 80.
And we've specified the actual security group in the public EC2.
So that's the name of this security group.
So it's only going to allow traffic outbound to the web frontend.
The web frontend allows traffic only from the public.
Albi on Port 80.
And then it has a destination for outbound traffic of another security group called Private Albi and
a port of HKT, so that's what that particular application is listening on.
The private ALP security group will in turn only allow inbound traffic from the public to security group,
and it will only allow outbound traffic to the private to security group, and that's the one which
has the application layer in it.
So that's a way that we're locking down access to the different layers of our application and ensuring
that the application can talk to other components, but nothing else can.
So that's a best practice security group configuration.
Now let's have a look at network schools.
One of the first things you'll notice is we have inbound and outbound rules again, and we have allow
and deny rules.
So with an you can have an explicit deny that's different to security groups.
Remember members security groups only support allow rules.
Rules are processed in order so you can see that they're numbered.
So it's typically no all rules, and you might want to say that the next rules that you add in are two
hundred and two hundred and one and then three hundred and 301.
You can work out your own process for how you assign those numbers.
But just remember that they will be processed in order.
Now, the important fact about that means that once you actually reach a rule that ever allows or denies
traffic, the processing stops there.
So if we have an allow rule at 100 that allow us to traffic, then even if you had a deny rule later
on in the rules set for that specific traffic, it's not going to get there.
It's going to allow it because it reaches to allow and processing finishes.
So you've got to be very careful with how you set up your rules, the order that you create the men.
And just remember that they will be processed in order.
And then when a allow or deny is reached, then that's the end of the processing it will ever allow
or deny the connection.
So that's it for the ferry.
In the next lesson, we're going to do some hands on and set up our security groups and network cycles.