My guys in this lab we're going to cover VPC flow logs so VPC flow logs enable you to capture information
about the data that's going into and out of your easy two instances and you're able to log that to cloud
watch logs and Amazon is free.
Now the diagram here is showing that there's three different places where you can enable flow logs.
You can do it at the VPC level and you can do it at the public so you can do it at the subnet level.
Doesn't matter if it's public or private.
And then you can do it at the easy to instance level which means that it's actually attached to the
elastic network interface of the easy to instance.
So we're going to go for a lab and we're just going to enable flow logs in a couple of places and see
what data we can capture so in the IWC management console.
I've already launched an AC DC two incidents and what I need to do now is to go to identity and access
management and create a role.
Now what I'm doing is I'm pretty much following along with this article from.
So if you have a search for a publishing flow logs to cloud which logs and this gives you the instructions
I'm about to follow.
And one of those things is I need to have this Jason statement which I'm going to attach as a inline
policy to the role and it gives the permissions to create a log crew credit log stream write the events
and then to be able to list those events.
So.
So we need to copy this to a clipboard and this is a restrictive policy so it means that we're giving
the minimum rights we need to which is a security best practice.
So let's head back to I am and go to roll's great role and I'm gonna come down here and choose easy
to and then select your use case.
I mean I choose easy to and I pretty much just go through and finish this off by giving it a name.
I'm just going to call it flow dash logs and I can create that roll so I haven't given any permissions
yet.
So let's go into your flow logs and I'm going to add an inline policy change to Jason.
I'm going to get rid of the Jason code that's in there and I'm gonna put in my restrictive policy.
Now we can hit review give it a name
just called it flow lock policy and create policy so that's done.
And what we need to do now is oh there's one more thing we need to do here so we have to go to trust
relationships.
Edit trust relationship.
And if we come back here we can see there's this code here that we need to change so we can grab this
copy it to the clipboard come back over and paste this in
does make sure I got rid of all the code.
Yeah that looks good.
So and then we just hit update flow policy and all it's done is it's changed easy to do Amazon to IWM
stop come to BPC flow logs so that's uptight the trust policy.
So we've created our role and what we need to do now is head over to cloud watch.
So cloud watch performance monitoring for all resources and we want to go to logs and create a new log
group and we're just going to call this my flow logs
so that's very easy.
We just head over to the easy to console now and I've launched a single instance running a public submit
within my custom VPC I'm going to copy its IP address and we're now going to enable the flow log.
So we come down to network interfaces because you're actually going to attach this to the network interface.
So we're going to click actions create flow log and you can choose except rejects or all in this case
I'm just gonna filter to log packets that are accepted and we drop down into the dropdown box here when
we choose our destination log group and we can come down now and choose our role that we've previously
created and it's click on Create.
So now you can see that we have a flow log and see under flow logs here you can see that it's going
to filter to accept what I'm also gonna do is create an additional flow log.
So you can create multiple flow logs with different parameters.
This one is gonna be filtering for reject.
So I just want these to go into a separate look file but they're going to be in the same log group.
And you need to know that if you ever need to make a change to a flow log you just gotta delete it and
create a new one.
You can't modify it.
So we've got those flow logs set up correctly.
Let's go to a command prompt and what I want to do is use the Net cat utility which is NC I put in the
public IP address and first name when to choose a port which I know I have access to.
So net cat just creates a connection to the host that you provide or IP address on a port that you specify
just tries to create a network connection so that data will definitely hit a WS.
So if I click on answer it we can see the.
We get some return traffic here it tells us it's open SSA so we know that support that's open on our
Amazon land it's easy to instance I can break that connection and come back and let's go to cloud watch.
And we're gonna go to logs my flow logs.
So that took a few minutes but we've now got a log stream for accept and reject.
So we see that they're in two different log streams so let's hit the accept and we can look in here
we can see some information you get an I.D. you get the account number you get the elastic network interface
I.D. you get the source IP address and then you get the destination IP address which is always the private
IP address of the instance.
And then you can see the port source and destination ports some information about the protocol and the
bytes and then accept.
So we can see that this is a package that's been accepted.
So if we look towards the bottom of the file to the newer entries we should be at to see some entries
here and we can see Port 22.
And those are packets that have been accepted.
Port 22 again.
So that's the SSA connection so we now want to have a look in the regex stream.
And I've waited a few minutes because the events update about every 10 minutes or so in the meantime
what I did was I just tried to connect on a few more well-known ports to this instance.
Now if it looks a bit different to your console you even have this row format or text.
I prefer text.
So if we head down for instance I tried to connect on port 21.
So there we see a regex.
That's the FDA port which is an open on our server.
So what we're able to see from this then is that even if a security group is rejecting it we still get
the log here despite the fact that it hasn't actually reached the operating system.
So you can use this to identify how your security groups are configured and whether they're accepting
or rejecting the right traffic.
So the other thing I want to show you is let's go back to VPC and I want to show you where else you
can create a flow log.
So in the VPC dashboard you can choose your VPC highlight it and then you can go create flow log and
this will then capture flow logs from all the resources annual BPC so all network interfaces in your
VPC.
The other place you can do it is at the subnet level.
So then it will just capture flow logs for all traffic in your subnet.
Again from the network interfaces in your subnet.
So again you just go in and create flow log and it's the same screen whichever way you go.
So that's it for this lab.
We can we can stop this by going back so easy to head down to network interfaces and you can always
just delete your fly logs from here.
Of course we're going to we're going to terminate this instance anyway.
So I don't really need to do that but that's where you can go in and manage those flight logs if you
need to.
So we can just terminate our instance we've got rid of our flow log.
And if you'd like to you can also remove your IAM role and we can also head into cloud watch go to logs
and just remove this log group
so that's it the flow logs key thing to remember is that you can create them at the VPC level the subnet
level or the network interface level and that they're going to log traffic even if that traffic is rejected
by a security group you'll be able to see that in the flow log.
So it's a great way of testing and seeing what's hitting your security groups and then being either
accepted or rejected.
And the one other thing for the exam is to make sure you remember if you need to modify a flow log you
need to delete it and recreate that you can't change it.