We have these two snapshots that we created earlier of a root and a data volume and all I want to
show you here is how you can create a image or an AMI from one of these snapshots and we can also go
in and create a volume from the snapshot and choose which availability zone.
And that would just create an EBS volume or we can go in and copy it and we can copy to another region
or the other option there is.
And interestingly actually when you go into here you can see that you can optionally encrypt the snapshot.
Go into all that and a lot more detail later in this lab.
But for now let's look at creating an image.
So this is creating an AMI.
So let's just call this DCT labs AMI and you can choose the device name and you can choose various
other things around which type of hardware virtualization you use that ram this guy the kernel ID
and so on and we're just going to leave that defaults.
We could also use these snapshot idea of the other volume to actually add that in here so we could press
start in and just search for it and add the second volume in but we don't need to do that for now.
So let's just click on Create and what we should now find is that we have an AMI here so if we go into
instances and you can see that it's very quick because it's actually using that snapshot.
So it does require that snapshot to be available because the AMI links back to the snapshot.
So if we go into launch an instance now we can choose my AMIs and we can find our AMI in here and
then because it's an AMI we can then choose we're free to do whatever we want.
We can then choose to put it in any availability zone we like.
So I'll put it into to see where we haven't had any volumes or snapshots or we haven't had any volumes
or instances running in that availability zone.
So let's just click Next we can see the configuration and the snapshot I.D. which is the snapshot there's
some EMI backs off which is the same snapshot that we created earlier on so I'm just gonna go and choose
my security group and launch.
So that instance is running now and I've copied the public IP.
So let's just go over and secure shell into this instance so that's the instance is up and running and
we should be able to find our data directory there it is.
So you know we won't find anything in it if we change the slash data but at least we did create that
directory so it shows that we're using, we've booted off that snapshot.
And if we'd had any data in there that was local to that root volume we'd see it in this case we've
just got the Mount point that we use for the second volume.
So that's us using an AMI within the region.
Let's now look at how we can copy the AMI between regions so it can now simply go in here.
Copy AMI and choose another region.
I'm going to choose Singapore and click copy AMI and we could again encrypt the snapshot if we wanted
to.
So that's going to copy.
And by the way there'll be some transfer charges for integration transfer here.
So if you do this you might incur some charges so here we go we can see this is pending and the data's
in process and that's being transferred.
I'm actually just gonna kill this off because it's not really going to prove much but what I would be
able to do once that's complete is go in here and choose my AMIs and it would be available to me.
So that's how you can copy AMIs between regions and launch from them.
And the way you get rid of an AMI is you deregister it.
And if I do that it just deletes it.
And in this case we can see the snapshot which it was also copying across because remember that AMI
is backed by a snapshot.
So we can see that it's copied the snapshot across.
So let's also delete the snapshot
and now we're clear.
And so now want to go back and see the Sydney region
and I can go up and shut down my instance will terminate my instance and we finished with these two
now so we're just going to delete out these EBS volumes
and I'm going to keep these snapshots because we might work with these in the next labs but I can go
in and just deregister my AMI.