In this lesson, I'm going to show you the difference between access keys and IAM roles.
And we're going to use both of them for the same purpose to access some data in Amazon is free, but
you'll see how the implementation is slightly different and how one way is a bit more secure than the
other.
So back in the console here, I'm going to launch an active instance.
It's going to be a Linux two Army, 82 Micro, and we're not going to change anything here.
Go through to Security Group, just select our Web Access Security Group and then launch that instance.
Now, while that's launching, I'm going to go to services and open the SE free service under storage.
It's free is what's known as an object based storage system.
You'll learn a lot more about it later in the course.
For now, I'm going to create a bucket, and a bucket is simply a container.
It's kind of like a directory in which you can store data.
I'm going to call my DCT Dash IWC Dash Cloud, Dash Labs.
Now, this does need to be unique in the world, so hopefully nobody else has that specific name.
The region is USC small Virginia.
That's fine, and I'm just going to scroll down to the bottom and create the buckets.
And sure enough, that's been allowed.
So you'll need to change your bucket name.
You can't have the same one as me.
Let's just choose the bucket here, and I'm simply going to upload a couple of files.
So choose add files.
And I've got a couple of images here, so I'll just choose those images.
It really doesn't matter for the purposes of this exercise.
Just choose any small images you have.
So those have been successfully uploaded now back in easy to, I'm going to select my instance, choose,
connect and use EC2 instance connect.
Click on the Connect button, and now I'm logged into my EC2 instance.
So let's try and run a command.
I'm going to run IWC.
That's free.
Less so now it should list the names of the buckets that we have in the accounts.
But of course it doesn't.
We saw this earlier.
We need to run this command called IWC Configure.
And it's going to need an access key and a secret ID.
So let's go and get those first back in the console.
We're going to go to services.
Scroll down to security, identity and compliance and choose I am in the I am console.
We're going to choose users.
Select your user accounts, go to security credentials, and then create an access key.
So select this one.
Now, the key thing to understand about access case is that you only get to see the secret access key
once.
Now you can download the file, but you only get to see the secret access key in the console here once
and then it's stored in your file, so you do have to keep the secure.
I show you because I'm going to delete mine before you actually see this video.
Otherwise, you wouldn't want to share this in a video or in any of a form to people out on the internet.
You should keep this secure only for yourself.
Now I'm going to copy my access to my clipboard back in instance connects.
I'm going to type eight of us configure, and it asks me for the access key.
So I pay started, and it now asks me for the secret access key.
So back in I am, I'm going to copy the secret access key.
Come back.
Paste that in my region is U.S. Dash East Dash one, and then I'm going to press, enter, enter again,
and I'm back at the command prompt.
So let's try and rerun the IWC as free LS command.
And sure enough, now we can see this bucket.
And if I were to do IWC Free Alice.
As free colon slash slash and then the bucket name, I should then see the files in the bucket as well.
So this just proves that using these credentials, we've been able to access another U.S. service.
Now there is a problem if I go to this file directory, so I'm going to change Directory Tilde Slashdot
IWC and run the LS command, we'll say these two files.
Now, if I run the cat's credentials, come on.
This will actually read the file and put it on the screen.
Now, as you can see, this file called credentials has my access code and my secret access keys stored
in it.
And that's in plain text.
It's not encrypted in any way.
So if anybody were able to compromise this system, they would potentially be able to get access to
this file and then they'd be able to do anything in my IWC account because they would have the same
permissions as me.
So I don't like that.
That's not really a very secure thing to do.
And that's one of the I am best practices, which is to not store access keys in your code.
I've just cleared my screen to make things a bit easier to see.
And if I just run that else, command again.
We have these two files and I'm going to type all RAM Dash RF style and that should have deleted them.
So now we don't have those files.
So now if I run the IWC free ALS command again, we're back to not being able to access the service.
So now we're going to do the better way, the more secure way which is to use an I am role.
So I've changed back to the I Am console.
We're going to go to roles, create role, choose the create role here under IWC service, we're going
to choose common use cases etc.
So this means that it's going to allow the easy to instance to call other IWC services.
So choose easy to click next.
On this page, we're now going to search for free and we're going to choose Amazon as free read only
access.
So this is the policy, and we want to choose the one that has the least privileged that we need.
All we need at this stage is to be able to read from Amazon straight sets.
Choose next, go free to review and I'm going to call this one free, read only and choose Crate Roll.
So we've created the role.
Now let's go back to the new management console in the management console here.
I've selected my EC2 instance.
Let's click on actions.
We're going to go to security and modify.
I am role in the dropdown.
We should see the role that we created as free read only.
So select that and then click on Sage.
So that should have been changed instantly.
Back in the easy to instance connect.
I'm going to try and rerun this command.
So now I'm able to access Amazon as free, but I don't have any of those files on my file system, so
I don't have that security exposure of having a unencrypted file on my computer that stores the access
keys, that secret information I wouldn't want anyone to get access to.
So that's how it all works, and we're finished for this lesson.
And what we're going to do is just go and terminate are two instance.
So back in the console, just select your instance, go to instant state and terminate and were all
cleaned up.