Hi, guys, so let's have a look at versioning and replication.
I'm locked into Amazon is free.
Let's go into our DCT cloud storage bucket here in my pocket.
I'm going to go to properties and we've got bucket versioning.
Now you can simply enable bucket versioning and then you can suspend it.
Now, in our case, what we need to do is click on Edit and we're going to change from suspend to enable
and click on Save.
Now let's go back to objects, and what we're going to do is upload an object.
So I'm going to add files, not simply got a word document here called Versioning Dash Test.
Now you won't be able to see this potentially, but it says first revision.
So what I'm going to do is upload this word document and that's click on Close.
Back in the document here, I'm going to simply change this to say second revision.
Save the documents and then back, it's free.
I'm just going to do the same thing and upload exactly the same file again.
So the files being uploaded and as you can see, there's a toggle switch here for showing versions if
I click on show versions.
We'll see that we've got versioning test and then we've got versioning dash test underneath it as well,
and those are two different versions of the object.
So for example, if I want to download this object here, the old version and I've just opened that
document and it says first revisions so we can see that we can get back to the older version.
We can access the old version if we need to.
Now, let's try something else.
It's upload another file.
Just choose one of these other files we've got, like our confidential reports, and let's upload.
Now, what I'm going to do is simply delete this file, so let's delete the object, and that's gone.
So it's been deleted now.
Let's have a look at show versions.
Now, when you click on show versions, you can actually see that the object is still here, but there's
a delete marker.
So we've got the object, the actual version of the object before we deleted it.
And then we have it delete marker.
Now what happens if we delete that delete marker?
Well, let's try that.
So let's delete our delete marker.
Click on Close.
And now I'll report is back again.
So when you delete something, a delete marker is put in place.
It doesn't delete the object version itself.
And that means you can restore that object.
So that's versioning.
Now we want to set up replication.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a bucket.
Let's just give this a unique name.
I'm going to call it DCT cloud backup and just put two x x on the end just to make sure that it's unique.
So now I want to choose a different region.
Maybe I'm going to choose US East two, and that's where I want my copy to go.
So what I'm going to do is scroll down now I do need to enable versioning.
If I don't do that, I won't be able to set up the replication role.
You need versioning on both the source and the destination buckets.
So let's create this bucket.
Now, let's go back to our original bucket DCT cloud storage.
Click on management at the top here, and then let's create a replication rule.
We can give this a name.
Choose a status.
It's going to be enabled in this case, and then we can choose a rule scope.
So limit the scope of this rule using one or more filters or choose to apply to all objects.
We're going to apply the rule to all objects in the buckets.
Now we need to specify a bucket in another account or in this account.
We're going to choose in this account and then browse.
Let's choose our backup bucket and then you click on Choose Path on the right hand side.
That all looks good now, if I am wrong, you can actually choose this create new role at the top here,
and it's going to do it all for us.
You can choose to replicate objects in crypto with cams.
We don't have any, so I'm not going to enable that.
And you can even change the storage class for the destination.
So maybe you don't want to pay for standard.
There might be a cheaper tier for your back up.
I'm going to leave mine on the defaults.
There's now a few additional options.
You can set up replication time control metrics and notifications.
You can replicate the actual delete markers, which we looked at earlier on in this lesson.
And you can have a replica modification sync as well, and that will replicate massive data changes
made replicas in this bucket to the actual destination bucket.
So I'm happy with all these as defaults.
Let's click on Save.
So we can see we now have a replication rule, and it's in an enabled state and we can see the destination
bucket where the copies of our data are going to go.
So let's go back up to the top level here.
Let's go to our destination buckets and let's see what's in there.
And there's nothing in here.
So was there nothing?
Well, the thing is when you add a replication roll, it doesn't replicate the objects that already
exist in the bucket.
It will only replicate objects that we add to the bucket.
So let's go back up a level, choose our sauce bucket and let's add an additional object.
So I'm going to upload a file and something which I know is not in this bucket at this level.
That's upload that file close out of here.
Then let's go and have a look in our destination buckets.
And now it won't be instant, so you will need to give it a couple of minutes and then refresh and that
just took a couple of minutes and you can see that the new fall, I added, has been replicated to the
destination bucket in the second region.
But all the other falls haven't, so that's working exactly as expected.
Now I'm going to remove my rule, and that's simply going into management, clicking on the rule here
and then we can delete that rule.
So it's going to stop replicating data to the destination bucket.
And that's it for this lesson.
In the next hands on lesson, we're going to have a look at lifecycle rules.