Welcome back.
We're now going to continue and we're going to create a network load balancer back in the console.
You should have created your target groups.
You should also have two instances running because he created an auto scaling group earlier.
Now I want to attach elastic clips to my network load balancer.
So let's allocate an elastic IP.
Just going to leave the defaults.
I'm going to do the same again and once more so I should have free.
Now you have to clear the filter and then you'll be able to see all three elastic clips and these aren't
associated with anything.
Yeah, we're going to associate those when we create the load balancer.
So now we have everything ready.
We can scroll down on the left hand side to load balancers, create load balancer, and now you can
see the four different types.
So we've got the classic, the Gateway, the network and the application.
In this case, we're going to use a network and note that it's showing us the protocols we can use.
Let's click on Create Under Network Load Balancer.
I'm just going to call this my NHLBI.
This is going to be internet facing.
You can have internal load balances as well.
But we want a public DNS endpoint so we can connect from the internet.
I'm going to leave IP addresses IPv4.
If you use dual stack, then you get an IPv6 address as well.
The VPC has already selected.
And what I'm going to do is choose three different availability zones.
Now these must be public availability zones.
Now we only have one private one in this particular subnet, so that's easy.
And then what I want to do here is use an elastic IP.
We're going to do the same for us East 1B and then USC East 1C.
Now we might find that we get the same address assigned.
So if that happens, just change these addresses.
Make sure that we have three different elastic types across these three different subnets.
So these are the subnet in which the elastic load balancing service is going to place the network load
balancing nodes so that we can distribute incoming connections into those subnets scrolling down a bit
further.
Here we have the listener, so the listeners must be unique.
In this case, we have one listener listening on TCP Port 18, and we're going to forward to this target
group.
You could create another listener.
But in this case, you wouldn't be able to have the same protocol and port combination.
Now we don't need that at this stage.
We're going to see how to add additional listeners with the application load balancer later on.
Now let's create a light balancer, go to view load balancers, and we can see now that it's in the
provisioning state.
We have a DNS name, so this is the public DNS name for our load balancer, which will be able to connect
to shortly under listeners.
We can see the lesson that we have.
You can go to monitoring, see some cloud watch data here and under integrated services.
You can integrate services like Global Accelerator, which will cover later on in the course.
And IWC config is automatically recording a history of configuration changes to our load balancer with
the load balance of selected under actions.
You can also see that there's various things that you can edit here.
So, for example, if you edit attributes, you can enable deletion protection, cross home load balancing
and access logs with access logs.
You specify an Amazon S3 buckets into which the log data is actually stored.
Now we're not going to enable any of those at this point.
Now I copied the load balancer name to my clipboard.
If you haven't done that, go back to description and just use this option, he had a copy, the DNS
name.
And we're going to use that in a moment to connect to our instance.
Now, if we scroll down to target groups, this is where we can go and have a look at our target group
and see if we have healthy instances.
Now, if we go to targets here, you can see that there are no targets.
And the reason for that is because we haven't added our target group to our auto screening group.
So let's come to auto scanning groups, select auto screening group, click on Edit.
And if we scroll down a little way here, we'll find load balancing, choose application network or
Gateway Load Balancer and then select your target group.
Once you've done that, scroll down and click on Update.
Now, make sure that you have selected the TGA Dash and LP, not the Albi one.
Let's click on Update.
And what we should find now is when we go back to target groups, click on TG, Dash and LP.
We'll see some targets here shortly so that they've just refreshed and we can see that the health status
for the two instances is in initial.
So it's checking the health status.
Remember, there's multiple health checks that need to come back as successful before these are considered
as operational and that point in time, they'll change to healthy.
So we just need to wait a couple of minutes while that's happening.
I'm coming over to a command line and I'm going to use the nslookup utility.
So this utility will check the DNS name of my load balancer and find out what IP addresses are associated
with it.
So all I have to do is paste in that DNS name, former load balancer and hit enter in the response data.
Here we can see that we can identify elastic IP addresses.
These are the free elastic IP addresses.
Now, if you were using an application load balancer, what you'd see instead is public IP addresses
that are dynamically assigned, so you wouldn't be able to use those addresses if you needed to whitelisted
the firewall.
So what do I mean by that?
Let's say you have a company on the internet and you're connecting to your network load balancer over
some custom TCP pool.
Now you don't want to allow that pull out of your firewall to anywhere in the world.
So instead, you create a whitelist of IP addresses.
You add these free IP addresses knowing that they're never going to change.
Now your application can connect to the DNS name of the load balancer, and DNS is going to respond
with these different IPS and your firewall already allows them.
So that's a common use case for network load balancer.
Let's go back to our target group and click on Refresh, and it's still an initial, so I've got to
give it a little bit longer and hopefully they'll be healthy.
Let's go back to our target group now and click Refresh.
And now we have two healthy instances, so that's great.
What we can do now is try and connect to the load balancer.
So I'm just going to open a new tab in my browser, paste in that DNS name for the load balancer and
hit Enter.
So this is the web page that's generated by our actual instance, and it tells us that the actual instance
is located in the US East one a availability zone.
Now, when you refresh the load, balancer may actually send you to the other instance.
That's in a different availability zone, but it might not for a while.
So the NHLBI behavior is very different to the ALP.
See with the Albi.
It will pretty much every refresh of your browser send you to a different instance, and that's something
we'll see a bit later on.
Now, another thing we can do is actually take this address, this elastic IP address.
And if I put that into my browser, I should find that I can connect to the instance, so I've connected
directly to it via the low balancer node IP address.
I can now take the next IP address.
Now, one of these won't work because we don't have a node in every subnet or free subnet.
So yeah, that one's.
Not working.
Now let's try the last one, and this one should take us to the instance in the one see subnet, so
we paste it in hit enter.
And now we're on a different instance.
So what you can see here is a DNS name is really just giving you some DNS resolution for the static
IP used that are assigned to the nodes and then you have to connect to the nodes.
But the load balancer knows which nodes actually have instances that are healthy and attached to them.
So you do still want to use the load balance of DNS name, but the static IP can help you to whitelisted
your firewalls.
Now that's all I wanted to do for the NHLBI.
We're going to move on to the Albi shortly.
So for this lesson, we're just going to conclude by going down to load balancers and we're going to
delete our load balancer.
Now you don't have to worry about the target group at this point, they don't actually cost you anything.
So we'll leave the target group there now.
Something that will cost you money is those elastic eclipse.
Remember when they're not associated.
So what we want to do is go into each of these and we're going to release the address we might need
to disassociate first.
Let's see if that works.
It's not worked yet because the load balance is still being deleted.
So wait until the load balances, delete it and then you want to go in, disassociate these.
You have to do them one at a time and then release them afterwards.
And that's it for this lesson I will see in the next one.