Hi guys.
I mentioned before about the importance of the root account in AWS. The root account has all privileges
including to billing.
So even if you create an IAM user and give them full administrative privileges to your account there's
still a few privileges that they don't get.
But the root account has everything.
So the root account is an extremely important account and it's one that you really need to secure what
we're going to do in this lab is activate MFA on the root account.
Now in some cases you might see that there's also this option to delete your root access keys.
In my case it's ticked if it's not you can go into managed security credentials choose access keys and
you'll see an access key here and you'll need to delete it.
There'll be an option on the right hand side to delete it.
We'll talk more about what access keys are later but for now what we want to do is actually go to multifactor
authentication.  When we talk about multifactor authentication.
We're talking about using more than one type of tool for indication and those different types of authentication
this can be something you know like a username and password something you have which is a physical device
of some sort or something that generates a code and then there's something that you are.
Which means biometrics for instance retina scans or fingerprints.
In the case of AWS we need to we're going to use two factors of authentication.
One of them will be something that we know that's our username and password.
And the other will be something that we have and that's going to be a multifactor authentication device.
If we choose activate MFA we can see here that we have a few options.
One of them is a hardware device which will produce a token which you then enter into the console when
you log in.
Alternatively you can use a virtual MFA device and this is what we're going to use today.
I'm gonna use Google Authenticator.
So I've chosen virtual MFA device and I'm going to choose continue.
We now get a QR code on the screen.
We have to click show QR codes to get it and what you need to do now is install Google Authenticator
on your phone and then you choose the plus and then you choose scan barcode and you hold this up to
your monitor and very quickly it's added in your account to the list and you you're now able to generate
codes what you need to do then is enter the first code that you see on the screen.
In my case us eight hundred and then six five to you then need to choose the second code which is shown
on the screen once the first one expires.
In this case it's eight to seven free free free and then you choose a sign MFA and that's it.
We've now successfully assigned the virtual MFA device and you can always go in and manage this device.
You can remove it and you can resync it.
Now what we want to do now is see how this thing works.
So I'm going to choose sign out and then I'm gonna sign back into the console and I need to enter my
password
and to sign in.
And it now asks me for the MFA code so I'm going to type the one that's on my screen at the moment which
is 0 7 7 5 4 1 and to submit
so you now have the extra factor of authentication on your account.
Even if someone finds out what your password is they're not gonna be able to log in without also having
your phone that has Google Authenticator installed on it. Back in the IAM console.
We can see that under our security status that we've activated the MFA on the root account and there's
a few more things that we can do to secure our account.
The next thing we're going to do in the next lab is create individual IAM users.
So in this case we're going to create a user that has full administrative privileges to the account
so we can use that for the rest of the labs without having to log in as the root account.
So remember this is important for the exam as well that the root account is something that you shouldn't
be using on a daily basis.
You only use it when you need to.
You secure it you get rid of the root access keys you activate MFA on the root account and that's going
to really secure that account.