With excuse, the maximum message size is 256 kilobytes, so sometimes you might need to send a message
with some kind of attachment.
That's a lot bigger than 256 kilobytes.
And you can do that with messages that are up to two gigabytes by using the extended client library
for Java.
So what happens is the producer uses the extend the client library for Java to send a message with a
reference to an S3 object.
So the rest of the data, up to two gigabytes can be put as an object into this asheri bucket.
And the message that's placed in the queue will have a reference to the large objects that stored in
S3 and then a consumer can pick that up, picks up the message and knows where to get the object from
the S3 bucket.
So the maximum message size is 256 kilobytes for excuse and you can use S3 and the excuse extended client
library for Java to manage obscures messages and that's useful for storing and consuming messages up
to two gigabytes in size.
So you can use this to do the following, specify where the messages are always stored in S3, or only
when the size of a message exceeds 256 kilobytes.
Or send a message that references a single message object stored in a necessary bucket and you can get
the corresponding message object from a necessary bucket and you can then delete the corresponding message
object from the ashry bucket.
So there's nothing left behind.
That's probably all you need to know for the exam.
So just remember, if you see a scenario where the message size is exceeding 256 kilobytes and it's
up to two gigabytes in size, then you can store that data as an S3 object and reference it using the
extended client library for Java.