Hi guys.
In this lab we're going to explore scaling policies in a bit more detail for auto scaling groups.
And we're going to watch how an auto scaling group reacts to load as well.
So we.
I've kept my configuration running from the previous lab so I have my auto scaling group in my elastic
load balancer and if I go into scaling policies I can see that I have this target tracking scaling policy.
Now with target tracking.
It tries to maintain the average CPM utilization at the value specified which for me is 70 percent.
Now there are two other types of scaling policy that we can use.
And if I actually click ad policy here we get to choose from a simple scaling policy or a policy with
steps now with a simple scaling policy the ISG will increase or decrease the capacity of the group based
on a single scaling adjustment.
Now AWB W.S. actually recommend that for most use cases you use a step scaling policy rather than a
simple scaling policy with a step scaling policy.
The ISG will increase or decrease the capacity of the group based on a set of scaling adjustments known
as step adjustments and these vary based on the size of the alarm breach.
So let's have a look at a scaling policy with steps.
So I'm going to call this maintain load and what I need to do is specify an alarm.
So execute the policy when I choose an alarm.
So let's create an alarm.
So I'm going to say and I don't need to send a notification.
I'm going to say when the average speed or utilization hits 70 percent or greater for at least five
minutes.
And you can specify different values set off an alarm and then what we do is we come back and specify
what happens when that alarm is executed.
So we want to take the action of adding one instance and let's choose create.
So what I can do now is I'm going to get rid of my target tracking scaling policy.
And we just have this maintain load one which is going to set off an alarm when our C4 utilization hits
70 percent or greater.
So what we need to do now is actually generate some load.
So what I'm going to do is go to instances and I'm going to take the IP address of my instance and I'm
going to log on through secure shell and I'm going to install the stress utility again that we installed
back a couple of sections ago.
So I'm going to run this command which you can find in the course download and then actually install
the stress utility I have stress running on both my instances now.
So let's go back down to auto scaling groups and let's have a look under monitoring.
Now you can enable group metric connection by choosing this option here and then we'll get some more
statistics after a while.
But what we can see now is just the minimum and maximum group size the desired capacity and so on.
Another way we can monitor these instances is just going back up to easy to and choosing the monitoring
tab and it's going to take a few minutes because we're using basic monitoring so we won't see the load
being reflected in the metrics for a few minutes yet.
So it's been a few minutes and I can now see that the load is certainly above 70 percent it's way over
80 percent on instance one.
And if I go to my other instance I can see it's also got the load going a bit higher but it's not quite
reached plus 70 percent yet.
So what we need to do is just keep an eye on it and might take a few more minutes for all the information
to be received and then we should see a scaling event occur in a few more minutes and we can now see
that both of instances are well above 80 percent.
So one of them there is showing us as 100 percent.
So we should see a scaling event happen any minute now.
And there it is.
We can now see an additional instance initializing.
So let's go down to auto scaling groups and let's have a look at activity history.
And here we go we have a new instance so it says launching a new easy to instance and it tells us that
the alarm was triggered and it triggered the policy changing the design capacity from two to three we
head over to monitoring.
Again you can see some information here.
You can see the design capacity of two has now gone up to free.
And you can see the pending instances count has gone up to 1.
So there we go.
That's how it works.
We can now see that we have a new instance being launched now of course another thing that an auto skating
group will do is respond to failed easy two instances.
So for instance what I could do is go in and terminate an instance.
So let's just terminate one of these instances and that's going to shut down and then the auto scanning
group is going to realize that it's lost an instance.
So now it's going to have to replace that instance to get back up to the desired minimum.
So that's being terminated.
Let's head down to auto scaling groups and have a look at activity history.
In fact what I'm going to do is go back up and terminate my up and running instance with the reason
being that I want to make sure that we're under the threshold and we don't have to wait too long for
the auto screening group to evaluate whether the load is above 80 percent or not or about 70 percent.
So if I terminate this one we're now in the state where we've only got one running instance.
So it's definitely going to have to relaunch at least one instance straight away.
I'm gonna have a look here and we can see that an instance is being terminated and we now get the message
saying that we're waiting for You'll Be connection draining.
And so what this is this is probably the first instance where we can see that the instance was taken
out of service but it's saying it was in response to an easy to health check.
Well actually it was me terminating it.
So that's not really the case.
But the easy to health check did not come back as positive.
So the auto scanning group is then trying to make sure that any existing connections are drained before
it forces a termination.
And now we have a message not yet in service for launching a new easy to instance so this was in response
to a difference between the desired an actual capacity increasing the capacity from two to free.
So now let's go back to instances and we can see we have a new instance launching.
So that's just a simple lap guys to show you how things work.
Now the other thing that I just want to show you before we finish this off is that we can still connect
to the instances that are behind our life balance so let's go to load balancing let's choose to copy
our DNS name and I'm going to close this tab and just reopen it.
And then we'll put this in.
And we've got Rosalind.
So Rosalind will be the instance which we just launched a few minutes ago this one here.
So this is the one that was launched in response to the load that we placed on the auto scanning group.
We now have a second one initializing so that may or may not be ready.
Let's have a look.
We've just seen Rosalind at the moment so if we give that a minute we should then see that we can connect
to our second instance as well.
So I thought a couple of minutes and let's see if it's in service and it is we've got a destiny.
How about that.
So we can now cycle through Rosalyn and destiny and in actual fact while that was happening another
instance was launched.
So if we just head back to our auto scaling group we should get some more messages in here.
So we had another instance which it then terminated and then launched a new one.
Now of course I terminated both instances but the auto scanning group didn't receive the easy to status
check that it wanted to.
And that's why it then took the initiative to try and shut these down and then it launched two instances
to replace the instances that I terminated.
So we should now have a bunch of healthy instances behind our load balancer.
And as you've seen the low balance off because it's connected to the auto scaling group automatically
picks up that there's new instances and low balances to those instances.
So that's it for this lab guys.
What we're going to do now is just delete auto scaling group.
So let's just go in and choose Delete.
We can also delete our launch configuration
we can go to load balances and Alito our load balancer and we can also delete our target creep and we'll
just create another one when we need to.
And then if you go back to instances just go in and terminate all of these instances and that's all
cleaned up.
What we're going to do in the next lab is I'm going to show you how cross own load balancing works and
also sticky sessions.