Hi guys we're now going to cover Amazon Aurora.
So this is another database in the RDS suite of products and you may remember from a couple of labs
ago where I mentioned that I'd RDS Aurora is quite a different animal to the other databases in RDS
and I'm just gonna give you an overview of some of the key features here.
Now there are quite a few more and I do suggest that you go to the Amazon Web site.
Look up RDS Aurora and learn as much as you can.
But what is on the screen here I think represents the key information that you need to know for your
exam so let's start at the top.
First off you got a high performance and scalability audience roar offers high performance self healing
storage which scales up to 64 terabytes.
That's per instance.
You also get point-in-time recovery has a feature called backtrack that you can enable which enables
you to move your database back to a point in time within the last,
I think it's up to 72 hours, and it is right down to the sort of minute or second level and you can then
you can do that without actually having to restore your database as a really cool feature and you can
also get continuous backups to S3.
So very highly available we'll see the architecture in later labs on how they distribute storage.
So there's six copies of your storage across three availability zones so lots and lots of redundancy
D.B. compatibility.
There are two database engines you can use mysql or Postgresql and compatibility with existing
instances of these databases is is fully available.
And we then have the three different options here.
In fact there are 4 for high availability fault tolerance and sort of scaling your performance.
And these are Aurora replicas and an aurora replica is similar to a RDS Read replica in that you're
able to scale your reads.
So it's only read traffic that gets scaled.
It's however only within the region and you can have up to 15.
So like I just mentioned with Aurora you get six copies of your data across three availability zones.
And essentially what happens is the aurora replica is able to read data of those databases.
You can also use them as a failover target so they can give you that fault tolerance where if your
primary fails you can actually have them automatically takeover the database load and be able to perform
rights so they actually get promoted automatically and you can specify tiers you know which ones or
which order your redress because or your Aurora replicas will be upgraded or promoted to primary.
We then have mysql read replicas.
So these are very different.
Whereas a raw because a within the region might seek will read replicas are cross region and actually
creates a cluster within that region and labels you to scale your read traffic again and have a fail
over target in another region.
You can have up to five of these.
So that can be five different regions which you have a cluster in. That's a copy of your primary production
cluster where you're actually performing your database writes to each of those clusters can then have up
to 15 Aurora replicas coming off of there. We then have the global database global database gives you
cross region clustering with Read scaling.
So it's very similar to mysql read replicas.
In that you're able to have a read only database in another region and it will create a cluster as well
so you've got the same sort of storage redundancy in that of a region just as you do with mysql
Read replicas.
The key difference is faster replication and low latency reads so you can't have a lack of a few seconds
with my sequel.
There's also a performance impacts on the master because this is happening actually from mysql native
bin log replication whereas with global database you don't have that impact on your master and you
get lower latency read.
So if your application needs low latency reads you might have to use global database again you can also
promote these two primary and readable databases.
The next one here is multi-master and this is just in here for information because you might ask me
why I haven't covered it in the course and the reason is it's in preview.
So this is a technology that allows you to scale out writes within a region.
So now you can have multiple database instances writing to the same database storage cluster.
Now this is currently in preview what tends to happen is AWS have a rule where they will not add
anything to the exam until the product or feature has been generally available for six months.
So from the point the product or service becomes generally available or it could be a change to an existing
service or an additional feature it will be at least six months before you see it on the exam.
So this one is currently in previews so it's gonna be quite a way off yet you won't see this on the
exam now.
The last one on the list here is scaling.
So this is on demand
Auto scaling for your Aurora.
Now what this means is that rather than specifying a specific instance size you actually give it some
minimum and maximum thresholds and auto scaling takes care of scaling your database for you.
So that's some really cool feature.
The only problem of it is there are a few limitations so it doesn't support read replicas and it doesn't
support public IP is the only way you can access it is through your VPC or through direct connect you
can't access it over a VPN or for instance from another account or another VPC so those are just a few
key features about Amazon Aurora and what we're going to do over the next couple of labs is we're going
to go into more depth and actually create some configurations in AWS around read replicas.
MySQL read replicas and global databases.