Hi guys.
And welcome back.
In this lab we're going to build a Hello World API with Lambda proxy integration as with the Lambda
labs.
I want to follow an AWS tutorial and this is really to keep you guys on track.
This is not a coding exam.
The solutions architects associate is more about understanding the architectural choices you make in
order to design the best solutions for a given scenario.
So we don't need to know a lot that coding stuff.
And the reason that these labs are useful is just to help solidify your understanding of the service
rather than getting too deep in the weeds.
So this is a very straightforward one to follow.
We're going to create a function in lambda which will return a greeting which just says good day you
know then your name and your city and have a happy day.
Happy Tuesday or whatever it might be.
So very straightforward to follow.
And we're going to start off by going to the lambda console.
So we're in the AWS lambda console.
We're going to click Create a function.
We're going to choose all four from scratch.
I'm going to paste in the function name and then we're going to choose node JS.
Make sure that this is consistent with the version of code that's being used in this example.
We then choose create a new role from AWS policy templates but we're not going to specify a actual
policy template this time or we're going to do is just go in and put the role names and paste in that
role name and it will create the role for us.
So we click Create function and that just took a few seconds and we can now click on our function and
then go down to the inline editor.
And I'm just going to delete this code and I'm going to paste in the code that came straight from the
article we'll click get started.
We'll okay this message and then we're going to choose new API.
This must be a REST API and then for API name we're just going to call it lambda simple proxy and we
don't need to enter a description and we're gonna leave the end hype as regional and just click Create
API.
The next thing we need to do is create a resource and we go in here and we type hello world and we need
the other options as default and we click Create resource.
We then need to define a method and the way we do that is you need to select Hello World and then choose
create method
within going to choose any.
So this is where you could define different or specific HTTP methods.
But we're going to choose any and then you can click the tick mark we're going to choose lambda function
you need to make sure the lambda region is set correctly and then you need to select this box which
says use lambda proxy integration and if you hover over the information icon it explains to you that
requests will be proxy to Lambda with the request details available in the event of your handler function.
So we then choose the function you just type any letter and it will come up and show you the list of
your functions and we need to choose the Get Started Lambda proxy integration function and then you
click save and just okay the message which explains that you're about to give API Gateway permission
to invoke the actual lambda function we've now defined our API and what we need to do is deploy and
so we choose deploy API we choose new stage and I'm going to call it test we can leave the other boxes
empty.
And just ahead deploy so we've now deployed to a stage called test and if you expand this you can see
the various methods you can see the at the top level you can see the invoke your URL and so you have
these options for throttling and Web Application Firewall and client certificates and all the other
ones across the various taps here.
And then if you come down to your actual methods you can then see the invoke your URL for the specific
method.
So if you try and open this one for instance it's going to give us a bunch of information.
And this is actually good it shows that it's working.
It just tells us good day you off world and then it's a bunch of stuff here which you don't really need
to worry too much about.
But what we want to do is generate a customized message so to do that we need to create a custom
URL.
I've just created that url on another screen and I'm going to paste it into my browser.
So the way this is constructed is we have our invoke your URL which goes up to Hello world for the get
method and we then have a question mark and then name equals and then you can specify your own parameters
in.
Put your name in here then as an ampersand then this city equals and then you can specify your city.
And if we hit Enter now instead we get a message that says Good day.
NAYLOR Sydney
now back on the tutorial if you want to play with this a bit further you can use the curl tool or you
could also use postman if you have access to that and you can then specify some additional parameters
which you can't do just by constructing the URL in the browser so you could specify the day and the
time of the day and get a more customized message.
So that's something else you could go on to do if you want to continue.
Otherwise we can clean up this lab by just going back to our API. I'm going to copy the name of the
API and then we just go delete API and paste that and click delete.
We go back over to our function and we simply delete the function and that's everything cleaned up and
what we're going to do in the next lab is we're going to have another configuration where we're going
to deploy a simple micro service using lambda an API gateway and a dynamoDB table.