Hi, guys, and this lesson is going to be a hands on lap, and what we're going to do is we're going
to create something like on the screen here.
So we're going to have an easy to instant's.
We're going to configure cloud watch events.
So we have an instant state change notification sent cloud watch when we terminate the instance and
we're going to get cloud watch to then send a notification to our target, which will be an excuse.
Q Now we won't have an easy to instant polling, which is going to do that manually, so we'll go in
through the console and find the message.
So let's head over to the console.
I'm going to I'm going to launch an instance and I'm just going to go through the normal defaults with
a T to micro and let's just use next next security group.
I don't really need to log into it, but I'll put it web access anyway, and then let's just launch
that instance.
So the instance is launching.
Let's now open up cloud watch and we're also going to need us.
So in fact, let's go to ask us first and what we'll do is we'll create a queue.
I'm just going to call this my simple queue and then choose quick create queue.
So we've got our queue.
Let's go to cloud watch and let's go to events and eventually create rules so you can go down the rules
and then choose create rule.
Now we're going to choose the event pattern.
They can choose a schedule as well, but we're going to choose an event pattern.
I'm going to search for two now.
I don't want it to be all event, so I'm going to choose easy to instant state change notification.
And in fact, I'm going to choose a specific state and I'm going to choose terminated.
So I'm only going to get notified when an easy two instance is terminated.
And you could even choose a specific instance.
But I'm just going to leave it as any on the right hand side here.
I'm then going to choose excuse Q and choose my Q and that's all I need to do.
So let's just choose configure details.
I'm going to give it a name and I'm going to call it Termini instance and then just choose, create
rule.
So that's it.
That's the rule created and that rule is now active.
You can say it's a green status.
So the way to test it is I literally just have to go over and terminate my instance.
So choose, terminate and choose.
Yes.
And now let's go to the excuse management console and let's choose view, delete messages and start
polling the messages.
And that took a few seconds to come through.
But now we can see our message, choose more details and we can see a bit of information here.
So we've got the detail type isn't easy to instant state change notification.
The sources, too.
We got the account ID, we've got the time, we've got the region as us west to and then we've got the
resource ayran and we can see the instant side in here as well.
So that's it.
Very, very simple.
But just to show you what you can do with event notifications.
So I'm going to actually delete my message and I'm going to go and delete my Q And we've already deleted
our two instance.
If you want to, you can then go in and clean up your role as well.
You just let you go and delete your role.