Hi guys.
In this lab we're going to cover cross account access.
Now there's a couple of ways you can do this.
You can even do it through policies or you can do it through access control lists and what we're going
to focus on in this particular lab is on using policies.
And then we're going to cover off access control lists.
And I'm going to show you how to access data across accounts using ACLs in the next lab.
So for now what we want to do is we want to enable this user John who's in Account B to access data
in a bucket which is an Account A which is our DCT Labs account that we've been using throughout this
course.
So we've already got our bucket and we've got some folders set up and I specifically want to allow John
to be able to read the bucket but also to write and read and write from the confidential folder.
So the way we set this up and it does get a bit complicated which is why I wanted to show you in a diagram
as well is we need to set up a role in accounts and we give that role permissions to the bucket.
So there's no bucket policy here.
The role the ACL is attached directly as an inline policy to the role John then has a policy attached
to him which allows the ability to assume this role so when John can assume this role he then gains
the permissions that are assigned to this role and he's then able to access the data in the bucket.
So let's look at how this works.
So what I've done already is I've set this up.
So what I want to do is just show you through the console what I've actually done so we've got
an account.
So this is an account in the DCT labs account.
And what I've done is I've created a role called account B.S. free.
So the purpose of this is to allow users and roles in Account B to assume this role and access S3
so let's go in and have a look at this role.
So you can see that there is a policy here but I'll come to that shortly.
Firstly let's have a look at trust relationships.
So what we're looking at here in this trust relationship is we're granting the user John who is in account
B.
So this is the ARN for the user.
In the other account to assume a role so STS stands for the security token service and allows you to
take short term credentials.
So what's happening is John will be given some credentials that allow him to use the role for a temporary
period of time
so the next thing is we have a policy called allow get/put confidential.
So this is going to allow the user to get and put objects in the confidential folder.
So if we just have a look at the JSON here we can see that we have some statements that allow us to
list all buckets in the estuary accounts so using a wild card then to list bucket and get bucket location
which you'll remember is required for when you're having when you need console based access and then
and that's to the DCT company bucket and then we have the specific permissions which we're going to
allow for getting objects and puts object within the confidential folder and anything benefits so that's
what's going on in accounts.
A So just to recap what we've just looked at.
There is an account saying we have the role the role is allowing John through the trust relationship to
assume that role and through the ACL to list the bucket contents and to get and put items or objects
into the confidential folder.
So now let's head over to account B. So this is Account B and I'm logged in as myself.
And so what we can see here is we have a user named John and he has a policy attached called account
S3.
And so if we look at this all this does is it allows John the capability to assume the role.
So account B S3 is the role that we created in Account A service allowing him to assume that role.
So that's the setup.
And now what we can do is look in and here I'm actually logged in as John and I've already previously
access so we've got the path here to the bucket.
But clearly we're not able to access anything.
So what we now do is we go to switch roles
and we need to put in the name of the account and then the name of the role
and then we can give it a display name as well and we click switch role.
So now we're accessing this S3 bucket as this user.
And so we can see the whole bucket.
But let's try to upload an object to the root of the bucket here which we shouldn't be able to do because
we don't have get put
privileges here.
And sure enough that failed.
But now we can go into the confidential folder and we should be able to upload a file
and again it shows an error but there it is.
You know the file the file is there and we can we can go back and prove that in our main console here.
Let's just pop into that folder and sure enough there's that audio file that we just uploaded.
So the user is able to put objects.
And if we click on download and we can see the file just pops up on another screen.
So that's it really.
And then you can switch back to your main user go back to John now and if you wanted to you could change
this so that rather than using a user an account B you could have a role an Account B and then perhaps
you might use that role to assign it to an easy to instance and then the easy to instance within turn
assume the role in Account A and then access the contents of the bucket.
So that's how it works, it's a fairly complex setup but that's how you do it with
S3 policies and we'll get onto how we do it for ACLs in the next lab.