So now we're going to talk about virtual private networks.
And there's a couple of times that you can use with eight of us.
There's a side to side connection and as a client VPN endpoint.
So this slide is about site to site VPN.
So in this case you have a corporate data center.
So this is could be the company you work in and you want to establish a virtual private network connection
so that you can send data using private IP addresses over the Internet and then into your VPC.
So the components that you need for this are the customer gateway.
Now this is a configuration that you create within a W W but then you apply that configuration to your
router or your network device in your corporate datacenter.
There's then a VPN gateway and this is the configuration on the AWB side of the connection.
And once you've got the customer Gateway and the VPN gateway you can then create the VPN connection
and layer that on top.
Now the other thing you need to do to be able to send data from your private subnet to corporate datacenter
is you need to add the correct side a block into your round table and then specify the virtual Gateway
I.D..
So when we create this this connection you'll see it as a virtual Gateway idea and that's what you use
as the target and then data that needs to go to this IP address range we'll just then be routed over
this connection.
So let's go to the console and this is the VPC dashboard.
I'm going to head down to VPN and we're going to create the configuration but I don't actually have
the correct devices to be able to actually enable this VPN.
And in your situation it would be different anyway depending on what type of device you have.
But the general steps are the same.
So we create the customer Gateway and there's going to call it my CCW and it's saying that we can choose
dynamic addresses which uses BGP or we can choose static.
And in this case I'm just going to stick in a bogus address and we can create the customer gateway.
Now what we next need to do is to go to virtual private gateways.
So now we're going to create our Virtual Private gateway.
I'm going to call it my VPC.
And on this side it does use BGP so there's an autonomous system number is even the Amazon D4 or you
can choose your own.
So I'm just gonna leave it at default and create virtual private Gateway
now that we've got that we can then go and create a VPN connection.
So let's just go this my VPN and we now get to choose the virtual private gateway.
Then we come down and say existing customer Gateway and we can choose the one we just created and we've
now got to put an aside a blog so it says that it needs to be a site a block in the 1 6 9 2 5 4 0 0
16 range.
So I'm going to do one sec.
Nine dot 2 5 4 0 dot five slash 30.
Because I know that's the first address block and then I'm going to leave the PRICHEP key to be generated
by Amazon.
Now the site to site VPN uses IP SEC and Telus for security.
So once that's created we can then go back to our customer gateway that's all configured correctly we
need to go to a virtual private Gateway and this is where we actually attach this to a VPC so we can
attach that to a VPC and it's now in the state of attaching and just a few seconds later and it's attached
and we can now go to our site to site connection and we can see that this is in the state of pending
it's not going to activate because this is a bogus configuration but this is where you could also go
and download your configuration and you could choose whatever type of network device you have you could
choose F5 for instance and select the type of platform and then if you hit download what will happen
is it then gives you this configuration file which you can then apply to your network device router
whatever it might be.
So that's it quite simply we can just go and delete this configuration
and I need to detach this from the VPC and then delete go back to customer Gateway same again.
So the other thing that you'll notice here is apply the VPN endpoint.
And so what you can do here is your able to use either mutual authentication or active directory authentication
along with a certificate in order to connect client devices directly and so rather than having a site
to site VPN.
This is a way of connecting client devices.
It could be you know users laptops as they're on the move
so that's it for virtual private networks.
You can just remember the key things are customer gateways on the corporate datacenter side so the site
that you're trying to connect into a is the VPN gateway or the Virtual Private Gateway it comes on different
names is on the AWB side and you need those two things to establish a VPN connection and the other key
piece is you need to update your round table.