We're going to cover EBS snapshots in a bit more detail now.
So an EBS snapshot captures a point-in-time state of your instance or specifically of your volume.
So it's a way of taking your EBS volume and creating a copy of it a snapshot of it in a specific point
in time and storing that on S3.
So you remember that the EBS volume is within an availability zone, the same availability zone as your
instance.
And then when you create a snapshot of that volume it goes into Amazon S3 which is a regional service.
And that means you can then access that snapshot from another availability zone so you can either copy
this between regions or you can create a volume from it within a region in a different availability
zone and we'll go through all the different scenarios shortly.
The other thing to know about snapshots is that when you create multiple snapshots they're incremental.
So that means if you have a volume that's 10 gigabytes in size and you take a snapshot of it you have
a 10 gigabyte snapshot if you then change a gigabytes of data you've got in the region of a gigabyte
of data that needs to be stored in this snapshot.
And what this snapshot will then do is it will reference the other 10 gig that's back here and that
carries on as you create more and more snapshots but there's a few important points to note about that
and I'm actually going to take you to an article because it explains it in great detail.
So you'll want to look up deleting an Amazon EBS snapshot and the key thing is here is that it says
if you make periodic snapshots of a volume the snapshots are incremental so that's what I just explained.
And that means that only the blocks on the device have changed after your last snapshot are saved in
the new snapshot.
Now in most backup systems that would mean that you need all of those snapshots in order to recover.
So you'd need the original that had the 10 gig on it and then you'd need each of the other snapshots
which has the changes the incremental changes and then you restore it altogether.
However that's not the way it works would be.
Yes.
So it then goes on to say even those snapshots are saved incrementally, the snapshot deletion process
is designed so that you need to retain only the most recent snapshot in order to restore the volume.
So actually in this case you don't need the original.
You only need the last one which should be seen on.
But anyway you only need this last snapshot and that's because it's designed in such a way that if you
delete these previous snapshots it just keeps the data and makes sure that this is a fully restore rebel
snapshot.
So what would you do then is if you want the most up to date version you would take this last snapshot
and you create your volume and enough availability zine from that snapshot so let's get into the console
now and just have a look at snapshots.
So let's go to volumes and I have an instance that's running and all I'm going to do is just create
a snapshot.
And this is the root device.
I'm just going to call it snap 1 and so we create that snapshot and if we now head over to the snapshots
you can see it's pending and that's being written 15 percent they go I refreshed and is very done very
quickly so we can say this isn't encrypted and that's because the root volume isn't encrypted and we
can then perform a few operations the next lab we actually can go into detail about all the different
operations you can perform whether it's encrypted or unencrypted and so on.
So we won't do that now but what I can do then is go and let's take a snapshot of this volume.
Now I haven't actually gone on and changed that data but just assume that you've got some changes in
the data here you now create another snapshot.
And so I now  have root snap 1 and root snap 2, root snap 1 will have the original 8 gig
root snap 2 will appear to have 8 gig still, the capacity still shows as the same because that's the size
of the volume but that's not showing you the used space and actually the amount of space this would use
up is unclear.
You can't see it in the console but that would be the incremental changes from Root snap one.
However if we wanted to do a restore of the latest copy of the volume this is the one we would use and
it would reflect the changes the original and any changes being made.
Another tool that we have is data lifecycle manager and this is a way that you can automate the lifecycle
of snapshots.
It's a relatively new service but it is several months old so it will be featuring on the exam now.
So what we can do is first before we run it we have to go back to our volumes and we need to give it
a tag.
So I'm going to create a tag I'm just going to call it DLM for data lifecycle manager and I'm just going
to call this snapshot
so we now go to lifecycle management and let's call this DLM snapshot and we can choose a volume or an
instance.
So if you choose instance then you'd you'd come up with your instance ideas or you you choose the entire
instance rather than just an individual volume.
But in this case we're going to go to volume DLM snapshot and then we have a schedule so you can modify
this.
And in this case it's going to run by default at 12 hours starting at 9:00 UTC and then you can define
the number of snapshots you wanted signs.
Let's say we want to keep the last three snapshots
you can perform tagging and you can modify the role if you like and it's as simple as that.
You then just create the policy and this will automate the creation of those look of those snapshots
for you.
So in this case I'm just going to remove this.
I don't need this lifecycle policy.
Now there's another thing about snapshots that you need to understand to take a fully consistent snapshot.
Sometimes referred to as a crash consistent snapshot.
You must stop right to the volume.
So that means that to ensure that you have a fully consistent snapshot you need to stop any activity
that's going on on the volume.
Of course that's very hard for a root volume when the operating system is running on it.
So ideally you would shut down your instance and you would then take a snapshot of it.
You can take a snapshot while the instance is running.
But that would be the ideal scenario.
We have non root volumes.
What you want to do is try to ensure that you you do stop any writes that are taking place.
So that might mean that you can pause your application shut down your application service or worst case
you might need to actually detach the volume and that will definitely ensure that there's no more activity
happening on it.
So that's set for snapshots for now in the next lab.
We're going to go into a lot more detail on the various operations that you can perform on UBS volumes
snapshots and a mind.