Now, this module's lesson comes in two parts.
The other key boundary to keep in mind is any legal limitations and potential ramifications you may
face.
You'll want to get to know your state or local laws, as well as federal self-defense laws.
Let's start with your state and local self-defense laws.
Do you live in a duty to retreat?
State a castle doctrine, state a stand your ground state?
What are your local weapon ownership and carry laws?
Now, all of these laws vary from state to state, including in their scope and parameters.
So make sure you inform yourself on the specific self-defense laws in your state while you have the
time to do so.
Laws on owning and carrying weapons also vary state to state, so make sure you look at those two while
you're at it.
On the federal level in the United States, self-defense is an affirmative defense in court.
Fun fact.
So is it insanity plea?
That means you are pleading guilty but with the justification of self-defense.
So if the court rules out self-defense, you've already pled guilty to using force so you could face
charges of assault or battery or even manslaughter or murder in order for your defense to qualify as
self-defense.
You must be able to explain how the threat felt both real and imminent, and for a threat to be real
and imminent, you must be able to identify four things.
Intent means opportunity and preclusion intent your assailant must demonstrate, and you must be able
to explain how you know that he intends to harm you.
It can be obvious, like with his words or less obvious with his actions, his body language, the brandishing
of a weapon.
But it needs to be clear to you means whatever the intent of the threat, he must have the means to
carry out the threat like actually having a gun when he's saying he's going to shoot you.
Opportunity the threat must be able to reach you with those means, even if he's yelling and waving
around a knife.
If he is far away, we're on the other side of locked doors.
He does not yet have opportunity.
Preclusion.
This means you had no other viable option in reaction to the threat, meaning you couldn't avoid, evade
or de-escalate it without using force.
You must be able to explain why using force was the only option that would safely work.
The only exception to this last requirement is if you are in a no duty to retreat state either in your
home under Castle Doctrine law or anywhere else covered by stand your ground law.
That exception aside, once any of those four has been eliminated or resolved, it is no longer legally
self-defense, like if you hurt him and he collapses to the ground injured.
He likely doesn't have as much means if he collapses and starts whimpering for you to stop.
You also likely doesn't have as much intent if you keep attacking him after any of these four are gone.
You won't be able to argue self-defense in court.
That's why I emphasize that your primary goal is always to get away safely.
If you leave as soon as you're safely able to, even after you start using force, you've stayed within
the legal boundaries of self-defense.
Now that we've got those legalities down.
Let's add in your mental and physical boundaries from earlier, and you'll be ready to not only recognize
all of them, but verbally and physically reinforce them when you're in danger.
You'll also know what to expect from both yourself and the authorities in response to an attack.
And as they say, knowledge is power.
When you know all of these boundaries inside and out, you can maintain a state of control and relaxed
readiness, hopefully de-escalate the situation or at least know where to draw the line for yourself
and for a self-defense legal claim.
So ready to set some boundaries, then let's move on to the next video and practice this for real.
These.