When danger strikes while traveling, it can be a bit harder to maintain control of your person and
your personal effects.
So knowing how and where to secure the more valuable of these like, say, your ID, your passport,
your money, your travel documents, etc. is really important to think about and prepare for ahead of
time.
Contrary to what some might suggest, I would caution against leaving your most valuable possessions
in your room while you're out.
But then it depends on where you're staying and how secure it is.
If you have a room that locks with a secure, safe inside that also locks, that could be a better option
than risk losing everything of value to a pickpocket or a mugger all at once.
But if you're sharing a room, especially with a stranger, maybe air on the side of keeping your stuff
with you on your person.
You can always keep it more secure with a portable safe.
That way, if somebody does grab it off you, they'll still have trouble getting to the goodies inside
wherever is most secure.
Keep your real passport there, then keep copies of it elsewhere as backups if you do bring anything
with you.
Keep it well hidden, like in a travel belt or a hidden bra wallet or this clever underwear with a super
stealthy crotch pocket.
You can also take a page out of the old spy handbook and keep a dummy wallet on you if you keep your
phone in your pocket.
Make sure it's in the front pocket then, where any person's bags or cameras across your body and keep
one hand resting on it as you go.
I also like to keep a spare $20 bill or the equivalent in local currency tucked away somewhere as a
backup.
Like in my bra or my sock.
If you lose everything else, 20 bucks can come in quite handy.
Again, the more prepared, the better.