Our last, but certainly not least, ABC step is at four familiar eyes.
This is less about another step in the order of how to defend yourself and more about the final lesson
you must learn in order to do so.
I've been saying it all throughout the course, but it's important enough to bear repeating.
It is vital to your survival that you make all of these steps muscle memory.
In the moment danger strikes, you won't have time to stop and think of what to do.
You'll only have a split second to react in a real attack.
So all of these self-defense moves need to be instant, or they'll be of no help to you when you really
need them.
So this entire module is all about continuing to practice those ABC steps over and over until they become
instinct this week and for the many weeks to come.
Long after you've completed this course, you must keep practicing these until they are firmly ingrained
in your mind and muscle memory.
Remember, the more prepared you are, the better equipped you'll be to stay safe and strong wherever
you go.
Practice, practice, practice until you are so comfortable with these notes that you can do them in
your sleep until you start doing them in your sleep.
Taking down threats in your dreams.
I do actually have a lot of dreams where I'm fighting off bad guys to save myself and others.
And I got to tell you it's pretty empowering to wake up from that.
Now to help you practice, practice, practice and familiarize.
You're going to need some version of the following supplies and support number one.
Some means of continuing to write down and take notes on all the tactics you learned in the avoid,
backtrack and control modules, as well as your chosen methods for events and evaluate.
Number two, your training space pads, clothes, practice, weapons and ideally a buddy for practicing
all the moves you learned in the defend module.
Number three ways to incentivize yourself and hold yourself accountable to a steady, recurring practice
routine until it becomes habit.
For example, automated reminders, incentives and social accountability.
So let's dive on into the next video and lay out how exactly you will use each of these supplies and
support to create an ongoing practice regimen that will hard wire your body and mind for safety and
home you into the ultimate tough cookie.
Ready to take on anything life throws at you with courage and competence and pizzazz?