Now it's your turn to master how you will avoid dangers.
It's not every day you get to practice being avoided.
So let's try avoiding some --.
First drill, eye scanning.
You want to stay alert, keeping all of your senses as sharp, undistracted and ready as possible,
look side to side up and down, near and far in front, behind and all the way around you.
Take note of everything that could potentially become a threat or dangerous situation, like someone
walking behind you a little too closely or a guy hovering by his sketchy looking van parked suspiciously
near you?
Or maybe that car that seems to be following you or driving a little too erratically?
Now you give it a try.
Wherever you're watching this video, I want you to stand up.
Go on now.
Take a good look around you.
If possible, take your laptop or your phone that you're watching this on with you and just pop outside
real quick.
Now I want you to stop watching me and take a good look around you.
What do you notice?
What catches your eye?
Use all of your senses and take note of everything, especially anything that seems slightly dodgy.
I realize you might not have much to go on at the moment, but you never know.
And just the act of practicing noticing each thing will get you in the habit for when the world does
finally start going again.
Second, drill no, you are frequent in areas and routes.
For example, I always take this public transit home from work, and there are usually this many or
this type of others writing too.
So I'll take note if someone gets on who seems to stand out or maybe look at me too much, or I usually
walk this way to the store, but that dark alley shortcut probably isn't the safest.
So I'll be prepared to take the longer, more populated and well-lit route when it seems smarter.
Or I usually park in this parking garage, so now I'll be extra careful walking to my car and maybe
keep a weapon on me at the ready.
If it seems to empty or dark, now your turn.
Think through all your regular routes to and from your regular haunts.
Your home, your work, your gym, your hairstylist, the store, your favorite cafes or restaurants
or bars, your friends and families homes.
What do you normally pass by on your way?
Who do you usually see?
What are you often doing as you go?
That might distract you or hinder your awareness.
What areas might be prime or entertainment to sneak up on you or get you alone?
Your homework this week is to continue this exercise for each of your regular routes and stops for at
least an hour or two this week.
Take a typical day in the life of you.
Go through it step by step and take note of each and every thing you might notice along the way.
If you do go anywhere this week, even better, pay attention to your surroundings and to your gut instinct
as you go and note down everything you see or feel.
You might not have noticed before now, as you do this exercise, remember to write down every possible
danger or threat.
Make a list.
Check it twice.
Identify what around.
You could be naughty or nice as you do this.
Also, notice how this starts to change the way you move and carry yourself.
And be warned, I might be checking your work.
So do your best.