Now, your turn to practice these backtracking skills, you're already eye scanning and identifying
potential dangers, right?
Well, now as you do that, let's add in identifying possible exit routes around you, as well as reachable
people and places of safety.
Let's return to last module's exercise of mentally or literally walking through all of your regular
routes and stops in your typical day.
Go back through that process.
And this time, as you go through each route and setting notice and knock down all of the possible exit
routes and places of safety within reachable distance, is there more than one way out of your home,
your office, your favorite bar, your favorite café, your gym, your local store, your salon?
Do your usual streets, have any side alleys or shortcuts or alternate routes?
Do you pass by a police station or fire station or hospital on any of your routes?
Do you see security guards posted at any entrances or around public transit stations?
Is there a hotel along the way that always seems to be bustling and well staffed?
Do you have a friend living down the street who works from home?
Is there a public park or square nearby that's usually busy?
Also, think about how you get to these places of safety that might create new routes, right?
So now let's go through those new routes in your head, too.
And note down everything you'd encounter along the way that might help or hinder you in getting to safety.
Make no list for both these escape routes and all these safe destinations.
I want you to continue this exercise as you go about all of your regular routines and routes for at
least another hour or two this week, wherever you go.
If you go anywhere, practice making note of all the possible exit routes and reachable places of safety
every time, over and over until it becomes habit.
It needs to be instinct by the time it really counts.
The more you can mentally rehearse every possible option and scenario, the more prepared you'll be
to act quickly when it matters most, when the danger is imminent and the panic sets in and you don't
have the luxury of pausing to figure out what to do or where to go.
You do have the time now, so take advantage of that and prepare yourself.