OK, let's learn some better moves.
Y'all ready for this?
Now remember, in every move, you want to utilize leverage, rotation and speed.
The power trio.
So first, let's practice how you will achieve these tactics.
Three.
And the other side you see for leverage power.
Practice getting low and centered in your ready stance.
Grounded yet quick on your feet.
Move around in this position to get comfortable with it.
The other key to leverage is to keep driving forward with every move advancing on your assailant and
keeping him off balance.
So as you move around in your low ready stance.
Practice stepping forward as it driving into your assailant.
Think of it as always, trying to get to where he's currently standing.
Now, since we want to be always driving forward, we can use that to put even more power into every
move with maximum leverage.
It's called the drop step, and it's exactly that a step you drop into with your full body weight as
you perform each move and strike.
That means that all of your body weight will go into every hit.
Start in low ready stance now, lift your back leg up as if to step forward, but don't put it down
yet.
Lean your weight forward.
And as your weight reaches a falling point, let yourself fall into a forward step.
Don't put your foot down.
Let your full body weight drop you into it.
Now, repeat this with the other leg taking another drop.
Step forward and on and on.
Marching forward with each drop step.
If you need more room, you can practice this move anywhere.
Drop stepping around your house, drop stepping down the street anywhere, you feel comfortable.
It's basically just a weird looking step lunge.
People will just think you're working out your quads and glutes for rotation power.
You want every hit you do to start from your feet.
Pivoting, come up through your center and your hips turning and into your shoulders, arms or legs.
You've got to engage that core and use your whole body.
So as you practice each of our ten basic moves.
Try rotating and pushing all that force behind whatever body part you're striking with.
Just twist your hips and let her rip.
For speed power, you want to make every move, every strike, every hit snap with it, good.
Try this exercise, hold your arm out, palm facing up now, take your other hand and extend it as well
on top.
Palm also facing up and bring it down onto the first palm.
Hurts a little, don't it, now do it again, and this time snapped the upper hand back up real quick,
like immediately after it makes contact with the first people
who feel the difference that sharp sting.
That's exactly what you want every one of your kids to do.
Now, combine that snapping speed with your leverage and rotation, and you will have a power, the
likes of which has never been seen, or at least the likes of which your assailant certainly doesn't
expect to see.
So practice this power trio until you've mastered it with every move you learn in this module and you'll
give him the surprise of his life.
While saving your own.