Now, let's practice how you plan to events and evaluate after you escape to safety the next time you
encounter a real and imminent threat.
Let's start with events how you will report what happened to the authorities.
Here are 10 pieces of information that would be good to remember and report after an assault.
Number one, what your assailant said or did to threaten you that made his intent clear, like any threats
he made, what words he used, the tone of his voice and his body language.
Number two, what your assailant had in his possession that he used to threaten or hurt you, which
goes to his means, like when and how he drew any weapons and, if possible, where it ended up after
the assault, in case the authorities can try to retrieve it.
Number three How your assailant approached you, where he moved, how close he got to you, and how
quickly which shows his opportunity.
Number four, What you did in response.
What you said if, when and how you tried to and finally managed to escape all of which speak to preclusion.
And exactly what, if anything, you did to fight back like if and when you drew a weapon where you
hit him?
How many times and what happened when you did?
Number five describe the moment at which you made the decision to use force if you did and why you made
that decision.
Number six Note exactly where he touched you on any part of your body and or your possessions.
So the authorities can try and take samples of DNA or fingerprints.
You may be taken to a hospital for this if you aren't there already.
Number seven Who else was present before, during and after the assault?
Who may have witnessed what happened?
How far away they were?
And any identifying information you can give about them?
Number eight, how long the whole confrontation lasted from when you first felt the threat of his intent
to after you've escaped to safety number nine, what your assailant looked like was wearing and any
distinctive features that might make it easier for the authorities to identify him.
Number 10 If you know it, definitely give them his name, his age, his height, his home or work address,
his license plate and or the make and model of his car.
Pick three of these pieces of information that you will focus on and pay extra attention to.
With every encounter and interaction you have this week, this is your events homework for the week.
Carry a notebook with you or use a note taking app on your phone to jot down what you notice about each
interaction for all three pieces of information.
This will get you into the habit of noticing and remembering this information for when you will need
it most.
Now for Evaluate, let's figure out how you plan to process what happened both immediately and long
after the assault.
Who will you go to for help and counsel and support?
One good thing to do is to save the number for the National Sexual Assault Hotline into your phone.
Also, if you know any attorneys, especially any who specialize in sexual assault or abuse, track
down their phone number and program that into your phone, too, do you have a therapist that you would
feel comfortable telling?
Or maybe an H.R. rep at work keep their number ready in your phone as well?
How about your personal network, it will help to have somebody you know really well and trust to talk
to you about it, to someone you know will believe you and support you?
Can you think of who that might be?
How about your family or your closest friends?
Write down the names of one to three people and make sure their numbers are in your phone to possibly
even on speed dial.
If you don't feel comfortable calling someone, you may want to write about it instead.
There are a number of online forums and chat support lines.
Some even anonymous, that you can reach out to as well.
So if that's an option you'd prefer, find one that you feel comfortable with and bookmark that link
somewhere you'd be able to locate easily in the heat of the moment.
Lastly, I want you to pick one mantra or phrase that you will remember and tell yourself every day
this week to remind yourself that you're OK, that you are strong, that you deserve to feel safe.
So pick one short phrase that best embodies this for you.
Perhaps something I've said in one of these videos or something a friend or a famous figure said once
that really stuck with you or a catchy phrase that you write yourself.
I have a simple three sentence, six word mantra I wrote that I use for myself.
But you use whatever works best for you.
Write it down in at least three places that are regularly visible to you in your everyday routine.
For example, I keep my mantra on a post-it note at my desk, on my phone background image and on a
nifty little drawing I made for the inside of my car.
Seeing it every day will help infuse this mantra into your psyche so that if and when you do experience
any kind of trauma, it will be right there in the bosom of your brain.
Ready to help you deal and heal?
This is your evaluate homework for this week.
First program your phone with all those people's numbers from your chosen support network and then pick
your chosen mantra and put it in three places.
You'll see every day and then look at it every day this week.