Now, it's time to put our power trio into our ten basic moves practice each move first into the air
and into any kind of pattern.
You have your pillow, your couch, your punching pad or bag your dad.
And then ideally again with a buddy, though still using pads.
Of course, you don't want to hit your buddy at full force, I'm guessing.
But who knows?
Remember, it's not just about what you practice, but how you practice.
You want to create as realistic of scenarios as possible when you practice these moves, especially
with your buddy.
This means starting from the approach, not just standing in front of each other already and ready stance.
Your assailant could very well catch you off guard and close in before you can get into your ready stance.
So it's vital to practice each of these moves from a variety of starting positions in each of our scenarios,
including one where you're standing there, looking away, not paying any attention at all.
Don't just stand there and wait for your partner to grab you.
Or, worse still, offer your hand for the initial grab.
It won't happen like that in real life.
So remember to train as realistically as possible.
This includes giving as good as you get with consent, of course, especially when you're playing the
assailant.
You'll get a better sense for what that will feel like and how much you can take and create a more realistic
scenario for you both.
Plus, as an added bonus, you get a full sense for how much power your body is capable of.
You might be surprised how hard you can actually hit and how empowering that feels.
It needs to become instinct for you to launch into these moves with full force and feeling as soon as
the threat becomes real and imminent and unavoidable.
She who hesitates is lost or injured or dead.
So with that in mind, let's start with our first move.
The eye gouge you for I, the first letter in our eggs, this is best used in the third scenario of
extreme close range attacks, especially with the first scenario from the front or in the fourth scenario
if you're taken to the ground.
The point is, your assailants head needs to be close enough for you to reach out and grab.
Wrap your hands around the sides of your assailants, head fingers, bracing against the back for leverage
and really dig your thumbs into his eyes.
Now, if you're practicing this with a buddy, obviously go easy on their eyes.
You can go full force on a pillow or a dummy, but it's still good to practice this move with the buddy,
if possible, to rehearse going quickly from ready stance or other less ready positions into this move.
Next is the ear twist, which could also be in eggs, though this can also be applied to your assailant's
nose, eyebrow or any other part of their body that you can pinch and twist between your fingers.
This also requires being in close proximity to your assailant's face or other part that you want to
twist.
So it's most applicable in our third close range and fourth ground assault scenarios.
But of course, use it anytime you're able.
Here's the gist of it.
Grab their ear or any other body part, ideally with your thumb facing down and then twist your hand
back as hard as you can with all your leverage, rotation and speed.
Work your way up to the speed part with your buddy, as well as how much force you use on their ear.
And be sure to both tap out when the pain is too much.
Then go full force and speed on your tummy or other inanimate pattern.
Our next basic move is one of the most universal and invaluable.
The palm strike, this can be used in pretty much any scenario and on any target point of the body.
Any of the Etgar or CNG spots, the eyes or ears, the throat, the groin, the shins, the stomach,
the instep or foot, the nose or other parts of the face.
It's an open hand strike hitting with the hard heel of your hand, which can actually withstand a good
amount of damage and have a lot of power behind it from the rest of your arm and shoulder.
So using your rotational power, you could put a lot of force behind your palm strike, using your whole
body weight and driving your hand through.
Even if you're a smaller woman, let's say about about 20 or so, that's still a 120 pounds of power
going into one spot.
Like their face, you're not high fiving their face, you're crushing it.
Now, it's important to mention that a punch is not the equivalent of this move.
This is far, far superior.
You should never, ever use a fist unless you are properly trained to do so.
Punching with bare fists runs a high risk of fracturing your knuckles.
Boxers and the main fighters mitigate this risk by wrapping their hands.
So unless you have and know how to use any wraps or hand protection, do not punch.
Stick to the palm strike, which frankly can take a bigger beating than your fist.
So let's do some drills with this from your ready stance.
Rotate your body as you extend your arm and hand with the heel of your palm out and bring it back.
Think about reaching for something, turning your body to get that full reach without leaning over reach
as far as you can turn while staying upright and centered.
Then bring it back with that same snappy motion.
Practice this move slow at first, then work up to full speed with full force and rotational power.
Try them in repetition.
Two at a time, then three at a time, then even more and even faster as you get more comfortable as
many as your little heart desires to ingrain this, move your muscle memory.
Our fourth basic move, the blade or axe hand, also uses the hand, but a different part of it.
It's also widely applicable in any scenario and on any striking point of the body, and it also happens
to be a personal favorite of mine.
The idea is to create a blade by flattening your hand and tightening your fingers together, hardening
the whole thing as stiff as possible.
Then you strike with either side of your new hand blade in an x like motion on whatever part of your
balance body you can face the eyes, ears, the nose, the throat.
It works particularly well throughout the groin, the shins, the stomach, the foot, all of them,
though orientation does matter.
So different target areas will work in different combinations, whether you're attacked from the front,
from behind, in close range or taken to the ground.
Make sure you practice all of these scenarios, at least by yourself and with a buddy if you have one.
Start slow and steady to get the proper form down and then gradually add more force and speed until
you're practicing at full force and adrenalized speed.
Mood ever five is another favorite of mine.
The elbow strike, which has roots in several martial arts styles, including Krav MAGA and White Tie,
once again, proximity is a big factor here.
So it's most useful in close range and ground assault scenarios, but could still be applicable to any
of them.
It's also good for nearly all of our target striking areas, except perhaps the instep is that would
require a pretty awkward position in order for your elbow to be the most effective move you have.
Let's practice them all anyway, just to be prepared for every possible scenario.
Start by getting into your ready stance.
Now take your elbow and as you rotate your body, bring your elbow up and across in a forward strike.
For another angle, let's imagine the position you're in has your body turned and your side or back
is facing your assailant?
Like in our second scenario of an attack from the rear.
In this instance, you'll want to rotate your body back the other direction as you bring your elbow
up and around in a backward strike.
There are many other scenarios that may call for an elbow strike like, say, if you're on the ground
with your assailant on top and you swing the elbow across to strike him off, or he's got you in a close
range attack like a chokehold and you twist your body to bring your elbow up and over to strike his
face and release his grip.
Practice all the possible angles for each of these scenarios from the front, from behind in close range,
on the ground as many times as you need into the air, into padding that ideally with a buddy holding
that padding.
Now for Move number six, the knee strike, this is essentially the same thing as the elbow strike just
with the lower body.
It's equally applicable to the same scenarios and target striking areas, including the awkwardness
of the instep.
The most obvious use is a knee to the groin in a frontal close range or ground assault.
But the knee could also be used to strike the stomach or his face if he's bent over or close to the
ground.
I'm particularly fond of the knee to the face move as a very effective finishing move that will often
knock him out enough to allow you to escape to safety.
But the knee to the groin is a bit more likely for you to use, especially earlier in the fight.
To practice this new strike, start in your right stance.
Now remember that drops stuff this time when you pick up your back leg to drop forward.
Swing it outward and upward, driving the top of your thigh up into your assailant's groin or other
striking area.
Then you can bring your foot forward and down again with the same full body weight of your drop step
driving forward and knocking your assailant off balance, which will be a nice added bonus on top of
the big knee blow you just gave them.
The key is to make contact with your thigh and all that strong muscle parts, not your actual knee,
which is much weaker and will hurt a lot more.
I call it a thigh strike, but it just wouldn't have the same ring.
Practice this knee strike with your drop, step repeatedly by yourself and then with your buddy, if
possible.
Of course, go easy on your buddies groin.
That's a sensitive area for all genders.
So let each other know how hard is too hard and, if possible, have the one being need wear a cup or
other protective padding over their crotch, while region one may maybe still going, it just have power
and speed.
Then you can confidently go full force having your buddy hold that sturdy padding option of yours in
front of them at groin height instead.
Our seventh basic move is the all too well known groin kick, the G and Eggs and SIMD.
And it's in both acronyms for a reason because out of all our ten basic moves, you're most likely to
have used this one before in your life.
I know I have.
So while you may not need a lesson in how to do this one, it can't hurt to go through it one more time
and just make sure you've got it down.
So starting ready stance now with a kick move, you'll shift your weight onto your stationary foot as
you bring up your kicking butt in a swift flick motion that drives the full rotational power of your
body out into the target area.
And then just as quickly pulls back and drops down again, you want it to be simultaneously powerful
and quick.
You don't want to take too much time to get into the move, or you'll end up telegraphing what you intend
to do to your assailant.
Losing the element of surprise and giving him a chance to counter the attack, you are aiming to connect
to the top of your shoe with the underside of your assailant groin, not the front of his groin.
The up and underneath.
Way up in there as way up in there, you can get really write it up in there.
I want to kick the guy in the groin so hard I lifted him off the ground with my foot.
That's what you want to do because that will cause the most damage and give you the best chance to get
away to safety.
Now again, practicing this with a body may be a little tricky, especially if you're buddy boy parts
down there.
So take it extra slow and careful, or stick to practicing the motions of the moves up until the actual
connect with the groin part or have where cup or just have them hold padding in front of them at groin
height, whatever you're both comfortable with.
But you can still practice this move fully by yourself, into the air and into your padding options
at increasing speed and force until you've really got it down or up as it were.
The eighth move on our list, the shin or knee kick, takes that same kicking motion and applies it
to your assailants shins or knees.
Essentially, the US in the eggs.
And let me tell you, that is a really painful place to be kicked for anyone.
It also works in just about any scenario you can imagine, but it's especially effective at knocking
down a standing assailant, either from the front or the rear.
To practice this kick, start once again in your ready stance.
Now rotate your body toward the side, it won't be kicking, pivoting and shifting your weight once
again onto the stationary foot as you flip your kicking foot out in a quick and powerful kick motion
aimed directly into and through your assailant, shin or knee.
And then just as quickly driving forward with the drop step into your ready stance.
Now, if you're doing this move in the second scenario with an attack from behind, you can turn this
into a back kick, rotate and shift your weight to your stationary foot as you lift and drive your kicking
foot backward into their leg.
In one swift, powerful motion like a donkey kick.
And, of course, just as swiftly pull it down into a drop step or if you prefer to still use the front
kick.
This may require an extra step to start your turn, then the pivot and shift on to your stationary.
But as you snap your kicking foot out into their shin or knee and back down again.
Now, if you don't have a buddy to practice this move with, that's OK.
You can just set up your sturdy padding option at shin or knee height and practice kicking that repeatedly
on your own.
But if you do have a buddy, you should still use that sturdy padding to kick.
Don't actually kick your body.
A shin guard could be good protection when you're going at half speed and force, but it won't really
be enough when you start kicking at full capacity.
So when you're ready to give it all you got, you should still have your buddy hold that padding option
at their shin or knee high for you to kick.
And vice versa you for them.
Next move number nine is the foot storm.
This is essentially the instep or the eye and CNG, though really anywhere on the foot will hurt pretty
good.
This move is especially ideal in the second scenario when you're attacked from the rear.
But it can work great from the front, too, though it does require close range or the third scenario
as well.
So this is an excellent move if your assailant has got you in an upright hold of some kind from either
direction.
Let's give it a go.
From your ready position, raise your stomping foot up and back down again swiftly and forcefully into
a sharp, decisive storm.
Remember to put your full body weight behind it for extra force.
This also helps you drive forward with your body as you start again aiming for where your assailant
is currently standing.
Now, try practicing with your buddy and get a sense of how close you'll need to be to your assailant
to get in a good start.
If you don't have a buddy, you can still recreate some of this scenario by standing close to a wall
or other tall stationary object as if that's your assailant and then drive forward into that wall or
object as you stomp the ground beneath it.
Our tenth and final basic self-defense move is the hip thrust.
This move is primarily useful for a fourth scenario of a ground assault with your assailant on top of
you pinning you down.
That's because this scenario might make it a bit tricky to use any of the other moves we've learned
as your legs and arms could be trapped and rendered useless.
In that case, the only useful part of your body that you can really utilize to fight back with is your
hip and core area.
Now, this move is rarely enough to get away in of itself.
So the goal here is to free yourself and your limbs enough to go into a barrage of other moves from
our list and do enough damage with those to help you get away to start.
You'll likely be on the ground on your back and your assailant will be on top of you holding you down.
Now this is where it gets extra tricky to practice without a buddy.
Maybe try putting something else heavy on top of you to mimic the assailant.
Now what you'll do in one swift motion is plant your feet and raise your hips sharply into the air like
you're doing a hip thrust or a glute bridge exercise.
Now, add in a slight rotation as you thrust and your assailant is launched forward and to the side
of you.
This will give you a window to push him further off you or shrimp out from under him, or at least start
striking him with all those other moves from your freed side.
Remember, one of our 10 rules is to avoid being on the ground at all costs.
This includes remaining on the ground once you've gone there.
So as soon as this move frees you enough to push or wiggle or hit your way out, you want to get back
up on your feet as quickly as possible and hopefully make your escape or, if necessary, continue fighting
back from there.
Now, I know this move may feel awkward and perhaps a bit silly to simulate at first.
But I urge you to push through it because if you end up in this position for real, there will be nothing
silly about it.
It's also a particularly difficult position to get out of.
So you want to be really prepared for this one?
Practice this move as many times as you can, ideally with your buddy.
Make sure you trade places you never know what position you'll end up in in a real fight.
And that's it.
Who you did it, you just learned the ten basic moves you need to defend yourself in any situation or
scenario.
Now I know this was a particularly long video and we covered a lot.
So don't hesitate to come back and rewatch this video any time you need a refresher.
I'll always be here.
Or at least this recorded version of me.
Well, in fact, that's your homework assignment this week to review and practice each of these 10 moves
for all of our scenarios.
As much as you possibly can give each move at least five to 10 reps each into the air against some sort
of padding with full force and speed.
And then ideally also with a buddy with as much force and speed as you're both comfortable using on
each other.
Remember to make it as realistic as possible, though, of course, without possibly endangering yourselves.
Happy training.