Speaking of familiarizing yourself, this is an especially important thing to do when you're traveling,
so not just practicing and in graining or self-defense skills, but also your knowledge of your destination
and its culture and its people.
The goal is to blend in seamlessly with each new environment like a ninja, so you don't attract any
unwanted attention or become an easy target or, you know, act like a rude tourist.
Part of traveling and blending into a new place is learning how to act like you belong there.
Think like a local.
And surround yourself with locals and see what doors that opens up for you both literally and mentally.
Learn the local culture and customs dress appropriately and respectfully.
Learn the language wherever I go and make a point of learning to say at least these six things in the
local language.
Hello.
Please.
Thank you.
Sorry, excuse me or pardon me.
And cheers, which sometimes in the local language is literally to your health.
It's also handy to know how to say, Do you speak English?
And I don't speak.
Insert local language.
Also, get to know the local transit system so well that you navigate it like a pro.
And then when you're not sure, talk to locals because that's what locals do, they talk to each other.
Because even if you memorize the city and metro maps, you're still probably not going to know everything
that's OK.
Locals are the best resource for all kinds of clever tips and tricks for getting around their city,
and there's an art to asking questions without looking naive or like an easy target.
Keep your composure, stay calm, and be confidently curious.
Remember?
Fake it till you make it.
You can also ask the concierge or front desk attendant where you're staying.
Pick the brain of your bartender or server when you go out.
I got some of the best local restaurant and live music recommendations from a bartender in Nashville.
All of these folks are usually very eager to share their insider knowledge with you, and you may make
some new friends in the process.
So make a point to make yourself a part of their world.
Now, that doesn't mean avoid the more touristy --.
As long as you're enjoying yourself, I say do what you want to do.
You want to brave the long lines and the packed crowds to see the top of the Statue of Liberty or the
Eiffel Tower.
Go for it.
You too, you bill.
Just be aware that a lot of the more popular tourist attractions are not worth the time and money.
I spent two days and unnecessary parking fees trying to see Mount Rushmore.
And by the time I finally saw it, I got tired of it in an hour and I left feeling like the cost was
so not worth it.
Then again, many group activities and tours and meet ups can be great ways to meet fun locals and fellow
travelers.
So once again, just do your research and know what you'd be getting in to weigh the costs against your
own travel goals and make sure the experience will be rewarding for you before you commit.
Don't be afraid to be picky and you only exactly what you want to do.
It's your trip and no one else's.