Let's take a moment to talk about that.
I know it may seem a bit of an odd topic for a self-defense course, but then it's not just for Buddhists
or even wise old martial artists.
Did you know Zen is an integral part of ancient martial arts?
It can also teach us much about how to stay safer and stronger without compromising our quality of life.
In fact, it teaches us how to get more out of life.
There's a reason they call it enlightenment.
To reach a state of Zen is to be relaxed and alert at the same time.
It's a lesson in preparedness, and it can be a very useful tool for your life, both for enjoying it
and protecting it, as it has been for martial arts for centuries.
The first principle of Zen one must master is chosen or the beginners mind.
This means being open and ready to learn without any preconceptions or judgments.
This will help you not only in life in general, but also in how you approach this tough cookies self-defense
course.
So let go of that negative, Nancy.
Inner critic telling you you can't do this or you don't deserve this.
You are much stronger than you think you are.
As long as you are open to it, once you understand that, you can learn to embrace who the ocean or
the immovable mind.
This is a sense of steadfast determination and absolute control over one's self.
You must be immovable in your belief in yourself and your right to defend yourself.
It's OK to be stubborn when it comes to protecting your life and your body.
Then you will balance the tenacity and perseverance with your chosen openness and readiness.
Once you've mastered that, that ready resolve will help you achieve motion or without mind.
This is when one is truly in the zone, completely in the moment and on the task at hand.
Who doesn't love that feeling when you're so engrossed in what you're doing that you don't have any
inhibitions?
Well, if you can combine that focus with your chosen openness and your food and courage, you will
be truly in the zone free from worry, anger, fear or ego.
All of that will aid you in mastering your ultimate level of Zen exemption or the remaining mind what
you are left with after you let go of prejudgment, insecurity, anxiety.
It's a state of constant situational awareness, perceptiveness and relaxed readiness.
This is where you truly master the way of tough cookies.
Self-Defense always at the ready, but without doubt, arrogance or fear.
Strong but soft at the same time.
Like a tough cookie.
This is the ideal state to be in when preparing to defend yourself, and even before that, when you're
just going about your day.
It is a true mastery and melding of mind, body and spirit to fully equip and fortify oneself.
Only then are you strong enough to survive and thrive as fully and happily and safely as possible.
You already have the strength inside you.
You just need to tap into it and harness it.
And that is exactly what we're going to learn to do in this course.
So free your mind.
And let's begin.