Avoiding dangers when traveling also includes watching out for travel scams, resource predators abound
in touristy areas where unsuspecting travelers can fall prey to a variety of different scams and cons
and thefts that can be very common depending on where you are.
So this is extra important to be prepared for both as you researched your destination and of course,
once you were there.
Depending on where you're traveling, there are a good many travel scams to watch out for.
So you want to make sure you do your research and know what's come and where you're going.
Some are pretty universal in any large city like pickpockets and muggers and homeless asking for handouts.
You also don't want to let anyone hand you or put anything on you like a bracelet or a necklace or a
pretty pin.
It's most likely a scam to then demand payment from you for the item you didn't even want as soon as
they've got it on you or pickpocket you while you're distracted.
You also need to make sure you're safe taking pictures of tourist attractions and performances.
This is common in countries like Morocco, where street performers will often demand payment from you
for taking their photo.
Also, watch out for taxi scams and other transportation services, especially in any countries where
kidnapping is more common.
It's important to be wary of anyone offering you a ride.
Even seemingly harmless people claiming to have their own taxi.
Be smart and use the legitimate taxi stands, also, make sure they use their meters and charge you
fairly, or just book yourself a trusty rental car from a reputable company before you go.
It's worth the extra cost to be safer than sorry or.
There are also more tech savvy thieves who can steal your personal information without ever physically
touching you.
That's why it's important to keep your I.D. and credit cards and an RFID protected wallet.
It's just as important, probably even more so to protect your identity as well as your stuff.
This also means being careful what information you give out about yourself.
If someone's asking you for sensitive or private information like your bank account or I.D. numbers,
make sure you verify who is asking after see their ID.
And if you're still not sure, call their company yourself to confirm if it's a police officer or similar
authority figure.
Ask to see their badge.
Nicely, of course.
And maybe even write down their badge number and name.
You have a right to ask for this information, and it's a good habit to get into any time you interact
with law enforcement.
You never know when that information will come in handy and whatever you do, never, ever give out
your passwords or your passport number.
Except for that customs form on the plane, of course.
I hope that goes without saying, but I'm going to say it anyway.