When you're traveling, speaking up and seeking support also means connecting with new people where
you're traveling and making new friends both after an incident or attack as well as before because traveling,
especially solo, can be a little lonely at times.
And there is safety in numbers.
Plus, it's fun, so it's always a good idea to establish some local allies where you're traveling.
Besides keeping in touch with the people you trust back home, just because you're staying alert and
cautious does not mean you have to be cold.
In fact, that might even make you stand out more, so put on a smile.
Try being friendly and see what a difference that makes.
Just a simple smile and an open mind.
Now, that doesn't mean you believe and do whatever anyone tells you.
Of course you got to be smart and keep your wits about you.
But that doesn't mean you can't say hi and ask questions and make friends.
As a woman traveling solo, you will be less intimidating and easier to approach.
That can be really lovely, or sometimes a little annoying, or yes, even dangerous.
But I'm always amazed to discover how rarely I feel alone when I'm traveling by myself.
As long as you can identify the friendly, trustworthy people wherever you go, you're probably less
likely to find yourself alone in a dangerous situation than and if anything does happen, you'll have
plenty of witnesses around you and people who can help you contact the local authorities.
So basically you want to build a local support network wherever you go.
I especially love to make new friends when I'm eating solo out at restaurants.
It's ideal for you and for the restaurant to sit at the bar or at a communal table if they have one.
Then you can just chat up the people sitting near you.
I've made some lovely connections and had some amazing adventures thanks to random dining conversations
when I was traveling.
So don't be afraid to ask your new friends for help when you need it.
It's good to ask questions so long as you do it with confidence and ease.
You've got a voice and a brain, so use them.
Speak up.
Be proactive.
And you will be just fine.