The Prius tutorial we learn how to find data errors through skill.
Today I'll show you how you can automate the same process but in essence I guess by the end of the editorial
you will learn how to use another tool in essays the conditionals plit.
Let's get started.
First we're going to open up Visual Studio.
Now open your saved project and go into your daughter.
We'll be rerunning the upload.
Therefore before we do anything at all we need to clean up the table that this daughter will be going
into.
Otherwise we will end up with duplicate records.
So go to a school and select the top 1000 records of your table.
Now delete everything between select and from and type in truncate table.
This may seem similar to the drop table command we used previously.
However truncate doesn't delete the table completely it just removes the data from the table.
The headers are left untouched.
Run your query now.
Select the top 1000 rows of your table to verify that is empty.
You can see that the headers are still there.
However there is no data in the table at all.
Good.
Let's go back to Assayas.
We need to add an extra step between the Flash file source and the destination.
Click on the blue arrow and presently Tonja keyboard.
Now go to your tool box and in the common tab you should find conditional split.
Personally I prefer to see it in the transform step so lets move it there.
Right click and choose move to other transforms.
Open up transforms and drag the conditional split into your workspace.
Now collapse all of the tabs in your toolbox and let's pause here for a second.
You already know that e-tail stands for extractors form load.
And as we discussed previously in Sosias we extract data from sources then we use transform to transform
it.
And finally we loaded into destination's right now on your workspace for the very first time.
You have elements of all three components present.
We will extract data from the flat file.
Use the conditional split to transform it and loaded into the ONLY DB destination.
Let's get to it.
Use the blue arrow to connect to a flat file source and the conditional split.
Double click of the split to open it up.
Here we're going to add to the same filter as we created in s kill in the previous tutorial.
It's extremely simple it's all drag and drop.
First add an output name.
Let's call it bad records.
Now let's work on the condition.
Open up the string functions folder and find the lende function.
Drag this function into condition.
Now open the columns folder and go to the end drag column 46 into the line function.
Now on the right go to the operator's folder here find the Greater than operator dragged into your condition
after the len function AAVSO the greater then operator type in a 0.
That's the first part done.
We are checking if call 46 is not empty.
As I recall this takes care of all the right shifts.
Now we need to pick up any left shifts in Asgill we checked for rows that did not have a period in the
longitude column.
Here we are going to achieve the same result but a bit different.
We will check for rows where the longitude column is empty.
Find the logical or operator.
Note We don't need the bitwise OPERATOR We need the logical one draggle logical or into your condition
.
Drag another lead operator into condition after the logical or draggle longitude into the operator find
the equal operator and place it off to the len operator and type in a 0.
This will pick up and your rows shifted to the left.
Great we have created a filter for bad records and euros that don't match this condition will go into
the default output.
So let's give the default output a name we'll call it good records click OK the good records are going
to go into the database but we also need a facility where we will store the bad records.
You can choose to send the bad records into a separate table in your database if you like.
However it might be handy to send bad records straight into a flat file which you can then send off
to the right person or team for investigation.
I will show you this method.
Go to the destination stabbing a tool box find the flat file destination and dragged into your workspace
.
Now let's connect the conditional split to the destinations.
First connect to the flat file destination in the window that pops up select a better Rickard's output
and click ok.
If you click on the conditional split there will be a second blue arrow connected to the database destination
.
You can see that good records have been selected automatically and now there are no more blue arrows
available from the conditional split.
This makes sense because records will either meet our criteria and follow the Baracus path or they will
not meet the criteria and follow the grid records.
There is simply no alternative options.
Now we will set up the flat file destination.
Open it up and as usual we need to set up a manager first click new Select delimited and click OK and
now click Browse.
We want to be in the data errors subfolder of the analysis folder of our project.
Make sure you navigate to this location first.
Create a new folder called automatically excluded results inside this folder.
Create a new text document.
Let's call it 2015.
0 8 0 5 underscore fake names underscore bad records.
The date should match the date of the folder from where you're uploading the data.
This way you will be able to understand which upload these errors relate to.
Select the file and click open.
Add a text qualifier.
Note that when we open the file later it might feel a bit excessive to have text qualifies on every
single cell.
However I recommend using these additional text qualifiers because they will help you spot errors.
Make sure to check the box for column names in the first dot a row before you proceed.
The rest of the process is similar to flat file source setup but it has its nuances.
Go to columns here you will see that there are no rows.
Makes sense since we haven't loaded anything here yet.
Make sure that the column headers are in place and now go to advanced.
She will see that all of the columns have been assigned the correct with even the feedback column.
This is because as I ask and see where the data will be coming from and has mimicked your flat file
source don't change anything and proceed to the previous step.
Click OK click on the mappings page and click OK now we're done.
Let's say this package.
And now let's launch it.
The bad records are being separated from the good ones and slowly both destinations are being filled
up.
What do you know.
There are 14 bad records.
That's exactly the same amount as we found in Eskdale in the previous tutorial.
Let's go and have a look at the results.
Open up your project folder and navigate to the bad records file.
Use Notepad plus plus to view it as you can see all 14 arrows are here and this means that now our table
in the database is free of these anomalies.
That's how you automate error handling and SOSIAS.
As you can see the conditional split is an extremely powerful tool that can save you lots of time in
the next Tauriel.
We will delve deeper into this feature and learn how to combine multiple conditional splits in SSX