Today will perform one final check.
So to illustrate how you can run these if you have some additional knowledge about 2 data.
So let's move on to our birthday column.
We're going to select star from cinephile table and then we're going to look for columns where let's
say birthday is just ridiculously far away meaning for instance where Let's find all the records representing
people over 100 years old.
So in this case it will be 19 15 0 8 13.
So 100 years ago was their birthday and let's have a look at that.
So hero not.
Strangely enough we did find one record where there was one.
The year 1900 and it's the 30th of January so that doesn't look right.
This person is would be 100 and 15 years old now over that going on to his 116.
So a good thing to do here is obviously exclude but just in case just in case this is a real client
to go ahead and verify although I highly doubt that this would be a real client.
So in this case we're going to just exclude the stroke.
Once again you can copy this record maybe in reality this is just an error most likely is just an error
in the birth.
They call them.
So you would go and investigate and find out what the correct birthday is.
Or send his daughter back along with all other records and those you found to get them fixed.
However we're not going to focus on that in this tutorial so we're just going to exclude it now as we
did before replay select star of did eat run the query again copy result underneath for future reference
.
All right so we've done the low birthdays.
Now let's look at the highborn this same concept select star from the working table once again.
And here we're going to say where birthday
is greater than.
So depending on your intrinsic knowledge of the data you might know that nobody.
Your company doesn't deal for anybody under 35 or your company or this particular segment that you're
looking at is only 40s to 50s or something like that.
So in this case we don't have any of those restrictions so we're just going to go for the essential
ones that perhaps this unless this is you know some school record there's no customers in here in this
financial institution that are under 10 years old.
So how about how we look at that just as an example.
So in this case will be 2005 0 8 13.
So let's see if anybody has a birthday that what happened after that date so we ran that by clicking
on five.
And you can see that there's none here so you can alter this condition once again based on your intrinsic
knowledge of the data set.
You might look for anybody who's under 20 so we can do that.
But for this data set it should be fine for people to be 20 years old.
So let's have a look at that.
You see here we have quite a few records where people born in 96 and 95.
So in this case it's not it's not a valid exclusion we don't need to exclude anything we haven't found
anything.
So in this case we'll just leave it to 2005.
We'll run it.
And just to.
So for all disability purposes so that we know it we did run this check.
We'll just say and a hair meaning we did not actually exclude in euros.
And so that's all for this part of the section we were done with the DTL of Phase 3 error handling part
of the course.
And in the next tutorial we will sum up what we learned in this section