Thanks for checking this out.
This is my full presentation that I gave a couple of months ago and I just wanted to give you some quick
introduction or some background of what you'll be listening to just because the audience that was there
they did have a bit more information.
It was an industry event so they knew what they were signing up for.
So where I work before is a company called Super it's an Australian superannuation fund in Australia
.
Pension funds are called super pension funds.
And basically every full time employee in the country is according to that legislation has to contribute
approximately 90 percent of their salary into a nation fund.
And since Byrd is one of the Near the top ten of salvation funds in Australia and the biggest problem
here was that people might have lots of special special accounts from different funds and you want them
to consolidate their funds into one account right to basically your preferred to be with your superior
one and therefore you can you contact them you send them forms to fill out and then they send these
forms back to you in order to control it.
So I suppose there is such a good job at getting members to consolidate or inviting them to consolidate
that the inflow of requests coming back was so great that it was causing capacity issues.
So there was a bottleneck actually of 40 day backlog in processing the incoming requests and that's
where super decided to apply Dallasites to solve the problem.
And I'm sure you'll pick it up from there.
Enjoy the presentation as you have probably gathered outside a super intelligent design of one of the
successes in this space.
But I don't want a case I don't want to pass on to a jury.
I want to understand the stakes.
My guess is how are you going to make your way to become the next.
It's so great.
So we get paid.
So those are all what exactly.
All right.
Just so everybody else
is a matter of money was most cases it's interest to them their funds.
So that's what during the year take a listen and go say Australia.
Where else do they spend on members from their BASIC was the right place for you.
For example 18000 people in August 2013 they were able to buy every 20 cents.
Now this drastic response rate was due to a requirement called proof of identification being dropped
.
So easier for them to swallow.
And finally in comparison to 65000 people of the age of consent now this increase in response rate of
5 percent doesn't seem like it does make a big difference.
And it was indeed Ju-Ju It does however focus on today.
We're going to talk about the dark side of cigarettes.
So if you look at these numbers 27 percent and take into account that we're sending tens of thousands
of members you could imagine that is never really going to have a drastic inflow of income requests
coming back into the bottle.
And we noticed this was in March last year the one was not ready for such a high volume of requests
coming in.
In fact the more than a day back in November.
So as you can imagine this is a successful campaign from a customer experience not so much.
And for a member centric organization it likes and super.
This was a major point of concern and that's when we decided to apply data science to improve the August
compay.
So that's what we're going to do now we're going to moderate that right now it's July 2014.
The march campaign has just passed and we have the results and the august campaign is upcoming.
And we're going to see how support applied Donna signs to fix the problem.
So just to reiterate the challenges of the super American Pain First of all it's urgent if you don't
get your members first you compare as will be true it is a resourcing might be a concern you might not
have enough staff to process all the incoming requests.
There may be tensions between departments because of that marketing might want to get to the members
as quickly as possible and operations might be concerned with their capacity to process these requests
.
And finally the most important challenge the backlog which can detract from member experience and that's
when some super decided to use data science to address these issues so how can you is that a science
to improve something that hasn't even happened yet.
Well the concept isn't that complicated.
Thanks to the infrastructure that my colleagues have set up and the unlimited access that I have to
daughter we can use the march campaign and mine it for data use that data together extract insights
and then apply those insights to the August campaign to fix the errors even before they occur.
And to do that let's start with the simplest thing that we possibly can.
Let's Plaut the distribution of the incoming requests over time.
And this is what it looks like.
So on the horizontal axis you can see here the number of days working days are passed since we launched
the campaign.
The vertical axis is the number of requests we received in that particular day.
As you can see the chart is a bit spiky So lets move it out a three day rolling average and all this
converter bartók.
And here you can see that this is an inside in its own right.
First of all soon realize it comparing the volumes per day or drastically increasing they peak around
8 and they quickly drop off but not to the end.
We can still see more requests coming in even around 100 working days later.
Okay so that's that's valuable you now know that you can expect a peak around day 8 and maybe you can
do something about it.
Now let's look at the chart.
And by that I mean instead of plotting everyday separately all we're going to do is we're going to plot
every new day on top of the previous one and so in a way we're going to see how the requests are all
money in.
From members we'll be piling up over time.
And this is what that chart looks like.
So it's a nice pretty smooth chart.
What insights can we derive from here.
Well let's look at the 50 percent line.
When did we receive half of the requests.
Well that happened at 13 days.
So out of 100 over 100 days half of the request came in 13 days.
Good insight.
Let's try another thing.
This is something I'm quite sure some of you in the audience are already familiar with the concept of
the Pareto Principle that 80 percent of the effects come from 20 percent of the causes.
Well let's see how that works in our case.
That's a tip and line.
And 80 percent of the requests came in at 31 days.
So that's not exactly 20 percent but it's close enough.
And what does this tell us.
Well the daughter here is screaming at us that the most labor intensive period for this campaign is
the first 31 days.
You have to make sure that your staff are trained up they're focused you have enough people in the campaign
and you have to avoid the backlog in those 31 days.
And if you do then you can slowly start taking people off the project and putting them on other projects
.
After the 31 days Mark because as you can see the curve flattens out.
So that's that's good.
Now let's put them side by side and have a look at them.
And now this is the part where this is where you get to see how scientists think.
So looking at them was like I've seen this somewhere.
I've seen this in one of my economics maths classes.
This is so familiar and then it me it looks a lot like an ideal mathematical lognormal distribution
.
And let's just put them side by side and you see what I mean.
You see that they're very similar.
And this is where I embarked upon a journey to find out exactly what distribution it was.
So just to make sure we're all up to speed we have a distribution here.
Now we're trying to curve fit it.
We're trying to find the right curve for this distribution and then find a name for that curve.
And so I use a tool called easy fit.
And once again thanks to Nathan brother.
Like any tool agile process we can get our hands on very quickly as you can see it wasn't a log normal
distribution.
It wasn't a Pearson distribution it wasn't a gamma distribution.
Had to try quite a few more and you know sometimes in life when you really really want something and
just so determined to get it you eventually get it.
Well this was one of those cases.
It turned out to be a Frechette distribution.
And at the time I had no idea what for sure distribution was had to go look it up and it turns out that
a for shared distribution to use is used to model the behavior of floods in extreme weather conditions
.
How crazy is that members of a super fund will respond to a super massive campaign just like a dam response
to extremely heavy rainfall.
And right.
Right.
And that is why I love my job.
It like you can like the only place you can come up with these things oh is only daughter can tell you
this like you can come up with some leg up by yourself and no consultant in the world would be able
to tell you this kind of thing only daughter can.
And let's look at the chart here.
You can see that they line up pretty well which is a good validation point.
And then comes a question why why did we do this.
If I take this Frechette submission to the operations department they'll say Carol this is really cool
but what is the value in this.
And that is when we take it to the next level.
So the Frechette distribution Oh because the sample size is so large we can actually apply the law of
large numbers which tells us that in essence tells us that we can use the dot information that we mine
from the March campaign pledge the August campaign and predict what's going to happen.
And so the for sure distribution is basically just a stepping stone for us towards the formulas the
formulas these formulas describe the crowd behavior of members that we triggered with a Super Match
campaign and now we have this intrinsic knowledge of how exactly they will behave as a crowd.
We can create a model a model that will predict and forecast what will happen in August and that's exactly
what I did.
I create a tool which is a unique tool dedicated specifically to this campaign.
We will go into details Abara about the controls of this tool but what I will say is that you can input
.
I can see some of your taking photos.
Great.
So what we can do about what we can do here is we can input the number of members we sending a complaint
to.
We can also input the number of lefties or staff that are processing this campaign when other responses
come back in and will give us a forecast as folks on the chart.
This campaign or this tool is currently set to the August data and you can see here that the red line
is the forecasted volumes of response rates how they will be coming in in August and the blue line is
our capacity to process those requests.
And from here we can see that even with 20 staff on this campaign we will still see a massive backlog
.
Just like the one that happened in March and this is the part of the I was talking about we have done
the predictive part of analytics.
We can even predict the problem we can see it right there is going to happen if we don't act upon it
.
Now we're moving onto the prescriptive analytics how do we fix the problem before it even happens.
Well the first thing that comes to mind is increase the number of staff on the job or even for a period
of time to get rid of that backlog.
Well what the DOT is telling us here is that you would need at least 45 to 50 staff processing this
project in order to mitigate the backlog completely.
And I'm sure none of you in this room have 50 of these just laying around waiting to be put on one single
project.
So that wasn't an option for some super and I had to come up with a different solution.
And what this tool allows you to do is it allows you to break up your campaign and send it in batches
and see how those Sinatras will work out.
So let's have a look at a scenario here we've got two batches.
Here's another scenario with three batches.
And if we visualize the total curve of these three batches this is what it looks like.
So here now you can see that if we break it up into three batches 10 days apart even with 20 staff we
can easily process this campaign without any substantial backlog.
And now going through the scenarios I was able to determine that the optimal solution here is five batches
and we can drop the number of stuff on the project to 11 people.
And that's that's that's exactly what we did.
And now we're going to like looking at this it looks great in theory right.
No backlog 11 stuff but we hear a lot of hype around data science.
It's a cool trendy thing it's it's you know it's somewhere in the clouds that can help your organization
.
But you know it doesn't really actually work and the way we structured our data science departments
and super was a keen focus on measuring success because we believe that success is the ultimate validator
of how we can work together how we can work together to deliver value for the business.
And that's what we're going to do now.
This is our forecast.
It's in blue what we're going to do is we're going to see how we measured the incoming requests.
Week by week that's on super.
And we're going to plot those over this chart in green and see how they compare.
So there's our first two weeks there's another three weeks there's another three weeks and you can see
the massive dip which was caused by the public holiday because the post office doesn't deliver mail
on public holidays and therefore the spike on the next day.
Here's another two weeks.
And here is an operator error which I was looking at I could understand there was a public holiday.
There was nothing that caused this and through dot we were able to pick this up very quickly and rectify
it right away.
And that that's also a valuable part of data that allows you to pick up things on the fly that you otherwise
would have seen maybe a month two months or maybe never.
Then here's another two weeks another three weeks another two weeks and the G20 public holiday in Brisbane
and another week.
And so as you can see the actual the Super Match applies very well to the forecast and what that allowed
us to do was to deliver this campaign with 11 if he were ill.
Rerolled in over 142 million dollars but what was more important we delivered an outstanding member
experience.
Were it just the backlog from 40 days to under three days.
And if I could leave you with one thought from this presentation it would be that the door is there
.
You can all do all to this in your organization.
A door is there you just have to look at it.
Thank you
.