All right so now you've performed this complex upload process and in your database you have some data
that you can analyze most of the data actually forty nine thousand eight hundred sixty eight rows out
of the 50000.
And for that you were supplied with.
However the question is What do you do with these anomalies or these files of rows that you're not including
in your database at the moment so the 132 rows in this flood file this so those that didn't have sufficient
data and those with bad records those four rows of bad records what do you do with them.
And do you need to include them in your analysis.
And that's what we'll be talking about today.
So there are two options here option number one which is my favorite is when it's not important.
And this is when your analysis that you're doing is of a certain nature where you're looking for averages
or you're looking for kind of trends and you're generally aggregating the data and you don't really
mind if there is a 5 percent error in your results and it's acceptable because you're looking for you'll
get a big big sample is 50 50 thousand rows.
And if you're taking the average of the sample then not having 132 hundred thirty six records that are
not substantial outliers you can assume that that doesn't really affect the average overall So if you're
looking at things like that or or different types of distributions core tiles deciles things like that
.
Then in your final report you can just state that some of the daughter has been excluded due to irregularities
and anomalies and this is the number of records that has been used in this analysis.
On the other hand there is Scenario 2 and that is the scenario when these records are important for
instance you're doing a fraud investigation or you reporting to the executives on how certain departments
are performing or how your customers are spending and you have to make sure that the data or the final
result that you have it actually matches to the result that they see on a daily basis coming from reporting
services or something like that so you can't it can't even be out by one dollar it has to be exact on
the spot because what they see from other reports and what you're reporting on is coming from the same
data source.
So therefore it has to match and if it doesn't match then that they're going to have a lot of questions
.
So if you're in the second scenario where it's important to make sure that you eventually include these
rows or at least find out what's going on there then the ideal solution to that scenario is if you go
back to the person who gave you this doctor who gave you these files or if you took them yourself if
you access the data yourself by yourself like through a database or something then you go to the person
who who is the custodian of his daughter who's governing all the processes around this data who's looking
after it.
And you talk to that person you e-mail them you call them you run to them I don't know like you have
to get in touch with the person who's in charge and question them on the specific rows because it is
their job to make sure that there are no anomalies in the data.
And big organizations usually have departments that look after the data they have data custodians who
make sure that there are no irregularities that Eudora's clean and well-presented and so on.
And you talk to them and they should be able to help you out and say oh no those are old records that
shouldn't be there or you might even alarm them and alert them to something that they haven't they're
not aware of and you might actually help them resolve an issue in the back end of the database or of
one of the systems.
And you know do them a favor that way.
But at the end of the day you need them to help you resolve these issues.
And finally if you don't have the time if you can't wait for their response because those people are
usually busy and takes time for them to respond then you can try the risky option and attempt to fix
the data itself like this data that where there is insufficient data Well there's nothing you can do
about it you just just can't fix it you can have a look at the file and just make sure that it is actually
insufficient data that the rows haven't been skewed so maybe the columns that you're interested in maybe
that zip code column has been skewed because of an anomaly or corruption in the data set and you actually
can fix that and return the zip code to its normal place and that way you will be able to access the
data that you need.
But if the data is just not there then there's nothing you can do about it.
And you have to go back to the previous solution where you find the person who's in charge of this data
and you find other means of investigation and you actually get your hands on the original proper original
data with the bad records.
In most cases I hate to like give you the Bladen truth.
But in most cases you won't be able to fix up data issues data corruption and irregularities because
they can.
There's a huge range of things that can happen of data and like you saw in Roe 81 just some columns
are complete completely got mangled up and they weren't there and some calls were in a wrong place and
some of those issues.
There's nothing you can do about them.
But at the same time if it is a simple issue with text qualifiers like we've been investigating so far
then maybe there's a chance that you can fix it up by through what you know already from the scores
how the text qualifiers are meant to be placed and what programs like Excel could have done with your
data set.
So there is a chance that you can fix them but if you do approach it from that perspective then make
sure that somebody checks your work because the last thing you want is check for records out of over
50000 that you fixed up manually and you did something wrong and they completely messed up your analysis
.
So make sure somebody checks your work and explain to them what you did and hopefully somebody more
senior can say that.
OK.
You did the right thing.
And this looks like it's fixed up and it's good.
Whatever you do.
If however you get this daughter what you need to do afterwards is re uploaded but separately so this
is this is done we have uploaded all 49000 868 records and we're happy with them.
We're not going to get this data and then put in the flat file source and do that all that again no
.
So once you have the correct data which is missing right now then you create a new upload so you create
in your original file you put them in there you upload them separately you create a new profile in a
school and then later on when you're working in sequel you will be able to combine the two raw files
this raw file and the other file.
It's much better to do it that way because you once again have traceability of what was done and you
always have the wrong data sets are all tables separately and SDL and you can always reverse if there
is some issues or some issues and to finish off what we're going to do today is we're going to look
at this specific file so just the bad records.
And just for practice sake because you'll have this in your homework.
We will see if we can understand exactly what happened in which one of those rows and identify where
you know the text qualifier was missing or what was wrong.
So let's go ahead and get started with that.
There is a folder of the automatically exclude results and we're going to be looking at the fake names
bad records.
So I'm going to open it up with notepad plus plus.
And here you've got all these qualifiers because that's how we create the file we asked for access qualifiers
just in case.
And now I'm going to open up the original file so in fact we're going to do is what I like to do in
these cases is just make a copy just in case.
So in case we messed something up here so we don't have to rerun the upload and then we'll go to the
fake names original daughter take a copy so we copied that file go to analysis go to data errors and
in automatically so we'll just put it in here.
And so we'll just say at the bottom copy and just so they're close together we'll say copy here as well
.
And now we can look at them both in Notepad plus plus so added with notepad plus plus.
And this one as well as you remember right click move to other view.
There's a we can synchronize them if we want to maybe vertically.
Let's try that.
You synchronize vertical and horizontal scrolling so.
So this way they're synchronized but they might not might not really work because there's a lot of text
wildfire's vertical there's no point so luckily for these records we have their own numbers sometimes
these row numbers because they're actually built into the data.
They could also get corrupted and that way you'll have to search through other means like the name surname
so find that way find it that way but now we have their own numbers so let's go ahead and look at them
.
So two to one 7:6 I'm just going to look here two to 176 not one not one.
There we go.
So there's 2 2 1 7 6.
And so let's slowly scroll through and understand what could have happened and we really know it's probably
a text qualifier somewhere around the feedback section and that's where we'll look right away.
There we go.
I'm so happy I found this company right.
Coma they save me a lot of time.
What did that turn.
What does it look like here here.
So I'm going to switch off this scrolling synchronization.
So what does it look like here.
I am so happy here is being separated as different columns and obviously because there was no text qualifiers
at all.
That's exactly normal that's what should have happened because here I am so happy I found this company
is one column.
C'mon they say me so much.
So how would you fix this.
Obviously you just put a quotation mark here quotation mark here and in the prepared data file.
And that way this would all be
perceived as one cell and put into one column.
All right so that's how we would fix this one up.
Was going to remove that and we'll just remember we are.
That's how we fix that one up.
OK.
Let's go on to the next row.
What's an row 3 5 0 0 1.
There we go so that's 3 5 0 0 1.
What can you see here.
Thank you.
Quotation marks starts and then nothing.
So let's see what that turned into in this.
Output 3 5 0 0 1.
Thank you.
And then it started eating up all this so this is where a column starts and it started eating up everything
everything everything until there until that text qualifier and then excel thought OK so that's out
of the column will start the next one here.
All right so now let's see how this row ends.
If you scroll to the end then something happened here with the credit card number because obviously
it fell into the wrong field and then it was converted to these characters so there's something that
you can fix as you can retrieve the text or the credit card number from there although you can fix it
in your original file so if you original file you just put an extra quotation mark here and then this
way all of this should be picked up properly.
So once again you don't put this into you're prepared to fold a file because we finished that upload
you create a new file and you prepare a file and then you upload and then you see if there are any other
anomalies in the show.
If not then maybe maybe just maybe you've managed to fix it so that your credit card number that got
mangled up over here.
All right.
So I'm going to undo that.
Thank you.
OK.
Next 1 3 5 0 0 2 right over here so what this person say.
Thank you kindly.
No quotation marks.
You know how that goes down that doesn't go down good at all.
Two separate columns.
All right.
Well you know how to fix this quotation mark their quotation mark there.
Once again fix is a very I'm using it very liberally.
Maybe there are other issues in this role that you don't know about yet.
And so by fix I mean you put those quotation marks in you creating your original file for maybe you
can put all these rules together if you want.
Once you've.
You think you fix them and then you try uploading them and then you see how many go through.
And then finally 4 5 9 4 7.
Let's look for that.
Oh whoops I think I skipped it.
Is that again.
There it is.
OK.
4 5 9 4 7.
Let's scroll that see what the Coleman says and voila there's no comment.
So this one's a bit more interesting right.
So what happened here.
There is no comment.
How come there is an anomaly.
Why.
Why is it skewed so if you go to the end of this file you will see what we see here.
Well you see these rows and I think you don't see an empty row at the end so there should be an empty
row so that means it will skew to the right.
If you look at the end here.
OK so what can we say about this fall.
Well let's just keep looking at this.
Look keep looking through it and see what could have happened.
So nothing nothing nothing.
And do you see anything like that that other records don't have anything there or have a quotation mark
.
You know maybe that's just the record so that's fine.
Let's just keep looking maybe we just keep that in mind.
And then when you get to the end you see that there is a quotation mark here just like this one has
a quotation mark.
So it's basically the same same record.
These two things are the same.
But here you go double quotation marks.
You go to a single.
So somehow the double irritation Mark turned into a single quotation mark.
And therefore this whole thing has been messed up.
How has it been messed up.
Well the only reason be messed up is because of this comma.
So basically one excel or any other program gets to this point.
They're like OK so that's that's our browser that was used.
That goes into the browser column.
And then this goes into the next column where the number of telephone number should be so that's how
this Rugel skew to the right.
So how would you fix this.
Well you would change this to a double quotation mark.
There you go so that's some basic analysis.
Once again you don't have to fix the roads yourself and preferably you shouldn't but but maybe analyzing
them can help you guide the person that is the custodian of the data to what you think happened to these
roads.
So that is the end for today we are getting close to the end of the section.
Hope you're enjoying it.
I know it's very very tedious lots of working with data but that's that's the reality of things and
sometimes as the scientists you to do that the information that we talked about in this section will
be helpful for you in your homework.