All right.
Welcome to the homework to Tauriel for this section.
It's exciting that you've decided to undertake this challenge.
And let me show you where to get that does it.
So if you go as usual to super size that comsats training and then you scroll down to part 3.0 prep
and then you look at Section 4 handling areas doing it well phases 1 and 2 then your homeward data sets
over here over to our set.
FAKE NAMES UK dot zip.
So if you download that and unzip it then you'll get a file which looks like this.
FAKE NAMES cadency a sweep.
And let's go ahead and open up this file so I can explain what the challenge is for today.
So I'm going to zoom in a bit.
So here you've got a file with some customer records.
And then it's got quite a few columns.
If you scroll down you can see that the number of rows is supposed to be 100000 according to this column
but in reality it's much less not much less but a bit less.
So there was definitely already we can tell something is wrong with the file probably a lot more is
wrong with the file.
And what I wanted to tell you so what is this whole project about.
Well you are Imagine yourself as a data scientist who's performing some research or analysis for a medical
facility and this research is reliant on three factors three main columns that you definitely need for
analysis are the last three Kolbe's blood type kilograms and centimeters.
So basically you're assessing as you can kind of guess from here that you're assessing how the blood
type affects people's BMI.
So body mass index which you can calculate from kilograms and centimeters something.
So there's some combination of these three columns that you will be assessing or that are going to be
assessed in this project.
And right now what you need to do is upload the data into the database.
So because you will be using these two columns that means that they're critical and your role that doesn't
have information in it in any one of these columns is not useful for your analysis can because he's
got a lot of rows 100000.
And according to the instructions you are.
It's like it's a statistical analysis so you're not going to be reporting back to these people or anything
.
It's more to see how how this effect a phenomenon that you're observing how it's actually distributed
across the population and things like that.
So if you exclude a couple of rows not a problem because you are going to be looking at averages and
things like that.
So from here you gather that you have to have these three columns Yeah old all the records that you
can analyze.
They have to have these data in these three columns.
The rest are nice to have but they're not critical.
So that's what you'll be looking for and that has to be included in your T.L. upload part.
So that as this is I guess uploader we're doing through conditional splits you've got to take that into
account there.
Plus you going to remove any corrupted records that will jeopardize your analysis down the track.
So that's that.
I'll leave you with those instructions.
Good luck with this homework.
And don't forget that all the homework solutions for all the exercises and the scores are available
at the very end of the course.
So check that out.
After you finished.
Hope you go well and I look forward to seeing you on the next tutorial.
Until then happy analyzing