Cross departmental work.
Now if you're really working as a data scientists you will totally know what I'm talking about.
If you're not yet then prepare yourself for what's going to happen once you start as a data scientist
.
You will find that you're working not in one division not into working across three four or five divisions
at times and you working with everybody because data scientists are a very unique type of role.
You need to have access to all levels of the organization levels up and down and sideways so hierarchical
levels and we'll talk about that more.
And also like different departments I'll give you my example so in my previous role I was in the marketing
department but half the time I was working with I.T. department.
And the funny part was they were actually located in two separate buildings across the road.
So I was sitting in one department and the I.T. people were sitting in the opposite on opposite sides
of the road.
And I had to work very closely with him.
And how did that come to be.
Well the I was in a team called Casler experience and insight.
So I was doing data science which was related to the experience that some members of this organization
or customers of this organization goes through on a daily basis.
But at the same time I need access to databases any skill server I needed reporting services I needed
to extract I needed all these all sorts of things I need new tools and software.
And so I had to over fighting the department a lot.
And before this happened because I was first out of scientists at this organization the two departments
actually didn't talk much to each other.
Yes they did throw around some data once in a while but they didn't have this connection.
And that is what you will find when you come in you will become this bridge between departments.
Sometimes when the connection isn't there but she needed you will become that hub where light which
connects all sorts of different departments can be marketing I.T. operations finance whatever.
All of these departments that you are connecting in your work they'll be going through you.
And from my experience and this is the feedback I got from the organization I brought these departments
across here like it.
It didn't even feel like there was a brawl between us anymore it felt like we were working close so
we had by the end of my side that we started having every Monday we would have a catch up where there
was the I.T. Department and the marketing department sitting together for an hour talking about you
know what one of the plans for the week.
Like that's unheard of in that industry in which I was working and we prepared for that.
So you will need to work across departments.
That's a that's one example.
Marketing and I.T..
I also worked in operations a lot.
Because you know optimizing existing business processes or resolving backlogs increasing efficiencies
and so on so you will be working for operations.
And so every time you work with a new department make sure to establish the connections there so that
you like know the managers there or executives there and like they know the work you're doing so you
can always come back there and you know get inside if you need their help with something and they need
your help with something you're going to be a people person generally.
And don't be afraid to work walk around the organization Don't be afraid.
Don't always just sit at your desk and do the work that I would normally easily just grab my stuff and
spend two or three days with I.T. guys just sitting there working on a spare computer there or you know
go and sit with Operation guys for for a day like you would be really hard to find me at my desk because
I'm always getting these insights you go to.
You got to know not just the dot but you also going to know the intrinsic details of your organization
how it works is like it's like a living organism you've got to understand exactly you know how pulsates
and what is cool what are the cause and effects that that lead to certain phenomenons that you're observing
and things like that so the more you get out there the better the data scientist is a person that works
across a lot of different departments