Hello this is curial And today we're talking about types of variables.
So variables they can be of two distinct types.
One is categorical and categorical variables as the names gests they describe quality or a characteristic
of a data unit.
So basically they're answering the question to What category does this record belong and what what what
are its properties.
So there are two subtypes of categorical variables.
Number one is nominal and nominal variables are observations that cannot be organized into a logical
sequence.
So basically things like gender male or female Let's have a look at a few examples actually.
So male or female you can't order them.
You can say one is greater than the other or the other one is comes first and then comes second.
You can put them in order.
Same thing with red green black with colors you can order them so they basically they do categorize
your data but you cannot do anything about it you can't put them into a chronological or any kind of
order and that's why they're called nominals So basically a good way to remember this is like name is
so nominal and the word names they sound similar and therefore as with names you can order them nominal
where variables you can order them either.
The other subtype of categorical variables are ordinal variables.
So these are variables which are categorical.
But you can order them.
So let's have a look at a few examples.
So for instance small medium large these categories they say in terms of clothes in a store you can
break down your clothes into groups based on what size the label states small medium or large.
And moreover you can order them so you can put these groups of clothes in a logical order meaning that
clothes in this batch are bigger than the clothes in this batch and then they're bigger than the clothes
in the smallest batch unserviceable think of grade's ABC So you know is the highest grade B is the next
grade C is the lower grade and so on.
So even though their order even though they don't have numbers here they have a logical inherent order
within them.
And so those those are the two different types of categorical variables.
Now if we move on to the other type of variables we will go to numeric.
So numeric variables are basically numbers and there are two types of numeric variables and these variables
actually overall numeric variables.
They answer the question how much or how many.
So for instance there are discrete numeric variables and discrete numeric variables.
They are basically whole numbers so how many units of something or they are or how much of something
occurred.
But Econ. it can be a fraction of a number and let's have a look at a few examples here as well.
So for instance 1 2 3 5 10 100 businesses you can have one and a half businesses right you can have
2 1 2 5 businesses so basically it can be they can be an infinite number of observations that doesn't
matter.
But as long as there's nothing in between so there's a there's two businesses there's three businesses
but there's nothing in between you can have a value in between same.
Same with people.
You can have 168 people you can have 567 people but there's nothing in between so you can't find another
variable between two sets discrete variables that are that come in sequence.
And finally the last type of numeric variables or overall variables that we're going to look at is continuous
variables so continuous variables are a subtype of many variables.
They also answer the question how many or how much.
But unlike discrete variables they can be a fraction.
For instance age or height.
So you can be a hundred and seventy three meters tall you can be a hundred and seventy three and a half
meters tall.
So basically any two continuous variables that you take are continuous values that you take on your
scale.
Say one hundred one hundred seventy three and one hundred and in three and a half there will always
be another continuous variable between them so one hundred seventy three point to five.
And even if you take 173 point to five and 173 and a half they'll still be another one in between them
173.
Point 2 5 7 and so on.
So there's always another variable between any two or there's always another value between any two continuous
values so they can be of course restricted at a minimum maximum so it can be lower.
Or for instance with age you can be younger than 0 years old and you can be older than 150 unless your
medicine goes through the roof in the next couple of years.
So there are there can be restrictions but within those boundaries there is an unlimited number of values
that the variable can take.
So those are four types of variables nominal ordinal discrete continues.
Have a look around you try to think of other examples.
It's a very good exercise to remember these four different types