Improve the toil we talked about the accuracy paradox.
Hopefully now you see why we need more robust methods to assess how models and we talk about the cumulative
accuracy profile which is in fact one of those methods.
Let's look at a scenario.
Let's say you're a scientist at a store which sells clothes and your store has a total of 100000 customers
.
I'm placing that number on the horizontal axis.
And you know that from experience whenever you send and offer like an e-mail to all your customers or
to any random sample of your customers approximately 10 percent of them respond and purchase the product
.
So I'm going to place 10000 which is 10 percent of the total on the vertical axis.
And so what we're going to do is where we've got an offer that we want to send and we want to see how
many customers are going to purchase our product.
We send it off so if we send it to 0 customers obviously we'll get zero responses right.
What do you think will happen if we send it to 20000 customers.
How many do you think will respond.
Well because this is a random sample and we know that about 10 percent response I would say about 2000
would respond.
Fair enough right.
If 40000 if we send to offer to 40000 of our customers then about 4000 will respond 60000 6000 80000
8000 100000 then 10000 of our customers should respond.
And this is a random selection process so here we can draw a line which will actually represent this
random selection the slope of the line equals to that 10 percent that we know that respond on average
to offer as if we just send them out like that.
Now the question is can we somehow improve this experience can we get more customers to respond to offers
when we send out our letter so basically Can we somehow target our customers more appropriately so to
get a better response rate.
And how about instead of sending out these offers randomly to say a random sample of 20000 customers
.
How would we pick and choose the customers we send these offers to and how do we pick and choose.
Well to start off with let's build a model just like we did in the previous section.
Basically a customer segmentation model.
Joe German graphic segmentation model but which won't predict whether or not they will leave the company
it will actually predict whether or not they will purchase the product.
It's a very simple process actually.
In fact it's the same thing because purchased is also a binary variable yes or no.
And we can also run the same experiment.
We can take a group of customers before we send out the offer and then look back and see who purchased
where the male or female.
Which country were they in.
What age predominantly were they.
Were they browsing on mobile were they browsing via a computer.
And all of these factors we can take them into account measure them put them into a logistic regression
and get a model which will help us assess the likelihood of certain types of customers purchasing based
on their characteristics are they job and demographic status and and other characteristics.
And once we've built this model how about we apply it to select customers we will send the offer to
.
So what the model will tell us like just like in the example in the previous section where females of
female customers of a bank whose favorite color is red they're most likely to leave the bag here will
have a similar result.
Ill say perhaps male customers in this certain age group who browse and mobile are most likely to purchase
a product.
It will tell us something or ill actually rank our customers will give them a probability of purchasing
our product and then we can use that probability to actually contact our customers.
So of course if we contact 0 customers we'll get zero response rate but if we contact 20000 we'll probably
get a much higher response rate than just 2000 because we're picking out the customers that are at the
highest risk of accepting this offer.
We know from their previous behavior from the previous behavior of customers similar to them that they
have a 90 percent chance or an 80 percent chance of purchasing this product and we will go for them
first.
We will put them at the top of our list of people who would contact then when we contact that they would
contact not 20000 but 40000.
Our response rate will be higher than 4000 which we get in the random scenario.
If we if our model is really good then by the time we're at around around 60 thousand so more than just
over half of our total customer base we are really getting to that 10000 mark so we know that 10000
people will respond in total.
There's no way we can get above that because that's just the response rate if we contact everybody it'll
be 10000 but we're getting very close already.
So even at 60000 we're already at nine and a half thousand respondents or purchases.
We we could actually stop here.
We've already pretty much contacted everyone.
But if we want to contact more if we send it out to 80000 we're getting even closer to 10000 responses
.
And if we contact 100000 we will still be back at our 10000 responses.
So now let's draw a line through these crosses.
So what do you see this line here is called the cumulative accuracy profile of your model.
And as you can imagine the better your model the larger will be the the area under the slides so the
area between the red and the blue lines it will increase as your model gets better.
And if your model is worse then this red line will be closer to the blue line so it'll be closer to
random.
The next step we want to do is convert these axes from absolute values to percentages.
So for so they range from zero to 100 percent and this is how the cap kirpan is normally represented
.
Now let's say we ran another regression model and this time we used less variables listen to variables
or just because we had less access to independent variables or we didn't see that there a multicollinearity
effect in a model or something else that went wrong.
And that model because it will be worse.
This is what its cap curve will look like and therefore by plotting the cap curves you'll be able to
compare models to each other and understand how much gain this is also sometimes called the gain chart
how much gain you get in each of these models compared to the random scenario or how much again you
get additional gain you get from switching from one model to the next or from the green one to the red
one for instance you're improving your hit ratio and therefore you're improving your return on investment
.
So therefore the read model is better.
And this is how we are going to be assessing models.
So let's label them the blue line is a random selection process like a monkey could do that you just
pick out random sample and you send the letter or you just send it to everybody and you get 100 percent
of respondents.
The green line is a poor model.
So it's it's a model is better than random but it's still not as good as the red one the red one is
a good model as you can see here or around the 50 percent mark we're getting just over 80 percent response's
that's considered a good model.
And there's one more line that you can think of here and it's this line.
This line is the ideal line.
And this is what would happen if you had a crystal ball if you could predict exactly who is going to
purchase and contact those people.
This is what it would look like.
Why.
Well because if you look at that the place where that spline occurs you'll see that it's exactly 10
percent and 10 percent as you remember.
We know that only 10 percent of our customers ever purchase.
So basically you're saying that on the horizontal axis I'm going to take 10 percent and each and every
single one of those customers I pick and that 10 percent they are going to be those that purchase.
That means I will go right straight to 100 percent with this last scenario.
This actually took me a while to get my head around.
When I first heard about it because I never understood why the spline at the top why does it break like
that.
But that's exactly the reason because you you mad you can imagine that you have a crystal ball and your
contact in the first 10 percent or however many in your specific business scenario customers ever purchase
you contact them right away and then it's just flat from there because it doesn't matter how many more
you contact they're not going to purchase.
That's just the reality of things.
And that is the curves that you have on a cap curve if you ever see a model that goes under the blue
line.
I didn't even draw one here.
But if that happens that's a very bad model is basically doing you a disservice if it's if you see the
curve on the blue line and we'll talk about model deterioration further in the course when you're talking
about maintaining your models.
So that's it for the cap curve for the introduction of Kepcher will be using the cap curve very actively
in this section to assess our model.
And in fact we've actually built two of them and one for a model and one for our test data so that will
be very interesting to compare.
One last thing I wanted to mention is and note that we have the cap which is a cumulative accuracy profile
and we have a rock which is a receiver operating characteristic.
A lot of people get these things confused and I myself included I used to get it confused I even tried
proving one time a colleague of mine who knew this stuff really well at the time when I was just learning
it that she was wrong because that was a funny experience but they're not the same thing.
So cumulative accuracy profiles when we talked about receiver operating characteristics we won't be
covering this course.
It'll be in my advanced course on statistics.
It's very similar it looks similar and that's why a lot of people get confused and actually I think
the other reason is that the rock curve is in Wikipedia.
There's an article for their occur but there isn't one in English for the cumulative accuracy profile
.
So it's quite hard to find information on the cap curve just by searching in Google so maybe you'll
be the first person to write say the article on the cap curve.
Who knows maybe.
Anyway I look forward to seeing the next tutorial and where we will be working with the cap curve.
And until then happy analyzing