Storytelling is important.
And we talked about this a little bit in the previous tutorial where we said that your audience has
to feel like they're engaged.
You have to create a journey for them and they have to feel part of their journey.
They have to anticipate what you want to say next.
What's coming round the corner.
And they have to be completely immersed in your presentation in order to achieve that effect you can
do a couple of things.
So we talked about a few of them in the previous tutorial and the other thing that I wanted to invite
you to do is scroll down to the end of the section you'll find the full presentation.
So it's about 15 minutes.
And if you watch it you will pick up a couple more of the things that I do or I did in that case to
engage my audience and I got some print out here just a couple.
So one was to add a funny image.
If you added funny to a presentation you know that can get them excited.
But it has to be relevant of course.
And another one was a plot twist.
So you'll hear me say at some point that this is a great finding.
And you know this was a great resolve.
And you're kind of expecting that we're going to talk about it how how we achieve that.
But then I say but that's not what we're going to talk about.
We're going to talk about the dark side of the Superman.
So completely 90 degree turn and we're talking about for the representation we're talking about a completely
different thing.
So that's a plot twist in your presentation.
You get them you get them standing on their toes and waiting for what's coming next and not knowing
what's coming next.
So you kind of showing them that this is not going to be a linear presentation is going to have swerves
which makes it more interesting.
Also another good one which you should watch out for.
I mean like in my presentation I actually say that I want to reenact the series so I'm not in those
exact words but I do suggest to the audience that this is exactly what we're going to do.
We're going to pretend that we are data scientists and it is like we actually rewind time backwards
and it is August 2014 and we are performing this analysis so I'm reenacting the situation with them
participating as the data scientist.
That is very powerful.
And why do we need to do that.
Well and why should we take advantage of that as that aside.
Because first of all data science is very complicated.
Second science is hype right now.
Lots of people are talking about it but they don't know anything about it.
And a third everybody wants to be a data scientist but not many people are going to have an opportunity
to be a data scientist ever in their lives because in so many different skill sets that you have to
have a lot of commitment to this type of mindset to this type of work.
It's it's completely out of this world so people would love the idea to be a dark side for 15 minutes
.
Right it's like try before you buy or even buy.
Just try just just try what it is like to be a dozen put them in your shoes.
Use that to your advantage like my Probably the biggest presentation cigarette for dollar signs that
I can give you right now.
Put the audience in your shoes.
Make Create the journey in such a way that they will experience what you experience through art your
work or your analysis and when you're doing insights.
And in order to do that you've got to use visuals you've got to use visuals and you're going to propose
to them that you're going to put them in your shoes and reenact the situation.
And in terms of visuals what we're going to do now is I want to jump behind the computer and I'm going
to show you my presentation and you will see how little text there was.
And we'll talk more about storytelling now so stay tuned.
I'm jumping.
We have a computer now.
All right so here's my presentation and I don't think that I'm giving away any secrets here whatsoever
.
This presentation is publicly available online and you can freely find it on the web.
And before we continue I wanted to say that if you are planning on watching my full presentation the
video as it happens then probably pause this video actually stop this video and go ahead and watch the
presentation because if you watch this video to the end you will like he's got a few spoilers in here
because it is a journey and if once we go through the slides you will know how the journey ends and
all the plot twists.
So once again if you want to watch the full video they'd probably do that now and then come back to
this tutorial.
Otherwise off we go.
So this is the presentation and what I wanted to show you or focus on is two things.
First of all how little text there is.
And second of all the journey the story so let's go ahead.
So first light of course the intro by the way the template supplied by the events of this case was see
him Assef.
It's called the conference of major super funds 2015 anyway.
So at the start.
I've got some like Overall I'm giving in terms of the journey I'm giving them some overall background
of what has been happening over the years.
So like kind of building up some inspiration.
And like well what are we going to be talking about.
Give a giving them the the problem I'm outlining the problem and you'll find you'll see me say here
that.
OK so this is is is good.
This percentage is increasing the percentage of people who actually take action is increasing and that
is due to Darcys.
But that's not what we're going to talk about so that's a plot twist and the plot twist then I say that
because a person is so high.
There's a there is a backlog issue.
So we're not going to go into detail of the actual text or the actual problem at hand I'm just showing
you how to structure the presentation.
So then once I've told them the problem I make sure that they understand that it's important problem
and it can it can they can relate to it because here are the challenges.
So challenges and as you can see I have like this is all the text I'm going to have in this whole presentation
is after this isn't going to be much text at all so challenges so I highlight four separate challenges
which they can relate to and they also highlight the importance of this.
So step one is to outline the problem that we're going to be discussing and then funny image.
Speaking of ways to engage audience.
So here we say we're going to use our science to approach this problem and solve it.
And there we go.
So here I'm taking them on a journey and putting them in my shoes.
I'm They are imagining that they are a scientist now and for the next 15 minutes.
So I exactly step by step I'm showing them how I approach the problem.
First of all this is exactly what I did I charge a dollar to graphed out.
How many forms were received per in each working day after lodgement saw how much how many of these
forms that we were sending were coming back and how quickly they would come back.
So I saw this this type of curve.
This is exactly as it happened just you know for all the programming or referral the Excel and data
prep and data cleaning just the the fun bits I'm showing them the fun bits of data sets.
Then I applied a three day rolling average so from from this slide I moved to right away the slide.
And then I plotted as a bar chart.
And you know that's a couple of clicks so this presentation is like over 50 slides but every slide takes
like one less than one second on average or one or two seconds on average.
So it worked out really well.
And then after that.
So that's that's what I see so far.
And then in order not to get them bored I decided to give them some quick insights before we go into
the big guns into the real solution to the problem.
So I plotted the cumulative chart and this is also what I did in my analysis and from the simulative
chart what I showed them is that half of the forms are half of the incoming requests were already received
by 13 days.
Right.
So I can show them that I can see this is this.
This is information or an insight which is contained in the data but I can see it and they can see it
too right away from this chart.
It's obvious that only takes 30 days to get half the forms and then there's this longtail.
Then I told him about Pareto's law something that they can take away if they don't operettas low they
can go ahead and apply it further in their own work and I show them how it applies here.
I showed them that 80 percent of the forms or the incoming requests were received about 31 days so not
exactly 80:20 but close enough right.
So you get the 80 percent of the forms back very quickly.
And already this is in terms of backlog it means that the backlog happens in the first 31 days.
And as you'll see from the full presentation is for the for the company.
This means that they have to have the maximum maximum number of people maximum staff in the first 31
days and then they can ease off.
And then so then after they have these inside so they can really see it's interesting if you don't give
them some insights at the very start they'll get bored.
So once they see these in size you can see that oh wow we can derive value from the data.
This data science thing is awesome it's pretty cool.
And also notice by the way a second thing we're talking about here is how little text no text at all
just the picture.
The slides are supporting me not me supporting aside side same thing.
That's how you should present.
Never have never be the the have the slides as the main thing and you're like they'll exhilarate function
performing the auxiliary function supporting the slides in the opposite way around the slides or supporting
what you say people should be looking at you.
Most of the time.
And then I put them together and then I made a funny joke that they look a lot like something I saw
back in university.
And so if you put them close enough that is a log normal distribution right.
So everybody laughs because not many people know what a log normal distribution is.
And so then I take into the process actually show them the tools I was using to find what distribution
this actually is.
So it's not a low gamma distribution not a lognormal not a glow gamma not a Pearson distribution.
And I keep naming these things and they don't understand what I'm talking about.
But to them it's like an anecdote it's like they're seeing what life does scientists is.
I don't expect them to understand these things.
Like I I expect them to see them.
And that's that's the power of pictures.
That's how pictures and journal work together even if people don't understand something they can see
it.
And that's already enough for them to kind of grasp the overall idea because the point of this presentation
is not only to get them to resolve but also take them one journey and by seeing things there like it's
like watching a movie or reading a book.
You don't have to know how to shoot like a gun or ride a horse or you know go scuba diving.
But you can see it in the movie and you can kind of relive that experience with the hero in the movie
.
So this is kind of what's happening here.
They're going through this journey and they're getting sucked into this presentation that's what you
want.
And then they get to get we get here and we get to hear it's not that it's not that.
And then finally we found it right so it's a Frechette distribution and you'll hear me explain in the
video.
This is like a an additional proof that it is a Frechette distribution the cumulative charge fits really
well.
And so you'll hear me explain the video the Forshay distribution is really it's like.
It's fascinating.
This is war and this is where I'm like oh I made another joke saying that this is why I love my job
because the Forshay distribution is actually used and this is true fact to model the behavior of floods
in extreme weather conditions.
So this means that the customers of an organization or pension fund behave in the same way or customers
on a pension fund in Australia should say behave in the same way as a damn response to a flood or two
extremely heavy rainfall and that is you know out of this world like only daughter can show some of
that.
And then you pause and you make them make that thought sink in that this is something you can't logically
think of.
No consultant in the world can tell you that off the top of their head but daughter can.
And dad is super powerful anyway so that's another joke to keep them alive excited.
And what are you going to face next.
That's exactly what you show them.
So I had just had a slide of a question mark and I asked the question so like you're probably thinking
now what is this for is it all sounds cool but what is this for like what is the value to the business
from all these formulas and.
Well and speaking of formulas that for sure distribution allows us to reverse engineer the formula the
distribution of how there are so this takes once again this is not text text because this is more of
a picture.
I expect them to look at this and think Whoa that's that's too much like they should get disgusted by
these formulas they should not want to understand them and I don't I don't need them to understand it
.
You show them the formulas to get them like impress them or frighten them or something cause an emotion
And once they've seen the formulas what happens next you say what do you use the formula for.
And I actually show them how I create a tool that will allow to you know model these distributions and
understand the capacity that the company has to have to to avoid a backlog and actually show them like
this is the backlog this is how much stuff will be like there is a backlog so I actually had a picture
showing them how they can see the backlog.
We knew that there was a 40 day backlog but now using the data and through this whole process which
was really fun they can actually see the backlog visually how big it is going to be so this is a prediction
and you'll see it in the full video.
Explain that.
I've already put in the data for the next campaign for the next event like this and this if we do everything
the same way this is how the back at the back was going to be like.
It's not rocket science.
This is what's going to happen.
And we have to avoid it.
And so then using this to you know use created multiple batches and I had a double slide there but I
knew about it so that's Oko.
So a solution was made through data science and we came up a solution that is multiple batches have
to be used and then upped this process was optimized and even reducing the number of people processing
this campaign a backlog reduction battle was.
It was able we were able to achieve a reduction backload from 40 days to three days.
Right.
Water What a great customer expert.
So you can impress them and then and then you say.
So this is what I said in a real position like data science and this is a good good tip for dosshouse
presentations.
Dollar Signs is all hype.
It's a lot of theory.
Right.
So but you want it to be practical.
People want practical application so include that in your presentation.
So I said All right.
We actually we predicted this is what we predict is going to happen.
Right.
So this is how much we can process this is how much we're going to have.
How bad.
Now we see what actually happened.
And this is a.
And we're monitoring the situation in reality.
So this is what we predicted.
Let's see what happened in the green overlayed green is what actually happens is you can see it's lining
up really well and then like hey explain the anomalies.
Once again you'll you'll see all of that from the full presentation.
Some public call those some errors and so on.
And so what is this.
This is measuring success.
I even named these slides measuring success.
It's important for data size presentations to provide proof and the best proof proof is evidence evidence
that what you forecasted or what you calculated actually works.
And the practical application actually makes the audience go wow.
You did all of this calc all these calculations all this theory all these for share distributions and
it was fun along the way.
Very picturesque lots of images.
And then in the end it actually did work and allowed the company to you know deliver a great customer
experience and a role or consolidate.
Like millions of dollars of funds.
What an impressive presentation what a great ending to a presentation so far.
Like that's something to think about something to consider in your presentations.
Two things.
First of all the journey and I'm sure you just now probably felt like you were in a journey already
.
And the second thing is the lack of text just pictures and that is like data science is visual.
Will we see data and the better you can visualize it the more Culliford you can make it the more N-Gage
audience will be.
So that's how I presented at the same Assef event in 2015.
I wish you luck.
Best of luck with your presentations.
Hope you picked up some useful tips from this tutorial and I look forward to seeing you next time.