Hello and welcome back I hope you had a chance to play around with Tablo in terms of the new functionality
that we discussed where you can have several charts on one worksheet and that in turn brings quite a
few tabs over here in the marks pane so you can control the charts separately.
And today as promised we're going to talk a bit about stats and in particular the chi squared test.
But don't worry it's still going to be heavy stats will just cover off some like basic intuitive things
.
The heavy stats or not even so heavy that's the main discussion about chi squared.
I've taken it out and put it into two separate tutorials that are at the end of the section so feel
free to check it out if you do want to get into the nuts and bolts of chi square and understand it a
bit better.
However today we're just going to look at the practical application of cry squared.
So what is the whole reason we're doing this why do we want to see the look at the statistical significance
and learn about it a bit more.
Well the reason is all of these results that we're seeing here they're great like we can see that it
looks like it's pretty obvious that for instance age has a SIGINT a significant impact on the choice
of people to stay off the bank or not.
You can see that these age groups are more likely to lead these age groups are less likely to leap.
Now look at another one say We can see that here is gender we can see that gender has a significant
impact.
So being a male customer a female customer impacts or there is an association between gender and the
choice to stay with the bank or leave the bank.
However as you recall I've mentioned a couple of times that this is not the hard statistical test so
it is just a visual interpretation or or a visual improvisation of the test will how do we get confident
with this visual and precision how can we be sure that what we're reporting is actually the result and
that we can use this as insights to drive business decisions and we can communicate this to managers
and executives because we all agree that if we have an inside we're not totally sure about it then it's
kind of not the best idea to report it probably or you will feel as comfortable.
So that's why we need the chi squared test.
And basically what the chi square test will tell us is is this result a statistically significant result
.
So as simple as that.
The chi squared test will tell us that we do observe this difference in the sample.
So in our 10000 records.
Well is this a random difference.
So is it just happened.
Has it happened by chance that there is a difference between female and male or is this a consistent
difference can we surely confidently say that in the whole population of the language can be a million
customers which can be 10 million customers.
Can we confidently say that we will observe a similar discrepancy a similar difference in the whole
population of the bank.
That's that's all the squared test does.
It can tell us whether it's just by chance or there is an actual difference that can be and will be
observed in the population.
So how do we run this case square test once again there's more details in the last two trials of this
section and if you do wish to dive into that please go ahead and check those out because there I talk
about how to run it in Excel and you know all the details about chi squared.
But here I'll just show you some online tools that are very quick and can help you do these things very
ad hoc.
So I'm going to bring up a browser now.
And there are two Web sites that we're going to be looking at.
The first one is w w w.
Evan Miller dot org slash AB Ifan testing slash S.H. I hyphens squared dot HMO.
So you can find lots of these Web sites just if you google for chi square test online you'll find quite
a lot but I kind of fancy this one so we'll talk about this one to start with what you have to do here
is basically input your values.
So now the rule number one here an important rule is that chi squared squarely countered use percentages
you have to use actual values so if you put percentages in here you will get a wrong result.
So getting back to the actuals is very easy.
I'm just going to go back to our Tablo worksheet here I'm going to duplicate the tab duplicate the sheet
and I'll call it gender actuals or you can call absolute's And here we just need to replace the table
calculation so I'll just take number of records I get into here and then drag it in to here as well
.
So there are ups are absolute values and now we can put them into our tool.
The only thing is that we'll also need the absolute total.
So for each of these columns a quick way of doing that is we go to Edit or right click access go add
a reference line and then we'll just sum.
And then we want the sum.
Right.
And we wanted her per cell.
So we wanted just the sum to appear at the top so that we have it for our reference purposes and we
wanted per every cell.
And here we don't want the computation we want the value that's just a quick way of bringing up the
summer without changing a chart.
And now I'm going to bring back the online tool.
So all I have to put here is I'm going to get rid of these values so sample one it's one and we're going
to look at this.
You can choose any one of these as success stayed or exited doesn't really matter.
I'm going to choose exited as I had success in floating quotation marks.
And so I'm going to type in here 1 1 3 9.
The total number of trials or not the total number of observations in this category is four thousand
five hundred forty three four thousand of 143.
And here it's eight hundred ninety eight and the total number of the patients 5 4 5 7.
OK.
So what can we see here.
There is a verdict some pull one is more successful meaning that this summer a female that female customers
have a higher exit rate and it is statistically significant.
Here you can see this P-value is less than zero point 0 1.
What's that we don't talk about p values right now.
And what you will find is that basically if P-value is a P there is less than zero point zero zero point
zero five.
So listen five percent then it's a statistically significant result.
So in our case you can see that it is more likely it is going to be the same in the overall population
of the bank.
Can confidently say that female customers are more likely to exit.
That's how you use a chi squared test using this tool or any other tool basically just full of instructions
that it gives you here.
Let's look at another one.
So we've validated this one and sometimes when say you validate something I like to change the color
of the tab.
Right click the tab and maybe change it to green so that in the future you know that this is a validated
result.
You've checked the chi squared test and you're 100 percent sure that you can report this observation
.
Well basically this observation and these numbers were used to check the chi square test.
Now let's look at this look at it from one that has credit card.
Same thing here right.
So we want to duplicate or even faster if you just duplicate this sheet.
Right.
And then you take the color off because we haven't validated yet and you could rename it has credit
card actuals.
And then here you just need to change gender replace it refresh credit card and then you go so once
again Tablo drag and drop.
Super awesome.
Get rid of the label here so that you can see the total total values and then go back to.
OK.
So here we've got a different different values that's put them in.
Right.
Simple one successes 613 trials 2345 success has 144 trials 7 are 5 5.
All right.
So verdict no significant difference P is very high.
Greater than 5 percent no significant difference.
And as you can see from here it's hard to tell but we already knew that we already said that there's
no significant difference just by looking at this chart over here.
And that speaks of how great this template is.
You don't you can't tell of statistical significance but just by looking at this you can say probably
there's no difference 21 percent 20 percent doesn't really you know doesn't really sound like a significant
difference.
So and this tool has validated that for us.
So we can now confidently report this finding.
So I'm going to change the color of the Stapp to green here and there we go.
So that's how you use a chi square test.
In the case when you have two categories so basically what we're doing here is an AB test if you noticed
we're just doing an AB test.
We're just validating it through a chi squared test.
What we're going to do in the next two trials I'll show you quickly how to approach the situation when
you have more than two categories so when you might have three categories like we have in country or
you might have many categories like you have.
We have an age.
And for now as a suggestion you could practice with a different variable.
For instance we've done gender we've done has credit card.
How bad is active member so you could practice this exercise with is active member and see if you can
confirm that there is a statistical significance between these two.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing