All right.
So today we're finally going to start building our stored procedure to create the working table.
And the way we're going to go about it is we will break it up into a few tutorials to make them shorter
and we will build it bit by bit.
So today we're going to create the table.
So let's get rid of this bit in the middle here we still going to use proc that we've already prepared
.
And now I'll show you a trick we're going to open up our customer list table which we're going to be
creating a work table for.
So as you remember the goal right now is to take this table which is all text fields which is not prepared
for the real world this is a raw table and create a working table that we can later use in our analysis
use to create other tables and so on.
So basically give this table a makeover and we're going to start by copying all the columns here and
we'll just click copy here.
And for now we'll just copy them into here.
We'll just leave them there and we will work with them in a bit.
So the code that we're going to type in is we're going to type in create table and obviously the name
of our table will be exactly this as the name of all Proc..
But without the build part.
So that's a convenient shortcut which is going to copy that and paste it into the square brackets.
So that's the table we want to create.
Right but that's not enough information for a scale we have to specify the columns that we want to put
in the table and there types.
So off to create table put a normal bracket and then after these Colma columns put another normal bracket
over here closing on bracket.
So let's tabulate this to make it look pretty.
And before we go going to specify a row number column and I'll explain what it is in a second.
So put a comma before customer ID and I'll just tabulate it nicely like that and so do you see what
I did there.
I used the end of the span of the script space so the end of the file as as kind of a bumper I bomb
to all of them by pressing shift tab.
I bumped them all to line them up.
And I press tab once.
And now they're all lined up with phone number.
So there's another handy trick for you.
And now we're going to specify the taps as you can see they're all like red and I can run this right
now if I try running this it says datatype must be included.
That's correct you creating a table you know the code names but you're not telling a skill Management
Studio What exactly is going to be in those columns what's going to be stored in those calls.
So let's go ahead and do that.
And the way we do it is we look at the table that we are replicating or we creating a working table
for this table.
So let's take that table and let's select it so I'm here after that and keyword.
I'm going to put in some comments and here we're going to put up a comment saying selects star from
and this table that we are creating.
So if I run it I'll have it at the bottom here I'll know what I'm working with.
So to start off with row number is not this phone number it's separate.
It's we're not just copying this number we creating an identity field separate for this table.
I recommend creating identity fields for every single table that you have because that allows them to
be stored better and they save space and they're more efficient.
So never use this row number as a reference point because it might not match.
Don't think of it that way it's just a phone number just the field just an identity field.
That's how most of my tables start with.
And now we're going to move onto the actual columns that we're copying so customer id on.
So here let's start with city because it's easier.
So City is a textfield right.
So we need to give it a bar chart type.
And how many characters.
Well it can be quite a quite a long field.
So here there are up to a thousand we know that because that's how we uploaded them.
They look shorter or they can be maybe 100 symbols here but we will be on the safe side and we'll give
it a thousand because that's the maximum that it can be in our roundtable that's the where we uploaded
it.
So we're definitely not going to risk anything by getting 1000 zip code.
We will skip that one for now as well so gender is easy because obviously gender is male or female or
an amp or an F and here will give gender also bar Chaar and we only give one character why.
Well because here we can see there's only one character.
And also it's like a safety thing.
So if this Vascellaro one character if anything here is more than one character.
So for instance somebody typed in a or a male or female then that is not the right format for this field
.
And there will be a truncation era because this field now is only expecting one character so when we're
going to be copying this table into the new table there should be only one character if there's any
more characters and one there'll be a truncation which will tell us that there's something wrong with
the dot and we'll go in investigate So it's it's like a precaution method for us.
All right so that's good.
Next we're going to deal with age so age often is an integer and that's good.
But in this case the data is stored as a float so you can see that there's a decimal point.
There are some integers here but we don't want to lose this information.
We don't lose any information when we doing this process so we want to make sure that we are converting
this age which is right now stored as a string or a bar char.
We need to convert it into a number and four number we're going to use a float.
So a number with a floating decimal points or just basically a decimal point so here you can type and
float.
Now going back to zipcode and customer ID.
So zipcode.
The temptation here is to.
It's a number it looks like a number right.
So the temptation here is to use a integer for zipcode.
But the thing is it is it is technically a number but you will never use zip code is the number you
will never add add zip codes you will never order zip codes by ascending or descending order.
You will never multiply zip codes you will never ever use zip code is the number for use zip code is
actually is just a variable that allows you to it's a categorical variable is it allows you to understand
you know what where this person lives and things like that.
So you'll use it in Joines and you'll use it in groupings but you will never compare zip codes to each
other so you shouldn't use it.
Put it as an integer.
It's actually a string you should keep it as a varchar So here we're going to type in Varsha.
And these are the decisions you have to make here it's having two symbols five symbols.
These are the decisions that you have to make.
You have to understand what type of data type to give each of these variables.
And if it's a or how long it should be and customer id So here we've got an interesting thing.
Customer I.D. It's once again it's like zip code.
It looks like a number it is technically a number but you don't want to store as a number you want to
store it as text because you're not going to compare customer IDs to each other.
It's an I.D. So you even think of it this way if something could have had technical or theoretically
could have had a letter inside so would it.
Would anything be different if all the customers IDs started with a letter the letter T for instance
then.
No they wouldn't.
Nothing would be different for you.
It's still an I.D. right.
And some maybe some other customer customizes could solve for t some because of an F.
Representing different things.
Same thing.
Nothing would have changed for you.
You still be able to work with them.
Well in that case with the letter T They're not numbers they're actually strings and you can't turn
them into numbers so same thing here.
We are not going to convert them to numbers because there's no need for that.
And actually we can cause confusion by doing that.
We're going to keep them as a bar chart.
And here you look at the lenth you can see that the loan has variable so maybe give it like 100 symbols
just in case.
If you know for sure that your customer I.D. can not be more than nine symbols out then then give it
nine symbols.
But in this case it doesn't look like we can tell that from this short snippet of the data set.
So that's how we create our table so that's actually how we write up the code to create our table.
And now if we go ahead and run it.
So first of all.
First thing I recommend doing is save your stored procedure so just click 5 or execute.
Now the stored procedures saved.
And now we can run this body and create the table so if we highlight and click execute and if you're
a short refresh tables you will see that there's a working table here.
Office supplies customer list.
And so let's open up select top thousand rows and of course it's empty because we've just created an
empty table in the next few tutorials.
We will learn how to populated our data