The various tutorial we added a reference a chart.
And today we're going to start replicating this chart and analyzing other categories.
So it's very easy to replicate this AB test.
All you have to do is right click your tablet here and click duplicate sheet and I'll rename it right
away because we'll be analyzing country.
And this framework that I have shown you here it actually is very simple to alter for different calcifications
.
And the beauty of it is that over here we only have gender one time and a whole tab as you can see it's
not in the marks it's not in the rows only in the columns.
So whenever we want to change a category all you have to do is drag a new category on top of gender
and replace it.
So in this case we're talking about geography track geography replace gender and let's make some room
and bam it's all done.
We've got our reference line we've got our labels we've got our percentages.
Everything has been done for you.
So you see how quickly it is and this is why I am a big fan of data mining through Tablo.
You can talk to your daughter and it just happens like lightning fast.
And so here right away you can see what's going on.
OK so Germany people in Germany are exiting the bank at a rapid rate.
Thirty two percent of customers in Germany left over the period of the observation.
And France and Spain are below average.
Once again it makes sense that these jobs will average because they're equal at approximately equal
and or this other one is above average so they have to be below.
So right away from here we've got some inside's we can you know run to the executives or to your manager
and say hey something's going on in Germany.
Germany maybe there's a competitor there.
Maybe the products are not suitable for the market.
Maybe there's some sort of new legislation something is going on and you can already start digging into
this deeper.
That's how we do the this is not an AB test anymore because there's three categories so this would be
an A B C test or you can just call it like a classification test or categorization test or something
like that.
But you kind of get the picture that we can see that there is an anomaly something is going on in Germany
and that is exactly what we're looking for through this process.
We're interrogating the data to look for anomalies and once we find them we can investigate them further
and take them to the next level.
So now what we want to do is do another one.
It's so quick and easy why don't we do a couple more.
So let's Right-Click country and duplicate sheet and let's look at another variable so I'm not going
to name it for now.
Let's select a variable here we've got some some measures so actual numeric variables.
And here we also have some categorical variables that happen to be in measures like has credit card
that is a 1 and 0 flag.
Right.
So we need to change it into dimension we don't need it as a number.
So let's drag it has credit card in two dimensions and let's now drag has credit card on top of geography
.
Once you've done that what do we see here that in fact there isn't a much of a difference between has
credit card yes or no.
And once again here you can see the aliases are not fixed up so let's do that.
Let's go to his credit card and create some aliases.
So here we can say has credit card so 0 would be a no.
And this would be a yes and OK.
So here we can see that 20 of the people that have a credit card 20 percent left the company and the
people don't have a credit card.
Twenty one percent left the company.
And why say that there's no big difference.
Well because the difference is only one percent.
And more importantly remember that this is not a full fledged statistical AB test.
And if you do run the statistical Abts then little differences like that when there's only a 1 percent
difference.
They require a very large sample size to be statistically significant.
And in our case it's only 8000 people.
So you could check and take this further.
But my point here is that this is not your best investment of time.
You would much rather look at country or gender because their differences are massive and there you
can actually have a impact and maybe make some business rules of business decisions around what you're
going to do to fix the problem.
And this case there's not much to fix there is you know only a 1 percent difference.
So now we're going to rename the Stabb to has credit card and let's do one more so let's look at our
verbals we've got is active member here so people who have been active in the past couple of months
have the bank can determine that in different ways.
So it can be whether a person has logged in in the past three months on to the online banking whether
they've made a transaction in the past month or so and the period can be different.
So there's a number of ways this can be determined but since we have this call them let's work with
it.
We're going to take this column and I'm going to convert to dimensional sure.
Another way you can do it here and sort of Dragon Age you can just right click and say convert to dimension
.
Now we have this has created is active member here.
Let's duplicate Oh she just read it like we did before.
Right away we can rename it because we know what we're investigating is active member.
And once again our beautiful framework allows us to just take his active member and replace it here
in columns.
And what do we see here.
So once again let's do that.
Alias's right away so that we can analyze properly is active member 0 usually means No.
1 means yes click OK.
So what do we see people who are not active members of them 27 percent left the company in the period
of observation and 14 percent or only 14 percent of active members left the company.
So this is above average is below average.
And what does that tell us.
Well it kind of backs our intuition right here that people who are active who are actively using your
bag they are less likely to leave their you know they're invested into a bank they maybe like your products
they keep plugging in they keep checking the balance.
Why would they want to leave.
Of course some of them will leave because you know competitors and maybe they have better offer somewhere
else find better offer somewhere else.
Maybe they're consolidating their accounts but people who are not active are at higher risk of leaving
.
That makes sense if somebody hasn't logged into your bank online banking for three months.
He's a major suspect to leave your bank maybe Israeli banking with somebody else or somebody who hasn't
usually does a transaction sometimes a transaction per month or a couple transaction has stopped doing
that.
Then once again there is a higher chance that this person is going to leave.
So there we go.
We've created so far for tests and took us just a couple of minutes so we've got gender.
We can see that female customers are higher Liska a risk of leaving.
Germany is at a higher risk of leaving people who have credit cards.
That doesn't really affect.
It's not a important variable in this situation and is active member people who are not active are more
likely to leave.
So what I wanted to suggest for us moving forward is we've got one more categorical variable here and
that one is number of products so how many products does the person have with the bank.
Does he only have a savings account does he have a savings and a credit card.
Does he have a loan and so on.
So I wanted to suggest that you practice with that variable and do it as homework before our next tutorial
so just create another AB test.
But this time for a number of products and see if you can find any anomalies see if you're if what you
see actually backs your intuition and you create an alias and just have a look and investigate that
verbal and then you'll get back to it in the next to Tauriel and I will show you how I created the same
test although his it's very simple very straightforward just like the ones we did here.
I'm sure you'll go fine.
And I look forward to seeing in the next tutorial.
Until then happy analyzing