All right exciting to Tauriel ahead.
Today we're going to build our very first multiple linear regression and we're going to be using the
backward elimination method.
I hope you're pumped about this.
Let's get straight into it.
Open up Grettel and let's connect our data file open data mine is in on my desktop modeling section
multiple integration.
So it's a CSP file.
There it is.
That's fine.
We don't need to do that.
And the first thing you can see here is that Grettel has identified that we have a categorical variable
it says variable for which Skuld's state is a string so it is a warning.
So we're going to have to deal with this.
And there's two categories New York and California.
So very very convenient.
Now we know that there is two categories.
So let's go ahead and deal with these dummy variables right away.
As we discussed previously because we have a categorical variable we can't just included in our multiple
linear regression formula equation because that way it's it's a it's not a number so we need to replace
it with some dummy variables as we discussed before.
And that's exactly what we're going to do here.
It's very simple to do in griddle.
All you have to do is select a variable.
Go to add and down here it actually has an option dummys for discrete variable.
Click that and here make sure you encoding the right variable.
And here you have three options and code all values.
Or you can skip the lowest value or the highest value.
And Grettel smart like that.
It knows that you won't be able to use all of your dummy variables in your models anyway.
You're going to have to omit one of your dummy variables and we discussed that also in this cause just
previously when we're talking about the dummy variable trap because you can't if you include all of
them then your model won't work.
So it's right away it's offering you to skip one of them but as we agreed we're going to encode all
.
And then we'll select the ones that the one we want to use ourselves because that gives us a bit more
flexibility.
So we'll just click OK here.
And if you expand state now you will see that there's two dummy variables the state underscore one in
DC underscore.
And one is for New York and once for California.
We don't want to remember the names and which one is for what.
So we'll just quickly modify the names.
Right click your verbal click Edit attributes and here change take New York and put it in the name of
the variable.
So it's called variable New York or you can have spaces so get rid of the space.
Click this check mark here and then proceed to the next variable by clicking the down arrow to California
.
And same thing.
OK so now we have two dummy variables.
New York and California.
And they're really great.
We're ready to proceed with our modeling part.
So I've put a picture here of our previous slide by the way I didn't mention this but I am intending
on attaching the slides as a downloadable file to the previous Lakesha So go ahead and download that
in the course materials and you can you know keep this file for yourself and then refer to it whenever
whenever you need to.
So this is our building a model backward elimination method.
Our first step is to select a significant level for variables to stay in the model.
In our example we're going to use 0.05.
So I'm going to say it out loud.
I am selecting the significance level to be 5 percent or 0.05.
Good.
Step 1 done next fit the full model of all possible predictors.
Let's go ahead and do that.
So model ordinary least squares and here we're going to take profit and we're going to move it into
our dependent variable and because we're going to be doing this process quite a few times is going to
be an iterative approach.
We're going to click this box here set as default so every time we come back to his menu.
Profit is already the dependent variable.
And now let's go ahead and move our independent variables into the regressors box.
We'll start off one by one here.
R&D spend so spend on research and development.
Yes that's one of them.
Administration expenses yes.
Marketing spend.
Yes State No.
Because we've agreed that we will replace state with dummy variables.
Profit is our dependent variable and now we have two dummy variables.
We can only include one in order to avoid the dummy variable trap and we're going to include the New
York will which include the New York one you feel it you can feel free to include whichever one you
like.
So there we go.
Our regressors are ready and all we have to do is cook.
Okay.
Vola congratulations this is your first multiple linear regression model and as you can see here you
have the four variables present plus the constant you are modeling independent dependent variable profit
.
And let's have a look at this.
And now we know how to read these Let's extract some information from him.
So these are coefficients and we'll talk about interpretive coefficients in the next tutorial so we'll
leave that for now.
We're not going to focus on the center arrow to.
What we're interested in is in the p value right.
So we've got the p values for all of all four variables.
And here you can see some stars meaning that it's a good P-value it's a significant variable because
it is so small it is seven times ten to the power of minus when you show tiny values.
These values are quite large actually so 0.60 5 0.12 0.60 2.
So that's why they don't have stars you get.
I think the way it works is you get three stars if you're less than zero point zero or one two stars
if you're less than zero point zero five and one star If you're less than point 0 1 so 10 percent.
So that's how this rating system goes.
Anyway let's go back to our backwood elimination step by step method.
So we've run the former model with all possible predictors.
How about we do the next step now step three.
Consider the predicter with the highest P-value.
Right.
So let's go ahead and look at him predict some of the highest P-value is this guy administration.
He's got the highs.
Good we've picked him out next.
If the P-value is greater than the significance level go to Step Four Let's check that P-value is greater
than 0.05.
Definitely greater.
So we're going to step 4 and Step 4 remove this predicter and fit the model before this variable and
then move back to Step 3.
OK that's interesting.
Let's go ahead and do that.
So basically what that's telling us is running you model blue for this variable.
We're going to do exactly that.
We won't touch this window we'll leave it open and we'll go back to Grettel.
And here we're going to go model ordinary least squares.
And now we're going to take administration out of our model so we'll just remove it like that and we'll
click OK.
So now if we go back here and put it side by side you will see what happened now we have one variable
less so here administration is present here administration is no longer present.
And also you can see that some things have changed.
So for instance the constant has changed the coefficients have changed the p values have changed basically
everything has changed and even a star has appeared for marketing spend so before it was so large says
0.12 it was greater than 10 percent now it's less than 10 percent so it's got a star so it became more
significant without the administration Mirable present.
And that happened.
That's normal.
That's there's lots of factors that influence that and excluding or including variables will always
affect your existing variables.
And that's one of the reasons why you can't just exclude it exclude administration and assume that everything
else stays the same.
That's exactly why we have to rerun the model.
And so we are ready to proceed to the next step.
But before we do I wanted to show you one quick thing.
Good.
Good exercise to do and this is not part of our step by step method and this is also not the awesome
tip or hint that we're going to look at to make the role model robust.
This is just something for us something for us to understand what happened here.
A way to understand is always a good way to understand is always to visualize things so let's go ahead
and visualize this variable or visualize the proffered against this variable.
If we hold all other variables constant It's very simple to do just go to graphs Graf's fitted actual
plot and here select against administration.
And what that will do is it will plot profit against the administration bearable assuming that all other
variables are held constant.
And so the blue values are fitted the red vows the actual So ignore the blue values for now.
What are we looking at.
Is that is there a any kind of relationship any kind of obvious relationship that we can see between
a profit and an inspiration.
So is like like we used to see like a line that we can go that we can draw that goes through the various
variables all the values and it's quite close to me personally.
Looks like there is no relationship.
And like it's all scattered all over the place and what that means is that even if you change administrations
spend so much money you're investing into your administration or how much that expense is if you increase
or decrease it you can't really effect profit.
So by changing this independent variable the dependent variable is not affected and that is exactly
why we chose to exclude administration from our model because it is not a predictor of profit.
You take two companies that are identical but they spend different amounts on the industry and you can
really tell which one will have a higher profit or you can even according to a model make a prediction
.
So we're going to close this window now that should kind of explain a little bit better more intuitively
what this means that we're excluding a variable from our modeling.
Now we're going to move on to this part we're going to proceed with the next step over backward elimination
process.
So I'm going to bring up the rules again and here we can see that we've just fit the model for the new
variable and now we're going to do this part again.
So consider the predicter of highest P-value check if P-value is greater than your significant level
.
And if it is go to Step 4 Let's go ahead and check that.
So we'll find the variable the highest P-value which is this one New York so our dummy variable has
the highest P value 0.5 sound very high p value definitely greater than our significant level which
is 0.05.
And therefore we need to exclude this variable from our model as well.
Let's go ahead and do that model ordinarily squares take New York and take it out.
Click OK and let's move this one over here.
All right.
So what have we got so far.
We've got two variables once again coefficients changed the constant changed P values changed as you
can see this P-value got even smaller.
It's now 0.06 it can it can really go both ways.
You never know until you actually run the model.
But now we've got a new picture.
We've got two variables and we're in for next step.
Once again you can quickly check the graph if you like go to fit actual plot.
And here we want to check against New York.
So look at the Reds again.
Basically because it is a categorical variable.
This is a dummy variable now.
So 0 1 Remember we're talking about the on off switch.
So are you in New York.
Yes.
Are you not in New York.
Where else can you be.
But California are in California.
So but basically what is this is saying is being on not being in New York is not really doesn't really
make a difference the way if if there was a difference you'd see like a lot of red here and a lot of
red here meaning that if you're in New York your profit is much higher than if you're not in your.
But here it's kind of evenly distributed across like across the whole line here and across the whole
line here so no wonder we were so suggested to exclude that variable from our regression.
It doesn't doesn't really predict anything it's not that much of a predictor.
So that's why we took it out.
All right.
So now we're doing the next step again.
We don't need to go back to rules because by now we should remember them.
Look for the highest P-value.
This one.
And check if it's greater or less than our significance level.
So 0.06 is quite close to zero are five but it's still greater than 0 0 0.05.
So what does that mean.
We need to exclude this verb.
Let's go ahead and do that.
This is our Grettel software and we're going to go orderly squares once again.
Which one is it.
Marketing spend.
So we're going to take it out.
It'll click OK and now we'll move it over here.
OK let's have a look at what we have now.
So now we have only one variable left it's very significant.
Lots of stars is definitely less than zero point zero five.
So what does our method tell us.
Let's go back to our method here.
Our method would say that we've only got we get to this part.
This is not true.
As you remember that means we don't go to Step Four we go to Finne.
Your model is.
Good.
So theoretically according to this approach this is our model Don it only actually has one variable
.
We went from four variables down to one.
And it's very very significant.
So what I wanted to show you here is let's do the same thing we did with the previous ones and let's
look at the chart and see what what actually went on here is is marking spend.
Really that's not much of a predictor.
Let's go to Graf's fitted versus actual.
And we'll go against marketing spend and what you can see here is even though they're kind of scatted
right.
The observations will look at the red ones and there are some outliers but in reality.
Personally I think I could draw a line for this I could go like like that.
Yeah it does look like there is a good level of corruption here and that is what we saw here that marketing
spend.
It's the one star basically that it's not a huge P-value like we had with administration of New York
it's quite a small p value but still it's not sufficient enough for our significant level.
And this is the problem with these step wise regression building methods that they're very arbitrary
.
We once we said our significant level is 0.05 we stick to that and we just follow this cold blooded
rule that if it's greater than 0.05 we have excluded from our model and there's nothing you can do about
it.
So that's that's the rule and that's how it works.
But in reality when you look at something like this you think maybe there is a chance that just maybe
I should have kept it in maybe my model work would have worked better with it.
And how do you tell.
And this is where I'll show you the handy trick that will help you make the models more robust.
And we'll talk about it in the next tutorial