Last and we had a very long tutorial on corrupted CSU files and text qualifiers and I hope that by now
you are a pro with text qualifiers and you know exactly what they're for and how they work and how CACP
files operate as well.
So today what we're going to do is we're going to start our upload Hulver before we do that.
I wanted to show you something in this preview over here.
So as you remember we excluded row 1 from our analysis because it was totally corrupted and fro '96
we decided to fix it.
And we added that quotation mark so that the feedback column is in one cell rather than skewing this
whole row.
But if you scroll a bit to the Right now what you will notice is that the date the birth date is not
in the right format it's not in the format that we wanted to put it in.
And the reason for that is because the rows were actually skewed to the right in excel when we originally
put the file in Excel the rows automatically go skewed to the right.
So this birthday was actually in the tropical zodiac or colon.
And then when we performed our daughter wrangling before the load in Excel and we corrected the birth
the column as you remember we didn't affect this specific cell because it wasn't in this column at the
time.
So all the other cells got affected.
And then this cell only came back into this column so this data only came back into this column after
we corrected the CACP file just in the previous tutorial.
So that is some of those discrepancies that you have to keep in mind that the adjustments that you make
to the file are affected by the discrete anomalies that are present in the file.
So in this case this data was not in the right.
Call them when we were making the changes.
On the other hand the dollar sign is OK because it is to the left of the column that had an error.
So it is to the left of this column and it wasn't affected by that by this anomaly so it wasn't skewed
and it got fixed up OK in Excel.
The date wasn't.
So if you're fixing up columns to the right of the problem area then you might have you might experience
issues in this case what you would need to do is you need to go back and correct this column as well
.
That's option number one.
Number two is you can upload the file like this and then deal with this error.
This is an error in as well.
Or option number three.
You can go into your file and exclude this row and that's exactly what we're going to do.
Because I find it just safer if you find any kind of anomaly.
You can try to correct it like we did in the Preuss tutorial and you know I hope that's a good illustration
of how you would go about correcting issues manually.
On the other hand I find it's a bit safer to exclude anomalies and then deal with all of them separately
.
So that's what we're going to do now.
We're going to go to our folder fake names.
That file is in the uploaded data that's the one we're dealing with now what we're not going to touch
it right now.
We're going to always go to the prepared folder and here we've got osseous Veep.
So as you recall we want to excluded from this file from this file.
And we will find the column and row its row number 96 the low record number 96.
So here it is.
Thank you for a great experience.
So all we can do is we're going to delete it make sure that you didn't delete anything else.
That's great.
And we're just going to save it now we're going to take this file first.
We're going to close our manager here.
Now we're going to take the file and we're going to replace the one that's over here.
And also we need to remember that we need to make a copy of that role so we're going to take the original
data file copy it put it in the prepared data for now or actually which is good to put in the analysis
right away data errors.
So we're going to go to manually exclude results.
Fake name then we're going to just say original row.
Ninety six.
So now we just want to go here and delete everything except for Rule Number 96
that will allow us to come back and deal with all of these error rows when the time comes.
So we'll save that.
Now we have to delete rows in the correct result which is going to get rid of this whole folder.
All right.
Now let's proceed with our upload.
We're going to go back to the source.
We're going to create a new connection manager find a file see us we file.
There it is.
So it's going to be quotation marks columns.
Let's have a look here.
96 is not here.
And so is 81.
That because we took them out.
Now we're going to go to advanced.
We're going to select everything and say which is a thousand press Enter preview.
Check again click OK columns are output could only be destination here.
What I wanted to say is that for every single project Ideally you will have a separate database or at
least a separate schema within your database.
That way you can separate the files or the tables that relate to that project from the tables that relate
to other projects.
In our case we're going to use the same database just because this is training.
So as I recall we've already used year straining for tables not related to this project in the previous
sections of discourse.
However today we're still going to use this training just because we're practicing and we don't really
need a separate database for every single project we're doing.
OK so India-Australia we're going to create a new table we're going to give our table name as you recall
the name is going to have a role and there will be something familiar.
Fake names.
And then the date.
And now we're going to add an identity row just because we do that every single time.
All right so that is our table.
Those are all our columns including the last column over here which we will deal with in Eski already
and click OK mappings.
There is our mappings heire output.
Good.
So everything is ready just need to fix this up because of the code page and off we go to the races
.
So there they go as uploading and we get an error.
What happened here.
Let's have a look.
This is how it looks like when you get an error in your society process.
So a certain number of rows has been uploaded.
This number of rows has very little to do with where the error occurred.
You can't really tell the error didn't occur on a row thirty thousand two hundred seventy eight which
you can find out is more information on the error and you need to go down here where it says package
executed execution complete with error.
So basically you want to click this button or as we discussed this button at the top stop debugging
and that will stop this process.
And now to find out more about where you go to execution results over here and here you will have information
on what happened during the upload.
So this is exactly what is going on.
We started the upload over here and some information some information.
And then finally here these red crosses over here it tells you about the error right away.
Here you can see daughter conversion failed the daughter conversion for calm feedback returned status
value for and status text text was truncated or one or more characters had no match in the target code
page.
So that's our era.
And then there's some more information so then it's like regraded here by the way if it doesn't fit
in the in this line you just have to take make a copy so you copy that era and let's say we take notepad
plus plus now and we just copy the error in here and we want to view Wardrop.
And here you can read the whole area.
So basically there was a truncation of the text in the feedback column and we will need to go have a
look at that.
If you keep reading here you can see it actually tells you the row.
Thirty one thousand three hundred and fifty one.
So let's go ahead and check that row out.
So we're going to go back to notepad plus plus close this.
And now we will go to our daughter errors Nelson's fake names so prepare data this one that we're working
with.
We're going to open it up and see it's in Notepad plus plus now we go into view.
Word wrap unwrap it.
You just press control on your keyboard and say where you want to go through 1351 OK.
And there you go that's your old 1351.
And if you scroll to the right what can we see here.
We have we see the column feedback and you can see that it is quite long.
So this person left a lot of feedback like a lot a lot of feedback really had something to say.
So this is one of those anomalies people like in your daughter said people don't usually write more
than a thousand characters of feedback but this person really had a massive complaint to make and they
made it.
So obviously we want to preserve this information.
How can we get it into the database.
Very simple we just need to specify more than 1000 characters for this specific field for the whole
field of feedback.
So that's what we're going to do.
We're not going to change anything in fake names and therefore we don't need to change the file in the
uploaded data folder.
All we need to do is correct our connection manager and our database.
So we're going to go to the connection manager wrote two columns advanced and here we'll leave everything
at a thousand with output.
The one we want to correct is feedback.
There is feedback.
So we're going to change it to 5000.
I like to specify 5000 that is usually enough in these cases the maximum you can specify here is 8000
because that is the maximum length of a VAR char variable in your database.
So you don't want to go over 8000 If you have a field that's over 8000.
You will have to deal with that separately you might need to exclude that record as an anomaly or you
might need to break that up and try to break it up into two pieces of text.
So we're just going to say five thousand go to preview look at it here just in case.
OK.
Then you see this exclamation mark up here.
That's because we corrected the flat file connection.
We haven't corrected the flat file source so DoubleClick that it will say do you want to replace the
metadata of the output columns with the method out of certain columns.
Yes exactly you want to do that and it's already done it for us so we don't need to do anything in here
.
It's correct to everything click OK.
Now this needs to go.
We need to delete this connection because here the table that we created is not going to be good enough
for the flat file sources you'll see that in a second.
So what are we going to do is we're going to go to you all and and ask Well we're going to drop the
table that we just populate because we don't need it anymore.
So this is this skill if you can see your table.
So just right click tables and click refresh.
Should be there so if you take your table and select top thousand rows you will see here that some rows
have been uploaded.
Of course this is the top thousand.
So if we just get rid of that and click the execute button over here you will see.
Now this is the full table.
What there is you'll see that a certain number of rows have been applied but not everything obviously
.
So we want to get rid of this table we don't need any more.
You can right click here and click delete or I'll show you the proper way of doing it.
So get rid of everything from from from select to from.
So just leave the table name and click drop type and drop table and then click execute.
What you'll see happen is Tables drop successfully and so if you click refresh tables no longer there
.
Great.
So we got rid of that is good to clean up after yourself.
And now we're going to go into Assayas and we're going to create a new table all the D-B destination
.
We're going to create new.
Same thing.
And now we're going to add a roll number.
All right so that's how table why the previous still wasn't good enough.
Well have a look here in feedback.
Now this table is going to be created as a click OK.
This table is going to be created with varchar of 5000 not 1000 so everything else is still thousand
but this one's going to be 5000 why it will because of that blue arrow that connects the to the flat
file source and the destination.
This manager knows that we want to create a table that is 5000 with this column.
The previous table was 1000 with and now it was fixed.
You would have to modify the table itself to to fix it to correct that.
We don't want to waste time on that so why follow.
It is it's already done for us.
We're just going to click OK.
Tables being created will go to mappings error output.
Good.
And we could just launch this and off it goes.
So everything has been uploaded.
Great.
Let's have a look.
Let's obviously stop this process.
Click here.
Don't forget to save your package.
All right.
Now let's go to Eskew all again and here.
We don't want to drop the table so we're just going to close this refresh.
There is our table and we're going to select the top 1000 rows.
All right we're going to actually select everything.
So you can just get rid of that the top thousand and you'll select everything.
And here as you can see they're not uploaded in in order so basically they're uploaded kind of randomly
and that's just you know that's how the skill works.
They don't have to be uploaded in order.
So here we go to the bottom.
We can look around and basically this is our table.
But as we discussed this is not the heredoc format yet it's not ready for us to do our analysis.
Why.
Well because we know that there are still errors in here or we suspect that there are still errors in
this data and we would love to get rid of them somehow.
Obviously we can go through everything manually and like right now it doesn't look like there's anything
and your problems in this column but that's just because we're scrolling so fast and we can see if there's
like one record somewhere here in this column that's anomalous.
You won't be able to visually pick it up.
You just scroll through it quickly.
So in the next tutorial I will show you how to pick up errors in skill and then we'll learn how to deal
with them