The truth isn't always pretty.
And I'd like to solve this sort of a question.
So when I told students of course that I'm going to have this tutorial in the course of one of them
said yes that's exactly what I want.
How do you deal with that well the fact that the truth isn't always pretty when the client wants to
challenge you.
How do you keep from alienating the client when your results aren't giving them what they were hoping
for.
What always do you avoid this minefield.
How do you get back.
How do you go back to your team and say does it go well.
But I have some new ideas for looking like the film.
So this is true.
The truth is not always pretty Darren My neck is like insulting but it's from the bottom up.
So consulting is a top down kind of approach where you come up with strategy and trickle down from executives
to managers to the execution level and the whole business.
Whereas Dolemite or does science is the opposite.
You start from the bottom by dynamiting to looking for her daughter.
Then you go up up up through the levels and you take it all the way to the executives.
So in Dallasites you simply are looking at the facts the hard facts and if something happens if something
is there you can say it's not that like if there was a bottleneck there is a bottleneck if there is
an inefficiency in the part and there's an inefficient in the department.
You can't avoid the truth.
And sometimes the things that you find and present will not resonate with the people that you're presenting
to.
They both like these things and that is normal.
Be prepared for that.
That happens happens a lot and you've got to prepare yourself for that.
But more importantly and this is my answer to this question.
You've got to prepare your audience.
So the people that asked you to do this product are the people you're going to be presenting in the
end of the day where you are starting this project you've got to make it clear that you don't know what
the outcome is going to be you.
You will look for solutions for insights and so on.
But those insights they might not like.
And so the best way to go about it is just tell them at the start that the insights that I find might
not you might not be comfortable with and what and then discuss it with them like what do you think
we should do if this happens like what are your what is your plan of attack and so on what would you
like to do.
Would you like it.
You know what if this happens.
So put it in their head right away that you're mining for facts and those facts might not be pretty
.
And that's it that's that's how you go about it.
And when the time comes you present and you've got to be prepared for it.
And just just remember that's not everything is always going to be pretty what you've got to find your
to find out what happened what's happening.
And you know hopefully you will come up with solutions to the problems that you did.