In the previous tutorial we ran our model on our test data and here's the result.
So we have the wrong number.
We have the predicted probability of the person leaving and we have the exited the actual value did
the person leave or not.
And I just want to clarify one more time that when we run the model we did not use this test data.
We created the model using the main data which is in our churn modeling file then we input this data
where we know it was appended to our churn multi-file But these test records they didn't have the exit
column appended we added that later.
So this prediction is nowhere is in no way associated with this exited actual value.
And so what that means is the model is predicting whether they will or not they will exit and all we
need to do now is actually test check how well it is predicting because this is like the real deal it's
a simulation of the real application of the model in a real environment.
So what we want to do now is run this data through our Kepcher of template.
Now let's go ahead and do that.
So I'm going to bring up the cap curve template there it is maybe expand this whole thing.
Okay.
So where is our data set.
It's in this file.
And first thing we need to do.
Remember we need to order our data set by this last column.
So by way I'm going to maybe this time just do it like this.
So Data Filter and now are sorted by largest to smallest.
So that's the most probable person to leave and the least probabl person to leave is at the bottom.
That's a probability.
And now all we have to do is copy this data copy and go to our Kepcher template.
All right.
And we need to put in here remember'd says ordered.
So we did do that we ordered it.
So I'm going to paste it in here.
OK I'll just try.
Please click delete the ring and paste.
So that's good because it is a total of 1000 records two legs that is 260 26 percent exited.
Now old delete this and all we need to do is take 1.
This Lustral not to just the last one and either drag it like that or you can just double click on the
corner and it will automatically go to the end.
So as you can see it's all popular and just go down to the bottom and check that there's no no issues
along the way.
Yup.
So everything adds up at the end there's a thousand records shown and 60 exited 260 exited 100 percent
everywhere.
Everything's good.
OK.
And actually even the confusion matrix is already populated for us as well.
So you can see how many type 1 Type 2 errors the model has made.
And now all we have to do is as we did previously select this column press control hold control and
select these columns insert line.
Bam done.
So get rid of that.
There is our cap curve.
So that's what it looks like and it looks very similar to the one we had for the real fall when we were
building the model.
But it's a bit different.
So if I do the 50 percent line which is somewhere over here you can see that the model is performing
less than 80 percent at the 50 percent line.
So once again we're not going to calculate the area in the area of the ideal line and calculate the
actual accuracy ratio.
We'll leave that to stats programs.
But just by looking at this
picture we can see that the model is performing well really well but a bit worse than it was on the
train.
So let's go ahead and bring up the train data result over here so we can compare side by side.
There it is.
It was we saved that in our Excel file over here.
So this is what we had before this what we have now.
All right so here they are side by side and you can see two things right away.
First of all the model is performing a bit worse on the test data than you can see that because at the
50 percent mark the models only capturing about seventy eight I would say maybe seventy five percent
of the Turners in this scenario in the testing are at the same time in the training environment.
The model was able to capture 81 percent.
So about a 3 percent drop over there three or six percent drop.
Just moving from train daughter to test.
And don't forget that the train the test that is pretty much just part of the or the test or is part
of the trend or just we separated it before we built the model so these people actually came from the
same time snapshot that when we created this whole lot of it and the second thing that you can see is
that this model is a bit more rugged.
So like you can actually see the bumps in this model.
It's more obvious than they are here.
This one looks a bit smoother.
So the second observation can be explained by the fact that there's less record so there's only a thousand
records here and therefore every like the concentration of breakers here is 10 times less than here
and therefore any kind of deviation or anomalies or randomness in the records it's you can sense it
more because there's just generally less records and therefore that's why the line looks less smooth
.
Here you can still see some ruggedness but it kind of smooths out because there 10 times more records
and even if one or two are deviating from the norm then they're smoothed out by the other eight as opposed
to here where there's 10 times less.
So that's the first thing.
And you will notice that the less data you can put them into the model the more of these jagged lines
you will have.
And the second the first observation the main one that's the deterioration of performance.
Well there is a couple of reasons why that could be.
First of all perhaps maybe our model is over fitted and you will find that to a certain extent models
will it's natural for a model to be better fitted to the daughter that is trained on.
It's it's like in in anything you say even if you're doing martial arts right.
You're better at the gym that you are training at than at a gym where you go.
Or let's say soccer or or American football right.
Your as a whole.
If you're the home team you'll always play a little bit better on your own ground than when you're playing
away and somebody else's field.
So that's OK as long as it's not too much of a drop.
The other reason why this could happen that the drop off here is once again because there's less records
because we only have 1000 records for this test which is which is OK which is fine but maybe there is
some you know maybe all those records some how it happened that they are a bit skewed one way or the
you know they have a certain characteristic that these other records don't have.
And that can affect this.
What you're seeing and that is also there has also to do a lot with how the sample the test sample is
selected from the overall the whole data set that you have for your training and testing.
It is very important to select the correct that we will talk about this further down in the course how
to correctly select a test sample to minimize any potential for this effect when just because you select
a test sample incorrectly the results are not matching up.
So but otherwise this is good.
It's it Matt it validates that our model is performing.
So basically in this case even without knowing anything about this data all model was able to predict
quite quite well.
So imagine this like you can by contacting just 50 percent of your sample of these thousand people by
contacting 500 of them you will get nearly 80 percent of those who are actually at risk at living at
a high risk that you'll actually leave.
So that that is a great result and that's why we consider models between 70 to 80 percent good models
.
And so our model has possible Ed. This is how you use test data to validate.
One other thing I wanted to mention is that this is a very powerful technique that we use just here
.
We plotted the cap curve.
The cumulative accuracy profile for both models and we compared it so just visually comparing of course
we can calculate the area.
And so on be more mathematical it but just visually comparing We can tell right away which CNR is better
.
So the models performing better here.
But you can also use the same exact technique to comparing models to a different model.
So if you had two options or the model so you create one more and then you create the second model and
you didn't know which one was better.
Then you could put them side by side like this.
Use this same type template the cap curve template create the cap curves and for two separate models
but run them on the same data set.
So here we are using different data.
We're using trained out and test data.
But if you run them both on on the test data set for instance this model on the test not a set and then
a different model in the test data set and you compare it you can just say in the same way compare visually
the graphs.
And that way you can assess which model is is better and so is going to be like a random metric or an
unreliable metric like accuracy rate from the confusion matrix.
Here you can actually it's a more reliable metric because as you can see it's taking account all the
records it's you can visually see how it's going so if there's any problem with the model you will find
that you see it right away.
And the third scenario when you can use this technique as well is when you're comparing a model to itself
over time.
So this is how you modeled performing Now this is before and test data and then you know six months
later or 12 months later you run this same test.
But for a new data set in the future like for the people that are going to be banking with you in six
months and for their behavior and for that geo political environment you run the same model on those
people and you see how it changed you look at the curve and this is this is a very important to me.
We'll talk about this more as well when we're talking about deterioration over time.
Just wanted to run ahead a bit so that you're prepared and you're kind of thinking about this already
now.
Before we get to that tutorial you'll see that over time maybe your model will be getting worse and
like this curve this red car will be getting to the blue one every time you check your morals every
six months.
And that will speak more of the situation but more on that later.
This is all for today I hope you found today's information useful and definitely use this technique
in your career.
It can help you create a much better models