All right, guys, in this video, I just want to show you the next project we'll be building, which
is a portfolio project that uses SAS.
Now, the inspiration for the look of this site comes from a template that I found on Mobi Ryzhkov.
So I just wanted to show you guys this real quick, and it's just a one page, it's just a single page.
Our template is going to be multiple pages.
I didn't even look at the HTML or the CSS for this.
And then as far as this typing effect here, the typing effect we're using comes from my JavaScript
tutorial on YouTube.
So if you're interested in the actual JavaScript, you can just search for JavaScript typing effect.
And the first result here will be my tutorial that shows you exactly what's going on as far as this
course.
We're just going to kind of include the file.
So we have a landing page here with a background image.
This logo up here pertains to the the developer's name, John Doe.
Now, I did include the PSD file.
If you want to change the initials, if you want to use your own logo, if you want to use text here,
if you don't want to use anything here, whatever you want to do is fine if you're going to use this
as your own portfolio or whatever.
And then we have the menu over here with the different pages, which I'll show you in a second.
We have a button to go to the work page, and then down here we have what John specializes in some font
awesome icons.
And then here we have some more icons with clients, awards, hours worked, projects completed, creative
process.
So down here we're going to add some visual effects using transitions footers, pretty simple.
Just have some social media icons with a hover effect.
And then the about page, you can see we're still using that same background image, but we're pushing
it up into the nav bar and then we have the about section.
We're actually going to be using grid template areas here.
Then we have some progress bars, so we'll be creating these from scratch.
I know that Progress bars are included with frameworks like Bootstrap and stuff like that, but we'll
be creating these with just HTML and CSS.
We have some logos here, some testimonials, and then on the work page we have some images with some
overlay effects.
So we'll be using some CSS transitions here as well I think looks pretty nice.
All these images will be included in the project files as well.
So let's take a look at the contact page, which is very simple.
We just have a form here.
We have this section with the email, phone and address, big text that says, let's start your next
project and the footer.
All right.
So now let's take a look at the responsiveness of this.
So I'm going to open up my chrome tools and let's hit the device icon here.
So this is what it would look like on an iPad, which is very similar to what it looks like on desktop.
Basically, everything is is pretty much the same.
So let's look at let's say iPhone X, so on on smaller devices, smartphones, we're just going to kind
of narrow the header down to just the logo and the menu centered and then everything else is just nicely
stacked on top of each other.
For the about page, you can see everything is nicely stacked.
Testimonials, Progress, bars, the work page.
We just have the images and then the contact page.
Everything is nice and stacked as well.
All right.
So that's the responsiveness of it.
So that's it, guys.
Hopefully you enjoy this.
Let's jump in to the next video and start to set up our SAS environment.