All right.
So we've built a couple of small projects on our local machine.
Now I want to start looking at how to actually get a website online.
And we talked a little bit about this in the beginning of the course, you're usually going to register
a domain name and then buy some kind of hosting account, although many hosting accounts do include
a free domain name.
So in this video, I just want to go over the different types of hosting there are as well as the pricing
points.
So these are the most common types of hosting we have shared hosting veeps, which is a virtual private
server, dedicated server reseller hosting, cloud hosting and static hosting.
So we're going to go over each of these and talk about what they are.
So aside from from free tiers of static hosting, which I'll get to in a bit, shared hosting is definitely
the cheapest, ranging from around $3 to $15 per month, although a lot of times you'll have to pay
by the year.
So it'll be around 70 bucks, 70 to 100 bucks a year, which isn't bad.
And shared.
Hosting means that you get one of many accounts on the same server and on the same operating system
environment, and this is suitable for most small websites.
So anything that we build in this course would be just fine on a shared host in terms of data and size,
however, they usually restrict bandwidth.
So if you have a site where you're expecting tens of thousands of users every day, it's probably not
the best thing you probably want to go with with something of a higher tier.
But if it's some local business, like a flower shop or something like that, in most cases it's going
to be fine.
I built websites for local businesses for a long time and I would say 90% of them use the shared web
host.
So this is definitely where you're going to want to start, I should say probably where you're going
to start or maybe static hosting, which I'll get to in a little bit.
And this is this is what we'll be doing in this section.
We're going to set up a shared host shared host account with In Motion, which is a great service,
great company that I've used for years.
Now.
Most of these these types of accounts are managed and they include email servers.
So you'll be able to set up your email with your domain name.
You get a control panel to view analytics, create FTP accounts, you can upload files, you can even
create databases.
A lot of them come with like one click installs for things like WordPress.
So shared hosting is great for small local businesses and like I said, I suggest in motion.
But there's also HostGator, Bluehost, these these are some other companies that I've worked with that
are really good as well.
All right.
So next up, we have VPNs or virtual private server.
And this is a step up from shared hosting.
You're going to get a it's basically an account that's on a physical machine, but it's a virtualized
environment.
So with shared hosting, you have the same environment.
You just have different accounts on a veeps.
You have you have less people on the same server and they're all their own environments.
So it's more secure, you know, it's less prone to issues from other accounts, things like that.
You also get much more access with a shared account.
You usually can't log in through SSH or through the shell as a route user and with a veeps you have
much more control.
You can log in as route, you can install things, and these range from usually range from about 20
to $100 per month.
And obviously different packages have different disk space and bandwidth restrictions just like a shared
host, a VP is great.
If you plan on having more than one website, you can actually create your own smaller shared accounts
with their own separate control panels, and you could even sell shared accounts.
But a reseller is better for that, which I'll talk about next.
So a reseller account is very similar to a veeps.
It's except it's more geared towards reselling shared hosting to third parties.
So you'll basically get a panel where you can create and terminate shared accounts and you can sell
those to to users on your website.
And most reseller packages come bundled with a piece of software called W.H CMS, which is used for
billing.
You can actually make it so when a user pays through the system, which you can integrate into your
website, a new account gets set up on your reseller server and then they'll get sent an email and they'll
be able to log in and all this.
I actually did this for about three or four years when I had my web dev company, but I wouldn't suggest
doing it unless unless you really know what you're doing.
You know, you need to really know about things like DNS and and DevOps and stuff like that.
All right.
So a dedicated server is an actual physical machine sitting in a data center that you rent out.
So as opposed to just basically having an account on a server with other people, you, you actually
not own but rent the machine and these are definitely the most expensive.
They range anywhere from 100, which is very, very cheap.
You're lucky to find a dedicated server for 100 bucks to 400 and even more than that.
Now, these are great for large sites and applications that are going to have tons of users.
You get full freedom.
You can usually install whatever operating system you want, stuff like that.
Most likely Linux, Linux rules, the hosting world.
So most of the time your servers will run Linux some some distribution of Linux.
The downside is they're much harder to manage.
And in most cases you'll probably have like a designated DevOps person on a team managing a dedicated
server.
All right.
So next is cloud hosting.
And this is more for web applications, more so than just static websites.
So if you build something like a social network or an E commerce site using a language like Python,
PHP or something like Node.js, cloud hosting is great for that.
It's basically having multiple servers working together and it's extremely powerful and scalable.
Digital Ocean is one of my favorite providers for this.
The downside is you have to know a lot to manage cloud hosting.
You need to know a bunch of Linux terminal commands.
You need to know how to set up things like Engine X servers, firewalls, and it gets really, really
advanced and way beyond, you know, what we're doing in this course.
All right.
So lastly, we have static hosting, which is fairly new and a good example of this is NetFlow Phi and
GitHub pages.
We're actually going to be deploying to Net Phi a little later, which is a fantastic service.
They offer hosting, but they also have additional features like serverless functions if you want to
add some dynamic functionality and also contact form submission, which is really cool and they're used
for both front end applications and static websites, including sites that want to have backend services.
NetFlow find GitHub pages, both have free tiers.
So if you just want to host your site without having the bells and whistles of a control panel, you
know, email and all that, you can do that for free.
But if you I mean, you could still have email on that domain.
You'll just most likely have to have it connected to some other service, some kind of email service.
Now, you will need to know at least the basics of Git, which is a version control system to deploy
to either nullify or GitHub pages.
But we're going to do that later.
I'm going to teach you some of the basic commands, and it's really not that difficult.
All right.
So for now, what we're going to do is jump in and we're going to upload our Edge Ledger website to
In Motion hosting to a shared account.
And it'll show you how to create FTP, how to upload your files and all that good stuff.