All right, guys.
So we're going to start a small project here and this is a presentation website.
So this is not really like a mainstream website, but something that maybe you would do at some kind
of conference if you want to if you want to have some kind of presentation, but you don't want to use
PowerPoint, you want to build something custom.
Obviously this is very simplified, but you could add graphics to it, charts, stuff like that.
So basically we're going to be using a bunch of stuff that we've we've already learned.
So we're going to use variables, we're going to use a little bit of keyframe animation, transition,
stuff like that.
So basically when the page loads, I'm just going to reload it.
The top comes in, the side comes in.
All right.
And then we also have a transition on the button.
You can see it kind of fades nicely.
And this is like the landing page, so the greeting page and then notice there's no scroll bars, I
can't scroll up and down.
We actually have to click the button to go to the next page.
And what I've done is I've integrated that smooth scrolling jQuery script or jQuery code that we used
a while back.
But you don't have to do that.
If you don't use it, you'll just click and it'll just it'll just go to the next page.
It won't have the scrolling effect.
So it's up to you if you want to use that or not.
And then notice that this is just page two.
You would change the title here and the content.
You could add any content you want we have previous which will bring us back up and then we have next,
which will bring us to the next page, which is a different color background.
We're going to use variables for that and then the next page.
And of course, if you wanted to add more, you could.
But I just I just have four pages now.
These are not separate HTML pages.
It's all in in this.
Well, I called it landing HTML, but we'll be calling it indexed HTML.
But it appears to be multiple pages.
So this is what we'll be building.
So let's get started.
So I'm going to go ahead and close that up, open a new tab.
Let's go to about here.
Just because I want to have both on the same screen and I just have an empty folder called presentation
website and we're going to create an index HTML file and let's create I'm just going to do a style dot
CSS.
I'm not even going to create a CSS folder because this is a very small project.
So in our index, HTML is it's generate our boilerplate.
I'm just going to close this and let's just say presentation for our title and we'll put in actually,
you know, what we're going to do is link our style sheet.
So let's go above the title and link and let's link to style CSS.
We don't have a CSS folder, so we don't have to do CSS slash style.
And then for the content, the content is going to be pretty simple.
So we're going to have a section actually, let's put a comment here.
We'll say this is going to be page one, which is the intro, and it's going to be a section.
These are all going to be sections with IDs.
So we're going to give it an ID of page dash one, and then each one is going to have a class.
I don't want to put the word class.
We want to say dot and then the class name, which is Page.
Okay.
And then we'll have an H one and let's say welcome to my presentation.
And then under that let's put a paragraph and I believe I did lorm, I think I did 40 it sounds about
right.
So lorem 40 and underneath the paragraph we're going to have a div in this div is going to have whatever
buttons there are now on the first page we're just going to have one button because it's just a next.
There's no previous.
We're on the first page, so let's do an A tag, let's give it a class of BTN because we're going to
style that.
And then this is going to go to the ID of page dash to OC and then inside here, let's say next page
now we are going to be using font.
Awesome.
So I'm actually going to go to font awesome dot com and we're going to grab the link here so that we
can use these icons.
So let's put this right above our link to our style sheet.
Excuse me.
Okay.
Now we should be able to use icons, so I'm going to go after the text of next page and I'm going to
put an I tag with a class of f, a s and let's do a class of F, a dash, arrow, dash, circle, dash
down.
So that will give us a down facing arrow.
So if I save this and we open this with a live server.
We're going to see something like this.
So notice the the arrow coming from font.
Awesome.
So for the next page, I'm going to copy this whole section and go right under it.
And this is going to be page two and get rid of that.
And this is going to have an ID of page two and for the title or the H one, I should say.
I'm just going to say page two, I'm going to leave the same text.
Obviously, it would be different content if this were a real life project.
And then down here the next this is I'm going to have this go to the previous page.
Well, actually, you know, what I'll do is just copy the entire a tag here and paste it under.
And this one is going to go to page one and this is going to say previous or prev page.
And then for the icon it's going to be a circle up.
And then this one here is going to go to page three and this is going to be circled down and it's going
to go to the next page.
So now let's copy page two.
We'll copy that section.
Paste that in.
And this is going to be page three.
Change that all to page three.
And then as for the previous, it's going to go to page two and this is going to go to page four.
All right.
Actually, one thing I wanted to do is for the let's see for the previous page button.
Let's let's give also give that a class of button dark because I don't want them to be the same color.
So that will be button dark.
This one also.
Button dark.
All right.
And then we have one more page to do.
So we'll paste this in.
This will be page four, giving an idea of page four, and then the previous is going to be page three.
And then we're not going to have a next.
So we can we can get rid of this whole a tag.
All right.
And let's see.
We won't do the button doc here just because it's the only button.
All right, so I'm going to save that.
And that's what that's what we're going to get.
And you can see just how much CSIS does, because this is the HTML.
And just look at this.
It's absolutely horrible.
So CSS is very important when it comes to shaping up a website or an application.
So that's the HTML.
In the next video, we're going to start on the CSS.