All right, guys.
So now we're going to go ahead and set up Node Sass so that we can compile our XSS files in our SAS
code.
So you need to go to Node.js dot org if you don't already have it installed and just go ahead and install
either the long term support or the current version for latest features doesn't really matter in this
situation.
Now we're going to jump into VS code and I just have an empty folder called SAS Sandbox and we need
to use the terminal or the command line.
I'm going to use my integrated terminal.
We can open that in V code with control tilde or you can go to the view menu and just go to terminal
or you can use your standard Mac terminal, Windows Command prompt to Linux terminal or whatever and
just do a quick NPM Dash Dash version just to make sure you have NPM installed.
And then what we want to do is create a package JSON file since we're installing anything with NPM and
we can generate that with NPM init.
And then I'm also going to add on dash y so that we don't have to answer a bunch of questions.
It will just give us the defaults.
So let's go ahead and run that and I'll clear this up with control L and in our package JSON, it just
has the name, the version, all that stuff.
Once we install Node SAS, it should get listed in here as a dependency.
So let's say NPM, install node dash SAS.
Okay.
So it's going to install it in a folder called Node Modules.
And you can see it's listed here as a dependency.
Now in order to use node sass, we're going to create an NPM script.
So inside here at this scripts, we don't need this test.
I'm actually going to change this to SAS.
That way we can just run NPM, run, run SAS.
And then in here we want it to run Node SAS, we want to set a watch flag.
So Dash W we want it to constantly watch a folder called SAS, which we haven't created yet.
So slash and then we want it to output dash oh to a folder called dist slash.
CSS dist is where basically our project is going to live.
The HTML files, the CSS, anything that we would deploy will be in that dist folder.
And then we're just going to add a dash dash recursive flag here.
All right.
So that should be good.
Let's go ahead and save this and we'll close it up.
And now what I'll do is create a folder called Success, and this is where all of our SAS files will
go.
So let's create a file called Main Dot Success and you can see it as a little SAS logo there.
Now we also want to create a folder called Dist and this is where the compiled CSS is going to go as
we direct it in our script.
So let's go ahead and clear this up down here and let's run NPM, run SAS.
Now what this is going to do is it's going to constantly watch the SAS folder and any SAS files in it,
and as soon as we save it'll compile into dist CSS, which we haven't even created.
We don't have to create it.
It will do it on its own.
So we'll test this out by just creating a variable and I'm going to discuss variables and stuff in depth.
I just want to test it out.
So I'm going to say we want to say color.
We'll set that to red and let's say body and we'll set the background to the variable of color.
So this is SAS, this is not regular CSS.
Now I'm going to save it with control.
S And as soon as I save it, it'll tell us down here that rendering is complete and if we look in DIST,
we now have a CSS file with a main dot CSS.
So it's going to copy the name which we called main and it's going to just name it that, but it's going
to be a CSS file.
And if we look in that, it's just a body background read.
So it takes this sass with these variables, compiles it down to this CSS and then this is what we include
in our HTML.
So in DIST, I'm going to create a file called index dot HTML and we'll just put in our boilerplate
here.
Let's call this SAS sandbox and we want to link to see CSS slash main CSS and we'll just put an H one.
And we'll save that.
Now we can open this HTML with a live server.
And now we have a red background.
Now, if I go back into my SAS file, this is where you want to do all your styling.
You don't want to touch the CSIS, just the SAS.
I'm going to change this to Blue, and as soon as I save that, you'll see down here it renders and
then we can go back.
And now we have a blue background.
So our entire environment is set up.
Now when you're ready to deploy, you will just take this dist folder, this other stuff, node modules,
you all your SAS package, JSON, this is your development environment.
This only has to do with your development.
This DIST is your actual project, your actual product that you would deploy.
All right.
So that's how we work with Node SAS and we're going to come back to this.
But in the next video, I want to show you another option which is using a graphical program called
Koala.
So we'll take a look at that and then we'll jump back in and we'll start to look at the features of
SAS.