All right, guys.
So we're going to jump right in and start to learn HTML.
We're going to learn all the important HTML five tags attributes.
We'll learn how to insert images into pages, links, forms, stuff like that.
And I realized that a lot of you guys probably already know some of this stuff.
So feel free to skip around, skip some videos.
If you want to skip this whole section altogether, that's fine.
Later on after section three, we'll be getting into like CSS grid and Flexbox and animations and more
difficult stuff.
But again, I want this course to be very friendly for absolute beginners that have never even touched
HTML before.
So let's go ahead and create a new folder for our HTML files.
So we'll just go ahead and right click and say new folder and I'm going to rename this to HTML sandbox.
And the idea here is for every section or every video, I should say, we're going to be touching on
a different topic.
So for instance, we'll look at like links and images in a video.
We'll look at forms and input and I want to have a separate file for each video and create a sandbox
that you can use as a reference if you need to go back to it later on to see how how a tag is structured
or what attributes it takes, things like that.
So let's go ahead and open this up in VS Code and Visual Studio code and there's a few ways to do that.
If you're on windows, you should be able to right click and say open with code.
You can do it that way.
If you're on a mac, you can drag it down to your VTS code icon in your bar down below or you can just
open up V's code and just click open folder and then search for it.
So mine's on my desktop.
There it is, HTML sandbox and I'll go ahead and open.
All right.
So we can close this up.
And now on the side you can see the HTML sandbox folder is open.
So let's go ahead and create our first HTML file.
And I'm basically going to create a file called indexed HTML oops, not comma but dot HTML.
Now there's something really important for Windows users.
If you are seeing a dot txt here after the dot html, then you have to actually change something in
your your folder settings.
All right.
So I have a screenshot here.
If you're on windows and you're seeing a dot txt, you should check this anyways to make sure that this
box is unchecked.
What you want to do is go to your Vue tab in your your file manager and go to options right here and
then click change folder and search options.
You'll get a box like this that pops up and you want to click the View tab and make sure that this is
unchecked.
This hide extensions for known file types.
You want it to show the file extension.
So just just make sure that that's unchecked if you're on windows.
All right.
So I just wanted to mention that so you don't run into problems.
So now we have an HTML file.
So what do we do with this?
We need to put in what's called an HTML tag.
So HTML files are full of HTML tags which surround content.
So let's take a look at how HTML tags are actually formatted.
So elements are surrounded in angle brackets.
So basically this the the left standing greater than signs.
So the element here, for example, is an H one and different elements do different things.
This is a heading tag.
There's actually H one through H six and I'm going to go over that in another video.
But basically this will make this text much bigger.
This here is a paragraph tag, which is just for paragraphs, just regular sized text.
And notice that there's an opening tag and there's a closing tag or a start in an end tag and the end
tag has a forward slash.
So that's how you identify the ending tag.
Now there are some self closing tags for stuff that doesn't have content inside of it, like the H one
and the paragraph.
They have content inside the bar tag is actually just a line break, so it just kind of skips a line.
So there's no need to put any content inside of it.
So it's a self closing tag, it doesn't need an ending tag.
Now notice that this one has a slash in this one doesn't.
This is actually a remnant of XHTML, which is a derivative of HTML, and it's it's not used that much
anymore.
HTML five is definitely the standard.
That's what you want to learn in HTML five.
You could use either of these so you can use the HTML version with the line or the slash, but you don't
need to.
This would be just fine.
So this is how tags are structured.
So what I'm going to do now is just put in a couple of tags and I want to show you how to open an HTML
file in the browser.
So remember, tags have an opening angle bracket and we'll do an H one, which is a heading.
We'll close that H one and with V's code, every text editor is is different with VS code, it's going
to end.
The tag for you.
So notice that the ending tag was put in automatically, which is very helpful.
And VTS code actually has a tool that comes pre-installed called emit which you can use to type really
fast HTML.
And I'm going to show you some some tips and tricks with Emit as we move along.
So let's put something in here.
We'll just say welcome to my website and then we're going to go on the next line and we're going to
put a paragraph tag.
Now remember, we have emit installed and with them we can just do P because we want a P, a paragraph
tag which is a P and then we can hit enter or tab.
You can do enter a tab and it'll actually complete it for us.
So it makes it very easy.
If we want an H to tag, we can do H to enter if we want.
So let's say an image tag, we can do img enter and that will actually give us the attributes that we
need.
I'm going to go over all this stuff later, so don't worry about it.
But just to show you that emit is very helpful and it allows you to write HTML very fast.
So in the paragraph, let's just say this is my very first website.
So we just have a heading tag and a paragraph.
Let's go ahead and save this.
You can either go to file save or you can just do control s or command s on a mac and that will save
the file.
So now let's go ahead and minimize this and let's go into our HTML sandbox folder and you can see we
have our index HTML file.
Now you might have a different icon.
It's probably going to be whatever your default browser is, it could be Chrome or Safari or edge if
you're on Windows.
So you just want to open this with a browser.
So I'm actually going to right click and just say Open with Google Chrome, which is my default browser.
And there it is.
So you can see that the H one is a large heading and then the paragraph is just, just normal sized
text.
But this is in fact an HTML file.
You can see in the in the URL bar here, it gives us the full path.
Yours will probably be different, but mine is in my desktop in HTML sandbox and then index HTML.
Now of course, when you upload this to a web host, it'll be your domain name.
So let's say you registered my website, which of course is already taken, but we'll use that as an
example.
So this would be replaced.
This file, this stuff here would all be replaced with whatever your domain is.
Now, there's a reason that I called it index HTML.
And this name here is significant because when you call it indexed HTML, this is your home page.
If we were to upload this to a host with let's say my website is the domain.
If we go to my website, it's going to load the index page.
So it's very important to understand that whatever you want your home page, you want to call that index
and then any other page you can call whatever you want.
Like let's say you had an about page that listed your company info or something like that.
You could create an about HTML page, upload it, and then you would go to my website, slash about
HTML and that would load that.
But index is significant because that's always going to be your home page.
All right.
So now that we have created an HTML file and open it, opened it with Chrome, in the next video, I'm
going to show you how to correctly structure in HTML document because this isn't correct.
There's some other things that we need to add in order for it to be valid.
HTML document.
All right.
So we'll get into that next.