All right, guys.
So we're going to deploy our site to a shared host with In Motion hosting, which is a service that
I've used for a long time.
I'm actually going to create a new account.
They're not paying me a dime for this.
However, I do have an affiliate link that I'll attach in a document to this lecture.
So if you are going to buy a package, I'd appreciate it if you could use that link.
All right.
So I'm actually going to go ahead and set up an account just out of pocket just to demonstrate this
to you.
So as you can see, there's different types of hosting they offer.
Many of them are the types we've talked about now.
Their shared hosting plans are going to be the business hosting.
You'll notice with different companies, they'll call it different things.
They also have WordPress hosting, which is basically the business hosting or shared hosting.
But with WordPress already preconfigured, WordPress is actually a content management system and it
might be something worth looking into after this course.
They also have veeps hosting, dedicated servers, reseller hosting.
We're going to go ahead and click on Learn More for business hosting.
So as you can see, if you choose any type of hosting, they're going to have additional packages with
different price points.
And these prices here are actually if you pay for two years in advance, 399, you'll see one year is
4.99.
This one is one year, 6.99.
So very rarely, if ever, are you going to find a hosting company that allows you to actually pay $3.99
month by month.
Usually you have to pay by year by two years.
Sometimes they'll allow six months.
It really depends on the company.
But for now we're going to choose or I'm going to choose the cheapest version here for one year.
Now, the difference between these, you can see, is the number of websites.
So you can have different amounts of websites.
The disk space and bandwidth is unlimited on all of these, but you have to be careful with shared hosting,
even though it says unlimited.
If you start to slow the server down, you start to slow down resources.
They're either going to throttle you or they're going to ask you to bump up your package.
If you have a website that has a ton of users or it's a really big or big application, something like
that, then you're going to want to use a VPN or dedicated server or something like that.
But like I said, most small business websites, these are absolutely fine.
I would probably say go with the middle tier, but since I'm just doing this for the course, I'm going
to choose the cheapest one available, which is going to be one year for 4.99 per month, which should
come to about $60 a year.
Yeah.
Now, if you want an sstl certificate, they do offer free SLRs, but you do have to have a dedicated
IP for that, which is an additional $4 a month, which is $48.
So they're going to charge you an extra $48 if you want a dedicated IP and an SSTL.
I'm not going to choose that, but just know that you will need to if you want sstl.
And then here, this is for just like a quick start or one page website for 100 bucks.
Obviously we don't want that.
And then if we want to install WordPress or Bold Grid, we could do that.
But we're not going to do that either.
So let's click Continue and now it's going to ask about a domain.
Now within motion, you can purchase a domain through them.
I think it's 1499 per year or if you have your own, you could choose this option here and to your domain
and then you would have to go wherever you registered that domain and just update what's called name
servers to point to your in motion hosting account for just registering domains.
I actually suggest name cheap dot com.
I'll put an affiliate link for name cheap in the document as well, but I'm just going to go ahead and
purchase a new domain here.
So I'm going to do Edge Leger and I believe dot com is already taken but dot net is not.
So I'm going to just choose edge ledger dot net as my domain.
So as you can see, it's available.
So I'm going to add it to my cart.
And then over here you can see my total is 84 to 86.
That's for the entire year for the domain and for the hosting.
And let's see, just continue here.
Actually, I'm going to remove the domain privacy.
What that means is if someone tries to do a who is check on your domain, they won't be able to see
your like the email address you used and stuff like that.
But I don't care about that, so I'll delete that.
And then over here I am a returning customer, but I want to create a whole new identity for this just
because this is only for the course.
So I'll go ahead and put an email address in here
and continue.
And then it's probably going to take me to a page where I have to enter my credit card information and
stuff like that.
Yeah, all my information.
So what I'm going to do is pause the video.
I'm going to fill all this out and then I'll come back.
All right?
So I filled out all my information.
It gave me a summary up here.
So now I just need to click agree and check out.
Okay.
So now it says welcome to In Motion hosting order details.
And down here it's going to ask if we're creating a new website or transferring an existing website.
So we're going to go ahead and click creating a new website.
And they also ask if you want a one on one call from a new account specialist so someone that can actually
call you and help you out if you need help, which I think is really cool.
But obviously we're not we're going to click no, thanks.
And then here they have really good documentation and support for the control panel, setting up FTP
accounts and stuff like that.
And you can get custom articles sent to you, but I'm not going to check any of these, so we'll just
leave them all blank.
Oh, I guess we have to check at least one.
So we'll do.
Let's do getting started.
So it's going to process that.
Now, we should have an email that has information on how to access our C panel, our control panel
and stuff like that.
So I'm going to just pause the video and pull up that email.
All right.
So this is the email that you'll get welcome to In Motion hosting.
And it's going to say get started with your account management panel also called AMP.
So your email, your login is going to be your email address.
And then it says to get started, set your password here.
So we're going to go ahead and click that.
We're going to set a password.
So
actually use something different here.
All right.
So that might be too simple.
I'm going to be canceling this account anyways.
All right.
So this is your AMP panel, and this is this is basically in Motion's customer panel.
You can update your contact information, your credit card info.
If you have trouble, you can send in a support ticket.
And then down here you have your link to see panel, which is basically your web hosting control panel
and many, many different companies.
You see panel, it's the most popular type of control panel for managed hosting.
You can also check your email from here, but you can also do that from C panel.
You can install software like WordPress, stuff like that.
You can manage your SSL certificates.
So it's basically your your client panel.
So let's go ahead and click on See panel and that should open up and let's just close this up.
So this is your control panel for your basically your website, your hosting account, and you'll see
there's different sections preferences.
We have a lot of the stuff that we have in the AMP panel like Contact Information and to get back to
AMP, you can click here or you can go click home.
There's also links up here to get to different sections, but email, you have your email accounts,
you can set up your forwarders, your email routing, you have spam filtering, stuff like that.
Domains, if you wanted to add another domain, if you want to create redirects, you can do that from
here.
If you want to install applications on your website like WordPress, which is a blog slash CMS content
management system, you also have like shopping carts, open cart press to shop.
These are open source shopping carts that you can install and use on your website.
You have software, so PHP packages, stuff like that, files, FTP accounts, we're going to get into
that because we need a way to actually upload our files to our site and databases.
If you get into application development, you'll probably want to get into like MySQL or Postgres.
These are relational databases and these are included as well metrics.
If you want to look at analytics, your website, visitors and so on, security, you can block certain
IP addresses.
You do do have shell access, which means you can log in through the terminal into your account and
do different things and advance.
We have things like cron jobs, but that's way beyond this course.
All right.
And on the right side, I mean, I have mine blurred out just because there's some sensitive information,
but it has all your stats and stuff like that, the number of FTP accounts you use and email accounts
and so on.
So in the next video, before we start to deploy our website, I want to show you how to create email
accounts as well as FTP accounts.