All right.
So up to this point, we've only looked at HTML, which is definitely needed.
We need it to actually put stuff on the page.
But by itself, it's very ugly.
We need CSS to style it and move things around and and align and add colors and background and anything
else that has to do with layout and style.
So in this section, we're going to look at all the basics of CSS.
So let's go ahead and create a new folder.
And just like we did with HTML, we're going to create a sandbox.
So I'm going to call this CSS sandbox and these files will be in the lecture, the last lecture, the
introduction, if you want to download those, or you can just create them along with me.
So I'm going to open this with VS code.
So in Visual Studio code, I'm just going to go ahead and open folder and open up CSS sandbox and we're
going to create in here a new file.
And I'm going to call this just we'll call it basic .01 underscore basic dot HTML.
So I'm just numbering them.
So you know what order we're going in.
And again, you don't have to number them.
And if you didn't watch the last section, the HTML section, we are using an extension called Live
Server so that we can open our HTML file in a little server and it will auto reload.
So you just want to install that if you don't have that yet.
All right.
I also went over some tips and tricks with shortcuts as well as Emit, which allows us to write faster
HTML so we can actually do exclamation and hit enter or tab and it'll give us this basic HTML structure.
So in the title here, I'm going to call this implementing CSS because I want to talk about the different
ways we can actually bring in CSS.
And we're going to look a little bit at selectors, but we're going to talk more about that in the next
video.
So let's put some basic HTML in here.
I'm going to put an H one and just say heading one and then I'm going to copy this down by doing shift
option or shift alt on a Windows machine and then hit the down arrow twice.
So this will be heading two and heading three and let's actually make this an H to make this an H three
and I'm going to save this and then we're going to open with live server.
And right now I have this, I have both the browser and the editor on the same screen, but later on
we're going to have to make this bigger if we're going to build, you know, real websites and stuff.
So we have three headings on the screen and I'm going to show you three different ways to implement
CSS.
The first is called inline CSS, which is not something that you want to do, but it is something you
should know.
And this is what we what we were doing in the last last section, the HTML section, when I just wanted
to show you a couple examples of stuff.
So we use the style tag and you can actually put CSS in here.
Like let's say we want to use the color property and we want to set that to red.
If I go ahead and save that, the heading turns red.
Now you don't want to do this.
And the reason for that is you want to you want to keep it's called separation of concerns.
You want to keep your styling out of your markup.
You want to keep those two things separate.
And when you do it like this, you're just clumping it all together.
It's much harder to read, it's much harder to change.
It's just not good practice and any developer will give you crap for doing this.
So this is not something you want to do, but it's something that you should know you can do.
All right.
So next one I want to show you is called internal CSS, where it's still on the same page.
It's on this HTML page, but it's separate from your HTML.
The way that you do this is inside your head tag.
You put in a style tag and then in here you can just put CSS.
Now with when you're using CSS, you need a way to select whatever it is you want to style.
Let's say we want to change the color of this h to well, we can use the actual element as the selector
so I can say h two and then open some curly braces and I can put as many styles in here as I want.
So let's say we want color and let's, let's add green.
And if I save that, notice that it turns green.
All right, now let's go over this syntax really quick.
So if we take a look here, I mean, this is similar to what we just did, except we use color instead
of background color.
But the first thing here is a selector.
In this case, it's an A tag.
What we just did was we did the H one, then we did the H two.
And you can use the actual tag as a selector, but you can also use IDs classes.
There's something called pseudo selectors.
There's a lot of different things.
We can do four selectors and we're going to get into that in the next video as well as later on.
So that's the selector.
Then we have the declaration start, we also have the declaration end.
So everything goes within these curly braces.
And inside the curly braces we have a property such as background colour or colour, as you just saw,
and then the value.
And in between that we have the property value separator, which is a colon.
All right, so you have the property and value and you can add more of these.
If we wanted to add a colour, we could do that as well.
You just want to end each one with a semicolon.
So this is the basically the just a diagram of how CSS works.
So we've looked at two ways to add CSS in line, which you don't want to do.
And then internal and I'm just going to put a comment here and you can have comments in CSS as well.
If I hold down control and hit the question mark or forward slash, you'll see that it adds in a forward
slash asterisk and ends with an asterisk.
Forward slash.
This is a CSS comment.
So in here I'm just going to say that this is internal CSS.
All right.
So I'm going to save that and I'm going to show you the third way, which is external CSS, where you
actually have a separate file that you bring in that has all your CSS.
So let's create a folder.
I'm going to go over here and I'm going to click the folder icon and call this folder CSS.
And in here let's create a file called Style DOT CSS.
That's a common name for a for a main stylesheet.
And you can include more than one style sheet if you want as well.
So now that we have a separate file, let's start let's grab this H three right here.
So I'm going to use the H three element as a selector and I'm going to do color blue.
We want to end that with a semicolon.
Now, if I save this, you'll notice that the the H three is not is not blue.
And the reason for that is this file has no clue that it's supposed to look at that, that style CSS.
We actually have to bring that in.
And the way that we do that is with a link tag, HTML has a link tag that we can use in the header.
So we'll say link and then I'll hit Enter or tab and it gives us some necessary attributes such as Rel.
This tells it basically what, what type of link is this.
It's for a stylesheet and then in a graph, just like with the A tags, this points to the location
that we want to basically load, which in our case is in the folder called CSS and it's a file called
Style CSS.
So if I save this now, you'll see that the h23 change is blue.
That's because we're now including this file.
If we don't have this, if I comment this file out and save, it's not going to read it.
So you want to make sure that you include your style sheets.
Now out of these three, this is the preferred using an external CSS file.
When we build our projects, when we create a website, all our CSS will be in a separate file.
However, for this sandbox, for this section, I'm going to be doing it this way because I don't want
for a couple of reasons.
One reason I don't want to have to go back and forth to to go to my CSS.
I also want you guys to get a big picture of what's going on.
So I want you to see the HTML and the CSS at the same time.
But usually you would do it this way.
You would have a separate file.
So just keep that in mind.
So in the next video, we're going to start to look at how to use IDs in classes for selectors, how
to use multiple selectors, nested selectors, things like that.
So I will see you in the next video.