All right, guys.
So we're going to jump into CSS grid here.
Now, I've created a whole new folder called CSIS Grid Sandbox, and I'm going to create a new file
called zero one underscore grid, underscore columns dot HTML.
And we're going to go over just the basics of how the grid works.
Also the grid template columns property.
So I'm going to close the sidebar up and we'll generate our boilerplate here, let's say grid columns
and style.
And the fact that, you know, Flexbox, if you've been following along with the course, is going to
benefit you because the grid works in a similar way where we take a parent element and we set display
grid just like we would do display flex.
And it makes all the child elements of that of that parent, it makes them grid items.
And then we can add specific properties on the parent to affect the grid items.
So let's go ahead and create our markup.
I'm just going to do a class of grid.
This is going to be the container and it doesn't matter what you call the class.
Obviously, I just called it grid and then let's do a few divs with the class of item.
So we'll just for the content, we'll say item and then an incrementing number and we'll do times three.
So we have three div elements inside of our our container here.
So let's, let's style the items first of all, just so we can kind of get a better visual picture of
how this works.
So I'm going to add, let's say padding, we'll do three REM and let's do a border.
One pixel solid and a background of light gray.
And let's do a font size of 1.3 REM will do font weight bold and lets do text align center.
All right, so I'm going to save this and we'll go ahead and open this up with live server and we just
have our three elements, three items here.
So what we need to do now is add for this, this parent right here, this div we want to add display
grid.
So I'm going to say the class of grid, we want to do display and then grid.
Now if I save that, nothing happens.
It's not like flex where it automatically turns into a flex row.
What we need to do is add a another property called grid template columns.
So let's say grid dash template dash columns.
And here is where we specify how many columns we want and also the width of those columns.
So basically by columns I mean we'll have one column, another column.
So basically going in a horizontal row.
So let's say we want to do three columns that are 200 pixels wide.
So 200 pixels for the first, second and third.
And if I save that, that's exactly what we get.
So no floats or anything like that.
We simply create the number of columns we want and the width.
Now, even if we have more than three, three grid items here, that's absolutely fine.
It's just going to continue on to the next line.
So if I were to copy this down and say four and save, it's just going to go right into the next spot.
If we do two more and we say five, six and save, it's just going to it's just going to keep going
in this in this sequence.
All right.
So this is great for like news sites, which is one of the projects that we're going to build.
It's great for our image galleries and it's just great for just basic layout.
It's just to if you want just a main area with a sidebar, you simply set two columns.
All right?
Now, this obviously doesn't go all the way across its container, which which is container is the viewport.
But let's say we wanted the middle one to stretch so that this went all the way across.
We could use auto.
So if I put an auto here and I save now, it's going to give it the length that it needs to fill the
container.
And if I stretch it out, it's always going to fill its container.
And let's say I wanted them all to be the same, but I wanted them to fill the container.
I could do this.
Let me just copy this down.
I'll comment this out.
And instead of doing the 200 pixels, let's do auto, let's do it three times.
So now we have three columns that are all the same size.
If we wanted four, we could add in another one like that.
Now there's a better way to do this.
If you're going to be repeating the same width like this, you can simply use repeat.
And then this takes in two things.
It takes in the number of times you want to repeat, which I'm going to say three, and then the width
you want to repeat, which I'll do auto and save.
And you see we get the same result.
If I were to put let's say 200 pixels in here and save, it's going to repeat 200 pixels three times.
So this is a much nicer way to do it.
Now we used pixels here.
You can also use other units, you can use percentages.
But the most common unit you're going to see when using the grid is an FR unit, which is a fraction.
So it's basically a fraction of the page and it works similar to how the, the, the flex property works.
When we say flex one, flex two, it works similar to that.
So I'm going to copy this down and comment that out.
I just want you guys to have this as a reference.
But we can do, let's say one FR for the first row, too far for the second and one fr for the third.
And we'll save and you can see that it's split up into fractions.
And the second one is larger and if I wanted it even larger, I could do three FR and it will extend
more if I wanted to do two and then maybe two on the end.
So we'll have one short and then two longer ones.
We could do that, could do any combination we want.
And of course we can do repeat with FR as well.
And that's usually what I would do is repeat three one FR if I wanted three columns that were all the
same with now.
Notice that these are all stuck together, right?
So instead of adding margin, there's actually a specific property we can use called grid gap.
So we're going to say grid gap and you can put any unit here, pixels, whatever.
I'm just going to do one REM and save and it's automatically going to add that gap, that spacing in
between.
All right.
And there's no dealing with know, calculating widths or anything like that.
It just it just simply works.
And it doesn't matter how how wide or or narrow the browser is either.
All right.
So that's pretty much the basics of how to create a grid and create basically like horizontal row with
columns.
What I want to show you now is just how easy it is to do a simple layout like a main area and a sidebar.
If you remember back to when we did the floats where we had to carefully choose the percentages, we
had to clear them, stuff like that.
So I just want to show you how simple it is.
If we had, let's say, main and Inside Main, we want our main area or content area to be a section
and we'll just put an H three.
Let's say welcome to my site and we'll do a paragraph and say Lorem 30 and let's say we want an aside.
So this would be our sidebar.
We'll just say whatever hello and let's say Lorem ten.
So we're going to save this and we want this to be our sidebar.
So we want this to be over here.
So with the grid, we could take this main because that's the parent of the section and the side and
we could simply say display grid and we'll define our grid.
Template columns and we'll simply do two FR for the main area or for the section and then one fr for
the aside for the sidebar.
And then let's give it a grid gap of, let's say 1.5 REM and save and that's it.
So three lines instead of having to float and deal with percentages, it's very, very simple.
If we wanted to have it split in the middle, we could do one fr, one fr like that.
If we wanted this to be a little bigger, we could do three fr.
So it's very simple to manipulate how your content is displayed and how things are aligned.
All right.
So in the next video, we're going to start to look at grid rows, because up to this point, we've
looked at grid template columns, but there's also a grid template rows.
So that's what we're going to get into next.