All right, guys.
So now we're going to start on the markup for the showcase area where the navigation, the header,
all that stuff, and we're going to also style it.
But before we get started with that, I just want to mention I'm using the prettier extension for VS
code.
So if I have something that's out of line like put this link way over here and I save it, fixes it
automatically because in my settings I have it set to format on save.
So if you want this extension, you can just click on the extensions here and just search for prettier.
And it's this one right here.
So prettier code formatter and if you install it and you want it to format on save like mine is, then
you just want to go to your settings.
So if you click on the little cog down here and go to settings or you do control comma or command comma
and just search for format on save and it's right here.
You want this box checked if you want that functionality.
And I just want to mention it because you might see at times when I save, it'll kind of change up a
little bit.
And that's why it's just it's not changing any of the code or anything.
It's just formatting it in a more readable way.
So let's get started down here in the body.
So I'm going to get rid of the H one and we're going to go ahead and and create the header.
So everything we do right now is going to be wrapped in a header tag and I'm going to give it an ID
of header dash home.
Now the reason I'm doing a header home is because the home page and the inner pages are very different
in terms of the header and the menu.
So the inner pages are actually going to have an ID of header inner and we're going to style them differently.
All right.
And then inside here, I'm going to put a class of container, which is a utility class that we'll use
over and over to just center content.
And then let's put our NAV and I'm going to give this an ID of main dash nav.
And then some of these in some cases, if you want to use class, that's fine.
I'm basically using ID for things that are just for that single element and then classes more for utilities.
We're actually going to create a utilities CSS file where we'll put like the container buttons, backgrounds,
things like that, anything that's basically a utility.
So in here, let's put the logo.
So I'm going to do an image with the ID of logo and the source is going to be in the image folder and
then the logo tag.
And again, I did include the PSD if you want to edit it and change the initials or anything like that
for alts, we'll just say, I don't know my portfolio.
So let's see, under the image we're going to put the UL, which is going to have the links.
So we'll do a list item, let's do an A actually, I'm going to give this a class of current since this
is the index page, this is going to go to index HTML and we'll say home and then let's copy this down
four times and then we're going to have the about and I'm just going to highlight this class current
and hit control DX twice and then get rid of it so about is going to go to about HTML.
We also have work html.
So work and let's do contact.
And contact.
HTML.
So those are our links now under the nav.
We're going to put let's do our header content.
So I'm going to give this a class of header
dash content and we're going to have an H one and say, I am, let's do caps, I am John V and then
this is where the type text is going to come in.
So JavaScript is going to be used for that.
And again, I'm not going to really go over the JavaScript code.
I do.
Like I said, the tutorial is on YouTube.
However, we need to put in our span here because this is what the JavaScript is going to grab on to,
to insert that text, that type text.
So I'm going to give this a class of text, dash type, and we're going to give this some special data
attributes that the JavaScript can basically grab and read from.
So we want a data dash weight and I'm going to set that to 3000.
So that's basically the time it's going to take in milliseconds after it types, photographer or whatever
we put and then types the next thing.
And then it's also going to take in data dash words and I'm going to use single quotes here because
this is going to take in some brackets and then any word that we want in the type effect is going to
go in double quotes.
So I'm going to say photographer.
Let's put a comma and then we'll do designer.
If you remake this for your own portfolio, obviously you can change these and then UI dash UX dev.
So the JavaScript is going to grab on to those and and add that type effect.
So under the H one, let's add a paragraph.
I'm going to give it a class of lead, which is going to be utility class just to make the font size
a little bigger.
And let's say.
Um, I specialize in graphic design, UI, UX and photography.
And then the last thing we want in here is an a tag with the class of BTN Dash Lite.
It's going to be formatted as a button and it's going to go to the work HTML page.
And as far as the text goes, we'll just say, view my work.
All right, so I'll save and you can see prettier.
Just kind of made things look a little more readable.
It put all these attributes on separate lines.
So now let's take a look and notice that it's just white because we actually set the body text to be
white.
So the next thing we're going to work on is the CSS or the SASS, and we're going to add that big background
image so that we can actually see the text.
So let's jump in to main access.
And we have the header home, the header dash home, and then the inner pages are going to have header
dash inner.
So what I'm going to do is let's say header and we'll do ID header.
Now there isn't going to be an actual ID of header, there's header home and header inner.
So in here I'm going to use ampersand dash home and then we'll do ampersand dash inner.
So anything for header home will go in here and then enter will go down below.
So for header home, let's do background and we're going to set that to our variable.
Remember we have a variable of BG image which holds the location of the background image and then we'll
do no repeat.
I'm going to do center and I'm going to position it right.
So center right.
And then we want it to cover the entire area.
And as far as the height goes, we're going to take up the whole page.
So we're going to do 100 viewport heights and then let's just make sure the colour is white.
All right.
So if we go ahead and save that and we go back now, we can see the image.
Now let's work on this logo because obviously it's it's giant.
So the logo and the nav bar, while we're at it, let's take a look there inside the header home.
Right.
However, we're also going to be using the nav bar and the logo inside header inner.
So we don't want to embed it inside either of these or in header because there is no idea of header.
So I'm going to put that outside of it.
So right here, let's do logo and we'll do main nav.
So for the logo, let's do let's do a width of 70 pixels.
I should probably put the selector.
Let's see it's an ID so logo width, 70 pixels and let's do a height of 70 pixels.
Now you may not want to use an image, you may want to use text or like an H one with an idea of logo.
So I'm also going to add a colour of white and I'm also going to make it uppercase.
So text transform uppercase just in case it's not an image.
So if we save that, we take a look.
Now the logo is smaller, we can see the rest of the content.
Now, before we move on to the main NAV, let's center this with the container class.
Remember, it's there.
This stuff is wrapped in a container.
Now, like I said, I'm going to create a utilities sass file that we can are a partial for things like
buttons and stuff like that.
So let's create a new file in the case folder called Underscore Utilities, Dot CCS.
And in here I'm going to put our container class.
Now we have a variable called website width that we have in the config folder.
So let's set the max width to a variable of website width.
Right.
And then I'm just going to add some padding on the side.
So let's do 1.5 REM and then let's do margin auto to push it to the middle and then overflow hidden
so nothing goes out of its container.
And now we need to bring this utilities file in.
So up at the top here after config, we're going to bring in utilities and let's save that.
And if we go back now, you can see everything is pushed to the middle.
So let's continue working on the main NAV, which is basically the logo and the list here.
So let's go back down.
And let's see.
Main nav.
Let's put an ID of main main dash nav and we can embed the UL, the ly or I should say nest.
We can nest the ul ly the link stuff like that.
Now the whole main nav, including the logo and everything.
I'm actually going to set this to display flex as I usually would.
I wouldn't use the grid for something like this.
And then I'm going to justify content with space between because I want the logo on one side and then
the UL on the other side and let's just do a padding top just to kind of push everything down a little
bit.
We'll do one REM.
And then we can embed in here the UL, which is also going to be Display Flex because we want the list
items inside to be flex items.
So let's do that.
Let's do lye.
And what's nice is we can we can nest all this stuff within the main nav, just like we do in the HTML.
So I'm just going to add a little bit of padding here.
So let's do one REM and then 1.5 on the sides and then the link.
Okay.
So, Link, I know I did a global text declaration.
None, but I'm going to do it again here.
Same thing with the color.
Let's do white and I want it to be all uppercase.
So I'm going to do text transform to uppercase and I'm going to do a border bottom.
And this might seem a little weird, but I'm going to do three pixels transparent, solid.
Now, the reason I'm doing transparent is because I want to have a hover effect.
When we hover over it, it gets a line under it.
But if I don't put a border here and I just do it on the hover, it's going to basically push the text
upwards to give it the border.
And I don't want that kind of effect.
I just want the border to just show up.
So we want to make it transparent at first.
And then I'm also going to add some padding bottom that's 20.5 REM.
And then I'm also going to add a transition.
So it kind of has a smooth effect.
So we want to transition the border color because that's what's going to change on the hover.
So we'll say border color, 0.5 seconds now I want the hover.
So inside this a tag or this a selector, I should say I can do ampersand dot, I mean colon hover.
So this will be the hover effect and I'm going to set the border color to the variable medium dash color
so that we define that already in our config.
Now I also want the current link to have a border as well.
So I'm going to do Ampersand Class Current, which will be a dot current in the NAV.
And I'm going to set the border color and let's set that to what do they call it?
Main color.
So we'll call.
We'll do main dash color.
All right.
So let's save that and we'll take a look.
So it looks pretty good.
So this is this whole thing is the main nav.
It's Flexbox.
And we have space between for the main nav.
And then the UL is also a Flexbox where each list item is a flex item and you can see the border.
And now when I hover over it, it just kind of fades in.
If I didn't do the transparent border to begin with, it would just kind of tick up when I hover over
it and I don't want that.
All right.
So that looks pretty good.
So let's see, let's move on to the the header content so that basically this stuff right here and then
we'll bring in our JavaScript file as well.
So let's see, let's go down to header.
And we want to be.
Let's see.
We want to be within the header home.
So inside here, let's say header content sometimes helps just to comment this stuff.
Header home.
All right.
So head of content.
It is a class of header dash content.
Let's align everything to the center.
So text align center and let's I'm going to add a padding top of 20% and then I'm going to take the
H one that's inside the header content so we can nest it like this.
And I'm going to set the font size to be pretty big.
I'm going to do four REM and I'm going to give it a line height of 1.2.
All right.
So let's take a look at that.
Now, this right here has a class of BTN lite, which is going to be a utility.
So let's take care of that while we're at it.
So we're going to go into utilities and I showed you this in the last section, how to basically extend
a selector or extend styles.
So I'm going to just do buttons and we're going to create like a, like a base shared button style.
So I'm going to use a percent sign and say BTN dash, dash shared.
So all buttons will share these styles.
They're going to be display inline, inline block and let's do some padding.
So 0.8 REM and let's do two REM and then I want them all to transition on hover.
So let's say transition and I'm just going to do all 0.5 seconds.
We're going to set the border to none.
And let's set the cursor to a pointer because this is for both buttons and links.
Now.
Down here, we're going to have BTN and I want to add a couple of different options here.
So we'll have button, main button light and button dark.
So let's do ampersand dash main.
So this will pertain to a class of button Dash Main and we want to extend
the shared button class or style.
So we want to do percent BTN shared, so we want to extend all that stuff above.
And then the color for right now I'm just going to set it to set it to a dark color.
But later on we're actually going to use that set text color function that I showed you guys in the
last section.
So let's do background color, which is going to be the main color so that for right now it's that yellow.
But of course, you can change that within the config.
All right.
And then I'll just grab this.
Copy this down twice, and let's make this one the light.
So this will be button dash light.
We're going to extend everything.
We'll keep the dark color here and then the background is going to be the light color.
All right.
And then down here.
Let's do dark
shared button.
We'll put the light color here and then the background is going to be the dark color.
Now, as far as the hover, I actually want any any of these buttons to when you hover over it to have
the main color as the background.
All right.
So the way I'm going to do this is let's go outside of this BTN and we're going to say so four button
and then in here we can actually do like class.
We could do class equals something.
However, I want to only include part of it.
Anything that has the BTN dash inside the class I want to grab on to so we can put a carrot character
here, which is shifts shift and then number six and then equals and we'll set this to just a BTN dash
and then we want colon hover.
So any class, any button with the class of BTN dash, anything this will this will be in effect for
now.
We also want links with the same thing.
So I'm just going to copy this and we'll do an a tag with that stuff.
Let's also do if it's an input with the class.
So yeah, we'll do input.
K So any of these, if they're hover, then let's make the background color main colour.
So it just saves us some room here.
Now I'm going to add a couple other utility classes.
We, we already use the lead class, so we want to definitely put that in.
So lead is just going to have a font size of 1.3 REM.
And let's add a little bit of margin bottom as well.
So we'll do two REM.
And then I also want to have a text center just to center something if we want.
So we're just going to set text align to center.
All right.
So let's save that and let's go back and take a look.
And you can see we have our button.
And when we hover over it, we get that that main color, it happens to be yellow, but we could easily
change it in the config to be any color.
And this would change this color up here with change.
All right.
So the last thing I want to do in this video is this part here.
I want to add the JavaScript script so that this actually works.
And again, I'm not going to go over the actual JavaScript code.
If you want, you can check the tutorial out.
In fact, what I'll do is I'll put a comment in.
Let's see, let's go to the index HTML down at the bottom here and I'm going to paste in a comment to
the actual tutorial.
So we'll say type effect tutorial and then let's just include the script.
So we want to do source to JS slash typewriter JS, save it, go back and it works.
So the script, the way that it works is it just looks at or is it the span looks at this right here,
looks at the wait time, it looks at the different words.
If you want to change up the words, you can just simply change them right here.
All right.
So I think we're good for now.
In the next video, we're going to move on to the next part, which will be what the developer specializes
in, the different icons, stuff like that, the creative process with the transitions.
So we will get into that next.