All right, guys.
So in this video, I want to show you how to install something called Live Server, which is something
we'll be using through the course.
And basically, it's an extension to voice code that allows us to open our HTML pages on a little development
server as opposed to opening them in the file system.
So right now you can see that the website is open.
And if you look at the URL bar, it's file colon with three slashes and then basically just shows the
path to the file.
So the server will actually open it on what's called our local host.
And not only that, it will it will auto reload.
So when we save an HTML file or CSS or JavaScript or anything else, it's going to just auto reload.
So we don't have to keep hitting the reload button every time we make a change.
So we're going to go ahead and do that and I'm going to just create a new file here.
I'm going to call it zero to underscore live underscore server HTML, just naming it after what we're
doing here.
And there's something else that I want to show you guys.
Instead of typing out the whole structure here, like we did in this file with V's code, we can use
Emit to generate that structure.
So what I'm going to do is just put an exclamation and I can either hit enter or tab and it's just going
to kind of create that structure for us so we don't have to type it out for every HTML page we create.
Now notice there are some some added things here.
We have some meta tags.
We're going to go over meta tags, including these ones in the next video.
But for now, I just wanted to show you that we can quickly generate our structure, our our dock type,
HTML head, body tags and stuff like that.
So I'm just going to change the title here to live server and we'll go down here and just put an H one
and we'll say we'll just say hello world doesn't really matter.
I just want to put something and then I'm going to save this with control.
S And we want to now install a live server.
So we're going to go over here to this extension's icon and make this a little bigger.
And we're going to search for live dash server and it's going to be this this one here, this first
one with this purple icon.
Now to install an extension in V's code, you just want to click the little green install button once
it installs, you want to click reload to activate.
So it's just going to kind of reset the the editor and now under enabled you're going to see live server
and any other extensions that you install will also be displayed here.
So now what we can do is instead of of leaving and going and opening up the file, we can simply right
click and we can say open with live server and the browser will automatically open and it will display
the web page and notice the URL now is different.
It's not just that file path, it's 127001, which is what's called the loopback address.
And this is always going to loop back to your local machine.
So this is your local host and then this colon, 5500, this is the port number that it's running on.
You can run things on different ports and then you just have the name of the file that's loading.
So from now on we're going to use live server to open our files instead of leaving and going and opening
the file manually.
Also, if I change something like let's change this to we'll just add a paragraph here and we'll say
This is a test and I'll just save.
And now if I go to Chrome, you can see this is a test is displayed.
I didn't have to go and reload it.
It just auto loads and this is great for when you when you actually have your editor on one side and
then the browser because it automatically updates.
Now I don't want to do that because I only have so much screen real estate here for you guys and I don't
want to make the editor too small.
We might do that in some videos later on, but for now I'm just going to switch back and forth.
So to stop the server, if you go down here, you can see this port 5500.
If you click that, it'll stop the server from running.
And if I go back to the browser and reload, you'll see it no longer works.
If I want to start it again, I can either again do open with live server or I can click this go live
link down here.
If I click that, it will start it back up and open it in the browser.
All right.
So I just wanted to show you guys that and let you know that that's what we'll be using, as opposed
to just opening and opening our HTML files right on the file system.
So in the next video, we're going to take a look at meta tags.
We'll look at the ones that are generated here as well as some others.