All right, guys, welcome to your next project.
So I think you're going to enjoy this project because we haven't looked at hamburger menus or anything
like that yet.
And this is going to be a a hamburger menu that's completely in CSS.
Now, most of these things have JavaScript involved, and we're not going to do that.
I'm going to show you a trick so that we don't even have to use JavaScript.
But first, let's take a look at what we'll be building.
Now, what you're seeing here, this this little splash page with the image, this isn't really important
to the project.
We've done all this before.
We're just going to add an overlay and image and use flex to center it.
What we're focusing on is this right here.
This is a hamburger menu and I believe it gets its name because it has a three lines that look like
a hamburger.
And I'm sure you've seen these before where you click them and maybe something opens from the side or
comes down or you get an entire overlay like we're doing.
So I'm just going to go ahead and click this and notice that a couple of things happen.
So one, if we look at the hamburger menu itself, it turns into an X, which is really cool.
And when we hover off of it and go back on, it kind of just goes back and forth, which is a neat effect.
And then we get this entire menu overlay with some links here.
So this is a really nice menu because it's completely responsive.
It doesn't matter how big or small the screen size is, it's going to work and you don't need any extra
media queries or anything like we've been doing.
And I built it in a way so that you can use this in other projects pretty easily.
We're actually going to put all this the menu CSS in its own file in a file called menu CSS.
Now let me explain how this is actually working without JavaScript, because usually what you would
do is you would dynamically set a class in JavaScript, maybe like a show class or something, so that
when you clicked you had a JavaScript click event that would put in a show class or something like that.
But we're not doing that.
This is actually a checkbox.
This is an HTML input with the type of checkbox and with a checkbox you can style the checked state.
When it's actually when it's checked, you can, you can add styles to that.
And that's what we're doing.
We're basically going to get rid of the checkbox itself and replace it with this, but it still has
a check state.
So when I, when I click it, we're actually checking it and we can create all these styles.
Basically, you choose to display this overlay, add transitions, transform stuff like that, and then
we can uncheck and it goes away.
All right.
So this is something that is very useful, very unique.
There's no JavaScript involved.
So I think you guys will like this little project.
Now, we're going to start with just the HTML.
I want to create all the HTML, which isn't much at all, and then just the base styles.
So we get this image and stuff like that, all the stuff we've done already.
And then in the next video we'll start on the actual CSS for the menu.
All right, so I have an empty folder called Hamburger Overlay Menu, and I'm going to just make this
smaller.
We can probably make this a little smaller.
Because this is completely responsive.
So it doesn't matter if we keep it small, but we're going to create a file called Index HTML.
So let's go up here and let's create index dot HTML and then we're going to have a folder called CSS.
And inside here, let's create a style CSS.
And then like I said, I want all the menu stuff to be in its own file.
So menu dot CSS and we're going to have one image.
So we'll have a folder called IMG.
And let me just grab that real quick.
Now, you guys can get this from the the files in this lecture.
You'll have all the completed files and you can just take it from that.
But let me see let me just grab it real quick.
Uh.
Where is it?
All right.
So I'm going to just bring this in here.
So this is our image.
And now let's go into our index HTML.
And I'm just going to close up this sidebar.
All right.
So we'll call this hamburger menu overlay and let's link in our style sheet.
So we'll do link.
We're going to have style CSS.
Actually, it's in CSS slash style CSS.
And then we also want to include our menu dot CSS.
All right.
And it's up to you if you want to do this stuff, if you want to include multiple style sheets, if
you have a ton of styling for one particular thing like we're doing here, then you may want to do it
this way, or you could just include it all in one.
So let's start with let's let's take care of the HTML.
So we're going to have a a div here with the class of menu wrap.
And inside here we want our input.
And like I said, it's going to have a type of checkbox and we don't need a name and an ID.
All we need is a class and I'm going to call this class toddler because that's what it is.
It's going to toggle that overlay.
And underneath that, we're going to have a div with the class of hamburger.
And we're going to have an empty div in here.
Now, the way that we're structuring this might look a little weird, but that's what we need to do
in order to get the effect that we're going for.
So we're going to have a class of menu underneath and then a div and then another div.
And inside here will be the UL.
So this will be our list.
We'll have list item.
Let's put in a tag.
These aren't going to actually go anywhere.
And I want to give you guys a challenge to turn this into a full website with what you've learned so
far.
I'm not going to go through it because I don't want to repeat stuff that we've already done and that
we're going to do in the future.
But it'd be a nice little challenge for you to create an actual site from this.
I mean, obviously you can just point to about dot HTML and also include the menu in that page as well.
But we're going to just copy this down a couple of times.
And this next one, actually the top one I'm going to make home.
So home about let's do services, it doesn't really matter services and let's do contact.
So that's that.
Let's save this and we'll open it with live server.
And this is going to look very.
Oops, hold on.
What's going on?
I think I have something else open with live server.
Let's see.
I think I still have my news grid open.
Yep.
We just close that up.
Okay.
So let's try that again.
And there it is.
So we just have a little checkbox here.
So we're somehow going to turn this into this with CSS.
That's how powerful it is, how powerful CSS is.
Okay, so let's do the rest of the content.
So under the last div, we'll create a header with the ID of showcase and let's have a container and
let's also have a showcase.
Dash container we're going to use flex here to center everything and let's put an H one, we'll just
say welcome and then a paragraph we'll do like lorem 20 and then under the paragraph let's put in a
tag with the class of BTN.
I realize I didn't have to do this part, but I'm doing it for two reasons.
One, just so we have some things, just so it looks decent and so that we can reiterate things that
you've already learned.
All right, so now let's go into our style, CSS, and let's add our our main styles.
Now we're going to use variables here.
So let's say in our root scope, we're going to have a primary color
and I'm going to use our GBA.
You remember our GBA is red, green, blue alpha.
So we can add transparency to to the element using the color.
So we're going to have 13 110 139 and then the opacity or the alpha will be 0.75.
So it's going to be this color here and it's going to be a little see through.
And we're also going to have a secondary color which is going to be like an orange.
So let's say secondary color, we're going to use that for the hover links and that's going to be
2291480.
And let's do an alpha of just 0.9.
Okay.
And then we're going to have an overlay color.
So the overlay is going to be actually, you know what?
I should probably keep the keep the file open.
Just so I can show you, like, what's what?
So this right here, the background is going to be the overlay color the yeah, that's going to be the
overlay.
So let's change this to overlay.
And this is going to be.
24, this is going to be pretty similar to the primary, but darker so 24, 39, 51 and we're going
to do 0.85.
Now, if you want this to be less transparent, see how we can see the welcome behind it.
You can just raise this up.
You'll be able to just put this to maybe 95 or just one if you want it to be solid.
But I like I like the see through effect.
All right.
So that's our overlay color.
And then last thing I want is the is the speed, how fast this actually opens.
I want to put that in a variable so that it's easy to access.
So let's say menu dash speed, 0.7 5 seconds.
And I know that this has to do with the menu and this is style dot CSS, but I didn't want to put separate
variables in the menu CSS.
We can actually use these variables in that file because we're putting we're including the style CSS
before the menu, so we're able to use those variables.
Now let's add our reset.
So we'll say margin zero.
I always like to put a space there, margin zero and padding zero.
And then let's do box sizing for a box for the body.
We're going to use the Roboto font.
So we have to grab that real quick.
Let's go to Google Fonts and Roboto I have right here.
I'm just going to click that and I'm going to grab.
Um.
Let's make this a little bigger.
Okay.
So I'm going to grab this link and put that in the index.
HTML read above the style sheets.
All right, so let's see.
Next thing in our style, CSIS, we want to add the font family, which is going to be Roboto sans serif.
And then let's do a line height.
Of 1.4.
And then we have our container to move everything to the middle.
So we're going to set a max width and I'm going to do 960.
And the reason I'm doing it so thin is because I don't want it to get in the way of the menu.
I want the menu to always be outside of it.
So even if we go like here, you can see that there's, there's room here.
So when we scroll down, the content will be this won't cover the content basically, but you can experiment
with it if you want.
And that goes for any project.
If you guys want to experiment with different values and do things a little differently, that's that's
absolutely fine.
In fact, I encourage that.
So let's say margin auto, we want to push it to the middle.
Overflow should be hidden and let's add the padding.
That's another thing that's going to push the content in.
So let's do zero, top and bottom and three ram left and right.
So if we if we save this, it's going to look like this for now.
Now, let's see, what should we do next?
Let's do the showcase.
So showcase and I'm going to do the background of the showcase as the primary color.
So we'll put in our variable variable of primary color and let's do color white and we'll set the height
to 100 viewport height.
So I want to take up the whole page and position relative.
I'm doing position relative because we're going to use the before pseudo selector to add our overlay.
And the overlay has to be position absolute.
And remember the position absolute is relative to its first relative container, which of course we
want to be the showcase.
If not, it will use the, the body as the, as its container.
So that's good.
Let's save and just you can pretty much completely ignore this whole part because we're going to be
changing this.
It's not going to display at first.
We're going to add some CSS to hide it.
And then it's only going to show when we click the the the hamburger, which right now is a checkbox.
So let's go down here and say showcase before and remember if we use before or after, we need a content
value, but we're not actually inserting content, so we just put nothing and then the background URL.
So the URL is going to be dot, dot, slash, IMG slash showcase.
We want to do no repeat center, center slash cover as usual.
And then again, like I said before, we want to position this absolute.
We want it to start at the top zero and left zero corner and spin all the way across and all the way
up and down.
So if we save that, we get our image.
Now the image is covering everything.
So let's set the Z index to negative one and save.
And there we go.
So now the image is behind the coloring.
All right.
And the this is a little different than how we've done it before because we're using an GBA value.
And that is what this primary color right here.
If I change this to one and save, it's going to be solid.
So the transparency for the background image is controlled with this.
If I do like four or five, you'll see that it's lighter so you can change it to how you want.
And then the overlay is going to be the menu overlay transparency.
So there's really two levels of transparency.
So let's see, let's, let's make the showcase container a flexbox so that we can center everything.
So we'll say showcase showcase container.
We want to display flex and set the flex direction to column because we want this to go up and down
and we want to do all of our centering.
So align items center.
This should start to get drilled in your head, justify content center and text align center.
So that should put it in the middle.
Now it's not down here because I haven't added the height.
We have the height for, for the actual showcase which is 100 viewpoints, but the showcase container,
we need to set that to 100% of its parent.
So we'll set height to 100% and save and now that'll get pushed down.
All right, so let's see the h one.
I want to make that bigger.
So showcase h one.
Let's set the font size to let's do four rem.
I think I did three on the other one, but I think I think it should be a little bigger.
We should probably make the the paragraph a little bigger as well.
Showcase paragraph, font size.
We'll do 1.3 REM.
All right.
And then for the button, that will be the last thing.
Let's just do a class of BTN.
So the button I'm going to do our same rigamarole we've been doing.
We want to display as inline block and let's set the border to none and the background.
I'm actually going to use the primary color.
And let's do color white.
Let's do padding.
So for the padding will do 0.75 REM.
Top and bottom 1.5 REM, left and right.
And I just want to add a little margin, top of one REM, just to bring it down a little bit.
And let's add a transition so that when we hover over it, it will kind of smoothly transition into
the hover effect.
So I'm going to say all 1/2 and we'll say ease, ease and out.
So save.
There we go.
And oh, the the underlying.
Let's get rid of that text decoration.
None.
All right.
So now we're going to do the hover state.
So button hover.
And since we're using a variable where it could be any color, I'm just going to use opacity as the
effect and we'll do 0.7.
So I'll save.
And then when I hover over it, you'll see that it changes and it does it nice and smooth because we
added the transition.
We could just do transition opacity.
We don't need to do all.
And there we go.
All right.
So that's going to be it for the this whole showcase area.
Everything we do from now on is going to be for the menu.
And there's a lot of CSS now.
Having something like this is really cool.
It looks really cool, but it is a lot of work.
There's a lot of CSS that goes into doing something like this.
All right.
So we're going to jump into and that's the reason I haven't created a hamburger menu on every project
we've done because it would just take up so much time.
But I did want to include it in the course, so I'll see you in the next video.