All right, guys.
Now I'm going to show you how to take a grid item and span it across multiple rows and columns.
So we're going to create a new file here called zero three, underscore grid, underscore span, HTML.
And let's go ahead and generate our HTML head body tags.
We'll say grid span and style.
And as far as the markup, let's just do our parent call it grid and then let's do a class item.
Just say item money sign and let's do a bunch of them.
So we'll do times 15.
So we have 15 grid items here.
So let's say grid and display grid.
And then I'm going to add grid template columns and I'm going to just do a repeat of four one half hour
items.
So we'll save that.
Let's open it up.
All right.
It's going to look like that.
I'm just going to grab the styling of the item from one of the other files just so we can clearly see
see them as boxes.
Why is this not copying?
All right, so save that.
Good.
Now, what I want to do is take one of these items.
We'll take the first one.
And I want to show you how we can span it across across the columns and also down through the rows.
So I want to take this item one and I want to have it go like this, fill up this whole area and basically
push the rest over so we can do that.
Using I'm going to show you the kind of the long way first and then I'll show you a shorter way.
So let's first target this first item.
We could give it a special class, but well, let's just use our pseudo selectors.
We'll use first child.
So I'll say class of item.
We want the first child and we have a property called Grid Column Start so we can specify where we want
it to start in terms of the column.
So it starts at one right now, let's say let's just put it to two and save and you can see that it
gets pushed over so we can start it wherever we want.
But I'm going to start it at one and then I'm going to use another property called Grid Column End,
and we can basically tell it where we want it to end.
And I'm going to put in here for and you can see what happens is it's spanned across what looks like
three, but what you're going to do is you're going to look at the lines.
So you have one, two, three, four.
So if you use this grid column and start and then that's what you're going to look at is you're going
to count these lines.
Now, we can also go down and that's that's the big difference between the grid and Flexbox or one of
them is that you can't do that with Flexbox.
You have your rows and that's it with with the grid.
We can, we can be multi dimensional and we can span this down into the next one.
So let's add grid dash, row dash start and we'll start at one, which is where we currently are.
And then let's say grid dash row, dash end and let's say we want to end at three and I'm going to save
that.
And now you can see that this is now spanning basically what looks like two rows.
But again, if you look at the lines, it's going from 1 to 3.
Now, this is kind of a long way to do this.
There's a shorter way, much like with many things in CSS.
So I'm going to comment this out and I'm going to show you how to do the same thing by using the grid
column and the grid row property rather than start an end.
So let's say grid dash column.
So it's basically just a shortcut and we're going to say start at one and then we want to do a slash
and we want to span three.
So I save that.
You can see it's doing the same thing that these two lines are doing.
And even though I put four here, when I put three, it does the same thing because here we're saying
we want to take we want an item to start at one and go to four.
When here we're saying we're taking item one and spanning it three and item one is here, so we're spanning
it three.
Now, if we want to go down like we did before, down, down a row, we can do grid row and let's start
at one and we want to span two and we'll save and we get the same result.
So this is just a shorter way of doing this.
Let's grab another one.
So let's let's get a random one.
We'll just take nine.
So we'll use Nth Child.
So we'll say item and let's say ninth child and we'll do nine.
And I want to keep it in its place, but span it across all the way to the end here.
So in terms of columns, it's in the second column, right?
So we want to do grid dash column and we want to set two.
We want to start at two and then we want to span two.
We'll go ahead and save that.
Actually, I wanted to go all the way over.
So we want to span three.
All right.
And then if we want to span it down, we could do grid row.
And let's start it.
So we're at one, two, three, four.
So let's say start at four and let's span two and save.
And now it gets pushed down.
So, I mean, you can start it wherever you want.
Like we could do grid row two and span two.
And it's going to get it's going to get pushed up here.
All right.
And notice that it's completely out of order.
But you may want that.
You may you may want your markup to be a certain way, but you want to move the the element visually
without changing your markup.
So the grid is good for that as well.
All right.
So in the next video, we're going to take a look at auto fitting and min Max.