Okay.
So the top part of our site is complete.
Like I said, we'll add the JavaScript for this later on where this is transparent, but now we want
to do the this icons section and the solutions section.
So we're going to be using Flexbox to align everything.
So let's jump into our HTML first and add that.
So I'm going to go under the header and I'm actually going to use a main tag here.
And all of our sections aside from the footer will go inside this main tag.
So our first section here, I'm going to give an ID of a boat so that our menu goes to it.
And then let's give it a class of icons and we're going to have background classes as well, utility
classes.
And I want this to be light.
So I'm going to use a class of BG light and we'll, we'll create that in a second.
And then for anything that we just want simple flex flexbox rows, I'm going to have a utility class
called flex items that we put directly on, you know, as the flex container.
So we're going to have some divs and in the div we'll have an icon.
Let's give this, let's say face and then f a dash university.
So that's our icon that we're going to use.
I'm also going to give it a class of F, a dash to X, which will make it twice as large.
All right.
And then underneath that, we'll have a Div with an H three.
So this is just going to be like a heading, we'll say investment, investment banking and then a paragraph
and let's just do lorem ten for the paragraph.
So that's the style of the or the format of each flex item.
So we want to copy this down twice.
The second icon is going to be book reader and we just want to change the heading up here as well.
So let's say investment.
No, we already did that.
Let's say portfolio manager.
Then this third icon here is going to be pencil, dash, alt and for the heading, let's say tax and
custodial.
So if we take a look at that, doesn't look too good, but we'll fix that.
So let's jump into the CSS.
So we're going to go into style CSS first and any direct styling for the icons class will go here.
So let's say icons and I just want to add some padding.
So we'll do 30 pixels for the whole thing and then for the H three, let's say icons H three, I just
want to bold the font.
So we'll set font weight to let's do 400 now, do bold and then add some margin to the bottom.
So 15 pixels now for the icons, I want to style them so that so icons I the font awesome icons I want
to style them so that they have this round background.
So let's go ahead and set the background color to our green.
And I mean, we probably should be using variables or custom properties for this because we re using
the colors, but I haven't gone over those yet.
Those are going to come in a later section.
So let's say color white and we want padding, so we want some spacing around it.
So 16 actually we'll do one REM, which in this case will be 16 pixels because that's the root element,
font size, border radius.
I'm going to set that to 50% and then let's set a margin bottom of 15 pixels.
So if we take a look at our icons now, we have this green round background.
Now we want to deal with our Flexbox because we want these aligned in a row.
So in our utilities, I'm going to I'm going to style the flex items class that we used.
So let's say flex items and we want to display flex and let's go ahead and text a line center and justify
content center and also text a line center.
So pretty simple and I'm just going to set the height to 100% and then add some padding to the divs
inside.
So let's say flex items and we can say the direct div.
So basically the the direct div child, we're going to set a padding of 20 pixels.
So let's take a look at that and there we go.
So that looks pretty good.
Yeah.
So the next thing that we're going to do is this section here.
And for these two column layouts, you'll see this looks similar to this one, which looks similar to
this one.
So we're going to have a utility class called Flex Columns for these because it's going to be slightly
different than how we style the three we just did.
So let's jump into our HTML and we want to go right under where we did the about actually we can let's
put some comments here.
So that's let's about icons and then under this section, this is part of the about section.
This is the solutions.
So we want to add a section here and let's give this a class of solutions and also a class of flex dash
columns.
And then within here, let's, let's create a row.
So take note of the structure of this.
We're going to have a row with two column div, so we'll say column times two.
And then inside this column we'll have a div called column one.
And in this one here, we'll have a div with column two.
All right.
So this this first one is going to be the image.
So let's add that we'll say image and we want to go into images, slash home and then people that's
all we want.
And column one, column two, we're going to have an H for we'll say what you are looking for and then
an H two and we'll say we provide bespoke solutions and then a paragraph and let's do lorem 20.
I believe I did.
Or lorem 30.
I don't know.
We'll see how it looks.
So that's column two.
And actually under the paragraph we do want a link formatted as a button.
We'll use BTN.
I'm also going to have a BTN outline class as well and we'll just put the text of Read More, but let's
put an icon as well of a Chevron.
So we'll do F as F a dash.
Chevron shares a space after it.
All right.
So if we take a look at that, we just have a stretched out image because remember, it's with 100%
by default.
We set that in our style CSS and then we have our content down here.
So let's go ahead and style the flex columns.
So this class right here, so we're going to go to utilities and let's go under where we have our flex
items.
And I'm only creating this utility class because we're doing a few different sections that have this
same exact styling.
So let's say flex columns, and we want to style the row and say display flex and the flex direction
is going to be a row, which is the fault.
So we don't really need that, but we'll specify it anyway.
We want the flex wrap to be wrap and we want width to be 100%.
And then for the columns, let's say flex columns, and then we have the class of column.
We also want to display Flex here, but we want the flex direction obviously to be a column and we're
going to set the basis.
So basically the default, we're going to set that to 100% and set it to flex one.
So it'll take up the entire height.
And then for column one and column two.
Let's say call them one and then we'll copy that down.
Call them two.
We want the height.
Make sure we set that to 100% as well.
So let's take a look at what that looks like.
Good.
Now I want this to have a green background.
So one thing I forgot in the HTML is to add, let's see, we want to put this on column two.
So BG primary.
And by doing that, it should be green or not.
Oh, we didn't do the background classes yet, did we?
So let's quickly add those in our utilities.
Now we already have the button classes and the BG classes are going to have the same exact thing, the
background color with the text color.
So what I'll do.
What I'll do is just excuse me.
We'll say BG primary and let's go here.
We'll say class BG Secondary.
We'll have a BG dark.
And a big light.
All right.
So now if we take a look, we have that green background and it doesn't go all the way down just yet.
We'll do that when we get to the column, to styling.
But for the image, I just want to do the image for us, because if we go to a certain width, you can
see the image starts to go up.
We want it to fill this entire area.
So let's go back to let's go back down here.
Oh, we had we had a colon there.
But that should so.
Oh, now it.
Yeah.
Now it fills the whole height.
But as far as the image goes to fix that, let's say flex column's image and set the make sure the width
is 100%, the height is 100%.
And if we take a look, the width and the height are 100%.
But see how it looks all stretched out.
We can easily fix that with a property called Object Fit and we can set that to cover which it works
similar to a background size cover with the with a background image.
So if we look now, you'll see that it takes up the whole area, but it's not stretched out.
It just covers it.
All right.
So that's what we want.
Now, as far as column two, let's style that.
Let's flex columns and let's do column two.
And we want this to display flex so we can align it display flex.
We also want the direction to be a column and then we want to align items center and let's I'm sorry,
let's align items to flex start since it's a column, align items has to do with the horizontal and
then justify content is going to be center.
So we'll center that and then just add some padding and we should be good.
All right.
Now, we do want to style some of the individual elements here.
So the H two, I'm going to make bigger I'm also going to add some margin and we got to take care of
this button outline class that we created or that we used.
So let's say flex columns h two.
Instead of font size of 40 pixels and let's make the font weight 100 and that's it for the H to the
H for.
Let's add a margin bottom of ten pixels and then the paragraph, flecks, columns, paragraph.
I want to add 20 pixels, margin on the top and bottom.
So if we save that, that all looks good.
Now for the button here.
I just want to have a border and I want a transparent background.
So just an outline.
So let's go to style CSIS up to where we have not style utilities, up to where we have our buttons.
And let's add a BTN outline and we'll set the background to Transparent and set a border of one pixel
solid and white.
So that'll be our button outline.
Let's take a look.
Good.
So that takes care of the icons.
That takes care of this.
Now, when we make this smaller, it doesn't look too good.
Later on, we're going to add media queries so that everything stacks and the navigation looks better.
But we're going to do the desktop version first.
In the next video, we'll go ahead and we'll do the cases and hopefully get to the blog section as well,
which should be really easy because it's the same style as this, except we want the image on this side.
All right.
So we'll get to that next.