All right, guys.
So we're going to jump back into our SAS sandbox.
Now, remember, we have the the SAS script, the MPM script, so I'm going to run NPM, run SAS, we're
going to want to run that when we're in development and then in our index HTML, let's open that with
live server and it should be blue if you've been following along.
And if I go ahead and into my SAS main access and they change this to let's say black and save, it'll
it'll reload automatically.
All right.
But I'm going to set that back to blue now.
Variables.
I mean, you can see how they're used.
We use a money sign to define a variable and then we simply use a colon for assignment and then whatever
the value goes in here.
So it could be a color, it could be absolutely anything.
Just just like with standard CSS variables.
So I think what we'll do here is just create a couple of different ones.
Let's do primary dash color.
I'm going to set to steal blue.
We're going to just create kind of a simple interface to to work with for the next few lectures.
So we'll do secondary dash color and we'll set that to sky blue and let's do a light color.
And a dark color.
Okay.
So as far as this kiss here for now, I'm just going to add a reset.
So we'll say margin.
Adding zero and then let's just add some stuff for the body.
So the background I'm going to set to the light color
and color I'm going to set to four now just set to the dark color and then for font family
we can do Arial Actually what we'll do is we'll take this and we'll put this in a variable called font
stack.
Just in case.
We want to change that.
It's right up here, easily accessible.
So we'll set that to font stack and then let's just set a line height.
It's completely up to you guys what you want to put in variables in your projects and what you don't.
I try to keep a minimal amount, usually things that are going to be used quite a bit in different places.
But yeah, so that's how we can set variables.
I'll go ahead and save that.
Now we also have what are called partials, so a lot of times the SAS, you break your CSS up a lot
more.
For instance, if you use bootstrap, which is a CSS framework and you use sass, every element like
the buttons, the nav bar, they all have their own separate partial file with just those styles.
So you can really break it up.
Now you can import these partials into a CSS and to a sass file.
And it's important to mention you can do this with regular CSS.
However it works differently.
You make you have to keep making extra HTTP requests to the server to fetch these the regular CSS files
with SAS, it just kind of takes them and builds them on top of each other.
All right.
So it's just much more efficient using SAS partials.
So in our case, I'm going to create a new file and I'm going to call it underscore variables CSS.
So this is a partial where I want to store all my variables.
Now notice I put an underscore.
The reason for that is this tells the SAS compiler that this is a partial and I don't want this file
to be compiled.
I don't want a variables CSS file in my main in my CSS folder.
I still we still want to keep just one file here.
However, we want to split it up here.
So I'm going to take all my variables here and cut them out and I'm going to put them into variables
CSS and save that.
Now, if I go back here and I save, we're going to get some errors down here.
It's another good thing about SAS is it gives you errors and tells you what's going on.
So this is basically telling us we have undefined variables.
So in order to use the variables in the partial, we have to import the files.
So we're going to go up here and we're going to say at import and we want to import variables.
You don't want to put the actual underscore the underlying.
You also don't have to put dot CSS just simply variables.
All right.
And then I'll go ahead and save that.
And now that's working again.
If I go to variables and change light color to red just to show you.
And I say, actually, you know what, we'll have to restart SAS down here just because we created a
new file.
So let's run that.
And now if we save this, now it turns to red.
All right, so I'm just going to put that back.
And safe.
Good.
So you can see we can structure our SAS however we want and notice that it didn't create a variables
CSS because it is a partial.
If I left that underscore off then it would have compiled this whole file into the CSS folder.
We don't want that.
We just want this single main dot CSS and notice it's using the light gray that we set in the variable
and you never want to touch the CSS that that gets compiled from SAS.
All right.
So in the next video, what I want to do is finish up our index HTML so we can get some markup in here.
And we're also going to look at nesting and structure within SAS, which is very important and a really
nice advantage of using SAS.