All right, guys.
So before we go ahead and create an FTP account and upload our website, I want to show you how to create
an email account and also how to create an email forwarder in case you want to send your email to something
like Gmail.
So you want to go to your C panel and click on email accounts.
And it's very simple, very self explanatory.
We have one domain on this account which is edge ledger dot net.
So let's say we want to create Brad at Edge Ledger dot net as an email address and we'll put a password
in here.
You can also choose to generate a password.
And then you can choose a quota.
So if you have employees and you don't want their emails to take up so much room on the server, you
can limit it or you can do unlimited.
You can also choose to send a welcome email with client configuration instructions.
So if you're if you have a company and you use like outlook or something like that or Gmail, you can
send them, you know, the account configuration stuff, but we're not going to do that.
So let's click create account and we get success.
If we click this view right here, it'll show us the email account.
Also, if we go back out to see panel and we click on email accounts, we'll see it here as well.
Now to check your email, you can do that right from C panel by just checking off or clicking access
web mail.
And it's basically going to ask us which which default application we want to use.
And they're all pretty much the same.
I would suggest using something like Gmail, just forwarding all your email there and then within the
Gmail settings, you can actually make it so you can send email from your account as well.
If you just look on the Gmail, the Google documentation, you can find out how to do that.
So I usually choose squirrel mail.
If I do use this, you're probably going to get a welcome page where you need to put in your name and
stuff like that and then just click submit and then this is the inbox here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go off screen onto my Gmail account and I'm going to send an
email to Brad at Edge Ledger Dot Net just to make sure that it works.
So I'll say Brad at Edge Ledger dot net and I'll just say hello.
And it works.
All right.
So I'm going to go ahead and send.
And let's reload our page here and it might take a couple of seconds.
It's chicken box.
Should be here any minute or any second.
There it is.
All right.
So from Brad Travis, see if we go to hello.
You can see that the message is it works.
And I just put hello in the subject.
So this isn't the best looking interface.
So like I said, I would probably use Gmail or something.
So to add a forwarder, we can go back to C panel.
Let's close that up and let's go home and then forwarders and let's say add forwarder.
So the address we want to forward is Brad and the domain.
We only have one domain which is edge ledger dot net.
So it's going to use that email address and I'm going to forward it to tech guy info at gmail.com.
All right.
So we'll say add forwarder.
And now anything that's sent to Brad at Edge Ledger dot net is also going to go to tech guy Infocom.
Now if you're not going to use something like Gmail, if you're if you're going to use your C panel
email, there's a there's a shorter way to get to your inbox rather than logging into C panel, clicking
on email accounts, searching for it.
What you can do is you can go to your domain so we can go to edge ledger dot net and then just slash
web mail.
So it's going to take us to this login right here and you can log in with your email address and password
and there we go.
And you can if you want if you don't want to show this screen, every time you can choose to set squirrel
mail or any of these as your default, that way it just automatically goes right into your inbox.
So that's just a much easier way to get to your inbox.
So you can also set up things like auto responders.
So if you're out of the office, you can do that filters, spam, filtering.
I'm not going to go through all this.
It's out of the scope of the course.
But I just wanted to show you how to how to get your email set up.
All right.
So in the next video, we're going to set up an FTP account.
We're going to I'm going to show you how to use something called file zilla so that we can actually
upload our website to edge ledger dot net.