Okay.
So now I want to get into alignment and justify properties.
So I'm going to take everything from the Flex Base Basics file and copy it and create a new file called
17 Underscore.
And we'll call this flex aligned HTML and let's paste that in and save.
And we, of course, we have to open up live server with this page now and I'm going to get rid of I'm
going to keep all the same HTML but get rid of this stuff that the specific items and let's see we'll
keep flex one so if I save this they'll just all be even and we can get rid of this flex wrap and we'll
go ahead and uncomment this.
And we want this to be a row, which is the default anyway.
Now align items is the property that I want to look at first and it's put on the container, not on
the items themselves because it applies to all of the items.
Now remember, when it's in a row like this, the horizontal axis is the main access and then going
this way is the cross axis.
What align items does is it aligns them on the cross axis.
So if it's a row, it's going to be this way.
So let's go ahead and say align items and let's go ahead and add center.
Now notice that nothing changed.
And that's because the height of the flex container is only the height of the content within it.
We don't have a specific height.
In fact, I can go ahead and add just so you can see this better.
Let's do a background color, I guess.
Yeah, we'll just do gray.
So that's the flex container, that's the height.
So if we add a height to this of let's say 50 V H, which is viewport heights, half the browser.
Now this is the height of the flex box or the flex container, and we've aligned the items to the center
on the cross axis.
Now, as far as values for this, we have center, we have we can do flex start, which is where it
was at the beginning.
You can also do flex end.
So it makes it really easy to align things, even if it's just like a showcase and you have maybe some
headings, a heading or a paragraph button, just a div with some content.
It's very easy to align things without having to use margin and padding and all that.
Now if this was a column, so I'm going to change the the direction to column.
Now notice that it's, it's going this way.
It's aligning it to the end here horizontally because when it's a column, this is the cross axis and
this is the main axis and line items is always on.
We just put this so cross axis a line and if I change this a line items to center, then it's going
to be centered this way because remember, it's on the cross axis and when it's a column, this is the
cross axis.
And one thing I didn't show you in the last video with like the flex grow and all that is that in a
column.
So if I set Flex one, let's just comment that out then it's just going to be the regular the regular
height of the items.
But we can set flex one or I could take item two and I could set Flex to like that.
And then that's going to be so you can do the same thing in the column fashion.
I just I didn't show you that in the last video.
So back to align items, let's set that to row.
So we have flex, start, flex and center.
We also have stretch.
So if I do stretch, it's just going to stretch all the items so that they're all the height of the
container.
But yeah, that's that's a line items.
Now we also have justified content which is going to be the main axis align.
So let's see, main axis align and let's say justify content center.
Now you can't really tell here because I mean these are we have a set to flex one.
So let's comment that out and let's set this to width or we don't even need a width.
Let's just comment out flex one.
So now you can see that it's centered on the main axis because we have justify content.
We could do flex start which will put it there.
We could.
You flex and which you'll put at the end.
Now we have some other cool options here too, like space around.
So it takes what it does is it takes whatever the remaining space is.
And these could be any width, but it just distributes it around the items, including the sides.
Now, if you don't want the space on the sides, we also have space between and now.
There's no space on the side.
We just have everything distributed in the in the middle of the items.
And it doesn't matter again how many you have.
You put some more here and it's just going to distribute that space in between.
All right.
So pretty cool.
Very, very easy to to do.
And obviously, if we change this to column.
Then justify content is going to be this way because it's on the main axis.
So we have space between each one.
If we wanted to do center or if we wanted to do flex, let's do flex end and it'll align it this way
down at the bottom.
So there's going to be a lot of times that you see display, flex, align items center and justify content
center because just I mean, you just center a lot of things in your layouts and that's one of the easiest
ways to do it.
So yeah, now we can also align each one individually if we want.
So let's change this back to a row.
Not that I don't know what that is.
Call Rome.
Let's change that back to a row.
So we have everything centered.
Now, if I want to take, let's say item one and there's a property called Align Self and let's set
that to Flex Start, they're all set to center, but I'm going to take just the first one and put that
to Flex Star and then I'll take let's take item three and let's say align self and let's set that one
to flex end so you can take each one and you can align them differently than the the main alignment
of align items.
So those, those properties are really important, especially these two.
So we'll be using them quite a bit through the course.
But that's the main idea of Flexbox.
It's just aligning things in rows or columns and centering them, and it just makes things much, much
easier than floats with margins and padding and percentages.
And, and you'll see when we get into our projects how much easier this makes it.
All right.
So that's it.
I'll see you in the next one.