All right, guys.
So we have the news grid files.
We have them in a repository on GitHub.
So now we can deploy the net lo fi in literally seconds or minutes in in our case, because I'm going
to be explaining some things, but you'll see how simple it is if we go to our panel here and the FI
panel, which is very simple, we could just say new site from Git and we have different providers here.
We used GitHub, so we're going to click on GitHub and you might get a little box set that asks you
to to authorize your GitHub account so that I can access your repositories.
And then you're going to see all your repositories down here.
And you can see I have quite a few, so I'm going to search for News Grid.
And if if you just created a GitHub account and did and follow the instructions, you'll just have this
one repository.
So we're going to choose that.
We're going to choose the master branch.
It's the only branch we have.
And then we don't need a build command or publish directory because everything is in the root.
So we're going to just say deploy site and you can see this little gear spinning should only take a
couple of seconds and now our site is deployed.
So it's as easy as that to actually get your website live on the Internet.
Now, the domain, as you can see right here, is something it's going to be different than this, but
it's going to be something crazy.
Mine is optimistic.
FEYNMAN And then some numbers dot net ft.com.
So let's go ahead and open this up in a new tab and there's our website.
So deployment is that easy with notify now the domain.
We're going to take care of that.
Don't worry about it.
But what I want to do is I want to make this form work.
So I'm going to search for net phi forms and this is documentation page here will show us what we have
to do.
We have to add method post to our form tag and data net equals true and then just make sure we have
a name attribute on on each field which we only have an email field.
Now we've already deployed our, our pushed our repository to GitHub and deployed our website, but
we need to make a change.
So whenever you need to make a change, you need to push your need to update your repository and push
to GitHub and then it should automatically update on the site.
So let's do that.
Let's go to let's see, I'm just going to minimize this and I'm going to open up our news grid website
in vs code.
And just make that bigger.
And let me just close this stuff up.
So let's see, we have our news grid website open and the form is on every page.
So we're just going to have to go to each of the three HTML pages.
Let's go down to our form and let's add a method of post and we need to say data dash net fi equals
true.
And then the input of this email input, we want to give a name of email.
All right.
Let me just make sure that.
That's correct.
So we did data.
Net net fee equals true method post.
Let's give it a name as well.
So we'll say, where is it?
Form name equals.
Call it contact.
All right, so that should do it.
Let's save and then let's take this whole form and go to about HTML, because obviously we want it to
work on all pages.
So we'll paste that in here and then let's go to article HTML to the footer and do the same thing.
So now that we've updated that, we're going to go back into our terminal, make sure you're in the
news grid folder.
As you can see, I am and we need to go get add all.
So it's going to add anything that has been changed is now in the staging area.
So now we need to commit once again I'm going to say get commit dash and then I'm going to say updated
form.
So we're going to commit that.
You can see three files changed and now we need to push to GitHub.
Now we've already added it as a remote repository and all we have to do now to push our changes is simply
get push.
All right.
So just doing that.
Should go ahead and update our repository, see how it says one commit if I reload.
Now we have two commits and if we look at one of these HTML files, we should see the changes.
So let's go down to the form and there it is.
So there's what we added.
Let's go to our website, notify site and reload, and let's take a look at the source code.
So I did I'm on a mac, so I did command option U and if we go down.
You can see that the form.
Now this.
It's going to look different than what we actually uploaded.
So it has a method of post.
You can see the name is contact.
What it does though is it puts a hidden value in here.
So basically net ify needs this to to process the form.
But it has changed.
Maybe we should have changed something else just so I could prove it to you.
But it is there.
It should work.
So let's try it out.
Let's go down to the email and let's say test.
We'll just do test at test dot com and subscribe and look at that.
Now if I actually gives us a success page, we don't even have to deal with that.
And then we can just go back to our site.
Now, if we go back to nullify and we go down, we go to overview right here.
You can see recent form submissions and we have test at Test Dotcom.
If I click on that, it's going to show us the email field and any other fields we have.
If we had name and address and all that stuff that would also show here, we can delete these so we
can manage all of our submissions from here.
We can also download them as CSV file.
All right, so really, really cool service.
Definitely recommend it.
Now the next thing I want to do is I want to set up a custom domain.
So in the next video, I'm going to show you how we can register a domain name from name cheap and we
can basically link it to our net website.