All right.
So we deployed our website to notify and we have our form working, but our domain looks like this.
So obviously you're not going to want that for your website.
Now, there's plenty of domain registrars out there.
I go with name cheap.
They're they're cheap, obviously.
Also, they're very reliable.
They have great support.
I've been using them for years.
It's a company that I personally recommend.
They're not paying me a dime for this.
However, I do have an affiliate link that I'm going to include, if you guys can use that.
If you do purchase a domain, that would mean a lot to me.
So what you would do is just search.
So let's say we wanted like news.
Obviously, news grid is taken, let's search for news grid site and click the search.
And as you can see, it is available, the dot com is available and it's 888 per year.
So pretty cheap.
And then down here you can see some other options like the dot net dot I, which is much more expensive,
dot org, dot IO and then there's a bunch of other ones down here.
Usually I would suggest if it's a if it's a real site like your company site, I would suggest registering
the dot com, the dot net, the dot org, all the big TLDs I would suggest taking because you want to
be in control of that, especially if your company gets big and stuff like that.
But I'm not going to actually register a domain because I already have some, so I'm just going to use
one of my my current domains.
So once you register and you go through the process, if you go to your dashboard, you're going to
see all of your active domains.
Now, the one that I'm going to use for this project is this app demo 112 dot com.
So I'm going to go to manage and this is going to bring you to basically the control panel for that
particular domain.
Now, before I do anything here, we're going to go back to Fi.
And step two is you can see is set up a custom domain and you're going to put in the domain you want
to use.
So I'm going to say W WW dot app demo 112 dot com and click verify already has an owner.
Is it you.
Yes add domain.
All right.
So now here says by default your site is always accessible subdomain.
So it's still going to be accessible through the net subdomain, which is this crazy domain here.
Now, there's a few things we need to do to connect app demo one 1202 to our account because if it just
let us do it, anyone could take any domain and connect it to that, to that website.
So I'm going to go to this this documentation page here, this custom domains documentation and scroll
down.
And this basically tells us what to do, but it's kind of long winded.
So I'm going to go to let's see, where is it right here so we can use.
We can use Natalya Fi's built in DNS, but I'm not going to do that.
I'm going to use this method here.
It says, Create an A record pointing your root domain to our load balancers IP address, which is this
number here, 104 1981452.
So this is an IP address.
Remember, we talked about this a long time ago, so we're going to copy this, this load balancer IP,
and we're going to go to our domain panel and go to advance DNS.
And remember, it said, create an A record.
So down here you can see it says Add new record.
I'm going to click that and I'm going to choose a record for the host.
We're going to put the at symbol, meaning just the root, the root of the domain.
And we're going to paste in that IP address and then click the check mark.
All right.
And then the next thing we need to do is add a new record of a C name.
So we're going to say C name and we're going to point W WW to whatever your net ified domain is, which
mine is this right here.
So yours will obviously be different.
So I'm going to grab that and I'm going to put that in here inside the C name and we're going to click
the check.
All right.
Now, this stuff up here, I'm actually going to delete.
The stuff that was already here.
Okay.
So we just have our a record and see name record now.
If you needed to have an email addresses with this domain, you would find a separate email service
and you would have to use what's called an MX record.
But I'm not going to get into this in in this video, in this course.
We just want to deploy this website so we have this stuff done.
So let's go back to our domain management page and let's reload.
And you can see now that check, check status thing is gone and these are now green.
So I don't know if it's going to work yet.
Sometimes it takes a little while to propagate, but let's try it out.
We'll go to WW W Dot App Demo 112 dot com.
There it is.
So it's as easy as that to create our domain.
All right.
And as you can see, it's HTTPS and this is all free.
Didn't pay a dime.
Didn't put any credit card information in.
Nothing.
So it's a fantastic service, really.
So if we go back to overview, everything is done, everything is deployed.
We have our form.
Just to test that out one more time, we'll go down here.
I'll just say Brad at Gmail and subscribe back to site.
We'll go back to our panel here and reload.
And if we look at the form submissions, you can see Brad at Gmail.
So that's it.
Our website is deployed and that's that.
All right.
So I'll see you guys in the next video.