All right, so now it's time to actually upload our website.
So if we go to our domain name, obviously yours is different, but mine is edge ledger dot net.
We're just going to see the in motion just placeholder.
So we obviously want to replace this with the website that we built.
So we're going to go down to where it says files and we want to click on FTP accounts.
FTP stands for file transfer protocol and it's an Internet protocol that's used for file transfer.
That's I guess that's the easiest way I can put it.
And right here we can put in just like with the email accounts, any name we want, I'm just going to
do Brad and it's going to be at edge ledger dot net.
Yours would be different obviously.
And then a password.
So I'll just put in a password here
and this is really important.
So the directory by default, it's going to put it into this this FTP account will go to just a separate
folder called Brad, which is not very useful.
We want to actually go to the root of the of the website so that we can access the root page here.
So we're going to just clear all of this out like that.
And you can also set a quota if you want and upload quota, but we're just going to keep unlimited and
then let's click create FTP account.
And now that's been created now to access our file, we need to we need to add an FTP client and I would
highly recommend file zilla.
So if we just search for file zilla, it's going to be this right here file zilla project dot org.
And you want to make sure you get the client, not the server.
The server is if you want to have your own FTP server, so you just want to click download here and
download and it's for Mac Windows Linux, it's cross-platform.
So just grab that once it's installed you can open it up.
I already have it installed, so I'm just going to open it up here and you're going to see you're going
to see something like this.
And over here on this side is your local machine.
As you can see, it's showing my desktop right here.
These are the folders I have on my desktop, which includes the Edge Ledger website that we built.
So if I go in there, you'll see the HTML file or CSS image javascript.
DataStore is just a hidden mac file, so don't worry about that.
If you're on Windows you won't even have that.
But what we're going to do now is log in to our website through FTP.
So up here in the host we want to put our domain name.
So I'm going to use edge ledger dot net and then the username is going to be whatever your FTP account
is, mine is Brad at edge ledger dot net.
And then the password that we used.
What was it?
And then port, you can leave that blank.
The default port for FTP is 21, but if you leave it blank, it's still going to use 21.
So we don't need to put it in and then click connect and you might get a box that says like authorize
or something.
The first time you try to log in, just say okay or authorize or whatever.
Now what we're looking at here is the root of our entire server, or I should say our count.
And the place where you want to go to for your website is public HTML.
This public underscore HTML.
This is our actual website.
So if we go into there, what we're going to see is a couple of files and the default team so it can
be HTML or FTM.
That is the the landing page that we see the coming soon page.
So what we want to do is delete everything in here.
We're just going to delete all of this.
So we'll say yes to the confirmation.
And then if I go back to Edge Ledger dot net and reload, we're just going to see this this blank index
of so there's no files here.
So we want to go to file zilla and just bring all of our website files, not the DD's store, but our
website files right over.
We can just drag and drop and it's simply going to upload them to our host.
So it's all done.
So there's only a couple of files, so it doesn't take long.
And then if we go back to our domain and reload, there's our website.
So our website is now live on the Internet.
And it's easy as that.
Now, FTP is when you start to get into application development.
When you're building these larger apps, FTP is not really efficient.
It's very slow.
You'll probably want to start to learn about Get and using SSH, using the control panel, stuff like
that.
But that's later on down the road.
For now, if you're just building small business websites, HTML, CSS, a little front end JavaScript,
I mean, FTP is fine.
So now that you know how to purchase a shared hosting account, create email accounts, create FTP,
upload your site.
In the next video, we're going to start to learn more about CSS.
We're going to start to learn about transitions and stuff.
We're going to start to look at the grid system and then we're going to build some more projects.
I'm also going to show you how to deploy to a static host called NetFlow Phi a little later on.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next section.