Okay.
So now we want to start on our cases, which is basically our photo gallery section and also the blog
section.
So let's go into our HTML and under the solutions, let's say cases and we'll have a section.
We're going to give this an ID of cases because it's part of the menu and then a class of cases.
And we're going to use a class called Flex Grid and also a class of section padding.
Now in here, we're going to have a header with a class of section header.
And headers don't have to be just for the main website header.
You can use them for articles or for whatever.
And then here we're going to have an H for and say this is what we do.
Underneath that will have an H two and let's say business cases, then a paragraph and we'll do law
M ten here.
So that's our header.
Now underneath that we're going to have our row.
So class of row and then a column.
Column.
So within each column, we're actually going to have two images.
So let's have our first image here, which is going to be, say, images, slash cases, and then cases
one, and then the second one will be cases two, and then we'll just grab this column.
So we're going to have four columns.
So that's one, two, three, four with two images each.
So this will be image three or cases three, four, five, six.
Seven and eight.
So that should be it as far as the HTML goes here.
So we'll save that.
And if we take a look, we're just going to have large stretched out images and this is the header which
also we need to style.
So let's go into style, CSS.
And as far as what we need to do here, actually the only thing we need to do here is for the image.
I want to add a hover effect.
And set the opacity to let's do 0.7.
So we just have that hover effect.
The rest of the stuff is going to basically it's going to be for the header, the section header, and
then the grid.
So let's go into utilities because we're going to reuse these classes later.
Anything that we're going to reuse is going to go into utilities.
So let's do the section
header first.
So section header, we're going to add padding 30 pixels, let's display flex, but we're going to change
it to a column.
So Flex Direction column and we want to align everything to the center.
So align items to the center.
We want to set the justify content to the center and text align to the center.
So if we take a look at that, everything is now centered and then let's style the H two.
So section header H two, let's give that font size of 40 pixels and then let's add margin, we'll say
20 pixels on the top and bottom.
Now we also have a class of section padding, so I'm going to add that as well.
So section padding and let's do 20 on the top.
Yeah, we'll do 20, 20 left and right, 40 on the bottom.
So if we take a look good.
Now we want to do the flex grid class that we created that has a row and a column class in it.
So right here we'll say flex grid.
And we want to style the row.
So as a class of row and we're going to display flex and set the flex wrap and let's just say padding
for pixels on the sides.
So that's the row.
And then for the column, let's say flex grid column, we want these to have we want these to be 25%
each.
Because, remember, there's there's four images across.
I mean, there's eight images, but we have two in each column.
Whoops, that shouldn't be column two.
It should just be column.
So flex grid column, we're going to set the flex to a percentage.
So instead of like flex one or whatever, let's do 25% and make sure that we have a max width of 25%
so it doesn't go over that and then add padding on the sides for pixels.
All right.
Now we want to do so.
Take a look at this.
So looks pretty good, actually.
Yeah.
So we'll just keep that if we make this smaller, you know, the images get real small, but we're like
I said, we're going to add media queries later to stack stack everything on top of each other.
So that should do it for that.
Now, the next section is this blog section, which is very similar to the solutions.
So what we'll do is in our HTML, let's just copy the solutions section and paste that in here.
And this is going to be blog.
We're just going to change.
First of all, let's add an ID of blog because we have the menu pointing to it and then also the class.
Say blog.
And then we just have to change.
Basically change the content so the image here will be in home blog and then for the the text, it's
going to be formatted the same way, but we'll just change the actual content, let's say April 16,
2020.
So we'll just pretend that this is like a teaser for the first blog post or the latest blog post or
whatever.
And we'll leave this.
We'll just say, read our blog.
Now, I do want the image to be on the other side.
We could change the HTML like we could take this image, put it here, put the text here.
But I don't want to do that.
I'd rather just add a class of flex reverse.
So if I add that, let's go to utilities and four for flex reverse, we can just go.
So that's the that's flex columns.
Right.
So I'm going to go.
Up to the top here.
And let's say so if it's flex columns and it has a class of flex reverse, then we want the row to change.
You want to change the flex direction to row reverse because it's just going to switch it.
So if we take a look now, the image is on that side.
Now, I also want this to be a different color, which we made it really easy to do that because we
have utility classes for backgrounds, so we can simply change it to secondary or dark or whatever you
want.
So now we have that blue background.
So I mean, hopefully you can see the pattern here.
We just create these classes that we can reuse whenever we want these specific types of layouts.
So the next one is the team which again has a section header which is identical to this section header.
All right.
So that will make it easy to do that.
And then we just have these flex items so we can use the flex items class that we used here with the
icons.
So it makes it really easy to just keep adding sections.
So in the next video, we'll go ahead and get into those.