All right, guys.
So in this video, I want to take a look at nesting.
So we actually need some mockup to work with.
So this one here, I'm actually going to put in a header tag.
So we'll say header and we'll go ahead and move this up into the header.
And then under the header, I'm going to put a section and I'm going to give this, this section of
class of section and also a class of section, dash a and let's put an H three in here and we'll just
say section A and then let's put a paragraph and I'll do like Lord 30 and I want to also have just a
link, a read more link that we're going to style as a button.
So let's put an a tag with the class of now I'm just going to do BTN dash light, I'm not going to do
BTN and BTN light like I would before with CSS.
And then in here, let's just say read more and then I'm just going to copy this whole section and we'll
bring it down and we'll call this section B, so we'll change that class and change that to B and let's
change this button class to button dark.
All right.
So if we save that, it should look like this.
So we're going to head back into main access and let's just look at some some basic nesting.
So I'm going to put in my header here.
Now for the header itself, I'm going to set a background of the dark color and a color of the light
color.
And then let's just add a little bit of padding.
So we'll do one REM.
So we'll save that.
Now I want to align the H one to the center.
Now, normally what we would do is we would take a header and we would take h one and create our style.
However, with SAS we can go right in the header and we can do h one and we can set let's set text a
line to the center and if I save that it works.
Now this text center is only going to apply to the H one that's within the header.
If we if we put another H one, this is not going to apply to it because it's nested within the header.
And what is what's really nice about this, I mean, just having this, you might not see a huge advantage,
but when you start to nest a lot of stuff together, you can really see the benefit of it, but you
can structure it like your HTML.
If we look at our HTML, we have a header and we have an H one nested inside.
We look at our SAS, we have a header, we have an H one nested inside so we can structure it very similar
to the HTML.
So that's basic nesting.
Now I'm going to let's see, let's go to our section now we have a class of section and I'm just going
to add a padding here of let's do three REM, spread it out a little bit.
Now for the h3i want to say in all my section H threes, so let's go ahead and nest that.
Let's set the font size to two REM.
Now we can get creative here since we have some classes, we have section dash A and section dash B,
we can use an an ampersand as basically like kind of like a, like a wild card or like a placeholder.
I guess since we have session dash, what I'm going to are I'm sorry, section dash I'm going to go
within my section class here and I'm going to do ampersand dash a so what this ampersand represents
is whatever its parent selector, so in this case DOT section.
Now I want a style dot section A which is just right here.
Right?
So this is actually going to take this section, put it in this ampersand and then just add dash a to
it.
So let's say we want a background and this kind of stuff.
I mean, you don't have to do.
I like it.
I think it's organized.
You have everything in one place related to a section.
So let's do primary color for the background and color.
I'm just going to say white.
I'm going to show you something cool later on when it comes to text color.
Now, if I save this, you'll see that section A now has this styling.
So this ampersand is just replaced with this.
And at the same time, if I want to do section B, I'll go ahead.
Paste that in and we'll just change that to a, B, let's change this to secondary color and save.
And now Section B has that secondary color.
All right.
So I think it's just organized to have everything we want.
We're dealing with sections, have it all in here rather than doing, you know, section, section H
three, section A, section B, it's just all in here nice and encapsulated.
So I think it's a it's an advantage.
And I like to do things this way.
All right.
So that's basic nesting.
Now, we can also do like pseudo classes.
So for instance, let's say I'm going to change this later, but let's say our a tag, let's say we
wanted to do some styling here like color three, three, three.
So I save that.
You'll see.
Now the links are dark.
Now to add a hover, I could simply do a stamp colon hover.
Whether it's hover before or after any pseudo class.
I want to use first child, last child, anything like that.
And I'll set the color to I don't know, I'll just say coral.
So if I save that and now when I hover over it, you'll see that it's coral.
Now, in the next video, I want to do a little more with nesting with the buttons.
But I also want to show you how we can use inheritance.
We can actually extend other selectors or other styles.
All right.
So we'll get to that next.