All right.
So in this video, we're going to look at auto fit and Min Max, which can make your grid kind of responsive.
And it's good in certain situations, not so good in some other situations.
It's great for like image galleries, stuff like that, but probably not so much for just regular website
layout.
So we're going to create a new file here called zero for underscore min max dot HTML and let's generate
our HTML here.
Okay.
And I'm just going to copy the styling for the item.
And paste that in here and then in the body.
Let's put our parents and then we'll do item.
And let's do Time's four.
So we have four grid items.
So let's set display grid onto our parent element here.
And then we're going to set grid template columns and I want to set it to repeat.
And I want to set in here auto fit.
So auto fit.
And then instead of just setting a width here, I'm going to use min max, which is a minimum and a
maximum.
So it's going to take in those two things.
I'm going to say a minimum of 300 pixels, a maximum of one F, R, which is just the whole fraction.
So let's save this and let's open this up.
So immediately you can see that there is at this browser size we have two columns, right?
But as soon as I get to 300 pixels, which is our minimum, it's going to just go to they're going to
stack.
So it's pretty responsive.
And if I go bigger, you'll see we'll have three until it hits.
They hit 300 goes back goes to two bigger.
Now if we were to make this, let's do like 200.
And let's add in a bunch of items here and save.
So now you can see that it's it's pretty responsive.
It stacks here, but it's only good for certain types of content, in my opinion.
I don't use it for regular layout because if I wanted to have like, let's just, let's say I just wanted
three boxes, right where we have an icon, some text, it's like the features or whatever for the website.
I don't ever want it to be like that, you know.
So I like to have more control over it in media queries so that I can set it to be either three or stacked
like that.
I don't want this midpoint here, so it's good for some, some things, but not so good for others.
Image galleries, things like that.
It's really good for.
But I did want to just show you that.
But in the next video before we get to, I'm going to show you how to use media queries with the grid
as well.
But before we get to that, I want to show you something called grid template areas which are really
nice.
They allow you to basically map out your content visually within your CSS.
And I'll show you what I mean in the next video.