All right.
So now we're going to get into a property called grid template areas, which basically allows us to
visually map out the alignment of our elements through CCIS.
So let's create a new file here called zero five Underscore Grid Underscore.
We'll just call it grid areas HTML.
All right.
So I'm going to close that up and I'm going to paste in the body here and just go over it because it's
kind of a lot.
I don't feel like typing it out, but basically we have a main div here.
Let's just push this back like that.
All right.
So we have a div with the class of container that goes around everything and then we have a header which
just has an H one.
We have a section with the class of content and inside here there's an H three and a paragraph.
Then we have a side which we want to be our sidebar, and then there's three boxes and then a footer.
So I just want to lay this out like a very simple website where we have the header, the main content,
the sidebar, the three boxes and the footer.
And we're going to do this just using the grid template areas property.
So let's go up here and actually let's save it and open it first.
Everything is just going to be straight down, but we're going to set on the container.
We want to set a grid, so we'll save that.
Now here's where we want to put the grid template areas right in the in the parent.
So template dash areas.
And we basically, like I said, we want to map the map this out visually.
So the header, I want to go all the way across.
So I'm going to do header header header.
Now the reason I did it three times is because we're going to have three boxes that go all the way across.
So you want to have the maximum number of columns you have to have in every row that you do.
So that's our header row.
We don't need a comma.
The next one is going to be the content and the sidebar.
So I want the content to take up two of the three and then the sidebar will take up just one here.
The next one will be the boxes which we have box one which quotes so box one, box two and box three
and then the footer I want to span all the way across.
So we're just going to say footer three times.
I don't know why I keep forgetting the quotes.
All right.
Now, if I save this, it's going to it's going to turn into a grid, but it's not doing what we want
it to do because we haven't we haven't referenced these as grid areas.
So what we need to do is take each element and and assign it to one of these grid areas.
So we have a header with the class of header.
Right.
So I'm going to say class header and I'm going to assign grid dash area to header matching this right
here.
And if I save this, notice that now the header goes all the way across and you might not be able to
tell.
I'm actually going to just paste this in real quick, which is just going to add a border around everything
so you can see the actual outline of it.
Let's actually add a grid gap as well.
We can you can use all this stuff.
Even though we're using grid template areas, it still works like a grid.
So let's say grid gap one ram and save.
Oops.
What I do here, I forgot my semicolon.
Okay, so as you can see, the header spans across all three.
Now the section, the content area I want to be, I want to span two and then have the sidebar right
here.
So we have that set in the template areas, but we haven't assigned the grid areas yet.
So let's take the content and let's assign the grid area to content and then we'll assign the sidebar
class to the grid area of sidebar.
And if I save that, you can see that the content takes up two of them too.
And then the the sidebar takes up one and the heading is pretty much in place, but we have to add that
as well.
So we're going to take I'm sorry, not the heading the boxes, they say heading inside.
That's what confused me.
But let's take box one.
And let's assign a grid area to box one which pertains to this right here.
And then I'm just going to copy this down because we want to do the same with two and three.
Okay.
Save that.
No change.
But then the last one here, the footer, we want to go all the way across, which we specified right
here that it's going to.
But we need to assign the grid area so it has a class of footer.
And then we can simply say grid area footer and save.
And that goes all the way across.
Let's actually align that to the center as well.
So text a line center and we'll do the same with the header.
Very, very ugly.
But I'm just showing you how you can use these grid template areas to literally map out what your what
your layout should look like.
Now, let's say we wanted to change this.
Let's say we wanted to do let's actually change.
Let's have box three have its own its own entire row.
So I'm going to say this is going to be part of box two.
And then we'll go down and we'll say Box three, box three in box three.
So try to visualize what that's going to look like.
So I'm going to save.
And what happened is box one takes up one, box two takes up two.
You can see it's longer.
And then box three takes up basically its whole its whole area here, just like the header in the footer
does.
So you can kind of experiment with this a little, but it's just so easy to create layouts now as opposed
to having to float everything and clear them and so on.
Now, in the next video, I'm going to show you how to utilize media queries to make your grids responsive.