All right.
So in this video, I want to quickly talk about the different color types that are commonly used.
Now, I'm not going to go over all of them, but I'm going to go over the ones that you you'll see for
the most part, the most common types.
So let's create a file called zero for underscore colors, HTML, and let's put our boilerplate in here
and we'll go ahead and change the title to colors.
Let's add in our style tags.
And as far as the body, let's just put a couple of headings.
Let's do an H two here.
And an H three.
And then up in the style, I'm going to grab the H one as a selector and give it a colour property,
which is going to be the color of the text.
Now, as far as colors go, anything I'm going to show you you can use for the color property, you
can also use for the background color.
You can also use for a border, anything.
And the first type is, is a name.
So we can put like red in here.
So let's save this and let's run it with the live server.
So open that up.
And of course we have a red heading.
So this is a color name.
Now, in addition to common colors like red, blue, green, we have a bunch of not so common colors,
like, for instance, coral.
We save that.
You can see we get coral.
And in this code, if I just put any letter in like a G, it's going to show us all the different options
for the different color names.
If I put an A, you see all these different colors, we've aqua, aquamarine, azure B, all these beige,
blue, violet, burley wood, some really weird names.
But anyways, these are colored names.
So the second color type that we can use is in our ggb value.
So for the H two, let's say our ggb and this takes in three things three values red, green and blue,
and each value should be anywhere between zero and 255.
So if I do zero, that means that the value for red is zero.
Let's do blue zero.
I'm sorry, green zero and blue zero.
And if I save that, it's going to be black because we have no presence of red, green or blue.
Now, the highest you can go is to 55.
So if I say to 55 for four, the first one here and in V's code, it even gives us a little preview
here, which is nice, but if I save that, we get red.
Now, if I wanted it slightly darker, I could do like, I don't know, 210.
You can see now it's darker and let's say I want it to do all blue.
I could go to the last one here.
255 is the highest and it's, it's, it's blue as it can get really.
Now there's a lot of different color combinations.
Obviously, it can be anything between zero and 255 for all of these.
So if I do like, let's say 100 of green and maybe, I don't know, 20 of red and save, we get this
blue color.
Let's let's tone this down a bit.
We'll say like 120 and save.
And we get this color which is like a grayish blue and it gives you a little preview right here.
So just remember that all zeros is black.
And then if you do all 250 fives take a crack at what that's going to give us.
If all zeros are black, then oops, all 250 fives are going to be white, as you can see, and you
can't even read it because the background is white.
But as you can see, it is there.
So that's red, green, blue or.
Now the third type is the most common and the one that we'll be using the most.
And that's hexadecimal or hex, which is a base 16 number and it pertains to the composition of a certain
color in the RGV space.
So it's always going to start with a number sign and it's going to be six or three characters that are
going to be letters, letters and or numbers for numbers.
It's going to be either 0 to 9 or for letters it'll be A to F, so all zeros is going to be black and
then all FS is going to be white.
Now, just like our Ggb, we have red, green, blue.
In hexadecimal we have red the first two green, the second two in blue the last two.
So if I wanted red, I could do f f for red for the first two and then zero zero green, zero zero blue.
And that gives me red.
If I wanted blue, I'd put F for the last two.
Like that, and if I did fefe in just the middle, it would be green.
And then any combination of, of any of those.
So just like our GB, it's going to give us just a colour based off of the values of red, green and
blue.
Now obviously you're not going to remember all these different hex codes.
You may have some preferred colours that you use often that you'll remember, but there's there's plenty
of websites and software that you can use to, to reference different colours.
And I'm going to give you an example in a minute, but what you do want to remember is obviously black,
which is all zeros.
Now, when you have something that when you have a hex value that's all the same, you can actually
cut it down to three.
So three zeros is black and three FS is white.
You want to remember that?
And then anything else that's going to be all the same, like let's say three D's or three C's, it's
going to be a shade of grey because all the red, green and blue values are the same, same thing.
If we do like f four, three times, that's going to be some shade of of grey.
If we do e three, that will be a shade of grey.
As you can see, it's very light.
So some common ones that I use are three, three, three, which is almost black.
It's a really dark grey.
I think it's cleaner than using jet black, so I use it for a lot for backgrounds if I want a light
background, a lot of times I use F for like that.
So those are just some of the ones that I keep in mind as far as colour is like different blues or reds
and stuff.
I'll use a reference like this website here.
This is Colour Dash Dexcom so we just have a palette here of different colours.
These are just the latest favourite colours.
But we can go up here and we can use the colour palette.
But if I click one of these like let's say this blue right here, let's say we're building an application
or website, we like this blue.
If I click on that, it shows us the hexadecimal, the GB value and then other colour types as well
that I didn't talk about like h hsl hcv.
And you can use these in CSS, but I don't I and they're not that common.
Also, what's cool about this site is if you go down, you have a palette of different shades, different
shades and tints that have to do with this, this hexadecimal value, because often you're going to
want a colour palette or a colour scheme in your website or your application with colours that relate
to each other.
So you might have buttons that have this colour and maybe your background has this colour or something
like that.
And then down here you can see the percentages of our GB.
So this, this gives you a lot of information on different colours, gives you examples and CSIS, so
really, really helpful site.
I would definitely bookmark the site.
Another good one is HTML colour codes dot com.
And this one here, you can see we have a colour palette.
We can just kind of slide and it gives us the hex value, the GB, the HSL.
So this is a pretty cool site as well.
Down here we have a colour chart we can click and it shows us in the header the different values.
All right, so you'll learn more as we go along.
But I just wanted you to understand these these three different types of colours that we can use in
CSS.
And of course you can use colour names.
I prefer hex.
Like if I have to make something white or black, I'll use the hex value.
A lot of people have asked me why?
Why don't I just use white or or black?
But I like to be consistent.
I don't like to just have I don't like to have colour names mixed with hex values.
It's just kind of just it's just my thing.
But you can do it any way you want, so just.
Just keep that in mind.
Everyone's different.
Everyone does things differently.
All right, guys.
So that's it for this one, and I'll see you in the next video.