All right, guys.
In this video, we're going to take a look at CSS variables also called custom properties.
So in documentation, you might see them as custom properties, but most people call them variables
because that's what they are.
They're just placeholders for values.
So let's create a new file called zero six, underscore variables dot HTML, and we'll put in our boilerplate,
let's say, CSS
variables and let's put our style.
I'm going to just close this up and in the body, we're not going to have too much here.
We're going to put a header and the header will have in each one.
We'll just say CSS variables and outside the header let's do a container and it's going to have two
divs.
So class of box, let's do a class of box dash and then money sign and then let's times that by two
and enter and each one is going to have let's do an H three, we'll just say heading paragraph, we'll
do lorm 15 doesn't really matter what the content is.
So I'm going to copy the H3 in the paragraph and put that in this div as well.
And let's just move this back and open this with live server so it should look like this.
And we're going to add some, some base styling here before we get into variables.
And I know a lot of this stuff is repetitive, but it's good to keep typing it out because you get more
familiar with things.
So we're going to add a reset of so margin zero, padding zero and the body just want to make it look
somewhat decent.
So we're going to do a font family of aerial.
I wish Ariel was the default font for browsers, not times New Roman because it just looks horrible
or some kind of sans serif font.
So let's do a line height of 1.4 and let's do a background of light gray.
All right.
So I'm going to save this.
Now, before I move on to styling this other stuff, I'm going to show you how to create a variable.
Now, you need to define a scope for your variables.
Well, actually, you can define them right inside here.
If we wanted to, like, I could go right above and I could say, Dash, dash.
This is how you format the variable.
Dash, dash.
And then name it.
So I could say, let's say light dash color and set it to f four, three times like that.
And then I could use the variable right here by using the var keyword, opening up some parentheses
and then putting in dash dash light color.
You'll see in V's code we'll actually get a dropdown with with the options.
And if I save we get the same result.
So this is how you can define a variable.
Now, usually you're not going to define it right in the same right where you're using it.
That kind of defeats the purpose.
I like to use variables, so I have a single place in my CSA, in my stylesheet that I can update,
like primary colors and stuff like that.
So what I'm going to do is just take this, just cut that out, and then I'm going to go up here and
I'm going to define a scope to define my variable in.
Now, since I used it in body, I could just do body like that and then put in the variable, but I'm
going to put it in the root, what's called the root scope.
So we do colon root.
So any variable that you create in the root scope, you can use anywhere in the stylesheet.
So if I save this, you can see that this still works.
All right.
Now, what I usually use variable variables for is primary color, secondary color.
And then you usually have some kind of light gray at least, at least when I build sites.
Otherwise, I have some kind of light gray, sometimes a dark gray, sometimes a really like a black,
almost.
And I put these into variables because I might use them over and over.
And then if you ever want to change it, you don't have to go to each instance of that color and change
it.
So let's create a primary color.
And for the primary color, I'm just going to do steel blue and then let's do a secondary color because
usually you'll have kind of a color palette to your your UI or your website and I'm going to do sky
blue.
So we have a primary color, a secondary color and a light color.
And then we're going to go down here and add some, some more styling.
So let's go header.
And for the header, I'm going to set a background color and I'm going to set that to the variable of
primary color.
So if I save that, we get the color.
I'm also going to change the text color to white.
All right.
And then let's see, let's let's text a line to the center and then I'm going to add a bottom border.
Actually, I'm going to go right here and I'm going to say border bottom, let's do five pixels, and
then I'm going to use the secondary color.
So var dash, dash secondary color solid and we'll save.
All right, now let's do the container.
The container is actually going to be a Flexbox.
So we'll say display flex.
It has two items in it.
So those are going to be side by side.
And then in the container, I'm going to add.
Let's see, let's do margin auto and then let's add a max width.
And this is some this is something I may put in a variable as well because if you want to for some reason
change the width of the the interface of the website, you can easily do that up here.
So I'm actually going to go right here and say max width and let's set it to 100 pixels and then we
can set that right here by saying var dash, dash, max width.
Now if I save it, I shouldn't be able to go past 100 pixels.
And if I wanted to change it, I could just very easily just change it to like 960 and now you can see
it gets it gets thinner.
Now the boxes I want to have the the primary color as well.
So let's go box and let's say background color and we'll set that to var dash, dash, primary color.
And let's do the same thing with the board or bottom.
So border bottom.
We're going to set to five pixels.
We're going to use the secondary color and solid.
Okay.
Let's change the color to white.
You could even put the text color in a variable if you wanted to.
You can put whatever you want into variables, but sometimes it just doesn't make sense.
It really makes sense when you're going to be reusing it or if it's something major, like the width
of the the layout or something like that, at least in my opinion.
And then let's just add some padding here.
We'll say one REM margin, one REM, and we'll save that.
And now you can see that it has the same colors as the header.
All right.
So what's great about this is if I want to change, let's pretend that this is a whole website and we're
using these variables all over the place.
So we have like seven, eight, nine instances of the primary secondary color, light color.
We can now easily change this.
So if we wanted to change it to like, I don't know.
Dark, dark gray and then maybe like light gray or something like that, that might look a little weird,
but we'll save it.
And now the whole thing changes.
So it's very convenient to use variables for colors and then things like widths and layout and stuff
like that.
So another thing that maybe we can do is is the width of the flex boxes.
So if we actually let's go up here and let's set dash dash box one width, we'll set that to one and
then dash dash box to width, we'll set that to two.
And then let's add the box one class and we'll say, What do we do in here?
We're using Flex so we can say, var dash, dash box one width.
Copy that down.
We'll change this to two, box two and swap and save.
Whoops.
What I do, just delete everything and save.
And now you can see that there's a different layout here and now we can easily change this.
If I wanted to do maybe three here, save that, that gets that gets bigger.
If I want it to do maybe one and three here now, I can easily change the layout with these variables.
Now everything is in.
All the variables are defined in the root scope.
But again, you can, for instance, the boxes.
If we want, we can say dot box and we can move these.
Into here, since we're not going to be using these variables anywhere else except for the box scope.
Right?
So if I save that, that's still works.
Now, if I move the max width into the box, that's not going to work.
So if I stretch this out, you'll see the max width doesn't work anymore because it's in the container.
I could put this in the container scope like I could do dot container and put that in, but that's something
I would I'd keep in the root because it's like a main just a main part of the site.
All right.
So that's pretty much it, guys.
I mean, like I said, I mostly use it for primary and secondary colors, things like widths.
But yeah, we'll be we'll be using variables throughout the coming projects and that's it.
I will see you in the next video.