All right, guys.
Now we're going to look at some tags that have to do with topography.
Some of the stuff we already looked at, like like the H one tag, which is a heading tag.
We'll look at some of the other headings and also paragraph and the strong tag and stuff like that.
So let's create a new file here called zero four Underscore Topography dot HTML.
And I'm going to show you some other stuff as well, some little tips and tricks when it comes to VS
code.
So let's put in our our boilerplate, which is we'll do exclamation tab and that puts in all of our,
our structure here.
And for the title, let's change this.
We'll just say like headings, paragraphs, typography.
Oops.
And then we're going to go down to the body here and I'm going to put a comment.
Now, if you want to just put a comment like an empty comment, you can just do control and then the
question mark or the forward slash key, and that will put in an empty comment.
It might be command and that key on a mac, I'm not sure because on my mac I actually switch the control
and the command keys.
So when I say control, it might it might be command on a mac, I'm not sure.
So let's go ahead and just put in headings here.
And another tip, if you want to go to the next line, obviously you can go to the end here and you
can hit enter.
But if you're in the middle here and you hit enter, it'll do that.
If you want to have a clear new line and you're in the middle, you can hold down control or again might
be command and then enter and it'll create a new line.
No matter where you are here, it'll create a new line if you hold down control.
So keep that in mind and I'm going to give you these little tips throughout the course, because I think
that it really helps you write your code in a more efficient way, in a much faster way.
All right.
So let's, let's put some headings in here.
So H one, I'm just going to say heading one and I'll hold control and enter to go to the next line.
Let's do H to tab heading to oops h three.
Heading for what else we got heading five.
It goes up to six.
So h six.
Heading six.
All right, so let's save this and let's open this up with a live server.
I may have to close some of your other tabs and this is what it's going to look like.
So this is H one, it's going to be the largest and then it goes smaller and smaller and then H six
is going to be the smallest.
Now you can change the font size through CSS.
You can do whatever you want through CSS.
But by default H one is going to be the largest.
Now, a little tip or some advice that I would give is, is you usually only want to have an H one,
H one per page because the search engines actually look at this.
And you want to have like you want to describe whatever the content is.
For instance, if it's a blog post, you want to have your your blog post title in the H one and you
can have I mean, you can have multiple H ones, but it's good practice to just have one per page and
then these other ones you can have as many as you want.
Say you have a role of blog posts.
Maybe you have an H three for each title.
So I mean, it's not mandatory, but I would suggest using 1h1 per page if possible.
So those are headings.
Let's go ahead and look at paragraphs.
We've already done this, but it's just a P tag.
Now I'm going to give you another tip here with Emmet.
We can generate some dummy text if you need just some text to kind of fill as a placeholder, you can
do lorem r m and then hit tab and it'll give you a paragraph of dummy text or filler text.
And if you want to specify a certain number of words, like let's say we want a ten word sentence or
paragraph, we could do lorem ten tab and it'll give us ten words we could even do, like lorem 500
and it'll give us 500 words I'm going to do, let's say 100 and just generate some text.
And if I save this and we go and we take a look, you'll see that we have this paragraph of 100 words.
Now, inside the paragraph, I'm going to add, we'll just go anywhere.
It doesn't really matter.
And I'm going to put in a strong tag now with VTS code.
Once they put the beginning tag in, it adds the ending one automatically.
So I'm just going to just cut that out and put that over here and then anything that's within here is
within this strong tag.
So let's save this and go back and notice that it's bolded.
So by default it'll be bold, but with CSS you could change the styling of this strong tag to be a different
color or to be bigger, bigger font, whatever you want to do with it.
But it's made to make it stand out.
And at the same time you have the emphasis tag, which is the M, so let's say M.
And I'm going to just put the ending tag, let's say, down here.
And if we save that, we take a look by default it's going to be italic.
It's actually this right here.
So you can see that the text is italic, which again you can change within CCIS and we're going to get
into CCIS in the next section.
So that's strong and emphasise.
We also have the line break which I showed you in one of the slides.
It's one of the self closing tags.
So let's say we want a space right here without adding a new paragraph.
If I just do this and save, it's not going to reflect that in the browser.
This is only in the editor.
I can put a million spaces here and save and it doesn't show in the browser to actually have a line
break without adding a new paragraph.
You would add in a bar tag.
So I'm going to go right here and put in a bar tag.
So what that's going to do is it's going to knock this on to the next line in the browser, as you can
see right here.
If I wanted it to go down again, I could add in another bar tag.
I'm just going to put a comment here.
So if we have to line breaks, you'll see that it pushes it down again and I can push it down as much
as I want.
And since it's a self-closing tag, you could either do this format or you could do that.
So both of these are going to work.
As you can see, I tend to use this just the HTML five, but sometimes I use a Visual Studio code extension
called Prettier, which will auto format your code and it adds the slash automatically.
So if you've watched some of my other videos and I have the slash, that's because I'm using Prettier
and I might introduce that extension to you guys later.
Now, in addition to the bar tag, we have an air tag which is a horizontal rule.
I'm actually going to put that let's see, we'll go right here and let's say horizontal rule and what
this does the air tag is it it does a line break, but it also creates an actual line.
So if you check this out, you can see it, put a line across the screen.
So that's a horizontal rule.
Now, if you've studied HTML before, especially if it was a while ago before HTML five, you might
have seen tags like the bold tag.
So if we put a B here, you might have seen stuff like this.
So if we actually take a look at this in Chrome, you'll see that it actually is bold.
But the bold tag along with the eye tag for italics and stuff like that, the U tag for underlying.
It's all been deprecated because HTML is not meant for styling and this strong tag replaced the bold
tag.
Because the strong tag is a semantic tag.
It doesn't necessarily mean it's bold, it just means that it should stand out in some way.
But we leave it up to the CSS to to say what that way is, even though it bolds by default.
And that's kind of hard to understand.
It did confuse me in the beginning when HTML five came out, but just know that we don't really use
this anymore or the you or I think there was se for strikethrough although we do have a semantic tag
for deleted text which does by default add a strikethrough.
So let's say we do Del and we're going to wrap this text right here.
So this is actually a semantic tag.
So we'll save this and take a look and notice that it does add a strikethrough, but it doesn't necessarily
mean that it has to be strikethrough.
We can change that in the CSS if we want.
Maybe we want it to be highlighted with a yellow background or something like that.
It doesn't necessarily mean strikethrough like the SE tag did.
They took that out of HTML five or deprecated it.
All right.
So in the next video, we're going to take a look at links, hyperlinks, and we're going to also look
at embedding images into a Web page.