All right, guys.
So we finished the index page here in terms of the desktop view.
We will do some stuff, you know, for a responsive design later.
Now we're going to move to the about page.
So in this code, we're going to let's actually create a new file in the dist folder.
You want to make sure you're in the dist folder and we're going to call this about HTML.
Now what I'm going to do is copy everything from the index and then get rid of most of it because there
is some stuff here we need, such as all the head head data.
I'm sorry, head head mark up here as well as the footer and also some of the stuff from the header.
So as far as this goes, is this this can all be the same actually.
We can change the can go ahead and change the title here to about me and then let's delete everything
from section A down to the top, down to section C.
So we want to leave the footer there.
We also want to leave the reference.
Actually, I'm sorry, we want to delete the reference to the typewriter script because we no longer
need that.
That's only on the home page.
And let's see in the header, we're going to actually cut this down quite a bit.
So we want to change the ID now to head our inner.
We want to keep the container, we want to keep the nav.
That should all be the same, except we want to move the current class from home.
Now that we're on the about page, we want to move that to about K and then we can get rid of the whole
header content div right here.
You don't need that and that should be good.
Now if we save this and we go back and we go to about I'm sorry, that's, that's the finished product.
Let's go to a boat and now it looks like this.
So let's deal with the header inner.
Obviously the image is not showing here.
So we're going to jump into main dot seas and go up to where we have our header stuff.
So where it says header enter here where I'm actually going to copy the background image.
So I'll grab this background in height and in the header dash inner.
We're going to have the same background image, except I just want to change the position a little bit.
Instead of center right, I'm going to do 20% on the x axis and then let's do 30% on the Y just to kind
of move it a little bit, just so the head of the guy isn't covering the logo or anything.
And then the height, I'm just going to set to 5.5 REM.
And then I also want to have a border, a border on the bottom to kind of separate it from the rest
of the content, which will be three pixels solid and I want to make it the main colour.
So if we save that and we go back, it's going to look like this.
So let's see.
Now we want to deal with the rest of the about content and we're going to start with this area.
So this is going to be about a it's going to be a section and I want to use grid template areas.
So we'll have like the bio I'm sorry, the bio image, the bio and then award one, two and three.
So let's go to about HTML.
We'll go directly under the the header here and let's just say section A, I guess it's the info.
So we're going to create a section and let's give it an ID of about since we're on the about page and
then a and a class of text, class of text dash center and let's do P three for some padding.
We also want a container to move everything to the middle.
We want a title.
So section dash title.
And we're going to say about me and let's do bottom line div.
Okay.
And then we're going to do a paragraph with the class of lead.
And we're just going to say, let me tell you a little about myself and what I do.
And then we're going to have a class of let's do info.
And this is where this this info here, let's call it about info.
This is going to be the grid and then the items will be the template areas that will assign within the
CCIS.
So let's first have our image.
I'm going to give it a class of bio dash image and let's give it a source of IMG.
You want to go img slash and it's the about JPEG.
All right.
And then underneath that, we're going to have a div with the class of bio.
And I want to give this a light background.
So I don't we didn't create the background classes yet, but we will do that.
So I'm going to do BG Dash Light because I wanted to have a light grey background and then let's do
an H for and let's say we'll just say your project is in safe hands and if you don't like this text,
you can change it.
And then I'm just going to do like, let's say lorem 30.
So underneath this div of bio and bg lt we're going to have our awards.
So let's do a class of award, dash one and we're going to use the award icon.
So we want to do AI with the class of face and then a dash award.
And then for the size we're going to do fa-3x and then let's put an H three and we'll just say award,
award one and then some text.
We'll do.
It's just not working.
I'm ten and I'm just going to copy the award div.
So we'll do two, three of them and we're just going to change the class here to two, this 1 to 3,
we'll keep the same icon.
Let's just change up this text.
So this will be award two, this will be award three.
So that should be it for this section.
So we'll save it.
And if we go back, this is what it's going to look like without styling.
So let's head into let's let's do our utility first, our background colors because I want to be able
to assign BG dark.
BG Light what else?
BG Main.
So we'll add those classes.
Let's put it.
Let's go under the buttons.
So go right here.
Backgrounds.
So let's let's take class B, g and then we're going to add in here ampersand dash main, which will
be BG Dash Main.
And then I'm going to set a background.
Of main dash color.
And then for the color, this is where we definitely want to use set text color, which is the function
that we created and we want to pass in the same as the background.
All right.
And then I'm just going to grab this and let's have four of these, except this is we're going to change
to dark.
I'm going to do control DX one, one time, two times and then just do dark.
Same thing here.
We'll do light and let's also do medium.
So that way we can have all the different colors as backgrounds if we want, and the text will adapt
to what it should be so it can contrast.
All right, so now we have that down.
So we want to start to deal with aligning all the stuff that's in this about info class.
So we're going to do this, let's see in our main source.
Let's go back below the home.
Uh, let's see.
There's a lot of stuff in the home, so that ends here.
So let's do about sections.
So we have about and then we want to style the A section.
So we'll do an amp, dash A and we have our about dash info.
We want to display that as grid.
So grid items except we're going to use grid template areas which we haven't I don't think we've used
in a project yet and in grid template areas is basically just a visualization of how you want it set.
So we're going to have the bio image and then the bio.
So the bio is going to extend further than the image, as you can see right here.
So we have bio and then bio bio.
So this is longer and then down below we want the three awards.
So let's go on to the next line here and let's do we'll just say aw1, aw2 and aw3.
So that's this is visually how we want it set up.
So we have to assign the grid areas.
Actually, let me just add a grid gap first.
Let's put a semicolon there and let's say grid gap and we'll do 1.2 REM.
Now under the about info, let's set up our grid areas so we have a class of bio image and I call it
image or img.
So right here.
But let's do.
Yeah, we'll keep image I guess so.
Bio image.
We want to set that grid area to the bio image grid area which is this right here.
We want to put this inside that or assign that to that and then let's also grab the bio.
So class of bio, we're going to assign that grid area to bio.
And then I'm also going to add just a border left just to give it a little bit of just a little bit
of style.
So we'll do three pixels solid and let's make it the main color.
Okay.
And then we'll just do some padding.
Let's do 0.8 REM.
So that's that.
Now we want to do the three awards.
So remember we have the class of award dash one which we'll set to the grid area of aw1 above.
And then I'll just copy this and let's do award two and let's do award three.
Now the icon for the award.
I just want to make it the main colour.
So I'm going to go down here and just grab all of them.
So we'll say award one.
To, uh.
I'm sorry.
I want to grab the icon.
So we want the class of face in each one face.
Don Award dash three f as.
Okay.
And then let's make the color, the main color, and I'm just going to add a little bit of margin one
rim.
Give it some space.
So let's go back and there we go.
So we set the bio to this grid area.
I'm sorry, the bio image, then the bio to stretch across basically two columns and then the award.
Each award goes in each column.
So I think we'll go ahead and stop here.
And in the next video we'll continue on with the progress bars and the rest of the about page.