All right.
So now we're going to deal with these buttons here.
So I'm going to just get rid of this a tag here with the hover.
I just wanted to give you an example of that, how to use pseudo selectors within your nested elements
or nested styles.
Now these buttons are going to share a lot.
So they're going to share like the padding and the border and cursor pointer, all that stuff.
What we were doing before is we'd have a BTN class with all that stuff and then also a BTN dark BTN
light that have to do with the colour.
So instead of doing that, I'm going to create a style, a set of styles to be extended.
So to do that we use a percent sign and we're just going to do BTN Dash Shared All right.
And then all the core styles that we want to share, I'm going to put in here like display inline block
oops let's do padding say 0.7 REM to REM.
Let's do what else?
Let's do a border.
None.
Pointer should be a cursor.
Whoops.
I spell that wrong.
Pointer cursor.
I don't know why it's not popping up.
Oh, I did it backwards.
It should be cursor pointer, brain fart.
Let's do text decoration none.
And let's just do a margin top one ram.
All right, now the styling here I want to use for both buttons, light dock.
And if we had other ones, I, I would want to use it as well.
So I'm going to go down here and let's do BTN.
Now we don't have a BTN class, we just have BTN light and dark.
However, I'm going to use this type of of nesting, I'm going to say ampersand light.
So this will pertain to any BTN light and I want to extend the button shared.
So to do that we use ampersand extend and then we want to put in here percent BTN shared like that.
All right.
And then I'm going to go right below it and do the same thing for dark.
So we want to extend and we want BTN shared.
All right, so I'm going to save this and it gets all of that, all these properties.
So the padding border, none.
Cursor, all that stuff.
What we want to change between these is the color, the background color, as well as the text color.
So I'm going to add background color for the light is going to be our variable of light color.
And then for the text or the color I'm just going to put in, let's do three, three, three.
So we want a dark text and then down here let's do
background.
Color and we'll set that to dark color.
And for color we'll say F, F, F, and I'm not using variables here because I'm going to show you in
the next section, when we deal with functions, we're going to have a function that automatically sets
the text color based on the background color.
So let's save that.
And there we go.
So now you can see we have the different colors.
Now, again, if you don't like this syntax here, you could of course instead just do like BTN dash
light and then you could just take this and put it in here and then you could do down here.
BTN Doc So I mean it's up to you what parts of SAS you want you want to use.
I like this because it's all encapsulated.
However, if you don't like the look of this ampersand or whatever, you can just do it like this and
you can still extend the button shared.
All right.
So hopefully that makes sense.
So in the next video I'm going to show you, I'm going to look at functions, mix ins, which are similar
to functions as well as conditionals and color functions.
And the reason I'm doing all that in one video is because we're going to create probably the most helpful
SAS function in my experience, which is one that will look at the background color of an element and
depending on the the brightness of it or the lightness or darkness, it'll set the text color automatically.
So if it's dark, it'll be a light text.
If it's light, it'll be dark text.
So we're going to create that function and do some other stuff as well.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next video.