Okay.
So we have the homepage done.
Now we want to move on to the about which is completely empty right now.
If I click on it, it's just a blank page.
So what I'll do is copy what we have in the index because we're going to be reusing some of this stuff
like the nav bar and the footer and also some of the stuff in the head.
So I'm just going to copy it all.
I'm going to just control A to select it all and then copy it control C and let's go into about HTML
and paste it in and start at the top here.
Now if you want to leave the same meta tags, description, keywords, you can do that.
We don't need this this link to the font.
Awesome, because we're not using any icons on this page so we can completely get rid of that.
We want to keep the reference to our style CSS because that's where all of our custom styling goes for
the title.
I'm going to change the welcome to about and then we have our header which had initially has the nav
bar and the showcase, but we're not going to be using the showcase.
So let's get rid of this whole div with the ID of showcase and everything in it.
So now the header only has the NAV and we want to move the current class off of the home link link because
we want that to go on to the about whatever the current page is is what we want highlighted and then
we can get rid of everything else up to the footer.
We just want to keep the footer, so let's save that.
And now if we click on a boat, we just have our header and footer.
So this is basically like the start for any page that we create on this website.
And when you start to get into like let's say PHP or some JavaScript frameworks, stuff like that,
you don't have to reuse, reuse your HTML like this.
You'll be able to like import files and stuff.
But that's, that's later on, that's after you learn HTML and CSS.
So let's go ahead and create this.
Where is it?
Right here.
We want we have basically two sections on the about page.
This is going to be the about info section.
This is going to be the testimonial section.
So right under header, I'm going to put in a section tag and I'm going to give it an ID of a boat dash
info.
And inside here we want a container because we want all the content to be contained and we'll have info
left in info, right?
So info left class and under that let's do info right class.
So info left is going to have a heading an H one and we're going to do a boat hotel beat.
And I'm going to wrap the text about in the text primary class inside of a span because I want I wanted
to have that that tan color.
So let's say class text primary and we want that span to just wrap around the boat, word like that.
And then underneath the H one, let's put a paragraph and let's do let's say lorem, we'll do lorem
30 and then let's do one more paragraph and let's do lorem 20 like that.
So that's the left side.
Now on the right, we're just going to have an image.
So let's put in an image tag and the source is going to be dot slash because we're looking in the current
directory and then we want to go into the image directory and we actually want photo to JPEG and for
the alt I'll just put in the word hotel.
So let's save that, see what we get.
So we have the heading, we have the paragraph, this is, this is info left and then info right.
We just have the image in here, which is the full size image.
As you can see, you can scroll away the way over.
It's actually a really large image.
So let's add our CSS to get this looking better.
So we'll go to our style sheet and let's go all the way down.
So put in a comment.
Actually, you know what?
Let's leave the footer at the bottom.
I always I like to keep the styling of the footer at the bottom, but let's put a comment here and say
about info.
We have our ID about dash info and let's see for about info.
Actually, you know what, I don't think we have any specific style for that just, just that particular
div.
What I do want to do.
Is I want to add a BG class, one of our utilities.
I want to use BG Light.
So in addition to the ID of about info, let's add a class of BG light and save.
And as you can see, it's very faint, but it is gray, it's not white.
And then for the info, right let's style that.
So about info and then there's a class of info, right?
And we want to float to the right and we want to set the width to half 50% and I'm just going to set
a min height of 100%.
And let's see for the image, this, this, this image is inline.
It's not a background image.
And by default, it'll break out of its container.
So usually with images you want to set the width to 100% because what it does is it contains it 100%
of its container, which in this case is info.
Right.
So I'm going to copy this right here.
Oops, I want to copy that.
And we want to say image.
We want to target the IMG tag and then we want to set the width of the image.
Actually, you know what I'm going to do 70%, so we'll say with 70%.
And we also want to display it as a block.
And if you remember back in the section where we talked about display block, display inline, I showed
you an example of an image and I wanted to align it in the middle, but we couldn't do margin auto on
the image because an image by default is displayed in line.
So that's why I'm going to display this as block because I want to set the margin to auto.
All right, let's save that.
Good.
Now we want to take this, which is info left and we want to float it to the left.
So let's let's go right here.
We'll say about dash info, class info, dash left and float to the left.
We'll set the width to 50% in the min height to 100% and save.
And there we go.
So now we have that floated to the left.
Now we need some spacing here, right?
Because it's right up against the header.
It's right up against the footer.
So a lot of times what I'll do is I'll add a utility class for padding and sometimes for margin.
So I'm going to go to my style, my utilities up here, utility classes that we've been creating and
let's create one for padding.
So we'll say padding, we'll just say padding and let's do some p y padding.
And what I mean by p, we want to make this a class.
What I mean by py is the y axis.
So padding for the top and bottom and let's do p one and we'll make that padding on the top and bottom
ten pixels oc we could even since this is only going to be one property, we could go like that and
copy it down and then we'll do P two.
Even if we're not using them right now, we could have them available for the future if we were going
to add more pages.
So let's say 20 pixels, 30 pixels.
So we have these different padding classes now and I'm going to save it and I'm going to go and add
one to the about info.
So right here about info in addition to BG LT let's do padding y-3, which should be 30 pixels on the
top and bottom.
Let's save.
And there we go.
So now we have some spacing here.
And then whenever we have a section where we want to add some padding to the top and bottom, we can
simply put in one of these utility classes.
So this is this stuff is is it's not mandatory.
I mean, we could put a put padding on the about info, but I think it's much cleaner to do it this
way because you have these classes that are available to you whenever, whenever you want, as opposed
to just having senseless padding and and background colors for every single element.
You just have these classes, you can add kind of like a framework.
So let's move on here.
What else did I want to do?
I think that's oh, we want to make the image circle or we want to add a radius to the image.
So to do that, we just need to go back to our CSS and go down to where we have our image, which is
we've written credit, quite a bit of CSS already.
So right here, this, this IMG tag, we just want to add a border radius to this.
So we'll say border dash radius and we're going to set it to 50% and save.
And now you'll see that it's a circular image.
Now, the last thing I want to do is make this heading bigger, because right now I have it as an H
one, which is the biggest heading, and I still want the text bigger.
So I'm going to add a class to it and I'm going to call this LX dash heading.
So we'll call the we'll do large heading and we'll use this as a utility because we can use it on other
headings as well.
So let's go up here and let's see.
We'll go right under the clear.
We'll go right here and say dot lx dash heading and I'm just going to set the font size to let's do
40 pixels and save and there we go.
So now the text is bigger.
So let's move on to the next section, which is going to be the testimonials.
And since we have the clear I mean, we have the floats here, we have to clear them.
So we're going to add a class of Claire, which we already have in our class, and then we'll add our
section with the ID of testimonials.
And I'm also going to add a class here of py3 because I want to add padding here as well.
Then we want our container so you can see the you can see the pattern here.
Just it's just sections stacked on top of each other.
And then we have our container to move the content in the middle if we want some kind of background
image or something, we put it on the section which I'm actually going to do.
So inside the testimonials, let's see, we're going to have a heading, let's do an H two.
But I'm also going to give this a class of L dash heading because I want it to be large and we'll say
what our guests say.
So those are H two.
Let's add testimonial.
So basically we're going to have two testimonials here and we're going to give them a class of testimonial
and also BG primary because we want it to we want them to have this tan background.
So let's do a class of testimonial.
And inside the testimonial we're going to have the image of the person.
So this is going to go to slash image and then let's pick person one JPEG for the ALZ.
I don't know, we'll just give her a name, we'll say Samantha.
And then under the image is the testimonial.
So it'll be a paragraph and let's do Lorem 40.
So that's one testimonial.
And I'm going to give the div here.
Also a class of BG primary which will give it that colour, that background color.
And then we can just copy this whole div, the whole testimonial and go on to the next down here and
just change the image to person two and we'll change the name.
Is it they both female Yeah.
So we'll just change the name to I don't know.
Jen So let's save and let's take a look so it doesn't look too good.
So let's go ahead and add some CSS.
So right below the where we did the about stuff.
Let's do ID testimonials and I want the height to be 600 pixels and let's give it a background image
of let's do a URL.
It's going to be outside of the CSS folder, into the images folder and then into and then we want to
test BG.
We don't want it to repeat.
We'll do center, center slash cover.
We want the whole image to show.
And then let's add let's do a padding top of 40 pixels just to push the heading and all this stuff down
right here.
All right.
So this is the testimonials, 600 pixels area.
And as you can see, everything is is busting out and it's because of the size of the images.
So I'm going to grab those images.
So let's say testimonial.
And then each one of those testimonials has a class of testimonial.
And then I'm going to grab on to the image and I'm going to give it let's see, let's do a width of
100 pixels and save.
Wait a minute.
Oh, this should be testimonials.
So now that the images are smaller, it doesn't bust out of its container anymore.
So let's see.
Let's let's do this.
Let's start from here and go down.
So this h two.
Oh, it's an h2i believe.
Say testimonials dot we want to target the H two and we're going to set the color to white and let's,
let's align it to the center.
So text align center and let's do padding bottom 40 pixels.
Why isn't that?
Or Oh, I put you see how I put this testimonial.
It's this h two is not within either of these divs and these divs have the class of testimonials.
So this is wrong.
We just want that.
Here we go.
So let's see.
So for the testimonial div, I want to add some styles for that.
So I'm going to copy this because that one's for the image.
This is for the actual div I'm going to set.
Some padding.
Let's do 20 pixels.
Let's do some margin bottom just to push push them down.
And if we added more testimonials with the with a div with the class of testimonial, this would apply
to those as well.
So let's see, margin.
Bottom 40 pixels.
Let's do over.
Actually, I'll I'll do that after.
Let's save that.
And then I want the image to float to the left.
And we don't have to make the text float to the right.
It'll automatically push the text over.
So in the image, let's say float left and save.
So now the image is float to the left and it's right up against the edge, though.
So I'm going to add some margin right to the image to push the text over.
So margin, right, it's 220 pixels.
Push the text over.
Let's also make the image rounded.
So we'll add a border radius of 50%.
And there we go.
That looks pretty good.
Let's see for the testimonial itself.
Let's give that let's give do a little bit of rounded corner here.
So the testimonial class, I'll do border dash radius.
Let's do five pixels.
So it has a little bit of a rounded corner and then I want it to be a little bit see through.
So in CSS we have a property called opacity where we can make the the element opaque, so basically
transparent and we can add a value from zero to or 0 to 1 where one is, is what it is now not see through
it all and zero is completely transparent.
So basically the higher the, the, the less transparent.
So I want to do 0.9 because I want it to be barely transparent.
So right here for our testimonial div, let's do opacity 0.9 and save.
And you can see you can barely see through it.
If I do 0.5 and save now you can really see through it.
But the problem here is when you when you add opacity to a div like this, it also makes everything
within it opaque.
So even the text we can't really read, the image we can see through and that's not really what we want.
Even if we wanted the background to be really see through like this, really transparent and we wanted
the text to be really readable, we would have to do something different, we'd have to add another
element and then make just the background see through.
So basically we'd have to add an overlay and I'm going to show you how to do that later on.
Not right now.
If you want it to be just a little bit see through, then you could add it to the whole div like we
are now because it's, it's such a small amount that the text is still readable.
The image, you can still see the image, but at the same time it's still a little opaque.
So I'll show you how to do an overlay later on.
So I think that's it.
Yeah, that looks pretty good.
Let's see, let's compare it with that.
Yeah.
So that's good.
Wait, why is it?
Did I miss some padding?
I think I did.
Uh, let's see.
Testimony.
Oh, I had you know what?
I had 100 pixels padding on the top.
There we go.
Okay.
So that's our Bo page.
It's I mean, there's not a ton of content, but I think it looks pretty good.
I think the homepage looks pretty good.
So especially if this is your first website.
In the next video, we're going to start on the contact page, which just has a form.
We have some icons and and that should be it.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next one.