Okay.
So now that we've done the home page, the about page, now we just have the contact.
So I'm going to copy everything on the about page.
It makes sense to to copy the about page because it has the nav bar without the showcase and stuff like
that.
So let's jump over to contact HTML and paste that in and let's just change the title to contact and
let's take the class of Current off of a boat and let's put that on to contact and then we can get rid
of everything down to the footer.
And we'll save and then we'll go to contact and we should see this.
Now, one thing that we need to grab is the font awesome link to this font, awesome CSS because we
are actually using icons here.
So from the index page in the head, I'm going to grab the link for font.
Awesome.
So this right here, I'm going to copy that and bring that over to contact.
Put it right above our link to our style sheet.
And that should be good.
So now let's go down below the header and we'll start to create our form.
So let's put in our section and we'll give it an ID of contact dash form and I'm going to give it our
padding class, our p-3 class and let's add a container.
Push everything to the middle.
Let's put an H one.
Let's use a class ll heading class.
So you see how we keep reusing these classes.
That's, that's the idea of a class and ID is more for identifying a section like we're doing here.
So hopefully that that starts to really make sense.
So this, this h one is going to say contact us, but I want the word contact to be that, that primary
color.
So we're going to put in a whoops, we want to put in a span with a class of text dash primary and we
just want to put this span on the other side of contact.
And then below the H one, we're going to put a paragraph and just say, please fill out the form below
to contact us.
We'll save that should look like that.
And then we're going to create our form.
So the form will, will go somewhere.
I mean, we'll just put like process dot up for now for the action.
But it's not we're not actually handling the submission right now.
And for the fields, we're going to have a name, email and message and I'm going to wrap the label
and input inside of a div with the class of form dash group.
So inside the form group we'll have the label, the for attribute will say name, name, and then under
that we'll have an input.
So let's give it a type of text and the name will be name ID will also be name, and then we'll have
another form group.
Actually, we can probably just copy this div, paste that in and this will be the email.
So for email we'll change the type to email.
That and the ID and then we'll have one more, which is going to be the message.
So paste that in and change this to message
message.
Let's take this another little little trick here.
Keyboard shortcut.
If you want to highlight something without the mouse, you can hold shift and I'll hit the back arrow
and you see how it's highlight.
If I go the other way, it'll highlight it so I can highlight name and then do a controlled DX to choose
the next version of name.
And I'm going to change it to message.
Except we want this to be a text area, not an input.
So I'll just take this and change it to text area and text areas have a closing tag.
So we just need to add that in there.
All right, so that looks good.
And then we just want our submit button.
So we're going to go below this last div here with still within the form we'll do button and remember
our class of BTN.
We want to use that on this button and we just want to give it a type as well of submit type equals,
submit and let's say submit for the text.
Go ahead and save.
Take a look.
It looks absolutely horrible.
So we have to add our styling.
So let's go to our style CSS.
I'm actually going to make this smaller so we can see it and we'll go below our testimonials, let's
say contact form.
So an ID of contact form, that's our section.
And then let's style the form group which wraps the label and the input.
And I just want to do a margin bottom just to push each field down.
So we'll do 20 pixels.
All right, then we'll do the label.
So contact dash form label and we want that to be display block so that it pushes on to the next line.
And then let's do a margin bottom of five pixels.
We'll save that.
Good.
Now let's do the input and the text area.
So contact form input.
We also want to do contact form, text area.
And let's put this on a separate line just to make it a little neater.
And we want a width of 100%.
We want it to go all the way across, save that, let's add some padding to make them thicker.
So we'll do ten pixels on all sides.
Let's do a border.
Notice the message has a thicker or a darker border.
We want them all to match.
So we'll do one pixel.
Let's do DX and solid and save.
Now the text area.
I actually want to be a little bigger.
I want to increase the height, so I'm going to take just the text area selector here and just set a
height of 200 pixels like that.
And notice that our button looks just like the other links that have the BTN class.
All right, now I want to show you guys that you see, when I when I click on one of these, it has
the blue outline.
We can actually change that color if we want.
This is something I haven't gone over yet.
So these are these are the focus states of these inputs.
So I'm going to actually copy this that the input and the text area selectors and I'm just going to
add on this pseudo selector of focus.
So we want to say in the focus state we want to set the outline to none and we want to set the border.
Color to that f right here f7c, z, 08a and save.
And now when I, when I click on one of these, you'll see that the outline is that same color.
So we can target that focus state and style it how we want.
So the next part we have is the, the, this part right here with the icons and this is going to resemble
the boxes on the home page.
We're actually going to use the box class.
So let's head over to contact HTML and let's create our section.
So we'll call this, we'll give it an ID of contact dash info
and I want this to have a dark background.
So we're actually going to also add the class.
Let's do class equals BG dash dark and inside the section we'll put our container and let's add our
boxes.
Now I'm actually going to copy from the index HTML.
Let's grab those, those boxes.
So let's see under features we have the div class box so we have three of these.
Let's grab all three, all these divs and we'll bring them to the contact, paste them right in there
and we're going to change great location to just location.
We're going to keep the same same icon, the hotel icon.
But I want to change this paragraph to be the actual location.
So we'll say 50 Main Street, Boston, Mass.
And the next one here, I'm going to change the the icon to a phone icon, which is going to be a phone.
And you can look up all these classes at font.
Awesome.
We're going to change this to phone or phone number.
And inside the paragraph, let's put a fake phone number.
We'll say 617555.
We'll just do all fives.
And then this last one, I want it to be the email.
So there's actually an icon called F a dash envelope and we'll change this h three to email address.
And then let's just add in a fake email address here.
We'll do like front desk at let's do hotel B t.co.
All right.
So we'll save that.
Now, these boxes actually have the the BG light.
BG primary.
We want to get rid of those because we want it to be just dark behind all of them.
So I'm going to get rid of that.
BG Primary, get rid of that class, but make sure you keep the box class and save.
And there we go.
Let's make this a little bigger.
Make sure it looks okay.
And that's our contact page.
So that's it, guys.
Our project is complete.
We have our little hotel website and hopefully you learned quite a bit from this project, especially
if you're brand new to HTML and CSS.
Hopefully you can see now how things come together because I know with the sandbox sections we just
kind of looked at at individual parts of HTML, CSS, and now we're actually putting it all together
to build something.
So what I'd like to start to do now that you know the basics, you know, HTML and the basics of CSS,
I'd like to get into more modern parts of CSS like media queries for responsive design, the grid system,
Flexbox.
Later on we'll get into like transitions and animation and then of course deploying a website.
So we have quite, quite a bit to do.
All right.
So that's it, though.
At least now, you know, HTML, you know the basics of CSS and we're ready to dive in more.