All right, guys.
So now we're going to take a look at media queries with the grid.
So let's create a file called zero six.
Underscore grid.
Underscore media queries dot HTML.
And we'll put our style tags.
So I'm going to create the the markup first.
So we're going to have a container of grid and then let's do an item.
And in H three inside here we'll just say heading and then a paragraph with the text.
We'll just do lorm 15 and then I'm going to copy this down.
I want four of them, so I'm going to do three more.
All right.
And we'll go ahead and save this and open it with live server.
So let's start off with adding a grid.
So we'll take the parent element and we'll set it to display grid and let's say grid dash template columns.
And we're going to do a repeat, let's say repeat for auto.
Okay.
So that's going to set them to basically a four column grid and we'll do a grid gap of one REM.
All right.
Now, the way that that this is naturally is it's just it's it's four columns, no matter what, no
matter how small.
And what I would like to do is have it so that when we get to a certain point, like maybe tablet size
seven, 68 or so, we change it to two columns.
And then when we get to mobile, it's stacked, meaning that it's just one column.
So this is pretty easy to do.
We can just add in media query.
So let's say we want this to be for Max with 768 pixels.
We need that.
And then we're going to simply take our grid element and we're going to say We want grid.
Actually, I'll just copy this here and let's say for max width.
768 we want to.
So we'll say repeat to auto.
Now, once they hit 768, you can see that it goes to two.
All right.
And then we'll just add another one.
So I'll copy this and we'll say at 500.
So basically smartphones.
I simply want one fr actually, you know what I'm going to do instead of auto, I'm just going to do
one fr like that.
So we get the same result on big screens and then basically tablet size and then we get to smartphone
sized stacks.
So it's as easy as that to use media queries with the grid.
Now we also have grid template areas which we went over in the last video.
So I want to show you what we would do in that case.
So I'm actually going to open up the file from the last video and just add to that.
So let's go ahead and open this with live server.
So right now, even if we go down to mobile size, that doesn't look very good.
So all we would have to do is add a media query.
So we'll say add media.
And I'm just going to do let's see, let's see what this looks like at like 768.
So it's okay that that's fine for like a tablet size, but for smartphones, we want to change it.
So let's do a max width of, let's say 500 pixels.
And what we would do is just change up the grid template areas.
So we'll take this and if we want to stack everything, we can simply have one column.
So we'll do header.
Content.
Oops I forgot to put the the select the selector which is going to be our container of grid.
Or is it.
Wait, no, it's container.
Sorry.
So container.
And then I'm going to paste that in and we'll say header.
So we only want one.
We want these to be stacked.
So header content and then we'll add in here sidebar.
We'll do box one, box to box three and footer.
So it's only one column.
And again, this is this is visually representative of what we actually want to display in our browser.
So let's save.
And now everything is nicely stacked.
So when it hits 500 pixels, everything stacks nicely.
So pretty easy.
And we're going to be getting more into this in our project, which we're going to get into in the next
section.