All right, guys.
So in the last video we started the about page.
So now we're going to move on to the progress section of the about page, which goes underneath this
info section.
So let's go to the about HTML and go down below the last section.
We'll say section B, which is the progress bars.
So this is basically like level of skill for four different technologies or topics, whatever it may
be.
So let's do section, we'll call this A boat dash B and I want this to have a dark background.
So I'm going to add the class of BG Dash Dock and p-3.
So let's do class container and H two with the class of section, dash title and let's say technical
skills.
And we're going to do the bottom line.
Oops go under that neath that.
So each progress bar we're going to have an H for for each skill label.
So let's say photography do photography colon and then under the H for let's do a class of progress.
Now within this progress class, we're going to have a DIV and I'm actually going to use inline style
here because we need to set the width.
So the style is going to be basically how how full the progress bar is going to be.
I'm going to say for this, it's going to be 100%.
So 100% full for photography.
Now let's copy the H four along with the div here and let's do two, three, four, five, six.
So the next one after photography, let's do Adobe Photoshop.
And for that, let's do 80%.
Okay.
And then for this one, let's do Adobe Illustrator.
And of course, you can change these up.
I just basically just thought of these randomly.
So let's do 70% and then let's do HTML and CSS.
Let's do 100% for that.
Let's do WordPress.
So WordPress will say 80% and then let's do Magento, which is an E commerce platform and we'll do 70%.
So if we were to take a look at this, you'll see that we just have we have a dark background and we
just have each label.
So let's go into our main dot success and it's up to you.
You could see the progress bars, I guess could be a utility if you wanted to use them other places.
But I'm just going to I don't plan on using them anywhere else, so I'm just going to put them in the
about Dash B section.
So I'm going to go under the Dash A here, which ends right here.
Say about B, we'll label this one as well.
So we'll do Ampersand B and then we want the progress class and I'm going to set the overflow to hidden
so that it stays contained.
And let's set a height of 20 pixels.
And then the background is the background is going to be the medium color, which is a gray.
Now the div inside of it with the style, with the percentage, with the width, with the percentage
is going to be the main color.
However, the empty progress bar is going to be the medium color.
And then I just want rounded edges.
So I'm going to do a border radius of five pixels and then let's do a margin bottom just to push them
down.
So we'll do 0.3 REM.
Now we want to focus on the div inside.
So we want to be within the progress style here and then add in our div.
So this is remember, this is the one with the the style, with the width.
We want the height of this to be 100%.
So it fills up, you know, vertically.
And I'm going to set the color to white in case we put any text in there and let's do a text, a line
center, and then we want to set the background color, which will actually be the color of the progress.
So I'm going to set that to the main color.
All right.
So we'll save that.
We'll take a look and there we go.
So that looks pretty good.
Let's add a little more to the margin bottom.
We'll do like 60.6.
Push it down a little more.
And that's how we can create progress bars.
So pretty easy.
You see these in frameworks like bootstrap and stuff, but they're actually pretty easy to create on
your own.
So the next part of the about page is going to be the logos.
So let's work on that.
We're going to go back to about HTML, close this up in that I don't think we have any more utilities,
but we'll come back to it if we do.
So under the section we just did, let's say section and this is going to be section C logos.
So basically like logos of like the technologies that this person has worked with, stuff like that.
So we're going to do Section.
Let's do an ID of about C and let's do a P Y for class for padding.
And I want a big light background and then we'll do a container and let's do a div with the class of
a boat dash logos, which we're going to use the grid for and then we just want our images.
So this is going to be image slash and then in their own folder called about logos and we're going to
grab the Envato logo and then let's paste this down, copy this down.
Four times next one is going to be WordPress.
Next one is WooCommerce, which is a WordPress plugin for eCommerce and then Magento.
All right, so that's our logos.
And if we take a look at it, they're just going to be giant.
They're going to fill up the whole section.
So let's go into our CSS and we want to work on C, so let's go outside of Dash be.
So we'll do ampersand.
Dash.
See?
And let's grab the boat logos.
Let's use a grid.
And let's set the grid template columns.
We have four.
So we're going to do a repeat four times one fraction and let's add a grid gap of two REM.
And then the image I'm going to take the image and set a width of 70 because 100 is a little too, too
much.
So we'll do width of 70.
And if we take a look there we go.
It looks pretty clean.
So next section is going to be the testimonials here.
So let's add those.
So we'll go back and let's go to a boat.
C Section D
testimonials.
Do a boat dash dx As far as classes, I'm just going to do a Pi Dash four and do a container.
I know this is very repetitive, guys, but it's good because you'll get it in your head, you know,
at least if you want to lay stuff out like this, which is what I would recommend, having just separate
sections, you know, using utility classes and so on.
So let's do H two with a class of section, dash, title and testimonials.
Okay, we'll do our bottom line.
And let's do a paragraph with the class of lead.
And I also want this centered.
So let's say take a look at what my clients say.
All right.
And then underneath that, we'll have our class of testimonials, which will be a grid.
So we'll have Divs and just a paragraph.
We'll do like form 30.
And underneath that, underneath the paragraph, I'm going to put a UL on unordered list and we're going
to put an ally with an image.
So this is going to go image slash, testimonials slash and then this is person one JPEG and then I'm
going to copy this div and we have four testimonials.
So two, three, four and we're just going to simply change the name and the image.
So this will be person to person three, person four.
All right.
Actually, you know what I forgot is the name.
So we also want to list item with the names.
So for the first one here, let's say Sam Smith and we'll say location, just say New York and let's
go here.
We'll say Sarah Williams, say Michigan.
Jill Johnson.
London.
And let's do.
I don't know, Steve.
Steve Thompson.
And let's say Boston.
So if we look at this without styling, it doesn't look very good.
So let's go ahead and jump into.
Main asks, and we're going to start to work on the D sections, so we'll go right under here.
So am DD and we're going to grab the testimonials.
So testimonials is going to be a grid.
And let's do a grid template columns again for columns.
Grid gap 0.5 REM.
Now let's style the UL.
So we want to make sure there's no bullets.
So list style none.
And let's do a margin top of one REM just to push it down a little bit.
I'm going to display it as flex and let's align items to the center.
Now for the paragraph.
Uh, let's see for the paragraph inside testimonials.
I'm actually going to put a border around the whole thing.
So one pixel solid and let's use the medium colour, let's give it some rounded corners.
So we'll do five pixels and then let's do some padding.
Padding will do 0.5 rem and then the image, obviously the images are giant.
So we're going to say width, let's do 50 pixels.
We want these really small height.
50 pixels.
Let's do a border, let's make them circle.
So we'll do border radius 50% and let's do let's move them over a little bit.
So margin, right.
We'll do 0.5 REM.
That's it.
Take a look.
Let's see.
That's not right.
Looks like the grid messed up.
What did I do?
Oh, I forgot.
Repeat.
And there we go.
So I think this page looks pretty clean.
Looks nice.
So that's that's it for the about page.
Next thing we're going to work on is the work page where we have all those the transition effect and
all that stuff.
So there's some pretty crazy CSS involved in that.
So we're going to start on that in the next video.