All right.
So in this video, we're going to talk about the box model and we're going to talk about margin and
padding, as well as what a CSS reset is.
We're also going to look at some of the default styling of the browser.
So let's create a new file here called zero six, underscore box, underscore model HTML and let's put
in our head body tags.
And for the title, we'll say box model, margin and padding.
And let's put in our style.
And then for the HTML, I'm going to put in a div with the class of box, which is just going to have
an H three, I'll say box one and then a paragraph with 20 words.
So alarm 20.
All right.
And then I'm just going to copy this down.
So shift option or shift alt and then down we'll copy it.
And let's just we'll just change this to box two and they both have the same class, which is which
is absolutely fine.
We're just going to style them the same way.
So let's save this and open it with live server, open it in Chrome and I want to open up our dev tools.
So on Mac, it's command option I on windows it's F 12 or you can use your your menu.
So remember, this is the HTML over here.
This is the CSS.
So I'm actually going to just click on the div right here, the first div which will give us the CSS
which by default just has a display block because remember divs by default are displayed as a block,
meaning they go all the way across.
And right here you're going to see a diagram of the box model, which makes it a lot easier to explain.
So there's basically four layers.
There's the element itself, which we can put a height and width property on by default.
The width is all is all the way across and the height is going to be however much content is in it.
If I add a bunch of more paragraphs, it's going to extend more or I can just set a height and see this.
Then we have padding, so we have spacing we can put here.
Then we have the border.
We looked at the border properties in the last video and then we have the margin.
Now the margin in padding, the spacing is some people get this confused when they first start.
But all you really have to remember is the margin is the outside of the element or the outside of the
border.
The padding is the inside.
So to give you an example, let me just add some styling for the box.
So we're going to say box and we're going to say background.
We're going to give it a color of light gray and then we'll give it a border, let's say two pixels,
gray, solid.
And we went over the stuff in the last video.
So now you can get a better picture of of the box model.
So we have the content, then we have the padding and then we have the border.
And then outside of the border is the margin.
Now notice that there's some spacing here, there's spacing here, there's spacing here, and there's
even spacing around the sides.
That's because the browser has default margin and padding on certain elements.
So if we grab the selector tool here and I hover over the H three, you'll see that there's some orange
areas here where the space is.
That's the margin.
And if I go over the the paragraph, we have some margin and even the body if I go right.
Actually, it's not going to let me show it.
But anyways, the body has some some margin as well.
So let's click on this, the three, and then over here you'll see the styling.
So this margin block start margin block end is basically margin top and bottom and it has a value of
one.
M and M is a relative unit.
It's relative to the number of pixels of the font size of its element of its parent container.
And if you don't understand what that means, don't worry about it.
If you want to see the computed pixels, you can actually click on computed and it'll show you that
the font size and the margin on the top and bottom for the H three is going to be it's 18 seven two
pixels by default.
If we click on the paragraph, you'll see that it has a margin on the top and bottom of 16 pixels.
If I click on the body, you can see it has a margin on all sides of eight pixels and there you can
see the orange around the whole body.
So these are all default browser styles and there's other elements as well, like a UL and unordered
list and in ordered list, they both have margin on the top and bottom and they have a padding on the
left of, I believe, 40 pixels.
So this is just stuff that that you're going to run into and you can overwrite those values.
Obviously, like I could set for paragraph, I could set margin to zero and get rid of that.
And I can actually show you that real quick.
So if I say box paragraph and set margin to zero and save that, we go back.
Now, if I you'll see that there's no orange when I hover over the paragraph and if we look at the styles
you can still see the default.
But this overwrites it what I just did.
Now if you want to take away all the default styling, you can do that with what's called a reset.
So I'm going to get rid of that what I just did and I'm going to create a CSS reset and there's different
ways to reset.
You can reset margin and padding font size borders.
There's actually like popular reset files that you can use.
Like Eric Myers has a reset file that's pretty popular, but the easiest way to do it is just to use
an asterisk which selects everything and then just say you want margin to be zero and padding to be
zero.
So we're just setting the margin and padding to zero for everything.
So let's save that.
And this is on all sides, top to bottom, left and right.
So if we go back now, notice there's no spacing anywhere, not even on the body, not even on the side
here.
And if I grab the selector tool, there's no orange, there's no green, which is padding, there's
just no spacing at all.
Now it's up to you on if you want to use a reset or not.
I do.
Sometimes it really depends on the layout, but if you do use it, you have to remember to add all of
your your your own margin and padding because now if I add another paragraph under this one, it's going
to be right next to it.
It's not going to have that that default spacing that the browser gives it.
Same with the heading.
Usually you'll want some space here.
It's not there anymore.
We'll have to create it if we're going to keep the reset.
All right.
So I just wanted to kind of explain how the default margin in padding works, also the structure of
the box model.
So now let's look at some properties that have to do with margin and padding.
So I'm going to add a width to the box as well.
Let's do with 500 pixels and let's say I want padding on all sides.
So I'm going to put a comment right here and I'm going to say padding on all sides.
So we would just use padding and then we could do, let's say 20 pixels.
So this will put 20 pixels on all sides.
You can see top and and notice the green one.
If I use the the element selector and we hover over it, we see the green, that's actually the padding.
And you can see that it's 20 pixels on all sides for both, obviously, because they're both they both
have the class of box, which is what we styled.
Now, when we add padding, if we if we keep the box sizing the way it is now, the box sizing property,
it adds to the width of the entire thing.
All right.
And to just give you an example, if I say padding 120 and we take a look, the width of this is no,
it's not 500 pixels.
It added to that.
It's 500 pixels plus the padding.
And that's not usually how you want to do it.
Usually you want to keep the.
With at the right width and then just add the padding.
So to do that, you want to add to the asterisk right here, a box sizing property and you want to set
that to border box.
So now if I save that and we go back, we still have 120 pixels padding, but the box is still 500 pixels.
It just pushes it inside as opposed to adding it.
So let's put that back to 20.
I just made it that big.
Just so just so you could tell that the width was larger.
So we'll put that back and the next thing I want to do is show you margin, because right now there's
no margin and these are kind of stuck together.
So margin is going to be spacing around the border on the outside of the border.
So let's add, let's say margin on all sides and we'll say margin 20 pixels.
And if we take a look and we use our element selector, see the orange, that's the margin.
The green is the padding, the orange is the margin.
In fact, if I click on one of the divs and we look at the box model, it'll show us all the values.
20 The border is two pixels, the padding is 20 and then the width here.
So just remember that margin outside padding inside and it doesn't matter if you have a border property
set or not.
It's still it's still going to be relative to the box model.
All right.
Now, these properties that we've used, map padding and margin with just one value, it's putting the
same on all sides.
But there may be cases where you want different values on different sides.
So I'm going to go down here and let's say padding per side so we can use padding top.
So let's say on the top we want ten pixels and let's do padding.
Bottom.
Actually, I'm going to do top.
Let's do right.
And I'm doing this in a certain order for a reason and I'll show you that in a minute.
So padding, right?
Let's say we want 20 pixels.
Let's do patting bottom.
We'll do ten just like the top and then left.
We'll do 20.
Just like the right.
Now, this is going to overwrite this, and that's something that I really haven't talked about yet.
When you have the same properties, the the ones that are further down are going to overwrite the ones
that are further up.
So all this padding here is going to overwrite this one.
So even if I leave them without commenting, the so this is going to take effect.
So let's take a look.
And you can see now there's less padding.
If you look at the green, there's ten pixels on the top and bottom, there's 20 on the left and right.
So if you want to do this but you don't want to have four different properties, you can you can shorten
this just like with with most cases, like you saw with the with the border and the background, there's
there's short hands.
So let's say padding, shorthand.
Now, when we do this, there's a certain order to the values.
So it's going to be this just like I did right above top right, bottom left.
That's why I did it in this order.
So if we say padding, it's going to be in that order.
So let's do top ten pixels, right?
20 pixels, bottom ten pixels left 20 pixels.
So if I save that and we take a look, it's going to be the same thing.
So this is just a shorthand for this does the exact same thing.
Now we can make this even shorter because the top and bottom and the left and right are the same.
Top and bottom or ten, left and right or 20.
So let's say padding, shorthand.
So we can actually just have two values.
One will be top, bottom, one will be left right.
So we'll say padding top and bottom.
We want ten left and right.
We want 20.
So this is the same exact thing as this, which is the same exact thing as this.
So we're just shortening it up.
So if we look at it, we get the same exact thing.
We have the ten on the top and bottom, 20 on the left and right.
So hopefully that makes sense.
You can add padding all these different ways.
Now with margin, it's the same exact thing, same exact thing.
I'm actually going to just copy all this and change it to margin.
So margin, top, right, left bottom, this same thing, same order.
So let's grab this and let's put this down here and just change this to margin.
Change these to margin.
Uh, margin.
Okay.
So that's going to do same exact thing.
Save that if we take a look now we have ten pixels, top and bottom margin, 20 left and right margin.
So yeah, I think that that's all I want to do here.
One other thing.
Usually since we did a reset, we'd probably want to separate the the H three and the paragraph a little
bit.
So what I would do is just add box H three and I'd probably add like padding bottom ten pixels, five
pixels, whatever it may be.
Oops, what happened here?
Inside, I'm inside this style.
So let's check that out.
And now we have spacing under the heading.
All right, so that's it, guys.
In the next video, we're going to start to talk about floats so we can align things.
Now, ultimately, when you when you align stuff, you're usually going to want to use Flexbox or CSS
grid, but we're not going to talk about that stuff just yet because that that stuff is a little more
complicated and it's much newer.
I want you to get a handle on just old fashioned floating before you start to deal with flex and grid
and stuff like that.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next video.