So in the last video, we looked at key frames and we looked at how we could animate different properties
such as the position, the width, the colour, but we just did a two in a frame, so basically a starting
point and an ending point.
But with key frames you can actually have more than just those points.
You can you can use percentages.
So that's what I want to go over in this video.
So I'm going to create a new file here called zero eight, underscore keyframes, let's say keyframes
to XHTML.
And I'm just going to close the sidebar up here and let's say Keyframes two and we'll put in our style
tags.
And I'm just going to have again, just an ID of or let's do that.
I do an ID or a class in the last one.
I just want to be a little consistent here.
So we have a class of box.
Let's do that.
Same thing.
So box.
And in the style, let's add box.
We'll make the background dark like we did in the last one.
So body background, three, three, three.
So the box will give it a background color of white and let's set the width to 200 pixels and the height
to 200 pixels.
I should probably spell background correctly and we're also going to position this relative because
we're going to be dealing with positional properties.
So let's say position relative and let's save this and open this up with live server.
So we have our box.
Now I'm going to add an animation here with a keyframe and I'm just going to add I'm just going to use
the animation property instead of using all the separate properties and we'll say animate one, let's
say we'll have it.
The span will be a 5/2 span forward so that it stays where it's at when it ends.
And let's do ease.
We'll do ease in and out.
All right.
So just like in the last video, we're going to create a keyframes and let's call it animate one.
And before what we did is we did two and from.
But in this case, I want to use percentages.
So basically 0% are the starting point we already have set here.
In fact, I'm going to set the position that I want, which is top zero left zero.
Uh.
Yeah.
Left zero.
And then I'm going to say, well, at 25%, I want it to be top zero.
So I still want it to be at the top, but I want it to be left.
Let's say 300 pixels.
Now, what I want this to do ultimately is I want it to go from here, over, down, back, over and
up.
So a complete circle.
Complete 360, 360 degrees.
So let's go ahead and save this and see what happens.
So it gets pushed over and it's going to end in the same spot over a period of 5 seconds.
Now, obviously, we want we want to add on to this.
We want it to go down after.
So let's go right under this and say at 50% of the base, basically like the timeline, we want it to
be top 300 pixels because we want it to move down and we still want left to be 300 pixels.
So let's try that.
We'll save.
Goes over, goes down.
And it's going to end up in the in the starting position.
All right.
So next thing we want to do is add 75% and it doesn't have to be 25, 50, 75.
You can use any point in the timeline that you want.
So here I want it to be from the left.
Let's do top first.
So top, I still want it to be 300 pixels, but the left, I want it to be zero because I want it to
go back over.
So let's save it goes over, down, back, over and up.
Now, I just want to make sure that at 100%, which is basically the ending point, I want it to be
back in its original place, which is top zero, left zero.
All right.
So now our square just does a complete square.
Now, obviously, we can change other properties if we want.
So let's say at every point we want to change the color.
So let's do right here, background red.
And then at 50%, we'll say background green.
Let's do background blue.
And then at the ending point, let's do background light, we'll save that.
And you can see it changes to red, to green, to blue and to white.
Now let's do something else.
We can also animate the border radius, so let's do border radius.
I don't know if I show this to you guys, but you can have more than one value and it pertains to each
corner.
So let's say we want the left corner, top left to be 50%.
So basically rounded and then the other one zero.
So I save that.
Notice that it turns into 50% when it goes to 25%.
This this corner here.
Now I'm going to copy this.
And then right here, let's say we want both both the top corners to be rounded.
So 50% and then we'll go down here and then we want the top.
So 50% and then also the bottom, right.
I believe this is will be 50%.
And then by the end, it should be a complete circle.
So we'll just say border radius, 50% like that, meaning all corners.
So with each iteration, each corner changes and by the end it's a circle.
So I mean, obviously this animation is is it's not very practical.
It's not something you would actually put in in a project, but it gives you the the tools that you
need to be able to create some cool stuff.
So you should be able to come up with some nice ideas.
As far as animation goes, it's not really my specialty, but you know, if you're if you're creative
in that area, you can do some really, really awesome things with CSS animation.
So in the next video, we're going to continue on with with animations and we're going to look at transitions.