All right, guys.
So we have one page left to go.
That's the contact page.
So that's what we're going to start working on.
So let's jump into VS code and let's open up.
I'm going to open up about HTML and I'm going to copy everything in there and then let's create a new
file inside the dist called Contact HTML and we'll go ahead and paste this in and let's just pick and
choose what we want.
So in the head, I'm just going to change the title to contact me and let's see, we want to keep the
header, but we're going to move the class here to contact and we're going to get rid of all the sections.
Just keep the footer and we'll save that.
And now we should be able to go to contact and we basically have our just our boilerplate for an inner
page.
So on our contact page we have a form and we have an email address, phone number, address area.
And then we just have an area that says, let's start your next project.
So we're going to have section A, B and C.
So let's start off with the form which is going to be section A.
So we'll go under the header here, let's say section A and we'll say contact form.
So let's create a section with an ID of contact dash a we're going to give it a class of text center
and let's do class of py-3 and we'll put in our container and let's do our H two with the class of section
title.
And we're just going to say contact me.
And underneath that we'll put our bottom line.
So I know this is very repetitive.
So we also want a paragraph with the class of lead and we'll say, here is how you can reach me.
And I mean, it's repetitive, but that's that's really what you want.
You want to stay consistent with your your design, with your your markup, your styling.
You want everything to be consistent.
So being repetitive is actually a good thing.
So let's go underneath the paragraph here and create a form.
I'm just going to I'm not going to put any action or anything like that in the attributes in it for
now.
Just, just a form tag and let's do a class of text dash fields and then we're going to put our inputs
in.
I'm not going to use a label, I'm just going to use a placeholder in the form.
So let's do an input with the type of text and actually know what it's going to be text by default.
Let's do a class of text dash input and also a class of name dash input.
And then let's do, let's see, let's add a placeholder which we're going to use as a label.
So we'll just say name and then I'm going to just copy that down.
Let's do that's two, three, four, we'll do and then one we'll do five.
So one, two, three, four, five.
The last one is going to be a text area, but we'll change that up after.
So we have our name.
Next one is going to be the subject.
So let's do.
Text input, subject input.
And by the way, we're going to be using grid template areas for this form to place the inputs in the
correct areas for placeholder, let's do subject.
And this third one here is going to be the email input.
So we'll do email.
Let's change this class to email input.
We'll also change the type to email and we're going to have a phone number.
So let's do right here.
We'll do phone input, change the placeholder to phone number actually for this placeholder, let's
say email address.
And then this last one is going to be the message.
So it's going to be a text area.
So I'm going to get rid of the type text and the input and let's say text area and let's see, we're
going to have text input class.
Let's also do message input and then get rid of the placeholder.
No, I'm sorry, not get rid of the placeholder.
We want that.
We're going to say enter message, but we do want to add an ending tag since it's a text area.
And then I'm going to go outside of the div here and add a button with the class of BTN Dash Dark and
let's make sure we give this a type of submit because it's a submit button.
And then for the text inside, we'll just say submit.
All right, so that's our form.
So we'll save that pretty or fixed it up a little bit, made it a little more readable.
So if we go to our form, it looks absolutely horrendous.
So we want to add our styling.
So we'll head over to Main dot C's and let's go down to the bottom.
So let's see, we have our boat and then our footer.
Let's go right above the footer and let's say contact page.
So for the contact we have our our A section, so let's do ID contact and then we want to focus on the
ID of contact dash a so we'll do ampersand, dash a and let's do the text fields class, which actually
wraps around all the inputs.
And this is going to be our grid.
So display grid and we're going to use grid template areas here.
So let's go.
We want to go on to the next line and we're going to basically map this out visually.
So we want our name and email field on the first line, then we want the subject and the phone and then
we want the message to span across both both columns here.
So we'll go ahead and put a semicolon here and then let's add a grid gap of 1.2 REM and let's do a margin
bottom of 1.2 REM.
So still within this text field, I'm now going to add the grid areas.
We need to connect the actual elements.
So we have these classes name input, subject input and so on.
Want to map them to these grid areas.
So let's do the name dash input and let's do grid dash area and set that to name.
And then I'm just going to grab this and copy it down.
Let's do two, three, four, five and then I'm going to select this name here, control DX and just
change this to subject.
Same thing here, control D Change these to email and this one, change this to phone and this one will
be message.
All right, so we'll save that.
We'll take a look.
And now you can see it's mapped out how we how we did it in the grid template areas.
So I want to add some padding.
These are way too small.
So let's go.
Let's go outside of.
Well, no, we'll.
We'll stay within the text fields.
So we want to go like right here and let's do text input.
So all the class of text input, which is everything we're going to add padding of 0.5 REM and one REM.
And then the message, the text area, I'm just going to add to that.
I'm going to I'm going to change the height.
Let's do message input.
Actually, we already have the message input up here, so I could just add it right here.
We'll say height.
Let's do like 200 pixels.
See what that looks like.
It's too big.
Let's do let's try 100.
All right.
So it looks pretty good now for the button.
The this button right here.
I want it to be a little wider.
I don't want 100%.
I think that's too wide.
So let's do 50% for that.
So we'll target let's see, we have button.
Button.
I guess we could target the button dark inside of the text text fields.
Actually, it's not in text fields.
We have to go outside of it.
So that ends here.
So we'll just say the button dark.
Well, actually, we don't want to do that because we might want to change it to a different utility
class.
So we'll just do, let's say button and we'll set the type equals submit.
So we want to target the submit button and let's do a width of 50%.
All right.
Let's see what that gives us so it makes it a little wider.
So next we have the contact info, so we're going to add that to the HTML now that we have our form
all styled.
So in contact HTML, let's add section B.
So section B is the contact info.
So section, let's give it an ID of contact dash B and I'm going to give it a class of py padding three
top and bottom.
And let's also do a BG doc, give it the dark background and wrap it in a container.
And then we're going to do a class of contact dash info.
Current contact info.
And this is going to be a grid as well with some divs.
And we're going to have an icon.
Let's give it a class of face.
Let's do a dash envelope and let's make it a little bigger.
We'll do fa2x, so that's that.
And then we'll do an H three with the email.
We'll put a paragraph here and we'll just say John at something dot com.
So that's our email.
Let's just copy this div two more times because this one here is going to be the phone.
We'll change the icon to phone.
Change that to phone.
And let's just do fake phone number.
Five, five, five, five, five, five, five.
Just all fives like that.
And then the last one here is going to be the address.
So the icon is going to be address, dash card, and then let's say address.
And we'll change this to, let's say 50 Main Street, Boston, Mass.
OC.
Now I'm just going to add the C, the contact C section as well, because it's basically just an H one.
So let's say section C, we'll just say tagline and we'll do let's do a section with the ID of contact
dash C and let's do an H one and we'll just say, let's start your next project.
All right.
So we'll save that.
And actually, let's let's add a couple of classes here as well.
So I'm going to do BG Main and let's do p y for let's see what that looks like.
So I'm going to save that and if we go back, so that's good for now.
You know, we want to add a container in the sea.
Forgot about that.
So let's do container and then we'll move this up into here like that.
So let's start to style this part, the section B.
So we want to go under the A which ends right here and we're going to do Ampersand B
and let's see, we're just going to we're not going to do too much here.
We're going to grab the contact info class and display it as a grid because we want those three contact
info icons and stuff to, to go across.
So let's do grid template columns and let's say repeat and we'll repeat three times one fraction and
let's text a line to the center.
And I think that should be good.
And let's check it out.
All right.
Now, last thing is this right here.
So I want it centered.
I'm just.
Actually, we can just text center it.
I believe so.
Let's go under B and let's do ampersand C and let's do H one.
And we want to text a line to the center.
And then I'm going to raise the font size to four REM.
So let's say font size for REM.
And take a look.
There we go.
Let's starting next project.
And if you guys don't like this, you could put an image here, you could put a Google map or something,
whatever you like.
But I think that's pretty good.
So now we have all of our pages.
So in the next video, what I want to do is the responsiveness.
That actually doesn't look too bad.
There's not a lot that we have to do.
We want these too.
Obviously, this isn't good.
We want to stack like the testimonials and stuff like that.
This needs to be fixed.
These need to be stacked.
So in the next video, we're going to start to make this much more responsive.