All right, guys.
So now we're going to get to the fun part, which is the time line.
So let's go to our style Cscs and let's start off with the timeline.
UL So we'll say timeline.
UL And it's not much.
We just want to add the background, let's say background, which is going to be the primary color.
So we'll save that and we see no difference there.
But I just want to add that and then padding, we're going to do 50 pixels, top and bottom zero left
and right.
So we just move that down a little bit.
Now for the list items, let's do timeline ul ly and we want to set the list style to none.
So make sure there's no bullet points.
And then we want to position this relative.
And the reason for that is we're going to position some of the stuff inside of it absolute.
So we want to make sure this is relative and then we're going to set the width to six pixels and we're
going to and you'll see why in a little bit.
But we're going to set the margin zero auto so that pushes it into the middle.
And then we're going to say some give it some padding top of let's do 50 pixels.
So for each list item and then the background, we're going to do white.
So what we've done here is we've created our line, as you can see, which is a has a width of six pixels.
Now the boxes that are going to be coming off the sides are actually going to be the divs.
So if you look in our HTML inside the ly, we have the divs.
So those are going to be the boxes.
So that's why I put six pixels for the ly itself because it's basically just the line.
So let's go down here, let's say boxes.
Actually, right here.
What we'll do is we'll say create line.
And let's see, we're going to take timeline ul ly div and let's say position relative.
And from the bottom we're going to say zero.
So we're going to start from the zero, from the bottom, and then we're going to set the width of the
initial width of the boxes to 400 pixels.
So now we have each div is 400 pixels wide and we need some padding.
So padding will say one, REM gives it some padding.
We also want a background.
So we'll do background and let's use our secondary color.
So we'll say var and let's say dash, dash, secondary color and save.
And now we start to see our boxes forming.
Now I want to add a transition on this because ultimately if we add our JavaScript, we'll have some
animation.
So we're going to add transition all and let's say 0.5 seconds and let's do is ease in out.
Okay, so that's all divs.
Now the way I want to do this is the right side because remember, we're going to have them on the right
and the left.
The right side is going to be the odd and the left side will be the even.
Now, remember, we have the nth child selector and we can choose odd.
And even so let's go down here and let's say right side.
So we're going to take the timeline
ugly and we want to choose the North Dash child and let's take all the odd and we want the div.
We want to make sure we're targeting the divs.
The divs is what happened was where the box with the padding 400 pixels wide that's the div not the
line.
And then here we're going to say from the left, we want this to be 40 pixels and we'll save and notice
that all the odds now are 40 pixels from the left.
So for the left side, we'll go ahead and just copy this.
And let's say left side, we're going to choose the evens and we're going to say from the left, we
want to go.
Now, remember, what we're saying is from the from the middle here, which is the left, we want to
go this way.
So we're going to do -434 pixels and save, and that's going to bring it to the other side.
Now, I want to have the little dots here for each item in the timeline.
So let's go down here and let's say dots and the dots.
It's going to be timeline ul ly and we're going to say after so we're going to use the after pseudo
selector, let's say content, nothing and position absolute.
So remember we created this this line here with the ly.
So we're just saying after that we want to position this absolute.
We want to say from the left 50% and we're going to set from the bottom.
Zero and let's set the width.
So the width of the dot, I'm going to say 25 pixels height, also 25 pixels.
Now if I save that, we're not going to see it yet because there's no background.
It's basically just just invisible.
So let's say background and I'm just going to inherit.
So it should be.
Well, actually, let's what I want to do is I want it to be white to begin with.
But once the sides are once they're brought in, when we use the JavaScript, I then want it to be filled
with blue.
But for now or I'm sorry, not blue, but the primary color, but for now let's just use the primary
color.
So we'll say dash, dash, primary color.
And if we save it's you can see do we want.
No, we want secondary.
I'm sorry.
You can't see it.
So let's say secondary color.
All right.
Now I want to move it over and I also want to make it into a circle.
So to move it over, I'm going to add a transform, because remember, we can do transform, translate
to move it.
So let's say translate and we want to translate on the x axis.
So we're going to use translate x and we want to bring it over negative however much to the left we
put it.
So we put it 50% to the left.
So we want to say -50% and save, and that will bring it right smack dab in the middle.
And then let's make it into a circle by just simply doing border radius 50% and save those.
There we go.
Okay, so now we have our dots.
Let's see.
So the next thing.
Actually.
Yeah, that's good.
So let's add a transition because like I said, when we add the JavaScript, I want it to be white at
first and then and then transition to to blue when, when a certain class is added.
That's basically what the JavaScript is going to do.
It's going to add a certain class that will do certain things like position these, so slide them in
and also change the color of this.
But for it to do it smoothly, we need to add a transition.
So let's transition the background 0.5 seconds and ease and out.
So let's see, the next thing I want to work on is the arrows because we want little arrows pointing
to the dot and the way that we can do that is manipulating the border.
So let's go.
Yeah.
We'll go.
Great.
Right down here.
Now we're going to the arrows are going to be on the div before, so we're going to say timeline div
before and we're going to have to we'll have some styles that will pertain to just the left and just
the right, because obviously the arrows will be facing a different way depending on if it's on the
left or right box.
But we're going to add some similar styles to all of the arrows.
So let's say content, just blank quotes, and then we want a position absolute.
So it's going to be positioned absolute within the div and we're going to say let's go from the bottom
five pixels up because we want it to be we don't want it to be right at the bottom.
We want it to be like up five pixels and then we're going to set the width to zero and the height to
zero because the board, the arrows are going to come from the border.
It's going to be just from the border width.
And then let's set border style to solid.
Now the reason I'm just doing border style here is because whether it's on the left or the right, it
the style is going to be solid.
However, the width and the color are going to have different properties depending on if it's on the
left or the right.
So let's go down here.
Actually, I'll put a comment here and I'll say arrows.
I'll say arrows base.
And let's go down here and let's say right arrows or right side arrows.
And notice if I save, we have these see these little dots or these little squares on each side.
That's what we created with this this whole style right here.
If I get rid of that and save those, those squares disappear.
So we've created that.
Now, what I want to do is grab this the odd div, because that's the right side.
And we'll paste that in and remember that before selector is is how we're creating these arrows.
So we want to do colon before and let's move it over.
So we'll say from the left, -15 pixels.
If I save that, you'll see that now this has moved over and the way that we can get this to basically
shaped like a like a point using CCIS is with the border width and border colour in certain spots.
So border width we can do top right, bottom left.
So we're going to do eight pixels, top 16 pixels right, eight pixels bottom and zero left.
So top right, bottom left.
And if I save that you'll see that it just gets bigger really.
Now we only want to colour certain, certain parts of it.
We want to make transparent in certain parts, we want to colour.
So let's do border dash colour and we're going to say transparent for the first value.
Second is going to be the secondary colour.
So var secondary colour and then the next two will be transparent.
All right.
Now if I save that, it turns into an arrow or it's shaped like an arrow, and this is done with with
just the border.
It's a solid border.
We give it widths on each on each side and set it to transparent except one side.
And we get this point effect.
And if we move this, if we add to like, let's say bottom 25, we can move the arrow up if we want,
but we want it right on par with the circle.
So five pixels is good.
It's basically right in the middle there.
And for the other side for this over here, let's just copy this, paste that in and say left side arrows
change this to even because that's the left and we're going to set the position to be from the right
15, 15 pixels.
And then we need to change this stuff up because if I save this, you'll see that it's it's pointing
the wrong way.
So we want to change the width to be eight pixels, top zero eight pixels, and then 16 at the end.
All right.
So if I save that, we can't even see it because we need to change this.
The colour pattern up basically we want transparent for the first three and then have the secondary
colour as the last value like that and save.
And there we go.
So now we have our arrows.
So it's kind of cool that you can do this kind of stuff with CSS and it's a little difficult to understand,
but you know, you'll, you'll get the hang of it as you create stuff like this more and more so and
this is kind of advanced.
This is this is pretty, pretty advanced CSS.
So we have our points.
This looks pretty good.
I think what we need to do next is make it responsive, because if I make this smaller, you'll see
it's basically just it's just stuck in that width no matter what I do.
So in the next video, we're going to add some media queries and we're just going to change a couple
of things up, depending on the screen size.