All right, guys.
So we have all of our pages done.
Now we're going to start to look at responsiveness and making it look better on smaller screens.
So I'm going to actually create a new SAS file.
So in success, I'm going to create a file called Underscore Media Access.
And this is where I want to put my media queries.
Now I want to bring this in to the main CSIS or CSIS, but I'm going to bring it in down at the bottom
because that's where I want this stuff to be included.
So at the very bottom here, let's do import media.
So we'll just put a comment here, we'll say import media queries.
So let's head over to media success and let's start off with tablets and smaller.
So I'm going to put a media query for a max width of 800 pixels here.
So let's do at media and let's say max width is going to be 800 pixels.
And let's start with the header home.
So let's do ID header dash home.
We're actually not going to have very much in here, but what I want to do is make the height much less
than what it is on on laptops and desktops.
So I'm going to take the height from 100 viewport width, our viewport height to just 30 REM, which
is still pretty big.
It should take a good chunk of the screen, but we don't want it to cover the whole screen on a tablet.
And then I'm just going to take the header content.
And actually, you know what?
We can nest this within header home.
So we're going to take the header content and just add a padding dash top of five REM.
So let's take a look at that.
Now, if if this doesn't show, like if the media query styles do not show, just go ahead and restart
this down here with control C and then run npm run SAS again.
You might have to just re save media access and then let's go back here and let's make this smaller.
And once we hit 800, you can see that it then goes down to the width or sorry, the height goes down
to 30 REM.
So I think that that's better on a tablet rather than having it take up the whole screen.
So that's pretty much it for the 800 pics me pixels media query.
Now I want to deal with smartphones.
So anything that's under 500 because right here, I mean things look pretty decent.
We don't really need to do anything else for this size.
So we want to now deal with smaller.
Actually, what we'll do is open up.
Chrome tools and let's set it to iPhone X.
So there's a few things we want to do here
under the media, max width of 800 pixels.
Let's do smart phones and we're going to do media max width and let's do this, let's say 500 pixels.
So first I'm going to work on the header and the main nav.
Now the main nav, I'm going to set the flex direction instead of row.
I'm going to set it to column.
I actually want the the logo on top in the center and then the menu underneath in the center.
So let's take the main nav and let's set the flex direction to column.
And I want to align items center.
And I also want the list items.
So I'm going to embed the our nest the list items here.
I'm going to set padding to.
Let's do one REM.
So now you can see that it's in a column fashion rather than a row.
So we have the the logo in the middle on top, and then we have the the menu in the middle here.
So let's deal with the rest of the header because this obviously doesn't look very good.
So we're going to go under the main nav and let's do header and we're going to do ampersand dash home.
And the reason I'm doing it like this is because we're also going to add some styles for Dash Inner
as well.
Notice up here, I just put in header dash home because we weren't we don't have any styles up here
for header dash inner OC.
So I mean and you can do it if you want.
Had our dash home, had our dash in or you don't have to do it this way.
I just like to organize it in this way.
But you know, everyone's different, so I'm going to set the height to be much smaller.
So on tablets it's 30 REM on full screen, it's 100.
It takes up the whole thing on smartphones.
I'm just going to do ten REM.
So if we save that, we take a look.
You can see that it's much smaller now.
I'm also going to add a border on the bottom here to kind of separate the rest of the content.
So let's do border bottom and let's set that to three pixels solid and we want it set to the main colour
variable.
All right, now I don't want the header content displayed.
All we want is the the logo and the menu.
And it's not shown here just because.
Well it is actually we have you can see the button here.
So we want to just we don't want to show that at all.
So I'm going to nest in here the header content.
And let's just set this to display.
None.
So now if we go back, you'll see that none of that contents displayed.
That button is gone.
And we just have a very simple header with a logo and a menu.
Now, the inner pages, if we take a look here, you'll see that the menu is is covered.
So we want the same height for the inner that we do for the home menu or the home header.
So let's go back in here and let's go after home and let's say in our and let's also set the height
to ten REM and then if we go back and you'll see the inner pages now are the same as the home.
Actually, you know what we want to do, though, see how the home, the positioning is different.
We want to set the positioning of the home to the same to the same X and Y values as the inner.
So right here in the home, lots to background dash position which if we look in main dot six is right
here so 20% 30%.
So we want to set that to 20%, 30%.
And now if we save that, you'll see that now it looks the same on all pages.
So let's start to work on stacking some of this stuff.
So we'll start with the home page.
We'll just have basically one style for everything we want stacked.
So anything that has a grid template columns of repeat for one FR or repeat three one if our we just
want to set it to one fr one fraction, which is just one column that will make it stacked.
So I'm going to go let's see, let's go under.
We want to be within the media query.
So this media query ends here.
So I'm going to go right here and let's say Stack, we want this to be a comment.
So stack grid columns.
So first thing is let's do home dash a specials, which is a grid.
Next, we want home B, so home dash B stats stats and let's do home dash C process.
So these are all grids.
And then on the about page we have our testimonials.
So let's do a boat dash D class of testimonials and then we also have our items on our work page.
So let's say items.
So within here, I'm just going to set the grid template columns simply to one fraction.
So if I save that, we go back.
You can see that these are all stacked the three sections on the home page.
We'll deal with the footer in a little bit.
And then on the about page, the testimonials are stacked.
We're going to deal with this and then let's see on the work page.
These are all stacked.
So let's see what else we want to do here.
I want to add, uh, and the reason that this doesn't look good is because, remember, we used grid
template areas here, so we have to, we have to manage this in a different way to make it responsive.
Same with the contact.
But before we do that, I want to make this look a little bit better by taking like these boxes here
and putting a little border underneath each one because they're kind of running into each other here.
So let's do that.
Let's go back in and let's go under here and let's do home and let's do Ampersand A and we want to grab
the specials div.
So each div inside the specials class, I'm going to add a border bottom to let's do one pixel, I'm
going to use the light color.
I want it to be pretty faint and solid and let's add a little bit of padding to push each one down.
So padding bottom, I'm going to set to one REM and I don't want the very last one to have a border.
So I'm going to add in here ampersand, colon, last child.
And let's set the border to none.
Whoops, border none.
And let's set the padding bottom to zero on the last one.
So if we save that, we take a look.
Now, you can see it has a very faint border after each one, except for the bottom.
We don't need a border here.
That would look kind of weird.
Now, let's see.
What else do we want to do here?
The stats.
Which are these here?
I want to just lessen the padding a little bit.
So within this a right here, we're going to go outside of the specials, but within the A I'm sorry,
not within the A, it's it's section B.
So we want to go after the A, let's say B, and we're going to take the stats, divs.
And set the padding to let's do two REM top zero and then one REM bottom.
So that lessens the padding a little bit.
Now.
I think that that's good for the the home page.
I think that we should handle the footer, though, before we move on, because this obviously doesn't
look very good.
So let's.
Go back in and let's go.
Still within the media query.
So we want to go right here.
Let's say footer and we have an ID of main dash footer.
I'm going to set the height of the footer to seven REM and then I'm going to grab the footer content
and set the flex direction to column.
So we're kind of doing the same thing that we did with the nav bar.
I'm going to set it to column and then we're going to set padding to one REM and let's set the height
of that to five REM and let's see what that looks like.
So instead of having it in a flex row going across, now they're in a column and we just added some
padding to kind of separate the stuff a little bit.
So I think that that looks pretty good.
Let's see.
Next thing we want to do is let's do the about page.
So we'll handle this part right here, which is which are grid template areas.
So we just want to basically reframe the grid template areas.
So I'm going to go here and say about let me just put a comment right here as well for home.
So we'll say ID about and we want to deal with about Dash A so let's do ampersand dash a and it has
a class of intro or wait, what was it?
Let me just.
Check this out.
So a and we want the grid which is this oh, it's about info, not intro.
So what class about dash info which is already displayed is a grid and it has template areas which sets
the columns.
Now I just want it to be stacked.
So I'm going to take the bio image.
And just to show you what I'm talking about, if we look at about let's see, where is it?
So right here we have bio image, bio, bio.
Basically, we want all of these just to go straight down and one, one column or one row.
So let's say bio image.
Wait a minute.
This isn't right.
We have to add in grid template areas and then we're going to do.
Bio image.
Next line here will be bio.
Then we have award one, award two and award three and we already have the grid template.
The other grid area is set right here so we don't have to redo those or anything.
It's already set.
We just simply want to change the orientation.
All right.
And then.
Four, see?
Let's see this right here.
This is see the logos?
I'm just going to remove this whole thing because I don't it's not that important.
And I mean, we could we could stack the logos on top of each other, but that's just too much room
just to show some logos and they're way too small to leave it like this.
So I'm going to just get rid of that.
And of course, again, if you guys want to do something different, that's absolutely fine.
But that's what I would do in this situation.
So I'm going to go actually, let's add a semicolon right here.
I'm going to go below the oops, below the A, which ends here and do dash and dash, see which is the
logo section.
And I'm just going to display none, get rid of it completely.
So now if we go back, that part is now gone so the about page looks pretty good let's go to the work
is good let's go to the contact page.
So let's see, let's head over here and let's add a section for contact.
So we have ID contact and let's target contact, dash a and I'm going to grab the text fields class.
So text fields and we want to change the orientation of the, the inputs.
So again, we're going to do grid template areas and.
Let's set name.
Email.
What you will do.
Subject.
Email.
Phone and message.
So we're just kind of stacking all those inputs.
So if I save that, we go back.
Now, you can see that they're all stacked.
So the next part is this.
This right here.
I also want to stack these.
So we can actually.
Let's actually add that up above where we put all the other stuff we want stacked.
So what is the selector for this?
So it's contact info is the grid.
So we can just go back here and I mean here.
Uh.
Let's say.
Dot.
Contact info.
And now if I save that.
Wait a minute.
Why is.
Contact info.
Hmm.
Actually, we might have to add the section.
We should do that anyway.
So contact B.
So let's do ID contact.
Be contact info.
There you go.
So now these are stacked.
And the reason for that is because that's the selector we used to add the the the repeat three one fa.
Now, that still doesn't look very good.
I want to separate these a little bit.
I also want to add a little a faint border below each one like we did on the home page.
So let's jump down here and let's target contact B
and we want to target the div or the divs inside.
And let's set a margin bottom of one REM.
Let's do a padding bottom of one REM and let's do a border border bottom.
So the border bottom, I'm going to set to one pixel and I'm just going to use a hard coded color.
I'm going to use five, five, five solid.
I mean, we could use a variable, but.
It has a dark background, so we can't use dark.
And I think medium is a little too light.
I want it to be very faint.
So that's why I hardcoded this.
But again, you can do what you want and then we don't want a border for the last child or margin or
padding.
So let's do ampersand last child and let's set the border to none.
Let's set margin bottom to zero and padding bottom to zero.
So we'll save that.
Go back and there we go.
It looks pretty good.
Now, I do want to make this text smaller, so I'm going to go let's see.
So that's section C.
So we want to be in contact.
We'll go under B and let's do ampersand C and we want to target the H one and it's for REM by default,
I believe.
So I'm going to set it to two REM.
All right, we'll save that.
And there he goes.
That looks better.
So this looks pretty good.
Let's check it out on an iPhone five.
So if it passes the iPhone five test, I think we're good.
And looks nice about.
Work.
Contact.
Good.
Now, the last thing I want to look at is landscape mode.
So I'm going to go to iPhone X and turn it.
Now, I'd like this to be in the middle on landscape mode, and you can see that the button is actually
outside of the the container here or the it's below the fold.
So we want to just move this.
So I'm going to jump in here to media success and I'm going to go with the very bottom and let's do
a media query for landscape.
So to do this, we want to target the height.
So let's do media and let's say max height of 580 pixels.
And we want to grab the header home.
So header dash home.
And then we want the header content which is inside of it.
So class header content and I'm going to set the padding top to just three REM.
So that should move it up if we go back.
There we go.
So everything is now in view.
All right.
And even if we go to the let's go to the galaxy and it looks good.
iPhone five.
So the iPhone five.
I mean, I guess.
It's so small, it's it's kind of hard to to deal with.
I guess what we could do is set another media query for the height, see how it's 320.
It's really small.
The iPhone X height is 325.
Let's see, the galaxy is 360, pixel is in, landscape is 411.
So let's set that.
Oops, I want to go to iPhone five.
Let's set 143 20.
And what we'll do is I guess, I mean, we'll reduce the, the font size of the heading here.
So let's actually copy this.
Let's say a max height of we'll do we'll do 330.
And if that's the case, then let's take let me see.
I just want to check the HTML.
So it's this h one right here.
So the header content h one which what's the size by default.
I didn't plan on doing this.
That's why I'm checking all this.
So the size by default is four REM, so I guess we could change it to two REM.
So we'll say header home header content h one.
And we'll set the font size to two REM.
See if that works out.
So I think that that's that's good enough.
Not too many people have iPhone fives anymore, at least that I know of.
And then if we go back to something bigger than 330 heights, you'll see that the H one is back to form.
All right, so that's it, guys.
We have created our project in the next video.
I want to get it ready to deploy, to notify, and I want to make the contact form work as well.