All right, guys.
So we're going to look at the Transform property now.
And this is a page from the MSDN website, the Mozilla Docs, and it gives you a pretty good example
of some of the effects that you can do with the transform.
So for instance, we can rotate.
Actually, I got a click off at first.
This is Skew, so you can kind of skew it, you can rotate, you can scale.
So make it bigger, you can translate, which is basically move it around matrix.
So we're going to look at some of these properties and we're also going to kind of integrate it with
transitions.
So let's, let's create a new file called ten underscore transform, dot, HTML,
say transform, and it's put in our style.
And again, I'm just going to have a class of box.
So we're just working with this box here and I'm just going to copy from the transitions, I'm going
to copy the whole body because I just want a box in the middle.
Actually, I'll just grab both of these, grab the hover as well, and I'll just delete some stuff.
So let's paste that in and I'm going to keep for the box, the background, the width and the height,
and I'll get rid of all the hover for now.
And I'm actually going to set it to 300 pixels.
All right.
So let's save that and let's open this with live server.
We have a 300 pixel wide, 300 pixel height box in the middle of the screen and let's apply a transform.
So we'll go to the box here and let's say transform and then we're going to have an effect.
Let's use rotate.
So we'll say rotate.
And that's going to take in whatever the amount you want to rotate, let's say 25 DG So 25 degrees and
we'll save and that's going to rotate it.
Now of course you could use rotate this rotate with animation with keyframes transitions, but if you
just wanted to have something tilted a little bit, you could just use it directly like this.
All right.
So next, we're going to look at oops, let's let's comment this out.
Next, we're going to look at skew, which will just kind of skew it diagonally.
Diagonally, is that a word?
Diagonal?
And let's try that so you can see what skew does.
And this is nice if you want to have diagonal lines like in your layout, if you want to have maybe,
you know, a little showcase area where you have something on this side, something on this side, you
want a diagonal line in the middle instead of just having it half and half like that.
So that is skew.
Let's see, let's copy this down and comment this out and let's look at scale.
So scale, let's just put in two and that's just going to scale it up.
So essentially we're doubling it in size.
We could put three and it'll scale even more.
All right.
So let's comment that out.
Now, the next thing I want to show you is, is how to use transform with transitions.
So I'm going to add a transition for all elements that are animate able.
And let's do 1/2, ease in out and then let's just save that it's going to go back down.
And in our hover let's let's do the rotate.
So to rotate instead of 25, though, let's do 180.
So now when I hover over it, it rotates.
When I hover off, it goes back.
So pretty cool.
We can also skew it.
Let's grab that.
So now when I hover over it, it skews and this this is going to basically, you know, overwrite the
rotate.
And then we can also do scale.
So if I save that and I hover over it, it'll scale up.
Now, we can also move this around the page without having to do, like a position relative and then
doing top bottom, left right properties.
And we can do that by using translate.
So we have translate, we have translate X, translate Y so we can move it along the x axis and the
Y axis.
So let's actually comment this stuff out and let's do a trance form.
And then we're going to set it to translate.
Let's do translate y and let's say 100 pixels.
All right, so let's save that.
Now, when I hover over this, it's going to move it down 100 pixels.
So I didn't have to do like a position relative or a top, you know, top one, whatever property.
It just simply moves 100 pixels.
And now if I want to move it up on the Y axis, I can simply put a negative value.
So -100 is going to move it up.
And if I want to do on the x axis, I can do translate x, let's do 100 pixels and that's going to go
over.
And if I want to go the other way, I could of course, do a negative value there.
Now, let's say I want to move it on the x and y axis.
I can just use translate so I can say transform
translate.
And this is going to take in the X and the Y parameter.
So let's say 100 pixels on the X axis, 100 pixels on the y axis.
And now when I hover over it, it will go 100 over and 100 down.
And of course, I could use negative values if I wanted to.
Now, for if you want to increase performance, you can actually use translate three DX, which I don't
use all that much, but we can do translate three dx and let's actually comment this stuff out.
So if we use translate three dx, this actually has to have a Z value as well.
So 100 pixels and that's going to do the same thing.
And I believe it increases performance if you use translate three DX and you can do some really cool
things.
I'm I'm not that familiar with it I usually use translate but it is available to us.
All right.
So that's the transform property.
We'll be using this later on in other projects, but that's going to be it for this video, guys, and
I'll see you in the next one.