All right, guys.
In the last video, we went ahead and dealt with the boxes.
We created these boxes with these arrows.
But this is not.
Whoops.
This is not responsive.
You can see that it's just the same no matter what the screen size is.
So I want to add a couple of media queries.
So in the CSV file, let's go down here and let's say media and this is going to be a max width of 900
pixels.
So basically when it's when it's less 900 pixels or less, I want the width of the boxes to change from
400 to 250 pixels wide.
So we're going to say timeline ul ly div and let's set the width to 250 pixels, which were originally
400.
So now when I hit 900, which is right here, they change.
Now we have an issue with the left side where it's too far out.
So we can fix that really easily by just taking the let's see.
Ly We want to do nth child and we want to grab the even which is the left side and grab that div and
then just move it over.
So we'll say from the left we want to do -284 pixels and save and that brings it over.
All right.
Now, when you're creating this stuff from scratch, you're going to be you're going to be experimenting
a lot.
You're not going to know these values right away.
So you won't going to be experimenting when it comes to like the border and making these arrows.
It took me a while to to figure out exactly what values to use.
So just keep that in mind.
It's not it's not always going to go as smooth as you see in courses, in tutorials.
All right.
Now, that is if it's under 900.
Now, if we get to like right here, it's still it's not it doesn't look good.
And what I want to do is move them all to the to the right side.
And I want this line, basically the list item to be on the side here.
So let's add another media query and let's say max width, let's make it let's do 600 pixels.
So basically smartphones and we're going to take the timeline ul ly and this is set to margin auto on
the left and right.
If we go up here and we look at the ly, we have auto for left and right, but i don't want it in the
middle anymore.
I want it on the side.
So I'm just going to simply set the margin left to 20 pixels and save.
And that does nothing.
It's because I'm not 600 yet.
So if we go, there we go.
So at 600, you can see that the the line gets pushed over to the left and it's margin left 20.
We don't want to do zero because it'll be right up against the edge.
So margin left 20.
And if you're confused of why that happened, again, it's because we had margin auto, which puts it
in the middle.
Now we changed margin left to 20 pixels, which makes it no longer margin auto.
So let's move on to the width of the boxes.
And I know that you can't see the the other side, the left side boxes.
We're going to fix that.
But I want the width to actually be a calculation, meaning I want it to, to be dynamic.
So let's say timeline ul ly div and let's set the width.
Instead of using just a fixed number, I'm going to use the CSS calc calc function here and we can say
we want to take 100 viewport widths.
So basically the whole viewport width, regardless of how big the browser is sized or the device is
sized, and we just want to take away 90 pixels from it and let's save.
So now you can see that these just ignore this for now, but these ones perfectly fit in there.
And if I make the smaller they adjust.
Okay.
So we're just taking the viewport width, meaning the whole thing, and we're taking away 90 pixels
because if we were to do just 100 viewport width and save, you'll see that it actually goes off the
page like that.
That doesn't look right.
So we're just taking 90 pixels away.
Now we want to move these boxes over to the right.
We want these all in line.
So to do that, let's take Timeline ul Lee.
We want to grab the ones in the left.
So oops.
I want to do ly and.
Child and we want the even divs and I'm going to say from the left 40 pixels and save.
Now we're just about there but the arrows on the the ones that were on the left, the arrows are still
facing on the right side.
So we simply need to move them to this side, which we can copy this whole thing right here, the right
side arrows, because these are pointing this way and paste that in here and just change this to even
and save.
And now they're all facing that way.
All right.
So now it's completely responsive.
Hit 900 pixels, they get smaller, gets 600 pixels, and they adapt.
They all go to the right side.
All right.
So that's it.
In the next video, we're going to show you how we can implement a little bit of JavaScript to have
a little bit of animation on the scroll.