All right.
So we've completed our initial age, HTML and CSS, but I want to just add a little bit of JavaScript
here to make this dynamic.
So we're going to add some lines of JavaScript in a in a JS file, and then we're going to edit the
CSS a little bit because we need to kind of change how this works.
Basically what we need to do is check to see as we scroll down, we need to fire off an event that's
going to check to see if a certain list, item, certain box here is actually in the viewport.
So right now, put the python.
One is not in the viewport, but when I scroll down it starts to enter.
It is now when it hits that point, we want this to basically just come in, fade in from the right
or from the left on this side.
And the way that we're going to do that is with JavaScript, we're going to add dynamically add a class
called show, which will add a transform to to bring it in.
We're going to initially hide these things at first, and then the show class will allow them to basically
animate in.
So let's create a new file called Main JS the JavaScript file, and I'm going to paste this code in.
And again, this is not a JavaScript course, so I'm not going to explain every single line here.
But basically what's going on is we're grabbing on to all the timeline list items.
So basically each of these and we're putting it in a variable called items.
And then down here we have a function called run which is looping through those items.
So it's going through each one and it's checking to see if it's in the viewport.
That's what this function does right here.
And if it is in the viewport, it's going to add the class of show.
All right.
So that's exactly what this does.
It loops through all of these list items, checks to see if it's in the viewport.
If it is, it adds the class of show.
Now, down here, we're just firing it off.
We're firing off this run when the page loads.
So when the page loads, if anything is in the viewport, it's going to just slide in also on resize.
So if we resize the browser, it'll run and then if we scroll it'll also run.
So every time something enters the viewport it should add the class of show.
Now that's all JavaScript is doing is adding this, this class of show.
We have to handle the rest of it in the CSS so you can see all they work together.
So let's save this file and let's go to index HTML and make sure we include it and JavaScript files
for 99% of the time.
You want to include them at the bottom of the page, right above the body.
So we're going to put a script tag and we're going to add a source attribute pointing to main JS and
we'll save.
Now, nothing is going to happen yet because all we've done is included the JavaScript.
But I can show you if we open up our chrome tools here, let's actually just make this bigger.
Now I want to show you what the JavaScript file is actually doing.
So I'm going to go to Elements and if we look at our you'll notice that these lines all have a class
of show.
So even though this this fourth one here is in the viewport, it's, it's, it has to be fully in the
viewport.
So if I scroll down a little bit as soon as it's fully in the viewport, notice that the class of show
got added.
If I keep scrolling as soon as the next one is fully in the viewport, just watch over here on the right.
Keep scrolling.
There's that one.
That one.
So it's just.
It's just adding that class of show to the document object model.
So it's adding that class to the lie.
And that's exactly what we want the JavaScript to do.
Now we have to handle the rest in CSS.
So let's jump over to Styles CSS.
And I'm going to add a couple of things in a few places.
So I mean, by default, we don't want this stuff to show unless the class of show is added to it.
Right.
So let's go to the div.
So this box is the ul ly div and we want to add on here a visibility of hidden and then we want to also
add an opacity value of zero.
Now when I save this and we go back, everything disappears, which is what we want because we're going
to make it so they only show if the class of show is on them, which they are right now.
But we haven't added the rest of the the CSS that we need.
So right here.
For the the right side and the left side.
We actually want to have these pushed over a little bit.
So actually, I'm going to comment what we just did out these two lines for a second, because I do
want these to show I'm going to just close this up so we can see both at the same time.
So we'll go like right here.
All right.
Now for the left and right.
We want these to come in.
This will come in this way.
So I'm going to add an initial transform value.
Of translate.
And we want to say we want to we want to do 200 pixels on the x axis.
I guess we could do translate x, but we'll just do it this way.
So translate on the x axis, 200 pixels.
Now, if I save this.
Over here, you can see that this is now pushed over 200 pixels.
And we want to go to the left side and we're going to paste this in same thing, except we're going
to do -200 pixels because we want it to be pulled over that way.
Now, once the show class hits, we want these to come in.
So basically, we want them to go to transform, transform, translate zero to bring them back.
So let's add the show class.
We'll go.
I guess we'll go right.
We'll go at the bottom here and we'll say show boxes.
We want to grab the timeline ul lie with the class of show and then the div.
Remember, the div is what is is the box really.
So we want to set transform.
To none.
Okay, because we set the transform to be offset on each side initially.
But as soon as they're shown, we want them to come in to transform none, which would just be set them
to their their natural spot.
So if I save this and I reload, you can see that the ones that have the class of show are coming in.
Now we want to make these disappear.
So let's go back up to the visibility in opacity and let's uncomment that.
So now if we save that, everything should disappear.
But if we go back down to the show, we want to set the visibility to.
Visible.
We also want to set the opacity to one which is which is just solid opaque.
All right.
So let's save this.
And now remember the when the page loads, the first three already have the class of show because they're
in the viewport.
And then I'm going to scroll down a little bit.
And as soon as the Ruby on Rails one gets in the viewport, it slides in.
Next one slides in.
So what's all that's going on with the JavaScript is it's adding the class of show.
And then in the CSS we're saying, you know, initially make everything disappear.
But as soon as that show is added to the to the DOM here to the list item, we want that div to transform
non meaning come back to its original spot and also display with the visibility visible and opacity
one.
Now the last thing I want to do is I want these dots here to be white by default.
And then as soon as the show class is comes in, then it will be blue.
So let's go up to where we created the dot, which is right here.
We used ly after and we created the 25 pixel height with border radius 50% and we have the background
set to the secondary color.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy this background secondary color and then change this one
to just inherit.
So if I save that now, they're going to be white.
But down here let's go right under where we put the the light show div and we're going to do timeline
ul ly dot show and remember the after.
That's where the dot is.
So we're going to do after and then we'll paste in the background secondary color.
So this dot is going to get the background of the secondary color when the show class is added.
So let's save.
And now you can see that the first three are blue.
This one down here is white, but as soon as it comes in, it turns blue.
All right.
So that's going to be it, guys.
Hopefully you enjoyed this little project here and learn quite a bit about CSS and transitions and how
to integrate it with JavaScript.
And don't worry if you don't understand every line of the JavaScript.
Basically though, it's just looking to see if an element, if a list item is in the viewport.
If it is, it's adding a class of show.
That's all the script is doing.
All right.
So that's it.
Thanks for watching and I'll see you in the next video.