All right, guys.
So our project is now finished, so I want to go ahead and deploy it.
I also want to give functionality to the contact form using net forms.
So I'm in my notify panel.
So you just have to sign up if you don't have an account and then log in and you can do all this for
free.
And then this is the forms documentation because we want the contact form to actually work.
So there's a few things we need to do.
First, we need to add a method of post and then this data nullify true to our form tags.
So I'm just going to grab that and go into our contact page, contact HTML and right here I have the
form tag we want method equals post and data and PHI equals true.
Now we also want name attributes for each input.
So let's say name.
This is the name field.
Let's do name equals subject.
Let's do name equals email.
Name equals.
What is this phone?
And then name equals message.
Now we also want to add some spam filtering with reCAPTCHA.
So I'm going to go back to the forms documentation and go down.
Uh, let's see.
We're going to go down to spam filtering.
Honeypot field.
No, we don't want that.
We want this explicit reCAPTCHA.
So basically, you guys have seen this before and it says, I'm not a robot.
You have to check it and sometimes you have to do those pictures.
So we want that just to stop spam from from coming in.
So what we have to do is add this attribute data, nullify reCAPTCHA equals true.
We want to add that to our form tag.
Which is right here.
So I'm going to paste that in.
And then wherever we want to put it, I'm going to go under the text area and I'm going to put a div
with the class of my dash to just to give it some margin around it.
And then we want to grab this this div right here with data recapture.
True.
And I'm going to put that right in there and save.
Now, this won't show until we deployed a PHI because the platform looks at these attributes and then
puts in the reCAPTCHA.
And I believe that's all we have to do here.
Ajax form submissions.
Yeah.
So we should be okay.
Now we have to upload this to GitHub or we have to push to GitHub.
So I'm going to go to GitHub dot com and I'm going to create a new repository.
I'm just going to call this portfolio underscore website.
I'm actually going to make this private, but you can do public if you want.
We'll just say.
Portfolio website.
And let's go ahead and create repository.
So now I have an empty repository.
So we want to go back into our project and I'm going to just use the integrated terminal down here.
But before I do anything with Git, I'm going to add in a file in my root here.
New file, I'm going to call it Dot get ignore.
And what this does is it allows you to specify files and folders that you don't want to push to GitHub.
Now we installed Node SAS, which is located in this Node Modules folder.
You don't want to push this node modules folder.
This is just dependencies of your project.
If someone wants to use your project, they'll pull it from GitHub and they'll run NPM install, which
will look at any packages you have such as Node SAS, and it will then create the Node modules folder
with those dependencies.
So we don't want to push the node modules folder.
So we're just going to put in here node underscore modules and save.
And I do want to push the dist, I want the, the sass and that's that should be it.
So we just want the node modules not to be committed.
So now let's initialize a git repository with get init and make sure you have git installed if you don't
go to get dash sim dot com and install it.
So we initialize our get repository.
Now let's do git add all.
Okay.
So now it's added to our local repository.
Let's commit it.
So get commit and we want to do dash m and then a comment.
I'm just going to say initial commit.
So it added it committed it to our local repository.
Now we want to add our GitHub repository as the remote repository that we want to use, which is this
line right here.
So you want to grab that and paste that in and run it.
So now that's added as our remote repository.
And then the last thing we want to do is this last line which is get push dash u origin master.
So we want to push to the master branch.
So clear this up and I'll say get push dash u origin master.
Okay.
So it's just pushing it to the remote repository.
Now, if I go back and I reload this page, you'll see that our project is now uploaded to GitHub.
I probably should have put this DZ store file in the git ignore as well, but that's fine.
All right.
So the project we want to deploy is in the dist.
This is what we want on net fi.
So when we deploy to nullify, we want to specify this as our build folder.
So now let's head over to Fi and I'm going to say new site from get GitHub.
And I'm going to search for portfolio.
Okay.
Let's see.
Portfolio website and the branch I want to deploy.
I only have one branch which is master.
Now the published directory is going to be DIST and it even says right here some examples are dist public
site.
So we want to do DIST because that has the HTML and our compiled CSS.
So let's go ahead and say deploy site.
Site deploy in progress.
So it should just take a second.
There we go.
So now we have our domain here.
So I'm going to go ahead and open this up and there we go.
And you can see we have a subdomain of nullify, but we could easily set up a custom domain.
I'm not going to do that in this video, though, but let's make sure that, first of all, all of our
pages show which they do that loads kind of slow.
Well, that's slow.
And you know why?
Because the images are so big, so the first load is a little slow.
So if you're going to actually use this as a production project, you probably want to resize these
images because these are really, really big images.
And I didn't I didn't optimize them at all.
So contact.
You can see we have a little reCAPTCHA here.
Let's go ahead and try this out.
So I'll say.
Kevin Smith Email address.
Kevin Subject We'll just say hello.
Phone number.
Hello.
This is a test.
I'm not a robot and submit.
Thank you.
Let's go back to our site.
Now, if we go back to our notify panel and let's reload this page.
And go down here.
There's our form submission.
Kevin Smith.
Name subject.
Hello.
Email, phone and message.
So we have a fully working site that we built with SAS, that we deployed with working contact form
that has spam filtering.
And of course you could add any fields you want.
So hopefully you guys enjoyed this project and learned a lot from it and hopefully you'll use it in
your career and in your life.
So thank you so much for watching, guys.
I really appreciate it.
And I will see you in the wrap up video that we deployed with working contact form that has spam filtering.
And of course, you can add any fields you want.
So hopefully you guys enjoyed this project and learned a lot from it and hopefully you'll use it in
your career and in your life.
So thank you so much for watching, guys.
I really appreciate it.
And I will see you in the wrap up video.