All right, guys, in this video, I want to just show you how to quickly create a CSS dropdown menu.
So we're going to create this right here.
Basically, it's just we're focusing on the menu.
And when we hit services, you'll see that we get this dropdown, we hit blog, we get a dropdown.
We also have this this area over here which displays the number of posts.
I figured it was just a nice addition.
And then we just have a simple showcase here and you could go on to to add to this if you wanted to.
But the main focus is how to get it to show you how to get this dropdown effect.
And I made it semi responsive.
So you'll see that when we hit a certain point 600 pixels, they'll still display block and we hover
over it.
We'll get this as the sub menu.
So it'll basically just push the rest of the links down and show the sub menu here.
All right, so let's get started.
I just have a folder called Dropdown.
I'm going to create an indexed HTML and let's also create a style CSS, generate our boilerplate here,
closes that up and let's say CSS dropdown menu and let's put in our style sheet.
And then we're also going to use font awesome for these little arrows right here.
So I'm just going to go to font font awesome dotcom start using free and we're going to grab this link
right here, paste that in.
Okay.
So now what we're going to do is go down to the body and we're going to start to create our HTML or
our markup body, whatever you want to call it.
So we're going to have a nav tag and we're going to give this an idea of nav bar.
And inside here we'll have a UL, we're going to have an LY with an A tag and this will be the home
home link and I'm going to copy this down.
This one will be about and then the next one is going to be services.
However, this is going to be the dropdown.
Now, I'm not going to have this be a link, so I'm going to get rid of the a tag.
I mean, you could if you wanted to, but I'm just going to have just the text and then we'll have the
dropdowns and I'm going to put the icon next to it.
So that's I with a class of face and then f a dash angle dash down.
So that will give us the icon.
And then after that we're going to put a nested list.
So another ul and let's do ly and in a tag and this is going to be web development and we'll just copy
this down a couple of times.
This next one will be, let's say, website design, and this one here is going to be mobile development
and then let's do SEO.
And then the next one is going to be the blog, which is also a dropdown.
So we want to go after this list item after the services, and we're going to say blog.
And again, we want our icons.
So face f a dash angle dash down and we're going to put UL once again and let's put a list item with
an A tag and this is going to be HTML.
Now we're going to have that that the post number as well.
So we're going to put that in a span.
So we'll say span 22 posts.
All right.
I'm going to copy this down.
Let's do that's one, two, three, four, five, six.
And we can just change these numbers up to whatever you want.
Okay, I'll do 21 and let's change these up.
So we'll do some CSS JavaScript.
Python PHP.
And we'll do one call design and then after the list item, we'll do one more.
And this is just going to be to this is going to be the contact link.
So contact.
All right, so that's our menu.
Let's save it.
Let's take a look.
It's going to look horrible.
Okay.
So it's just a list, an unordered list with some nested unordered lists.
So let's jump into our CSS and let's turn this into this.
So we'll start off with just a general reset of the margin and padding.
And let's do box sizing, board or box, and then let's do our body.
And a lot of times you'll see HTML and body like that.
And for this we're going to add a background.
Let's do a background color of light gray and let's set a font family of let's do aerial.
All right.
Now we're going to work on the nav bar.
So let's do nav bar.
The nav bar itself isn't going to have anything.
But we're going to take the UL.
We're going to do list style none.
Make sure there's no bullets.
Then we're going to deal with the list items themselves.
Basically all list items.
So let's do nav bar ul ly and we're going to set the color to dark gray, which if I save it, it's
only going to affect the ones that are not links because we have to color the link separately.
Now we want to display each of these as an inline block.
So if we do that, they'll go side by side, we'll do some padding.
So we'll save one realm of padding.
And we also want a position relative.
Basically, the way that the dropdowns are going to work is they're going to be positioned absolute
inside of this inside of the the the top ally as a container.
That way we can position it and we can add it so that we can make it so that it comes down on hover.
Now let's color the links.
So I'm going to just grab this here.
Let's say A and color will be dark gray and let's take away the underline.
So text decoration is going to be none.
Now, we want to we want to hide the nested URLs by default.
So basically anything that's in a dropdown, we don't want that to show by default.
So let me just put a comment here.
We'll say hide, hide nested UL by default and we can target that by doing nav bar ul ly ul because
we're grabbing the unordered lists that are inside the lies, and we're going to set that to display
none and save.
And now those all go away.
All right.
So let's see.
We'll go ahead and.
Okay.
Um, if I hover over these, we get, we get the cursor changes to a pointer, but not on these because
these are not links.
But I want, I want a cursor on these when we hover.
So let's do nav bar ul ly hover and let's do cursor pointer.
And I also want the background to be a different color.
So let's do background coral and let's do color white and save.
So the color white is not showing on the links, but it is on the text because we have remember links,
we have to target the color separately.
So let's just take this and say when we hover, we also want the links to have the color of white.
So now when I hover over any of them, whether it's an actual link or just text, we get the white color.
Now when we hover over these here, we want the drop.
We want the nested uls to show.
So let's do that.
Let's say nested.
Drop down show.
So we're going to do nav bar ul ly hover and we want the ul inside of that to show.
So remember we set it to display none by default.
So now we're going to set it to display.
BLOCK So now if I hover over it, we're going to we're going to see it, but it's going to it's it's
just crazy.
So we're going to fix this up.
Let's go ahead and let's do a position of absolute.
And we're going to we're going to say from the left, zero, and let's set a width to be 200 pixels.
And if you guys want to mess with this a little bit, you can.
And then I'm going to do a margin top of one REM.
All right.
So if we check it out, you can see that at least it's positioned underneath.
It's going to be 200 pixels wide.
There's no background, though.
So let's target each list item.
So I'm going to grab this right here, what we just did, and we're going to target the list item on
hover and we're going to say display block
and we're going to add a background and let's do E, we'll do e73 times.
And now if we hover, you can see that it has the background.
However, the links are white still, so we want to target the a tag when we hover.
So let's do like a and let's set the color to three, three, three.
So now the links are dark.
Now we also want a hover color for these if we hover over that.
So we'll have to do.
Let's see.
We'll have to do this.
So when we hover over the top lie we want, we're going to target the hover of the nested lies like
that.
And let's do a background.
And we're going to do e03 times.
And make sure the color.
Well, we shouldn't have to do that.
Well, we could just do color inherit.
Oops.
All right, so we'll save.
And now we have that lighter color I'm sorry, a darker color when we hover over these.
All right.
So it's starting to shape up now.
Let's deal with the spans these 22 these posts right here.
We want these to have a coral background.
I also want the color to change for those when they're hovered over.
So let's target the span.
Remember, we put those in a span, so we want this nav bar ul ly hover ul ly and then the span.
So we'll go like that and we'll say the span.
We want that to actually float to the right and we're going to make the color white and the background
coral.
We're going to add a little bit of padding.
We'll do 0.2 REM, top and bottom, 0.5 REM left and right.
Let's text align to the center.
And let's make the font size a little smaller.
We'll do 0.8 REM and let's round the corners a little bit.
So border radius and we'll do five pixels.
So let's save that.
Take a look.
Good.
And I think that's well, I also want them to change color a little bit.
So let's let's grab this.
But let's say on the list item hover.
So the inner list item hover, we want the span background to change to let's do chocolate, which is
pretty close to coral.
So as we hover over it now, you can see the background of those change.
All right.
So pretty good.
Now what I'm going to do and if you want to add a background to the nav bar, you can do that as well.
But I'm going to add our showcase area right underneath.
So did I already add it?
No, I didn't.
So in the HTML, it's going to be very simple.
I'm just going to go under the NAV and put a let's do a header showcase and all that I'm going to put
in here is an H one and just say your website here and we'll go back to our style sheet and let's grab
on to the showcase.
And let's set actually, what I'm going to do is I'm going to display this as a flex column.
So display, flex, flex direction is going to be column.
And for the height, I'm just going to do 300 pixels and then let's align everything to the center.
So we'll say align items.
Center justify.
Content center, text align.
Center.
And let's do padding zero and let's do two REM on the left and right, and let's go ahead and put our
semicolon there.
All right.
So we'll save that.
Oh, I didn't add the background.
So let's add background.
Coral.
All right.
Actually, you know what?
Let's put the let's put that in the in a variable, the color.
So we'll say for the root scope.
Let's do primary color is going to be coral.
And then we'll just change this to var dash, dash, primary color.
Grab that and go down here.
Replace that.
That way it's easy to change the color and then we could use this as a secondary color.
So up here we'll say
a secondary color chocolate.
All right.
And then for the H one in the showcase.
Let's make it color white and let's make the font size.
Let's do four REM.
Here we go.
So I have the showcase matching the hover state, which I like.
I like that effect.
And if you're on a certain page, you can do like a current a current class and have it like that.
So it actually looks like it's kind of part of the showcase.
All right.
So let's let's deal with the responsiveness, because right now, if we go like right here, it's I
mean, it goes off the screen.
So I'm just going to do a quick solution for this.
And let's add a media query with a max width of 600 pixels and we're just going to take the nav bar
ul ly and instead of displaying inline block, we're going to display block.
That way they go on top of each other.
All right.
And then let's see, we're going to take the the nested UL on hover and we're going to set it to a width
of 100% and also position it relative.
Right now, it's 200 pixels wide and it's position absolute, which means it just goes over the rest
of the content and we can't see the rest of the menu items.
I want it to basically just push everything down.
So we're going to say nav bar ul ly hover.
So we hover over it.
We want the UL to have a width of 100% and we want the position to go from absolute to relative.
We'll save that.
And now when we hover over it, we get all of our sub items and we can still go to the next one.
We can see all the menu items still.
So I mean, it's not really the best looking thing in the world, but it is a solution for if you're
for smaller screens.
But yeah, that's going to be it, guys.
A lot of these dropdown menus will involve JavaScript, but I'm trying not to get into too much JavaScript
because I don't want because I want to focus on HTML, CSS and how you can do things with just those.
And I've mentioned it before that I do have a modern JavaScript from the beginning course on Udemy as
well, but that's it.
Hopefully you enjoyed this little project.
It's just something that I thought of that I think should be included in the course is how to create
these little dropdowns and of course there's many other ways to do it.
But this is one and and I think it's pretty, pretty easy, but that's it.
Thanks for watching.
And I'll see you in the next video.