[MUSIC]
Welcome to the next section of the course.
This is Number Wizard UI, and
we're taking the code base that we
created in Number Wizard Console,
remember where we were having
a guess of higher or is it lower?
And printing that out to the console,
we're gonna take that code base and
we're gonna implement
an interactive user interface, so
that we can click buttons and
determine what happens within the game.
So this is going to mean getting
a little bit deeper into the UI canvas,
talking about anchoring, how we anchor out
elements using text, using buttons and
using images to make our game interesting.
Where in terms of the buttons, we will
link up our button functionality with our
code functionality, so
that we can have a public method
within our script that we can
call when the button is pushed.
So we've talked previously about
calling a method from another script.
Now, we're gonna call a method from
a button push, which is really cool.
Getting our fundamental
is really taking shape,
with one of this that we're up to in
terms of our game development journey.
We're going to be looking as well in a lot
of detail about scenes and scene loading.
Again, this is a foundation
that we're gonna build upon
in the later sections of the course.
The first scene we'll have will be the
welcome to the game, what is your guess?
The next scene will be the main
part of the game, which is,
is it higher, is it lower?
That's where we're doing all
the guess functionality.
If you click on this,
you've got a correct button,
then that will load up the third scene,
which will be a well done,
congratulations, game over,
would you like to play again scene.
So we'll be having those scenes that
we load and we progress through,
working through that functionality.
As well as getting our buttons hooked up
and creating a game that someone can click
and play and go through the whole game
flow, the whole game loop of the game.
Okay, so in the next video we're gonna
talk a little bit about the game design
to make sure that we're super clear on
exactly what it is that we're creating.
And then after that,
we're gonna be diving in and
creating the functionality
of Number Wizard.
So let's jump in and get started.