Hi, Unity students,
welcome to section two.
Rick is gonna be shipping
into this section from now
on a pretty much daily basis.
Rick, what are your plans for
producing Number Wizard Console and
what's it all about?
&gt;&gt; We're following the original
Number Wizard Console pretty closely, so
this is great for
people who are completely new to C#.
We're gonna be jumping in
right at what's a variable?
How do you write a method?
In the previous section,
we very quickly wrote print Hello World.
Why do we need a semicolon?
What's a statement?
So all that really foundational stuff
we'll be doing in this section.
And at the end, we'll be producing
just a simple little game that'll
allow us to flex out coding muscles.
So I've reviewed the code that Rick is
heading towards, and we've basically kept
it as Rick says exactly the same as
the classic version of this course because
literally hundreds of thousands of
students have been through that.
And apart from a little bug I
left in the original version
this is gonna be pretty much identical.
I did consider making it into something
much more grand and intelligent and wise,
but frankly,
it's right where it is it's perfect for
right where you are in your learning
journey so that's what we're going for.
So I hope you enjoy
this section with Rick.
Any other parting words of wisdom for
them Rick?
&gt;&gt; Yep, yes, is someone's already
pretty familiar with C# then
you might want to watch through
these videos at two time speed and
if you find yourself covering stuff that
you already know really well then feel
free to skip this and
go to the next section.
But, you're new to coding dive
right in now, take your time,
do the challenges and enjoy the fact that
you're really expanding your knowledge.
&gt;&gt; And I should say that the more advanced
people this section is specifically
designed to not cover very
much at all of Unity.
It is focused on basic C# just
to reinforce Rick's point there.
&gt;&gt; Yep.
Great, let's jump in and get started.