[MUSIC]
Hello and welcome to the Laser Defender
section of this course.
This is gonna be a really,
really fun section.
We're gonna make ourselves a top
down shooter, it's a space shooter.
And I've got my black background again
to recognize the fact that we're off
in space.
Let me just show you a little bit of
the prototyping I've been doing of late.
Taking the build that we had previously
and adding a little bit to it.
We've got a spaceship,
we move left and right, we shoot.
We've got enemies that
are coming in on paths.
And the enemies can shoot us.
And if they shoot us a few times,
we have a health system.
And if they shoot me enough times,
then I can die.
And when I die, we go to the screen
where it is, PLAY AGAIN.
Okay, so
lots of cool stuff that we're creating
in this particular section of the course.
And you know what, we're gonna take a step
up in terms of the depth of programming
we're going to be doing.
We'll be building upon a lot of the
systems that we've gone through before.
One good example of that
is scriptable objects.
You see I've got my scriptable
objects assets here and in that,
we can put a whole bunch of
information about the wave itself.
What we want the wave to do,
what do we want the wave to spawn,
and how often do we want it to spawn,
and what are the waypoints.
And the waypoint system that we're gonna
have in this section of the course
is not gonna be super comple.
It's gonna be very simple, it should just
go from here to here to here to here, and
you're done.
If you've gone through our Unity 3D
course, that's the other big beginner
course that we offer, then you may have
gone through our Gun Assault section.
Where we have some waypoint
system that we use and
then we go into a timeline system, so
we do a lot of that in that course.
Because it's in a 3D environment,
and because we need that very specific
things that we're looking for
in that 3D world, there's a lot of depth
in that and we go into a lot more detail.
This section's gonna be
a lot simpler in waypoints,
it's just about as simple as you can get.
Just go from here, to here, to here.
So it's a very powerful tool for
you to have.
You'll be able to see in your projects,
in the future.
Hmm, what would I like to have
just to go from there to there?
Maybe there to there and
return on a circuit.
If I have an NPC in a game, I want them to
walk there and then walk over there and
then walk back here.
Then this is the same
fundamental logic for that,
that we're going to be working on.
And because we do have this notion of
spawning particular things on a timer, so
we spawn enemies, spawn an enemy,
wait, spawn, spawn, spawn.
We have to find a way for
us to create a timed mechanism.
So we could just get there and
say spawn a thing and
then count how many seconds have gone
by and then spawn another thing.
That's the simple way to do it.
We're going to do it with a little bit
more depth and this is going to be a great
chance for you to understand how
do you do things with a delay?
How do you do things with a timer?
How do you do things so
that they repeat over and over.
There will be a lot of
cool learning in there.
So this section's all about,
let's build upon what we know already,
let's really cement some of
those things that we've done.
For example, writing public methods
in one class or one script, and
then calling them from another class or
script so that we can execute something.
Building upon our scriptable objects.
Building upon the knowledge we have and
how to trigger sound effects,
how to get some particles into our game.
Building on that, but adding some new
depth and complexity and creating,
I think, a really great landscape, a
really great canvas for you to get there.
And put your own personality into it,
put your own creativity into it
to make a cool top down shooter.
So in the next video, we're gonna talk
a little bit more about the game design,
just so we could've got our boxes to tick.
We're gonna go through that very quickly,
so we know exactly what it is that we're
creating, and then we'll be ready to start
this section and make our cool project.
So I really look forward to
seeing what you come up with.
Let's jump in and get started.