[MUSIC]
Now that we've got our title map set out,
we need to turn our attention
to game play functionality.
We need to have our player run around,
to jump, to climb ladders,
to collide with things and
possibly die, lose health.
We need to have coin pickups
that increase score.
Need to think about enemies,
having them move around,
how do we have them
stay on their platform?
And in particular, to have a look at what
happens when the player reaches the next
level, or has to load the next scene.
What is persisted?
What do we destroy?
What do we not destroy?
And look at how the code
architecture all fits together.
Together in a way which is very readable
and very usable and very scalable.
And so Ben and I have been prototyping a
lot of that and have come up with a lot of
really good answers after going through
two or three or four ways of doing that to
give you the cleanest outcome for
our particular solution to that.
And what I wanted to challenge you in
this video was to make sure you stop and
try to figure things out yourself,
and make the mistakes.
And to do things differently
to the way that we do them, so
that when we come up with the solution,
you can look at it and say, how does that
differ to what I was going to do, which is
better to have an opinion on these things.
And this is what's gonna really
strengthen you as a programmer and
as a game developer.
Don't just follow what we're doing or
else you won't get the learning.
It won't embed in there.
You won't get to the point where you
can create this yourself independently.
We've talked about a spiral syllabus a
number of times where we start off simple
and then we layer on top of that but
we keep doing those early principles, and
keep adding those early
lessons into what we're doing.
And in this section there's gonna be
a lot of things that you've done already,
you've seen already we've done it once or
we've done it twice.
And I'm gonna be challenging you to do
it yourself independently before seeing
the answer.
So if you're like me, and here's
a confession time, if you're like me,
you tend to go through these courses.
And someone says, here's a challenge for
you, you have a quick think about it and
if you know how to do it, you think,
yeah, I'll do that, not a problem.
If its a little bit challenging
you say well, I want a learning so
I just wanna see the answer,
once I've got the answer that would make
me smarter because I have that knowledge.
And it is more complex
than that if you just get
the answer you don't go through
process the good learning process.
The structured discipline practice
of trying to figure it out yourself,
which is where you really really learn.
So if you've been cruising through
the challenges, if you've been cruising
through the course, if you've
just been watching and observing.
Now is the time for you to step it up and
to take on the challenges.
And really push yourself to try to figure
it out before we give you the answer.
And on top of all that,
I'm super excited by this section.
We're gonna make a really fun game.
We'll have some really tight code
architecture by the end of it.
So let's keep pushing on and
let's get our player moving.