[MUSIC]
In this video we are gonna be making
our enemy move on our waypoints and
then destroying when it
gets to the last waypoint.
Let's jump in and get started.
Okay, so the code we're going to write
will start off by saying go to the first
waypoint so we need the position of
the enemy to be the first waypoint.
And then each frame it's going to say,
head towards wherever
the next waypoint is.
So move, move, move, move.
And when you get there or
check to see if you've got there yet.
And when you've got there then go
to the next waypoint in our list.
[COUGH] So that's the foundations of it.
We're gonna use a really cool
method called MoveTowards.
And MoveTowards takes in three parameters.
It needs to know the current position,
so in other words,
this is the current position
where the enemy is right now.
It also needs to know the target, and it
needs to know the maximum distance delta,
in other words, how fast to go.
And if we're right out our flow as some
pseudocode, then it would look like this.
And I encourage you to write out
pseudocode when you're trying to work
through a problem to say, okay,
well, what are the elements?
What's the process?
How does it flow in terms
of what I'm trying to do?
For our particular challenge at
the moment, we start off by saying,
if I haven't yet reached my last
waypoint then do these things.
And we're gonna say, otherwise,
this'll be the end of our code block.
At our pseudocode here,
we'll say otherwise destroy yourself.
So we wanna know if you've not
got there yet, then go move.
And we're gonna use MoveTowards
the target waypoint when we're moving.
And then we need to check if
we've reached the target, so
this particular waypoint we're going to.
If we have reached that waypoint, then we
want to increment our target waypoint.
So to go from waypoint one to two,
waypoint two to three, and so on.
And then, if we have reached our last
waypoint, we destroy the enemy gameObject.
I wanted to show you that rather
than just diving straight in, and
typing stuff into my script.
But we will dive in now and
start typing stuff into our script.
And the script is the EnemyPathing.cs.
So what we need to do at the top
is give ourselves a couple
a variables to be using.
First of all, we need to have an integer,
which will be for our waypoint index.
And we need to initialize this at 0.
Basically, the waypoint index
will be what index am I or
which waypoint am I
currently working toward.
And we started at 0 to say
that's the starting point.
Why is it 0 and not 1?
Well, a list,
just like an array, starts at 0.
[COUGH] Okay, we also need and
I'll put this,
I'll keep my serialized
fields together here.
I'll serialize another field for
a variable which we typed float and
this is gonna be our move speed to say how
fast do we want our enemy to be going and
I'll start this at say 2f.
Okay, so we've got our three variable.
Now, let's have a look at our pseudocode,
where you need to do an if statement that
says, if we've reached our last waypoint.
Actually, not before that in our start,
we actually need to say where to start,
we wanna do our starting
point first of all.
So where will the starting point be?
Well, the starting point is
gonna be transform.position.
So the transform.position of this
particular thing that the script is on,
our enemy pathing script is on our enemy.
So we're saying, the transform
position of the enemy, in other words,
the instance that this script is on.
Equals, [COUGH] well, here we want to
get some information from our list.
Basically we wanna say,
the transform position of the first entry,
or the 0 index in our list.
So we'll say waypoints and
we access, not waypointIndex,
we wanna say waypoints, if I can
type it properly, yes, that's right.
And then we use the same open and
close square brackets we used for
an array, this is a list we're using.
And we want to say for waypointIndex,
no, having a bit of a mess with this,
waypointIndex.transform.position;.
So our position should be the transform
position of whichever the current
waypointIndex is, and
we know we're starting waypointIndex at 0.
Okay, so basically go to position 0.
Now, in the update is
where we want to move.
And this is why I was looking
at my pseudocode in here.
If we haven't yet
reached our last waypoint,
how do write that as an if statement?
So type if(waypointIndex &lt;=,
what's it gonna be less than or equal to?
It's gonna be waypoints.count.
The reason it's count is
because we're using a list.
If we were using an array,
we would say .length.
Because an array is fixed,
we know the length,
whereas we actively have to count for
our list.
Then, we need to say -1 to make sure
that this will continue unless we
are definitely above and beyond.
So if we've gone higher than
the number of items in our list.
So that's why we do the -1.
Open up our curly braces and then we need
to create two things in here first of all.
If we go, jump back over into,
sorry, I'll just have a look.
Yep, into our MoveTowards, we need to
establish a current position, we need to
establish a target position, and
we need to establish a maxDistanceDelta.
So two of those,
we need to construct a variable for.
So we'll say, var targetPosition =,
while we're looking for
the position in the waypoint
we're moving to.
So waypoints,
what's the current active index?
That will be waypointsIndex,
and with .transform.position.
So what is the position
of the current way point?
We're heading towards would
be the target position.
And then we need another variable
which would be var movement.
We'll say, movementThisFrame,
that will be the speed we're moving at.
We're going to times this by time of delta
time, so this will be based upon a frame.
And when we frame right independent,
as we've talked about just recently.
We'll say this equals our
recently created moveSpeed,
everything is recently created,
moveSpeed * Time.deltaTime;.
Okay, so we're establishing,
this is where we want to go to, and
this is how fast we want to move.
And in the next line, we'll need
to say the transform.position of
the thing that we're on,
in other words, the enemy, equals.
And to finish this with
our Vector2.MoveTowards,
I'm gonna give this to you as a challenge.
And the challenge is to write or
finish this one line that will move
our enemy towards its target waypoint.
So that's the challenge.
Let me just leave on the screen for
you the URL, here it is,
that has the MoveTowards.
So you can see that, again,
here is the construction of it.
This is the signature.
And we have everything that we need.
So far we've created all of the elements.
So finish off that statement and
I'll see you back here in a moment.
Okie-dokie, so what do we need?
transform.position = Vector2.MoveTowards,
that's our method.
And we're taking in three things in here,
and for our signature,
we need the current.
Well, the current we know is
transform.position, that's where we
currently are, transform.position,
we've already created targetPosition.
And then we've also already
created MovementThisFrame;.
Okay, and this is big line, so
I'm just going to put an indent, or
a return after MoveTowards and
before our parameters.
Okay, just to tidy things up a little bit,
we having our MovingTowards.
Now, what do we need to do?
Back over to our pseudocode here.
We need to check to see if
we've reached the target, and
if so, to increment the target waypoint.
So the way we do that is, we need another
if statement, and it'll be if, what?
Transform.position is the same as or
equals, but
it's equals-equals, targetPosition.
Then, what do we want to do?
Open our curly braces, we say,
waypointIndex needs to increment by 1.
So that's waypointIndex++;,
I'm gonna put a little line in here
just to keep it nice and
clean in terms of our space.
You don't have to, but
that just helps me see what's going on.
And then as the very last step in this
whole process we need to align ourselves
where our if is need to
be putting in an else.
What we're saying in here is so,
if we still have a valid waypoint,
then do all the moving.
Otherwise, or else, we will say Destroy,
what are we destroying?
We're destroying the gameObject;.
Okay, and as a very final step
I will highlight all of my
code within update to there.
I'll right-click and just factor this out,
so it's not sitting there in our
update method looking all busy.
And we'll call this Move as our method.
Okay, so now when we look at update,
we're saying, move, and
if we wanna do other things in update
it would be nice and clean and
our whole Move code is sitting just below.
Okay, let's save that, jump over into
Unity, check that this is all worked.
It doesn't really matter where
our enemy is on our screen.
When we tidy all of this up, we won't
actually have this enemy on the screen.
We'll be instantiating an enemy
from our prefab asset, but for now,
we're going to use this one that's on
the screen that we've dragged into.
We've instantiated ourselves
by dragging it in.
We have the way point on there, we have
the three way points in our script.
So let's click on Play and
see what happens.
It jumps to the first point, moves to the
second, and then goes off to the third and
then it should [SOUND] destroy itself,
fantastic.
If you wanted to make your
enemy move more quickly,
then we could change
the move speed to say, 5,
not 56, to 5, click Play and then it
should move faster through that flow.
There we go, boink, boink, excellent.
So there it is,
there's the foundation of our pathing.
And our waypoint system, you can lay
down as many waypoints as you want.
You can have a nice elaborate path
that zigzags through the screen.
We're gonna do it coming off screen,
do some action and
then off screen again
after the enemy goes away.
So this is really cool,
this is a great foundational piece.
Foundational piece that we can
build the rest of our game on.
Great work and
I'll see you in the next lecture.