[SOUND]
In
this video we're gonna take a moment to
just finish off the polish for our game.
We'll update our title using TextMesh Pro,
I'll take you through the process
on how to use that and we'll just
put a little bit of flair into our color
to try to get it to match our fame.
So let's do some polishing of our game.
Unity has a lot of goodies that we
can find in our Package Manager.
So let's go out to Window, and
then scroll down and see Package Manager.
Click on Package Manager, and you'll
see the first button here, In Project.
These are the things that we
currently have in our project.
Click on All, it will show you all of
the available packages that we can access
to add more functionality to Unity.
I'm gonna look all the way down the bottom
here I can see TextMesh Pro, click on
Install, whatever number it says for you
that should be the latest install that.
Click on that, wait for
it to work its magic.
It will probably do some importing and
some compiling and
some just general thinking and
grinding behind the scenes.
When it's finished doing that, you will
see In Project you'll see TextMesh Pro.
After you have TextMesh Pro installed,
close the Packet Manager,
head up to Window, scroll down and
find TextMesh Pro.
Now, if like me,
it doesn't exist, it's not there,
it's not down the bottom of your Window
list here, what I had to just now was
close Unity and restart Unity and
there it is, TextMesh Pro.
So if you're not finding it there,
you might need to do a restart.
So if you've got TextMeshPro,
click on the Font Asset Creator.
And again we'll have another
set of importing to do.
It asks us to import the TMP,
TextMesh Pro, essentials.
Click on Import.
Again, wait for it to work its magic.
This is all stuff that's useful but
takes a little bit of time to do.
Little bit of time to set up.
Once we've done it once on our project,
we won't need to do it again.
And just to be thorough and complete
we'll import the other examples and
extras just in case you want to play
around some more in TextMesh Pro
will have those imported just so
everything, we've got it all.
We've got all the things that
we have access to at the moment.
After that, you can close this
TMP importer window, close that.
Now we have the Font Creator
window in front of us.
Now the first thing we need
to do is create some font.
TextMesh Pro needs to take in font and
then generate its own
font atlas from that.
So, let's go find a font to use.
I've given you a link in the resource
is to dafront and you can search for
whatever seems to make sense to you.
So I could search for steam punk for
example cuz that's what I'm using.
I know that when I search for steam punk
I'm not gonna get a lot of hits, so,
I just search for punk.
And I've searched this search
earlier after I searched for punk,
I found there are a whole
bunch of them and
I scrolled all the way down the bottom and
found this one.
It's called the TC Fuzzy punky slippers.
So, font is a very personal thing.
Search for what you want, have a look
at what you want, see if it works.
Try to match it to the theme of your game,
that's pretty important.
But at the end of the day, it's up to you.
One thing I will say is that I'm
looking for 100% free fonts.
Under font, you can see it says 100%
free or free for personal use, or
donation ware, or you have to pay for it.
For now I'm just looking for 100% free.
Make sure you always know the licensing
agreement before you go and
put your font into your game.
Make sure you're fair to
the person who created it and
abide by whatever licensing they ask for.
So once you found your font,
click on Download.
That will download your font file.
Go and find that in the folder
where it's downloaded.
It's for me, it's over here.
It will provide a zip file so
we'll unzip that.
I'm just right click dragging and
saying extract here.
And if you don't have
a way of unzipping or
you're not sure how to unzip then that
might be a quick google search for you,
how to unzip on what particular
platform you're using.
It's gonna be different on Mac, different
on Windows, you might have something
installed already so I'm not gonna dig
in to all the different ways to unzip.
That might be a google
search if you don't.
If it's not as easy for you as it was for
me just right clicking it then having
Extract Here or Unzip Here as an option.
Now that we have our font file,
you can see here our VTC fuzzy
punky snippets or
whatever your particular font is.
I'm gonna head back over into Unity.
Just pop this window out of the way for
a moment and I will find, I'll make a new
folder actually, new folder,
Create Folder I'll call this fonts.
Double click on that so
I'm within the fonts folder.
Jump back to my Windows
where I have the font file.
I can drag the font into Unity.
And you can see it's sitting there.
It knows that it's a font file, wonderful.
Bring back my Font Creator window here.
We can navigate to Window,
TextMeshPro, Font Asset Creator
if you happen to misplace it.
Here we go.
Now, I drag in the font that I found
into where it says Font Source.
Or I could have clicked
the selector as we usually do.
And I will leave everything default,
generate font atlas.
Again, a little bit more thinking.
There’s a lot of thinking [LAUGH].
Thinking, importing, and
creation in this process.
But once we’ve got it done,
we won’t have to do any more
of this thinking and creating.
It will be done.
Okay, there we go we've
created our font atlas.
Now we can do a save.
It will ask us where we want it to save.
I'm gonna save it into
fonts just as it is, Save.
Wonderful, now we have a font atlas
that is a .asset file that has all
of the information in it that TextMesh Pro
needs to be able to work its magic.
Back over into our canvas,
I am going to right-click and
create UI &gt; TextMesh Pro text,
that will give us a new piece of text.
I will just resize my windows a little
bit here so I can see it nice and easily.
Drag it up over to where we
currently say My Name Game.
What if we called
My Game Name here Title Text.
I'm going to delete Title Text, we don't
need that anymore, thank you very much.
And our TextMesh Pro Text I'm
gonna rename that to Title Text.
You are now the champion of Title Text,
you've ousted the pretender.
[LAUGH] Here it it.
And once again we can type
into the box just in here.
We can type in whatever our
game is gonna be called.
For now I'm still waiting for
you guys to let me know what you
think my game should be called.
For now I'll call it steam,
no that's a little bit too obvious,
we'll call it air ship.
No, I'm gonna call it the injured pilot,
there we go.
That was part of what I
had in my design document.
The injured pilot, why not.
It doesn't really tell us anything
about the steam punkiness of it.
But for now that shall be my placeholder.
A lot of things,
when you're making a game.
You'll have these titles and
you'll have the name of your project.
Don't get too attached to it at the start.
Wait until you've had people play your
game and you get a feel for it and
then you can do your name later on.
Name something I find you don't
really lock in until the very end.
Okay, same with before.
We've got our usual kind
of font settings in here.
We can send for
a line by finding our alignment button.
We can align within the middle of the box.
I'm gonna make a little bit more
room right now [INAUDIBLE] so
you can see it all.
We can select the middle,
change the font size.
We'll make the font size here what, 80?
You know what I should do is select the
font that we just took all that time to
bring into our project.
Going to drop down our properties
down here so it's not in the way.
Let's see, where do we find our font.
It's right in here, Font Asset.
Click on our Button selector.
We’re looking for
VTC Fuzzy Punky Slippers or
whatever your font was
that you just brought in.
Double-click on that and
then you can see a much more
interesting font than we’ve got here.
I think again it needs to be a little
bit larger so I’ll pop mine up to 120.
Okay, there we go.
I’m not gonna finesse too much on
camera cuz you can finesse yours.
It doesn’t need to look
exactly the same as mine.
But there we go.
We've got some interesting font.
You could do the same
thing with your text font,
I'd recommend not doing the same heading
font as you do for your text font.
You wanna have it a little bit different,
this needs to be a lot more readable,
this is more sort of for
the theme and the style of it.
Before we jump off TextMesh Pro, I should
show you a couple of other things in here.
There's a whole lot of,
if I'm clicked on title text,
there's a whole lot of other options in
here so we can change the color of it.
I can change the color
to maybe a dark red.
I'm gonna get to colors in
this video in a moment.
We can have an outline on our font here.
I'm going to change the thickness of it,
so it's nice and thick.
We can have and underlay,
a bevel, lighting.
So, that lighting will give
a little bit of a sheen to it and
change where the lighting is coming from.
Maybe a yellow and
we'll do the light angle over this way.
And then what we need to do, which I
often forget to do is click the Enable.
When you click enable then that will
allow this particular setting to
actually be used.
And so when you move things around you
might see a little bit of difference,
there we go, now I'm seeing a little bit,
not a lot using this lighting setting with
the way that I've got
my other things set up.
And bump map we're not gonna dig
into too much at the moment,
Glow is the other thing that I
find actually has an impact.
So we click the Enable and
scroll in a little bit here.
You can see that there is a little bit of
this green glow if I offset it a little
bit, then it's moved around.
So, I'm not really going for something
that I think will look good just at
the moment, I'm just showing you some of
the functionality and how to enable it by
clicking on the box and then just
twiddling around with the sliders.
So this is an introduction to TextMesh
Pro, as opposed to an intermediate, or
advanced, how do we make our text look,
award winning.
We're just getting to the point
where we know how to use the tool.
So this is my font for now.
What I need to do next is figure out
how I'm gonna manage all my colors.
So I know it shouldn't have a bright
green outline, probably not.
And let's talk about colors
a little bit for a moment.
First thing I'm going to do is show you
where I get some inspiration for colors,
so jumping over to the Adobe Color Picker.
I call it the Adobe Color Picker.
I don't think it's its official name,
but Adobe Color CC.
I've given you the link for
this in the resources as always.
You can see in here it shows some
harmonious color relationships, so
we've got these five colors
as Imove the sliders around,
we kind of get this sort
of feel that I'm going for.
If we select it on Complementary,
it will show me complementary.
If I select on say Monochromatic, it will
show me all of the similar kind of color.
And there as we move this around and
then you can see below is where we capture
the information for each of these.
What I'm gonna do is search for a color
scheme cuz I'm not much of a color wizard.
So I'm gonna come out to Explore,
you see a search box up here,
I'm gonna type is steam punk and stand on
the shoulders of giants as they say and
I like this particular theme over there.
These colors are like those colors.
So if you click on Edit Copy
you can come in here,
see the colors that have been selected.
Click on a particular one.
We're after the hex value.
Highlight the hex value,
copy that, jump back into Unity.
What shall we have is that dark green.
Maybe we will have our
camera background that.
So my main camera,
click on the background.
And down the bottom of our color
selector we have our hex of decimal,
blink, there we go.
We've got a greeny color.
And back over into hue, what shall
we have is some of our other colors.
We'll go with this other
different greeny color.
Grab that, copy, back over into Unity,
we'll do that for maybe for our heading.
Find the story back note,
the title background.
Well named, thank you.
And paste in there for our hex value and
that looks pretty gross but
we haven't changed the color
on our heading just yet.
So I'm gonna finesse mine a little bit,
play around with it.
You don't need to see the exact
values that I'm using,
cuz I don't want you
to match mine exactly.
I want you to play around
with your own colors and
do something that you think that works.
But I'm gonna take a couple of
minutes to play around with my values.
I'd like you to do the same.
I've got a challenge for
you which is Polish The Look of your Game.
Consider colors, consider your theme.
If it's a steampunk theme,
you might wanna search for
steampunk colors as I've just done.
Use TextMesh Pro, at least for the title,
also for the main font if you would like.
And then any other details you would like.
Play around with it.
Add some flares, add some finess, and
then please I beg of you share
a screenshot in our Facebook group or
our GameDev.tv community site cuz I
would love to see what you've come up.
I would love to see your creation.
So post a video, jump in,
do a bit of finessing with that.
When you come back I'll just briefly
show you what I've done, and so
you can see the conclusion of my polish.
See you in a moment.
Okay, welcome back.
I've gone for a bit of a brown theme here.
I've added these rectangles at the back.
I've just called them story backgrounds,
stripe 1 and 2.
Just to put a little flair back there.
Click on the Play button
to show you full screen.
And this is how my game looks.
Played around with TextMesh Pro it takes,
so the colors aren't critical, you don't
need to copy the colors that I have used,
use whatever colors your heart desires.
I'm deliberately not showing them
to you to force you to go ahead and
pick your own colors and create this
the way that you want it to look rather
than just doing a copy and
paste of what I have done.
So now that we finished polishing
our colors and putting a little bit
of detail on our text, that concludes
the functionality aspect of this section.
So great work,
you’ve made yourself a game engine.
It looks pretty good, and
you can give this to people to play so
they’ve got a full game experience.
Well done, and
I’ll see you in the next video.