[MUSIC]
Okay, exciting times in this video,
we are going to create a spawner that
will pump out a whole bunch of attackers.
We'll create five spawners, actually,
using our spawner script and
co-routines and some randomness.
So this is starting to look a little
bit like a game, let's jump in and
get started!
Okay, let's start this framework together,
and then I'm gonna give you a pretty meaty
programming challenge,
hopefully you'll find it meaty.
So first of all,
I need a concept of a spawner.
So right-click, create empty,
we'll call this spawner,
hit Enter, reset the transform.
Now, where do we wanna spawn?
We want to have them spawn over
on the right here, so I will move
my spawner just to the top right,
I think this is gonna be an okay place.
Remember, in my design,
I'm not placing defenders on these two.
So you kind of wanna have it
up here from on the screen.
That's a good spot for
our first spawner, we can finesse
the position a little bit more later on.
Now to move my trophy just
a bit out of the way so
to simulate the fact that it would
be placed there in the game.
And then this lizard, I will just
move it a little bit out of the way.
But he is the sort of guy that we wanna
have spawn, how do we need him to spawn?
Well, we need to turn him into a prefab,
so
grab a lizard, drag it down into Prefabs.
We wanna be spawning, and instantiating
prefabs is the way for us to do it.
So I now have a lizard prefab, over here,
we'll drag the trophy down, so
we have a trophy prefab.
And while we're here, we'll drag the
spawner down, so we have a spawner prefab.
What else can we prefab while we're here?
You know what,
let's prefab the canvas, there we go.
And why not the camera as well?
There we go, this is how you do
it when it comes to prefab-ing.
Anything you can prefab,
you should prefab.
Okay, now jump over in our scripts folder,
I will right-click, create
a C# script that I will call, should
I call it Spawner or AttackerSpawner?
I'm gonna call it AttackerSpawner,
because in the future,
I think I'll be spawning
defenders as well, maybe.
So we'll call it AttackerSpawner, so it's
super clear, and it also makes it right
next door to the Attackers script,
I find that pretty useful.
Let's open up AttackerSpawner script, and
I'm just gonna give you one thing in here
as a starting point,
then I'll give you the challenge.
And that is,
we need a bool that is called spawn, and
we'll start that off as being true.
So we're saying that when this
spawner script comes into action,
which, you know what,
back over into Unity, let's actually put
it back on our spawner, so we have that.
Drag that AttackerSpawner script
onto there, great, got it.
Now back into our
AttackerSpawner script itself.
We wanna saw that spawn is this notion of,
can you be spawning, or
can you not be spawning.
At the start, we'll say true, cuz what
I wanna do at the end of my level,
I want to stop spawning.
I need to stop things spawning, so
we'll have that as part of our mechanism.
What is the mechanism, I hear you ask?
Well, this is your challenge,
to spawn the attackers.
So to turn our Start method
into a coroutine, so
that when that Start method is
called at the very start of
when the script comes alive,
we want this coroutine to start.
And while our spawn bool is true,
to keep spawning.
And then, a little bit of extra flavor,
I want you to spawn randomly between
one second and five seconds.
So creating this coroutine's not gonna
produce anything on the screen just yet,
but see if you can get this shape.
What I mean by that is,
nothing is actually gonna spawn just yet
cuz we're not creating our spawn method.
You can do that if you want, but
this is to create the coroutine, and
the structure for
spawning between one and five seconds.
So jump in, give that your best shot, and
I'll see you back here when you
have given it a good old try.
Okay, so let's turn our Start
method here into a coroutine.
And we do that by, I think we know
we use this for initialization, so
I'll delete the comment.
So we write in,
if I delete this correctly, IEnumerator.
Okay, IEnumerator Start, still needs to
be called Start, put in our parentheses.
Open our brackets, close our brackets, get
rid of that extra bracket that was from me
not knowing how to delete things properly.
And within here, what do we want to do?
Well, first of all, I'm going to
use my bool to say while(spawn),
which is saying while(spawn) = true,
but we can just write while(spawn).
What do we wanna do, well, we need to do
our yield because it's an IEnumerator.
yield return new,
I've done this a few times now.
WaitForSeconds, how many
seconds we wanna wait.
Well, this is where we can just put
in here 1 and then we're done, or
we could do a little bit of randomness.
So I wanna do some randomness,
Random.Range,
with a capital R, Random.Range.
And then we'll have some concept
of a minimum spawn delay,
through to a maxSpawnDelay, and
then our semicolon at the end.
So let's go and create these, I'm gonna
copy that up to the very, very top.
We'll have a serialized field that will
be, what, a float, I think we need
this to be, called minSpawnDelay,
and we'll initialize that at 1F.
So it's one second at the start, and
then I'm gonna copy that whole line and
then paste that whole line below it.
We have a serialized float, minSpawnDelay,
this'll be a maxSpawnDelay.
And we will have this at, I'm gonna say 5,
I think that's what I asked you to do in
the challenge today, yes, 5, so
I'd better do that as well, okay.
Cool, so that's all looking pretty good.
We've got our coroutine
with our randomness,
now we need to spawn something,
what do we need to spawn?
Well, let's go and create our method,
so I'm gonna yield first, and
then spawn second.
So that I have a little bit of that
randomness happens at the very start.
You could put the spawn above the yield,
so everything would be like blink, and
spawn immediately with no delay.
But, I think this way allows
us to have a bit more control.
So do your delay first, however long that
needs to be, and then SpawnAttacker.
We haven't created that yet, so
we'll get red squiggly lines.
Let's create our SpawnAttacker
just underneath,
so private void SpawnAttacker, okay.
And then I'm gonna keep
it really simple for now.
We'll add more complexity to this
as we go, and as the need arises.
But for now,
we'll just do our instantiate,
instantiate, and
what do we know about instantiate?
Well, it's going to be looking for
an object, and what is the object?
We haven't told it what the object is yet,
we need to create a serialized field.
We need to be able to assign to our
spawner which particular game object, and
so for now, we'll keep it simple.
We'll just have the lizard,
which we've just gone and prefabbed.
So at the top, we'll create
a new variable serialized field.
We could make this Attacker type,
okay, let's do that, yeah,
I think, so of type Attacker.
So that means we can only be dragging
into our field Attacker type.
We could make a game object,
then any game object could be dragged in.
We'll say this is the attackerPrefab
Okay, save that, now down here,
what are we instantiating?
Well, we're instantiating
the attackerPrefab,
where do we want to do that?
Well, we wanna do a transform.position, so
where we currently are, and
then what is the rotation?
Well, we can just do rotation.position,
we could do the quaternion approach.
Both of those work just fine,
but we'll say rotation.position,
so whatever our rotation is at the moment.
Sorry, my bad, transform, back to front,
trying to speak and type at the same time.
Transform.rotation, there we go,
that's the way we actually type that.
Now what we should be doing here is
spawning our attacker, instantiating,
let's see how this works,
I'm sure we'll find an issue or two.
I will just remove my current lizard, so
we're not getting confused by what
that little guy down there is doing.
Delete him, and then we need to find our
spawner and assign our attacker prefab.
By finding where our prefabs are,
dragging over Lizard,
[SOUND] there we go, found it.
Click on Play, watch for
any errors in the console.
And then there should be a little bit of
a delay, then [SOUND] the guy comes out.
And he's not moving because we,
[SOUND] and then another spawn,
[LAUGH] another spawn.
Because in the last video, you probably
noticed, when I was playing around with
my lizard and giving it an attack,
we left the default to 0 of walk speed.
So I'll put this walk speed to 1, and
I update, remember to update your
prefab if you're working on a game
object that's in the scene.
If you're working directly on the prefab,
then you won't have that option
cuz it's updated already.
So let's try this one more time,
we'll see how this looks when we have
an attacker jump onto
the screen after a short delay.
[SOUND] And then walk, walk, and
another one, [SOUND] walk, walk.
And a little bit of extra excitement,
let's duplicate our spawner.
I'm gonna call this spawner,
I'm gonna go from rows one, no, actually,
back to front here.
Because this coordinates down the bottom
is 1, 1, that's 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5.
So the top one is 5 and
the bottom one is 1, so
I will drag this down to the bottom,
rename it as Spawner1, okay.
Just cuz it's lane one, it's grid position
one, the coordinates are one on here,
you can see it's close-ish to one.
And then we will duplicate that,
two, three, four, five.
2 we'll put into lane number two,
3 we'll put into lane number three.
These should all have our
spawner script already on them,
it should know exactly what to do.
5 we'll put up to five, and now when
we click on Play, we should have a mad
cacophony of lizards leaping onto the
screen, short delay, welcome to the level.
There we go, attack, one, two, three,
here they all come, this is great.
And like I said before, there's a little
bit of messiness with our animation, but
that's something we will
tune as time goes on.
But look at that wave of
enemies coming along.
Probably noticed that,
cuz of our position of the lizard and
stuff, we need to move our
spawner up a little bit.
That'll get it just looking
a little bit tidier.
That's the only finesse I'll do for
now, because we will be doing lots of
positioning finesse and
polishing later on.
That's pretty good, how cool is that?
We've got some attackers
running into our game.
We do need some defenders to stop them
getting to the end of the base, but
great progress.
Well done, I'll see you in the next video.