[MUSIC]
In this video, we're gonna create
our first wave ScriptableObject,
our WaveConfig file, which will have
the enemy prefab, path prefab and
some information about
the spawning itself.
So let's jump in, talk about
the structure of what we're doing and
create our first wave configuration.
Yeah, let's talk about enemy waves.
First of all,
we will be spawning enemy waves.
Spawn X enemies, for example,
11 as I have here going along a path.
We've already created our path or
at least a framework for it.
And there's a whole bunch of information
that we need our wave to have.
So we want our wave to have
a particular enemy type.
For example, this guy, we'll call him
Roger the Orange Thai Fighter and
we need to have a certain speed
that Roger will be flying.
We need to know how many Rogers we'll be
spawning, and also the spawn rate, so
how fast the various Rogers can
add [LAUGH] onto the screen.
Is that working, calling him Roger?
I'm not sure if it is.
Anyway, you get the point.
We need to have things spawning, and
as much data as possible we want to have
sitting in our ScriptableObject
asset file and
not scattered around on the various
places within the script.
We wanna shove as much data as
we can In that ScriptableObject.
Okay, so let´s have a look
at which script owns what,
cuz it´s gonna be getting
a little bit complicated.
And we´ll be having a few scripts that are
accessing information from other scripts
in this particular project.
So we need our Enemy Spawner,
as a script to say pushing
things into the world under the.
We need the enemy itself
with its behavior.
We need the Wave Config and
we need the enemy pathing,
which we've already created
in previous lectures.
So what is in each of these,
the enemy spawner,
I'll be putting in the order of the wave.
So wave one, and then wave two, and then
wave three, and then maybe wave one again,
and then wave two and so on.
We need to spawn each wave, so the Enemy
Spawner needs to say radio wave one,
spawn yourself and
then spawn each enemy within the wave.
Okay, wave one, enemy one, go,
enemy two, go, enemy three, go.
Okay, there was only three,
now we need to go into wave number two.
So that's all in the enemy spawner.
The enemy.cs needs to
hold the enemy sprite.
So Roger is gonna be
this orange Thai fighter.
We need to know what this sprite looks
like, how many hit points this enemy has,
the shooting behavior, how fast it shoots,
what sort of damage it does, and so on.
And the score, if you kill this enemy,
needs to be sitting on the enemy itself.
So it's nice and clean, and the enemy
death sound effects and visual effects.
Okay, our wave config,
this will be our ScriptableObject file.
In here we need the path's
waypoint data and
then also we need to know
which enemy prefab to use.
And the enemy prefab is gonna have
all of this information over here.
We need to know the, I don't have
my laser pointer on, there we go.
We need to have the spawn speed for
the wave.
We need to know how many enemies.
And we need to know
the movement speed of the wave.
So the spawn speed is say,
spawning one every one second.
Whereas the movement speed is
when you get onto the screen,
you move it five units per second.
So that information I think we
should have on the wave config.
Then the enemy pathing, well,
we've already created a bunch of that.
That's just saying,
move the enemy along the current path.
Where do we get the current path from?
Well, we need to be getting
that from the enemy spawner.
The enemy spawner is saying things like,
okay,
how many enemies are in
my particular wave?
So the enemy spawner is grabbing
information from the wave config.
The enemy spawner is pushing
information to the wave pathing or
the enemy pathing is grabbing
from the enemy spawner.
So there's a lot of
interconnected relationships.
But the first step is to say where are we
putting the various pieces of information?
So I've spent a bunch
of time on this just so
you're clear when we're
typing up our scripts.
You're not saying where are we?
What are we doing this for?
How does it all make sense?
I wanna make it super clear.
This is the game plan.
So let's jump in and create ourselves
our ScriptableObject script.
First of all, we'll go in our Scripts
folder, right-click, and Create.
We will create a C# script,
and I will call this
our WaveConfig and then hit Enter.
Okiedokie, open up WaveConfig.
This is where we will change
it from a MonoBehaviour
file to being a ScriptableObject file.
And as soon as it opens up, okay,
so instead of MonoBehaviour,
we are having this as a ScriptableObject.
Excellent, and as we've done
previously with scriptable objects,
the one other time that we've worked
on scriptable objects in this course,
we want to create ourselves a menu so
that we can add this into our scene.
So open up our square bracket say,
CreateAssetMenu.
And then, we need a name for this, so
menuName =, what's it going to equal?
We'll call this Enemy Wave Config.
So if English is not your first language,
or if video games is not your first
language, then Config is just
a short way of saying configuration.
Configuration is the way
that things are arranged.
So config is kind of a word that
we use for data files like this.
Okay, we'll save that.
We'll just check this work, okay,
I'm going to just put it anywhere near.
I'm just testing it.
I'm not actually creating at the moment.
Right click anywhere in our assets area,
Create, and
enemy wave config is there already, cool.
You know what I will do.
I will create one of these.
We'll call it wave 1.
Now we're gonna have a little bit of
fun figuring out how to name our waves,
because in my particular game I'm gonna
have Wave 1 and then 2, and then 1 and
then 3 and then 2.
So the wave here is
the identification of it.
It's not necessarily the order
that it comes out in.
So you could call it wave A or
wave B or wave 72 or Jeremy the froggie
wave, whatever you wanna do.
For now I'm just gonna say wave
1 until I get to the point where
I think I need a different waving
convention, waving convention?
Maybe it's a naming convention, Rick.
Okay, so I'll give myself a new folder,
just to tidy all of this up.
Create Folder, Waves, and
then where did we stuff that a moment ago?
We had it in Scripts,
drag Wave1 into Waves.
There we go, we've got our first wave.
Nothing in there as of yet, let's rectify
that back over into our WaveConfig.cs.
I'm gonna eliminate my Start and Update,
we won't be needing those and
creating ourselves some variables.
So we'll do some SerializedField.
First one I'll say GameObject,
what should we create?
We'll start off by saying what our
enemy prefab is, so enemyPrefab;.
I'll just put all of these in here for
now,
all the things that I think we'll need.
Next up I will do SerializedField again.
SerializedField, this will
also be a GameObject cuz
I would like to put in the pathPrefab.
So we've already created both of these,
enemyPrefab and pathPrefab.
Now I will create another SerializedField.
I'll serialize a float.
And this float will be
time between spawns.
That's how quickly we want
our enemies to spawn.
I'll initialize this at 0.5f,
f, okay, cuz it's a float.
And I'll create another one.
And this is where I'd like to give
myself a little bit of randomness so
they're not coming out exactly at 0.5,
0.5, 0.5,
which can be a little bit dull and
a little bit obvious.
So I'll create a spawnRandomFactor.
And I'll initialize this at 0.3.
And this randomness just makes our game
feel a little bit more organic and
not quite so rigid.
You want to get that organic-ness
into your game wherever you can and
not have things look really
super predictable and
robotic, unless you're making
a robotic game, of course.
Okay, SerializeField,
[LAUGH] robotic game, this will be an int.
The next one we'll have numberOfEnemies,
Enemies, and
I know this is a lot of you
following me at the moment.
I'll give you a chance to write
your own stuff in just a moment.
But we'll crack these out.
I'm gonna initialized 10,
no, I'll say 5 in a wave.
Doesn't matter, it's very easy, it's fine.
Not an f cuz it's an int.
Very easy for us to change this
in our ScriptableObject but
we just want something to start with,
so 5 I think's pretty good.
And then the last one we'll do for
now, SerializeField float,
this will be moveSpeed.
So tthe moveSpeed of the enemies
that are in this particular wave.
And we'll start with 2,
2f, and we'll save there.
Okay, so
this is the data that we want to have in
each of our Wave Configuration files.
At this point you're welcome to put more
in as we go along, that's totally cool.
And the next step is for
us to give a way for
our other scripts to
access this information.
And so
we'll create our first public method.
Let's say public, and this will be
whatever our first one up here,
GameObject, so GameObject.
And basically I'm gonna say get and
then the particular information
that we've got there.
So I'll say GetEnemyPrefab
will be my method.
And typically,
this is the way that we create.
We give ourselves a new line and
then we have our curly braces.
And within here I would
say return enemyPrefab.
Okay, and we've been through this
before in previous sections.
So I'm just trying to reinforce this
aspect of scriptable objects that we have
the data is sitting within here and
then other scripts are welcome to come and
pull from that and get that information.
Now, to conserve space a little bit,
cuz we're gonna have one of these, so
one of these public methods for
each of our pieces of data in here.
I'm going to pull my return
up onto the same line.
It's totally cool to do this.
And like that, so there it is.
We need to do this for
the remainder of our variables, which
is where I've got a challenge for you.
And that is to complete
the public methods for each.
And take note of the fact
that I'm saying for
each because in an upcoming video we're
gonna be talking about for each loops.
So conceptually I'm saying, for each of
our WaveConfig variables, so for this one,
and this one, and this one, and this one,
which is what a for each is saying.
So for each of those, create a public
Get method which returns the variable,
just as I did for the first one.
Okay, should be pretty straightforward.
Just follow what I have done and
I'll see you back here in a moment.
Okay, now shall I cheat and
do some copy pasting?
I think I will.
And paste will say public,
it's a GameObject, yes.
Get, what are we getting?
GetPathPrefab will be the name of this
method and return the pathPrefab.
So just using that information from there.
Okay, so the next one is going
to be time between spawns.
So again, public, and we need to
return the type that this variable is.
So we need to say public float,
GetTimeBetweenSpawns,
and we need our parentheses and
return timeBetweenSpawns,
okay, and semicolon after that.
Right, now I will copy this one,
cuz it's a float.
Copy that, GetSpawn, sorry,
GetSpawnRandomFactor, okay.
Hopefully, you did this well and
you had no worries with it so
I'm just validating what you've
got on your screen already so
be SpawnRandomFactor.
And then we need an int,
and I'll paste here.
Even though if it's not an int,
I can just change that float to an int,
how easy was that?
Okay, GetNumberOfEnemies and
then return numberOfEnemies.
And we shall have one more, which will
be public, it is a float, it's gonna
be GetMoveSpeed return moveSpeed.
Everything looks pretty honky dory.
Back over into Unity,
we'll have a look at Wave 1.
Give Unity a moment to recompile and
think about things, and
you can see that we've got all of this
data sitting here ready to be populated.
The enemy prefab, so clicking our prefabs
folder, drag over the enemy prefab.
There we go, the path prefab,
we need to click in the paths and
drag over the parent.
And at the moment that's
not gonna mean much but
we will update that in the next video
in terms of what that will mean.
Okay, so that's it for now.
We've given ourselves our
first ScriptableObject wave.
Excellent work,
nothing's gonna be changed.
Just at the moment we need to hook it up,
but we are well on our way.
Great work and
we'll see you in the next video.