[MUSIC]
Hello again,
welcome to our instructor hangout.
We've got Ben with us here.
Good day Ben.
It's been a while since we've seen you.
How have you been doing?
&gt;&gt; Good day Rick.
How are you doing sport?
I'm fine mate, thank you very much.
I've been away for
a little trip so I'm back now and
looking forward to helping out.
&gt;&gt; Cool, cool.
So what we're gonna go through in this
video is, we're gonna go through some of
the things that we've dug into
throughout this section and
get Ben's take on what we've been doing.
I said at the start of this course it's
good to hear things from different
perspectives, angles.
So we're gonna get Ben to give us
his take on what we've been doing.
And the first thing I wanna dive
into is a good meaty conversation.
We've had some questions about state
versus state versus state and so
we use the word state about 1,000 times.
And a little bit of why
have we got state state?
What does that mean?
Just to touch on that and to get your
thoughts, Ben, on how do we know, for
example, that we can access our
public method in the state class.
What in here is telling us
that we can access that?
But first, a really quick note when
Ben and I were goofing around,
we've commented out this line of code just
while we're experimenting and talking.
Don't comment out that line of code,
don't follow what we've done
with that particular line.
Leave it as it is,
you don't need to comment it out.
Okay, back to it.
&gt;&gt; Okay, so first thing I want you to pay
attention to the coloring,
here, and the capitalization.
So state state is saying that we wanna
make a variable called state with a small
s and is of type state.
Now why are we calling it state state,
why use the same word twice?
Simply because as you get more experience,
you will use the same word twice because
your eye will be attuned to two things.
To the capitalization, which of course
we're hoping that you are nice and
good people and make your actual things,
your instances, with lowercase.
But the thing that's more robust
than that is looking at this blue.
This state is in blue,
just like text is in blue here.
All these things that are in
blue are types of things.
Input is a type, key code's a type.
All these things are types.
So it's a variable of type state and
they both happen to have the name state.
So-
&gt;&gt; Cool, great.
&gt;&gt; That's that bit.
&gt;&gt; Very good.
Yeah, excellent.
So that's one part and
then the next part is,
I've seen a couple of questions in
the Q and A about why does this work?
Why can we say that our
TextComponent.text we're calling our
method from our state class over here.
Why is this state effective in allowing us
to call this method?
&gt;&gt; Well over in state.cs,
if you pop over there for a second, we've
said that when we make these state things,
which for the moment I understand
that you guys haven't got the detail
of exactly what a class is.
And a lot of these details
you're gonna have to.
Remember how pictures used
to load on the Internet?
They were fuzzy and then they get
sharper and sharper and sharper.
And now the Internet is so fast that they
just appear, but they used to go fuzzy,
then sharper, sharper, sharper.
That's the way we're teaching you.
We're not teaching you line by line,
right.
Because the reason images used to do that
is cuz you kind of got an overview really
quickly and you could scroll down the page
if you weren't interested, same here.
So we're giving you the overview,
then we're gonna drill into
the detail on successive approaches.
So what we're doing here
in this other class,
is we're saying that it's public,
a public method
called GetStateStory is available to
anything that is a state instance.
So we have this state class in blue.
I've done it in red, but you get the idea.
And then we make ourselves
a little state variable here.
It's now on this state variable
we can say, .Get.StateStory etc.
All right, so that's whats going on there.
The reason that you can say
back in your Adventuregame.cs
class .GetStateStory is because the State,
this State here is this word here and
it is of typestate.
Because it's typestate it has
this public method on it.
So, that's kind of all you
need to know at the moment.
Well, unless there's another question.
&gt;&gt; Excellent, no, that's good for now.
And you were saying we haven't
dug a lot into class and
in upcoming sections we're gonna dig into
that a bit more or a lot more I guess.
We're gonna dive into that a bunch.
There's also a conversation that we've
been having throughout this whole section
that's been about scriptable object.
And there's been some great questions
about the notion of here is
game as a game object.
And we can see very clearly we've
got our script attached to it.
So that brings the script into existence.
That makes the script come alive,
cuz it's attached to this
GameObject as an instance.
Whereas this script here,
state, is just hanging out.
But let me give ourselves a bit
more screen real estate here.
When we create our scriptable objects,
you can see that the state script,
the state class,
is sitting on this asset file here.
Do you wanna give us your take on
what's going on here from a different
direction?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so
let's take it from the direction of where
things are on the disk to keep it simple.
So over on this GameObject anything you do
on that is being stored in the scene file.
So that is just in your scene file
which will be in this folder over here.
So anything you're doing there's stored
in this scene until you get into prefabs
which we'll get into later,
which are prefabricated objects.
So when you make the changes that,
store them there.
Now, when it comes to these files down
here, all of these state files that we've
created, the point is, is what it's
saying in the inspector here is, firstly,
when you make one of these you're
just making a file on the disk.
You can see it here.
It's in a cell.asset,
it's A2 in a cell.asset.
So when you make one of these, you're
literally just make a file on the disk.
And the template that that file is based
on is defined by this state script that
we made.
So the state is just the template for it.
It's like the form you're
filling out basically.
And then here is the form
showed to you in the inspector.
It gives you options to both specify texts
and to link to a couple of other states.
So that's what's going on there.
You're making a file on
the disk to a given template.
The template is the state.cs
script of an object class.
It's a template for
storing information in.
Just like a Google form or
a Wufu form or a SurveyMonkey form.
It's just a form.
&gt;&gt; Yep, cool.
And in your opinion, Ben,
when should we be looking beside let's
just jump to scriptable objects?
At this stage people are going
through the course and not yet
familiar with how do I make decisions,
how do I problems solve?
One of the things that I've been
hitting on is let's teach you how to
problem solve.
What's a nugget that we can be
giving people at this point,
in terms of when they should be thinking,
scriptable objects would be a good idea
from my project versus I don't [INAUDIBLE]
scriptable objects at the moment?
&gt;&gt; Okay, so two answers I think to that.
Number one is you won't know yet.
If you're brand new to coding and
you're following a 3D,
you don't have enough experience yet.
So step one is watch us do something,
right?
Step two is start to follow along with us.
Step three, later on and
the learning journey you'll be to be able
to make those decisions for yourself.
So don't expect to be able
to make that decision yet,
we're just introducing you
to a possibility, right?
And then to answer more specifically,
when you start to wanna watch out for
that type of stuff is in code you
should never have magic numbers.
We've started to talk about that.
Any number that's not zero, one, or
two probably shouldn't be in code.
Even two is questionable because it's some
sort of number that contains information.
It's the number of days of the week.
It's something else.
So that should be
a parameter to your code.
It should be something that you use
to change the way your code works,
not buried deep inside the code file.
And the same goes for
words and strings of text, so
putting all the story text in the code
has a couple of problems with it.
Firstly it obfuscates,
it makes unclear how the code works.
And the other thing that it does is that
if I'm working on a CS file, a C# file
trying to make the game do something,
behave in certain way, somebody else can't
simultaneously work if you wanna work with
a partner on creating the story text.
Because they'd be clashing
on the same file, and
we'd have a lot of trouble
reconciling those changes.
So that's kind i the bottom line as
to why we're using them here and
we wanna introduce you
to them really early.
Uncomfortably early for me in the design
of this course to introduce it to you.
But the point is that,
if we do that and as you move forward,
you'll start to question
whenever you create a new script.
In the future,
in about three sections time,
you'll be ready to start questioning,
I'm making a new script.
Should it just be what comes
out the box by default,
which is more on behavior thing which
is just what comes out the box.
Should it be a scriptable object,
which we'll try to see now or
should it be something else
which we'll cover later.
So that's the point,
it's to get you in the habit of
questioning the type of script that Unity
just automatically gives you.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's a really great point about
multiple people working on it, cuz you
might have a friend you teamed up with.
The friend's gonna be the story writer and
you're gonna be working on
the functionality, for example.
And the friend can be in there creating
all sorts of great story and states and
flow and not at all impacting the fact
that you're in here working on the script
and getting some
functionality into the game.
It's pretty cool.
Another thing that Ben and
I were talking about just before we turned
on the camera was our bracketing,
our braces and where things fits.
So I wanna touch on that
just very briefly Ben.
What's important at this stage and
what's not important at this stage in your
opinion for people to be focused on when
it comes to the layout to white space,
to their formatting?
&gt;&gt; So this is an interesting one.
It's a bone of contentions.
So it's a marmite point.
Either you love it or you hate it.
One thing actually matters is how
the compiler in service that code.
Now I'd really like you to be able to read
code even if it's not perfectly formatted,
otherwise when you even go to Unity sample
code it may not be perfectly formatted.
If you find other people's code on
the web, it's not gonna be perfectly
formatted, there is no perfect, but it may
not be consistently formatted, all right.
Now what you're seeing on the screen here
is not currently consistently formatted,
but it's okay, let go of it.
Yes, of course, we should have
a consistent coding style and yes,
of course, it's good if we stick with
a perfect and consistent code style.
But to do that you have to learn as
Rick says, to change the template, and
what gets spat out in terms of
this code with start and update,
there's spaces between the method name and
the brackets here but there aren't here.
This curly braces here rather than here,
relax, its okay.
It all works in C#,
it's all white space, it doesn't care,
we know it's not 100% consistent.
We, in the future of the course,
will think about changing the template and
really tightening that up.
But the first thing you need to do is let
go of perfect code formatting before you
then start fully owning it, in my opinion.
Cuz first you need to make a decision
about what code style do you
want to employ.
There is no one code style
that is the right code style,
it's what's right for you.
And secondly, you need to be not
allergic to other people's code.
You need to get in the habit of
suppressing that urge to say,
it's not right.
And remember there's no right or
wrong, there's just styles.
It's not consistent, it's not good, but
you need to get able to read code
that is inconsistently styled.
Otherwise, when you come to solve bigger
problems later, where you wanna copy and
paste or at least you're inspired by other
people's code, if you can't get over the,
it's not perfectly consistent, you can
lose out on a lot of value that other
people have created.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's a great point.
As you were talking I've just gone and
formatted this to our preferred
formatting, which is not to have any space
between the update and the brackets here,
and to have our curly
braces on the next line.
But there's a lot of people who
prefer to do things like that,
and they both work.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, absolutely.
[CROSSTALK] So strive for
consistency in the code you write but
forgive inconsistency in others.
&gt;&gt; Excellent, really good.
The other thing I wanted to hit on in this
instructor hangout is there are some part
of the design in this section that
we've gone through pretty fast, for
example how to write a story or
how to come with a story idea?
Or how to connect from one
state to the next state.
We've gone through that pretty quickly cuz
we just don't have time in this course to
dig too deep into design.
People are here to learn programming,
they're here to learn Unity, and
they're here to learn how to make
a game from start to finish.
So we skipped some of that, and hopefully,
we'll have a narrative design course.
If you really want one
then make some noise and
we'll put that on the agenda
to create one of those.
But I've deliberately not spent too much
time on that throughout this section cuz I
know we just don't have time
to dig into it too much.
&gt;&gt; Awesome, well thanks for
being with us guys.
Do dive over to the community side and
share your biggest takeaway,
at least your biggest single takeaway
from this instructor hang out.
Let us know if you like these instructor
hang outs, hopefully you do and
we look forward to seeing
you in the upcoming content.