[MUSIC]
In this video we're going to spawn
multiple enemies in our wave.
You can see here we have got one, two,
three,four, five enemies coming out and
that was based upon our waves total
to have numbers of enemies at five.
Excellent.
We are reading from our wave
configuration file and spawning waves.
Let's jump in and get started.
The next few lectures are going to get
pretty deep and pretty detailed, we're
going to be using some nested coroutine,
we're going to be doing four loops.
So let's just have a look at
what we're trying to create, so
really super duper clear.
Now we're going to spawn enemies, so
here's an enemy and where we've spawned
it, we're familiar with that concept
of instantiating and spawning an enemy.
We also needs to have some waves spawning
all of the enemies in the waves.
So, this blue thing here is the wave and
enemy 1 spawns and
then after a certain amount of time,
enemy 2 spawns, 3 and 4.
So, it's spawning our enemies.
When we get to that last enemy,
then we want to spawn the next wave.
So, we need this concept
of spawning all the waves.
Maybe up here is wave 0,
index 0, and then 1, 2, 3, 4.
And then, for the game that I'm creating
at the moment, so that I don't need to go
and create gazillions of ways,
I'm gonna loop the wave.
So once you finish the last wave
that we're aware of in the list,
then we go back to the starting wave and
start all over again.
So here's the concept, and for
each of these, we'll need a coroutine.
So when we're spawning all the waves,
we need to start with the first wave and
then wait for a certain amount of time.
How long do we wait?
Well, we wait until all of the enemies
in this wave have been spawned,
and then we go on to the next wave and
so on.
Okay, so these are the loops,
this whole thing is one big loop, and
then within the wave itself we have a loop
where we go through each of the enemies.
Jump back over into unity lets set
ourselves up with a couple of things.
First of all, right click Create empty,
we need a game object for
spawning enemies so
we will call this an enemy spawner.
Just as an empty game object,
reset the transform.
And this will be a place
where we can put our script.
And our script folder, in our Assets
directory, I'm going to right click and
create a C# Script that I will call
EnemySpawner is what we'll call that.
And then I can drag the EnemySpawner
script over onto EnemySpawner and
that will now attach it as a component.
So a little bit different to
how I've done it in the past,
just to show you a different way.
Often I just click Add component, Create
a script, and then through that it's
automatically attached and
also it is in our assets directory.
But this way I just kinda went
about it the other way around.
Okay, so
let's open up the EnemySpawner script.
Now, we need to give ourselves
a couple of variables,
a couple of things at the start.
So, let's serializeField.
What do we need to do?
Well, we need to list out
all our wave configuration.
So, we will type in List&lt; waveConfig&gt; and
we'll call this waveConfigs
to indicate that this is all
of our wave configurations will
be serialized within here.
I'm gonna save at this point,
jump back over into Unity,
see how many waves we have
in our Assets folders.
We have a waves folder down at the bottom.
We've got two waves.
Okay, so we do have two at the moment.
If was to click on Enemy Spawner,
we can see that under WaveConfigs
we have a space that we add this.
So add this now, just so
we're doing this as we go along.
So we click on Wave,
we have to lock out inspector.
And then drag over wave 1 and 2 over
the top of where it says WaveConfigs.
And now we have our two
WaveConfigs in there.
Okay, so
that we know this is working as we go.
Back over in to our
EnemySpawner.cs script.
Okay, what next?
Well we need to have a concept
of what our starting wave is.
We know where to stop.
So we'll create ourselves an integer,
and we'll call this startingWav = 0.
We're gonna start at index
0 within our WaveConfigs.
Okay, starting off at 0, cool.
Now, what do we need to do?
Well in start we need a way of
saying what the current wave is.
So I'll create a variable in here,
just var currentWave=,
well it's gonna equal the starting wave
index within our WaveConfigs list.
So we say WaveConfigs, and
then what do you think we do next?
We have our square brackets,
and we say startingWave.
So startingWave is our index,
so, basically starting wave is 0.
And next in start we need to
place the start our coroutine so
I'll start it in here and
then we'll go create it in a moment.
The start coroutine where we want to
loop through the enemies in our wave,
we'll call this SpawnAllEnemiesInWave.
I know it's a big old name, but
it makes it super duper clear
exactly what's going on.
And then, what is the wave that we
want to be spawning at this point?
Well, we're spawning currentWave;.
So remember that when
an enemy is instantiated,
when an enemy is created,
it says okay, what wave am I part of?
At that point, we say hey you're
part of this current wave.
It says right, I know I need
to move at a certain speed and
move along a certain path.
So, that's why we have this
concept of the currentWave.
Now, I don't think we're
gonna need updates so
I'll delete that to keep things nice and
clean.
Let's go ahead and create our coroutine,
it will be private.
It's a private method, private coroutine.
What type is a coroutine?
It's type IEnumerator.
And then I'm going to double click on
SpawnAllEnemiesInWave, copy that, just so
I know I've typed it correctly or
pasted it correctly.
So Ctrl+C and Ctrl+V to paste that.
And now we need a requirement,
we need to say when anything calls
SpawnAllEnermiesInWave, we need to know
for the details we're about to create,
we need to know what
wave we're talking about.
So we're specifying here
of type WaveConfig,
we need to know the waveConfig.
There we go.
And you know what, this section of the
cause is gonna feel a little like being
a detective, cuz we have things link to
things, link to things, link to things,
you have to follow
the evidence trail sometimes.
So we have WaveConfig here
as our type in the list.
We have our particular WaveConfig,
the very first one, so index 0,
which I've shown you before.
Here it is wave number 1,
that's our element 0, it's our WaveConfig.
And then that is being passed
along our process here because we
know that the currentWave is
going to be the first WaveConfig.
And then when we start our coroutine
it's saying hey the WaveConfig you're
interested in is the currentWave and
that is what is being passed into our
WaveConfig in here that we're asking for.
Saying, when you call me you need
to tell me what the WaveConfig is.
Now instantiate our enemies
by typing Instantiate().
And from doing this before we know that we
need what it is that we're instantiating
and then the position of it and
the rotation.
So I'll give myself a new line,
to make this clear,
cuz it's gonna be a pretty long line,
if we try to do it on line line.
We'll say waveConfig., well,
how do we know the particular
enemy that we're instantiating?
If we go back to our waveConfig,
which is where we're accessing,
we made ourselves a method,
a get method that returns the enemyPrefab.
So that is what we wanna know,
the enemyPrefab.
This will be GetEnemyPrefab.
So I'm back into EnemySpawner,
typing GetEnemyPrefab.
I'm gonna close the parentheses
because it's a method.
Comma, next line, we are looking for what?
We're looking for the position.
So again,
we're looking within waveConfig.,
what do we know within our
waveConfig that has position?
Well it's the GetWaypoints.
This is our list of waypoints,
so back to EnemySpawner again.
What did we call it?
GetWaypoints.
And then it's a method, so
open and close parenthesis.
And then we need to say the index.
So open our square brackets,
we'll start off with index 0, and
we'll be incrementing this in a moment.
And because we are looking for
a particular position,
we type transform.position,
and comma, next line.
Here we're looking for the rotation.
So we'll just say nice and
basically quaternion.identity.
Which is a way of saying, without going
into the details of what quaternions are,
it's saying we don't need rotation.
Just use the rotation that you're
starting off with that you have already.
And then semicolon at the end of this.
Okay, so we've got our instantiating
the what, the where, and the rotation,
excellent.
Now within our coroutine we
need a concept of yielding,
so underneath we'll say yield return new,
what are we going to do in here?
We need to WaitForSeconds again.
How are we gonna say WaitForSeconds?
Let's go have a look with some clues,
again being a detective
in our WaveConfig.cs.
What in here gives us clues
about how long we should wait?
Well we've got our GetTimeBetweenSpawns.
Which will return the time
between spawns that we want.
So back over into EnemySpawner.cs,
WaitForSeconds(waveConfig.GetTimeBetweenS-
pawns()),
and then down at the very end
you're going to want a semi-colon.
Okay, so let's save and see what behaviors
we're getting here at the moment.
We already have our instance so
we've dropped ourselves into the scene.
If you click on Enemy and
delete that then when we click on Play,
we should instantiate a new enemy and
have it follow the path in wave 1.
Okay, cool.
So that is what we're doing.
It's following along the path and
then when it gets to the end,
it should destroy itself.
We won't have a second enemy yet,
or will we?
Waiting, waiting, waiting.
We won't.
Cool.
There's a reason for that,
is we haven't told it to increment.
We've only said to do this action once,
and then wait for seconds, and
then go back to where you started,
which is up here.
There's no mechanism at the moment
to do this over and over.
And this is where we need a for loop.
So highlighting here, this is the code
block that we want to do over and over.
We want to do this many times,
so we need to have a for
loop that will loop through this so
long as a particular condition is met.
This is where I'm gonna give you
a challenge to create a for loop.
We've done this before but
I've got a lot of reminders in here for
you in case that you're
not sure how to do it.
So we wanna wrap our Enemy
instantiating in a for loop,
that's what I was highlighting just say,
we wanna wrap this in a for loop.
And we need to increment our enemyCount.
In other words, how many enemies sort
of have been spawned until we reach our
desired number of enemies.
So we're gonna increase until we've
reached the desired number of enemies,
which we have set somewhere.
And a reminder for
you this is the framework.
This is the structure for
how we write a for loop.
We start off with the for
key word and then we define the type.
And this [INAUDIBLE] Will
be an integer as well.
Here we have i in our example I'm
going to call mine enemyCount.
As my integer=0; and
then enemyCount is less than something or
other.
We need to figure out
what it is less than.
And then increment enemyCount.
And then we do that we wrap our
instantiation below that within
our curly braces.
That is the structure of for
loop, this is the challenge,
this is what I would like
you to go ahead and create.
Give that your best shot and
I'll see you back here when you're done.
Okay, so just above instantiate, I'm going
to start typing for, we've got a for loop.
And what is in here?
Well, integer, as I mentioned,
mine is gonna be called enemyCount = 0.
And as I've talked about before,
you could just refer to this as i.
But when I'm skimming through my code,
I don't find i as informative as typing in
the actual name of the thing
that we're incrementing.
So, I like to give it a name.
Even if many others do not.
;enemyCount is less than something.
Well, what do we know?
We know just looking our waveConfig again,
we know that we have this
notion of number of enemies.
That is what we want to be checking,
if we've reached that number yet.
So waveConfig.GetNumberOfEnemies().
And then our parenthesis
because it's a method.
So we're checking to see if the enemy
count is currently less than the get
number of enemies or
the number of enemies.
And then enemyCount++ to increment.
Okay, there's our for loop and
then we need to give ourselves extra line,
open curly braces and delete the second
part that auto created for me.
Right down underneath yield return new,
put in the close brace and
we have wrapped all within here,
is to instantiate.
Wait for a little bit of time and
then return back up to our for loop and
then continue to do this until the
condition is met where the enemyCount is
no longer less than the total
of NumberOfEnemies.
So loop, loop, loop,
loop until this condition is not met.
And then we have finished our
current spawn all enemies in wave.
And then we'll need in our coming
lectures a way to spawn the next wave.
And then to spawn all
the enemies within that wave.
So it's saved.
Make sure this all worked as expected.
Click on Play, and we'll see if
we get multiple enemies spawning.
One, two, three, four, five.
Excellent.
So we have our five enemies
spawning on our wave.
Can't treat them yet,
that'll be coming up in the future, but
we've successfully spawned on our wave.
Once we get to the end,
it's not spawning the next wave yet.
That's what we'll need to do to say,
cool, you've spawned one,
now it's time to spawn the next wave.
So that's exciting stuff.
We've got multiple enemies
spawning in our wave.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.