[MUSIC]
In this video,
we're gonna shift the movement speed and
the wave configuration that has its
waypoints in it off the enemy and
have all that information within the enemy
spawner and the waves themselves.
So the enemy is clever in knowing what
path to follow, without us having to go
and link all of those things onto
a particular enemy prefab itself.
Why do this?
Well this is so
we can have this particular enemy
come in at different speeds and
go on different paths and not always have
to go on the same path every single time.
I think that's gonna give
us a lot more creativity.
So what we'll start off with is jumping
over into the enemy pathing script.
We haven't used that for a lecture or two.
Enemy pathing is what
we will be looking at.
And I'm gonna start here by highlighting
the fact that we need to or
we can remove some of
our SerializedFields.
So we still need to have
our WaveConfig variable but
we don't need access to it anymore.
So that will no longer show up
on the enemy in the inspector.
And likewise, this float moveSpeed,
we're going to remove completely and
replace it with something else.
And what'll we replace it with?
Well, here's a little challenge for you.
I want you to get the speed for
the enemies from the WaveConfig data
instead of using moveSpeed,
which I just deleted.
So find where moveSpeed is,
or in my case was, and
instead of using that moveSpeed variable,
get the information from the WaveConfig.
Okay, so there's your challenge.
Pause the video and jump into that now.
Welcome back.
Hopefully you are taking
on the challenges.
They are the absolute number
one best way to learn.
That's why you're taking this course and
not just watching along
some random YouTube videos.
This is the process of learning cuz
you're taking on the challenges,
I hope as the best way to learn.
So you can see now cuz I've delayed
moveSpeed, got the squiggly red line.
Instead of moveSpeed, we need to access
our waveConfig., what's its gonna be?
GetMoveSpeed, it's highlighted already,
GetMoveSpeed and
then we need our parentheses
cuz it is a method.
So, now it's going to go into our
waveConfig, get the particular
movement speed that we've set for
this wave and then use that for our enemy.
Now, in terms of the wave configuration,
to know which wave to follow, so
that we don't have to
connect it up manually.
We're going to add ourselves a new
public method that, in here,
has the information that we feed
into our particular waypoint.
So you can see this is following our path,
we need to know which path to follow.
And to do that, we want something else to
be telling us that from another script.
So what we'll do is we'll create
ourselves a public method,
say public void, set,
we'll call this SetWaveConfig.
Now we've been doing, I'm just
going to leave that midway through,
just remind you in our waveConfigs.
We've been doing these get methods
where we say hey, return me a value and
that value we've established
in our waveConfig file.
In this instance, we're gonna say hey,
set the particular thing for me.
So it's a public method that
something else can be feeding into
a value into this script.
So it's a set method, if you will.
And in here,
we put inside the parentheses, what is it?
What's the information that we
need to have when this is called?
So as soon as we have parameters in
our signature here, SetWaveConfig.
As soon as we put something in here and
I'm gonna put in waveConfig, so it's of
type waveConfig, we'll call it waveConfig
cuz that's what we need to know.
We want to know what is the waveConfig
that we should be following for
this current enemy on this current path.
And so,
when anything calls this public method,
it has to also tell us
what the waveConfig is.
If it doesn't do that, if in another
script if we just say SetWaveConfig and
open close parentheses, semicolon.
If we just do that,
then we're going to get an error because
we've constructed our method here,
saying you have to give me, thou shall
give me the waveConfig information.
So when we are calling our method from
another place, which we'll do in just
a moment, we actually have to put
in there what the waveConfig is.
So that this waveConfig
is getting fed into here.
So we know that this
becomes a container for
whatever it was that this
waveConfig is in the other file.
Okay, just going nice and slow on
that because I know it puzzled me for
a long time in terms of what's
this stuff inside the brackets?
Well the main thing to know is that
we are wanting information from
whoever called this.
Now, this part is going to blow your
mind if you're not paying attention.
So, get ready to pay some attention.
What we need to do here is to set
the waveConfig variable in this class,
which is up here,
we've set this as waveConfig.
And we're using this waveConfig variable
in a number of spots down here to say
okay, what I'm I following?
What I'm I heading towards
in terms of my waveConfig?
But then we also this concept of the
waveConfig local variable to this method,
which is being passed back in.
Now we could call this something
different like waveConfigToSet.
We could do that but
at the end of the day, it's a waveConfig.
So we're gonna use the same word,
waveConfig but it has two slightly
different meanings or
they're slightly different variables.
So what I'm going to say
in here is this.Wave,
sorry, little w,
waveConfig = waveConfig, okay?
And again, I'm gonna go slow on this so
it's super duper clear,
I'll just get rid of
some of my white space.
Super clear,
when we say this in front of waveConfig,
we're referring to this in the class,
the instance variable.
So at the top here, this variable can
be used throughout our entire class,
our entire instance.
Therefore, it is this, this is the thing
that we're on, this is the script,
the class, the document.
When we use this,
referring to this whole thing.
So this.waveConfig is referring
to this particular waveConfig and
then it equals the waveConfig that
we receive when something calls
the public method SetWaveConfig and
passes to us the waveConfig.
Okay, I'm gonna save up this and
then go to the spot where we are.
I'm going to call the waveConfig and
I'll show you what I mean.
So over into EnemySpawner,
instead of just instantiating,
we're gonna create a new variable,
which we'll say var
newEnemy = Instantiate and
then what and where and the rotation.
So now we're storing this new enemy
each time we create an enemy,
it will be newEnemy.
And that allows us to grab the component,
so
if we give ourselves a line between
the end of our instantiation and
before the yield, we'll type in newEnemy.
So, we're referring to this
newEnemy we've just created dot.
So there's something within
the newEnemy that we're looking for.
GetComponent, With our angle braces cuz
when we create this game object,
we're looking for a particular thing.
The component we're looking for
is the enemy pathing.
So that's the enemy pathing script.
Then when we have a look at our enemy, you
can see, if I find an enemy, you can see
it has a script and the script is also
a component that's sitting on the enemy,
that's how we can access
it using getComponent.
Then we need to add our parentheses after
enemy pathing.SetWaveConfig
that we just created.
And what do we need to feed into that?
We need to feed in,
you guessed it, the waveConfig.
And which wave and
then put a semicolon on the end.
Which waveConfig they're referring to?
It's the waveConfig that's locally
within the SpawnAllEnemies.
So it knows, this is the particular
wave that I'm referring to.
And then when we call this method,
it's going to pass in this waveConfig
that we're getting from here into our
enemy pathing because it required us.
It said, you have to give me
this information when you
are calling SetWaveConfig and
I'm gonna use this information
to define my own waveConfig
in my particular class.
Okay, let's save all of these, I've jumped
back over into Unity, click on our enemy.
Those extra bits and
pieces are no longer there.
Let's go find our waves.
Click on Wave 1.
I'm gonna change the movement speed
to 8 and make sure this works.
Path zero, which one's path zero?
That's that one.
Okay, I'll change it to path one for now,
on wave one just to check that
it works and then click on play.
We should have it coming
from left to right, is it?
Or right to left?
Okay and they're going nice and fast,
it looks like they're definitely
going eight amount of speed.
If I was to just change it over to
the other path, to check this all works,
path zero and make the movement speed,
I don't know, 20 just to be ridiculous.
Click on play and it should go zing and
spawn, one, two, three, four, five.
Excellent, okay, there we go.
So now we've got more of our
information stored on our wave.
The value in doing this is now we
can create waves where we mix and
match the speed, the paths and
the enemies to give us a whole
ton of variation within our game.
So, great work.
In the next video, we'll continue
on with spawning more waves.