[MUSIC]
In this video we're going to move
our Zucchini across the screen so
it actually looks like
a proper projectile.
Here we go, [SOUND] here we go,
let's jump in and get started.
Ultimately, I'll be moving my Zucchini
through code but I wanna show you first
how I would move it if I was just
straight up using the animation system.
So I'm gonna drop my Zucchini Prefab
into my scene so that I can work on it.
There is a Zucchini Prefab.
Now I need to add a component on
the Zucchini which is an Animator.
I've already typed that in,
so type in animator.
We now have our Animator.
What do we need to make
our Animator make sense?
We need an Animator Controller.
So over in my Animations,
Defenders, right click, Create,
Animator Controller, which I will
call Zucchini, Zuckerberg, no,
that's not how we spell it,
Zucchini, there we go.
I was in the middle of typing Zuckerberg,
I don't know why.
It must have influenced my brain.
Okay, so we've got our Zuckerbergcchini
that we're gonna throw across the screen.
And as our Animator Controller,
now we need some animations.
So we right click, Create, Animation.
And I'll call this Zucchini.
Zucchini, no dumb jokes
about Facebook founders.
Okay, Zucchini in there.
Now clicking back on my
Zucchini in the hierarchy,
I need to assign my Animator Controller.
So we click on the selector,
find Zucchini.
We have now hooked up
the Animator Controller.
There is no animation within this, so
I'll drag in my Zucchini animation, plop!
There we go.
So it's going straight into
the Zucchini animation.
At the moment,
there's no animation within that.
So let's click on our
Zucchini in the hierarchy.
Click on our Animation window.
Now when we click on Record, we can
move around our Zucchini and do stuff.
So let's say within our window here at
the one second point, I want it to go from
wherever it spawns, [SOUND] to the end
of its trajectory within one second.
So I move my play head down to one second,
[SOUND] and then hit W and
move the Zucchini all the way
down to where I want it to go.
And you can see that's
inserted a key frame.
Now if I scrub up and down you can
see that it is moving literally,
[SOUND] along the screen.
I will get out of Record mode.
Okay, and then you might need to click
off, yeah, that will work for me.
Now I can apply back to the Prefab.
I'm gonna delete the Zucchini that
we've got in the scene just to make it
very clear what is being instantiated and
what's being thrown across the screen.
And then when we click Play, it should
do its little dance, [SOUND] and then,
[SOUND] there we go.
There's the Zucchini
flying across the screen.
And of course from within the animation,
when I'm gonna put my Zucchini back in
again so I can play around with it.
From within this animation you
can do other nifty things.
You could change the rotation.
So I move the play head down
to the one second point, and
do a whole bunch of rotation on there,
blah, blah, blah.
And then so as we are scrubbing through,
we can see that it's gonna rotate as well.
So that's a way first to hand animate
our Zucchini, there's some pros and
there's some cons.
I think this gives us
a lot more flexibility.
I could have the Zucchini for
example at the start.
It could do a little of
a backwards move like.
So to go backwards a little bit, and
then up in the air a little bit,
and then go like that.
So we can handcraft all this like
very specific pieces of animation
to give a lot more depth to our game,
which is cool.
If you're into animation, then it's
a really good approach to do that.
We can also be doing these things
from our code to say well,
let's move it across the screen,
let's rotate it as it's moving.
And that will be the challenge for
the video.
So I'm not going to keep this
animation that I've created in here.
I will get rid of that.
So let's find out.
Defenders, Zucchini,
I'm gonna delete all that.
I don't need this animation, there we go.
[SOUND] And
we just have our Zucchini Prefab.
Apply that back.
I don't need the Animator Controller.
That was all just me showing you.
That's one way that you could do it.
If you want you can absolutely
leave all that on there.
Apply this back to the Prefab.
But we're gonna do it as a code challenge.
And that will be the challenge for you,
is to move the projectile through code.
And we'll start by adding a component, so
a script,
that turns things into a projectile.
So wherever we place this script,
the projectile script will
make the thing a projectile.
And then we need to use
transform.Translate(),
which we've used already in this section
of the course to move the projectile.
So they are your hints,
they are your clues.
Move your Zucchini using code bonus
points if you make it rotate.
But for now, you only need to
make it translate from left or
right of the screen.
So jump in and take that on and
I'll see you back here shortly Okay, so
first up we need a script
which we will call Projectile.
So Create and, C♯ Script.
Call this Projectile with a capital P.
Drop the Projectile onto the Zucchini
that we still have in our, it's thinking,
it's loading, it's compiling, it's saying
I'm generating you a script, there we go.
And my computer's going a little
bit slow at the moment.
Drag the Projectile,
drop it over onto Zucchini.
Now the Zucchini has a component,
which is Projectile.
So that makes the Zucchini a Projectile
because of this component Projectile.
Play that back to the Prefab while
we remember, and let's go and
open this up in Visual Studio.
Right, I'm gonna remove Start for
now, I just don't need that.
I'm also gonna remove the comment telling
me what an update is, I know what that is.
Now, within Update,
we want to be moving our Projectile.
So as per the hint that I gave you,
we're gonna type in transform.Translate(),
with a capital T.
And then, what are we doing in here?
Well, we're looking for
a Vector3 translation, or
we can use Vector2 which
is what we're gonna use.
So Vector2 dot, and we talked before.
Previously we had Vector2.left
where you're gonna use
Vector2.right because we want it
to right on the screen, times by.
Well, I wanna have it times by a speed
variable which I'll create in a moment.
And then of course, Time.deltaTime.
Let's create our speed variable.
We'll serialize that so
we can access it quite easily.
Serializefield, and
this needs to be a float I believe.
Speed, and we'll initialize that at 1f.
Okay, that looks pretty good.
Save that up, jump back over into Unity.
And then let's check
that it all works out.
Click on Play.
We should have our first Zucchini that's
just the game object in the scene.
We'll go zinging very,
very slowly off the screen and
then we'll shoot another one out.
So there we go.
We're instantiating and
moving across the screen.
Now the reason I prefer this particular,
and this instance to be using code,
is I'm wanting the Projectile
just to go straight.
I don't need any magic.
I might have it Rotate as well,
that'll be a cool thing to do.
But it gives me flexibility
to easily tune it.
So now I can go into my Zucchini, find the
speed and change it to say for example 10.
Click on Play.
And then it will do 10 speed for
our Zucchini.
And if we have other things
that we're spawning,
we can drop this script
onto those other things.
Maybe it's an, [LAUGH] okay,
I didn't apply that to the Prefab.
But you get the picture there.
There we go.
We're moving the Projectile.
Next up we need to be doing some damage
and colliding with our attackers.
So I'll see you in the next video.