[MUSIC]
In this video, we're gonna give ourselves
a way to have our waves loop over, and
over, and over.
So even if you have only two ways,
and I'm gonna change my to two here,
it just goes wave one, wave two, wave one,
wave two, over, and over, and over so
that our game can loop.
So we'll hop over into EnemeySpawner.cs,
create ourselves a variable.
So we'll serialize this, so
it's available in the inspector.
We're making a bool, so it's either gonna
be either true or it's gonna be false and
we'll call it looping.
So I have a bool called looping,
which we will initialize as false.
So bool looping = false;.
And then within our start method
here's something really cool.
We're we can say we can change the type
of return value for our start method.
So that when the engine calls start, it is
doing something a little bit different,
we can change it to an IEnumerator,
so that we make our start a code routine,
which is really nifty.
And then within our StartCoroutine,
just gonna put my curly
braces down a line here.
So within our StartCoroutine
we can create a do while loop,
which basically means it goes over and
over and over at do while.
And we'll make it while looping is true.
So we'll give ourselves a little bit
of room here and start by typing do.
And then give ourselves a code
block in here of curly braces.
We're going to change our stock
StockCoroutines inot our yield conditions.
So yield return
StartCoroutine SpawnAllWaves.
So this now becomes the yield condition.
Once we get into the do while loop, we're
saying do a thing, go, go, go, go, go.
And then,
once it's finished doing all this,
the yield will then return
back within our start method.
And we can say, close our, curly braces
here, so we've got our yield condition.
And then we can say, While (looping).
And this is another way of saying
While (looping) equals true.
We can say while, and
then in brackets, looping.
So what we're doing here is saying when
the engine call start, do this thing,
start the co-routines.
This is a series co-routine.
And we are gonna yield.
So come back to start and
continue with whatever is after this
statement once this has completed.
So once this completed, we come back here.
We see the while.
If looping is true,
then it jumps back up to the do and
it starts this all over again.
And because it started as part of the
yield, then it waits until it's finished,
then it comes back to the while.
So this is a really neat loop and
a really neat way of saying we can do this
particular thing here, this SpawnAllWaves,
we can do it over, and over, and
over, so we can loop it in there.
So we'll save this up and hop over
into Unity, check that it all worked.
The first thing we need to
do is click On for Looping.
So let's check it without looping on, and
make sure it's working as we're expecting.
You might wanna stop at the end
of a number of waves, and
then the player can go on to another
level, so you don't want it to loop.
Okay, that's it without looping.
We'll click Looping On, click on Play, and
we should see these waves looped over and
over.
Okay, once, twice, okay, so you can see,
they just keep getting spawned,
and spawned, and spawned.
And so you can imagine, this is a game,
if we're spawning all these waves, and
the game is just going on and on,
you don't have to have to have
created 300 different waves.
You can create a certain number 10 or
20 or 30 and the game will go on and
on forever.
And if you make your enemies engaging,
if you make your waves interesting and
all that kind of good stuff then
the player is gonna feel like this is
a pretty awesome game to play for
a bunch of time.
Okay, so it's just a quick
lecture on the do while loop and
how we have used that within our
co-routine and how we have changed our
Start method to be an IEnumerator so
that we can use it as a co-routine.
Great work, well done, I'm sure you're
game is shaping up really nicely.
I look forward you seeing your
sharing in the community.
If you've got something neat that
you're enjoying with your waves,
then please do share it with us, and
I'll see you in the next lecture.