[MUSIC]
In this video we're gonna trigger a sound
effect when a block is destroyed and
we'll look at the problem with that when
you're destroying something the fact that
the audio also gets destroyed.
So we'll figure out a solution so
that we can destroy our block and
still play our audio,
let's jump in and get started.
First thing I'll do is figure
out which audio effect
I want to play when we break a block,
I think I'm gonna use the bounce sound
cuz it's very different to the others.
That means I need to remove it from
the repertoire of sounds that we currently
have as part of the ball.
So to do that I'm going to make
my ball array, ball sound size,
ball sound array size zero,
got there eventually, and
then lock the inspector,
it's locked at the moment and
so that's just the top right up here,
the little lock symbol.
And then grab the four
that I do want to have,
drag them over into Audio Ball Size
until the ball sounds just here and
drop them onto Ball Sounds [SOUND]
there we go got these four.
Now important,
I didn't do this in the last lecture, but
importantly we want to click on Apply,
and watch what happens here.
Apply and
we apply our changes to the ball prefab
and all of our sounds here that were
ball before are no longer ball to say that
the prefab now has these details on it.
Cool, so now in our other scenes the ball
will be as the ball is just here.
Cool, okay, so
what's the problem we have at the moment?
Well, when the ball flies up and
hits a block,
we know that we in our block.cs,
we know that it says destroy,
the very moment the very frame that the
ball comes into contact with the block.
So ball hitting the block on collision
enter, it means that it will be destroyed
but the problem is if we have on our
block which is where we want to have
our destroy sound if we have an audio
source that also gets destroyed.
So the very moment the sound starts
to be triggered its mechanism for
playing the sound is destroyed so
we need a solution.
Let's have a look at the problem here.
So the problem is, destroying a GameObject
will destroy it's AudioSource,
which means also killing our SFX, the very
second it started it is also stopped.
Couple of solutions,
one solution, we could delay destroying
the GameObject until the SFX has played.
So what I mean by that is when the ball
hits the block, gonna have a look at our
block script, we could say,
Destroy(gameObject,), and we could put in
there say, 1f, and that will be one
second delay until it gets destroyed.
But that's gonna be a little bit crummy
because the block will still be sticking
around and then it will blink out of
existence after a second little bit clumsy
we want the block to be gone
the moment the ball hits it, okay.
So that solution is no good anyway,
this is problem solution part of becoming
a better game designer and a better
programmer listing out our problem.
So, what's another
solution to our problem?
Another solution is to find a way to play
to play the SFX even if the GameObject
is destroyed and
that's what we are going to do.
There's a really neat method that we
can use, I say ours, I'm looking for
my documentation, here it is, I've
shared this with you in the resources,
AudioSource.PlayClipAtPoint.
Now, PlayClipAtPoint has a couple of
things that it can do which is cool.
One thing that it does is if we
scroll down here to description,
this function creates an audio source but
automatically disposes of it once
the clip has finished playing.
So It creates a new audio source
that's not gonna be attached
to that game object It just
instantiates it in our scene.
And it will take in a clip,
so whatever we wanna play,
and also it needs to know the position.
This is important,
because it's a 3D sound it needs to know
where in the world am I being played.
We can't play it in the 2D way
it has to be a 3D sound and
we can also adjust the volume.
Okay, so that's not where I wanna go,
I wanna go over to here, cool, so
now we have our setup,
we know we need to use PlayClipAtPoint.
First thing we need to do, and I'm gonna
do a couple of mini challenges in this
lecture rather than having a slide on it.
The first mini challenge I'd like for
you to serialized a field that we can add,
in the inspector,
we can add our audio clip that will be
used for the breaking sound effects.
So find one of the clips, for
me I'm going to use bounce and
we need to in our scriptures here
have a way to access bounce, so
pause the video and do that now.
Okay, hopefully that made sense
it's pretty straight forward,
we're gonna say SerializeField and
we're looking for AudioClip and
we'll call this probably call
it breakSound, breakSound, okay.
And we're placing this breakSound on the
block cuz the block is gonna be the thing
that breaks,
that's why we have our sound here.
Now next step is for us to add our
PlayClipAtPoint, so what I want you to do
is have a look at the document that I've
shared with you it is this one here.
And based upon the description, the
example that we have in here just write in
the script, write in the code for
AudioSource.PlayClipAtPoint.
So using what you see here, add the next
line which will go before Destroy and add
that line in so we're playing ClipAtPoint,
so pause the video and do that now.
Okay, so if we have a look,
we're using AudioSource., and
what that means here is that because it's
creating an audio source we're not getting
the component as we did in
the other previous videos.
We're not getting the component
on the game object we're creating
an audio source, so
we say AudioSource.PlayClipAtPoint, great.
And then what are we passing in,
well first of all, we're passing in,
here's another spot to pause if you
haven't already completed this statement.
What are we pausing first?
We pass in breakSound, now here's a tricky
bit if you've gone through this exercise
and given it your best shot you may have
got this but if not have a think about it.
I want you to just pause and have
a think about where do we want to play?
So we see vector3position,
it's looking for
a position in the world where we
want our sound effect to play.
So where do you think we
should play our sound effect?
First step is what do you thing
conceptually it should go?
Okay, well, conceptually, where
are we listening to the sound effect?
We're listening to the sound effect
on our camera, so our camera which I
have turned off in my gizmos I need
to put my 3D icon on,there it is.
So here's our camera this is where our
audio listener is so we want to play
the sound effect right next to where
we're listening to the sound effect.
Otherwise, if we play it on the block,
it is not gonna be as loud as all
of our other sounds which are just
playing generally in 2D space.
Okay, click on 2D again, so that means
in here ever think about, so that was
the first part of that great work if you
figured out it needs to be on the camera.
How do we reference the camera's position?
This is a little bit trickier if
you haven't seen this before you
might not know but if you
want take a guess how do you think we
reference the camera's positioning here.
Well I'll give you the first part
of this which is to say camera,
which will access the camera class.
Then we say main cuz we need to
know that it's the main camera,
at the moment we've really
got only one camera but
you can look at our description
if you hover over main.
It says the first enabled
camera toggled main camera,
so basically whichever camera
it thinks is main camera, dot,
now what do we put in here to play
this at the cameras position.
Okay we will say transform.position,
so we're saying create
an AudioSource.PlayClipAtPoint,
it's gonna be breakSound
that we're applying and
then play it at these position
which is camera.main.
That's the way that we
access the main camera and
it's the main camera's
transform dot position.
Okay, save this back over into Unity.
There's one step we haven't done yet.
What is that step?
Okay that step is for us to find a block,
just a little bit of slow movement there,
find our block and
you should see audio clip break sound.
Okay break sound,
we drag in bounce, you could
drag in whatever you like you can use
whatever sound effect you want in there.
Okay, and one final, final step,
just gonna turn off my gizmos again.
One final, final step is to do what?
Our final step is to apply back to
the prefab, okay, and then when
we click on play let me just check
that I'm recording my audio yes I am.
Click on play, here we go it should,
let me put my headphones on so
I can hear what you are hearing.
[SOUND] Yep you click on click on then
we can if I can actually [SOUND] okay,
good, so when we're destroying
something we're getting the boing and
it's playing the whole way through.
Excellente, success, okay so in this video
we've implemented our sound effect so
that when the block is destroyed
the sound effect still plays.
I'm gonna show you exactly what is
happening over here in our hierarchy if I
can pause soon enough and
pause I think is going to be [SOUND]
should be pretty easy there we go.
But you can see here, it has created one
shot audio and then when the audio is
finished playing, I might [SOUND] yeah,
we jumped out of the scene a bit early.
But anyway it will create this new one
shot audio and when it's done playing then
it is destroyed, disposed of was the
correct terminology just to appease them.
Okay, so
hopefully this format's worked with me,
giving you a few little mini challenges
and you've had a chance to jump in and
implement that and
I will see you in the next video.