[MUSIC]
In this video we're going to hook it up so
that when all the blocks are destroyed,
we load our next scene.
Super exciting, so let's get started.
One thing I didn't talk about fully in the
previous video that I'll touch on now is
each of these blocks, you've got one, two,
three, all the way down to ten blocks.
Each of these blocks
contains the script block.
And on that script block we have,
we're saying, we're calling the method,
CountBreakableBlock which basically just
increments the number of blocks by one.
And the reason that adds up the total
number of blocks is when we start
the game, every single one of these
instances, these are instances of our
prefab, every instance says,
do the thing that is on my script.
So count me as a block.
And then this one says, add another block.
And this one says, add another block,
add another block.
So each of these are saying
And so they're doing that ten times.
That's why it's adding up in our level.
It's adding up all the breakable blocks.
Each of them have said count me,
and that adds up to ten.
Okay, so just wanted to be super
clear with what's going on there.
Now we're gonna jump into level.cs.
Again, we need to create
ourselves our next public method.
Cuz if we look at our flow we can
see that we have gone through,
we've created a level object,
we're keeping track of breakable blocks,
we're adding up the blocks.
Now we need a method to signal
that a block was broken,
an if statement to load the next
level if the blocks is zero, and
then also to tell each block to
remove itself when it's destroyed.
Remove itself from the total
number of breakable blocks, and
that's what we're up to at the moment.
The first thing we'll do is create
a public method, public void, and
we'll call this one block destroyed.
Block destroyed.
I have an enclosed parenthesis,
I have enclosed curly braces brackets,
and then within here we want to say,
well I'm gonna basically say the opposite
to what's happening up in here.
When a block is destroyed we want
it to say hey, decrease the number
of breakable blocks by saying breakable
blocks minus minus, and then semicolon.
Now what else do we need to do?
Well, within here as well, at the same
time that a block is destroyed,
we want to say right now hey,
have the number of blocks reached zero?
So put in an if statement, if,
and then our parenthesis we
wanna say if the (breakableBlocks)
is less than or
equal to 0,
then what do we want to have happen?
Well, what we wanna have happen
is to load the next level.
So we know from our ScreenLoader,
so we have a ScreenLoader class.
We've already created a load next
level method, so we wanna call that.
If you remember,
I'll find object of thought.
And once again,
I will cache this as a reference just so
that we don't have to find the object
of type every single time.
And so to do that we will say SceneLoader,
capital S, SceneLoader,
and then sceneloader.
So this is just a way of
saying we now have a variable,
sceneloader variable that
have type SceneLoader.
And again I'll just make a note in here,
cached reference, so
that we know this is our cache
not the thought we have,
our parameters, parameters,
that we need to keep track of.
Just helping you guys see that this is
the structure we have at the top of our
script, so you can get into the habit
of putting things in the right place.
You don't have to write in
your comments each time,
I'm just doing that to make it clear
from a teaching point of view.
Okay, so we have our scene loader,
now if breakableBlocks is less than,
sorry in our start method now.
I've jumped a step ahead.
What do we need to do next?
This is a question for you.
Many challenge for you.
How do we get access to our sceneloader?
How do we cache that?
Well, we say Start.
Hit Tab to autocomplete, and
then we will say sceneloader = what?
Another mini challenge for
you, complete that sentence.
sceneloader = FindObjectOfType.
Angle brackets, and within here we're
finding capital s breaks Sceneloader.
Open and close parenthesis, semicolon.
So now we know that SceneLoader is
a cash reference to the class or
the objective type SceneLoader.
Now in our if statement down here, we can
say, cuz we need to access sceneloader.
What are we accessing in there?
We're accessing load next scene.
So, here's another mini challenge for you.
Let's load the next level.
Okay, you're just waiting for
me to continue,
are you actually doing
these mini challenges?
It's okay if you're not but this is how
you really get better at these things.
If you push yourself and pause and
try to figure it out on your own.
That's how this really embeds.
It's cool if you're not, but
it's even better if you are.
So we'll say in here
sceneloader.LoadNextScene.
Open and closed brackets and semi-colon.
So now we've created our, when a block
is destroyed, we want to yell hey,
block is destroyed.
We decrease the number of blocks
by one that are breakable, and
then we say if it's reached 0,
then load the next scene.
I'm gonna save that hop over into block,
and
this is where I'll give you
your proper full on challenge.
That was our last level.
It's our last lecturer.
That's what I'm after.
Update Block.cs.
So here is the challenge.
Call our method for decreasing the number
of blocks when a block is destroyed.
Update Block.cs, and ensure that you
have your build settings correct.
We haven't done that yet for this scene.
You might have done it but
I haven't done it yet.
And to test and rejoice that it works.
And another little hint for
you, you might wanna decrease the number
of blocks in your scene to one just so you
don't have to get rid of all of the blocks
you can text it a little bit more quickly.
Okay, so as your challenge jump in and
get started.
Okay, so within Block.cs,
we need to find our OnCollisionEnter,
this is where things
are getting destroyed.
Underneath Destroy, we want to
give an update in here that says,
well not an update, but
we wanna call our method in here.
I'm thinking that it's updating the
situation but it's not the update method.
We're saying level, we've already created
ourselves a cash reference to the level.
So level., and what do we have in here?
It's gonna be BlockDestroyed );.
So we're saying access the level class
that we're doing and lock is destroyed.
Pretty straightforward.
Now I'm gonna do one more step while I'm
in here which is just to factor this out
to clean it up.
This is a refactor, it's not critical.
Things will still work without it,
but this is just for readability.
Not to do too many things
under this OnCollisionEnter.
So I'm gonna highlight my
three lines here, right-click.
Slightly different on the Mac, you'll see.
Quick Fix and then Extract Method.
On a PC, Quick Actions and
Refactorings, and then Extract Method.
We'll call this method DestroyBlock,
and then hit Enter.
So basically, Whenever we collide with the
block, then we want to destroy the block.
Okay, I'll call DestroyBlock or,
yeah, that's good for now.
It'll change a little bit later on, but
for now, this is what we've got, so
this is the best thing to call it.
Save that, jump over into our game.
Now, I mentioned about Build Settings,
Edit.
Sorry, File &gt; Build Settings.
And one thing you'll notice with our Build
Settings is that we don't have any level
two sitting there.
So I'll just click Add Open Scenes,
cuz level two is open at the moment.
Now I'm gonna cheat a little bit and drag
this above level one so that when we win
level two it'll take us to level one,
just to make it easy for testing purposes.
And as I mentioned before I'm gonna
select all of my blocks except for one.
Delete those, click Play,
we should see if I click on level,
we should see that there are one
breakable blocks, yes there are,
click back in my game window,
[SOUND] and then plonk, and Game Over.
Didn't work, okay,
what have we not done in here?
We're looking for in our level, we didn't
go through this quite in enough detail.
We have SceneLoader, I've forgotten that
we don't have SceneLoader in our scene at
the moment, do we?
That was an assumption that I made was
incorrect, so on level I'm going to drag
in SceneLoader, so drag SceneLoader
as a component on level now.
When we're saying fine object of type,
here it is right here sceneloaded.cs
is another way of saying
it's the SceneLoader class,
and it's in our scene because we
have it sitting right here on level.
Make sure on level we can click Apply, so
it applies all these back to the prefab,
so when we drop in level and
future levels, it knows what's going on.
So just a reminder,
why I was doing that is we're looking for
FindObjectOfType SceneLoader, but
we didn't actually have any SceneLoaders
in our scene just yet, and now we do.
So save everything up, click on Play,
look to see if there's any errors.
I don't know how long that errors
been there but it's now gone.
So there is no error, fantastic.
And we click and it should,
plonk, load into the other scene.
That's great, very excited to see that.
So excellent work,
we now have a fully functioning game.
You can add a couple of these
blocks back if you want.
I'm just gonna add one more,
so we've got two sets.
It looks a little bit more like a game.
And so when we complete this scene,
it will load the next scene.
That area has reappeared down
the bottom of the screen but
that should go away when we click Play.
We can now play fully through a full
game loop where the player can start,
win, lose, and restart the game.
So great work, and
I'll see you in the next lecture.