[MUSIC]
In this video, we're starting the process
of spawning our defenders when we click
the mouse button, we have a cactus
spawning at the zero zero origin point.
So that we're starting that process of
getting defenders being controlled by
the player.
Let's jump in and get started.
So the first step in this process is to
make sure that when we click the mouse,
the system knows that
we've clicked the mouse.
So I'm gonna offer this up to you as
a challenge right from the get go is,
to test from mouse click.
And we've done all this before, but
I'll give you a reminder on the steps.
First of all,
create a core game area, game object,
so a game object we call Core Game Area.
Add a collider to the play area
where your defenders can be placed.
For me, I'm placing them only in these
first, what's that, one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven squares,
so in that area there.
And then to use OnMouseDown(
) to listen for mouse clicks.
So you'll need to create
yourself a script.
I'm calling mine defenders spawner,
if you wanna call yours the same thing.
And finally to debug log, mouse was
clicked, so that is your challenge here,
the steps to it, take that on and I'll see
you back here when you've got that done.
Okay, let's start off by making our
game object right-click create empty,
we'll call this core game area.
Within core game area we need to have
ourselves some sort of collision.
So add a component which
will be a box collider 2D.
Now I'm gonna show you a little bit of
a step to make this a lot more precise.
You might have just grabbed the handles
and pulled the collider around.
What I'll do is say,
what is the size in world units?
We know that this is coordinates 1, 1,
and we know there is seven this way and
five that way so I am gonna see what
happens if I make the size 7 by 5.
Okay looks pretty good I reckon.
Now I am going to reset
the transform my core game area,
cuz it would just pluck right
in the middle of the screen.
So reset that, now the middle of
my collision is down at the 0,
0 origin point and I want the middle
to be in the middle of my place space.
So this is starting from 1,
1, and up here is 7, 5.
So my offset is gonna be 4 and
3, I believe, yes, exactly.
So this was 0, this was 1,
and that 7, 5 up there.
So to have an offset of 4, which is
halfway between our on the x axis between
the left and the right and on y is 3,
halfway between the bottom and the top.
Okay so we've created our play area.
This is the only place that if I click,
I can place a defender down in this area,
that's what I'm going for.
Now let's make ourselves a script so
over in the script folder here,
right-click, Create, C# Script and
I'll call this DefenderSpawner.
Open that up in Visual Studio.
Okay, use OnMouseDown to listen for
mouse clicks.
So I'm gonna get rid of all my start and
update, and
start by typing OnMouseDown and let it
auto complete all the stuff around it,
what do we wanna do here,
well we'll do something nice and simple,
debug.log, and
what did I say the message was gonna be?
Mouse was clicked,
mouse was clicked, okay, semicolon.
Save that, now we need to make sure that
we attach that script to our core game
area, so I'll drag Defender Spawner It's
a cool game area when it's finished
compiling and thinking.
There we go, now we have that as
a component, Defender Spawner, excellent.
When I click on play,
I'll open up my console so I can see that.
And click, yeah, mouse was clicked,
excellent so that's a good first start.
And one of the things that's easy
to forget about is this collision.
If I click outside of the collision,
nothing happens, let me just clear that so
we can see.
Nothing happens there, nothing happens
there, I don't want the player to put
anything in these spots, but
it happens just there, perfect.
Okay, so one other thing we'll do
in this video is when we click,
we spawn or instantiate our cactus.
So if you know how to do that already,
jump in and take that on as a challenge,
otherwise, let's do that together.
We'll go back over into DefenderSpawner.
We need to give ourselves this
mechanism of, what should we call this,
I'll call it Spawn Defender.
So private void SpawnDefender.
What do we need to do in here?
Well we need to instantiate and
I'm going to create this as a game object,
so gameobject we'll call it defender.
We could call it defenderspawn or
something more interesting than that, or
newDefender, maybe that's better,
newDefender that's much clearer.
NewDefender = instantiate, and
then what do we need to put in here?
We need to put in the object to
instantiate the position and the rotation.
This is gonna end up
being a really long line.
I'll clean that up later on, but for
now, we'll say defender, and let's go,
not DefenderSpawner.
So it doesn't know what defender is yet,
I'll go and
create that variable up
the top first of all.
SerializeField, later on,
we'll make this more dynamic where
we'll be picking from the UI who
the defender is, but for now,
we'll just say SerializeField GameObject,
and it's called a defender.
Now, we can go down to our Instantiate and
say we need a defender.
And it's like, cool, I know what that is.
Where do we want it positioned?
Well, for now, we'll just do our
boring old transform.position,
and it'll be probably in
the middle of the screen.
And we'll say,
I will do Quaternion.identity,
I often do it the transform.rotation
cuz I really don't care about it.
But in this instance what you called
Quaternion.identity we're just saying
a straight up no rotation needed,
thank you.
Okay, save that up, that should be,
and I'm gonna do one last bit here.
I'm gonna say as GameObject so
that we can see it in our hierarchy, and
we can manipulate it,
we can do other things with it if we need
to with this particular newDefender,
it's born as a GameObject.
Okay, save that up, back over over
into Unity, click on Play, and
when I click I should get a new
cactus somewhere up, sorry my bad,
we need to actually
make a reference there.
You see Defend none, so
click on the selector find our cactus.
Double click cactus now
when we click on play,
it's always that step of
the that I forget isn't it?
Okay, nothing happening so
it's saying mouse was clicked.
Why is it not happening my friends,
here's a little mini-challenge for you.
If you haven't been doing
any of the challenges,
this is a great one cuz a pretty simple
one to debug, have a look at that,
yell at the screen what do we need to do
to actually have that cactus show up.
On our mouse down,
we need to be spawning the defender.
So calling this method of SpawnDefender,
I'm gonna get rid of my mouse was clicked,
okay.
So instead of clicking the mouse, sorry,
instead of saying I clicked the mouse
we're gonna say spawn the defender.
Click on play, oay click and
there we go and down in the 0,
0 coordinate position we have
ourselves a defender being spawn.
If I click it a gazillion times,
I get a whole bunch of
these suckers down there in the bottom of
the screen shooting out their zucchini's.
Okay so that's a good step for now, I'm
gonna break this up into smaller videos.
So great work, well done.
We now have an instantiating
defender from a mouse click.
In the next video we'll get more
specific on making it actually appear in
the right spot.
Great work and see you in a moment.