[MUSIC]
In this video, we're gonna set up a system
where we can change the speed of the game.
So if I want the game to be really slow,
then I can.
If I want the game to be really fast, bop,
hey that was super fast, then I can change
that as well with this simple slider.
I can change it from 0.1 up to 10.
Okay, so let's jump in and
change the speed of our game.
First thing we'll do here is
jump over to the unity docks and
have a look at what it has to
say about Time.time scale.
Couple of clues in here.
One is that when Time.time scale is 1.0,
then time is passing as fast as real time.
And when time is 0.5,
then things are going half the speed or
two times slower if you wanna
word it the other way around.
If you want things to go faster,
then you increase the value.
Okay, so
now that we've got that established.
It's pretty simple to write.
It's just Time.timescale =
whatever we want our scale to be.
So first of all, we need to create a way
to keep track of the status of our game or
the state of our game.
So I'm gonna create a new
game object over here.
Right-click Create Empty.
I will call this Game State.
Cuz it's going to hold the current
state of where we are,
or Game Status might be a better
way of doing this, Game Status.
And Game Status will have score in it,
it will have speed in it,
any of those things that we wanna know,
what's the status right at the moment?
Technically, it's state, but
technically it's not state, so
we'll call it Game Status.
Okay, and then we wanna create
a script of the same name, so
I'll call Game Status as our script and
then create and add that script.
Okay, find where it is
in our assets folder.
On assets, if it's gonna let me here.
Taking a little bit of
time thinking about it.
Grab Game Status and drop it into scripts.
Double-click on scripts and
open up GameStatus.
Loading, loading, loading,
now the speed of the game is something
that we need to know every single frame.
Therefore, we'll be putting it
into the update method here and
it'll be pretty straightforward.
We will say Time.timeScale =, and
we can start this by saying, 1f.
That will say our time is started
off at just regular time.
Now as you know, it's bad for
us to bury magic numbers,
1's not a magic number at the moment.
But if we were to change this to a bit
faster, 1.5, it becomes a magic number.
So it's bad for us to bury that there, so
let's create a variable at the top
of our class, so that we can change,
we can serialize our time speed and
game speed in the inspector.
So pause the video now,
just a mini challenge for you.
Create a variable that we can serialize
instead of having this number 1f
just in here.
Okay, so the way that we do this
is to say, let's (SerializeField).
(SerializeField), we
need this to be a float,
cuz we'll have decimal places and
we call [INAUDIBLE] gameSpeed.
I could call it timeScale but
I wanna be really clear in
the inspector when I look at it.
It's like that's gameSpeed, that's how
fast my overall game is going to go.
And then chuck a semicolon on
the end there down into timeScale
we will say = gameSpeed and you know
what I do need to do or I should do is
initialize the game speed so it starts
at something I'll start this at 1f.
So it's good to initialize it, that
means that we've got a starting value,
and we're pretty sure that starting value
is gonna be what we want it to roughly be.
So let's go and have a look and
check that on GameStatus.
We have, I'll click on Game Status, game
speed of 1, great, as a starting point.
Now I'm gonna add one more
little bit of flair in here,
cuz we don't wanna accidentally get there
and say, well it can be -58 or 154.
I mean, we trust ourselves, but let's
put something in there just to make it
really easy for
if we're working with someone else, and
they don't exactly know what
our range of the speed is.
We'll go back into our script, and
I'll show you something new in here.
And the new thing is, how we say what
the range will be in the inspector.
So we type in our square brackets and
we say range, we don't say it we type it.
We can't say it at the same time as we
type it if you're one of those sort of
folks who speaks out
loud as you're typing.
And within [Range ()],
mouse over range here, is looking for,
you can see now a little description
there, float min, float max.
So what's the minimum speed
we're ever going all the way
out to what's the maximum speed?
For now we'll say, 0.1f is the minimum and
10f is the maximum.
And then if I save this,
jump back over into Unity,
you'll see in a moment that game speed,
once it compiles.
Game speed now has a slider and
the slider goes from 0.1 up to 10.
This certainly is pretty handy.
You can have it as a slider,
particularly if you've got someone else
who is using this,
as I mentioned a moment ago.
Okay, so let's test it out.
If I put this all the way down to 0.1,
and when we click play, then with a value
if 0.1 when I click go, very slow, you can
see that the whole game has slowed down.
[SOUND] Kills that the sound effects
still continue at the same speed,
which is good to know.
Particle effects will be slower.
Most of the things will be slower but
it's always good to test it out to make
sure the things you think will be slow,
will be slow.
If we went the other way,
if we set it all the way up to ten,
I'm kind of curious how
nasty this is going to be.
Ready, set, go.
[SOUND] [LAUGH] Do you know
what was awesome there,
that somehow it hit both of my blocks and
took me to the next level.
No idea how, but
that was kind of fun but stupid fast, so
let's click on game status,
put this back down.
I'm going to leave mine for at 1 for
now, because I was pretty happy with it.
But as we go,
as we put more content into our levels,
we'll probably change it around.
You can have it different per level.
You can have moments in your game where,
say you hit a particular block and
everything slows down for a moment,
or speeds up for a moment.
So there's lots of things
you can do with this.
Now that you know how to change
the overall speed of the game,
this allows you to change
the speed of the ball and
the speed of anything else you have
going on in your level, in your scene,
by just changing this one number,
this one element.
Okay, we need to pre-fab our game status
so that we can put it in our levels.
So I will grab game status and
drag it down and now is a good time for
us to check out this null reference
exception to see what's going on.
Object reference not set to
an instance of an object.
We've had this a couple of times, so
it's time for us to figure it out.
It's not blocking our progress, but
it is clearly upset about something and
it looks to do with our blocks.
So we'll double click on the error and
see what's going on here.
At level.CountBreakableBlocks();.
Often it points you to something that's
not necessarily the thing that's broken
but this is the first time that
it's getting upset about it.
So CountBreakableBlocks(); is coming for
level.
So let's go look at what's happening
with CountBreakableBlocks();.
breakableBlocks ++ that looks okay.
Have I not done something?
So not set to an instance of an object.
Let's have a look at our blocks.
In here,
we have block that is set to an instance.
Block in here,
maybe we need to look at our prefab.
So this is a process we go through
when we're finding bugs and issues.
It's often a little bit of a rabbit hole,
but this is good for
us to go through it together.
If you've already found it,
you're yelling at the screen saying, Rick,
it's this particular thing.
And I'm looking at it saying, I'm not
quite sure what's broken at the moment.
So let's have a look on block.
Okay, we've got our script.
We've got our sound effect bounce,
which should be valid.
Everything looks pretty good,
when I click on Play, what happens here?
Gone console.
It goes away.
Okay, so there's something
happening after we play the game,
after we [SOUND] get started.
Nothing happened then.
Back into our scene.
It could be when I change
some things around.
So this might be one of these
bugs that we keep our eye on.
And we find later on,
[SOUND] you what it was?
Actually, you know what it is,
it happened this last time.
When we got to the next level,
there's something going on with our
next level that we haven't tidied.
Okay, here it is now.
So something about previous
level needs tidying up.
Thanks for
bearing with me as we worked through that.
That's a good little example
of how to look for bugs.
We need to update our other level,
and that actually, coincidentally,
is part of your challenge.
So the challenge is to trim your
game speed, and first of all,
to update all of the levels that you
currently have with all of your prefabs.
And make sure your prefabs are up to date,
cuz we've made some changes.
And then to play it with the game
speed until you're happy with it.
So there's your challenge.
If you also have that bug,
see if you can get rid of it.
When you come back,
we will work through that together.
Right, so I'm pretty happy with my speed,
as I said.
I think I've got all of my
things prefabbed in here,
my game objects prefabbed.
I'm gonna save this level,
open up my other level,
my other scene as the wording might be.
Now, let's have a look in here.
We've got blocks.
We don't have yet, from our prefab list,
we don't yet have level, I believe, so
we'll drag level in here.
We don't also have Scene.
Yes, we have our Scene Loader, good.
And on level, we needed both of those,
Scene Loader and Level.
Why do we have Scene Loader over on here?
You know what?
I made a bit of an error, didn't I?
I had a game object called
Scene Loader in our previous videos,
and I forgot about that.
That's my bad.
My big apologies for that.
If you remember, when we're working
through scene two, I went and
dragged the scene loader
script onto our level instead of
having a scene loader game object.
We can do it both ways, for
now I am going to remove scene loader.
Cuz it's working just fine when
we have our script on level.
Okay, look at all these things we discover
when we go and tidy up our previous level.
What else do we need in here?
We've got Ball, Block, Event System,
Game Camera, yes, Game Canvas, yes.
Game Status, we don't have that
in there yet, so drop that in.
Great, we have Level.
We just dropped in Paddle,
Play Space and Scene Load.
All those things should be in there.
If we click Play,
we'll probably still be getting our
error cuz we haven't really done.
There it goes.
Goes away.
So
that could've been [SOUND] us fixing it.
Everything seems to work.
Click Game Over.
I'm not sure if it loads to the next
scene, but pretty sure it does.
We will test that at some point but
not just now.
So that's all fine.
The speed looks a little bit fast when
the blocks are closer to my paddles, so
if I go into game status,
drop this down to let's say 0.7.
Interestingly, if I don't
apply this back to the prefab,
then the speed now for
level one will be slower than level two.
So that's the way for us to change,
every time change the speed.
But just be careful if you are doing that,
having different speeds for different
levels, be careful when you are changing
something with the prefab, to make sure
that you're not going and altering
the other prefabs that are being changed.
So now that I've changed this,
if I click apply, anything that
is the same as the prefab at the moment,
ie 1, will be changed to 0.71.
But if I go and change in the other level,
and I change that from 1 to say 1.2,
then this 0.71 won't be changed,
cuz it is different to the prefab.
So, if that doesn't make sense,
jump back to the prefab video where
we talked about that in great detail.
But hopefully that is clear for you.
Now if I click play,
is this game a little bit more pleasant
given that the ball is close to the, what
wait [LAUGH] I'm still useless at it, but
I think slower was a bit
better in this level.
Okay, so that's pretty good for now.
I think we've changed our game speed.
We've updated our level.
We've gotten rid of that pesky error
that's been around for a couple of videos.
That was because we didn't quite have
things hooked up correctly in our original
level here.
Great work and
I'll see you in our next video.