[MUSIC]
In this video, we're gonna resolve
two issues that we currently have.
Issue number one is that the player
gets stuck on the wall as we run
along and jump.
You can see, if I'm holding left,
then I get stuck, and
slowly drift back down again.
The other is, that if I just hit jump,
I can do wall jumps,
which you might wanna have
wall jumps in your game.
It's not too bad.
If it is desired, in my game I don't want
wall jumps, cuz I don't want the player
accidentally just climbing the whole
way up the side of my wall here.
So I'm gonna get rid of
those too in this video.
First thing, the problem with our
players getting stuck on the wall is
the fact that there's friction on
both the player and on the wall.
To address that,
we need to add a physics material.
So if we jump over here,
I'm gonna create a new folder,
material, a folder called Materials.
So first of all, Folder,
I'll call this Materials.
And then within here, I'm going to
right-click Create a Physics material 2D.
Everything's 2D.
We will call this Zero Friction.
Whenever I hear the word friction,
I think of the song,
there's a fraction too much friction.
Have you heard that song?
Maybe it's just me,
maybe it shows how old I am.
[LAUGH] There's a fraction
too much friction.
Anyway, I have no idea who sings it.
I just, for some reason,
that's what friction is.
Okay, so click on the material
that we've created here.
You can see friction is 0.4,
put this all the way down to 0.
We don't need any bounciness
because they are stone walls, but
feel free to play around with that.
Just a side note, if you want to make a
bouncy thing, so bounce on a mushroom and
go boing, put down a mushroom, put
a bounciness on that of greater than 0,
maybe 1 or 2 or 10, or 100.
And that'll allow your player to go boing
when you bounce on a particular surface.
So that's something cool to
play around with, but for now,
we're gonna take this material.
Go over to the player, find the player's
capsule collider cuz that's the thing that
is sticking, not the rigid body.
There is a place to put
material on the rigid body, but
it's the capsule collider
where you want to put this.
That is our sticky point at the moment,
drag that over to material, hit play.
Run over to the side of the wall and
we should not be able to hold down and
get stuck on the wall.
Zoink, there we go, we're slipping.
Okay, we're still jumping.
We're still doing our big double jump.
That's going to be our next challenge and
this is a tournament challenge.
I'm gonna ask you to take
this on as a challenge.
So you stop the player wall jumping and
the goal here is to prevent the player
from doing the multi-jump when they're
touching the wall, and I've got a hint.
If you look at that and you're like, piece
of cake, I know what to do or you wanna
jump in and figure out, stare at it for
a while, figure it out like a puzzle.
If you're the sort of person who plays
puzzle games and you like puzzle games,
then this is a really cool
puzzle to work through.
If you want a hint,
I'm about to show you the hint now.
And the hint is, add a second collider
to represent the player's feet.
Make sure that that collider is
positioned in a way that it is only doing
feet-related things.
And then in our player script,
we need to make a distinction between
the feet and the regular colliders.
There's a hint for you, and if you wanna
jump in and take that on now, fantastic.
If you have any problems, I will see you
back here when you've had a go at it, and
we'll go through my solution.
Okay, for my solution, I am going to
scroll right in here onto the player,
I'm going to add a new component.
That new component is gonna be a collider.
I'll make it a box collider 2D.
Presently, we have a capsule collider 2D.
You can see that it opens up with
our big box around the player here.
I'm gonna click on the Edit Collider,
drag this in,
if I click on the Edit Collider
properly in here, Edit Collider.
One more time, Edit Collider.
And when I click on the green lines,
there we go, I can move it in.
Now, I need to make sure that
the feet are inside the capsule.
So that when the player comes
up to the wall, obviously,
this is a bit more extreme here, that
the wall is touching the capsule first.
The capsule is saying the player collides,
and stops and can't go any further, and
it is the feet that says,
am I touching the ground or not?
Because the problem is,
that this is the ground, but
the wall is also the ground as we've
got it set up in our tile map here.
It's a foreground.
So anything that's foreground,
the player can touch.
I'm gonna make, actually make
the capsule collider a little bit wider.
Make this a little bit easier, there
we go, a bit wider around the player.
I find this as an easier way to edit than
going into the offsets and size and stuff.
You can do it either way.
You can play around with these,
moving it left and right,
that does both sides.
Or you can grab the individual side and
play around with it.
Okay, back to our box collider, need to
bring this down a little bit to here, so
it's just fit, a little bit wider.
We don't want our player accidentally
not being able to get themselves
off of platforms.
Okay, it's looking pretty good,
there we go.
Like I said before,
if you wanna keep the wall jumping, cool,
then just make sure you're doing it with
the intention of it being wall jump.
Otherwise, you'll get in a bit of bother.
So we've got that in there.
Next thing we need to do is
jump into our player script.
And you can see that in our player
script here, we have the collider 2D.
And the collider 2D is a broad
way of saying, any collider,
2D collider type that
we have on our player.
But we can get the component,
we can get any of these components so
it's really cool.
We can get the individual capsule collider
2D, or we can get the box collider 2D.
So what I'm going to do in here,
is I'm going to leave the collider 2D.
So I'm going to leave myCollider2D.
It's just a holistic myCollider, that will
be used for bumping into walls and stuff.
And later on, we'll probably use that for
whether the player has hit an enemy or
needs to die, or
any of those kind of things.
So we need to keep that collider in
there and I'm going to change the type
though to, let's see,
it's going to be a capsule collider 2D,
and then we'll call this myBodyCollider,
I think we'll call it.
We'll do a control RR and
we'll call this myBodyCollider.
I don't think I need the 2D and
then I just got myBodyCollider,
and that's of capsule collider type 2D.
And you can see that's changed it
down in here, which is excellent.
I need a change in our GetComponent as
well to CapsuleCollider2D, excellent.
And then, we need to add one more,
which will be our type BoxCollider2D,
and I'll call this myFeet.
And then it's the myFeet
we're mostly interest in.
You're gonna copy myFeet here, and first
of all, I need to say what my feet is.
So myFeet, [LAUGH] Sounds funny,
doesn't it?
My feet, what are my feet?
Well, my feet are GetComponent
of type BoxCollider2D.
There we go.
And then, if we jump down to the two
areas, we're using this at the moment,
is in Jump and in ClimbLadder, and
we wish to change the myCollider.
So instead of it being myCollider,
we now need this to be myFeet, so
if myFeet are touching the ClimbLadder,
then we're able to climb.
And also in the Jump,
if myFeet touching the layers,
then it's all cool,
I should be able to jump.
So we'll save that,
I think that's all right.
I don't think I've missed
anything in there.
Jump back in here.
We now have this overall collider,
which doesn't have any functionality
at the moment but we will need that.
And we do need it for
when you're bumping into the walls.
And we have our feet, that is what we are
using to determine whether I'm touching
a ladder or touching, so I can jump, cool.
Can I double jump?
No, can I do wall jumps?
No, I cannot.
And last check, can I climb the ladder?
Yes, I can, fantastic.
Okay, so then we've shifted our mechanism
so that our player doesn't have those
nasty behaviors that we didn't want by
adding this extra, as our camera zooms in,
thanks camera, by adding a feet collider.
We could've childed underneath player,
we could add child game objective and
put feet on that.
I just find this is more
of a clean way to do it,
given that they're different
types of colliders.
We know that this box collider is
the body, and we know that the,
sorry, the box collider is feet, and
that the capsule collider is the body.
So great work, well done.
I hope you had success on that challenge.
If you implemented it a different way,
fantastic, good work.
There's plenty of ways to skin a cat, so
if it works for you, then that is great.
Run with it, otherwise, feel free
to implement it the way I've done,
and I will see you in an upcoming video.