[MUSIC]
In this video, we're gonna create
some vulnerability for the player, so
that when the player runs up and bonks
into the enemy here, they go flying off.
[LAUGH] That's a little bit too dramatic,
flying off and into a death state, and
we have no control for the play.
You can't move the player around anymore.
So let's jump in and
make our player perish, and
I'm gonna do a little
bit of tidy up first.
Some of you have been raising some really
good points about what's going on in our
scene here where we've got this
weird kind of gap between our tiles.
That's easily fixed by jumping into
your Sprite sheets, Sprite sheet here,
and instead of having Pixels Per Unit 32,
we have Pixels Per Unit 31,
just makes the whole thing
a little bit tighter.
So we'll do that for the background and
see those lines go away, and
then we do that for
the foreground layer as well.
That goes away.
We don't need to do that for the enemy and
the player cuz we're not
seeing this same issue.
But if I hit play now, we'll see that all
of those annoying gaps have gone away and
everything's nice and smooth.
That's so much nicer now.
The other thing I'm gonna do is just
tidy up my folders a little bit, and
put my enemy script
into my Scripts folder.
And I am going to prefab a couple of
things that we haven't prefabbed yet.
Click on my Prefab folder here,
just do a little bit of thinking.
And I'm going to drag my camera,
or Cameras
folder down here to prefab that, and also
my enemy, so we now have an Enemy prefab.
You might see a couple of
warnings from time to time.
I tend to get them if I've been
jumping between various different
versions of my project,
and other project, and
other versions of Unity as I'm trying out
different things to see what's working.
You'll also see it if you have something
in your script that you're not using like
the player is alive.
We're gonna use that in this very video,
so
we don't need to worry
about that at the moment.
And the myCollider, I think we're
gonna use that as well in this video.
So there's a couple of warnings in there,
that just based upon my code where
I put some things in, saying,
we'll use this later.
And Unity's saying, but
don't forget to use them.
Thank you, Unity,
don't worry, I shan't forget.
Okay, so we've got our player here.
And our player has on,
him or her, has a collision.
And this collision, this Capsule Collider
is what we're gonna use to say,
if that Capsule Collider comes
into contact with the enemy,
then we have some issues and we need
to trigger some sort of nasty death.
So I have a challenge that I'm going
to issue to you early in this video and
you can follow along with me at
any point in time if you think,
aha, I can do the rest of this.
Or if at any point, you think,
I've got this particular bit, please
the pause the video and jump into that.
So the dramatic death that we're gonna
trigger if the player touches the enemy
to stop the ability to move.
So stop the player as in
the person who's playing.
It's confusing, isn't it?
The player who's sitting
at their computer and
the player who is our little
character running around.
It's just the way video
games talk about themselves.
But stop the person playing the game
ability to move the character that
they're controlling in the game, to change
the player state so that animation state.
We don't have a whole big
death animation that's been
created in our Sprite sheet here.
But we've got enough to kind of
find something that we can use when
the player dies.
I'm just gonna use one
frame of death animation.
And then we want to trigger
some sort of dramatic death.
And for me,
I'm gonna have my character just kind of
go flying off in a particular direction
and make use of our physics system logo,
and boink off in a particular direction.
So we'll go through that together, or
you can pause the video and jump in and
do that now.
First thing I'm going to do
is open up my Player script.
And we can see that, as I was
mentioning at the start of the video,
we have this bool isAlive = true.
And at the moment,
it is true because the player is alive.
What we want to do is use
that as a mechanism to say,
if it's not true,
then the player is basically dead.
[LAUGH] That makes sense, doesn't it?
If you're not alive,
then you're dead, makes sense.
What I'm gonna do at the start is to go
down to our Update here, Update method.
You can see we're allowed to do all
these things, Run, ClimbLadder, Jump.
Most of these, these three,
have player input.
If we weren't calling those on Update,
then the player would lose their input.
So we're gonna have right at
the start of our Update method here,
we're going to say if is not,
so not, is not isAlive,
that makes sense, so
not isAlive, then return.
And what we're saying there,
return with a semicolon.
What we're saying there is, if you get
to the point where the player state has
changed, the state is now something
other than isAlive, then return.
Don't do these things down there.
And that should immediately turn off the
player's ability to control the character
running around in the world.
So that's step one of our process here,
stop the ability to move.
Now we need to create ourselves a method,
which is going to be the die method, or
the death method.
I know it all sounds terribly dramatic
when you use those words, doesn't it?
Hey, that's video games for you.
We use those words, so
I'm going to say, void Die.
Actually, I'm gonna call it a private
void, just to make sure we're nice and
clear on what's going on here,
private void Die().
And what are we doing in here?
Well, we want to say if
the player's collider
is touching something else,
then start doing this death sequence.
Let's have a look at what we're grabbing
at the moment for the collider.
We have a Capsule Collider.
So myBodyCollider that we set up before
when we differentiated the feet and
the body, we left in this myBodyCollider
so that we can use it now.
So that's the one we need
to access at the moment,
myBodyCollider back down to Die here.
We're gonna make this as an if statement.
If myBodyCollider IsTouchingLayers,
and we've done this previously
when we're looking at the player
being at a jump, IsTouchingLayers.
And then what's our layer mask?
LayerMask.GetMask().
Well, we set this up in the previous video
where we said our enemy has a layer mask
called Enemy.
And let me just double check that to
make sure I haven't typed in the wrong
thing in here.
Click on Enemy, and we'll see that
the enemy is on layer over here.
We'll go to Add Layer.
We don't actually need to add a layer, but
we're going in to see that
the layer is called Enemy.
Yes, it is, I remembered that correctly.
So I will go through the process
of pasting in there,
although we did have it right already
that if you're touching, if the player's
touching the mask that is known as Enemy,
then what are we going to do?
Well, we're gonna do
a couple of things in here.
This is a good spot that,
if you're ready, you can pause the video.
Let me remind you of our challenge in
here, is to change the player state and
trigger some sort of
dramatic death animation.
Well, not animation, per se, but
some sort of dramatic death.
I'm gonna fling my enemy
off in the distance.
You might wanna have them spiral around,
or change colors, or
grow huge, or
do something with the camera,.
So any particular dramatic sort of thing
you would like to do when the player dies,
so to do those too.
So there's a challenge again,
an opportunity to dive into the challenge,
if you're ready to do that.
And if so, I'll see you in a moment.
Otherwise, let's continue on together.
So in here, I'm gonna say if
the player is touching the enemy,
then first of all, I'm gonna create for
my animation, myAnimator,
sorry, myAnimator.SetTrigger SetTrigger,
SetTrigger.
And we haven't created this yet, but
I will go and create this in a moment, and
I'll call it Die when I do create it.
This is why the string reference is such
a pain, cuz I have to make sure this
is correct with what we've
got in our animation system.
So strings, in general,
are not so good, but
we're kind of forced to
use it in this instance.
But we're gonna set the animator to
a trigger that we will call Die, and
then I'm gonna do something
a little bit wacky.
I'm gonna get the component for
the myRigidBody.
So I'm gonna get the rigid body
of the player, RigidBody2D.
And what shall I do here?
Well, I said,
I'm just gonna sort of fling the player.
So velocity =,
I'm gonna serialize this, actually.
I'm gonna parameterize something that I'll
call deathKick, and we'll go up the top.
We'll grab deathKick here,
scroll all the way up to the top.
We will SerializeField up at
the very top of our script up here,
SerializeField, and
this is gonna be, not a float,
it's gonna be type Vector2,
Vector2 deathKick, as we've called it.
And this new Vector2 will be new Vector2,
And where do we want to push it?
So basically, we wanna give the player a
ton of velocity in a particular direction.
Let's just sort of throw it up in the air,
maybe 25f, 25f, see how that goes.
So to recap, what we've created down here
in our Die method, we're saying to get
the Rigidbody2D, something isn't liking
it here, I've left out my parentheses.
To get this Rigidbody and throw if off in
a particular direction, and at the same
time, set the animation to a state of Die,
which I'm gonna go and create right now.
Again, good chance to pause the video
if you think you know how to do this.
If you haven't paused the video yet, pause
the video and create yourself a die state.
I'm gonna go do through it the same
process that we've done before.
Find my Sprite sheet for the player.
Just find one that I think
could represent die.
That looks like a bit of a die just there,
so that's _10.
Right click on that &gt; Create Animation.
I know there's only one
frame in this animation,
but we'll use this mechanism in case we
want to put more frames in in the future.
We'll call this die, or death,
die, dying, dying, there we go.
Use the active mechanism,
the active process, the verb.
Is that what it is, is a verb?
Now, we've got our dying.
Let's go back to our enemy.
Where we are, let's put our
animation into our Animation folder.
Let's tidy up as we go.
Look at this mess I've created here,
just things in the wrong folder.
And we go to Animations, find the player,
animation controller here.
Now, we want to have death
possible from any state, so
I'm gonna grab this blue
Any State over here and
move that just in the middle, so
I can see it nice and easily.
Let's give ourselves a bit
more screen real estate here.
So from this Any State,
I want to transition into Death, and
our Dying, sorry.
So our Dying that we've got here,
drag that in.
We don't need to have it looping.
So that's one of the things that we
often look at, so we don't need to loop.
It's just a one time thing.
And we will right click,
make transition from Any State into Dying.
At the moment,
we don't have a transition parameter.
I'm gonna click on the + here,
and we'll make this a trigger.
It's just trigger dying, yes or no.
Dying when we trigger that,
that should happen, and
then that should make our
one frame come into state.
As with before,
we need to come into our transition.
So I'll click on Transition here,
and drag that guy out of the way.
Plus on the Conditions,
Dying is a trigger, so
there's not a true or false, and
dying is what's happening in there.
I'm going to tidy up my overlap here,
so it's not a fixed duration.
In the future, we'll use a mechanism.
We'll use probably
a co-routine with a wait for
seconds to say how long death lasts.
But for now,
we're just gonna trigger it and
then the player will get
stuck in that state.
That's fine,
we'll tidy that up in the future.
For now, we just wanna make sure
this mechanism actually happens and
actually works.
So we have Dying just here.
I'm gonna copy that cuz I typed
it in incorrectly in my script.
I was saying before about strings.
It is called Dying that we decided
to go with, save all that up.
Back into our editor, click play,
and if all goes to plan,
our player should fling off in
the distance and I should lose control.
Here we go, big dramatic moment,
nope, didn't do that.
So when we look at our Collisions, there's
gonna be something going on here in terms
of our Collision relationship,
usually because of triggers.
So let's have a look, our Box Collider,
our Capsule Collider here, Is Trigger.
We hadn't turned that on, let's try
that again, now that it is a trigger.
Run, run, run, run, run, and boink.
Okay, still running,
that didn't work either, so
let's put in a print statement
here to see what's going on.
Print, should be dying.
So here's how we do a little bit of active
debugging to see why our player is not
doing what it's supposed to do.
We haven't yet
turned off the controls, let's see.
Okay, so when I run up here on
the console, okay, that's not getting
triggered, so the problem is that this
collision is not happening in here.
Player should be dying, if myBodyCollider,
yes, IsTouchingLayers,
Enemy, then we want to die.
Aha, here we go.
We haven't added die into the list
of things that we can do.
Die, There we go.
I think that is gonna be it.
And you know what?
This seems to be a habit of mine,
I forget to put things in the update,
maybe make a mental note of that.
Not sure if you missed that as well,
but I definitely miss that often.
That and triggers,
they're the two things that I seem to miss
a lot when I'm going through these things.
Now, run along, run along, and boink.
Hey, and I can still drive
the player though, so that's good,
we've made progress.
I now need to go and
see why we are able to move around,
because as a last step,
absolutely, have you guessed it?
As a last step, if we are dying, so
as soon as we call this method of Die,
we want to say, in here.
Instead of is should be dying,
we wanna point out the truth which,
isAlive = false.
Okay, so
because we're saying isAlive is false,
then it will tell our Update
method isAlive is false.
Therefore, return,
then let the player run, climb, and
do those other good things.
Jump back into our building here,
click on play.
[SOUND] Run up there, boink!
Okay, and can't move and can't jump,
can't any of those things, fantastic.
Okay, and the last thing we wanna do is to
give our player a little bit more of a big
kick up into the air cuz it seems
there's not enough force going on.
So let's add a zero to the end
of this Death Kick on the X and
on the Y to see if that
satisfactorily flings the player.
It might be that our death kick to gravity
relationship was not strong enough.
Whoa, there we go, boing.
That was pretty dramatic.
I quite liked that one.
So one more time, just for the cameras.
Smile, Mr. Player,
when you bloink and die.
So we now have it that the player
has collisioned, it is a trigger.
When the player collides with the enemy,
we remove controls for the player.
The player goes flinging
off in the distance and
has their new death animation state, which
is just lying there in the corner and
having a bit of a cry,
which is what he's good.
Until we restart the level, which
we'll be doing in upcoming videos and
bringing your player back to life again.
So great work, well done.
I hope you're excited that your
player now is vulnerable, and
I will see you in the next video.