[MUSIC]
In this video we're starting to invest
a little bit of time into making our game
feel polished and feel interesting.
And we're adding a scrolling background.
So I've got it moving nice and
slow and gently, but
you can see our space field is
scrolling as we fly through our games.
Let's jump in and
make a scrolling background.
Currently we have a background in
our scene, which is pretty cool,
it's a Sprite.
We're gonna do something
a little bit different.
I'm going to start by creating a Quad.
So right click in your
Hierarchy &gt;3D Object, and Quad.
Quad basically is a flat surface,
a flat plain, that is the one side of
a cube, you can think of it that way.
So you can see we've got our orange
handles in our world here just
dragging it out.
And very very similar to a Sprite,
but a Quad has a property that will
allow us to do something cool with the
material, the texture that we apply to it.
So where as a Sprite is pretty much just
an image that is sitting in our scene.
This is a Quad, so a 3D object that then
has a material applied over the top of it.
What I'll do is take my blue background
and just turn that off for a moment.
So we can see I've got my big old white
Quad that's sitting in the scene.
Now, a couple of things for the Quad.
First of all, let's rename this
to be called Background, and
I'm gonna go ahead and
just delete my other background so
it's not gonna get in the way,
not to confuse me.
So I've got background in here, and
you can see because it's a Quad
it's brought in a couple of things,
it's got a Mesh Filter, it's got a Mesh
Renderer and it's got a Mesh Collider.
We're not gonna need the Mesh Collider,
so I'm gonna right click and
Remove Component and
then we focus on the Mesh Renderer.
Now, the material we've been using or
the Sprite we've been using for
our background.
This big blue, cool, spacey background
thing that I made, you can go ahead and
find a different space background
if you want, that's totally cool,
if you jump over to the Assets store.
If you don't have the Assets store tab,
then Window &gt; General &gt;and
Assets Store is how you find it.
Within the Asset Store, if that loads for
me, it's taking a moment.
We can search for
something say for example,
scrolling space background, for example.
And then, within there we've got
a bunch of different backgrounds,
these dynamic space background which
looks pretty cool, and it's free.
So you can jump in there and
grab your own background.
I recommend you do that, find something
that's different to what I have so
that your world, your scene,
your game is looking different to mine.
Even if it's only looking different but
acting the same, that's a great start
to have it really feel like its yours.
Okay, so I've got mine and
hopefully you've got yours.
Feel free to use mine for
now if you don't have a different one,
and our space background.
Now at the moment it's a Sprite.
I'm gonna leave it in the Sprite folder
despite the fact that we're gonna turn
it from a Sprite into a texture
that we can apply onto our Quad.
The way we do that is by clicking on
the space background we've got here.
And then in the inspector you can
see texture type Sprite 2D and UI.
I'm gonna change that to be default,
sorry, it's no longer a sprite.
It's now a default texture.
And the other thing I'm gonna do,
which is super important,
under Wrap Mode I'm gonna change
this from Clamp to Repeat.
That means that it can repeat,
it can loop over and over and over,
which I'll show you in a minute.
Click on Apply and
now it's as simple as dragging our
space background over our Quad, and
boom, there we go, it's been applied.
It doesn't quite look right though,
does it?
So what I'm gonna do is jump
over into click on background,
and then you can See here under space
background tiled we've got our Shader.
So this is a material we're using,
the shader type is standard,
I'm gonna change this from standard and
I expanded this.
I didn't need to expand this,
but I just expanded it cuz we're gonna
get down to some stuff in a moment.
Now change this from Standard Shader,
scroll down to Unlit, and Texture.
And now it looks as I'm
expecting it to look.
That's just taking the exact
same image that I had before and
just drop it into saying not
worrying about lighting.
Now underneath here you can see
that we've got Tiling and off-set.
And the cool thing about off-set, if you
hover over on the y-axis here, you can see
you get your little scroll wheel thingy,
with the arrows side by side.
If you move it to the right or
move it to the left then, it scrolls,
which is really cool.
And because I've created this texture so
that it doesn't have a scene,
although it's not perfect.
But it doesn't have a seam,
meaning that when I scroll in,
you can see down here is gonna
connect nice and neatly to up there.
Then it looks like it's seamless and
it's looping.
And this offset is just where do we
wanna have it positioned on our quad.
So this is the reason
we're using a quad and
applying a texture is cuz it
allows us to do this off-set.
And imagine what we could do if
we're moving this every frame,
then we can move our background, make it
look like it's scrolling, super cool.
Okay, so I've got background,
while I'm here,
I'm just gonna drag that into Prefabs.
It's always good to Prefab these things,
Prefab my background, and
I'll Prefab my Shredder that I've had
from before just in case we need it.
And I'll Prefab my Enemy Spawner.
It's good to Prefab all of these things.
Now, clicking on Background,
we need to have a script actually,
actually Igo to my Scripts folder.
I think this is a cleaner way to do it.
Right click, Create C# Script,
we'll call this Background Scroller.
Background Scroller if
you're in North America,
Background Scrollar if
you're in Australia.
Double click on that and open it up.
[SOUND] Now first of all I'm gonna need
some way of saying how fast it goes.
So I'm gonna SerializeField so
it's available in the inspector.
Create a float which we will call
backgroundScrollSpeed, nice and clear.
And we will initialize that at 0.5f.
I'm really not sure how fast we're gonna
go, and then I need to create another
couple of variables in here,
I need a way to connect with the material.
So when we go back onto Background we can
see that we have this material in here.
It's under Materials, Element 0,
Space-Background-Tiled, and
the Space-Background-Tiled when I open
it up has this concept of offset.
So we need a way to connect
our code with that, and
I'm gonna make myself a new variable.
I'll do it right underneath the other
one which will be of type material and
we'll just call it myMaterial.
Semi colon, and
then also we need a way of saying,
what the speed is or what the offset
is that we want to be applying.
So this is the offset down here,
just gonna reset this back to zero.
It doesn't really matter,
but I'll start it with zero.
So we're gonna create a vector too,
which I'll call offset.
Okay, so I have those three variables now.
Now, within Start, we need to kick
this off by saying, myMaterial equals,
we need to get the component
that is the material.
So, GetComponent, and
the component is the Renderer, Renderer.
Having closed parenthesis .material.
So this is how we are getting the material
that is sitting on our background
that is part of our mesh renderer.
And next we need to give offset some sort
of value on when we start this script.
So we'll say, I offset = new Vector2 and
then what is the Vector2 gonna be?
It's looking for an x and
it's looking for n y.
So here's a little mini challenge for
you, if you can figure this out.
What is our Vector2 going to be?
What do we need to be putting in there for
our x coordinate and our y coordinate?
Okay, so our x coordinate is gonna be 0.
We don't need to do anything with that,
0f.
And our y coordinate is going
to be our backgroundScrollSpeed.
Why is it the y coordinate?
Well, we wanna be moving our background
up and down or down I guess is the case.
So the y's the one that's moving.
If we would offset or change our x offset
then we'd be moving left to right which is
totally valid if you've got
a side-scrolling shooter.
That we have a top-down
flying upwards shooter.
And then finally, within our Update,
we need to be saying myMaterial.,
now this is the tricky part
that you might not know.
But it's gonna be mainTextureOffset, and
that's how we get access to this
mainTextureOffset down here.
So our mainTextureOffset += offset,
that's the offset that we
already created just above, *,
what do you think we times this
by to make it frame rate independent,
what we would times this by?
I hear you yelling at the screen,
Time.deltaTime.
Excellent, so we'll save this,
jump back over into Unity.
Make sure that we've added this
component to our background, so
click on Add Component.
It's called Background Scroller, there it
is right there, click and add, excellent.
We can see that in our, I'm just gonna
close this up, we have a speed of 0.5.
When we click on play, it should look
like we're flying, it does indeed.
Look at that, pew, pew.
Now, it's probably going a little bit too
fast for all of the galaxies behind us.
But this is something cool,
a little bit of extreme tuning.
What would happen if we put it to say 5.
Would it look like we're going through
some sort of jump speed, warp speeds.
My goodness, okay,
that's a little bit nauseating.
I'm not sure if my frame rate on my video
capture is picking that up for you but
that's way too fast.
So we'll say 0.02, see how that feels.
I'm just looking for a bit of
gentle scrolling in the background
just to give our world a little bit
of movement, a little bit of life.
That feels pretty good,
it feels like there is some movement.
And in the next video we're
gonna add a bit more depth.
We're gonna add some parallel x by putting
some particles that are closer and
moving quicker for the player.
So great work in this video.
It's super good fun I think
adding a little bit of polish and
I'll see you in the next lecture.