[MUSIC]
In this video we're creating sprites
in Unity, we're using just a square and
a circle to create a simple
little platformer scene.
You can see my amazing work of art, here,
inspired by Pitfall, my guy is jumping
to grab a rope across a water trap.
Let's jump in and
make some sprites in Unity.
Let's open up Unity hub and
start ourselves a new project,
click on New, choose the location.
We're going to put it, well I'm gonna
put mine in Repo's Unity 2D and
then I have a text 101
folder that I've created.
Double click on that, select project,
the name of the project, the project
name here I am going to call Playing With
Sprites, okay, Playing With Sprites.
And Template, we'll select 2D,
and Create project.
Now while Unity is loading up,
that'll probably take around about 20 or
30 seconds, let me show you
a quick slide on What Is A Sprite?
So a Sprite according to
the Unity documents is a 2D
graphic object obtained
from a bitmap image.
So here is our bitmap image, it's 8 by 8,
8 pixels by 8 pixels, so 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6,
7, 8, let me put on my pointer so
it's nice and clear, bouncy red.
These pixels, or this bitmap here,
this mapping of these individual bits,
is when we put it in our scene,
it's gonna look like this.
We won't the lines and
the other lines, they're just there so
I can show you where each of the bits is,
we'll acquire that in the scene.
Now this is only 8 by 8, so
it looks very pixelated,
that's why we talk about pixel art.
It looks like you can see every little
pixel, but instead of being 8 by 8,
if this image was I don't
know maybe 512 by 512.
Then you wouldn't see those individual
pixels and it would look more smooth,
more of a realistic image.
So Sprites aren't necessarily pixelated,
it's just I've zoomed in a long way,
that's why it's pixelated I thinks
what I'm looking for there.
And we can move, scale, rotate and
many other things with our Sprite.
So, a Sprite is an element
of a game aspect,
it's a game graphic that we can push
around on our screen, jump, and bounce,
and shoot, and explode, and
all those kind of good things.
So that is the core of a Sprite, and the
Sprites are really the building block for
our 2D games we're gonna be working on,
okie dokie, we're in Unity here now.
If your Unity doesn't look like this, then
again you can go to the top right layout,
click on Default, and
it should have the default layout for you.
What we'll do to start off with is take
a look at the relationship between
the hierarchy window the scene window,
the game window and the project
window with the assets directory in it
as well as the all important inspector.
So they're the main windows we're
gonna be looking at in here.
And we're gonna do that by adding
a couple of sprites into our scene.
First of all, within this scene here,
I can scroll outwards with my mouse wheel
to move backwards, or I can can forward.
So, I can also hold down Alt and
right mouse and move left and right,
the will move in and out within my scene.
The only thing in my scene is
the place that we built our world,
where we build all the things
that the player can see.
The only thing that we have in
there at the moment is this camera.
If I click on the little
camera icon there,
then you can see over in the hierarchy,
we have main camera selected.
If your camera is hidden,
maybe it's underneath the twiddle here.
This is our, the name of scene
is Sample Scene at the moment,
it's just the default name for it.
We have one Game Object,
and that's the main camera.
Everything within the hierarchy
is a Game Object.
So again,
have our camera as a game object.
We can have light, have the player,
have environment, have exploding barrels,
all of these things are game objects.
If we click on main camera, just click
on it once, over here in the inspector,
we get all of the information
about the main camera.
For now, we're not going to do very much,
we will just do one little thing,
which is, you can see our background.
If there's nothing else the camera
can see, as you can see down here,
this is the camera preview.
This is what we actually
see through the camera,
if we were to play the game now the way to
see what you can see through the camera if
you play the game is to click on game,
this is the default.
Then when we hit the play button,
as we did a lot in the last section,
we will run any of our code, and we won't
be able to actually play our game, but for
now this is the starting state of game.
Jump back over into scene here,
with our camera preview.
If I was to click on the color,
select it here, maybe change this color,
make it a bit brighter, maybe I'll make it
darker color, actually, make it brighter.
Okay let's make it darker.
That doesn't make sense, Rick,
but let's make it a green.
There we go, and
then x out of that window.
Now our camera preview is green.
It I was to click Click on the game tab,
and our background is all green.
Such is one little change we
made within the inspector here.
So now we have changed the properties of
the camera, these are all properties for
our main camera here.
Now, let's add ourselves
a couple of Sprites.
If we come down into the assets directory,
right-click anywhere in the space
in here under assets Right-click.
Scroll up to the top.
Under Create you'll see, over on
the right of Create, you'll see Sprites.
Within Sprites there's Square, Triangle,
Diamond, Hexagon, Circle and Polygon.
We'll start with Square.
So left-click on Square and
hit Enter on your keyboard.
That will create the square
in our assets directory.
Now this doesn't currently
live within our game.
It's not anywhere in our scene and
it's not anywhere in our hierarchy.
We can rectify that by grabbing this, and
dragging it either into our hierarchy,
or into our scene.
It will do the same thing,
in terms of creating it as a game object.
Let's drag it over into our hierarchy for
now.
Blink, and you'll see that
it has now appeared square.
Is now over here as a instantiated.
We've created an instance.
We've created one copy of square
over here in our hierarchy.
We can do that again.
We can drag it again and
create another copy and do it again and
create another copy.
These are all copying the exact thing
we have in our assets directory here.
And it puts it into our scene and
puts it into our hierarchy so
we can see a list of all
of our game objects.
Now you might not see it over here, cuz
they're all right on top of each other.
But if we were to click on
the second of these squares,
square one here, and
we have a mechanism for
moving our sprites around,
moving any game object in our scene.
Up at the top here we have a Sand tool,
a Move tool, Rotate tool,
Scale tool, Rect tool and a tool that has
more of a broad name that's not a such and
such tool, but move, rotate or
scale selected objects tool.
We'll call it a tool.
You can also use the keyboard
shortcuts of Q, W, E, R and T.
I'm going to use W, and
you can see we have our handles here.
We have our x handle.
Red is x in this instance and green is y.
If I was to grab, so mouse over the red
handle, left-click, and move to the right.
That will move our sprite that
we'd selected on square one,
move it to the right.
I'm going to click on square two.
And move that to the left.
We now have three squares
within our scene.
As we did with the camera, we can
click on one of these game objects and
change the color.
So let's change the color of
the first one to something else.
Maybe make it a yellow, whatever you like.
The color doesn't matter.
We're just playing around
with it here at the moment.
We don't just have to click on
it through the hierarchy though,
we can also click on it within the scene.
So if I click on this gameobject,
we can now see that it is selected,
change the color to dark red, why not?
X out of that, and then if I was to click
either in the hierarchy, or in the scene
on our third square, and change the color
of that to a bright blue maybe.
Now we have three squares,
three square boxes that are within our
scene that are also within our hierarchy.
So hopefully that's becoming really clear,
the relationship between the Game Objects,
these are game objects, are listed in our
hierarchy and are seen within the scene.
And pat of the reason we need
to have them listed here
is if we scroll the camera way over
here to some other part of our game,
and we're like hang on wait
a minute where was that square?
Then we can find it within
our list of gameobjects here.
And a little tip, if you double
click on one of your game objects.
It will zoom scene right
in focus on that object.
We can scroll back out again a little
bit with the mouse wheel, or
Alt+right click, and moving the mouse
left and right as we did a moment ago.
I'm gonna create one more of these
default sprites for our assets directory.
So right click from our Assets area.
Find create, onto sprites,
and I will put in a circle.
Now, it's waiting for us to name it,
just hit enter, that's fine,
now we have a circle.
Again, we can drag that into our scene,
and hey presto we have a circle.
One other main thing I'd like to show you,
in terms of manipulating our sprites here,
is when you click on any of your game
objects, we're having the same, we'll take
circle, you can change the position as
we did or the rotation or the scale.
We've already been playing around with
changing the position when we grabbed
the handle, so that's W on the keyboard,
and move left and right.
If you ever look at this number over here,
next to X on the X axes, you can see if we
move left It's getting lower,
as we move right, it's getting higher.
So it's showing us in the inspector here,
under Transform,
the transform position of our circle is
currently at 8.45x and 2.5 etc on the y.
We can move it up and down and
the y on that will change.
The z is going in and out of the screen.
Now I'm gonna show you something here.
We're not gonna play around
a lot with 3D in this course.
That's in our other course.
We're focusing on the challenges and
the benefits of 2D.
2D.
But if you were to jump up here to the top
just underneath where our game tab is,
the moment you'll see a button of 2D.
If we click on that 2D that toggles
between 2D and 3D, toggle it.
So if it's not highlighted
we're currently 3D,
that allows us to see what's
going on in 3D space.
If I hold down Alt And use my right
mouse button and move the mouse around.
I can rotate around in the world and
see what's going on.
Similarly, I could just hold
down the right mouse button, and
just look around from
the position that I'm in.
And I can move my position in
the world by just holding down my
middle mouse button and
just moving around.
So there's a little bit of
control we can have and
I wanted to show you that these
are all currently on the zero z-axis.
So on the z-axis they're
at the zero level.
If I was to move my circle,
here's my circle here.
If I was to move it in and out,
you can see the z-axis changing.
If I move it in and out,
it's not gonna change how I view it in 2D.
If I click over here on Game, you can see
there's my where my dot is in the scene.
You know what we'll do is
we'll grab our window.
So I'm bouncing around a little bit,
but we'll grab our window here and
move it next to our scene.
So we can see our scene and
our game side by side.
And I'm gonna click out the top
here on Free Aspect and
change the camera's aspect ratio
to one of these, 1024x768.
Just so it's locked in an aspect ratio.
And also move our circle back
onto the screen so we can see it.
This is where our camera is looking from
and you can see it's an orthographic
camera means it's looking at everything
straight, it's not showing any perspective
where things are on this plane
is where it's going to see it.
So, as we move our circle around left and
right and up and down.
We can see it positioned
within our world there.
If I do move it forward and
back, it doesn't change.
Because it's still being perceived by
our 2D camera, our orthographic camera,
in the same position on our x and
y coordinates.
So this is where it's on the x and y.
If I move the x and y up and down,
you can see over here in
the game it's moving up and down.
But if I move my z axis here in and
out, it doesn't change.
Okay, so I just wanted to show
you that briefly, just so
we've had a little bit of a look
at the The 2D versus 3D camera,
we gonna spend most of the time
clicked on a 2D button just here.
So, click on that to get back into 2D.
The last thing before I give a challenge,
and there is a challenge coming,
is we can scale up our objects.
I can scale in the x axes,
I can scale in the y axes to
make it bigger on the screen.
And the other way to scale
is by clicking on Rect tool.
We have that selected by
default at the moment.
You can grab the arms on the side or
even grab the nodes on the end
just to scale the object how you would
like to scale it, like that for example.
So that's us.
And then while we're in this
tour we can move it around and
you can see once we're
outside of this line here
we'll be outside of where our game
camera is rendering that object.
So if I move it over here it's off screen
and then in it comes and off it goes.
So the foundations of
animation right there as well.
Now here's where I have a challenge for
you.
Create a platformer level, just like the
little one you saw at the very very start
of this video where I was showing you
the example of what I've created.
Create your own platformer level,
just use the basic sprites and
it's a pretend level, so
make a little platform,
maybe make a little character if you want,
that would be cool.
Nothing's gonna move,
it's just a snapshot.
And note, this is just for fun.
We won't be using this in our game.
We won't be using it beyond this lecture.
It's just for you to get used to Unity and
share what you have with the community.
Once you've created something, create a
screenshot of that, take a screenshot and
we'll see what interesting and wacky and
cool things everyone can come up with.
So that's a challenge.
Pause the video and jump in and
give that your best shot now.
See you in a moment.
This is my sped recording at my work.
I'm duplicating my squares.
They're now rectangles, just moving
them around, creating a by a rectangle
that's rotated, working on a little guy
to be jumping over my water trap here.
Pitfall, an old, old game, making the
different elements of my character here.
And then highlighting them all,
selecting them all, and
rotating all of them in one go, that can
rotate the whole character in one hit.
Making a sun, changing the color of the
rope and the background of the camera, and
that is it.
And final note,
you can see that our hierarchy has
become a real big mess over here.
Things aren't named properly,
not organized very well.
That's something that in the future we'll
certainly spend a lot of time focusing on
but for now we just playing around
having a little bit of fun and
getting our hands dirty with Unity.
So great work in this video, I look
forward to your shares of what you've come
up with and
I will see you in the next video.