In this video,
we're gonna discuss what are variables and
we're gonna be adding a couple
of variables to our code.
So let's start by defining variables.
We can see that variables are like boxes.
So here's a box here and
the variable's name is hitPoints and
it has been assigned 20.
So there's a couple of statements
here that we can make.
Each variable is of a particular type and
I'll give you some examples
of types in a moment.
Each variable has a name,
in this case hitPoints.
And each variable contains data that we
can use in other places in our code and
throughout our game.
And with our example here,
we have a value of 20.
So, in this example, we would write
this in our code as int which stands for
integer which means it's a whole number.
hitPoints, that's the name that
we've given to our variable.
Starts with a lower case letter
when we're writing a variable.
Equals, now it's not equals,
it's an assignment.
You need to think of this as, we're
assigning whatever is on the right side,
is now going to be
the value of the left side.
So hitPoints is now has a value of 20,
and then semicolon at the end.
So our hitPoints box, our hitPoint
variable, now contains the data of 20.
So if we look at another couple of
examples, we have float, which is a type,
a float variable means that it has decimal
places, it's a number with decimal places.
The name is speed so
you can see our box here is speed and
it has been assigned a value of 3.8.
That's the value that's
sitting with inside the box.
And if it's a float we need to put
an f on the end and then semi-colon.
We can create a bool variable, bools
mean that something is true or false.
And our bool of isAlive is currently true.
And see is Alive and then
the assignment inside the box is true.
And the last example I've got
here is a type string name, so,
the variable is called name, it's of
type string and we've assigned it as,
the data value of Rick,
that's what name has been assigned as.
So, let's get tangible and
put this within our code.
What we need to do is jump back
over now in our script here, so
just a reminder, if you've been
closed down and you started up again,
we're now number wizards script,
we're in visual studio.
Is within our start method here, we want
to first of all declare the variable and
then we are going to
intialize the variable.
So we'll give ourselves a little bit
of space underneath the word start and
before we get to our debug.logs
when you're typing here, int,
cuz it's a type integer we're creating.
We'll call it max,
we could call it maximum or
maximumguess, that's up
to us what we call it.
So long as it's very, very clear what
the name of the variable is representing,
then we can call it what we like.
So int max, and
then if we put a semi colon on the end,
that would be enough to do what's called,
declaring the variable.
We hereby state we declare that
there's a variable called max.
Now, we can leave it and say later on in
our code, we would use that variable.
We would assign a value to it, maybe
we don't know what max is at start and
it's only after something happens
that we know what max is.
But for now, we know what max is for,
we're going to assign it at
this point in time as well.
We're gonna initialize it
by saying int max = 1000.
So that's our maximum guess.
And you may notice a green squiggly
line underneath the word max,
that's Visual Studio saying to us, hey,
here's a variable that you've declared but
you're not using it anywhere in your code.
That'll change in a just moment, I'm gonna
come down to Line 13 on my script here and
you see the highest number
you can pick is 1000.
So, instead of having
that written straight in,
cuz if we change our mind about 1000,
we need to go and
find this statement and
take it out there and change it up.
What if It changes over time?
What if we want to modify it?
It's much, much more powerful for us to
have this as a variable down in here.
So, what I'm gonna do is delete this part.
So, the highest number you can pick is,
I'm gonna go colon and then leave a space.
And then after the quotation mark,
leave another space and
type, + and then write in here max and
we'll touch on this spacing
a little bit more later on the video but
for now we're focusing on the variable.
And so, what we've said in here is,
we're gonna print out with our Debug.log
statement the same thing we had before,
the highest number you can pick is, but
then we've stopped the string part of it.
Unity and C# don't care what's inside,
the string, they're like, I'm just gonna
printout whatever you've got in there and
we've added a + operator here
which allows us to join on max.
And what is max?
Well, you can see when
you highlight over or
click over it knows max over here is 1000.
I'm gonna put put something in a little
bit silly, just so you know it's working.
I'm gonna put in, we'll see 99999,
save that, come over into Unity and
then click on play and
we should see in here,
it'll say, the highest number
you can pick is 99999, so
it's reading from the variable
which is very cool.
Just unplay that, come back in here.
And so we've got our maximum value that is
being printed out on the screen because
it's printing out this as a variable.
So, I can come back in here again and
change it back to 1000.
So, that leads me to the challenge
I've got for you, it's a nice,
straightforward challenge.
And the challenge is, to create a minimum,
create a minimum variable and
assign it a value of 1.
And then alter the player instructions to
use the minimum variable as we did for
the maximum.
So, just pretty much the same as
we've done here with max and max.
Do the same for min and min.
So, jump in and
take on that challenge now.
See you in a moment.
Okay, welcome back.
This is a pretty straightforward one, but
this is the foundation as we're
going through this process,
getting this stuff right, this is what
will really set you up for success.
So, I'm gonna give myself
another line in here, and
type in int, again, it's an integer.
Call it min, assign it a value of 1
enclose it with semicolon as always.
And I'll come down into
my statement down here.
The lowest number you can pick is, and
I will put a semicolon and a space.
I need a space because the spaces
within the quotation marks count.
It will give us a space in our console.
Plus to do that it would give
us a whole bunch of spaces.
But any spaces we do
outside here don't count.
Unity and C#, just ignore that,
they don't care about that.
I can do +min down here and it would just
ignore all of this white space in here and
it would go straight to the next
meaningful thing here, which is there, and
will join that right up against
the end of that quotation mark.
So, we can do that just so
we can make it nice and clean.
It's important to us to make it look good,
but
it's not important to Unity
how it uses it, or to C#.
Okay, save that.
And again, I'm just gonna to do
it something a little bit wacky.
I'll do 19 just so I can see if it works.
Jump back over into here, click Play.
And it should be between 1,019,
there we go.
So in this video, we have given
our selves, put that back to one,
given ourselves a variable to create
a maximum, a variable to create a minimum,
and then we are using that within
a Debug statement here, so
that we're joining our
string with our variables.
So it prints them out one after the other.
Great work and
I'll see you in the next video.