In this video, we're gonna write our
first line of code in Visual Studio.
That's going to be print Hello World,
and then when we go into Unity and
click play, in the console area of Unity,
it will print Hello World.
This is a small but very significant step
in making sure that our environment is set
up correctly, and Unity and Visual Studio
are working correctly together.
Let's start by talking
briefly about how Unity and
Visual Studio relate to one another.
So Unity is our game engine.
This is where we say what
the behaviors are in our game, and
how all the pieces relate to one another.
And how it all looks and
how it all shapes up and comes together.
One of the pieces that we
use in Unity is our code,
and our code is written in
files that are .cs files.
These are also called scripts, and
they're a bunch of texts that say what
are the rules and behaviors of the things
that we want to have happen in our game.
And the place that we write these
scripts is in Visual Studio.
Visual Studio is an IDE, that's
an Integrated Developer Environment.
And it gives us a whole lot of structure
and tools to make our life easier, and
to avoid making mistakes.
So if you're a Mac user, this is a good
time to point out that there's really not
a lot of differences between Mac and PC
when it comes to Unity and Visual Studio.
But in the next video,
Ben is gonna through those differences, so
it's really clear what you're
looking at and how it relates, and
how it differs from what
we're seeing on the PC.
So let's go ahead and
create our first scripts, and
use Visual Studio to make
a little bit of magic in Unity.
So let's open up Unity Hub, few after you
downloaded it, it might have a shortcut
on your desktop, or you might need to
navigate to it through your Program menu.
When you open that up, you can see
I've got a bunch of projects in here.
If this is the first time you are using
Hub, then yours is probably empty.
And you wanna make sure that,
under Installs, you got 2018 or
later ready to go.
So, from any of these tabs up hear,
click on New.
And that will allow us
to create a new project,
and it's gonna ask us where
we want to save that.
Let me just show you my directory here.
I put that and then we can see
exactly what's going on in here.
So for me, I've created under my D drive.
So just any of your drives.
I've got a D drive here, I've created
a photo called Repos which is short for
the terminology repositories,
which is something
that'll be relevant later on in the course
when we look at source control.
And then within Repos,
I've created Unity2D,
which is where all of the projects
from this course are going to go,
and the first section we're
working on isIntro_Setup.
So, I encourage you to
do a similar structure,
have a Repos directory
with our Unity2D course,
and then for this particular section it's
intro and setup, ready and running this.
So when we go into start our new project,
we click on the three little dots to
the right of location, down here,
and that will allow us to go and
choose where we want to set that up.
Go to DATA, or DATA, depending
from where you're from, Repos, and
then Unity2D, and then Intro_Setup.
So I'm gonna just click on that once and
select Project, and
we'll use that as our project location.
Now it's really important to
know that a Unity Project
is a folder with a set of directories and
a set of files with inside it.
When we start a project, it's not just
one file, it's a whole bunch of files.
We're gonna call the project name,
here we'll call this Hello World,
as all good programming first
steps should be a Hello World, and
under Template we're going to select 2D,
and then click Create project.
There might be a little bit of loading,
a little bit of setup,
a little bit of importing,
particularly if it's the first time.
So bear with that, it should do
all of that automatically, and
then we will be into the engine.
Okay, so that started up our project.
Let's just have a quick look in our
directory to see what happened there
in the Intro_Setup.
We now have a Hello World folder, I've got
a couple of other things in here that you
won't have yet, cuz I've put them in.
But the important thing is to see
that we've got a Hello World.
Within that there's a whole bunch
of folders that Unity's created for
us, including the Assets folder, and
that's where all of our information,
all of our game assets,
and artwork, and scripts.
Everything is gonna go into Assets,
so that's being created for us.
If your layout looks different to mine,
you can come up to the top right here,
it says Layout,
click on that button and find Default.
When you click on Default, that should
default everything back to the default
windows layout, so it should look
the same as what I have here.
So from anywhere down in this Assets area
down here, right click, go to Create,
and then find C# Script, click on that,
and you'll see it create a script.
Now, important message, we wanna typing
straight away the name of our script,
don't click anywhere else and
don't hit Enter.
Cuz if you do that, you'll accidentally
create this file with the default name.
And if we create it with the default name,
when we go and rename it in a moment,
it will cause some issues and some errors.
So you wanna make sure that while the
script name is still highlighted and blue,
that you start typing straight away.
We're gonna change the name of
this to HelloWorld, no spaces.
And I've put capital H and capital W.
And you know you've created your script
correctly if the name underneath
the script there matches the name we see
over in inspector you can see public class
HelloWorld.
So if its Hello World there ,and
HelloWorld under your script, success,
we are ready to go.
If they are different,
Unity is gonna be a bit upset and
you need to delete your script and
start that process again.
So let's double click on HelloWorld.
It'll open up Visual Studio.
There might be a little bit of
initial setup and initial loading.
Okay, and there's a lot going on here.
There's a few things we don't need,
so I'm gonna close over here,
my Solution Explorer, just x out on that.
And my Team Explorer and Properties,
all of those things we don't need at
the moment, so I'm gonna close that out.
So this script that we
created over here in Unity
already comes with a bunch of text,
a bunch of information on it.
We're not gonna go into
the details of that yet,
I promise you we'll get into all of that.
And in no time you'll understand
everything that's going on within here.
But for now, we're just going to get our
hands dirty by writing a line of code.
So, I want you to click on line number 9,
clicking there underneath Start
verses void start, just follow along
with me here, hands dirty, right.
Our first line of code and type print, and
after that we're gonna type open
brackets or open parenthesis.
And then quotation mark, and
you can see cuz we are in
our best friend of Visual Studio,
it knows what we wanna do.
It's already give us a closed bracket and
a closed quotation mark.
And it's already giving us some
information down here saying,
hey you might wanna know this,
and this might be useful.
This is great stuff.
Over time you'll recognize that,
and you'll see this fantastic.
For now, don't worry about all
that information coming out.
We're gonna finish typing here,
we'll type Hello World.
And then down the end of our
statement here, we need to type a ;,
and you can see when we did that
the little squiggly red line went away.
I'll do that one more time.
When we've got no ; there's
a squiggly red line seen, and
if you mouse over that,
you can see ;expected.
So this is our best buddy Visual Studio
trying to help us out here,
saying I really think you
should put a semicolon there.
Yes, we do need to do one of those.
Okay then, I want to hit Save, and
you can see the little star
that was up here went away.
And, we have a green line that appears
to say that we have saved our script.
Now, back over into Unity this
is a script we're working on.
It's been saved,
now there's one last step we need to do.
Our script just sitting on
it's own isn't doing anything,
we need to bring it into our world
by attaching it to a game object.
And, the only game object
we've got is our camera.
So, if your sample scene has closed,
you can click the little arrow next to it.
That'll open it up to show all of
the things in the hierarchy underneath
Sample Scene, and
you can see we have main camera.
That's our game object,
the only game object in the moment.
So we're going to drag our HelloWorld
script on to our main camera at
the top here.
We could have also dragged it over here
into the inspector while we're selected on
main camera, either these ways
would have served the same purpose.
You can see now when clicked on
main camera within the inspector,
we've got our HelloWorld script there.
If you come out to the top and
click the Play button, and
open up the Console here,
we haven't talked about the Console yet.
The Console is what allows
us to see the messages, and
the information allows
us to debug our game.
It's a great place to print things out.
You can see Hello World is
written right in there.
Success, we have created
our first line of code.
Now I have a challenge for you, and
what I would like you to do
is to print Hello YourName.
So to modify our Hello World code,
instead of printing out Hello World,
I'd like it to print out YourName.
And obviously it wouldn't say YourName, it
would saying Hello Rick, or Hello Fred, or
Hello Bob, whatever your name might be.
So, pause the video now,
go into the script,
change from Hello World to Hello YourName,
Save, and
then go back into Unity and click Play,
and see that it tops Hello YourName.
And after you do that, come back to
the video and play the video again, and
I will my approach doing that as well, and
we can finish off this excercise together.
So, I will see you in a moment.
Okay, welcome back.
We'll make sure we click out of play mode.
I'd left ourselves in play mode, and
I really hope that you did that challenge.
I'm gonna ask you to do a challenge
in each lecture in this course, and
it's super super important that you
jump in and take on these challenges.
Okay, so
I'm back over in VisualStudio here, and
you can see our statement print("Hello
World"), I'm just gonna hop in here and
change this to "Hello Rick" and hit Save.
Back over into Unity, we don't need to
attach it to the main camera again,
cuz it's already attached there.
If we click on the main camera,
you can see Hello World,
it's been updated because we've saved it.
And then when I click play,
you should see Hello Rick down here.
And this really was a quick exercise
to make sure that our environment is
set up correctly.
In the next section of the course,
Number Wizard,
we'll be looking at all the things
that we went over very quickly here.
About the inspector,
about the layout, in terms of just things
like semi-colons, why are we doing them?
So, all of that information we'll
be covering in great detail
in the next section of the course.
During the next video Ben is going
to be talking about Mac differences,
if you are a Mac person,
that's a great video to watch.
If not, you can skip that video and
go into the next video in the course.
Great work, and I will see you again soon.