[MUSIC]
In this video we'll be
creating our success levels so
that when the player reaches the very end
of your game there is a scene that loads
where they can run around.
Some sort of congratulations,
winner, winner chicken dinner.
Click the main menu, that takes
you back to the very first screen.
This is our main screen where
we've implemented a start button,
where you can start the game and
then go through the game.
So it's all just very
functional at the moment.
You can make it as pretty and awesome and
dressed up as you like, but for
now we just want to get that full complete
game flow implemented in our game.
Let's start by making
ourselves a start button.
I'm gonna right click, go to UI &gt; Button.
That automatically
creates a canvas as well.
I'm just gonna rename
this main menu Canvas.
Not critical to do that, but I like to
do it just do I know what's going on.
And then button, we are going to
rename to start button,that is cool.
And you can see underneath
the start button we have some text.
The text we will name start game.
Okay so that's all our naming done,
although I guess that's
labeling as opposed to naming.
I'm going to double click the start
button itself so it zooms in and
reposition that so
it's in the middle of the screen.
You can see when the line goes blue it's
in the middle, and hold down alt, so
I'm going to move this a little
bit then hold down alt.
So it moves both sides, and
drag it down a little bit, okay.
So we've got the button roughly
the size that I want to have it,
on top of my game screen there.
I'm gonna have the two
windows side by side, so
I can see how it actually
looks in my game screen.
Drag this over,
you see at the moment that it's not
matching with what we have on the left,
with what we have on the right.
This is, as I move my perspective,
I move the scaling of my window.
It's making a mess of my button here,
so let's clean that up by
clicking on the main menu canvas.
See the canvas scaler here instead of
constant pixel size say scale with
screen size.
Now as I move my window around, if we had
different resolution and different scaling
and all that kind of good stuff,
the button will stay as we want it.
And click on the button,
that'll take me down to text.
Click on the button, there we go,
I'm gonna move these handles.
Currently it's anchored just
generally in the middle.
I'll click on the up,
I'm sorry on the top, so
center top you can see it's
anchored up the center top now.
What I want to do is anchor it
relative to the rest of the screen.
So I need to grab the handles here,
pull that down to the bottom left,
pull that to the bottom right.
So I have a handle on each
of the corner of my canvas.
That means this will stay
relative to screen size, as well.
As we move it around, it's going
to stay anchored to its position
on the outside of the screen.
Last tip, click on the Start button.
I'm gonna change the color.
Well, this is probably
the second last step, actually.
Make the color a little bit of a yellow.
And then the last step, click on Text.
And change the font size here,
make this 50, nice and
big, probably change it to bold.
Plenty of scope in there for
you to go and change the font,
maybe do some text mesh pro and
make this look a little bit more fancy.
For now that's it.
Good for us.
Actually I told a fib,
there's one last last step.
How many last steps are we going to have,
Eric?
Well one last last step, which is change
the highlight color and press color.
Highlight color will change
to kind of an orangey color,
that's when you mouse over it.
And then when it is clicked,
we'll change it to a darker,
kind of brownie color here.
So I click play, then mouse over it and
we will see what effect that it has.
Mouse over, yep and then click.
And that's doing all the stuff
that I want it to do.
And still move my character
around independent of that.
You could just have the load next
out level exit button down here.
And have the whole thing blank and
let the player figure it out
when they come down here.
That would be cool as well,
having an exciting way to learn how to.
Exit a level but
for now when it goes through this
mechanism of doing stop button.
Okay, what we need to do for
our button is give it a script and
with that script we want
to load in the next scene.
So I come down to add component.
We'll call this menu, yes,
and then create and add that.
Open up Visual Studio.
And this would be a very
simple script in here.
I need to make sure we're
using the namespace,
unityengine.scenemanagement.
Okay, now we're using that.
Going to remove the start and
update functions, we don't need those.
Create our function,
which we'll call StartFirstLevel, I think.
StartFirstLevel, and
I typed that in first cuz I wanna
take a moment just to point out that
we're gonna need to make this public.
So public Void needs to be public so
that from our button,
we're in a position to cull this method,
so that we can load the next level.
That's why we need to have it public.
And then what do we need to do in here?
Well, we need to say
scenemanager.loadscene.
And what scene are we loading?
We'll load scene one.
That looks pretty good.
And we click on our selector here,
hit the Scene tab.
And then we're looking for
our start button,
which is in the scene,
selected the start button.
Now we have the start button,
which contains the menu script.
From there we can click on Menu and
find Start First Level.
That should be the mechanism for
when we click the button,
it will run this method and
it will take us to the first level.
Let's see if that actually works,
click play.
I ran a little bit, click the button, and
then it loads onto the next level,
fantastic.
Okay, so that's the mechanism
of creating a start button.
I want to top and tail the game, in other
words have something at the front and
end by having a success screen as well.
That's my challenge for
you, create a success level,
where we have a final you win screen.
Similar to the start menu but
with a you win, and
then some sort of congratulations or
well done this is fantastic.
And then a play again button, which will
take the player back to the first level.
Or you could have it take
them back to the main menu.
And then from there they can go to play.
So maybe I'll do it that way.
At the very end it says, finish or
success or well done and
then have that take
the player to the main menu.
And as a final step add some flair and
share,
do something nifty with your final screen.
When the player wins do something cool and
add some fireworks or
the play doing backflips,
and share that with us.
And when you've done that
I will see you back here.
Okay, let's quickly go
through this together,
I'm going to duplicate my main menu,
call this success.
Make sure that I've gone up into my
build settings up Yonda, where are you?
File, build settings.
And to add Success in here and
have it as index number 3.
Cool, that's all good.
We're currently selected on Main Menu.
Jump into Success screen.
And do just a little bit of editing,
very quick editing here on the,
Screen itself,
just to show it's a little bit different.
So Instead of climbing,
we need to click on Foreground, and
then on my tile brush, my rule tile.
I'll get rid of all this
stuff at the top here,
make it look like there's some
opening that they've reached the end.
And some sort of, yeah,
some sort of teasing them ladder,
that kind of goes nowhere,
I think might be a little interesting.
Click on the climbing layer, click on the
ladder, and then here's a ladder that sort
of just Ambiguously goes up
to the top of the screen.
Okay not the greatest of final screen but
one of those things it could be a little
bit cool having the player window.
What on earth should I be doing here?
We'll add something more complex as
we make the game in more detail,
I think as for what we've got now.
Okay so we've just duplicated all the
content over instead of our, where is it?
Instead of our main menu canvas, I'll
rename this to finish canvas or success.
Success menu canvas, okay.
And then instead of the button being stop,
I'm going to have this a replay button,
I think.
Replay good replay button, and
then the text will need
to say replay game, good.
That looks pretty good.
Like I say you can
differentiate this a bunch.
For now I'm just going through
the role of functionality of it to
make sure it all works.
And then the script is gonna
do exactly the same thing.
We need to point it back to the start.
So that's our end screen, if we're
on here, loaded on the success menu.
Run around, run around, run around,
and then click Replay Game.
It takes us back to the first level,
it looks a little bit odd,
cuz I've started my player in
the middle of the first level.
But we'd have it start in the proper
place in the first level.
If we want to have that go
back to the load screen,
then we would change the button.
Instead of it being Replay we would say,
main menu, or something along those lines.
Change the button to main menu button,
and then we need to change,
make a change for our script in here.
Jumping in the menu, reload,
I guess I need to do that, yup.
And then we create another
method instead of public void,
start first level,
we're going to say Public void,
LoadMainMenu, and
that will be a index of zero.
Okay, then back over into our,
what's this we're on now.
Main menu button down here.
We need to change out on click,
instead of being main menu.
Sorry, first startfirstlevel,
it needs to be loadmainmenu, there we go.
We've saved that and
then click play, all going to play, this
should take us back to the very start.
Click Main Menu,
it takes us back to Start Game.
Start Game, Run through.
Get to the [SOUND].
Okay, that killed me but that's all good.
So we've got our flow worked out now.
That should be enough functionality for
you to be able to do your full flow from
Main Menu to Game through
all the game scenes.
Back to the end, you win.
Once you have that success,
then you return back to
the very start of the screen.
I said adding a little bit of flair or
a little bit of something in there, some
text to let them know they actually won.
Let's do that very briefly.
So under my Success main menu,
I'm gonna right-click, UI, Text.
And this text box will say
something along the lines of,
let's see, winner, winner chicken dinner.
For those of you who are familiar with
PUBG, you will know what that's all about.
We'll make this 30, and
we will change the size of that
a little bit, go to my t tool here.
Move that, move this.
Little bit bigger,
winner winner chicken dinner.
Okay, center that text and I think I will
put a line break in between these two,
there we go, winner winner chicken dinner.
Its a little bit light,
lets make it white in color.
The color of the text in here white,
there we go.
Last step I'm just going to reposition
my text to be above the menu and
my menu to be below my text, there we go.
Okay, not super pretty,
but is super functional.
There we have our final success screen.
You've also created a main menu
screen which has a start button that
launches the game.
That's the full flow and
I'll see you in the next video for
some more chunky aspects of getting our
game flowing nicely for the player.
See you in there.