[SOUND] In this lecture,
we're gonna be implementing a delay.
So that when the player happens to
die by crashing in to an enemy or
any other way, we have a delay,
then we trigger our Game Over screen.
So let's jump in and
make a little bit of Game Over magic.
Before we do that, I'm first gonna tidy
up my enemy spawning a little bit.
And have that the enemy do damage
the player when the collide.
First of all,
I have to look at my spawner.
So I'm over in my game scene,
enemy spawner have two waves.
I'm gonna change this to four, cuz I've
created four waves at the moment, four.
And then Wave 1, Wave 2,
I'll make Wave 3, and Wave 4.
Just so
I've got a little bit more variation.
And then Wave 3 and
4 I think are triggering Bernard.
So you know what I'm gonna do, I'll just
switch this up, Wave 3, and then Wave 2.
Do it however you like.
I'm just, I know that my Wave 1 is
Roger and Wave 3 is Bernard and
Wave 2 is Roger and so on.
So if I show you that just very briefly,
Wave 1 is Roger, and
Wave 2 is also Roger, Wave 3 is Bernard,
and Wave 4 is Bernard, okay.
Just so I've got some variation there.
Now what I wanna do is have a look
at my prefabs for my enemies and
we'll see what's going on.
We're currently just passing
straight through the enemy.
So I need to change it so
that we bump into them.
To do that we need two things.
So I'm gonna highlight both of my enemies,
Roger and Bernard.
So I've control clicked on both of them.
So I've got the two selected at once.
Just gonna close up the enemy scripts so
I've got a bit of room here.
And I'll add components at the same time.
So if you've got two things selected
you can click add component.
And then what I want to
do is add a rigid body 2D
to both of these and then change
the rigid body 2D to be kinematic.
Okay, and then the last thing I
need to do in here I believe,
who am I selected on, if I select
Roger I can see Roger has a collider.
I'll make that collider a trigger,
the circle collider is a trigger.
I'm gonna right click on the circle
collider copy component.
Jump over to Bernard because I
realize that Bernard doesn't even have
a collider on him.
So what we can do now that we've
copied the component just right click
on any of the components,
paste component as new.
And that will paste in this circle
collider component from before.
Let's click on Play, just see now
if we can bump into the Rogers and
Bernards of the world.
Okay, so we've got this, it's a little bit
boring, what I've set up for my things.
Okay, we're not bumping into them,
why is that?
That's because we haven't
added the script or
the component as the script,
that allows us to do damage.
So again select Bernard,
select Roger, and then Add Component.
We need to add,
what is this, Damage Dealer.
Okay, Damage Dealer, and
now they should be doing damage.
I'll add this, I'll increase this to 200.
I think, so if you bump into an enemy,
you die instantly.
The player's got 200 health.
Right now I can see we've got
an error down the bottom.
We should always have a look at those.
Variable projectile of enemy
has not been assigned,
that's because Bernard we haven't really
set Bernard up with anything, have we?
If we go and
open up Bernard's enemy script.
I can see that we need to say
what the projectile is, so
I'll click on my select there,
Enemy Laser.
Need to see what the Death VFX are, so
I'm gonna say the Explosion Particle.
And what is the Death Sound,
I'll say Death Effect.
And then I'll say what's
the Shoot Sound We'll say, I don't know,
laser6, we'll do something,
we'll be different.
Don't know what that sounds like,
but we'll give it a shot.
So that should all be reasonably good.
The last thing I'll do in here is, I think
I have my Waves a little bit boring.
So I'm gonna just change these
back to Wave 1, Wave 2, Wave 3,
Wave 4, and we'll see how that goes.
Doesn't really matter at the moment,
I'm nowhere near the point where
I'm polishing and tuning my waves.
I'm just making sure that it
gives a little bit of variety.
So we're not doing the same over and
over in our game.
Okay, and out they come [SOUND].
Yes, I can crash into to Bernard.
And I'm guessing I can
also crash into Roger.
I'm really curious, if you wanna
leave a comment in the discussion,
what have you named your enemies?
Have you just gone with Bernard and
Roger as I have, or
have you done something more interesting,
have you come up with your own names?
I'm just gonna clear this in the console,
cuz that error is not happening anymore.
I just wanna clear it away.
Okay, so yeah, let me know, let us all
know what are you naming your enemies,
if anything.
Okay, now let's introduce a delay and
we'll load from this screen into
the game over when the player dies.
So I need to go and
find my script for player.
We'll be working in the player script and
the level script in this video.
First of all, we'll start off with
player and see what we need to do and
where we need to do it.
So that when the player dies,
we trigger the game over.
So let's see, scrolling down.
Well right in the middle here, we've got
die, we're destroying the game object.
So destroy the player that they disappear
and then we are playing a particular sound
within this die method
we're calling in here.
So I'm just gonna put in right in
here right now to say, let's say,
we need to load from the level,
we need to call the method.
So we need to LoadGameOver as a method,
public method.
How do we do that,
well first of all we need to say go and
point yourself to Level.cs.
And we know there's only gonna be one
level in our game at any point in time.
So then we can say, findObjectOfType.
What's the type?
The type is going to be Level.
That's how we go and
point ourselves to that other script.
And then we need parentheses, cuz it's a
method, dot, and we can call LoadGameOver,
which is contained within our
Level script, and then semicolon.
So we'll do that, save up,
jump back over into Unity.
And then I'll just kill the player, and
see if that triggers the Game Over screen,
which it should.
Actually, you know what?
It's not going to because we
haven't done one critical step,
which is go into our Build Settings and
to add our scenes.
And you can see see we're getting
that nice error down at the bottom.
I'll hop on the console here.
We can see that the scene Game Over could
not be loaded because it's, basically,
it hasn't been added to the build.
So thank you console,
thanks for the cool error.
And then we will go over the project,
go to project, grab Game Over,
drop that into our build.
Now it should all be nicely in place,
so that when the player gets shot or
bumps into an enemy,
they have the appropriate death happening.
Boink, and Game Over, great!
That's really cool, but
we need a little bit of a delay, cuz we
wanna be able to play our sound effect and
we want to trigger some visual effects.
And we also want the player to have
a moment to yell at the screen and
curse and, you know,
[SOUND] before Game Over comes up.
So to do that, I'm going to do
that in a reasonably simple way.
I'm gonna go into my Level.cs and
implement a coroutine.
And this is where I'm gonna give you
a challenge, to delay level load.
And it's a good challenge,
because you've already implemented
coroutines a couple of times.
So you should know how to do it.
But here it is, implement a Coroutine
with our LoadGameOver method when
the player dies, so that we have a short
delay before loading the Game Over scene.
That is your mission if
you choose to accept it.
And just a couple of reminders with our
Coroutine, we need to use StartCoroutine.
We need to have an IEnumerator
as the type of the method that
we are going to be calling and returning.
And then we need to use yield return
new and have some sort of condition.
And then after the condition has been met
then we will load the Game Over scene.
So jump in, take on that challenge and
I'll see you back here when you
have given it a red hot go.
Okay, so we're within the public void
GameOver in our Level.cs script.
What we need to do first within here
is to have a StartCoroutine, so
we're calling the coroutine.
We're not gonna turn
this into a coroutine.
We're gonna say that when LoadGameOver is
called, then when we start a coroutine,
so the StartCoroutine, and
we'll call this WaitAndLoad.
That's our method and
then parenthesis, semicolon.
It hasn't been created yet, so
let's down underneath LoadGameOver method,
we will start with IEnumerator.
IEnumerator what are we going to do here.
Well we are going to call it WaitAndLoad,
parenthesis.
And then we put in our curly braces.
That's all looking pretty good.
Red squiggly line, that's because we
haven't yet told it the yield conditions.
I'm gonna grab the SceneManager.LoadScene,
cut that out,
paste it in there cuz that's one
of the key things we're doing.
We are loading the scene but
we need to load the scene after our delay.
So we'll do our delay by saying yield
return new and then what are we doing?
WaitForSeconds, how many seconds?
Well we need it to be a variable.
We don't wanna have this baked
right within our code so
we'll say, delayInSeconds,
and then semicolon.
Delay in seconds hasn't been created yet,
so
I'm gonna copy that up to
the top of the script.
A little bit of space.
This will be a what, a float.
So float,
we need to serialize this actually.
SerializeField and
then float delayInSeconds,
and we'll initialize this at, what, 2f.
Okay, save that, I'll just have
a little look at our logic here.
We've created delayInSeconds that
we can change in the inspector.
And when we call LoadGame over, we're
gonna start our coroutine WaitAndLoad.
WaitAndLoad is basically saying,
wait for a certain number of seconds and
then trigger the Game Over.
Let's see if that works, it should be
okay if we've hooked it up correctly.
Let's click on Play, as our game compiles.
Here we go, fly our plane.
[SOUND] Crash into Bernard,
now it's Roger.
Crash into Roger, two seconds later,
badoom, there we go, that is very cool.
Now, let's just check the game loop,
play again.
Make sure that there's nothing crazy
going on, make sure we've got no errors.
Two seconds, main menu, Start,
and it's all looking pretty good.
Okay, you have a whole
bunch of Bernards coming.
Holy, that's, holy bullets!
[LAUGH] Bullet holes.
Awesome, okay, our game's really
starting to come together, isn't it?
This is very neat.
So there we go, we've implemented
our delay when we die, and
our loading Game Over scene so
that our game has a full game loop.
Great work, and
I'll see you in the next video.