[SOUND] In this video,
we're gonna discuss why our sound effect
disappears when we destroy our object,
when we pick up our coin,
it destroys, and how we can create
a mechanism, where we still trigger and
play our sound effect even though
that game object is being destroyed.
So if you're following the Talvania
section through from the three day course,
where it originally was over there and
now it's over here,
then you'll be familiar with the technique
we're going to use in this video already.
So it will be a good refresher for
you but not necessarily and
you I didn't know that moment.
But otherwise, this is gonna
be a really cool technique for
those of you who are seeing this for
the first time.
So what we're gonna do is make sure
these coins, when we jump on them,
go diddling and don't get destroyed.
If we look at our current script,
if we'd have put something in here
that said something along the lines
of play sound effect in here, so playSFX,
if we wrote out the code for that.
Then what's gonna happen is, it will play
and then immediately this whole game
object will be destroyed, including the
thing that would play, that sound effect,
which would be on our coin would be some
sort of audio source, audio component.
So let's actually go ahead and
create our audio source on here now.
On our coin, we'll apply that
back to the prefab so that means,
now that we've got an audio source,
we have a mechanism to play a sound, but
we don't have a script that's
going to allow us to play it.
Now there's two options
that we can do here,
option number one is to create a separate
script, a separate class that's called
SFX with a public method that we can
call when a player touches the coin.
Now public method would look something
like public void PlayCoinSound,
and then what would PlayCoinSound be,
it would look for
myAudioSource that we would've
established up and now start method.
And to define what our audio source is,
we would find out component.
And then we would say
PlayOneShot (coinPickupSound).
So basically, it's saying play
the sound as we've done before.
However, if we do that,
as I've pointed out, right in the middle
of our script here, then we'll destroy it.
We could do a coroutine.
That is something that I didn't
put in here as an option, but
it's not a very good option.
If we do a coroutine in here that says
play the sound, and then after that
sound has played, now we come back, we
yield, and then we come back to destroy.
The problem is that our coin will stick
around while the sound is playing.
And it's nice when you jump on a coin,
you want it to disappear straight away,
you don't want to have to wait [NOISE] and
then the coin goes away.
That looks a bit sloppy.
So we could use a coroutine but
that doesn't work in this
particular instance, either.
What we are going to do is
PlayClipAtPoint, and like I was saying
before, we used this in our 3D course
in the Argonne Assault section,
where we looked at the fact that it
creates an audio instance Independent
of the game object which
spawned it the PlayClipAtPoint.
There is one down side of this approach,
in that it plays it at
the point that is spawned from.
So it'll play the audio just here,
right on the coin, in 3D space.
We have no choice,
it has to be used in 3D space.
And I'll give you a link against
this lecture to the Unity Docs
on PlayClipAtPoint.
But given that it's in 3D space and
our camera is, where's our camera that's
the end of it, it's up here,
that's the start of our camera.
There's gonna be this distance
form the camera to the coin.
So we need to make sure that we're
telling this method to play,
telling the sound to play
exactly where the camera is.
So let's hop in and
do that, it's pretty simple,
it's just one line in terms of
the actual playing of the sound effect,
but first, we'll get the sound
effect we're going to play.
So we'll serialize field at the top here,
SerializeField AudioClip,
and what should we call this,
coinPickUpSFX.
Okay, and I've given you a sound effect
that I've created in Audacity like most of
my sound effects that you can go and grab.
Let me just find that for you, and
I've named it SFX Coin Pickup.
We will drag that into,
we don't have an audio folder yet.
I'll just drag it into assets,
and then it's a good time for
us to create an audio folder in here.
Give myself a little bit more space,
right click, create Folder, audio,
and then we have our SFX Coin Pickup,
drag that into audio, great.
So we now have one of those and
if we see on here,
our coin pick up SFX, I'm gonna save that,
hop back into Unity here.
Click on my coin, apply that,
and find where the script is and
we have a coin pickup on SFX,
drag the coin pickup.
Did I not put that, this is my script.
My script is out of its spot,
there we go, put that into scripts.
A little bit of a tidy up as we go.
Okay, so click on the coin, drag the SFX
over into where the script is down below.
Okay, there's our script.
We'll drag it over in there.
Okay, so now we have defined that the SFX
Coin Pickup is this sound effect here.
Again, apply that back to the prefab.
Okay, now that we've got that set up
we do actually have a sound effect
that we can play.
The line we're going to use
in here is AudioSource,
with a capital A,
cuz this is the audio source of the scene.
And then we wanna use PlayClipAtPoint.
And then what we need to do in here, we
need to pass in and you can see here it's
looking for the audio clip we need to play
and we've got this up here, coinPickUp.
And then a vector 3 position, so
we'll say coin coinPickUpSFX,.
Now if we put in the position
of where this game object is,
just by saying transformed of position,
then it's gonna play it along while away
as I showed in the scene here, that the
camera is distant to where the coin is.
So we need to say play at
the point of the main camera.
And so this is a micro challenge for you.
I don't have a challenge slide in this
video but just a micro challenge for
you to figure out how to play this
at the position of the main camera.
So pause the video now and
just write in the main camera's position.
Okay, that was a micro challenge just
a quick challenge for this video so
this will be
camera.main.transform.position.
Okay, so we call in, and
then, after we do that,
after this PlayClipAtPoint has been
created, then we destroy this game object.
Let's go and see how well that worked.
Our coin should be all good in there,
it's all applied to the prefab.
And fire up the player, drop in the coin.
Don't know if you can hear the feedback
coming through from my speakers there, but
I am getting a sound effect
triggering when that happens.
So that's success, that is us having
the coin sound effect triggered, and
I'm gonna do it one more time, just so
you can see what's created over here.
It's good to get into the habit of
seeing what's created when these things
take place.
So I'll pause, and then you can see
under Coin, I wasn't quick enough.
Okay, this time I'll be quicker.
There we go, we've got this one shot
audio that's been created in there and
then when we unpause, it just disappears.
So it just does its thing goes away,
bump, there we go.
And that's the same principle
we can apply when a player dies,
when the enemy does something,
when the player finishes a level.
So you can use this mechanism all
throughout your game when you're adding
your sound effects.
Great work, well done and
I'll see you in the next video.