[MUSIC]
In this video,
we're gonna close our game loop by saying,
when the player runs over these coins,
the score goes up.
But if the player accidentally dies,
then those coins don't respond again.
They're gone,
until the point where we die enough times,
go all the way back to the start.
Hit the start button, and
then those coins come back again.
We're gonna do that by creating
a scene persist game object and
a scene persist script.
So let's jump in and get started.
I think with our current feature set,
this is the last real step to getting
our game having a complete game flow.
So what we'll do, starting off, is to,
in our hierarchy we're gonna right-click
and create an empty game object.
We'll call this scene persist,
ScenePersist.
So basically this is saying anything that
we want to have persist within the scene
will be fitting underneath
this game object.
I'm going to reset that transform.
And then drag that down into our Prefabs
folder down here to prefab that.
While I'm at it,
we haven't prefabed Level Exit nor
let's prefab that while we're here.
Anything you can prefab you should,
particularly when we're
got tons of levels.
We need to just be
dragging them into place.
We can't prefab our tilemap grid,
because it's different in every scene.
We can't do the same for
pick-ups for the same reason.
Okay, but we've got now ScenePersist.
What we're gonna do is add a component
to this which will be a script
we'll call ScenePersist.
You've got it, and we'll create that,
open up that script.
Okay, blank canvas here, actually first,
what I'm gonna do is
just explain my logic.
So, in ScenePersist,
we're gonna do the same as
same as GameSession where we have our
GameSession has a Singleton Pattern on it.
Destroy if there's already one existing,
don't destroy unload.
We need to do the same
with our ScenePersist.
And then underneath our ScenePersist,
we put anything that we want to have
survive when the player dies,
to remember that, when the player dies.
But when the player goes
on to the next level,
that's when we want to
reset that progress.
And we have a big bucket at
the moment which is Pick-ups,
which I'm gonna drag underneath there,
similar to within GameSession,
we dragged under our UI our hard
canvas under there our UI canvas.
We can do the same with Pick-ups.
We'll have a slightly different
set of rules for ScenePersist.
So my challenge to you is a big one.
But I think it's one that you've got
all the tools to accommodate, and
that is to create scene persistence.
So here are the steps, use a Singleton
Pattern for the class, very similar to
what we did for the GameSession.cs,
in fact, identical to what we did.
But changing out GameSession for
ScenePersist.
And then next step is to determine
the scene's build index at the start.
So if the index is 2, it's Level 2, for
example, then we want to know that.
Because in our last step,
we destroy the game object
if the scene's build index is not
the same as the starting index.
So we've got that code,
all these pieces of code we've created
already throughout the project.
So might be a little bit of grabbing
from here and grabbing from there.
But you should have everything you need.
Those are the steps to put
inside the script here,
inside our ScenePersist script.
So that we can have that attached to our
game object, our ScenePersist game object.
So that anything underneath that doesn't
get destroyed when the scene reloads.
Okay, so there's your challenge.
Give that your best shot, and
I'll see you back here when you
have given it that best shot.
Okay welcome back,
I hope you went well with that.
I hope you gave it a really big shot and
I hope you had some success.
Let's go through it together, so you can
see my working through this process.
In our ScenePersist script,
we need to do something on awake.
The very first thing that's gonna
be happening void Awake when our
script fires up is we need to type it in
correctly for a starting point, okay?
Is to start with an integer,
which is the number of the ScenePersist.
Now our ScenePersist = FindObjects,
remember we need that s in there.
That's one that can be one that can
be a little bit tricky ObjectsOfType.
And we need to find ScenePersist
is the object of type.
And then we need to get the length,
cuz we're looking for objects,
so it knows how many there are.
Length, and
then a simple if num of (numScenePersist
&gt; 1), then we need to do a thing.
What is the thing we need to do?
Well, we need to Destroy this
gameObject with a small g,
Destroy(gameObject); else.
What is the case if it's else?
Else we do our DontDestroyOnLoad, and
again we'll just tell it it's for
this gameObject, DontDestroyOnLoad.
Okay, the next thing we do,
part of our challenge,
determine the scenes
build index at the start.
Well, let's create ourselves
an integer which is startingSceneIndex.
So that we know what that is.
And then in our start method, we need
to say what's startingSceneIndex =.
What's this gonna be?
Well, we need to make sure,
first of all we're using the namespace,
so I'm back up at the start using
UnityEngine.SceneManagement.
So that we know about our SceneManagement.
Then back down here, startingSceneIndex =
SceneManager.GetActiveScene().buildIndex.
Okay, I think that looks good.
So now we have our startingSceneIndex.
Index is basically whatever
the buildIndex is for this scene.
And then now,
in our update, we can be checking to make
sure that we're still on that index.
So that was the last
step in this challenge.
Destroy if the scene's build index
is not the same as starting index.
So we need to know what
the current scene index is,
so we've got something to compare.
So we'll define that as a variable,
say currentSceneIndex
=
SceneManager.GetActiveScene().buildIndex.
Okay, so
now we know here's the startingSceneIndex,
here's the currentSceneIndex.
Let's do an if statement, if
(currentSceneIndex does not equal, so !=.
Does not equal startingSceneIndex.
So if they're not in alignment,
if the moons aren't in alignment,
then Destroy(gameObject).
Okay, so just very quickly on that,
we've created a singleton at the top here,
DontDestoryOnLoad, which said
what's the startingSceneIndex.
And then we've compared
the currentSceneIndex to
the startingSceneIndex.
And then, if they're not the same,
then we destroy.
Save that, back over into here,
back over into our scene.
Make sure that SceneIndex does have the
script underneath that will make sure all
the Pick-ups are sitting underneath
ScenePersist, click on Play.
Hopefully our score is accurate,
yes, 0 and 3.
Pick-up, and
when we pick things up, now if we die,
ah-ha, our coins are no longer there.
We've picked them up,
we can only pick them up once.
And then, when we get new coins,
it should be the same thing.
It remembers those coins,
this one is still left on the same blump.
And then the other thing to
make sure we do is when we die,
we start the game and they're all
back again where they should be.
So that's a really lovely
part of our core game loop.
The fact that we can play
the game properly as a player.
We feel good that the game remembers
the things that we've done.
We feel smart that it
knows what we've done.
We can go into the next level,
we can die, we keep our score,
we decrement our number of lives.
And then, when we start the whole thing
all over again, we start from scratch.
So it's a really great step here.
This is, I think,
a really natural point in our game loop,
though we've got all the core
functionality in, so really great work.
Give yourself a huge high five.
There's tons of customization and
variation and changing the way things look
on the screen, adding different aspects,
and bling, and bounces and particles.
There's lots more that we can do, but I
wanna really celebrate the fact that we've
got our core game loop in a way that's
allowed us to have some really clever
persistence in at the game level and
also in at the scene level.
So, great work, and
I'll see you in an upcoming video!