[MUSIC]
In this video we're implementing score for
our games so
that when we shoot enemies
our score goes up, up, up.
And then when we die we have that same
score presented on our game over screen.
So what I wanna do is start off
with a challenge in this video and
the challenge is to add
score to your game.
Killing enemies increases your score.
And I wanna give you a reminder of
what's required by showing you what
I've just gone and implemented.
I've come back in the future,
back to the future, back from the past.
Anyway, I've just recorded it, and
I'm recording the start of the video now.
I wanna show you what I've done so
that if you want some reminders
you know what's going on.
I've created a game session game object
out of the game session script of that.
Within the game session script
I'm doing a couple of things,
I'm creating a singleton pattern,
I'm creating a score variable and
then three public methods to GetScore,
to AddToScore and to ResetGame.
I'm showing you these very quickly,
I'm going to go through them
in super detail in a moment.
But I'm showing you if you wanna go and
do this challenge yourself,
I'm also creating a score display which is
getting the text component that our score.
So main canvas that our score text is
on as well as the game object of game
session To be out of called the public
method of getting the score.
And then we are updating on every frame,
the score by using the ToString method.
Finally, when we kill an enemy, we need
to have a score value and when we die,
when the enemy dies, we are calling
the AddToScore and passing in scoreValue.
So that's just a really quick rundown,
if you wanted to go and
do this as a challenge yourself and
have some reminders and pointers,
that is the challenge.
So jump in, take on that challenge now,
give it your best shot.
And I'll see you here when you're done,
we'll go through it together in detail.
Okay, let's get shifty.
First thing I'm gonna do is free up
a little bit of space in my hierarchy,
right click Create Empty.
I'm gonna call this Game Elements, and I'm
just gonna shove anything in here that I
don't need have a look
at reset that transform.
So I'm gonna grab the background star
field, star field, shredder shredder.
Drop those into the game elements,
the path and the other path,
drop those in there.
That's pretty good, and
then just close up game elements,
drag it up to the very top so
it's tucked neatly out of the way.
Excellent, next I'm gonna right click and
Create Empty, create a game session.
Game session, game object.
Within the Game Session game object,
we're going to create ourselves a script.
Which I will click on my script folder,
right click, click C# script.
I'm gonna call this,
you guessed it, GameSession.
Okay, and
then drag the GameSession script onto,
when it finishes figuring out that
it's alive, okay you are alive,
great, the game session,
script under the Game Session game object.
And then while we're here for
due diligence,
drag the Game Session game object into our
prefers folder so it is now prefer core.
You might have noticed that my assets
folder here has changed a little bit.
I've just gone and drag my slider
from folders down in to lists,
because that's making it a little bit
neater and tidier to see what's going on.
Okay, we're going to need one
more script in this video.
So script folder,
right click, create c sharp.
I'm gonna call this particular
script ScoreDisplay so
that we can be displaying our score.
So this is our script building block.
So next stop I'm gonna add my
score UI element to the screen.
So find the game canvas,
right click create a UI text.
Now, we could do TextMeshPro-Text we
could do text we tend to do a lot
of TextMeshPro,
cuz I think it gives us a little bit
more control looks a little bit crisper.
But in this video I'm gonna be doing score
using just tick so that we've done the way
so you can see it is wanting to
do text you know how to do text.
So were covering a few different bases,
but in general you'd probably
just do one or the other.
Okay our text we'll rename
to be score text and
then let's see click,
if you click on your game canvas,
that'll zoom you can see
score text on your screen.
So right size is tiny at the moment.
So let's click on Score Text,
change our font to 100.
Change the color to be, for now,
white until I have a better idea.
Change from the New Text in the text field
to 000000, that's kind of six 0s I think.
And then w, whoops, not a w there!
Click on Score Text.
W tall move it roughly up to
the top right of my screen.
I need to zoom in a little bit.
I'm gonna click on my T-tool.
And make it bigger so
we can actually see it.
There it goes, it pops into existence,
make it nice and large.
Right click or right align and
I like to center line things.
Now, change the font so font, select that,
whatever you've selected for your game,
I've got batman FA just here,
looks pretty crisp over there,
I like it gonna move it up just
a little bit more and very important,
click on the anchor and
then right click on the anchor.
So no matter whatever screen resolution
and aspect ratio we have our score,
we anchored up to the top
right of your screen.
Okay, now we have score,
it called Score Text, perfect,
that all looking pretty good.
Our script we just made,
which was the ScoreDisplay.
We're gonna drag that over onto score.
Excellent, or you can add component and
search for it, either of those ways.
Now we have our score
display on our score.
Our last thing we're gonna do is change
the color just to make it a little bit
more of a bright blue spacey, fluorescent
kind of, there we go, wonderful.
Okay, so I've got score,
I've got my scripts,
we're ready to jump into the scripts.
Find our game session, double click on
that, open it up, jump into Visual Studio.
First thing I need to do is
create a notion of score.
So score a little s, score initialize
that 0; so you have your score.
Next, I'm gonna implement a singleton, so
that our game session there is only one of
them and we can reuse our score in our
game overscreen because it's a singleton.
So I'm gonna create Awake, so
it's the very very first thing it does
when it wakes up it will
SetUpSingleton(); as a method,
right click on SetUpSingleton quick
actions and refactors generate method or
you can just type it out
yourself if you like typing.
And then, I'm gonna delete
the default line that's in there.
What do we need to do?
Well, we need the integer, which is how
many game sessions we have already.
So int numberGameSessions and
what does that equal?
Well, we need to find how
many sessions there are.
So I say FindObjectsOfType and again,
I'm gonna do the s a few different times.
So you're like, there's an s in there,
don't forget that.
That's the most common thing,
if this line of code's not going well,
it's cuz we've forgotten the s.
It's game objects of type.
We're looking for GameSession().
How do we know how long it is?
Well, we type in length, okay?
Now we need to do our if, so
if (numberGameSessions &gt; 1) curly
brace space we will Destroy(gameObject);
else DontDestroyOnLoad(gameObject);.
Save that looking good except we
don't have our colored braces.
Being a little bit hasty here,
curly braces that wrap around our
code block of DontdestroyOnLoad.
Okay, that's looking pretty good,
we've got our single term
we're running it on Awake.
We're calling it on Awake.
Next up we want to add three public
methods that we can call from
other scripts or other areas and
we get rid of start, don't need that,
also don't need update so clear those out.
Public method number one is gonna be for
getting the score, so
public int GetScore().
Why is it an int I ask you?
It's an int because we have to return
a value, and that value is score, and
the score is an int, so whenever we call
that it will return score which is an int.
Next public method, public,
this will be void, there's no return type.
We'll call this AddToScore, this is
where another class or another moment in
our game can say, hey, game session,
please add something to the score.
What's the something?
Well we need to know how many
points to add to the score.
This is where we'll have a requirement
in here, we'll have a parameter.
Which we will make it an int,
and we'll look for a score value.
So if you want to call AddToScore,
you need to tell me the score
value that I'm adding.
And then within our method, within our
code block here we take out current score
+=, what's it gonna plus equals?
It's gonna plus equal ScoreValue, so
it is taking our current score and
then adding to it,
where the scoreValue is that was passed to
us by the thing that called add to score.
We will make one more
Public Method while we are here.
Public V=void ResetGame() and then {.
What are we doing here?
Well this is just simply destroying
this game session objects.
So, Destroy(gameObject);.
Okay, so there's game session all created,
looking pretty good,
no functionality we can see in the game
just yet but that is pretty tight.
Next up we need to find our score text and
specifically our score display.
So we've already opened that I believe,
score display here we go just nice and
empty.
We're working in UI so
we want to start off by
adding a namespace using UnityEngine.UI.
And remember if you are using TextMeshPro
instead of just the text component,
you'll need to add the TextMesh Pro
namespace in here or
else things won't go as
you're expecting them.
Now, what do we need to
do in our score display?
First of all, we need to get the component
where we want to display the score.
So if you have a look on your text,
score text,
we have the text component just in here.
So we need to get this, and
then within that we have the text field.
So there's a lot of texts, I know we've
dealt with this in previous sections,
text.text.text it feels like there's 70
text, but this is the text component and
this is the text value of the text
field that is within that.
So to get access to that text component we
start off by creating ourselves a variable
to store that in which will be a text
type variable called scoreText;.
And in the scoreText;.
And then when we start our game,
we need to give scoreText a value,
which is going to be the component.
So GetComponent&lt;Text&gt;();.
Okay, so get the component text
stored as this scoreText variable,
which we've declared as a type of text,
excellent.
Next, we need to do similar for
finding where the score is coming from and
we know the score is going to
be stored in game session.
So let's create a type GameSession.
We'll call this gameSession
with a small g, semi-colon.
Now also on the start when our
score display comes into existence,
we need to go and find the game session.
So we need to define gameSession that
we've just created as a variable as, well,
we need to define it as
this gameSession class.
So that's a type, we need to
FindObjectOfType &lt;GameSession&gt;();.
So we've gone and got ourselves
a reference to the component,
and we've gone and got ourselves
a reference to the GameSession.
Now on update, all we need to do is to say
scoreText.text=gameSession.
What's our method that we've created
in game session, we're looking for
get score because we need to know
the score so gamesession.GetScore().
And then we need to be converting
this into a string because we
have an integer at the moment.
The score itself is a integer and
our text field is a string.
So to convert out integer into
a string we say ToString();.
Sets are looking pretty good,
let's jump over to Unity,
see if we've got any sort of
different behavior going on.
We should have, yes, it goes from allow
placeholder zeros to just one zero.
And then no score going up,
but so far, so good.
Okay, so how do we make our score go up?
Where is it happening that
our score should go up?
Well, at the moment, we've only
got enemies in our game, that's,
we shoot them, we get points.
So let's go on find out enemy script,
without enemy script we need to start off
by creating a concept that
the enemies give us points.
And I've been putting this off for
awhile but I can't put it off any longer.
Let's tidy up our variables so
it's tidy in our inspector and
tidy in our script cause this
is a big old blob of stuff.
So I'm gonna create a [Header("")].
What are we gonna say in here.
Well, first up we've got enemy stats,
this looks like.
We've got some enemy stats.
I'm gonna go and
create a new enemy stat which will be
SerializeField of integer type
that I will call scoreValue.
That'll be the scoreValue of
this particular enemy, and
that will equal 150;.
Cool, next up, let's see,
copy my header code and then paste
that above the next blob of code this blob
of code is all about shooting, I believe.
Shooting, we have counter shot projectile,
projectile.
Okay, after my last projectile,
a couple of spaces.
Paste in our header again.
What are these all about?
This is all about sound effects.
Sound effects.
Okay, so much tardier.
I'm much happier with that.
Now, we've created score value.
Let's go and find where we
will make our score increase.
I think when the enemy dies,
that's a good place to increase the score.
So what are we doing here?
Let's just go remind ourselves
over in game session,
we've got our AddToScore method.
How do we call add to score
method from another script?
Well, we say FindObjectOfType,
we're looking for the GameSession().
This is what we call our AddToScore();.
Semi-colon is not working because,
can you guess why not?
Because we need to give it a value.
A reminder,
over here we need the value of scoreValue,
you need to tell it how many points you're
worth, you can't just let it guess.
So in here, it's gonna be nice and simple.
We have our scoreValue and
we've named it the same, clever us.
ScoreValue, so back down into AddToScore.
Score value blank.
Okay, let's save all that up.
I think we have implemented everything.
Click on play.
What's gonna go on here?
We will from zero [INAUDIBLE].
Okay, score's going up 300, 600.
Excellent, success.
But when we die we get a moment
to look at the score but
there's no real moment on here where I can
look at the score, call my friend over.
Hey, look, I beat your score,
whatever it might be,
so let's have the score
display on the screen as well.
And we've set ourselves up with our
game session is a singleton, so
it will continue.
It will exist and
live into the next screen,
which is very important, the next scene.
So I've prefabbed that good stuff.
The game canvas, here's a little thing.
I wasn't planning on doing this, but
just spur of the moment, I think I will.
See how we currently have
our game canvas prefab, and
there's only one element
here the score text.
So I'll click on apply, so
now our game canvas and
score text have been updated
in terms of the prefab.
So if we say all this up, jump over
into [SOUND] where are we, the scene.
Game Over scene.
If I find my prefab and
drag the Game Canvas
into this scene, it adds it in there.
We can have multiple canvases,
you can have a whole ton of
canvases doing different things.
That's something that we haven't
talked about much because we've
been putting everything under
the one particular canvas but
you could turn our particular
canvas on and off.
You can move the canvases around.
So this game canvas, I'm gonna change
the position of it, of the score text.
I'm gonna change the score text position
to be, let's see in the middle just there.
So the score goes form
being up in the top right,
when it's game over you get the score
right in the middle of the screen.
Do a couple of things in here,
I will just drag it to the right, and
drag it to the left so.
And then center align so
I know it's right in the middle.
And then we need to
change the anchor point,
rather than the anchor point
being up in the top right.
That's gonna be a little bit messy
if our resolution or our pixel,
aspect ratio changes.
Let's anchor this right into
the very middle of our screen.
Okay, there might be a little bit
of tidy up of anchoring our other
elements in the scene.
I'm not gonna go through that.
You know how to do that now in terms
of anchoring things into a particular
position if the aspect ratio is changing,
but this is all looking pretty cool for
now.
We're getting an error down the bottom,
assertion failed.
I think that might have just been
cuz I was playing around and
moving things around.
We'll clear it and we'll see if it
comes up again and then we'll go and
dive in and
see what needs to happen to fix it.
But let's go back to start, we'll go
back to the very start of our game,
very start start, click on START menu.
Okay, so click on START, and then sorry,
click on Play, and then START.
We will [SOUND] start our start.
Okay, score is going up,
excellent, we crash into someone.
[SOUND] 1050.
Is 1050 retained?
Yes, it is, all the way here.
What happens when we play again,
goes to zero, and, okay, so
our score's not going up.
Why is that?
I suspect because we are not properly
resetting our level loading.
So let's have a look at
our gamesession in here.
We've created ResetGame,
which was clever of us, but
we're not actually calling it any way.
Where would we reset our game?
I think that's gonna be in level,
isn't it?
When the player says load the game,
so load the game scene,
that's where we need to reset.
So once again, how do we find
this particular public method?
We will say FindObjectOfType and
it is type GameSession() and
we're calling ResetGame();.
Okay, resetting game, so save this.
I'll jump back over into Unity,
click on play.
See what we can do with
the full loop now if we can,
then we'll declare this success.
Click on start, shoot, shoot, shoot.
Get some points, shoot, shoot, die.
600 should be retained in here,
you can put an extra
text run here saying you scored or
your score is 600, if you like.
Back to main menu,
click on Start, start at 0,
scores goes up and
then [SOUND] back into Game Over.
One more thing we need to try play again.
Yeah, and the score does go up.
Okay, just a quick side note here,
I had a couple of errors on my screen
here, I just went and cleared them,
played the game through a couple of time
and the errors don't come back again.
So I forgot to mention that
before I pause the video,
but I've cleared out all the errors
just in case you're wondering.
So great work in this lecture,
great work with your progress.
Pretty excited to see score in our game.
We can implement it in so
many more places now.
We can have it when you shoot an enemy,
the enemy spawns a whole bunch of
little coins that you go pick up.
Like little pickups for points.
It could be that you just
have super mega point
things floating down your
screen that you can pick up.
Lots of places you can do it above and
beyond I just shoot an enemy and
I get points.
So great work with this lecture,
great work with your progress, and
I'll see you in the next video.