Here.
Hello again in this video we're going to do three main things we're going to tidy up our blogs.
We're going to protect our souls from issues where we might have.
The array not having any element in it.
And we're also going to have a smarter way of calculating Max hits so that we don't have to enter manually
Max hits and then also the number of spri to potentially have a mismatch there which I've done myself
a couple of times.
So step one in this process I don't know about you but I get annoyed every time I need to double click
on my block or triple click because my game canvas is getting in the way.
So this is the UI our big old UI up here.
It's getting in the way when they're clicking so I'm going to do what I've done in previous videos which
is jump up to the top to layer's up in the top right and click on the little eyes symbol next to you
I'd turn that off and that way it means that we won't see that as we're never getting our way around
our world.
Let's just jump in nice and close.
So it shouldnt getting away.
So when I click on a block and then click on another block it clicks straight on them are so much better.
Apologies if you've been noting that as I've been trying to click on blocks and you've been yelling
at the screen why don't you just turn off your UI or go to the next thing I know is remove all of my
blocks because buried somewhere in there is some dodgy logic and I've just been using it for prototyping
and play testing and I've just been messing around with it.
Sorry I think we're getting our array out of index issue because something we've done in there is incorrect
and broken so I'm going to delete it all and start from scratch with our new found awesomeness.
To do this I'm going to drop in.
Let's see my big three hit break will block why I dropped that in there.
I'm going to change the instant So it is twice now say four times as big so on scale.
I'm going to change it to four and four and four.
There we go.
There's the Whopper.
There's the mother.
Mother Ship of blocks and we can see who's got Max it's a three and multiple broken States may or may
not look amazing you can see that everything's been scaled up so it's not amazing amazing but from a
gameplay point of view I think it's going to be pretty decent.
Next up I'm going to drop in a couple of unbreakable blocks to make sure that they still work so 1 and
then duplicate to duplicate three duplicate four just so I can't bounce straight up towards the big
block and then I'll drop in some of these to hit wonders over the side one and then duplicate to duplicate
three.
Just check my max hits on this for some reasons.
Back down to zero-sum going to click on the prefab change to the max hits up to let's see this is the
two hits.
I will change it to 2 and that should change my instances.
Yes it does.
OK and then I am going to highlight all of these duplicate.
Move them over to the right hand side just so difficult is symmetry.
There we go.
There's my little nothing amazing but not too terrible and you can see I've got a mess in my hierarchy
so it's clean that up grab all the blocks put this underneath my blog's game object.
Grab the ones I have at the top do the same under blocks and then close up blocks.
Looks good.
Okay now I've got a working level that when I play my game it should not be giving me any errors and
it should be playing nice as while our case looks a little bit dumb.
Having that quite so big I'd need to change up the assets that I use.
If I want to have mega big blocks but no errors.
Game play is called nice big block to I aim for.
You could even have this as 10 states.
Sorry 10 levels of breakage.
OK cool now.
Next up what I want to do is open up my scripts open up.
BLOCK dotsie s within here.
I want to just protect against a situation where we can get an array not knowing what's going on and
having a little bit of a complain.
Add us in a way that doesn't make sense.
I make it very obvious so you can see we've got it Sprite index segal's times more times it minus one
and then we're getting the component and we're changing the Sprite renderer based upon our array.
So just to protect our self here underneath int Sprite index.
Then add a new line and say if.
What I want to say in here is if the Sprite index E is not null.
So in other words if it's valid then continue on.
Otherwise give us a particular error.
So I'll say if hit sprite's and then out a ray is going to be Sprite index index so if if that is where
our Sprite index is exclamation mark.
Equals.
That means not null is not null valid.
What have I done wrong here.
I have missed any apologies for the Sprite index.
Then let's wrap in our curly braces.
How get component changing up the Sprite in renderer.
There we go.
Else so.
Otherwise else we are saying what did one do.
Here to give us a warning so debug dot.
Log error to make it very clear that's going to show an error.
The red exclamation mark stop sign thing will say block Sprite is missing from a ray that should protect
us and make it really clear what's going on.
To put a couple of these things in so just to be clear we could be fine without this.
But this is the sort of check and balance you want to put into your code so you don't find yourself
in a position where you make a little bit of a tweak a little bit of a mistake and you're completely
confused about what's going on.
So we'll see if we can test this just by forcing a bad scenario.
Fine.
This is right just here it lets me click on at once I'm finished compiling.
Click on that and will say size of.
Or 3.
Just to change it up a little bit and then I'm going to slide all these to none.
None.
This is something that could possibly have happened that we forgot to put our sprite's in there click
play and we'll see what happens when we hit this block over on the right hand side here.
Boik nothing happens because of it.
The wink.
Because it's got multiple levels and we didn't see any affordance of the fact there is getting damage.
But when we look in our console block Sprite is missing from a ray.
Okay.
And then for bonus points he's a little challenge for you.
We'll see if we can do this.
I thought about this but it just popped into my head just now.
Also logout block Sprite is missing from Ouray and then logout.
Which particular game object is the problem.
So pause a video and see if you can do that now too.
In this era we're logging out.
Also add the name of the game object.
OK.
So I'm going to say.
Plus and then we will type in game object dot name.
Should be as simple as that.
Save Beco into unity.
Clear that.
Now when we hit that one game object the one block over in the top right there.
It should tell us the comply.
It should tell us the name of that particular game objects are and go look for it and then pause says.
Box is missing from a race to hit breakable 5 so.
It's from the array.
Great.
And then to hit breakable 5.
This one just here is missing so that's a really good way of adding some code.
So you can find exactly what's going on to help you with your debugging and help you with finding any
issues.
Trust me there will be issues because that's the name of the game having bugs is part of the fun of
making video games.
Right now the other thing I wanted to do in this video was to be a little bit cleverer with how we're
calculating our Max he.
And you can see at the moment where are we on one of our clocks.
You can see Max it's has two.
And the number of hits Brites we've got is three.
So it's actually bigger than the max.
So there's a lot of manual process in here.
What we know is how many hits brides we've got because we want to have a hit Sprite even if it's the
same visual representation if we've got three elements in there then we want to.
We know that the number of Max hits is going to be four because that's our logic.
We have the very first Sprite which is our non Braken non broken sprite.
And then we have varying degrees of breakage after that.
So we can hook that up in code and just get away with this idea of us manually putting in Max hits and
also to bulletproofing ourselves a little bit more in case we make any mistakes as I had done just there.
So what we have at the top is Max hits that we've serialized going to for now remove these and instead
we're going to put Max hits down in our code in here where we're first doing our Max its comparison.
So many times hit.
Plus Plus let's add it Max hits.
And what's this going to equal.
Well the max hits is going to equal something to do with the size of our ray.
So say he sprite's This is our Ray.
It's bright dot Layng.
That's going to be the length of our ray.
And then we know that it's going to be one be higher because our race starts at zero so there's only
one in free in our array it's going to be zero.
So NDA plus 1 to get the number of maximum hits so maximum hits is the length of our array plus one
from back over into unity will see that Max hits should disappear once it's compiled papa comp. Okay
megacities disappeared size is 3.
Let me just remove this block because that was one of the ones that we were using to test duplicate
the block above it.
Now it should be a good old fashioned size of one so that should take two hits to destroy.
We are CONSOL.
And play the game over on the right who play the game once.
Yes that's right America just right now if it gets destroyed.
If I can hit it there we go.
It gets destroyed.
OK.
So we're dynamically through our code figuring out how many levels of damage our sprite's should have
how block should have.
My calculating that I don't know about you but I find it difficult to talk and play the game at the
same time and so terrible on my game because I'm never concentrating on it.
That does really fundo play I'm quite enjoying it.
And there's a ton of level design variety that we can implement now that we've got our unbreakable blocks
and we've got bigger blocks and we've got multiple levels of damage on the blocks and in some upcoming
videos we'll talk a little bit more about a couple of game design philosophies or approaches you can
take and then take a little bit of a moment to make a bit more of a game and flex your muscles in terms
of tuning of your game.
But for now we've tidied up a couple of things we've created some cleverer logic we've given ourselves
protection against errors.
We're in a good place.
I will see you in the next video.