[MUSIC]
Hey hey, welcome again.
Here we have health up in
our top left of the screen.
We're displaying it when we take
a bullet hit, blonk goes to 100,
then blonk again goes to 0, we die.
Back to play again and returns to
200 when we start our game again.
So, let's jump in and display our health.
Hokie dokie, let's get started.
And what I'm gonna do is start off with
the framework of what we're doing and
a challenge which is to Display Health.
Because it's so
similar to displaying score,
I think I've got a lot of confidence
in you that you can nail it.
So first of all,
I'd like you to create HealthDisplay.cs.
And a sneaky hint,
this is is sneaky hint number one,
it's very similar to ScoreDisplay.cs.
Then create Health text within our canvas,
and
sneaky hint #2 its very
similar to the score text.
And we only need to be displaying health
from the game not in the game over
the screen.
Cuz I think it's pretty obvious what your
health is when you are at game over.
Need to create a health method and
sneaky hint number #3,
it's very similar to GetScore().
So GetHealth() and
GetScore() are very similar.
And then finally to Call GetHealth() and
convert that to a string.
And finally, well now I think sneaky hint
is you get the picture by now that it's
very similar to score.
So jump in, implement your health,
have it displaying in the game screen,
decreasing when you get hit, and
I will see you when you're done.
Okay where should we start?
I'm gonna click on my gain canvas.
I've got my score text so I'll duplicate
that, to make some health text.
Health text, great.
And then instead of a score display
script I'll remove that component, we
need to add a let's say, Health Display,
so jump over into my script's folder,
right-click, create, C sharp script
which I shall call Health Display.
Excellent, now when I
clicked on my Health text,
I can add component or
drag on over health display.
Excellent, so health display, all good.
Now we gotta reposition health text,
so click on health text, hit W.
Move move move move.
Looks pretty good.
Okay, and change the color from
blue to it was all yellow.
Okay, looks pretty sharp.
And I can see that I've got
six placeholder zero's but
only five of them displaying, which shows
me that my font's a little bit too big.
Change that to 80, left align.
And then click on my anchor point,
left align on my anchor point, top left.
That looks pretty sharp, I think.
And then my score I'm also gonna
change that font size down to 80.
There we go, lots of room for millions.
Well maybe not millions, but hundreds
of thousands of scores and healths.
I will apply all this back to the prefab,
but
at the moment I've got this game
canvas prefab to my game over scene.
So what I'll do first I'll save this up,
jump over into game over,
get all this UI stuff done first.
And in here, I've got my start menu,
game canvas.
So I don't want my changes to my
other game canvas to change this.
This is really the game over score
displaying canvas, it's not a game canvas.
So I'm gonna click on game canvas, go to
game object, and break prefab instance.
And instead of Game Canvas,
I'm going to call this Score Canvas
just to show that that's what it is.
We don't really need to prefab it
bu,t it's good to prefab everything
just in case.
So now we have a Score Canvas.
On our game over scene that shouldn't
be broken by any of the changes.
I'm gonna save the changes we
do over on our game scene.
So over here now we've
got our Game Canvas.
That is yes, so that's relevant.
Apply all that back now, this is prefab.
So if you've got multiple levels this
should work for those multiple levels.
Okay, so let's go have a look
at our script, where are we?
Health Display, open up Health Display.
Okay, nothing in there, I mention it's
very similar to Score Display, so
I'm gonna go get Score Display.
Might end up a little more
work changing all the words,
copy that over to Health Display,
but it's a good starting place.
Delete and then paste all this in.
So good one.
Instead of scoreText we
need to have healthText.
I'm not doing a rename all
just in case that goes and
renames things in other scripts for me.
I'm gonna just manually rename it in here,
gameSession.
Well, let's finish this.
Let's finish this healthText here as well.
So all of the scoreTexts
should be healthTexts.
Okay, they're all updated,
now Text has a squiggly underline,
which means that we're
not using the namespace.
So using UnityEngine.UI namespace there,
the squiggly lines go away, excellent.
So that healthText part should be done and
dusted now.
GameSession that's not where we're getting
the health from, the health currently
should be with the player cuz the player
has a concept of I'm taking damage,
here is where my health is at the moment.
So let's see,
yep there is a health variable already,
let's find a good spot to be
putting our get health method.
I think it's gonna be underneath Die,
so all of this health-related stuff,
then down here we'll, underneath
the Die method we'll create a public,
we need to return something we
need to be returning and int.
And we'll call this GetHealth,
parentheses,
curly braces,
what we will return we will return health.
And semicolon, save that up.
It looks pretty good, back over to health
display, now we've got our game session.
Instead of game session we
need to change this to player.
So type player and
variable we'll call player.
And then again instead of game
session it's called player.
Fun objective type this
will be the player.
And gameSession this will be player,
oops player small p, okay.
And we can set it up this way cuz at the
moment we've only got one level you might
need to do singleton on the player
if you have multiple levels.
But for us, we've just got the one
game level so this works okay.
We're gonna say get health,
under our updates, so
every frame we're updating the health text
with the player's get health value and
we're converting that into a string.
So let's save that up we'll check
that we've done everything that we
need to in here, click on Play.
The Health should be at 200 at the moment
if we've set things up correctly.
Yes, 200, score goes up great when I die.
It goes to 0, excellent, Game Over screen.
We've still got our score
display where we want it to.
Play Again Back to 200.
It's all looking pretty hunky dory.
Excellent, so we now have health,
we have score, we have a full game loop.
We can play the whole way through, we
can die, we can have laughs, we can cry,
all that good stuff.
So great work and
I'll see you in the next lecture.