[MUSIC]
In this video we're gonna setup our
input so that when the player hits up,
we print out a message that say, up arrow
is pressed, when hit down, it says,
down arrow.
When I hit Enter, it says, you hit Enter.
Let's jump in and get started.
First thing is first,
I'm gonna fix a bit of a boo boo that
I made a couple of videos ago,
I wrote Pick an number.
Crazy, you guys have been
yelling at me and saying,
that's not how you speak the English,
Rick.
So apologies for that.
Okay, so now onto what we're doing, which
is creating some input for the player.
And we need to give the player
one more step of instructions, so
let's create a new line here.
Debug.Log and then, again, (" ").
In here we want to say
something a long the lines of,
Tell me if your number is higher or
lower than my guess.
And at the moment,
we don't have the guess in there.
The first guess,
as we've said before, we have 500.
So let's break that in lower or
higher than 500, and you are brain at
this point should be saying hang on
a minute we could make that variable.
Which we absolutely will in some upcoming
videos when we get to the point where
we're calculating the guess.
But for now, we'll just bake that in there
and say, is it higher or lower than 500?
That'll be our first guess.
And then we need another line, Debug.Log,
to tell the player how
to give their input.
Debug.Log(" "),
it will be something along the lines,
so Push Up = higher, and
then we will say, Push Down = lower.
And the last one we need is,
what do we need here?
So return or enter, we'll say enter
cuz most keyboards have enter.
This is something we'll encounter
in this video that Return and
Enter are a little be synonymous,
and interchangeable.
We will say, Enter, so
Push Enter = Correct.
And again I've done some
capitalization mistakes in here.
We'll just make this capital L,
doesn't matter at all.
Just being a little pedantic,
and on the end a semi colon.
So there we go, added two more lines just
to give the player some instructions.
And our next process to say,
okay, we need some input and
we need to be able to display
what the player has pushed.
So I want to show you a couple of things.
First of all, I want to tell you our
mission, Ben and I, we have a mission for
you which is, wait, wait,
hang on sorry, wrong slide.
Okay, our mission for you is, to train
you to be an expert at solving problems.
That's what we're up to.
It's more than just, hey, follow what
we're doing and you'll kind of pick it up.
That's part of what we're doing, but
we really want you to think
the way we're thinking.
So in this video I'm going to show you a
little bit of the thought process that you
could go through to solve a problem.
And we'll be practicing it over, and
over, and over through out the course.
So by the end of the course you're
an absolute ninja in solving problems.
That's our objective here.
So what is our current problem?
What we're trying to do is,
if the player pushes a certain key,
we want to display a certain message.
And as we go throughout this section,
we'll add a little bit
more complexity to it.
But that's the foundation of it, and
that's a foundation of many games.
If you want your player to jump,
you push a button.
If you want your player to shoot,
you push a button or a key.
So that's what we're trying to do.
Specifically, push the up arrow,
we want to say, You pushed up.
The down arrow, You pushed down.
And Enter to say Correct,
to print that to the player.
So that's our current problem.
And depending upon your knowledge or
your skill,
you might already have some pieces
of information to solve the problem.
So for example, what we know already
is this has got to do with input.
We're looking for
some sort of input for the player.
So what we need to do is to take
that little bit of knowledge and
then expand on it to find
the right syntax, the right code,
the right methods to have
this work within our game.
And the place that I'm going to point you
to, now you don't need to understand all
of this yet, the place I'm going to
point you to is, unities documents, and
these are incredibly useful for
solving all sorts of things.
So open up a new browser window and
type in here unity docs, and then,
you can see I've already search for
it before.
Player input is what I'm searching for
at the moment.
I wanna know what the docs
say about player input.
See up at the very top,
Unity-Scripting API,
that's usually what we're looking for.
And it says Input, great,
we'll click on that.
And then, I'll also give you a link
to this in the resources, but
what we're doing here is,
we're training our problem solving.
So I don't want you to just be,
click the link I give you.
I want you to actually be searching for
it and finding it, and
going through this process.
Now within the docs, there'll be a lot
of stuff that I don't expect you
to understand or recognize at the moment.
But as you go through this course,
things will jump out, and
you'll be able to find what you're
looking for a lot more clearly.
So within here, within this input,
I'm looking for, under Methods,
I'm looking for
something that resembles pushing a key, or
pushing a key on the keyboard,
and I see GetKeyDown.
Ha, that's what we're looking for,
if I click on that.
We see Input.GetKeyDown has to
do with our returns true during
the frame the user starts pressing
down the key identified by name.
We'll talk about frame in this video
as well, to do with Start and Update.
And so we need a particular
key identified by name.
The first one we're looking for
in here is going to be the Up key.
So, if we have a look for
up key, if we scroll down,
within here we can find something
that represents the KeyCode.
This is gonna be a whole bunch of
the types of keys that we can choose.
So I click on KeyCode,
that's the particular code for
the key we're clicking on.
So we've got all these
different properties down here.
It can be the letters of the alphabet.
It can be, different keys on the keyboard.
What I'm looking for is some sort of
up arrow, and just there, upArrow.
So if I click on upArrow, it's gonna
take me through to the specific code,
the specific syntax I'm looking for.
And here we go, so you can see,
in the Update method, that's a great clue,
we need to put these in Update.
It detects when the key, up arrow,
the up arrow key is pressed.
And then we have our code here,
and I'm gonna copy that code.
So highlight it and copy it, and
take it over into Visual Studio.
So if you've just been surfing along and
watching at this point,
this is a great time.
If you need to pause the video and
find the link, and
go to this particular reference,
it's great for you to copy this yourself.
So that you're going through this motion.
So copy that piece of code back
over into our Visual Studio.
I'm gonna paste that under Update, and
you can see if input.GetKeyDown
KeyCode.UpArrow.
That might all seem like a little bit
gibberish for now, but we'll explain it
more, as we go through this section,
you'll understand this better and better.
But basically, what this is saying is,
if something is true, and
the something in this case is, we wanna
know if someone pushed a key down and
was that key the Up Arrow.
And if that's the case,
then write something to the console
Up arrow key was pressed, fantastic.
Now we can leave this as this, but I wanna
leave you with one a little bit of best
practice in here, and that's something
to do with our curly brackets.
So you can see curly brackets,
like these ones here on Update,
these ones here on Start,
whenever we see curly brackets,
that means there is a code block
in between those curly brackets.
And all those aspects of the code block
are statements that are executed one after
another when that code block is executed.
If we have this if statement,
it's saying if this thing is true,
then do these things in here.
If there's only one,
you don't need the curly brackets, but
it's good habit to add the curly
brackets in here, one before, and
then we'll go down to
the end of Debug.Log.
And Enter, and put another one at the end.
Visual Studio knows
where it should line up,
so that if in the future we wanna put in
another statement, and another statement,
and another statement, probably
not go with gobbly gook like that.
Then it will Execute them all together and
it won't be confused.
If we don't have these curly brackets for
our code block, then it can cause
some issues and some errors.
And there's a good chance we'll
forget to put them in, and
we won't know what is going on.
So you can see them here.
And just a little note,
while I'm in this conversation,
I promise you we'll get to Start and
Update in just a moment.
You can see that I've got my open
curly brackets on a new line and
my closed curly brackets
on a new line as well.
That is a total preference thing.
So you could have it,
it's totally valid to have this
on the previous line like that.
And you could also have this curly
bracket down there on the end.
It's not the white space that matters,
so it's not the number of enters.
It's not the number of spaces and
tabs that matters to Visual Studio.
All that matters is the order
that it finds it in.
So after it has this particular,
is this thing true?
We want a curly bracket, and
then it's gonna do all the things that's
in between these two curly brackets.
But from our readability point of view,
which is huge,
it's really important that
we can read our code.
We wanna have that on a new line,
and that on a new line, so
that we can see this is what
is going to be executed.
That's my particular preference,
has been particular preference.
Yours might be different its totally fine,
different people.
It's like, some people like red,
and some people like blue,
but that's the particular
way that we do things.
Now you might have a look at Update and
Start, and see that they're in a different
spot, that's because our template for
this script is being setup that way.
That's fine, I'm not going to dig into
changing the template just at the moment.
But if you want to be super pedantic,
you might say,
well let's just pop that down there, and
in our Start method we'll pop this curly
bracket down on a new line as well,
both of them are correct.
But we find this a little
bit more readable.
Okay, so that's about curly brackets,
that's about getting our
input into the system here.
Let's push out, let's save this,
and we'll see if that works,
then we'll come back and
talk about start and update.
So save that over into Unity, push Play.
We can see,
we've got our instructions in here.
Push up for higher and lower.
Now if I push up, then it says,
up key was pressed.
Excellent, success, that is working.
Okay, so we now have successfully
put in player input.
Now let's talk about Start and
Update, and what we've just done.
So Start is a method that runs once, and
it runs when the script
is first initialized.
It says here, use for initialization.
So when the game first runs,
our Start method will run, and
all these things will happen once.
So it's really good for
doing things that are to do with set up.
However, if we put our input into Start,
then once our very first
starting point has come and gone,
we won't be able to access that anymore,
cuz this is only relevant within Start.
And Update is telling us to do something.
As you can see here in these comments,
we haven't talked about comments, but
any time there's these double forward
slashes, anything after that is ignored.
It's just a comment for our purpose.
So you could write anything you want in
here and it will be ignored by the engine.
Okay, so this is saying Update
is called once per frame,
that means every single frame.
And so
if you've got a super fast computer,
your computer might be getting,
I don't know, 100 frames per second.
It might be getting 200 frames per second,
you might have a slow computer
getting 10 frames per second.
So we don't know exactly how many
frames are being calculated per second.
But what we do know is that Update will
occur on every single one of those frames.
The Update method is where we put anything
that is needed to have instant reaction,
such as our input here, we need to be
able and do it at any point in time.
Needs to be happening on an ongoing basis,
such as,
the quick intro between Start and Update.
And also, we now have one if statement,
which we'll talk about alot more in
the next video, where we have our
input for, the Up Arrow was pressed.
Now I have a challenge for you, and
that challenge is to complete
the other scenarios.
So if the player pushes Down,
we wanna print something,
if the player pushes Enter,
I'll give you a hint here, it's Return,
in terms of the keyword
that we need to use.
Enter, Unity and
Visual Studio don't know what that means.
Even though my keyboard has Enter
written right on it, for some reason,
it is Return.
I guess back to old school computers used
to say Return, so that is what it is.
So pause the video now,
take on that challenge,
if you get stuck then have a look at the
Unity documents, we were just looking in.
Copy the same flow that we've gone through
here, in terms of the Input.GetKeyDown and
the Debug.Log, to do the other
two scenarios Down and Return.
And I'll see you back here
when you've got that done.
Okay, welcome back.
Hopefully, you took on that challenge and
you're not just sitting around waiting for
me to go through it.
This is all about how you get better
at these things, is you try and
you take it on yourself.
So if we start typing this out,
it's good to practice the typing of it,
we copied the first one, but
we can type this next one.
if(Input.GetKeyDown) okay, and then
what sort of KeyDown are we looking for?
Well we need the KeyCode of, I'm gonna
have a guess here and say DownArrow.
Now here's another thing
I'm gonna introduce,
we're introducing a lot in this video.
It's coming thick and fast.
Is that Visual Studio has a suspicion
of what we want to write, so
it's always trying to auto-complete for
us.
So it's trying to say, I'm pretty sure you
wanna to type Down Arrow or Page Down.
These are the words I know of that can
come after keycode that have down in them.
And then if I type part of it and then I
see that highlighted is the rest of it,
I can hit Tab, and it will complete it for
me, so it completed Down Arrow.
And then I'm going to skip to the end,
hit Enter,
open my curly brackets,
hit Enter again to get a new line,
Debug.Log("Down Arrow key was pressed").
And we'll change this to
something more meaningful for
our game in the near future, but for now,
we're just doing it very functional.
You pushed a thing, Down key pressed.
Semicolon and
then we will go underneath that and type,
if input.GetKeyDown, and
see how it auto completed there?
And we have open brackets,
keycode so I can type K and
it's already highlighting it for me.
So hit Tab, .DownArrow,
we don't want down arrow we want Return.
So type, RE, and you can see the rest
of it's available for me there.
Hit Space Bar, so I hit Tab, and
then Return, down to the end.
Enter open squiggly brackets,
curly brackets, Debug.Log.
And we'll say, you hit enter,
so return, I keep getting it,
yeah actually,
enter is what is on the keyboard.
Even though we need to call it as return,
cuz that's what the key is known as in
the system,
the player is gonna know it as enter.
And then it's a statement, so
all of our statements end in a semi colon,
as you can see.
Okay, again, let's hit Save,
back over into Unity.
You can see that we've got an option
here that says clear on play, so
as soon as I hit Play, it's gonna
clear all of my console information.
I could also just click Clear right
now and just clears it all, so
that it's nice and clean, and ready to go.
I click Play, we'll get
the intra-information, our six lines now.
I can hit Up, I can hit Down,
and I can hit Enter, and
it logged all of those correctly.
Great work, I know that was a lot
to get through in this video.
I know there was a lot of, this means
that, and we'll get to it in a minute, but
we've now covered Start methods,
Update methods,
we talked about our curly brackets,
we talked about how to use input.
We've also been looking at the Unity
documents to get some more information
on when we're stuck, how do we find
this syntax, and move forward,
and solve problems.
And we are well on our way to making
a fun little game that we can play where
the computer will be guessing our number.
So I will see you in the next video.