[MUSIC]
Okay, next up we're creating
some user interface,
we're creating a Canvas that will sit
over the top of our entire game here.
We're adding text for our story, text for
our title and some images just to
give our game a little bit of a shape and
to have some backgrounds to our text.
So let's dive in and
create some user interface.
Let's open up Unity Hub,
click on New to start a new project.
I'm going to save mine in the same
location as our previous project we
created under Unity 2D text 101.
Select Project there,
project name will be Text101.
And then under Unity version,
I've recently downloaded a new version, so
we're on old version actually,
so I've got two options there.
Just stick with my newest, click on 2D for
template and then Create Project.
While that is loading,
I'll take you through a little bit
about what we're up to in this video.
We're talking about user interface,
otherwise known as UI.
And specifically, that's referring
to the buttons, the texts, the menus
that will appear in our game, usually
over the top of our gameplay itself.
And in Unity, the UI,
user interface, lives on the Canvas,
all of our UI has to be on the Canvas and
we'll be adding a Canvas in just a moment.
The Canvas overlayed
over the top of anything
else that's happening within our scene and
therefore within our game.
Now back in Unity, now click on Default
just to make sure that our view here looks
as the default view, we are going to jump
over into hierarchy and there is one or
two ways for us to create
a game object in the hierarchy.
We can right-click and click on
one of these options you see here.
Or up at the top of our menus
we can click on Game Object,
we find the same menu at the top here.
So I will click on UI and
then add a Canvas.
That brings in a Canvas into our scene.
It also brings in an event system.
Don't worry about that, that's just some
information to make sure that our Canvas
is doing what our Canvas should.
We're mostly focused on
our Canvas at the moment.
If you double click on the Canvas,
we'll zoom out and
we'll see the Canvas in its entirety.
Now the main camera is a bit more zoomed
in, and the Canvas is zoomed out,
that doesn't matter.
What we see on the Canvas is what will
be presented over the top of our game.
So it doesn't matter that the size of
the Canvas doesn't match the game,
the size of our camera,
the Canvas knows to present over
the top of whatever we see in our game.
And speaking of which, we'll grab the game
window, drag it over next to our scene so
that we can see what's happening here.
One thing that we can see is happening,
as we drag our window,
you can see the ratio, so
the size of our Canvas is changing.
If I make it look very vertical,
then our Canvas is very vertical,
matching what we've seen
in our game window here.
For now,
I don't wanna play around with that.
I don't wanna have that be an issue if we
accidentally got the wrong size layout for
our window here.
So instead of having free aspect,
and we have free aspect,
that means that we can
change the window size, and
our Canvas will match whatever
we see in our game window.
Instead of that,
I'm going to click on the 1080,
which gives a 16:9 ratio, and
that is the look that I want for our game.
If you don't see that, you can click
the plus and type in the width and
height yourself but for
now I'm gonna click on 1080.
That means no matter what,
our game is expecting to be a 1920 by 1080
game even if it's scaled down,
it will keep the same aspect ratio.
Now, double-click on Canvas again
to get it fully within view,
zoom in just a tiny bit,
we're gonna add ourselves some text.
So again, over in our hierarchy,
right-click on Canvas or
while clicked on Canvas,
come up to this top here to Game Object.
I'm gonna right clicking from now on,
so right under UI, we will see text and
in there it's pretty tiny at the start,
we'll scroll in a little bit.
You can see over while clicked on text
over in our inspector, we scroll down
you can see color, let's change that to
white so we can see it a bit more clearly.
Also, we have some font options here.
I'll change the font size up to 40 so
it's a bit bigger.
Now that I've changed it to 40,
we can't see it at all.
That's because it doesn't fit
within our text box here.
So I need to drag the sides of
the text box to make it bigger,
which also leads me to conclude
that I need to put the text box
where I would like it to be in
relation to our game window.
So I've got a question,
where should it be?
I have a look at my game design
requirements that we talked
about in the very first lecture.
And you can see that we
have a title at the top,
then we have all this section in here,
which is where our game text goes,
our story text goes, so I need to make
sure that my text roughly matches that.
I just got Title Text, Story Text, and
then the Story Area which is a colored
image that's gonna sit
underneath our text.
So back over into Unity, grabbing the blue
nodes on the sides the top left there and
the bottom right,
I will move it roughly into place.
It doesn't need to be perfect for now,
we just need to get
the general layout of our text.
Okay, so I've got my text there, and
always we need to make sure we rename
our game objects, so it make sense.
Scroll up to the top of my inspector,
and instead of just plain old text,
I'll call it the Story Text, hit Enter,
now we have a Story Text game object,
which has some text in it.
And in upcoming lectures,
we'll be dynamically feeding our story
into this text field that we see here.
For now, we've just got
placeholder that says, New Text.
Let's make a whole bunch of
placeholder story text just so
we can see how it fits on the screen.
I'm gonna copy that and then just paste,
paste, paste, paste, paste in here a bunch
so that we can see, yeah,
that's where our story is going to be and
that's roughly how large it would
when we have it on our game screen.
If I make the game screen bigger,
yep, okay, that's great.
Now the next thing I'm gonna do is create
a background image underneath my text, so
that we can see our text more clearly and
we can see our text should be going.
Again, on the Canvas, right-click UI &gt;
Image, and you see a small white square
appear, not just similar to the sprite
we were looking at in previous videos.
I will drag the side of that so it fits
a little bit bigger than where my text
is at the moment, a little bit bigger.
And it's completely consuming
the text because it's sitting over
the top of the text.
First of all, I'll change the color
of this so it's not white,
cuz my text is also white.
I'm gonna make mine
a browny kind of color,
feel free to make yours whatever you like,
x out of that.
And now the order that we see in
the Canvas makes a difference to what is
rendered first and second, whatever is
sitting at the top is rendered first and
at the bottom is rendered last.
And because this is rendered last,
it's sitting over the top of
the thing that was rendered first.
So I'm gonna drag image up here and
sit it above my story text.
And you can see that within Canvas we now
have these two game objects that
are sitting underneath Canvas.
They are referred to as
the children of Canvas.
So image is a child and Canvas is
the parent, story text is the child and
Canvas as the parent.
And in the future we're gonna be doing
a lot more talking about the parent-child
relationship, all we need to know at
this stage of our journey is that
it's a way of grouping so
that we can open and close Canvas.
We could move Canvas around
within our hierarchy here and
those two elements that are sitting
underneath of those two game objects
will go along with
Canvas wherever it goes.
There's a checkbox up in the top
right here that switches on and
off game objects.
If we switch on and off Canvas,
it also switches on and
off the game objects underneath
it cuz it's the parent.
However, if you switch on and
off the child, it only switches on and
off that particular child, it doesn't
switch off the other child or the parent.
Okay, so
that's just the start of parent child,
we'll be doing a lot more of
that later on in the course.
Now I have a challenge for you, and
the challenge is to get your Canvas ready,
create a text field for
our story like I have just done.
Create a heading, and then as an optional,
add some flair to match your theme in
terms of the images, the boxes underneath.
So for me,
I've got a heading background up here.
I've got couple of little heading,
couple little one of these
rectangles underneath for flare.
And then I've given my
story field a border here.
That's a little bit of bonus points if you
can figure out how to do a border just by
using the images that we have,
then that's a bonus challenge for you.
Don't worry about creating
funky font just yet,
we'll be doing that in an upcoming
video using TextMesh Pro.
So for now go ahead and
take on that challenge and
I'll see you back here in a moment.
Rodeo, welcome back.
What I need to do first is
create another piece of text.
I'm going to duplicate the text that
I have already by holding Ctrl+D or
hitting Ctrl+D or Cmd+D.
I'll change the name straight away
from story text to title text,
and then clicking on my theme object
I will drag it up to the top.
I don't need all of these place holder,
I'm just gonna type in My Game Name
at the top, very exciting, it is.
If you have any idea what I should
call my sting pong game and
please let me know in the Q&amp;A.
For now I'll just call it My Game Name,
I'll increase the font size to 80 so
that it's bigger.
I'll rearrange my layout a little bit,
drag it down a bit.
You can see a really
handy snapping mechanism,
the middle of my game object here,
the middle of my text field is matching
up with the middle of our Canvas,
so we see that blue line there.
It's snapping.
Likewise, if I drag the side,
it will snap whenever I reach any
other indicators in my Canvas.
So it'll snap when I hit the end
of my background here, and
also on the left when I hit
the end of the left background.
Now, next I'm going to change
the alignment of my title so
it sits in the middle.
We've got an alignment buttoned down
here under characters and paragraph.
So in paragraph,
click on the middle alignment and
then I can also change the alignment.
So as a horizontal alignment,
I can also change the vertical alignment
by clicking on the middle
button just there as well.
So now I've got My Game Name.
Next, I'll give a little bit of
a background underneath my title by,
I'll duplicate my image
here that I have already.
I'll just call,
I didn't rename this, naughty me,
this should be called Story Background.
Bad form, and then I will duplicate
that again, Ctrl+D or Cmd+D like this,
change the name of this straight
away to Title Background.
Title Background, moves it up a little
bit, rearrange the size of it,
stick it underneath or
the movements on top of my text,
I need to drag this up
above my title text.
Now we can see it above,
move it to the sides,
change the color so it's a slightly
different color just for fun.
We'll give it more of a dark blue
kinda thing, like I say, just for
fun, and there we have it.
And the final, final step I mentioned
to you about creating a border, so
if you click on your story background,
duplicate that,
drag it all the way up to the top so
it's gonna be the bottom most element.
I'm gonna change this to story
background border as its name,
up here in the Inspector.
I'll change the color to a, all right,
probably just a straight up black, so
we can see it.
And then when I move the outside borders,
so basically what I'm doing,
let me just drag this game object.
Even though you can see
I've just another box, but
because it's a little a bit larger
than the box that it's underneath,
it looks like it's creating some
borders around that out of the box.
And so there's other tools to be doing
some of the things we're doing now, but
we're in the early days.
We use the tools that we have, and
we make the most of what we can do now,
cuz there's plenty we can
do with our current tools.
So there we have it.
There's a not super sexy just yet, but
it's at least the structure of our game.
We know where we can put out text,
which we'll be doing very soon,
and in the next video or two,
we'll be having a look at how we can make
our title a little bit more interesting.
But our game is coming along.
Great work in this video, and
I'll see you in the upcoming lecture.