[MUSIC]
Hey, in this video we're gonna wrap up
the block breakers section of the course.
We're gonna create a couple
of extra levels and
then share our game to ShareMyGame.com.
And the process of creating extra levels,
we can just duplicate them,
that's usually okay.
We need to make sure that
everything is okay once we do that.
But first of all, I'm going to rename, cuz
my Level 1 at the moment is a little bit
too sophisticated, ie,
there's too many blocks.
It's not, I'm not saying that
the fact that it's a Rick level,
that's the sophistication.
That's not it at all, it's got too many
blocks in it, I think for Level 1.
You wanna think about progression, start
off easy and then allow people to ramp up.
Don't start off too easy, but
start off less complicated.
So Level 1, I'm gonna rename that to
Level 3, change it in my build order,
so Build Settings, that's off screen,
a moment, there we go,
change it to below Level 2,
great, jump back over into here.
Level 2, I'll duplicate that,
it's called Level 4,
I'll rename this to Level 1, and then my
Level 2, I'll duplicate one more time.
I tell a lie, I'll duplicate
two more times, there we go.
So I've got a Level 4 and a 5.
So, they should look exactly like
my level two, which they do.
Level 1 I'm gonna go in and
just, yes, I'm on level 1, and
yes make it a little bit easier.
Maybe one huge block and
have these invisible blocks in here we'll
train the player they can work their way
up to these invisible blocks delete those,
delete these.
Oops, I accidentally deleted my camera
make sure you don't do that that is not
the way to go about doing these things.
So I'll delete those blocks,
okay, so you get the picture.
I'm gonna go through and
make a very simple first level,
slowly ramping up in difficulty or in
the amount of content that's in the game.
So this one just starts off this one
big block and says, come and get some.
Might make it a three size, okay.
It's three size, we play that, we win.
This is Level 1, yes it is.
Let me going into my build settings,
File, Build Settings, and
just check that we've
added all of our scenes.
So drag in Level 1, up to the top.
Drag in level 4 underneath Level 3, and
Level 5 should go underneath Level 4.
There we go, okay, so
we'll create the levels.
We'll have some progression.
Make sure that Level 1 loads
into Level 2 and so on.
I'll just play that to test it when we
duplicate there's nothing crazy going on,
that it all works fine.
I've got Auto Play is turned on by
default, I'll make sure we turn
that off and then click on my
Game window and then 1, 2 and 3.
That's a good intro level, I think.
That's not too bad.
So my thought process is to start
off simple, add the complexity,
add the invincible blocks later on,
maybe add some rotated blocks.
A quick interruption, I've decided to
jump ahead in time, make my levels, and
then come back and
show you what I've come up with.
This is my Level 1,
just one big block, easy to kill.
Level 2, it's me saying hi.
A couple of indestructibles
to train the player this.
And indestructibles, unbreakables,
that they'll come up against.
And then this is just a colorful pretty
one where hopefully the ball gets in there
and does a little bit of boing,
boing, boing, bouncing around.
Level 4, it's the one we're all
familiar with, that's the Rick level.
And then Level 5.
I made just a little guy here and I bet I
know the first place you launch the ball,
cuz it's the first place I launched
the ball and I'm playing this game.
So they are the five levels that I got.
Just wanted to show those to you.
Once you've created at least five levels,
five levels that you
think are interesting,
slightly different backgrounds on your
levels, slightly different challenges.
Then what I'd like you to do,
save it all up,
make sure it works before
hand play test it, of course.
Go to Build Settings, within the platforms
here, scroll down, find WebGL.
If like me it says no WebGL module loaded,
then you can go through this manual
process, open the download page, or
open up Unity Hub and
then find your current install.
For me it's currently 28.18.2, click on
the little hamburgery thing to the right,
actually that's not the hamburger, that's
the three pancakes, over to the right.
Pancakes maybe, I guess I'm hungry,
click on Add Component and
from Add Component, scroll down
until you find WebGL Build Support.
And click on that, install WebGL, once
you've installed WebGL comeback into here.
And it should be all call,
you can create a build for WebGL.
And then once you've done that,
zip that up and
jump over to ShareMyGame.com,
follow the instructions.
First of all, make a WebGL build.
Then zip it, and then upload your game.
And if you forget how to do that,
I go through that in a lot greater
detail in a previous section of course.
So you can jump back there and
go through it Step by step.
But it's pretty easy.
Make a build, zip it up,
and then upload your game.
And remember, when you very first
upload it to pay attention to the link
that it gives you because that's the link
you'll need to share with other people.
So that's it.
Well done, great work,
super duper amazingly fantastic work.
I've been looking at what everyone has
been coming up with and I love that you're
being creative and really putting
your own impression into the games.
So to recap, finalize and upload,
create at least five levels for your game,
upload to sharemygame.com.
Share with the community.
We would love to see it.
And just a little hint for you,
if you can share a screenshot or a video,
as well as the link to your game, then it
helps people see a little bit more about
what your game's about and have a bit
more confidence to go click on it.
If you just say hey here's my link then
your less likely to get people to click
on it, so share a little bit of a screen
shot or a video that helps a Bump site.
This is a good time if you wanted
to try out any other things for
your game adding some extra features,
playing around with it.
This is the time to do it.
And also one more thing I'll remind you
of that as you go through the rest of
the course you'll learn new strategies,
you'll learn new Approaches new code.
And you can come back to this
point in your project and
add those new nifty core
things to this game.
So awesome, great work, fantastic, and
I will see you in the next lecture.