[NOISE] In this video we're
giving our defenders health with
asking our attacker to attack and
deplete that health.
And once we've destroyed
the defender to continue walking.
So let's jump in and get started.
Let's start by jumping over into
our Attacker script, within here,
what do we need to do?
Well, we need to create a method that
we can call from our animation, so
we need to be making an animation event.
So let us, underneath Set Movement Speed,
underneath attack,
we will create a new public method,
public void and
we'll call the strike current target.
And then here we need to create a float
because we want to know the damage.
And that will be created or that damage
will be specified on the attacker
that is doing the attacking,
okay so, what do we need in here?
Well, let's create ourselves a mechanism
that if we currently don't have a target,
which could happen if I'm attacking
something and something else attacks
something, that I can get in this state
where I think I'm attacking something but
someone else has killed it.
So, just saying here that if
there's no current target,
so if not currentTarget,
then what do we wanna do?
We'll do this all on one line,
curly braces,
return at return and then semicolon.
Okay, so just saying if you don't
have a current target, then return,
get out of here.
Now what we're looking for in here
does the thing we're attacking have
a health component if it has a health
component, that means it can be harmed.
Now, we wanna create ourselves
a handle to the health component, so
we'll say of type health,
our variable will be called health and
that equals currentTarget
dot get component.
And the component we're looking for,
you guessed it, is health, parentheses,
semicolon.
Now, we're gonna say, if a particular
thing has health, has a health component,
then we want to access
that health component.
And what are we looking for in here?
DealDamage is the method that we've
created already to do some damage,
and then obviously,
we're passing in damage.
Let's just have a look
in our health script,
remind ourselves of what
we've done over there.
DealDamage, it's the same DealDamage that
the defenders are doing to the attackers.
DealDamage, and it's looking to
pass in a float of type damage,
and we're saying health minus damage.
Okay, back to our Attacker script here.
So now we're hitting and
we're doing some damage.
What I want you to do is go into
the lizard, create an animation event and
in that animation event,
call strike current target
at the point where you think that
the lizard should be hitting the defender.
So there's a little challenge for you, no
it's a challenge to take on so jump in and
do that now.
Okay, our slide less challenge,
let's find our Lizard, and
on our Lizard,
we're going to have an animation.
On the animation, here it is,
we need to find the Attack animation.
Attack [SOUND] probably around about,
I don't think the very moment it reaches.
We'll give it a right about there,
his hand comes up to his mouth,
he's grabbed a piece,
and he's having a bite.
This is where we'll add a new
animation event, and I will change
this event to be strike currentTarget,
how much damage do we wanna do?
Well, we haven't really worked out our
damage system from attackers back to
defenders, but I'm gonna say twenty damage
just to see how that feels for now.
And then on my Lizard,
it doesn't need to be applied back.
Let me just double check that.
I'll click apply anyway.
I think it's fine because it's just on
the animation that we've created on
our attack here.
It's all good, okay.
So we've given ourselves
a Lizard animation event.
So what I'll need to do is add the health
component to all of my defenders
which it doesn't look like we have that at
the moment so add component and health.
Great, how much health
do we want it to have?
I gonna give it gravestone,
probably 200 health for that.
See how that feels, and
then find the Gnome.
The Gnome's a little bit squishier.
So where is the add component button here,
add health,
how much health do we wanna say?
Mm-mm, I'll say 100 for the gnome for now.
These are all returnable,
you'll change yourself, I'm sure.
Cactus is going to be the most squishy.
Actually, sorry,
click on Gnome, click apply.
Remember I said change it's course
to be rigged doesn't click on Apply,
click on Apply for the gravestone as well,
find our trophy, what was I doing?
I was doing the cactus, wasn't I?
Click on the cactus,
add a health component, and change cactus.
I'm gonna change this to 75
just to be a bit different.
Apply that back to the prefab and
then find our Trophy.
Trophy, what should we make that?
Health, we'll make it
the squishiest of all.
If you reach the Trophy,
it is in serious trouble.
We'll give it 30 health just to
see how that feels, click Apply.
Okay now, we should have a mechanism where
I'll click on my Gravestone just here so
we can see it,
It's health is currently 200.
We'll wait until someone
spawns in it's lane.
The stone's coming along
[NOISE] 180 [NOISE] 140,
jump down a couple in one go,
120, 100, 80, okay, cool.
Okay, it's because there's a few
characters in there at the same time.
They're all munching on it,
that's why it's going down.
At a non consistent pace,
because multiple people eating at it.
Okay, so this is looking really good.
The one thing we need to check in here,
I don't know if it was happening or not.
What happens after they're
finished eating something.
We'll put down a Trophy, cuz it doesn't
have many points, eat, eat, eat, eat, eat.
Once it's eaten, Trophy's gone,
he's still hanging around eating.
So I've got a challenge for
you on this one, what I want you to
do is update the animation state.
So once an attacker has killed
the defender, continue walking.
I'm not gonna give you
any more clues than that.
This is one of those ones where
want you to get in there.
It's within the attackers script
that you need to be looking at.
There's something that we need to do
in here so that the attacker continues
walking after it's killed the defender, so
take that on, give that your best shot.
Give this your best shot and
I'll see you back here when you're done.
Right, so let's think about this
logically, what do we need to do in here?
Well, it's something that I believe we
need to be updating on every frame so
I'll be looking to put
something into update.
What do we want to update?
Well we want to update
the animation state, so
let's create a new method in here,
update animation state.
And more the point I'm calling my method
in here that I haven't created just yet.
I'm gonna right click, and then quick
actions and refactors, generate method.
And then right below here we've
got our update animations state,
and what are we saying in here?
Well, we're saying if there's no target
anymore, if we've killed the target
then is Attacking should be false,
It's as simple as that.
If you're attacking and then your target
disappears, then don't attack any more.
So we'll say, if there is not current
target then what do we wanna do?
Well, we want to get the animator
component, get animator.
We wanna set the bool, so setBool, and
then isAttacking, do I have that in here,
yeah, I'm just gonna copy my
isAttacking from there, so
I know I get it exactly correct,
string references that we dislike.
("isAttacking", false);.
Okay, so
update the animation state on every frame.
Call update animation state,
if there's no target, then stop attacking.
Jump back over in here, see how this goes.
Pretty on a couple of Trophies cuz
they're easy to kill quiet quickly.
Trophy, trophy, trophy and munch, munch,
munch, munch, munch, munch, munch, munch.
And then it continues walking,
munch, munch, munch.
Awesome okay, and
we'll just check that it can back
into the attack state one more time.
Great, so we've got the transitioning
in and out of attacking.
We've got our defenders withheld.
We've got ourselves a real live
action tower defense game.
So great work and
I'll see you in our next video.