[MUSIC]
Hello again, and welcome.
This is a long video,
we're creating ourselves a fox,
we're setting up a gravestone component.
We're doing it so the fox can jump,
whereas the lizard can't jump, and
lots of other great things in terms of
having multiple attackers in our game.
So let's jump in and get started.
Let's start with a quick reminder of what
I mean when I talk about the compondent
system that we're using.
So if we take the lizard, for example,
the lizard has a whole
bunch of components on it.
Some of them I've collapsed,
so it's easier to see.
We've got transform, we got an animator,
we have an attacker script, and the fact
that we have an attacker component, and
the attacker component is a script, so
the fact that we have
an attacker component means that
this game object is now an attacker,
because of the fact that that is there.
The fact that we have a lizard
script means that it is a lizard.
Now what we could do is we could
put the lizard functionality, and
likewise we're making a fox in this video,
we could put the fox functionality, and
the jello guy functionality,
and the java guy functionality,
all within our attacker script.
But what that means is the attacker
script is going to get gigantic.
I'll just open it up so
we have a quick look at it.
It's gonna get gigantic cuz it needs
to say, if you bump into something,
then attack, and these are all
the ways that you need to attack, or
this is how you do the attack.
This is how you move, this is speed.
Also, by the way, if you happen to be
a fox, then we'd like for you to jump over
it, unless, of course, that it's not
a gravestone, then don't jump over it,
attack it, but if you happen to be
a lizard then attack everything.
By the way, if you are a jello guy then we
want you to not bump into anything at all.
So it makes this attacker
class gigantic and
figuring out what's going
on becomes a real pain.
Each time we add something to it,
it becomes a pain.
So at the moment when we say,
you know what, we've got a lizard, cool.
Hey, let's add a fox.
We don't need to go and
touch the attacker script at all.
It stays as it is.
We just go and add a new component that
we drop onto something that is the fox
component.
If we wanna get there and
say, okay, our defenders, or
we want some of our defenders to shoot,
like our cactus here, then we give it
a projectile shooter component,
now it shoots, it's as simple as that.
In this video, we're creating a fox, so
let's go through the mechanics of that,
and so if you don't wanna be setting
up the sprite and the animation,
all that stuff yourself, then you can
just copy your lizard and make it,
say, yellow, and give it a different name
and boom, there you go, you've got a fox.
But if you wanna follow along,
then let's do this together.
You can race me if your heart desires, but
I'll go through this nice and swiftly.
I won't be explaining too much.
Just going and creating our fox.
So create an empty game object, fox,
give it a body as we've done before.
Create empty body, make sure the body is
reset back to 0, which it is already.
On the fox I'm going to add a component,
which is an animator.
Cool.
On the body I'm going to add
a component which is a Sprite Renderer.
If I can spell it correctly,
Sprite Renderer.
Okay I need to go slice up my Sprite, so
let's find my Sprites folder Not In Use.
So I'm going to choose Fox Eating,
Fox Jump, and Fox Funning,
drag those into a folder that
I've created already called Fox.
There is my fox folder.
If you don't have a fox folder you
need to make one of those, and
then I highlight all of these.
I know from playing around previously that
I need to make these a little bit smaller,
so I'm gonna change my
Pixels Per Unit to 133.
Click on Apply, and also know that we
need to change Sprite Mode to Multiple.
Now, clicking on, oop, and
then click Apply, of course, thank you.
Click on Fox Eating,
click on Sprite Editor.
One, two, three, four, five by four.
Now, I know from my previous
calculations that I was doing offscreen
that if we grid by cell size,
and chop this up at 153 by 139,
then we can slice, and
it should work out nicely, as it does.
Great.
Click Apply.
Now, leaving this window open,
I can click on Jump.
Do the same thing, Slice 153, 159, Slice.
That all works good.
Click Apply, and
then click on Fox Running.
Slice, and Slice, and then click Apply.
Excellent, that looks all good.
Close down that window.
Now, we've got our three sets of sprite
sheets and click on the Fox Body, and
just give it a sprite,
now that I've chopped up my sprites.
Just type in my search box at the top,
Fox.
Choose one of these.
Fox Running 2, I think.
It looks fine.
Okay, it looks the right size as after.
I'm just gonna change Fox to be right
on the rounded point, so 4 and 3,
and z of 0, and we can't see it now,
because we need to go to the Body,
find the Sprite Renderer, and
ordering layer, we'll make this 5.
There we go, right in the cell there.
Actually you know what,
instead of being on 4,
I'm gonna shift this to
the right to let's say 8.
Okay, we've got the first parts of it.
Probably a little bit low in our
lane way there, so click on Body.
Okay, just move it up a little
bit into the middle so
make sure that my projectiles
definitely will hit the fox.
Okay, great now I'll click on FOX,
on Animation, Create.
Where are we,
Assets &gt; Animations &gt; Attackers.
We'll call this Fox Run,
Fox Run as in first animation.
Add Property &gt; Body &gt; Sprite Renderer.
Scroll down to the body, slide over
to the right, click out on the +, and
then I want to, what is this, the Run,
yes the Run, so Fox Running here.
Grab all those,
drag them over in to the first.
Delete the last, change the samples to 24.
Bingo, bongo, you've got it,
click on Play, just a little test.
That looks like a cool run.
Right, what's next?
Click on Fox Run, Create New Clip,
and this will be Fox Jump.
Okay, Fox Jump, Add Property,
drill down into Body &gt; Sprite Renderer,
scroll down the bottom, click on +.
Close that out.
Find the Fox Jump.
Highlight all these jump sprites.
Drag those over into my animation window.
Delete the last frame.
Change the samples to 24 again.
Click on play, do a quick test.
Yes, he jumps, great.
Now the last one we want,
click on the Fox Jump &gt; Create New Clip.
This is Fox Attack.
Okay, Fox Attack is coming
from our Fox Eating.
Click on Add Property &gt; Body &gt;
Sprite Renderer, scroll down the bottom.
We are gonna be absolute masters of this
by the time we're doing creating all these
sprites.
Highlight Fox Eating,
grab all of the characters.
It includes some sprites.
Delete the last frame,
change the samples to 24.
There we go.
Okay, let's check that one out as well.
[NOISE] Okay, what's next?
Well, let's set up our animator.
Click on the Animator, give ourselves
a little bit more room, make sure we're
selected on the Fox, and Fox Run came
in first, that's good, we want it to
be running along, and then we want to
branch into either Fox Jump or Fox Attack.
Now we're gonna use
a sightly different thing,
a slightly different parameter here,
I'm gonna set myself up a trigger.
So click on the little + in the animated
window, and click on Trigger.
That means we're not toggling a bool from
is true to is false, we're just saying,
make this happen right now,
kind of like pushing a button.
Instead of an on off switch, this is just
a tap the button and make a thing happen.
So this will be JumpTrigger,
is what I'll call this, and
while I'm here, I'll also create a Bool.
Oops, that's a Trigger, not a Bool, Rick.
Create a Bool, and
this Bool we will call is Attacking.
Okay.
Now write some transitions from Fox Run
to Fox Jump, and from Fox Jump back to
Fox Run, and from Fox Run to Fox Attack,
and from Fox Attack back to Fox Run.
Why are we doing this?
Well will run is gonna be
default save run, run, run, run.
And if you encounter a gravestone,
then we're just going to trigger jump.
Jump will play the whole way through
because it needs to jump up and
then land on the ground again.
And then it returns back to run.
If in that instance,
it encounters some other sort of defender,
then we will go into fox attack and
do the attacking.
Once we've finished attacking,
we will continue to run again.
Again we don't need
a connection between jump and
attack because we don't want to be
toggling from attacking to jumping.
There's no reason or from jumping
to attacking there's no reason,
we're going to return back to fox run.
So fox run to fox jump click on the plus
and the jump trigger that is great.
Remove has exit time because we don't want
to worry about whether the fox is midway
through a particular run but I'll change
my transition duration down to zero.
And then for returning back,
this is where we leave on has exit time.
Because we want the jump
to do its entire animation.
And after it's finished
its whole animation,
then we just say do whatever
you need to do, return back.
So we don't need a condition here.
We're just leaving on has exit time and
I'll make my duration
zero as I like to do.
Now, from fox run to fox attack,
what do we need to do here?
We need to click +, and
instead of JumpTrigger,
we're using isAttacking is true.
Again, Transition Duration to 0.
Remove Has Exit Time.
Same thing for returning from attack
back to run, remove Has Exit Time
cuz the attack ends immediately
after the defender is destroyed.
Transition Duration at zero, and
then we click our plus to say
that it is Attacking is False.
Okay, that's a lot of great work in there.
We've got our animator set up.
Click on play, see how this is working.
I want to see that the JumpTrigger
is working when I toggle that.
So if I tap, it jumps,
tap, it jumps, okay,
we haven't given it any
motion across screen yet.
We'll do that in a moment And
then is attacking yep num, num,
num, attacking good, is attacking awesome.
Okay, now if you're clicking on is
attacking, and it's not working,
that's because you've
already put on a script,
the attacker script, let me go and see if
the fox has got that on yet, it does not.
The attacker script has on our
update to force is not attacking.
So that's why if you're
clicking that it's not working
then that's the reason you've
already put on the attacker script.
Let's go do that now,
let's put on the attacker script, great so
we now,
this guy is officially an attacker.
We'll add a box collider as well,
box collider 2D, click on that
just to see it's in a good spot.
I'm going to change the Box Collider,
if I can click on it properly without it
accidentally clicking off, Edit Collider,
just to zing it down around our fox
and bring it in a little bit, and
bring it in a little bit there.
Okay, good one.
Now the moment we've been waiting for
which is to give our differentiating
functionality to our fox so
that our fox jumps over these gravestones,
I'm gonna do this as a challenge for you.
So I'd like for
you to create the fox component.
So first step is to
create our Fox.cs script.
And then the behavior we want,
this is what we want in here to
modify our previous lizard code.
So you can use that for inspiration.
If we encounter a gravestone, jump.
If we encounter anything else
that is an attacker, sorry,
that is a defender, then attack.
Okay, so there it is.
There's your challenge.
Jump in and take that on now, if you will.
Okay, welcome back.
How'd you get along with that challenge?
How did you find that one?
If you finding the challenges too
difficult or too easy or just right.
Then please do let me no
in the discussion section.
I always love to get that sort of feedback
and then to improve and modify as I go.
So what I'm gonna do here
is cheat a little bit.
I'm gonna take my lizard script and
duplicate and call this Fox.
Now, it's gonna break something in there.
What's it breaking?
Well, it's breaking that within
our script, it's called Lizard.
So let's open up Fox and
find where public class Lizard,
this needs to be changed to Fox.
I'll save that and then just hop
back into Unity, clear my console,
make sure that it is now happy
with what we've done just there.
Yeah, it looks happy.
Not unhappy at all with that, great.
Find our fox and
then attach the fox script to our fox.
You can just grab it and
drag it down there.
Excellent.
Now it is a fox.
Let's have a look at our fox script.
This is currently our lizard behavior.
We're saying, what are we saying here?
That if we're hitting a trigger, yes,
then we wanna create this
notion of a gameObject.
Yes, and then if the other object
is a defender, then attack.
Well, we wanna do something before that.
So we want to say, if this is a gravestone
then do what we need to do,
then do stuff, basically.
How do we know it's a gravestone?
Well, there's a few ways we can do it.
We can do the whole tag approach.
Tag approach is okay, but it's adding
some string references in there.
What if we create a gravestone class that
we, that the same way we were saying if
it's a Defender because it's got
a Defender component, then do start.
What if we say that if it's a gravestone,
cuz it's got a gravestone component,
then let's do something.
So that means we have to create a script.
Generally it's bad habit just to create
a script that's completely empty just so
you can call something as a class.
But if we think we want some
functionality for the gravestone itself,
then this is a great way to do it.
So let's go and create ourselves,
and sorry if this
challenge was a little bit random or I
left out a couple of details for you just
to see how you would approach this and
how you'd go about figuring it out.
So the interesting if you've done it
the same way as me if you've done it
a different way then no problem.
I'm creating a class here,
I'll call gravestone.
Gravestone, I think is one word.
So I'm just doing it with a small s there.
We'll open that up.
What do we wanna do in here?
Well, I think we'll do some sort of if
someone comes and attacks you then do some
sort of wobble or some sort of animation,
so breath some life into the Gravestone.
And so we don't want just one something
enters the space of the Gravestone.
We want wall it is staying in the space.
So, while something is still
in your trigger volume.
So it would, to do that we'll
say void OnTriggerStay2D and
it's going to add Collider2D collision.
We'll call this otherCollider just to
be super clear with our naming here,
OtherCollider.
Then we'll create a variable
that is of type Attacker.
We'll call it Attacker and that's
going to equal getting that component,
so otherCollider dot get Component,
and type Attacker.
Okay, so similar to what we were doing
in our lizard script just before.
We're saying here that if
the attacker that we've just created,
if(attacker), so If the thing that's
bumped into me is an attacker then we
wanna do something in here.
Do some sort of animation.
We'll get back to this in a little bit
cuz I wanna focus on the foxes part for
this video.
So I'm gonna add a TODO in here.
TODO add some sort of animation.
Okay, and then we'll save that up.
Go back over into our Gravestone.
I don't know why I keep
calling it a tombstone.
Add Component, Gravestone.
Okay, now this is officially a Gravestone,
cuz we have a Gravestone component on it.
So then, back into our Fox script.
We can say in here, now, that if
the other object is our Gravestones.
So if(otherObject),
we're interested in the Object itself.
.GetComponent, if it has
what sort of Component?
If it has a Gravestone Component.
Then what do we want to do?
Well, we want to change
the fox's animator, or
animation, you have the animator too.
We're going to click on the fox again.
Too.
What's the trigger here?
Is jump trigger.
Okay, and the way we do that
is say GetComponent&lt;Animator&gt;
.SetTrigger() is how
we're gonna call that.
Well done if you figure that out.
And this will be, let's go and
make sure we copy it.
Click on that a couple of times.
Copy back over into here.
("jumpTrigger");.
Okay, so I just want to acknowledge
that was a trickier challenge.
I didn't give you all the pieces to it.
I've gone and introduced this idea of
going creating a Gravestone class,
we had the Defender class was, I was
hoping you'd use that as inspiration for
how we knew we were hitting a Gravestone.
And also for SetTrigger, I don't
think we've used SetTrigger before.
So well done if you went figured
out all those pieces of the puzzle.
This is how I've solved
it my particular way.
And if you did it another
way that's great.
One last thing we need to
do in here is else if.
So if it's a gravestone then jump,
else if then attack.
So save that up.
Let's go and see if this works
before we celebrate too much.
So we have a gravestone.
We have a fox.
Here's our fox.
Run, run, run, run, run,
it doesn't jump, no problem,
it's probably cuz we haven't
made our Box Collider Trigger.
Let's make that a Trigger.
And then we haven't made this a Prefab.
Well, here we make it a Prefab,
drag then drop into my Prefab folder.
Okay, GraveStone,
Box Collider we'll make that a Trigger.
Okay, and you know what?
I think I've forgotten
something in the animation.
I've forgotten to set triggers
in the animation, trigger event,
an animation event.
Sorry about that.
So Fox Run,
we need to give Fox Run a speed in here.
So down at the start click on the event.
Change this to be what?
This is SetMovementSpeed.
SetMovementSpeed of the fox,
we'll have it at one for now.
We'll see how that feels.
And then when we're on the Fox Jump, we
want to have the speed of zero, I believe.
Let's see how that looks, cuz the
animation is doing the moving from right
to left, so set movement speed of zero.
This is a big video?
Hope you're hanging in there.
Fox Attack.
When it's attacking we
wanna set that to 0.
So as soon as Fox Attack is
called set movement speed to 0.
And then where do we want to attack
to be round about there as well.
I like a little bit of a pause
before the damage is done.
Head out event,
this will be the strike current target.
How much damage?
Well I don't know,
we'll say the lizard does 20.
We'll make the fox do 40.
Fast, I want the fox to be
a little bit squishy though, so
let's click on fox, add a health
component which it doesn't have yet.
We've got a few things here haven't we.
This is often how you find your forgotten
stuff is things don't work properly.
Health will make this really squishy,
so like 50 for now, half of the lizard.
Needs a couple of good shots.
And then Death VFX,
we want to click the selector.
Find our, what are we using for
Death VFX in here.
I'll do it the other way, I'll go down
to my VFX and drag in explosion VFX.
Drop that into there,
that should work nicely.
Okay, so let's check if this works.
I think we might've missed
something in here still.
Dun dun dun dun dun.
Not hitting the collider if I put
down someone, not hitting that.
Let's have a look at point of comparison.
I think I know what it is.
Rigidbody 2D, that's probably what it is.
Click on Fox.
Add a RigidBody 2D.
This is often why it's better just
to start by copying the lizard, so
you know you've got all
the components in there.
But I like to do it when I'm showing
you on the video, do it from scratch,
just in case you've missed any steps.
So RigidBody 2D, change this to Kinematic.
We'll see if the rest of that's okay,
click on Apply.
Now let's click on Play, see if the rigid
body 2D allows us to bump into things.
[SOUND] Yay, it jumped.
It didn't jump over it, though, it just
kinda jumped a couple of times in a weird
way, and then, and
that ate it really fast.
I got super quick at killing things.
Okay, so that means that our animation
did just jump straight up and
down on the jump.
So in here, when we hit our movement
speed for the jump animation,
I'll set this to, I don't know,
4, and see how that goes.
If that does push it
past the gravestone so
that it's not colliding with it anymore.
So run, run, run, jump, ooh,
okay, that did jump over.
It jumped way too far, so we'll put
it back to 1, see how that works.
Click on one.
This is exciting.
We've nearly got it done.
Run, run, run, and jump.
Our Rook didn't quite jump far enough so
I think a two is what we're
gonna be looking for here.
[NOISE] Click on that [NOISE] Set
movement speed, change it to two,
click on Play Run, run, run, run,
run, run, and big jump over it.
Okay, that looks pretty good, I reckon.
And then if we were to put down
a trophy it collides with that,
eats it really fast and
then runs off again.
Okay, so I think we've got it.
We've created ourselves a fox.
It has a fox component to say,
hey, I'm a fox.
There's some different behavior
in the fox where we've gone and
created this jumpTrigger to
jump over the gravestone.
Great work, well done for
hanging in there.
I know these lectures are big and long.
We've been going through a lot of
this character creation type stuff.
So we're nearly at the point
where I'm happy with it.
And we can move on to other aspects
of what we're doing in our game.
So great work.
And I'll see you in the next video.