[MUSIC]
Hello again, in this video, we're going
to hook up some functionality for
our start button.
So when we click the start button,
it loads to the next scene,
not much to see at the moment but that
is loading from one scene to the next.
So we'll be writing the script and
setting out our method to be able to
do that, let's jump in and get started.
Okay, we have three scenes
in our game at the moment,
we have our start menu,
our core game scene and our win screen.
And we want the player,
when they click the start button,
to load core game when they click
the that's it button or success button, or
you got it correct button,
whatever you like to label it as.
Then we go to the win screen and
then you click play again,
we return back to the Start menu.
So we have a cyclical flow
here from one to two,
to three, to four, to whatever we
get to and then back to the start.
And each of these scenes needs
to have a build index, so
we start off at 0 and then 1 and 2.
We could load by saying,
let's just load Scene Index Number 1 and
we happen to know that that means
we're loading the Core Game.
We could say it load Scene Index Number
2 but that becomes a problem if and
I'm gonna get my pen here.
If we were, for example, to add an extra
scene in here, it might be between our
core game and our Win,
our play again screen, our Win Screen.
Windscreen is the sort of thing you
have on the front of your car, isn't it?
Anyway, we might insert
another scene in here,
that for whatever reason because
we think it'll be neat and then,
we want to have that indexed as two,
so we can still keep it in order.
Go from Core Game to whatever our
neat new thing is, into Win Screen.
This would then need to be Number 3,
so if we've gone ahead and
said hard coded or
type straining, let's load 2.
Now 2, we have to remember has
change from this to this, so
it's always kind of manual work,
which is not a good way to set things up.
So what we want to do instead is to say,
we'll find out what scene
are we currently on.
So what are we on at the moment,
what's the scene number and
the what we wish to add load from
one scene to the next, we say,
take whatever I am at the moment,
for example 0 and just add 1.
And then when I'm on this scene, take
whatever we are at the moment and add 1.
So we would go from 1 and we would
add 1 and we would say that's now 2.
So the add one allows us to progress
along our chain when we're loading.
And we'll have a different challenge when
we wanna load back to the very start but
we'll get to that challenge
in an upcoming video.
For now, we wanna go through this
mechanism as saying, what scene am I on
and how do I +1 to load the new scene,
that is our loading mechanism.
And I know those of you who have been
itching to write more code will be excited
because we are about to
write some more code.
First thing we will do in our
hierarchy is create a new game object,
so right click, Create Empty, that's
why am saying create empty game object.
Or we can come up to Game Object and
Create Empty, we'll rename this and
we'll call it scene loader.
So via scene loader game object,
it doesn't look like anything and
it doesn't have any components.
We're just gonna use this a container that
will allows us to load the next scene.
As it's good practice, I'm gonna right
click and reset my transform, just so
it's in the middle of our game,
just one of these things we get into
a habit of doing it this point.
Okay, so now that we have our scene
loader game object, our container,
we're going to add a script, so I click
Add Component, we'll call this scene.
I don't know why button was [LAUGH] I
think that was cuz I was typing in button,
[LAUGH] funny thing to have
halfway complete, wasn't it?
Anywho, so who are we going to call this,
so whatever we type in here is what our
script will be called, we'll call
it Scene, what should we call it?
Scene Loader, yeah, Scene Loader as well.
So that will be a Scene Loader script and
of course,
we have no spaces and we have capital S
and capital L, Scene loader, it's the same
name as our game object, which is okay,
they're two totally separate entities.
This is our script,
that's our game object.
Scene loader, hit Enter and
create and add.
That will create our new script and
that has attached it as a component
to our scene loader game object.
Now scene loader script doesn't
have anything in it at the moment,
let's go find it.
It will be in our asset's directory.
While we're here, I'm going to right click
create folder and call this scripts.
We don't need to add folders
all the time like this but
it's a good habit to get into.
We're trying to create habits in ourselves
here, so it's easier later on and
you can see that we have
our scripts folder, so
it let's me double click, okay and
see loaded.cs, double check, yep.
And scene loader is the class name, so
I'll just double click on that to open up
Visual Studio And
we can see that we've got our
SceneLoader class right here.
Great.
We're not going to need our start
method or our update method, so
I'm going to delete both of those,
giving ourselves a little bit of space.
Okay cuz we're going scene loading, I need
to use the name space of scene management.
So using, we'll type at the very top
of our script here, under using engine,
we'll type UnityEngine.SceneManagement;,
that means we can
now use the name space of scene management
and all that is contained within.
We're gonna create a public
method called load next scene,
now, if you know how to do that,
if you know how to create a public method
called LoadNextScene, with no return type.
Then pause the video and type that in now.
I'll give you a moment to do that.
And generally, I wanna give you a few
micro-challenges in this lecture.
There won't be a big main challenge.
Just, if you know what I'm talking about,
see if you can type it in before I type it
or type it at the same time without
just waiting for me to type it.
So, Public method.
It's public method no return type, so void
and we're clearing at load next scene.
Capital L, N and S and
then parenthesis at the end.
We need our curly braces, great.
Now in here, we need a way of saying,
what is our current scene index?
And we want to define a variable,
wanna declare a variable that
is getting the scene index.
So what we'll say is end to say
this is an integer cuz our scene
index is going to be one or two, or three,
or four and those are integers, so,
it's an integer type and
we'll call it currentSceneIndex.
What is currentSceneIndex?
Well this is a little bit hairy what
we're gonna type here but bear with me.
First of all, we're gonna start
off with our SceneManager class,
SceneManager., within here,
we've got a whole lot of
options within this class that we can
use and we are trying to get this scene.
We want to know what scene we are on,
so we want to get the active scene.
We can either click on active scene or
we'll type it.
Get active scene as soon as
you can see in order to place,
you can hit tab A and
end it in auto complete.
Now, what are our options here?
So within our class of scene manager,
we have our method we can
use GetActiveScene and we then get
ActiveScene, what are our options in here?
What are the parameters
that we can dig into?
Well, what what we want to find,
sorry I forgot, on here is a method, so
we need our parenthesis,
my bad, forgot that.
And then., we need to say what's
the very first option here?
Build index, so buildindex.
Okay and then semicolon.
So what we've done here is we've declared
and defined an integer variable called
currentSceneIndex and
it is within the same manager class.
We're saying dot.
We're saying run the method
of GetActiveScene.
What's my current active scene?
Well, there's some things that we
can find out about the ActiveScene.
The thing that we wanna
know is the buildIndex.
What is the current buildIndex of
the Scene that we are presently on for
this instance?
Okay, then we want to load our next scene.
Not the scene we're on.
We're loading the next scene so,
we will type in
Scene Manager.loadScene and
in here, we want to load the next scene.
So the one we're on and the next one.
So if you know how to do that,
right in the little formula in here for
loading the next scene.
And if you're writing that, if you're
typing that in now, that's great,
I'll give you a little bit of a hint.
We want to know what is the scene.
We want to load the scene that is
one more than our current scene.
So to do that,
we say current scene index +1.
That will load whatever our
front zero at the moment.
Which we are because we are attaching
this in our start menu,
which we know it's scene zero.
Then it is going to be 0 + 1, which
will take us to scene index number 1.
Okay, let's save that.
The important step that we need to
do is go up to file, yep, okay,
build settings.
And you see that we currently
have no builds in our scene or
scenes in our build I'd say.
Builds in our scene that makes sense.
And what we can do is click on our scenes
folder and then just drag in start menu.
Drag in core game and drag in win screen.
And while we're in here we can
reorder these by dragging up and down,
wanna make sure the correct order,
so start, cool game, win screen,
zero, one and two, excellent.
We don't need to click build or run for
now, we're just setting up our scenes
in the build and that's automatically we
don't need to save this window either.
So out of that, we've saved,
now, as a final step,
we need to tell something
to call that public method.
So we've just created a public method
that we can use outside of this class.
That's what public means,
it's outside of this class in here.
We need to find a place to put
LoadNextScene, and we're gonna to that.
We're gonna put it on
our start button here.
So on the start button itself, not on
the start text, we don't need to do that.
But on the start button itself,
scroll down until you find this
field in here that says unclick.
At the moment, it should say,
list is empty.
This is where we can put in our rules for
what is going to happen when
this button is clicked on.
So we click the little plus symbol,
you can see we have none object.
What we're going to do is grab our scene
loader and drag that in because that is
the game object where we just put our
script which has the public method on it.
Now, when we look at the pool down here,
it says no function.
We have the SceneLoader and
from SceneLoader,
which is the name of our script, we can
find what do we call load next scenes.
So we just created that public method,
it's now in our list here.
We click on load next scene, so
just one more time in this cuz people
often get stuck on this depth.
We've dragged in our scene loader.
Our scene loader has our
scene loader script on it.
Our scene loader script has
within it our public method.
So from,
I'm just back up my start button here.
So I've dragged in scene loader and then
within scene loader, we need to click on
scene loader as an option down the bottom
here and load next scene, okay.
So, I've just clicked off.
So do that a couple of times slowly cuz
that's something that people get stuck on
and now when we click on our play button,
give my self a little bit more room,
my game,
it's pretty tiny on the side here.
Maybe a bit more room when I click start,
it's going to load into our core game
scene that has a our success button on it.
So we've loaded from our first to
our second scene and in our game,
when I click out of play,
it will take me back to the start screen.
So it remembers where we were,
when we're in the editor.
Rather than where we go to
when we played our game.
Okay, so we'll wrap up the video there.
This is a big tool to have in your
arsenal, the ability to click a button and
load a new scene.
Very cool.
In the next video,
we'll hook up the other buttons.
So great work and
I'll see you in the next lecture.