In this video, we are gonna be
setting up our tile palette,
creating a couple of tilemap
layers within our tilemap grid,
and then painting a couple of layers
of tile information into our scene and
creating a simple platform that might be
something that our character could run and
jump on in the future.
So let's jump in and
create our first tilemaps.
If you don't have it on your screen
already, make sure you go to Windows and
Tile Palette, to get the Tile Palette,
I've docked mine up here next to my scene,
so it's nice cose in hand, you will be
using this a bunch in this lecture.
I wanna give you a little bit of
an overview of the Tilemap Pipeline.
We started out with our sprite sheet.
We've sliced it up in the sprite editor.
Next we need to create a tile asset.
So each of these sliced sprites
will become individual tile.assets.
And then we add those tiles
into a tile palette and
from the tile palette, we can paint those
into our tilemap, which is our scene.
And we can have multiple tilemaps
that act as layers that you can paint
within and
then they can fit on top of each other.
So that's the pipeline,
let's go in and actually create that.
This is the flow we are going to
be going through in this lecture,
in terms of creation.
It's also the challenge for this lecture,
feel free to complete this challenge
as we go along, pausing the video.
Or watch the whole way through and
then complete it at the end.
Create a foreground and
background Tilemap.
Create your tile palette,
format the tile palette.
So arrange the tiles if need be if you
want it to be a little bit neater and
more arranged.
And then paint a background and
a couple of simple platforms.
That's what we'll be going through.
Let's jump in and do that.
Step number one is to right-click in the
hierarchy, go to 2D Object and Tilemap.
That creates for us a grid.
You can see this grid has
been placed within our scene
that has a whole bunch of cells in it,
a la a grid, which is very cool.
And underneath that,
it has our first tilemap.
We're gonna rename
the tilemap to Background,
right-click on Grid and
create a second Tilemap and
I will call this one, you guessed it,
Foreground, Foreground.
I'm also gonna rename our grid,
just to be really clear here I'm
gonna rename this Tilemap Grid.
So this is where all of our tilemaps will
live within this particular grid in here.
The next step is for us to jump over our
Tile Palette and create a new palette.
So right, sorry, sorry,
click on Create New Palette.
I'm going to call this Manual Tiles
because in the future we'll have
an automatic tile set up.
So we'll call this Manual Tiles.
That will all become
clearer in later videos.
It'll ask us where we
would like to save this.
I'm gonna create a new folder.
Actually while I'm in here,
which is a Tiles folder and
all things tiles I will drop in there.
We tend not to have to
access the Tiles folder but
it's good to know where they are.
Okay, so now we have our Tiles
folder with our tilemap, sorry,
our manual Tile Palette.
This is a prefab, you can see down here.
Next step is for
us to find our sprite sheet.
We'll use the background one first and
drag that into our tile palette and
it will ask us where we wanna save that.
This is more tiles, so double-click
into Tiles, select that folder.
It's generating these as tile assets, so
it's converting or
creating from the sprite,
it's creating actual tile assets,
you can see them in our tile palette.
If you go into the tiles folder,
you can see these as individual, I'll just
expand this a little bit, so we can see.
Individual.asset file, so each of these is
now a tile file, a tile file as a .asset.
There's a little bit of
information we can tweak on it.
We can change its color tinting and we can
change its collider type, not a lot going
on there but a little, bit of manipulation
we can do to each of these assets.
Now, in the tile palette, this is where we
can do some cool stuff within our scene.
If you were to click on the top left and
jump into your scene and
start painting, then we are painting
these tiles into our scene.
And you can see something
a little bit weird's going on.
It is allowing us to create
one tile per grid square but
the tile's not the right size.
So we go back to our sprite sheet, which
we sliced up previously where it says,
what is the pixels per unit?
When it comes to this is one unit,
it's saying, well,
how many pixels belong to that one unit.
We are going to say 32 cuz that's
the size of our individual sprites and
then click on Apply.
And that automatically makes it
fit nicely into our tile palette.
I'll do that for the other sprite
sheet while I'm here and I remember.
So I change that to 32.
And if you grabbed the tile asset
straight from our asset pack provider,
you will need to make this 16
because those assets are 16 by 16.
I've gone and increased the size.
I've doubled the size of our assets that
we'll be using, that I've provided for
you, just so that we've got a little
bit more fidelity on there.
Okay, so, within our tile palette,
the normal rule is you can scroll in and
out and move around the same
way you would in a scene.
We're going to paint into our
background scene a little bit more.
We're gonna paint a background.
Now, make sure your active
tilemap is Background.
If you're painting onto the foreground,
then it will be physically painting on
to this foreground tilemap layer here.
If we're painting on a background,
it will paint on there.
Clicking on the individual tilemap itself
doesn't change where you paint to,
it's only over here that
changes where you paint to.
This is just inspecting it,
it's not saying where we are painting to.
So we're painting to
the Active Tilemap background.
We will click on the, let's see,
we'll grab four of these.
Go over into our scene and we can
paint four of these wherever we like.
Which is cool,
we could grab these four and
paint four like that and
build it up manually.
We could grab this entire area and
that allows us to paint a big chunk and
we can move it along and paint bit by bit
or we can click on the filled box tool and
then highlight all of our background
which was nicely tiled and
drag it all the way over our area and
you can see it is tiled nicely and
it feels out our whole background.
If we wanted to, we could zoom the whole
way out and say you know what,
I think our level is going
to be about that big.
And then make a background for
that entire area.
I'm going to undo that for now,
we don't need it to be all that size yet.
You can see the white line is where
our camera is currently viewing.
If I click on main camera,
you can see it in here.
If you wanted to have a view that was
a little bit more zoomed out then you
could just increase
the size of you camera.
You can see the preview is being zoomed
out and the window is being zoomed out.
We'll spend a bunch of time on
our camera a little bit later on.
So for now, I'm just going to leave
it at five and not worry just yet
about how large I want my
assets to appear on the screen.
Now the next step in this process is for
us to make some platforms
in the foreground.
I'm going to zoom out a little bit here
and drag in my other sprite sheet.
And again, you can see wherever I drag it,
it'll literally place that sprite
sheet with the layout in that spot.
Click on tiles cuz it's creating
our tile assets, wait for
it to generate those and then we will
see a range in our tile pallet here,
we've got the exact sprite sheet all
plugged in there nice and neatly.
Now here's where you can rearrange
your tile pallet a little bit,
so that you can easily find things.
You can see here, we've got these
top areas, we've got a upper left,
we've got a bottom left.
The botton spots of our platform,
so click on the top left and
then I'll paint that in our scene here.
Now you might have painted that and
you don't know where it is hiding.
I fiddled around with this a little bit,
so this is now appearing on top.
But we have an issue now where
we need to tell our Tilemap
layers how to render in
relation to one another.
So we've go our foreground and
our background.
If you have a look over her
on the tarmac renderer,
you can see there is a sorting order
which is currently default and
an ordering layer which
is 0 on each of these.
If I was to go and
change the foreground to say 1,
then it should appear over
the top of the background.
If I was to change this to -1 then
it should appear underneath and
I would only see that if I was to turn
off the background and there they are.
So it's one way to manipulate the order of
your layers, we're gonna use a different
way that I think has a lot more
scalability, then that approach there.
I want you to go up to Layers up
in the top right of your screen,
click on Edit Layers and
here you'll see a few areas.
You've got tags, we've used tags a little
bit in the past and you can add new tags.
That's good from within code to say,
this thing is a such-and-such type,
as a tag or such-and-such tag,
not necessarily a type.
And we've got sorting layers and
that's gonna be the focus
of what we want to do here.
We've also got this nice and
ambiguously named [LAUGH] layers.
And for us, we're gonna be using these
layers when it comes to collision and
things to do with physics,
to say what bumps int what.
When it comes to displaying, to rendering,
we're gonna be using sorting layers, so
we're gonna go ahead and
create a new layer.
I'll call this Background.
And then also create another layer
which we will call Foreground.
Now the strength of doing it this way,
is that we can really easily rearrange the
order of this, so if we get them wrong or
if we wanna add a new layer then it is
very, very easy just in this one place
to change the sorting of everything
that happens across our entire game.
If I click on background,
then we will see over here we've
got the option sorting layer.
We'll make this sorting layer as
background and then over on foreground,
we'll make the sorting
layer as foreground.
And because we've set up in
our layers that the background
is underneath the foreground,
it has displayed it like that.
So, whatever is on the bottom
is gonna be displayed first.
Now the next step in the process,
I'm going to rearrange my tilemap,
my tile palette just a little bit.
Now I'll show you how to do that,
so you can do that yourself.
If we click on the Edit button here,
right at the top of your
tile palette is an edit button,
very important to click on that.
Now we can move things
around in our palette.
Basically, we can paint and copy and move.
So we click on the Selection Tool, then
click on the tile we're interested in.
Click on the move tool.
We can now drag and
move this to another position.
So it's a block that belongs on its own,
just a one-piece platform.
Put it over there.
We can also click on these
other kind of vertical pieces,
move those to the side, get them out of
the way, a little bit over there as well.
And you can of course click Select,
click Select,
highlight a bunch of these and
move them all together which is cool.
So I will select my block in here,
this will become apparent in a moment,
move that aside.
Okay, so I'm not gonna do too
much more finessing with that.
I will just get these guys out of the way,
so
that they are not in the way of
what I am trying to do there.
This last couple move them
down into there, okay,
you can spend a lot more time finessing
this and laying it out if you want but
I'm just gonna do it a little
bit quick at the moment.
What we do need to do, though,
is figure out a way to be able to paint
down all the pieces we need to paint down.
We've got this top left corner,
which we've already painted in there.
Just gonna turn off Edit mode for
the moment.
I can then click the tiles next to it,
these upper level areas.
Click on the paint brush, select those and
that will allow me to paint
the top of my platform.
Then clean things up a little bit by
erasing these other ones down here.
And then we've got our platform that
has a nice corner on the side and
a ledge we can run along.
What do we do at the right here?
Well we can do it two ways.
One, we can, first of all,
click on our tile, come in here, paint it.
And then we can flip it within our scene.
What do I mean by that is if
you select the Select tool,
click on the Select tool,
click on your tile.
This is now the instance in our scene,
I can scale that using -1 and
that will flip that tile.
But the process of having to do that every
single time we put that down in a scene is
a little bit clunky, so the better way to
do it is to click in our Tilemap, click
Edit, click on the Select Tool, click
on the tile piece we're interested in.
Paint that down, it automatically
changes to the paint brush.
Click that down, go to the Select Tool
again, click back on that piece.
Now we can change the scale
in here from 1 to -1.
And that will flip that so that we've
now got a platform that we can go and
paint into our scene.
So I'll click off Edit and
click on the paintbrush,
highlight all of those, and
I can now place those into my scene.
Likewise, I can do that by
grabbing the bottom left corner.
Need to click on edit again.
Paintbrush, select the dropper tool.
And then paint that down.
Click back to the selection tool,
click back on our tile piece.
And change that to minus one.
It's a little bit clunky
to go through that process,
but once you get your tile pallet setup,
it's quite nice.
Now we don't need to do the same to these
top pieces cuz there are two bottom pieces
in our sprite sheet here that
we've got in our tile pallet.
We do need to do it for
the two on our left, so I'm gonna select,
sorry eye dropper.
Drag on those, paint over there,
back to select and then change both
of those at the same time to -1.
And as a final step in this process, I'll
create, I'll grab this middle piece and
drag that into the middle.
So I know exactly where it lies.
There's a second middle piece in
here that I've created just for
a little bit of flavor.
I will select that and
then move it next to it as well.
Okay, so there we go.
We've got a tile pallet.
We're paining now the foreground.
I want you to go ahead as the last step
in the challenge is just to create
a couple of very simple platforms.
Please don't over invest
in this because we will be
doing an automatic process soon.
But for now,
drop down a couple of little platforms.
So that we can be creating
the first steps of our platform.
So if you do that I will
see you back in a moment.
Okay, I'm gonna place down a simple
little platform in here and
I'll speed up the video, so
that it's nice and quick watching it and
I will see you in a moment.
Okay, there we have it.
Very simple, kind of platform, ledge,
run along, jump, run along, jump, so
that we can get some shape for our level.
You can see that I've used these little
rounded corner pieces on the corner here,
so that it looks a little bit
more natural, how it flows.
And that's it for this video.
If you want to share a screenshot of what
you've created, that would be fantastic.
I look forward to seeing it and I look
forward to seeing you in the next video