[MUSIC]
In this video, it's another big one.
We'll gonna be jumping through
a few different scripts.
We'll get to the point where when
our level timer is complete and
we've killed all of the enemies.
We know our functionality
says end the level now.
So we're not ending the level just yet,
but we creating all of the functionality
so that we know when we should
be ending the level and
taking that the player to the next scene.
So let's jump in and get started.
Let's start by having a look at a diagram
of controlling our victory moment or
our level finish moments.
So here we go.
We've got these classes
Spawner is responsible for
obviously spawning our attackers.
But when we're looking at
our victory moment for
stopping spawning the attackers.
The Attacker script is to announce
when the attacker is spawned.
Say, I've spawned and also when
the attacker is destroyed or killed.
The Level Controller is what
we're focusing on in this video.
We need to listen for when the timer
has finished so that we know, a-ha.
The timer's finished.
The level should be complete.
We wanna track the number of attackers and
if the number of attackers has
reached zero, you've killed them all.
Then we know it's time to end the level.
We wanna tell the spawners to stop
spawning when the time is right, and
then we wanna enable a Win overlay,
in order to feedback to the user so
they know what is going on.
And then ultimately to say
let's load the next scene.
And the level loader does all
of our loading of levels.
So we're gonna be dealing in the level
controller a lot in this lecture,
why don't you go a head and
open up your Visual studio.
And just so we've some context, we'll
be working in the AttackSpawner script,
the Attacker script, the GameTimer script,
maybe we'll touch the LevelLoad, and
maybe I'll touch the DefendersSpawner.
Just so you've got those scripts open and
you're not wondering why
I am bouncing around.
The very first thing we're gonna do is
create ourselves a level controller.
So start by creating a GameObject,
we'll call this Level Controller.
Within that now Level Controller,
we're gonna add ourselves a script
which we will call the LevelController.
Okay, create and add that script.
I'm open that up we'll be
working in this video obviously.
There we have the LevelController.
You're now gonna do something
a little bit different,
I'm gonna give a challenge that's a big
challenge a very open-ended challenge for
those of you who are looking for
something advanced.
So here's an advanced challenge,
if you're not ready for this, no problem.
Follow along with me, I'll give you
some micro challenges as we go.
Here it is if you're up for
big challenge, is to create a system
that keeps track of how many
attackers we currently have alive.
And to listen for
when the timer reaches zero.
And when there are no attackers left and
the timer has reached zero,
print End Level Now to the console.
So we'll be doing more detailed
loading the next level.
Giving ourselves a time delay, all that
kind of stuff in an upcoming video or two.
But for now, let's just get to the point
where we can print out End Level Now when
our criteria is correct.
So if you're ready for a bigger challenge,
jump in and take that one on now.
And if you're not, no problem,
we can follow through together.
Okay, so let's go through this,
we've got our LevelController.
You know what I'm gonna do is have
a look at what I've got prefabbed.
It's always good to remind yourself
of what you've got prefabbed
in our core game here.
I'm just gonna drag in
the Damage Collider.
Cuz that wasn't prefabbed and dragging
the Level Controller, so it's ready.
We can just start applying things back or
probably cuz we're working on the script,
it will be applied straightaway.
Everything else is looking good.
Okay, so
over into our LevelController script.
First thing we want is create
ourselves a notion of,
how many attackers do we have remaining?
So create an integer which
we'll call numberOfAttackers.
And we will start that at 0.
Also, we want to create ourself
a notion of whether the level timer has
finished or not.
So I'll create a bool,
I'll call levelTimerFinished.
And we will initialize that as false,
cuz the level timer has not
finished when we start.
Just gonna clean up,
get rid of Start and Update.
I'll probably going to bring back Start.
I think but for now we'll do this so
it's nice and clean.
It's clear what's going on.
I'm gonna create two public methods.
One that says attacker has spawned and
one that says attacker has killed.
So public void AttackerSpawned.
Spawned like this, and
then what do we need to do in here,
to increase the number of attackers
that we're currently measuring?
Remember this is LevelControler,
I'm making this public so
we can call it when our
attacker script is created.
So we're gonna say in here,
numberOfAttackers++.
Okay, let's copy all that cuz we're
gonna replicate it pretty similarly.
Paste, public void,
instead of AttackerSpawned we
want AttackerKilled or destroyed.
No we'll say killed,
that's more sort of game terminology,
technically it's when
the attacker is destroyed.
But and it's numberOfAttackers--.
Okay, so,
let's create our logic in here for
what we wanna do when the number
of attackers reaches zero.
And I think we can do it in here
each time we call AttackerKilled,
that's the moment where we say,
are we at zero yet?
Are we at zero yet?
And has the level timer finished?
So, there's a simple if statement that we
can write in here, and if you didn't take
on the challenge and you wanna take
this on now, here's a micro-challenge.
Start our if statement to check that
the numberOfAttackers has reached 0,
and the level timer has finished.
So on our new line,
if (numberOfAttackers &lt;= 0 and
double &amp;&amp; there, levelTimerFinished,
then what do we wanna do?
Well, for now, we're just gonna say
Debug.Log, and End Level Now!
Yo, okay, cool.
So we've created our general structure for
knowing when we should end the level.
Let's go and call attacker,
spawn and kill.
So we'll jump over into
our Attacker script,
this is when our Attacker is created.
So right at the very moment that
an instance is created of this class, when
an Attacker is born, it will create this
class as well, in instance of this class.
We want to increase the numberOfAttackers,
I'm gonna use Awake for this.
So, let me write it properly,
so void Awake and
it'll auto-complete a little bit there.
Why Awake?
Well we're gonna use Awake and Destroy.
If we have a look at the execution order
here, this is Unity's execution order,
the very, very,
first thing that happens is Awake.
When a class is created or a script is
called, so we want Awake to make sure
that this is happening before
anything else happens on that frame.
And at the very end, we're gonna use
OnDestroy, that's the very last thing.
And make sure that everything else that
needs to have happened has happened.
So void, sorry, private void Awake,
this is where we will look for
the Level Controller and
call the methods we just created.
So FindObjectOfType, it's
the LevelController we're looking for.
And then .AttackerSpawned on
the very moment of waking up.
Also, let's put in here,
void OnDestroy, private void OnDestroy.
FindObjectOfType this is also
LevelController&gt;().AttackerKilled().
Okay, so when the Attacker is born,
we wanna call AttackerSpawned and
when the Attacker is destroyed,
we call AttackerKilled.
Save that up, back over into our Level
Controller, that all looks pretty good.
That should have our numberOfAttackers
going up and down for
all of the attackers that
are being created into our scene.
Now, how do we know that
our timer has finished?
Well let's go over to our GameTimer and
have a look at what's going on here.
We need a mechanism to say within our
GameTimer when we reach the point that
the timer has finished to say, hey,
timer has finished and to call that.
So in LevelController, I'm bouncing
around a bit, sorry about that.
So in LevelController let's
create ourselves another method,
also a public method, so public void.
And we'll call this LevelTimerFinished().
Within here, what we want to do is,
we'll scroll up to the top,
we made out notion of levelTimerFinished.
That's where we need to
turn that into false.
So, we'll do that first,
levelTimerFinished = true,
sorry, what did I just say?
Okay, [LAUGH] it's false at the start,
we need to turn it into true,
from false to true.
Now something has to call
LevelTimerFinished, what will call that?
I gave you a hint just a moment ago.
Over to GameTimer, somewhere in here,
we need to call level timer has finished.
What do you think that will be?
Okay down here where we've got
our debug level timer expired.
Instead we're gonna look for
ObjectOfType&lt;LevelController&gt;().LevelTime-
rFinished.
And at the same time that we do that,
we wanna make sure that this is not
continuing to loop through
any sort of functionality.
So we wanna stop this from doing what
it's doing when it reaches that point.
So I'm gonna create myself
a bool in here as well,
that I will call triggeredLevelFinished.
Just so we know we have triggered it,
cuz there's gonna be a little bit of time
between the time of being done and
us loading into the next scene.
In my Update method here,
right at the very top,
I'm going to add I'm just
gonna clean up my Update.
Hanging curly brace,
if (triggeredLevelFinished),
and leaving it like
that means equals true.
So if it's true, if this bool is true,
what do we wanna do?
We return, because that would
mean we've finished our level and
we don't need to consider this anymore,
just leave it as it is basically.
And at some point when it very first
changes so down here, bur bur bur.
If the timer has finished then we
just want to change our bool down
the bottom here
triggeredLevelFinished = true.
Okay, hopefully that all makes sense.
Okay Save that.
Now what are we looking for here?
We're looking for our AttackersSpawner.
Open that up if you haven't already.
He's our AttackerSpawner.
And in between our start method and
our Spawner attacker method, line 21 for
me, I'm gonna create a public void method,
what I'll call StopSpawning.
And, in here, we've already created
ourselves a mechanism way long-ago,
where we said, Spawn = true.
Now, it's all ready for us to say, oops.
To say, if we can type correctly,
spawn = false.
Okay as soon as something says or
calls StopSpawning,
then we want to stop spawning.
And that's for an individual spawner,
remember we have five spawners.
So we're gonna have to take
care of that in a moment.
But where are we gonna say StopSpawning?
In our LevelController.
So where we have, LevelTimerFinished
in our LevelController script.
Underneath LevelTimerFinished = true,
I'm gonna call a method,
I haven't created it yet.
But we'll call StopSpawners,
we'll call it StopSpawners(); let's go and
create that down below just now.
So private void StopSpawners(),
and then, put in our curly braces.
Now, what are we gonna do here?
We wanna find all of the spawners
in our assignment remember,
we've got five spawners.
Eat one per lane, one,
two, three, four, five.
So we need to find each of those,
and to tell them to stop.
So we need to create an array
of type AttackerSpawner.
And then our square braces for
an array and
we'll call this spawnerArray and
that will be FindObjects.
Remember this?
Objects of type,
what are we looking for here?
We're looking for attacker spawner.
Find all the attacker spawners,
and then for each of these, for
each AttackerSpawner.
So foreach (AttackerSpawner spawner), so
of each type AttackerSpawner
called spawner,
in spawnerArray that
we've just created above.
What do we wanna do?
Well, we say spawner.
So for each of this individual
spawners.StopSpawning that
we just created.
Okay, so, When we see that the level timer
is finished, we stop spawning attackers.
We stop spawning attackers
by creating an array and
finding each spawner within our array,
we say please StopSpawning.
How do we know what StopSpawning is?
Well, we're gonna save, we just created
that over in our AttackerSpawner,
that's the public method
that's called StopSpawning.
I feel this is all feeling pretty good,
we've got our game timer in here,
we know when that is all done, that looks
good, we've got our AttackerSpawner,
that's looking pretty good.
Level controller is looking pretty good,
let's go and
see what if any errors we're
getting when we try to do this.
Actually, you know what, I'm going
to go to my Canvas, not my Cactus,
the Canvas find the Slider within
the Slider I will find my GameTimer.
And just put this down to three, just so
we can stop our spawning
happening pretty quickly.
We'll have a look and
see what happens here.
I wanna make sure that I
throw in some defenders so
that I'm not [SOUND], I'm not killed.
The timer's reached the end.
We've got a couple more attackers
that we're still spawning in.
That last guy is killed, and then End
Level Now has flashed up on the screen.
Okay, great, we've got our functionality
where when the timer reaches the end,
we then say, stop spawning.
There's a little bit of a delay
cuz they're still spawning in for
a moment after that.
And then once we kill the final of those
attackers, that's the best experience.
We don't wanna have the level and suddenly
and you've still got attackers coming in.
It's all about killing the last guy and
celebrating.
Then, we get to the point where
we can load the next level.
Now while I'm here I just noticed there's
some debug information that we just don't
need anymore.
So I'm going to go on and resolve that.
See how we've got this 3, 4,
the coordinates where we
were placing our defenders.
So just double click on that,
it will take me to Debug.Log(roundedPos)
in DefenderSpawner.
Delete that, save it up, and
now we shouldn't have any of those
messages onto the screen which is cool.
Just tidying things up
a little bit as we go.
And I think that's pretty awesome for
this video.
So well done, in the next video we'll
do a little bit more of the loading
functionality and giving the player
a little bit of a better win experience.
So great work, and
I'll see you in the next video.