In this video we are talking
about PlayerPrefs.
What is PlayerPrefs?
Well prefs is short for preferences and
it's a file saved to the player's
system which stores and accesses
player preferences between sessions.
It's a place you can save stuff,
basically.
And Unity is great,
it saves to the relevant location
depending upon the platform it used.
So, it'll be a certain file on the PC,
a different place on the XBox,
it's a different place on Android,
and Unity takes care of that for us,
which is awesome.
It isn't secure, so it's easily hacked.
So you don't wanna put anything
important in there, in terms of, say,
unlocking a really amazing feature of your
game if you don't want someone to go and
be able to hack into it.
So we use it for things like what's
the volume level that it doesn't matter
if someone goes and
plays around with it and changes it.
Let's talk a bit about using PlayerPrefs.
We have this PlayerPrefs file, which
will be saved Onto the user's system,
onto their computer or their console or
their phone, and we can do three things.
We can set a float, set a string,
or set an int, in terms of setting.
There are things we can set against a key,
and we'll get to that in a little bit.
And we can also get those values.
So Get Float, String, or Int.
So we can set those things, and
we can get those things from in here.
Let's have a look at an example.
We might want to set the volume,
which is a float, or
we would make it a float, at 0.4.
And that will save into the playerprefs
file, something that we will name, for
example we will name it volume, 0.4.
And then we can have a method to
get that information to say, hey,
what is the current volume level?
It's 0.4.
But it can get messy
setting the volume to 0.4.
The way we would do that we would
write PlayerPrefs.SetFloat, and
then in parentheses, "Volume" as a string
reference comma and then our value of 0.4.
This is the part that gets messy.
Why is that?
Because it's a string reference and Boooo!
We don't like string references.
Because they can get really buried and
lost and hidden within our code.
And the main reason it can get messy is,
it's not easy to see all of our
stored keys in PlayerPrefs.
So we can, from any script, any file,
any class, we can say, hey,
save this as a PlayerPref,
save that as a PlayerPref, and then
it can be a big mess to try to find those,
remember those, know where those are.
So we're gonna create a PlayerPrefs
class to keep all of our keys,
that is the things that we want
to have stored, such as volume,
we might call it master volume, and that's
a key that have information against it, so
we want to create all of that
in one place in PlayerPrefs.
And we're going to use public setter
methods so that we can access these things
from any other class, player setter
methods and player getter methods.
So we can set the volume at such and
such and get the volume at such and such.
So let's dive into Unity,
and from our Options screen,
well, from anywhere actually, but
I'm on my Options screen at the moment.
I'm gonna go in my Scripts folder,
right-click,
create a C#script which I will
call PlayerPrefsController.
I'm gonna go ahead and open that up.
So let's get rid of Start and Update.
Right up at the very top,
I'm gonna start by defining a key
that we can use over and over.
So the key needs to be
a string when we enter it.
So if you remember just here,
PlayerPrefs.SetFloat, and
then we need to have
a string that we used.
So rather than having a string
written right within here,
we're going to use something called
a const, which is a constant.
This is not a variable,
variables can vary.
Constant is constantly a particular thing.
So typing const, and it's a string,
and we're gonna call it,
in capitals, to indicate that
it is a constant, it is a const,
MASTER_VOLUME_KEY.
And that will be defined as, or
assigned as,
master volume is what that's going to be.
Master volume we'll do as a,
I think that's pretty good.
Okay, so
we've kinda made ourselves a string but
we've created it not as a a variable,
it's like a variable,
it's a value that we can
use anywhere that we want.
So it all makes sense as we go through.
It's a little bit confusing at the moment,
don't worry.
We also need to make a const string for
our DIFFICULTY_KEY, DIFFICULTY_KEY,
which we'll get to in upcoming videos,
and we'll call this difficulty.
So in our quotation marks,
that is our string.
Now jump down a bit, create ourselves
a new public method, so public, static.
Why is it static?
Well, it's not gonna change based upon
what's going on in this instance.
We want this to be consistent
throughout our entire game,
throughout our entire project.
So it's only set once if it's static,
and it can only be updated, and
it will be the one value in all
of the places, as opposed to,
say, hit points, which for enemy a,
it might have hit points of 10, and
enemy b it might have hit points of 20.
But public static is only gonna
have the one value at a time.
Can be void,
we're not looking to return anything.
SetMasterVolume, and
then we're going to look for a float.
And we'll call that float volume,
that we need to return.
And then within here,
when another class calls this,
we are going to simply have
PlayerPrefs.SetFloat().
And then what is the string reference?
Normally, we could say volume, but
we don't wanna be baking that in here.
We're going to instead
say Master_Volume_Key.
And you see the autocomplete gives us some
clues which is great, helps us out here.
Master_Volume_Key, and then, well,
we want to be passing in volume, so
we will use the value of volume.
Okay, so that's pretty simple,
that's pretty light on,
in terms of setting up our master volume.
I'm going to put in a little bit of
a check and balance here because if
the volume is too high or too low, if from
some other class or some other place we
are saying, make the volume 328, and it's
not allowed to do that, then we don't want
that to break what's going on in here,
we don't want it to store a dodgy value.
So I'm creating myself an if statement,
if (volume &gt;=,
if I do it properly, &gt;=, and
I'll set these consts up in a moment,
but we'll create, we'll stub them in now.
MIN_VOLUME in capitals, cuz it's gonna be
another const, &amp;&amp; volume is &lt;= what?
Well, we'll say MAX_VOLUME,
Then what do we wanna do?
Well, if that's the case
then it's all good,
we can have our PlayerPrefs set
the volume level as intended.
And then finish off our curly braces here.
So if the volume is greater than or
equal to the minimum and less than or
equal to the maximum then go ahead and
do this, otherwise what should we do?
Otherwise, say else, not capitals,
else, curly braces Debug.LogError.
We don't do this often, but
we want this to be an error.
We wanna be a red exclamation
mark that says you know,
warning Will Robinson danger danger.
So a little one down the right hand
side here we want that to show up.
So log error and
well say Master volume is out of range.
Now we need to go up and
create our other two consts.
I'll give a bit of a space to denote
that these are our master keys and
these are other sorts of consts.
So const float MIN_VOLUME, and
we'll start that off at 0,
0 should be the lowest volume we can have.
And then const float MAX_VOLUME, and
I believe we're gonna have volume
go from 0 to 1 so this will be 1f.
Okay that's just a little make sure
we don't get ourselves in trouble in
the future.
Why are they in capital?
Because they're consts.
Why are they consts?
Because we don't want our program,
ourselves anyone else to ever change
what maximum or minimum volume are.
Its always gonna be from 0 to 1, they're
not variables, they don't need to change,
it's just always 0 is saying,
what's the gravitational force?
It's always consistent in the world.
Or what's pie equal to?
It's always consistent.
Don't make me recite it, I know it starts
with 3 and there is a decimal place but
that's about it.
Okay, save that up.
What I'm gonna do now is just test out if
this works before we go any further, and
to do that I'll put a little
debug line in here Debug.Log,
and then "Master volume set to",
and then space +, sorry,
space after to and
then space and then +, and then we wanna
put our a value in here of volume.
Okay.
We need a place to set this from.
So back over into Unity, and let's
create a little throwaway thing here.
So right-click,
right-click Create a Game Object.
I'm gonna call this Test please delete,
so it's very clear to future
Rick what's going on.
We'll add a component.
I'll call this script Test.
Open up Test.
And in our Start method,
start typing PlayerPrefs.
And we've got the regular PlayerPrefs and
we've got PlayerPrefsController.
PlayerPrefs is referring to, and
I've given you this link in the resources,
the PlayerPrefs in Unity
that's already set up, and
here are the things that we can access,
setting and getting particular things.
However, if we type in our own
PlayerPrefs, PlayerPrefsController,
now we can access .SetMasterVolume,
which is cool.
In parentheses what I'm going to set
the volume as, it's looking for a float,
we'll say 0.4 like in my
example in the slides before.
Okay, we've set the master volume.
Save that up over into Unity.
Looking on the console,
clear those old warnings that we haven't
really paid a lot of attention to.
Click on Play,
Master volume set to 0.4, excellent.
So that part of things is working,
It is being set and
when we access our PlayerPrefsController,
and setting the master volume
we know that it's being set because we
are saying over here that it's being set.
And now the important part is for
us to be able to get that
number from our PlayerPrefs.
So here is where I have a challenge for
you is to Get Master Volume.
Write a public getter method that returns,
remember to use the returns keyword,
returns our master
volume from PlayerPrefs,
write that in the PlayerPrefs controller.
And then to create a Test Game Object,
which I've done already, and
script to set the master volume,
we just did that.
Then to get it and print the value
to the console with a witty message.
So we were printing the setting of it.
Now let's print the getting of it.
So jump in, take that on now.
Pretty simple,
it's not huge functionality but
it's making sure that our PlayerPrefs
system is working already.
So I'll see you back here
when you've done that.
Okay, how'd you go with that?
Good and awesome I hope.
First of all,
we're gonna make our public static float,
it's a float cuz we need to return
something when we are GetMasterVolume.
And in here I'm going to
return PlayerPrefs.GetFloat,
so I'm gonna be getting the float,
and what is it of,
well, it's of the MASTER_VOLUME_KEY.
Nice so it's getting that.
Then over into my test and I'm going
to do this a little bit differently,
I'm going to straight up print this,
so Debug.Log and
then
PlayerPrefsController.GetMasterVolume();,
so I could put something
a little bit more fancy in here,
so maybe I'll say, in quotation marks,
"Returned value of " and
then + leave a space after of.
Save that up, we'll see what goes on here.
Click on Play Okay,
master volume set to 0.4,
returned value of 0.4.
Excellent, so this is working,
we're saving to PlayerPrefs and
we're getting information back from
PlayerPrefs, so that's a great spot for
us to stop this video.
Well done, and
I'll see you in the next lecture.