[SOUND] Okay,
something a little bit different.
I've found a bug in my game and I'm gonna
see if you can figure out how to fix it.
Bug fixing is a very very
important part of making games.
So here is the bug that I found
after I finished my last video.
I think it's probably been in for
the last three or four lectures.
So my apologies if you've found this and
you've been struggling with it.
One guy's made it through.
We've still got one life left.
Our timer runs out,
our remaining guys come in.
We shoot our axes and whatnot, and then
we're sitting there and it doesn't finish.
So our game does not finish
when it's supposed to finish.
So that's my challenge to you,
is if you've already fixed it,
you'll know the answer.
If you haven't fixed it,
it's probably a bug in your code.
And you can look through your code and
see if you can fix it.
Otherwise you can sit there and
just ponder what you think it is.
But see if you can figure out what's
going on and see if you can fix that bug.
Okay, hopefully you did give
it a good old try to fix.
So the process I went through, the first
thing I thought was, well, there might be
something to do with the fact that
the timer isn't getting to the end.
Or I've accidentally changed the code that
says, when the timer is done and there's
no more enemies remaining, that could
be a problem and I went down that path.
I couldn't find it.
I was looking through the code and
then I thought to myself, hang on minute.
What's really going on here?
What's going on is the fact that the game
doesn't think that there are zero
Attackers cuz that's our condition for
the game being finished.
So I went to the place where I know
my numberOfAttackers variable is and
scroll down, I saw that we've
got this HandleLoseCondition.
I look to see HandleLoseCondition
wasn't being called
because our condition of numberOfAttackers
use less than or equal to zero,
and time of finished
wasn't coming into play.
I printed out the numberOfAttackers, and
I could see that I still had
one Attacker in my game.
So went back in,
clicked on Play, and we had the fox that I
dropped in is saying run run run run run.
Drop my nos into here, I'm like okay,
so that guy would've been killed by the,
hang on a minute.
He's not colliding with our
DamageCollider and he's not being killed.
So there's an issue, very simple
issue with the DamageCollider there.
So that's the process I went through and
to fix that, we find our DamageCollider.
And at the moment all we're doing is
taking a life which is to do with
updating our score.
So we need to be gathering
the information on who has collided.
So I'm gonna put back
in here Collider2D and
otherCollider so that we have
a handle to the fact that this
is the particular thing, the particular
game object that has the collider.
And then after we take life, that'll
just make the counter go down by one.
But we actually need to get rid
of this thing to destroy it.
And the way we're going to do that is
Destroy and in parentheses we will say
otherCollider.gameObject.
Okay, save that up.
Jump back over into the game.
Let's click on Play.
Okay, you can see click on Scene view.
Run, run, run, run, run.
Blink gets to the end and is destroyed.
Cool.
Then if I kill all my other remaining
attackers, we should get to the end.
And after this last guy is shot- [SOUND]
[MUSIC]
Excellent.
Okay, so it fixed that bug.
There'll probably be a few
more that we find but for
now the game is looking pretty good.
So great work and
I'll see you in the next video.