[MUSIC]
In this video we're gonna talk about the
two main types of 2D animation that we'll
be working with.
Sprite sheet animation and
bone-based animation, and
also importing a sprite sheet and
then slicing it up.
So that we have a walk that we can use
to animate in our game in coming videos.
So let's jump in and get started.
Okay, so there's two types of
animation that we'll be implementing.
Mostly sprite sheet animation but also
a little bit of bone-based animation so
you can see what it's all about.
Now before I get started and show you
a little explanation of the difference
between the two, you might want to get
started downloading the resources.
If you want to go and
get all of the Glitch resources,
all of the images, and the characters and
stuff, there's a ton of it.
You can go to the link that
I'll give you in the resources,
that's the best way to do this.
Find the downloads and
see all sprite sheets,
and there's a zip file there and
if I show you.
Here we go,
let's just have a look in here.
This is what I've downloaded already.
There it is, there are folders
after folders after folders,
there is so much content in here,
it is incredible.
So it's great stuff to get your hands
on and within here you can see there's
sprite sheets like this one and
there's a whole bunch of stuff going on.
Let's talk a little bit about what that
means with sprite sheets in a moment.
If this no longer exists or
if you don't wanna grab all of that,
then I've given you the resource.
I guess resources,
I've given you exactly what I'm
using in this section of the course.
So it's way less size and
there's less stuff in it.
But you can just go and download the stuff
that I've given you if you want,
that I'll be using.
Okay, now what are these
two types of animation?
Let me give you an example,
this is from my prototype.
So your Unity's not gonna look
like this at all at the moment.
We'll get to this point,
so don't worry if you see a bunch of stuff
on here that doesn't quite make sense.
What I wanna show you, that in my game
I have a sprite sheet-based animation,
so that when this lizard comes
walking onto the screen.
There as they continue walking,
I'm gonna pause and
then just progress my
game one frame at a time.
Frame, frame, frame and
you can see that each frame,
there is a slight difference in
what this character looks like.
That's because it's coming
from a sprite sheet.
A sprite sheet is a single image,
this is just one image with about 16 or
so images that an artist has painted,
or crafted that image.
And they've moved it slightly that image,
I've got a bit of
a zoomed in version here.
So you can see, drawn that then
moved the hand a little bit.
Moved the legs a little bit,
and then moved the hands and
legs a little bit more.
So drawn this, drawn this,
drawn this, and not from scratch.
They're gonna be doing a bit of copy and
pasting, and maybe delete that hand, and
then move it a little bit.
But these are individual images, like
each of these are individual images on
a sprite sheet, so
these are sprites on a sprite sheet.
And you can see when I zoom out you
can see all of it in context and
then this will be one png image.
This is a single image and
what we need to do is slice it up and
say this is one image, now this is frame
number one, this is frame number two,
this is frame number three.
And then, when Unity combines them and
says play frame one, then two, then three,
then four, we get this sort of effect
where it's playing them one after another.
And of course this in my prototype build
where I'm also telling this lizard to move
across the screen so
it gives the impression that it
is walking across the screen.
Okay so that is using a spite sheet
to do sprite sheet animation, okay,
let me show you a little bit
about bone-based animation.
I've gone and grabbed from the Asset Store
this fantasy 2D character free,
as you can see it's free.
And just set that up, just very quickly,
we're not gonna be using
this at all in our game.
I just wanted to show you an example of
bone-based animation and this was a nice,
quick, easy way to do that.
Okay so this is a little demo game and the
point is we've got this character here.
Character is comprised of a whole
bunch of individual elements,
as opposed to sprite sheet where this
would be all drawn as one thing.
There's a head that is separate
to a sword, separate to an arms.
There's all these little pieces
that can get combined together.
If I can drill into this arm,
I can move it off and move it around, so
it's a separate piece.
And then I can rotate this arm and
say like [NOISE], I'm walking along,
walking along the street.
So this type of animation is called
bone-based animation, and it's all
about saying okay, when a character moves,
the arm needs to walk like that.
And also the legs,
if I can drill into it here,
the legs need to do
a little bit of walking.
[LAUGH] Need to do a little bit better
than that but you get the point here,
maybe it's moving left or right and so.
Let me see if I can undo it put his
arms back on, or might be funny for
if we leave the arm out there.
Then when I play the game,
and I'll just click on play,
I'll stay zoomed in over here so
you can see what's going on.
And I click attack or
if I move, you can see that these
are moving in and out, rotating.
And we have an idle animation here that is
just saying move this piece that's known
as the arm, let's move it to the left and
right, left and right, left and right.
Move the head up and down a little
bit every now and again, blink.
So that's bone-based animation,
and it takes a lot more work
within Unity here to set up exactly
how the bits and pieces move.
The animation is happening within Unity,
whereas for
the sprite based animation,
it's all been taken care of by an artist,
and they give you the sprites and
say, there you go.
So both are cool, both are fine, but it
just depends on what your artist wants to
do, and whether you're the artist and
where you want to put the emphasis.
So I'm gonna focus mostly on sprite sheet
animation in this section of the course,
but a little bit of bone-based just so
we can practice it.
Next up, I'll be importing a sprite sheet
and slicing it up, so if you haven't
download the assets against this lecture
already now's a good time to do that.
Or to download the assets
from the Glitch website,
find where you download those,
and let's see.
In sprite sheets, so within the following
in sprite sheets, I'm gonna look for
Lizard Walk,
drag that over into my Assets directory.
And I need to create myself a new folder,
so right click, Create Folder,
I'll call this sprites.
And then drag the lizard walk
into Sprites, double click and
you can see Lizard Walk here.
If we drag up the little preview, so
click down at the bottom and drag,
we can see there is our sprite sheet.
So if you've already sliced up sprite
sheets before, and you know how to do it.
Here's a good time for a challenge, the
challenge is to Import a sprite sheet and
then to slice it up so
that you have individual units to it.
If you haven't done that before
then let's do it together, or
you might want to watch me and
then do it afterwards.
Okay, let's start slicing up,
click on Lizard Walk.
Then Sprite Mode, we need to change
that from Single to Multiple.
And then to click the Apply button so
that that sticks.
Now, Unity now thinks that
there's multiple sprites
on this one png that we've given it.
Click on the Sprite Editor to bring
out the Sprite Editor window and
then up in the top left
you'll see a Slice button.
On the Slice button, we're going to leave
it as automatic and then click on slice.
And you might not have noticed it but
now we have a white lines
around each of our sprites.
So when we do automatic Unity's saying,
okay all of this is transparent.
That clearly not a sprite,
I'm gonna put a tight box around each
of these what I think is a sprite, and
then give it a name that goes up from two,
to three, to four, and so on.
So you can see each of these numbers,
you can rename these if you want,
I find it a little bit unnecessary for
what we're doing.
We've got the numbers that are increasing,
so click on Apply and
that is now your sprite
sheet all chopped up.
You can see it's chopped up by going back
onto your sprite sheet, opening it up,
and you'll see each of these.
Make sure we drag up our preview so
we can see it.
Each of these has been chopped up
to create an individual frame of
our walk cycle.
And then it should loop back to the start,
so if we were to simulate this being
an animation, that is how our character
would look walking, which is awesome.
So that's all we're going to do in this
video, I've had a couple of mega marathon
videos of late, I know so
this one I'll keep a little bit quicker.
In the next video, we'll be diving in and
taking care of animation, and
actually making our lizard animate and
look like he's walking in our game.
So, great work and I'll see you shortly.