Congratulations on finishing this section.
Well done,
you've been putting a lot of hard work.
Here is Ben hanging out with this again,
and we're gonna talk a little bit about
what to do next in your journey.
&gt;&gt; Hey guys, okay, so the reason firstly
that Ricky is doing this part of the
course is cuz over in our other partner
course, the 3D version of the course, I
cover basically exactly the same content.
So for a bit of variety, two different
ways of looking at the same thing.
Now, what is the purpose of this content?
It is not to understand Unity.
That is why we have purposely glossed over
Unity is to understand the basics of C#.
By the end of the section, what we want
you to take away is just how to write
single statements in a format
that the computer understands.
Where to put your whitespace, where to put
your semicolons, where to put your code,
that's all you need to take from this.
The rest of it will come clear, later we
will come back round to the topic and
revisit it, and
build on it layer after layer.
So awesome, congratulations.
Rick, what's next?
&gt;&gt; Well,
next up we are getting our
hands dirty with Unity,
getting into the engine and playing
around with it and understanding it.
Wherever you are in your journey at
the moment, whatever you know with coding,
if you're finding it awkward and
uncomfortable, not a problem.
When you're starting out,
things might not make sense.
But now is the time to keep pushing
forward, keep going, and really,
absorb it and have good fun doing it.
&gt;&gt; See you guys.