[SOUND] In this video, we're gonna
introduce the concept of coroutines,
a really, really useful approach for
us to allow our game to wait for
something to happen or to not continue
until some other conditions are met.
So let's talk about what is a coroutine?
Let me get my little laser pointer
down here so I can wave it around.
What is a coroutine?
It's a method which can suspend, otherwise
known as yield, that's an important key
word, yield, its execution until the yield
instructions you gave it are met.
So yield is another way of saying
give back or relinquish or suspend.
So here's a little example
that I've made up.
So say, for example,
when your player gets to zero health, so
in other words they're supposed to
die when they get to zero health,
we want to start or
call the KillPlayer coroutine.
And remember, coroutines are methods,
so it's like calling a method,
we do it the same way.
So we start the KillPlayer, or
we call the KillPlayer coroutine.
Within that, we will say, within this
coroutine we say, trigger the death
animation, some sort of heroic
explosion or the player falling over.
Then we also tell it,
wait for three seconds.
Why do we need to do that?
Well the death animation
takes three seconds.
We go and also say yield until
the death animation is finished.
But in my little example here we'll just
say, yield or wait for three seconds, so
we know the player's finished
dying all his dramatic death.
And then within this method, within this
coroutine, we say restart the level.
If we didn't have the yield in there or
if we weren't making this a coroutine,
then we would start the death animation
in the exact same frame we'd restart
the level, so we'd never see it.
And there are some keys words that we need
to use in the coroutine that you need to
make sure you include.
So the first key word is StartCoroutine.
This is when we want to call
this coroutine somewhere.
So it can be in a place where,
as I said before,
if the player is dying then you might say,
when the health reaches zero start
coroutine, and the name of the coroutine.
What did we call it in the previous slide?
It was KillPlayer, so instead name of
NameOfCoroutine, we would say KillPlayer.
So StartCoroutine is one important
keyword, the IEnumerator return type.
So remember when we do methods,
if we have the name of the method,
if we have void there's no return type,
if we say float it's a float return type.
Here the return type is IEnumerator.
So we need to have this
IEnumerator return type, and
then also the other keyword or
keywords is to yield return.
Yield return until some
sort of condition is met.
And you can see we've got our things to
do, yield return and then things to do.
You can have things to do above,
things to do below, or
you can have no things to do at all
depending upon the circumstances, but
these are the three important elements.
StartCoroutine, IEnumerator,
and yeild return.
So within our game I've got a simple
challenge for you, using the information
we've put here on the screen,
is to create a simple coroutine.
Create a coroutine which prints something
to the console, waits three seconds,
then prints something else.
So just jumping back up here.
So create your coroutine, give it
some sort of name, like PrintAndWait.
And then the things to do, we wanna
print something out here, yield for
three seconds, and then print something
else afterwards, and then call this.
And you can call this in
your start method for now,
just put it on the player .cs script.
Sow we can do this,
we've got that open at the moment.
And you can start your coroutine calling
whatever you've called your coroutine.
And the last bit of information is,
cuz I haven't told you this yet,
I'll tell you this now,
is to use yield return new WaitForSeconds.
That's one way that we can say, wait
until a particular thing has happened.
Wait for seconds, and
then I've just put in there, 3.
So on this line we would wait say
yield return wait four seconds three.
Okay, so I'll leave this slide up so
you've got this on screen.
Give that your best shot and
I'll see you back here in a moment.
Okay, so if that challenge was
a big challenge, not a problem,
we're gonna be dealing with coroutines
a few times throughout this section.
So what I really want you to do is to have
a look at it and think about it without me
just giving you the exact approach and
answer and you following along.
So giving you a chance
to think about it first.
So what we'll do is I will create
underneath my Update method here.
And just to note,
this is gonna be a throwaway.
We'll be changing this,
we're not keeping this.
This is just for an example for now.
So I'll just put it in here.
I'll say, IEnumerator.
And what am I going to call my coroutine?
I'll say, PrintAndWait, and
give my open and closed parentheses.
And then open my curly braces, and
you can see it's telling us already,
hang on a minute,
you haven't given me a yield return.
Not a problem, we'll do that in a moment.
First of all we'll say debug.log.
And what do we want to say in here?
First message sent, boss.
[LAUGH] And then, I'll put in my yield,
so yield return new.
We need the new keyword in
this particular instance.
Yield return new, and
it's gonna be a new WaitForSeconds,
open and close parentheses,
put a three in there, and semicolon.
So yield return, you WaitForSeconds(3),
and then we'll print something else out,
debug.log, and
we'll write in here the second message.
Second message, yo, okay.
[LAUGH] Getting all gangster again.
Not really.
And then we'll save this.
We need a spot to be calling this.
One note is [LAUGH] try to avoid
putting coroutines within update.
We're going to talking about that a bit
more throughout this whole section,
but generally we don't want to
be firing off coroutines, fire,
fire, fire, fire, fire,
every single frame.
It creates all sorts of
madness if you do that.
So I'm gonna put this in the start method,
we'll say, I'll type in StartCoroutine.
What's our coroutine?
It is PrintAndWait and we need our open
closed parentheses and semicolon, okay.
So we're calling our
StartCoroutine PrintAndWait, and
then our IEnumerator, so our actual
coroutine down here, PrintAndWait.
We're printing something out,
we're waiting,
then we're printing
something else out again.
The flow will be, on start it will say,
okay, do this thing,
it comes down here and it prints it.
And the very next thing it does in
the same frame, it goes and says,
yield, okay, wait.
Goes off, does everything else it needs to
do in the game after the three seconds.
So it's keeping track
of the three seconds.
It says, okay,
I need to come back into PrintAndWait and
do that other thing that
I was yielding for.
It comes back, finishes off, and
then it gets to the end of its curly
bracket, and the coroutine is done.
So we'll save up our script.
We'll hop back over into Unity,
click on play.
And then we should see
something immediately.
Print first message, yeah first message
sent, three seconds, and then second
message, yo, that was three seconds even
though I was babbling over the top of it.
Okay, so
that's a really really simple coroutine.
Once again, where we are calling
the coroutine and the coroutine itself is
saying, do some things,
yield until a certain condition is met.
And in this case the condition
is WaitForSeconds, and
then do something else.
And once you've done that something else,
then we're all done,
we've finished our coroutine.
Until it gets called again somewhere else,
which you can absolutely do.
In the next video we'll be implementing a
coroutine into our fire so that the player
can have repeating fire without having to
tap the space bar over and over and over.
So great work in this video.
If you have any questions at all about
coroutines, please throw them in the Q&amp;A,
throw them in our questions section,
and we'll do our best to answer it.
The community is amazing at helping out
with these things, so please do ask
if anything hasn't been clear, and
I'll see you in the next lecture.