Hello and welcome back to the course in
R programming and today we're talking
about statistical layer of our
visualization process. So let's move into
R studio and see what we have for
today.
Alright so statistical transformations,
well the functional we're going to talk
about or the layer that we're going to
be talking about today is called geom
smooth, so let's look it up.
Geom underscore smooth and we won't read
through all of this but let's zoom in
and look at the first sentence it says
aids the I in seeing patterns in the
presence of over plotting. So basically
geom's move allows you to observe trends
and dependencies and kind of like
relationships. It shows you all of these
things if there's like lots of points on
your chart, exactly our situation
it shows you those trends and other
things that you might not see right
away. So let's go back into the main
window of R and let's go ahead and see
how can use or take advantage of this
function. So we're going to create our
u functions, so that's the order you
layer starting layer is going to be u
today and going to say ggplot data
equals movies aesthetics and inside
aesthetics we're going to create that a
plot that we're pretty used to critic
rating, audience rating and color equals
genre. Alright there we've map our
variables.
Now let's say you + geom point,
so we're very well aware of this plot
and now we're going to add this smoother.
We're going to say plus geom so we're adding
a new layer and geom smooth so if I run
this now, you'll see that it is horrible.
It is very very not pretty, it's got all
of these smoothers with all their bands on
top of each other kind of kind make
things worse can't really tell anything
from here.
So what we will do is we'll say fill
equals N/A, so N/A means we don't want any
fill and if we run this now much
better right? So now we have the trends
and now we can observe them. We can say
that ok so we've got our legend over
here and we can see that for instance
this is romance right so this is how are
the critic ratings and audience ratings
interrelated so for instance if your
movie is their romance comedy and the
critics give it or have come in just a
romance movie and the critics give it a
low rating around 25 then it's actually
very likely that or you know
statistically likely that the audience
is going to actually rate it pretty high.
So over 50 surprisingly and or for
instance what else can we talk? Well
we can tell that let's take for instance
horror movies here and action movies so
you can see that if the critics give a
horror movie a high rating of 75 and
they give an action movie the same high
rating of 75 then statistically the
action movie is more likely to get
better and better rating from the
audience than the horror movie so you
can observe quite a few relationship
from here and they're quite interesting
especially as we move from left to right
and you look at how the critic ratings
change and then you observe what happens
the audience ratings so that is what a
smoother helps us see it helps us see
all these patterns in the data which we
otherwise wouldn't have ever picked up
because there is so many dots is like
500 dots on that chart.
Alright so that's the smoother and we
will be using smoothers a bit more
throughout this course and actually
actually so now we know where you know
books histograms so that's one way of
statistical analysis and now we know
smoothers, let's look at another one. Let's look
at box plots, alright these are the
favorite type of plus for executives,
they absolutely understand and they like
box plots from my experience.
Alright so let's say u is going to be
ggplot what are going to do this time?
This time is going to be different, we're
going to say data equals movies and
then we're going to say aesthetics and
instead of aesthetics we're going to say x equals
so the bottom axis the horizontal
actually going to be genre, that's
going to be
a categorical variable, y equals
audience rating and color is going
to be genre as well, so everything is pretty
much the same just we're changing the
bottom variable to from critic rating to
genre. Let's run that and now we're
going to say u plus geom with what you
think it's going to be? It's going to be
box plot so if I run that, viola!
Simple as that, we get a box plot already,
right away.
Alright and now I'm going to say u
plus geom box plots then size equals 1.2,
I'm gonna increase the size,
ok so I wanted to say right away here
that if you are not entirely comfortable
with what box plots are I totally understand
it you know, it takes takes a bit of
studying to understand them pretty well
how they're constructed you know what is
the first quarter 2nd 3rd 4th what's
this line in the middle and what what
are these anomalies around how they
calculate, I'm going to add in a tutorial
at the very end of the course in the it'll be
bonuses tutorial section and I'll add a
tutorial on box plots from one of my
other courses just so that you can go in
and check it out and learn box plot
once and for all. So go ahead and do that
if you would like to learn a bit more
about box plots.
It's they're pretty handy and definitely
can help you out sometimes when you're
presenting or when you doing some
analysis.
Alright so now we're going to just
continue with our box plots so there we
go, we've changed the size now let's add
some point so let's copy that and here we're
going to say plus geom point, so we're
going to combine box plots and points so
that's another layer we're at it we've
got one layer now we're adding a second
layer. Let's run that haha
there are our dots beautiful actually
not that beautiful because this is not
pretty like you can really doesn't add
any value to this truck that's why
there's a trick and I'm going to show it
you know. It's gonna it's a tip or a hack
for you so I'm going to do the same,
box plot but instead of geom point, I'm
going to say geom_jitter and what
jitter does is it
synthetically or just throws the point
around. It does is this the jitter comes
from nowhere, it's just like a random
chaotic thing that R does for you, just
throws these points around. So if I rerun
this you'll see that they end up in
different point in different areas every
time but basically it aids the I. It helps you
see the data better now you can actually
see all ok that's what the box plot
means. Alright so you know who you're
presenting to will actually appreciate
that are there's more points in here or
yeah that's true like most of these
brown points do fall in the box and then
there's only a couple here, a couple here
and so on and then the outliers that
much better presented and so on so a
jitter is a very powerful tool when you
use it in combination or box plots so note
that down that that's a good combination
I think and another way to present this
so this is one way to visualize it
another way which I personally prefer is
to put the points first so we say you
plus geom underscore jitter and then
we say plus geom remember if we change
layers then there you know which one is
on top which on the bottom also changes
which says size because of 1.2, so if we run
this the points are gone right so the
boxes are on top but the point I got so
what we're going to do now is we're
going to make the boxes half-transparent.
We're going to say alpha equals 0.5 so alpha is in charge
as we know alpha is in charge of
transparency, so 0-1, 1 is opaque. 0 is
transparent, so here we're going to say
0.5 and now personally I like this style
more I can see that the boxes are on top
and the points so the point is you feel
like the point where you there and then
somebody can put the boxes on top and I
think that's much better to present in
that way.
So there we go that's going to be our
shark number six.
Let's go ahead and export it what do we
usually do that and then that so I'm a
preview, save and let's take it
okay two more to go. We've got that
executive one and then we've got one
more which we actually like to the
bottom of the histogram which we wanted
to fix up. Alright so that looks pretty
cool I I kind of like how this box plot looks
and well of course we didn't we've
created the plot but we didn't talk
through it.
What do we see from here? Well we see
that I am based on the genre, so you
can see where the mean is so what is the
most statistically likely rating that
movie will get so I random movie that
just throw into this environment into
the world to create a movie and
depending on the genre you can kind of
guess if it's going to be an average
movies, going to be somewhere around its
peers you'll see what's rating it is
likely to get the audience so it's an
action movie it's probably going to get
somewhere on looks like what does it
look like 60 maybe 57 or something out
if its invention I get a bit higher
rating so the highest rating you're
probably going to get with a thriller
right? It's got this the most the
narrowest box so it means the variance
is very low and you're much more likely
to be at over here the lowest as you can
see is with horror movies, So it's very risky
to be in the horror movie business drama
is actually also pretty good
surprisingly so people kind of the like
drama these days as well as the romance
and thriller.
Yeah there we go, that's a box plots and that's
how you read them and that brings us to
the end of tutorial but before we go I
have a mini challenge for you. A
challenge to create boxplots but instead
of audience rating over here create them
for the critic rating and see what do
you can tell from those boxplots based
on what we've learned today and I look
forward to seeing you next time. Until then,
happy coding.