Hello and welcome back to the course in
R programming. Today we've got a very
exciting tutorial because we are going
to create our very first function. Up
until now we've only been using
functions but today we're actually going
to create one. So let's see how this is
going to happen.
What are we going to create a function
for? Well you see this bit of code over
here that we're using to visualize our
data, it happens to be that we're
always copying it along we're always
dragging this code along whenever we
want to create a new chart, so we have
this code here right, we have this code
here and now we have it here, so whenever
we want to draw create a chart we have
to copy this code along and how about we
find a way to encapsulate this code in a
simple form, so that whenever we want to
create a chart we don't have to type up
all of this code again or even copy it.
We just call that simple form and that's
exactly what functions are for, functions are
designed to encapsulate code that does
something in just one object inside the
function itself and then instead of
typing this code up every time you can
just call the function and possibly some
parameters and the code will work.
Alright so that's exactly what we're
going to do, we'll do it by step so that
we don't get overwhelmed. We're going to
start by just encapsulating all of this
code, so let's create a function that
visualizes minutes played for different
players. So we don't need this over here
we're going to encapsulate all of this
inside a function right? So how do we
create a function? It's actually pretty
straightforward, it's very similar to the
structure that we had for loops, like
for loop, a while loop and so on. So let's
check it out, to create a function you
type in the keyword function, then you
type in normal brackets and then you
type in curly brackets and you put the
code of your function, the body into the
curly brackets. There we go, so that
function is pretty much ready
what we need to do now is we just need
to assign it a name and to assign it a name, you
just type in the name before, so let's
say myplot that's going to be the name
of a function and then you put the
arrow. So basically here's myplot is
the object and inside that object you're
going to put not just like a value of
vector or matrix you're putting a
function. So function's also an object in
R and now if I run this code, I have a
function myplot. So if I look here,
you'll see it here myplot function and
now if I just call myplot and run it,
What it will do is it will actually
create this visualization. Now we didn't
see anything happened because it's the same
visualization. Let's change the player that
we're visualizing, let's say we're
visualizing the second player.
Let's change that here and let's rerun
this function and now let's execute it.
You can see the function has changed. Now the
color hasn't changed but that's because
that's how a legend is designed, it will
the top player will always in our data
set that we visualized always have this
color. So if we visualize that say the
second and third players right like that
if we run this function again, create it
again and we visualize it now we have
two players. Ok that's good but as
you can see every time we want to change
the players we have to go back into the
function and actually change these
values to the players we want to visualize.
Now, we don't want that, we want our
function to be flexible.
How do we do that? Well in order to do
that we use parameters and we've already
encountered parameters numerous times
when we were calling functions like
sequence or replicate or R norm other
any other function that we've been
working with most of them actually take
parameters. So how do we specify
parameters for R function? Well it's
also pretty simple. Here in the brackets,
you need to specify the parameter name.
So let's call our parameter rows,
so which rows do we want to look at? Then,
all you have to do is copy this in the
place of where you want that value to go.
So we wanted to go here and we wanted to go
here.
So now we've got this variable right? So
rows became a variable and when whatever
value put we put in here, the function will
automatically look for that word
throughout the code and we'll replace it.
It will replace it here and we'll replace
it here. It's as simple as that.
So if I run this now,
if I create this function and then for
myplot now I supplied some variables, let's
say, I say the first to the fifth players.
What the function will do and this is
the important part. The function will
take this value because it will see
aha, I'm looking for a value, their the
user is supplying me a value. It's supplying me
a vector. So I'm going to take this word
rows and everywhere I see rows inside
the code of the function I'm going to
replace it with the value that's being
supplied. Ok so let's try that out. As you
can see, it's beautiful.
We have the five players visualize.
Awesome, let's try a different one. Let's say,
players 1 to 10
all of them, see now we have all of them.
Ok so we're nearly done with the
function.
The last thing we want to do is we want
to use this function to visualize other
data sets that we have. Right now, the
only data set we're visualizing is
minutes played and if we wanted to change
it would have to go in here and change
this to games right? We would have to go
in and then we would have to run this
code, again recreate the function and
then plot and now we see the games
they've played or if we wanted to visualize
the points that they got for their teams
now if we run this code again, we can
visualize the point that they got
alright. So you can see that every time
once again there's this moving bit in
the function that we have to change and
that makes the function inflexible. How
do we change this? How do we make the
function flexible?
Well it's pretty simple, all we have to
do is once again replay, create
another parameter. So let's put one here,
we'll put it first because it's more
important and we'll call it, let's call it
data. So now we're saying that we want a
parameter positive function which is
data and wherever in this code we see
data we're going to replace it with the
value that's going to be supplied.
So here we're going to replace points
with data and so whatever is going to be
supplied as data is going to be
replaced here, so if I execute the
function, I create the function and then
here I need to supply the data. So let's
say I want to visualize salary for all
ten players. If I run that, you'll see
that now we see the salary for all
ten players. Once again, I can change
the players I want to visualize 1:2.
Alright, so that's beautiful isn't it? It's,
we're visualizing exactly what we
want and the final bit, the bonus bit
on top of everything is we're going to
set a default parameter. You know how
sometimes when we are using functions
that they have default parameters
already? Well this is exactly what we're
going to do now for our function. We're
going to say that rows will have a
default value, the default value will be
equals 1 to 10, so if the user doesn't
pass a parameter for rows. We want to
visualize all of them. So let's see, let's
try that,
let's create this function like this now
and now we're going to visualize it
right? So instead of actually putting in
the row numbers that we want to
visualize, let's say we just don't put
the row numbers in and we run it. As you
can see, the function has now visualized
all of the rows for us and that's
exactly what we were after.
Ok so that makes this function very
flexible, now you can set any data set
and any rows that you want and you don't
even have to set the rows. So you can
type in minutes played right and you can
run it or you can type in minutes played
divided by  games because we know that a matrix divided by
matrix is the matrix and we run that. We
visualize all the players or you can
look at a certain players, so let's look
at third player you can see that that's
how many minutes per game Lebron James
has played in the past 10 years.
Alright, so that's us creating R function.
It was a step-by-step process. I hope it
was quite clear what we're doing and now
we have a very useful function that we
can use in analyzing our data set. So we
will get to that in the next tutorial
and will try some very cool and
interesting insights from this NBA
basketball data and I'll look forward to seeing you then.
Until next time, happy coding!