Hello and welcome back to the course of
R programming. This is Kirill Eremenko and
I am super excited to have you back here
in the course and what are we talking
about today? Well today we'll finally
find out what is a vector. We've touched
on vectors a little bit in the previous
section of the course and it is time now
to finally get it down pat and have a
good understanding of what a vector is.
In fact, it is going to be a quite a
quick tutorial because of vectors are
not that complicated.
Ok so let's get started. The definition
of a vector is a sequence of data
element of the same basic time. The way I
imagined a vector is like a horizontal
bookshelf with lots of sections and in
each one of these sections you can put a
number so let's say in the first section
put 50 second section 34, 111 and so on. So
basically we're putting numbers into
this vector and there's ten numbers and
this is a numeric vector. Numeric
basically means either integer or double
so basically anything that has a number
so this is a numeric vector of length
10 and if you've studied other
programming languages before then a
vector in R is the same thing as an array for example and C or C++ so pretty
much in any other languages just called
different and the name a vector comes
from a linear algebra because R is a
statistical language from mathematicians
and statisticians and there are a lot of
concepts that come from linear algebra
and one of them is a the name of vector
and actually vectors are enumerated
because vectors the sequence of data
elements or in other words and ordered
set it will always have a beginning and
an end so in this case it starts with
123456789 10 and notice the difference
here if you studied other programming
languages then indexation of areas
normally starts with a 0, so in this case
would be zero all the way up to 9 but in R
indexations that starts with a 1 which
makes things a little bit easier
especially if you're just starting out
into programming.
Ok so that is an American vector of
length 10, let's have a look at different
vector. Let's have a look at a
character vector of length 7 so a
character vector would have character
elements in it and we've already talked
about character variable so there's
letters zed and of course it has to have
quotation marks as any character value
letter F letter or the number seven but
represented as a character because
remember that a vector can only have
data elements of the same type so even
if you tried to put in a 7 as a number
into a character vector. R would
automatically change it for you into a
character so because it can change a
letter into number but it can change a
number into a character you're resulting
vector would of course be of characters
and there's a couple more characters so
even multiple letters or a combination
of letters and numbers in R is
considered to be characters so this
is a vector character vector of length 7
and here is its indexation. Ok so that's
how vectors work and one final thing I
wanted to show you for today and that is
a little secret of R. Ok let's say you
have a number you have a number for
instance 27 and we've talked about
variables before we've talked about
values and how you can store values and
variable and so on and in fact the
secret of R is that even a single
number is stored as a vector. As a vector
of length 1, there you go that is our
little secret
and we're getting a bit of ahead of
ourselves right now why that is is kind
of a conceptual thing in the background
of R and we'll get back to it further
down in the course but just keep that in
mind that everything in R even a
single number or a single character is
always going to be a vector that's just
how this programming language works
and I look forward to in the next
tutorial, until then happy coding.