Hello and welcome back to a course on
R programming. Today we'll talk about
logical variable and operators.
Let's dive straight into it.
First off, we're going to save the file
for our previous project. So once again,
we're going to press command S or control
S, depends on what machine they are on and
we will give it a name, tutorial 02 and
just go ahead and click save and now
let's create a new script. Once again, we
will clean up the environment,
click yes and let's get straight into
logical operators. So logical operators
can basically have two possible values
and we've actually already talked about
these so let's put a comment in and what
other possible values that they can have.
They can either be true or they can be
false and it's important that it's all
caps and also you can use just the word
just a letter T or just the letter F,
but also it has to be kept. So what is a
logical operator?
Well let's have a look at a couple of
examples, let's say we want to check if
four is less than five then we type in
for less than five and we run this line
of code. What we get in result is the
word true. Meaning that R is telling us
that this, the result of this operation
is true. That is because this operator
here less than is comparing the two
numbers four and five.
Let's do another one, let's check that if
10 is greater than a hundred. Let's run
that and what we can see here is this
line has been copied. It has been
executed and as you can see it's false
which is correct. 10 is not greater than
a hundred. Let's check another one, let's
see if four is equal to five and let's
run this line of code. Once again, we get
false because four is not equal to five.
So these are examples of us using
logical operators, less than, equal or
greater than or equal to. In R, there are
actually quite a few logical operators
and we will be looking at
ten of them. Let's list them out here, so
the first one was is equal to, second one
is not equal to. So that's how you write
it an exclamation mark and an equal sign and also be
careful that in the equal to operator
you have to use the double equation sign
because in some programming language's
single equation is sufficient. Then we've
got the less than, we've got the
greater than, we've got the less than or
equal to, greater than or equal to then
we've got the simple knot and I'll show
you how to use on that one in a second.
Then we've got the or so in some
languages you need the double vertical
line like that, in R you have to be
careful that you use only the single one
because the double one will work but it
has a completely different meaning and
also you've got the single and four and
and then one more which is a function to
check if something is true and it is
true and then you put the variable
inside there. So let's have a look at a
couple more, so let's say I want to
check if four is less than five which we've
already done but I don't want to just
print the result as we've been doing.
I want to store it in a variable, now as
you can see our environment is empty
here so we don't have any variables
because we've been just printing the
results so far. So how about we put this
result into a variable and we'll call this
variable result. We know the assignment
operator, so what you can see is
happening here is we're checking this
and then the result of this operation is
going to be stored in the result
variable. Let's go ahead and run this
line. There we go,
as you can see with this line has been
executed and no value has been printed
out because we haven't asked for that
and what we got is a variable with the
value true which we can now just simply
print out and check its value. There we go, it
is true.
Ok so let's make some more space and now
for curiosity purposes, let's check the
type of result which we know how to do
from the first tutorial if we run this, we
will see that
result is a logical variable which is a
type of variables which we are familiar
with already and make sense right, if
it's a logical operator then the result
of that would be stored in a logical
variable. Alright so now let's say, let's
see how we can use the not operator so
this interesting not one that we saw
over here. Let's say we have a new
variable results2, very creative
Kirill, but anyway result2 and we want
to use the not operator, so we'll say not
true.
So basically, not is an operator which is
applied to anything that goes after it
in this case is the word true. So if we
run that, now we have inside result2, we
have false and you could have you
replaced this result true of any kind of
other operation or variable so for
instance here I could have said is five
greater than one. Run this line and
now if I check result2, you'll see that it's
false. So basically this is true and then
when you put the exclamation mark behind it, before it,
what you get is the opposite of whatever
is here. Whether it's true, it'll
be false or if it's false it will become true.
So there we go, soon result2 we have a
false now.
Ok and finally let's get to these two so
that the or and the and. So let's see
what happens if we say result which we
know is true or result2, so basically
saying one of these has to be true at
least one of these has to be true. So
either this one or this one and let's
see what happens if we're on that. If we're on
that we get true, because we know that
this is true. This is false, but true or
false gives true.
Now if we run a result and results to
now we are requiring but specifying this
operator here. We're requiring that both
of them are true otherwise so in the
only case in which this will return true
is if both of them a true. In our case,
one of them is false. So if we run this, we
get false
and there you go that's how these work.
The last one is is true
all we have to do is type in is true and
then put the value that we want to check
inside here so let's say we want to
check the value of the variable result
right?
Is it true? Yes it is true, the answer to
this question is true.
Alright so that's how logical operators
work and that is how we can use logical
variable to store result of logical
operators. Have a play around with that,
this will come in handy
throughout this whole course whenever
we're working with loops or if
statements or whenever we are checking
matrices or vectors for a certain
criteria so when we're filtering our
data and so on. So definitely gets a
group around that because it you will
need it further down the course and I look
forward to seeing you next time. Until then,
happy coding.