Hello and welcome back to the course in
R programming and today we're talking
about factors, so first things first
I've got an image in front of us and
this image will be like our map. It will
be guiding us through this section so we know
what layer of the visualization process
we're talking about in the current tutorial
and as you can see here, today we're
talking about the data layer so the
very first layer we're going to be
fiddling around with our data set, so
let's dive straight into it. We got R
studio open up here and let's load the
data set so first of all get working
directory, minus correct but for practice sake
let's say set working directory and
let's set it to what we want.
Check it again and remember on windows
it's a bit different.
Alright now we're going to read the data
set and it's going to be read dot CSV
and here we can say movie ratings dot
CSV. If I run that and I look at the
top rows we'll see that we've got the top
rows here. Let's make some space.
Alright great the six columns are here.
Where these dots coming from,
well if we look at the original file
you'll see that there are spaces, the
percentage signs, dollar signs, brackets and
all those symbols cannot be included in
names so R studio replaces them with
and dots.
Ok so we want to fix it up obviously
it's not convenient to work with the
names of columns like that so let's go
ahead and use column names of favorite
function and run that so you've got the
column names here and as we know we can
actually assign value or vector to column
names, so let's type up a vector. We're
going to say the film will keep the
first to the same, film and genre and then
we're going to say critic rating. The
next will be audience rating right and
they're about to budget and let's
remember that budget is in million so
let's put that in here as well and
finally what year around that now and I
look at the top rows you see that now
everything's beautiful.
Let's just check the bottom rows as we
normally do just to make sure that
everything is consistent everything
looks good. It hasn't
been shifted or anything great! Now
let's look at the structure and what do
we see here? Well this is the point where
we start talking about factors you can
see that we've got two columns that are
actually recognizes factors and what
does that mean?
Well it's factor in R, it's very simple
concept it's basically a categorical
variable. It's a way R works with
categorical variables and as you can see
here there are numbers so there are levels
here and there are numbers so what happens
is R looks through your column. Finds
all the different words that there
exists their action adventure, romance,
comedy, thriller, horror and so on and
assigns each word a number. So if we look
at the top, you'll see here a
comedy-adventure, action-adventure and
R has assigned the numbers 3,2,1,2 so
comedy-adventure, action-adventure. We
don't really mind in which way R
assigns these numbers because we're
never going to be using these variables
all this column for numerical operations
anyway it's just for us it's easier to
understand words, for computers it's
easier to understand numbers and that's
how R just just stores these factors for
us and the giveaway here is that it's a
factor in also the word levels, it always
gives away a factor it tells you what
levels exist in that factor.
Alright so that's our interest to factor.
It's pretty simple concept
let's look at summary for movies now.
Let's see what we have there so we've
got film, that's the name of the film. It's
also recognizes the factors. You can see
here but we're not going to be using the
name of the film at all because we're
actually interested in the trends and
averages and you know all these
aggregations of our data rather than
individual film. Genre, yes we're
interested in genre's category and
that's good that it's recognized as a
factor then we've got critic rating so
you can see that the minimum 09 sound
maximum average 47 average for audience
ratings a bit higher so audience seems
to be a bit more forgiving to movies
then budget so you can see that there
was actually a movie that had a bunch of
300 million dollars which is an insane
amount and finally we get to year what
we see here is that R is treating year
just like it is treating these three
columns, so it's saying all the minimum
has got an average. It's got a maximum
but do we really want that? Like let's
ask that question, do we really
year to be a numeric variable? We're
going to be adding them and we're going
to be averaging the model. We're going to
be doing any arithmetic operations here.
Well the answer to that is no. We want
year to be a categorical variable. We
want a year to be just like genre.
So we can group by year, so we can
color things by year, so we can compare
year to another year and so on so we
want a year to be a factor that's what
we're saying and right now we're going
to learn how to do that. How to convert a
non-factor in numeric variable into a
factor numeric variable because the
thing is that R, when it sees words, it
chooses to recognize them as factors
because there's no not many other
options and when these numbers by
defaulted things that you're going to be
using them as numbers but years we're
not going to be using as numbers. So
let's see how we can convert a years in
factor. So the function that we need is
actually called factor, it's a pretty
straightforward name and all you have to
do is put your vector inside the
function and if we run that of course I
need to give tell it which data set we're
using movies year. So if you run that,
you'll see that that is of variable like
our vector and now it has been converted
into factions giveaways here that has
levels. So it's got all these levels and
that's exactly what we want so the last
step would be to take this actual column
in the data set so this is a column in
the data set and assign it the new
vector which is produced from that same
column by factorizing it. So it gets a
bit of a tricky operation but actually
pretty straightforward.
We're just taking the column and well here
we are converting the column into a
factor so here we've got a vector which
is a factor here and we're then
assigning this into that same column
which used to be, so if we run that now
if I look at summary movies you'll see
that movies is no longer a numeric variable. It's
a factor and we can actually prove that
if we go into str for structure movies run
that you can see that it's a factor with
five levels. So there's five different
years in the data set. There we go, that's
how we work with factors. Very very
simple things but it's always important
to at the very start set exactly what you
want from your data. Do you want to
variable to be a factor? Do you wanted to be a
numeric variable or do you want to be
completely something different. So those
are the important things because then
going forward through this section we're
going to be relying on that quite
heavily and I look forward to seeing in
the next tutorial.
Until then, happy coding.