Hello and welcome back to the course in
R programming and today we're going to
solve the challenge where we need to
recreate this beautiful visualization in
front of us. So let's dive straight into
it. Here I've got R studio and the
first thing that we will need to do is
import the data so let's go ahead and do
that.
Import the data, we're going to check our
working directory first thing and here
you can see it's not the one that we're
after so let's set the working directory.
It's going to be users there we go so that
is going to set our working directory let's
run that and now let's check our working
directory again as you can see it is the
correct one now.
Now let's read the data into a new data
frame which we'll call just mov for
movie read dot CSV and what is
our file called, let me copy the name
here. There is the name of our file, so if I
run that and now we've got the data set
prepared. Now we'll just quickly do some
data exploration as we usually do so
we'll check the top rows. Let's make some
space here and let's rerun this line. So as
you can see there's a lot of columns and
that's why it's taking a few even bros
to output all this so here we've got the
columns looks okay
nothing stands out the only thing is the
names of course our it's not the best
but we're actually not going to fix them
up because we're not going to be using
all the columns. We're going to be using
some of the columns and fixing up the names
of all the columns is just going to take a
time that we don't really need to waste.
So let's check the summary so here
you've got your factor columns as we
remember
so all of these words and names and then
we've got some numeric columns as well and now
let's look at the str for mov. There we go
so that's all the columns listed over
here.
Alright so let's quickly decide which
columns we're actually going to need in our
visualization. Here's the visualization
and we can see right away, x is genre,
gross percentage us is the vertical
axis. So let's find them here, so
we've got gross percentage us, that's
going to be a vertical axis
then we've got the genre that will be
the horizontal axis and then one other
aesthetics because that's how you think
about right so is aesthetics are mapped
to they can either be set or they can be
mapped so we're looking for the
aesthetics that are obviously mapped to
some of the variables in our data so
some of the columns. This is mapped, this
is mapped. There we can see that this is
mapped as well right because there's
budget is one of our columns and this is
mapped so the size and the color sizes
budget of the movies color is the studio
that produced the movie so let's have a
look here. The studio
we've gotta column for studio and budget
so that's another column that we are going to need.
So as you can see we only need four columns,
we only need a genre, studio which have
good names budget million that's okay we
can remember to copy it from here
three dots then one dot and cross us. If
you feel like changing the names of the
columns please go ahead and do that you
are now comfortable doing that you have
the correct skills to do that, but I am going
to be a bit lazy. I'm not going to change
the names of the columns. So now we're
going to activate our favorite GG plot 2.
I'm just going to take this first line
here because that's what conventional
standards say or people are just
used to doing this just put it here just
in case person and the person who's
running this code doesn't have the
package installed from the internet and
commented out because we actually do and
then we'll just type in library ggplot2.
So if I run that, there we go we've
activated the package.
Alright so quickly what I wanted to show
you is a bit off topic, so cool insight.
This is not related to challenge but I
thought this was really interesting
about the data set and I wanted to show
it right away. So data movie and then let's
have a look at some aesthetics, we'll say
actually one aesthetic. We just want,  we just
want to visualize day of the week right?
I want to see when our movies released.
So remember previously would use geom
histogram but here you can use histogram
because it's not a continuous variable
so here we are using instead of like a
number in America will be using a factor
variable so we've got day of the week
here.
It's like fridays, saturdays and so on
so instead of histogram for factors or
categorical variables what you need is
geom bar so if you're on that is that
you'll see that most of the movies out
of we were like 600 something movies in
the data set and over 400 of them are
actually we're actually released in the
friday. A few on a Saturday, a few on a
Sunday, quite a few on Thursday to Tuesday
then in the next like over a hundred
were on Wednesday. That is I when I saw
that I was quite fascinated because like
so obviously there are strategies around
this so the studio's know that most
people go to movies on a friday and if
you release the movie on a different
day then it's less likely to make a lot
of revenue and the same thing so
Wednesday's like the midweek release and
the other thing you'll find here is that
there is no Monday. So it's Friday,
Saturday, Sunday, Thursday, Tuesday, Wednesday, there is
only six days so never out of all of
these movies that we have in our data set,
not even one was released on a Monday.
How cool is that?
So they obviously know that if you
release the movie on the Monday it will
be a flop so yeah that was just an
insight that you can get right away from
the data and this kind of brings me to
the other point which also wanted to
make that this data set has a lot of
information in it, like we just look
through it and we said we're going to be
only using four columns but in reality
there's so much more information so I
highly encourage you after you done with
this tutorial on how to solve the
challenges go ahead and explore and try
to set some other challenges for
yourself and see what other things you
can find in this data set and what you
can visualize because obviously we're
going to cover some of the skills we'll learn
in this section but not everything. So we
won't be doing any smoothers, we won't be
creating scatter plots and so on so
maybe explore data set and see what
else you can find.
Ok so what are we going to do now?
Now we're going to move on to the actual
challenge. We're going to proceed, we have
our filters. Why do we need filters?
Well what you'll notice is that in this
final visualization we've only got five
genres and we're going to go to 123456
studios. In the actual
data set, there is much much more so
studio has 36 level so the 36 different
studios and genre has 15 levels so if we
try visualizing the same thing but
without filtering out data set we'll have
a very very cluttered visualization and
so the there's a reason probably why
those filters were applied and I'll give
you a hint. It's because those are the
most popular genres and then the
students that produced most movies but
what concerns us is that we get the
exact same studios and exact same genres
and that also help us practice filtering
data sets a little bit right? So
let's do this, filter data frame number
one or let's say filter number one for
the data frame.
Alright so filt will be our filter and
this is how we're going to create we're
going to move dollar sign genre, equals action
so this is one of the genres in the
visualization here so we got
action-adventure animation comedy and
drama so if we do that that will give us
only movies that are in action in that
genre, so if I do that and then I say
let's say move to is going to be a movie
and then also filt comma nothing
right?
You remember this so if I run that, now I
will have a data set that only has
movies from that specific genre so if I
scroll up here, it's a lot of information
still a lot of information so here you
can see that all of these movies are
action, action, action, action, action,
action all of them. That is not what we
want, we want many different genres
so we want to say action and now we want
to say or right? It's either
action or it is just put some brackets
here, you don't have to put these
brackets but it might just make it a
more comfortable. So or here we're going to
say adventure or it is animation or it
is comedy or it is drama.
So we're using the logical or operator
this vertical line to say one of these
conditions has to be true, either movie
dollar genre equals to action or it
equals to adventure or and so on and
notice I'm using the double equal sign
to check that condition.
Ok so that's the first filter, now we
need a second filter right? Filter number
two how do we filter now? Well now we
need to fix up the studios and we can do
the same exact thing so instead of
movies genre, let's just say movie dollar studio
and then select the correct studios but
I wanted to show you a better way. I want
to show you kind of like a quick preview
of something that we haven't talked
about yet so filt2 this is just a
faster way of doing it is if I say move
dollar sign a studio and then instead of
equals I'll say percentage in percentage
and this operator means that you will
give it a vector of values and then if
this matches any of these values then it
will return a true value so let's say
I'm just going to copy the values that
we're going to be working with basically
I'm just copying these exact words, these
exact names of studios. I'm just copying
them into this vector. So there we go so
we got vector. We're creating a vector
here which contains these studios. The
Buena Vista Studios, Warner Brothers are
probably pronouncing on Fox, Universal,
Sony, Paramount Pictures so basically
this line means if movie studio is in
any of these then it's the truth. So
choose either way you like, you can
achieve accomplish the same thing with
this approach or with this approach. This
one is just a bit shorter. So let's go ahead
and run that and now I want to combine
the two filters right so I've got filt
which is filter 1 which is a true true
true and false and I've got filt 2
right, so another filter so how do I
combine them? How do I say I want a movie
to match this criteria and I want the
movie to match this criteria for it to
participate in our visualization.
Here I have to put and filt 2,
so there we go
and now if I run that, this data set will
actually only have the movies that we
want in the final visualization and
we'll see that as we're creating the
visualization. So there we go, we've only
now come up to the point where we're
going to be practicing our visualization
skills and that's not a problem. That's
okay because we hear we were refreshing
our knowledge and filtering data sets
and that's also important topic and also
works with some logical operators