Hello and welcome back to the course on
R programming and today we're going to
talk about plotting with layers. So I've
got the check mark set on geometry, it's
because we are going to be talking about
geometries and we will see how you can
layer geometries on top of each other
and what plotting with layers actually
means in R and let's dive straight
into it.
Alright so this is where we left off
last time we create beautiful beautiful
visualization and now let's move on to
the next point.
Alright so let's remember what we talked
about here.
Here we said what do we need from here?
Well what did we do? We added this
aesthetics right? We said okay what x
going to be? What's y going to be?
Color, genre and so on and then we said
plus geom point so what's going on with
this plus? What is actually going on? Well
the thing is that in ggplot that the way
its design every time you want to add
layer, you literally have to add it to
the object you're creating and that's
right you are creating an object and I
can prove it too you. So if we just take this
code right and if I say
P for plot and then I copy this code
right and now I run these two lines,
you'll see that nothing changed, nothing
appeared but what did happen is we just
created an object. Let me drag this down
so you can see object P, list of nine so
we haven't talked about list. That is
coming later on the course but if i open
it up now, if I unlock it over here,
you can see that this is a huge object.
It has the data frame so actually
the data is physically copied into
the subject and be careful that that's
important to remember because if you
refresh the data it's then your plot want
refresh until you recreate the object
and we'll we'll talk more about that
further down so you can see that the
data frame is in here then it's got some
layers, scale, add, clone. fine, all these
unknown to us things, oh here's got
color so there are aesthetic so you can
see the world mapping
which we will also talk about in an
upcoming tutorial but that's exactly
what aesthetics do they map variables to
our aesthetic and so there's lots of
things going on here and yep we create
an object and so now from this point on
which we're actually going to work with
layers open plots as they are objects so
what I can do now is I can just type in
p and if I run this line that creates or
visualize that object p of course we
don't see anything because we haven't
what have we done
we haven't said the geometry yet. So let's go
ahead and do that, let's say P + geom
underscore point, around this line you
can see that I've got about the object
and this is the important concept of
GGplot, so I got this object which is the
foundation of my plot, the starting layer
and what it's got is it's got it has the
data and it's got the aesthetics and now on
top of it I can put the layer I want, so
I can say what was this? This was a points or
I can say, I can use the same object and
I can say I want lines this time. It's a
P+, can you guess what it will be? Geom
underscore line correct, so brackets and
now if I run this line, viola I know it
doesn't make sense at all this line so
completely meaningless plot but the
concept stays the same
we just used P so the object and
overlaid it which already contained is
it's supercharged with the data, the
aesthetics so XY color and size and now
we're just overlaying a geometry and as
you can see here the lines
some of them are thinner some of them a
wider and that is because we've got the
size, aesthetic and also the colors are
different and so on. So that is what
plotting with layers is and actually
taking a step even further, we can say
multiple layers right? We can say P +
geom underscore point and then plus
geom underscore line. How about that?
We run that, you'll see that there are
dots and there are lines and of course you
can't really see the dots here because
the lines are on top
them so let's take that and will change
the order. We'll just say P + geom line,
then plus geom point. Around that now you
can see the dots better because they're
on top of the lines and once again even
though this is a completely meaningless
visualization, the concept remains the
same. We're plotting with layers, layer on
top of the layer, on top of the layer and
that's how GGplot works. So go ahead and
try experimenting with that,
see what you can come up with and maybe
change around the P object and just
give it a go and kind of get used to the
concept of layers because we'll be using it
a lot about the section and moreover it
will be very important in your work with
R going forward, and I look forward to
seeing you next time, until then happy coding.