Hello and welcome back to the course in
R programming. Today we're going to finally
get our hands dirty in the basketball
data set and also we're going to learn
about matrix operations while we are at
it.
Alright so let's get started right away,
let's see what kind of tables are at our
disposal. So we can see them over here,
let's type some of them out. So let's
start with the games table for instance,
matrix. The matrix, so here we've got the
players as we've got the years and as we
now know these this is a named matrix so
basically it's got row names and
column names. So if we check row names, get off
games we will see that that's the names
and same for column names we will get
the similar results so let's check games
we see that it does have, that's so
basically it's the matrix right, and now we know
how to access it as well so if we want
to for instance check how many games
Lebron James played in 2012 we would say
games and then instead of trying to
figure out what role Lebron James is
on, 3rd row and then what 1,2,3 the number
of the column. Here we can just simply
say LeBron James and then comma and in
2013 or 2012, whichever year,
let's say we want 2012 we check that we
get our on 276 game so here you can see
that that is correct
Lebron James played 36 games in 2012.
Okay great, so but now matrix operations,
what can we do with matrices?
Well we know that with vectors we can do
the same operations as we would do with
just variables right? So we can add
vectors subtract, multiply we'll explore
all of that in previously in the course
but now can we do the same things of
matrices?
Well yes of course we can, so let's take
another matrix that we have. Let's say
field goals right, field goals so this is
how many field goals each of the players
called in each of the years right? So
what we can do here is let's say we want
to find out how many field goals every
single one of these
players scored for game. One way to do it
would be to go through every player
through every year and divide the number
of goals by the number of years like in
the loop or it could even be a double loop, right?
You would have to loop by the
players and by the years but that's
overly complicated, so mathematicians
and statisticians that was overly
complicated and they decided that in R
we're going to just divide one matrix by
the other just like we can do
with vectors right? So let's do that,
let's say field goals divided by games. Let's
check that out, now this is way too big
of a matrix so let's try it again, let's
make some space and there we go. So now,
you can see how many field goals per
game each player scored if I round this,
if I round this and I don't give any
parameters and if I just do that or
maybe let's say let's give it one number
after the decimal, then here you can see
how many field goals each player
actually scored per game and it's and
the presented nicely than that
and let's say you want to find out Chris
Paul in 2010.
Here you go, he scored on average he's
scored 5.4 goals per game and that is
what this table is about. That is how a
matrix is divided by another matrix in R. it
just simply element by element so as you
can imagine they have to be of the same
size for you to be able to perform this
operation.
Alright, let's have a look at another and
what are the tables do we have? Let's
bring this back and here we've got let's
say minutes played right? Let's find out
how many minutes per game did each
player play. So let's do that, minutes
played divided by games and once again not enough
space and let's round that. Let's round
that to the nearest one decimal point, so
or actually no decimal point for
minutes played, so here we can see how
many minutes on average for every game
each player played in every single one
of these seasons. So you can quickly tell
Derrick Rose 29 minutes for game over
here, then 37, 35 then he was injured, then   31, then 30
and looking at
per game stats is actually quite handy
because if you just look at minutes
played what you'll find is that here
Derrick Rose only played 311 and you
can't compare to the other players or
you can't even compared to other years
because it's a very low number or even
zero here but if you divide by games is or what
we already have here it's much more
comparable so you can now compare
between different players and between
different years because 31,
here you can see that even though he
played only a few games he actually
played more minutes per game than in
2014.
Ok so that's how you divide matrices, the
same thing you can add matrices, you can
subtract them, you can multiply them. In
our case, it's just that the type of data
set we have we're mostly going to be
dividing one matrix by the other and but
nevertheless you can still do all those
other operations with matrices and so
that brings us to the end of today's
tutorial. In the next tutorial we'll find
out how to actually visualize these
results that we're getting, it will be a
fun tutorial. We'll start building charts
and graphs and for now what I would like
to do is to invite you to explore these
other matrices that you have here and
perhaps perform some other operations
like try to calculate the field goaled
attempts per game or another good one
would be trying to calculate the field
goals per field goal attempt and that will
give you the accuracy of each player so
you will know how many of the shots that
they actually make and up in the basket.
Okay that brings us to the end. On that
note, I will see you in the next tutorial.
Until then, happy coding.