Hello and welcome back to the course on
R programming and today we're finally
going to talk about visualization. We're
going to create some charts and graphs
and in particular we're talking about the
matplot function, so let me tight type out
the name of function here - matplot and
let me give you a quick overview of this
function. So we'll start by bringing up
the help and here you'll see that this
function is designed to plug columns of
matrices now we bear in mind we won't be
using this function a lot a lot we'll
just use it in this section and then
there'll be more powerful tools that we'll
learn but for now this function will do.
So what does it do?
Matplot takes him quite a lot of
parameters so don't get scared,
don't get put off by all these
parameters. We will go through the ones
that we need and I'll show you the
values that we will need to input. So XY
are vectors and matrices of data for
plotting and the right number of rows
should match, its if so I'm not going to read
through all of this. Basically you supply
some data for these parameters and
then, type is what kind of plot you want.
If you want a line, you want dots, you want
characters and so on. So then we won't be
using these parameters PCH is the
character string or vector, so what kind
of if you're plotting points then what
kind of images you want in those points?
You want dots? do you want X's? do you want
triangles? You want two squares then col
is for color and that is you need to
supply a vector of colors and that's
pretty much all we will need. We won't be
delving into the rest of these
parameters. So let's go ahead and check
this out and practice, so Matplot right?
We'll start off by plotting a simple
matrix, we'll just choose field goals for
instance. We want to visualize how the
players have been scoring field goals of
attempt. Now the important thing to note
here is that we can just apply field
goals because that would be incorrect.
The matplot function plots columns of matrix
one by one. So what it will plot
is if we look here, so let's just
run field goals, right? Field goals, if we
run this table, what the functional plot
is it will plot each column but we want
to put is we want to plot each row
right? We want to plot this player as one
color. This player as another color. This
player as another color and so on. We want to
see how the players have been
progressing through their career. So how
do we get that? How do we change this
table to be able to put it into this
function properly?
Well we need to transpose it and if
you're not familiar with the operation,
mathematical operation of transposing,
That's ok, that's totally fine,
what transposing means is it basically
means flipping this table and changing
the rows into the columns and the
columns into the rows. There you go, it's
as simple as that.
A very complicated word for a very
simple thing and how do you transpose the
table in R? It's very easy. You just
type in T. That's the name of the
function just T and then you type in
you put your color matrix into the
function that's all,
so if I run this now, let me make some
more space here and let's rerun this one
and if I run this now you can see that
the table has been transposed. So here's
our field goal's table and this is our
transposed field goals table. So you
can see that now the columns represent
the players and that's exactly what we
want for the matplot function. So just be
careful of that whenever using the matplot
function. Check if the columns
are actually what you want to plot or if
that's not the case, if you want to plot
the rows then you need to transpose your
table.
Alright so there we go, we've supplied
the data now matplot knows what to plot
right? So pretty much we could run it
right now, so let's make some room here
and let's run it for the first time. If
we run the function, you can see that
something has been plotted. It's not
exactly what we want right?
It's just numbers, there is already some
like trends but let's make this look
nice right? That's what we're going to do.
We're going to select the type and type
is going to be B, so once again you
don't need to know all of these off by
heart
because one is you get better as you
practice R, two we won't be using matplot
a lot. So let's just select type B which
will be for these characters that we're
going to select and the characters or
the pictures are going to be 15 to 18. So
just type in these parameters and the
last thing is color, so we need a vector
of colors and the colors we're going to use
are going to be one to four and six. So
if I run this now, you can see it's much
better right? So I've got better colors,
I've got a much more logical plot the
only thing I don't have is a legend. I
don't know which player is which color
here and which shape so there's actually
two black colors, two blue colors which
players who here. So to add a legend, we
can simply add a legend here by calling
the legend function so this is us using
the matplot function and legend function which
are built into R to build a chart and
the legend is going to go on top of the
existing chart you just created, so to
build a legend, very simple we have to
say where we want the legend, bottom left
then after that we want to say in set.
That's how far it will be moved away
from the bottom left and a corners of
the chart then we want a legend
what is the legend going to actually
represent? It's going to represent the
players.
Why what does players mean in this case?
Players is that vector which you can see
here with the player names because we
know that this vector was actually used
to create the columns, the rows of the
matrix so we know that this these rows
are actually stored in this vector
players so let's go ahead and actually
use that vector and then we're going to
use colors so we're going to use exactly
the same colors, let's just copy that.
So we want the cat colors to match and
then we want to use these pictures and
last we want horizontal equals false so
we want a vertical legend. So quite a lot
of parameters here, in your own free time
you can explore
or using the question mark, the legend function but
in short this is what we're going to use
basically you can see that we're using
the same colors and the same symbols for
our legend as for the chart and the
important thing to note here is that
this one, that's why I'm saying
we're not going to use a lot of this
function and the this type of approach
to visualizing a lot because here legend
is absolutely separate to matplot. It's
actually just going to happen to appear
on the same chart once we run this line,
but in reality there are two separate
objects and if you by accident
give the the wrong colors here, if you
supply their own color different colors
here then your legend will be misleading
you because it will be telling you the
wrong colors for the wrong players so
it's a you have to be very careful when
you supply the symbols and the colors
and also the data so here players
has to be associated with the players
used in the data. It's just that our
data is pretty clean and nicely
formatted so we're lucky that way. We can
do this, but for more complex situations
they are much more powerful tools which
will explore further in the course and
then you look back on today's tutorial
and you'll think wow. That was very very
inconvenient. Anyway, so let's run this
legend function and as you can see now
we have a legend on our chart. o Kobe
Bryant is that color, that's a Joe Johnson
over there. So now you can explore how
many field goals each one of these
players has scored right? Throughout
their career, you can see clearly that
Derrick Rose is this blue color here
because he didn't score any goals in
this season he was injured. I am not
picking on Derrick Rose. I think he's a
great player.
It's just a great example for our
data set to verify that we are
visualizing what we want because we
already know that Derrick Rose wasn't
playing in that season and so here ya
you can visualize the data. You can
see the trend, so you can see that kind
of general you going down but once again
just visualizing field goals isn't very
accurate because the players play
different games and this chart doesn't
reflect injuries.
So I mean like injuries are not taken into
account. The best way to take into
account injuries is if you divide by the
number of games, for instance. Also like
if you normalize your data so in this
case we're dividing by the number of
games and that's that's how just R
transpose should divide here. We divide
by the number of games and we plot this
now.
Now you can see the actual picture right?
So here you can see what has been going
on and the legend is the same. So you
can see which players actually scored
the most field goals per game they play.
Ok so that's how you visualize. Let's
just visualize one more and then I will
let you explore the data and let your
imagination run free.
Alright, so let's say we want to
visualize field goals divided by field goal
attempts. That's going to be an
interesting one because that is the
accuracy that's what we talked about at
the end of last tutorial. So if we divide
field goals by field goal attempts and
we visualize that you will see that we
are now looking at the accuracy that
these players have, so can you see this
line up at the top? That is the most
accurate player. Who is that? It's Dwight
Howard, Dwight Dwight Howard sorry Dwight
Howard is the most accurate player his
accuracy is like way above and it's
pretty consistent in the past years and
some players their accuracy is up and
down so Kobe Bryant for instances,
his accuracy has been dropping. Who else do we
have here? We've got LeBron James, but
his accuracy drop so sometimes the
accuracy drop can be due to injury as
well if they had an injury and then they
did come back to play and then for
instance they could still be not
performing to their best.
Alright so there's a couple of
visualizations and now you've got this
template, I invite you to explore this
data set and see what you can do and let
me just remind you what tables we have,
we've got field goal attempts, field
goals, games, minutes played, points, salary,
so you could look at things like, uhmm
let me give you a couple ideas. You can
look at Point a salary for point so how
many dollars per point to do they get
paid? Points per game?
You could look at minutes of points
points per minutes played, so how many
points do they score on average per
minute of their games and so on. But
don't get too carried away, just have a
look at a couple and then come back to
the next tutorial because we will be
moving on and we'll be continuing on
working with his data set
throughout this section so sooner or
later we'll come back and we'll
visualize some more and yeah we'll
explore the data together as well.
And I look forward to seeing in the next
tutorial.
Until then happy coding.