Hello and welcome back to the course in Python programming is super excited to get the section started
and we are going to kick off things with a list what is a list in Python.
So we've already touched on lists before here and there is going to be a very quick tutorial very easy
solidification of some of the things you've already seen about lists.
So let's dive straight into it.
So what is a lesson Python the best way to imagine a list and the way kind of I think about it is it's
a horizontal bookshelf with elements inside it.
So for instance let's say we have a list of some numbers in it so there's 50 30 400 11:7 24 681 and
so on.
So basically like a horizontal bookshelf and all of these elements inside of the list.
Now the thing about lists is that they're kind of like arrows in other programming languages so if you
studied C or C++ or other languages like that then you would be familiar with the concept of Aries and
listen like areas but also in Python they are areas which are a separate thing and we'll talk more about
them there.
But for now you can imagine illest as an essential aere or if you studied our programming then a list
is kind of like a vector.
But once again there are certain specifics because a list is a ordered sequence of elements or ordered
set of elements.
They are all always enumerated so there is an element with number 0 element from a 1 2 3 4 5 and so
on.
So here we've got 10 elements in the list in total.
But because the numeration starts at zero it goes all the way only up to 9 and not up to 10 so that's
an important thing to remember especially if you're coming from are because there are vectors they are
enumerated starting from one.
In other program languages areas usually are numerate from 0 so if you're coming from there that's that's
ok you'll you'll get she said or have Python is your first programming language then not a warrior at
all just this is something to keep in mind that Numeration of lists starts with zero.
So that's an example of a basic lesson python.
A great thing about lists and Python is that you can have mixed data types.
So for instance in our in a victory can only have elements of one specific type.
So once you select the type it has to stay that in Python you can have a mix so here's two strings.
A And hey then you've got a number so that's an integer.
Then you've got logical value you've got a floating point value to another string and then you've got
another integer.
And once again everything is enumerated as 0 1 2 3 4 5 6.
And that's pretty much it's about lists and the indexation is very useful because that's how we will
access elements and you'll see that in the upcoming tutorials.
That's what it's there for so that we know like the lists is the storage medium for information for
data and then to access this data.
We're going to be using the indexation So if we want out of this list to extract the value of true we'll
go and ask for this or so for the value of the index of number three.
Or if you want to extract twenty seven point five we'll ask for the value of the index of Number Four
and you'll see all that an upcoming tutorial can't wait to see you there.
Until next time happy coding
.