Hello.
Welcome back to the course of programming.
And today we're going to finally get to analyze the NBA data.
I hope you're pretty excited about today's tutorial and to start off what we're going to do is we're
going to have a look at what we created last time because that is going to help us a lot during today's
tutorial.
And last time we created our own very first function.
This function is called My plot.
It requires two parameters data and rose.
The first parameter is compulsory makes sense because our function can operate without any data and
Rose isn't compulsory because it has a default value so if you don't supply the rows you want to visualize
it will just visualize all of the values.
Here you can see what this function does it takes any data that you supply and it replaces it over here
and the rows that you supply get replaced here.
And so here I've got an example I'm going to plot the games of the top 10 page NBA players for the past
10 years just by running this one line.
And as you can see there we go.
That's the plot.
So now what we're going to do is we're going to move on to analyzing and driving insight and I'm going
to go to this new tab so I've prepared some code here already and I invite you to follow along so as
we run these lines just code them up.
I decided not to write them up one by one because we're kind of moving now from the stage where we're
learning all these things that we need for this analysis to actually performing the analysis.
So the focus today is going to be on analytics and on data science and you know doing analysis in smart
thought through way.
So that's what we're going to be talking about most of the day today.
So let's get started.
My plot salary what are we going to plot here.
First thing that I was interested to see was how have the salaries of these players been changing so
how did they actually get here to being the top ten paid players.
As you can see Kobe Bryant was always quite up there and his salary has been going up until the previous
season 2014 2015.
And his record was over 30 million dollars for a one year of playing.
And then here we've got the rest so you can see that Joe Johnson started quite above.
But then the rest caught up with him and now they're all sitting over here.
So that's how the salaries have been changing.
Now let's applaud how much they get paid per game.
So salary divide by game and this is where I first ran into this conundrum that we've got some anomalies
here what happened here.
So why is is this Kobe Bryant and Derrick Rose so why are they getting paid so much per game as we saw
previously.
Their salaries are comparable to the others.
Well the reason here is that both of these players were actually injured in that 2013 14th season.
They didn't play that many games so their salary pre-game is quite high.
And same thing salary for field goals.
So what we could do from a daughter and a league's point of view we could remove these anomalies then
continue for analysis.
However digging further into the Basketball daughter I found that these players put so much effort into
their game that they get injured quite a lot so we would see discrepancies like this throughout the
whole dataset and moreover where we wouldn't see them there would be still skewing 0.04 us snowing and
so therefore visualizing salary and in games to six together might not be the best option.
The reason for that is that salary is not affected by injuries whereas in game statistics are.
So the players get paid regardless of whether they're playing or not.
They have contracts.
But there are statistics such as games played field goals and so on they do get affected so from an
analytical point of view unless we can somehow exclude those effect of injuries we shouldn't visualize
salaries and in game statistics together.
So let's go and look at the in-game metrics.
Let's see what the minutes played and what do we see here.
Well here we see how many minutes each of the players played in the past 10 years.
OK.
And let's plot points.
So what we see here is another thing like we know that Derrick Rose is for instance a great player and
he was MVP in 2010 11 season.
But here we can see that the points that he brought to his team dropped over here.
And so Same with Kobe Bryant.
But the reason for that is that both these players were injured over here.
So once again we can see that injuries are affecting our vessels.
So how do we fix that.
How to approach it as a scientist and how do we take injuries out of the equation.
Well we know that injuries affect all in game statistics.
So if you don't attend a game you're injured you don't attend the game but you also don't score goals
.
So what we can do is we can normalize in-game metrics by in-game metrics.
That's what I have here.
So if we take field goals and divide them per game rather than just plodding field goals but by themselves
if we plot that then you will see that.
Now we can actually compare them so even though some players were injured some players were not your
device your calculator how many goals is scored per game so actually per game that they're tender.
No injuries do sometimes affect and quite often affect players even when they're playing.
But already we're extracting or we're mitigating some of that effects that injuries have on our vessels
.
And so now you can go ahead and compare their goals per game that players score and as you can see back
in the day Kobe Bryant had a crazy amount of 13 per game and now it's quite is dropped quite a lot.
And right now in the lead we've got Libran LeBron James.
We're about just over nine goals per game on average.
That's on points.
That's actually goals.
OK.
And now let's visualize another normalized metric let's visualize field goals per field goal attempts
.
I think that one will be pretty interesting so if we look at that this is basically the accuracy of
the play.
So how many goals a day make divided by that how many attempts did they make.
So here you can see right away that Dwight Howard is up there up at the top and way above all other
players in terms of accuracy and he is the fifth highest paid player in the NBA currently.
So what does that mean.
Well that means that basically out of the balls that he throws at the net about 60 percent nearly 6
percent actually and in a goal.
So let's see how he's going in terms of actual attempts so we know that his attempts convert very well
but how many attempts per game does he have.
Let's look at this visualization.
Here we see that Dwight Howard is actually at the very bottom.
So he was at the top for conversion of or successful attempts.
Now he's at the bottom for the actual number of attempts per game and therefore it makes sense that
he doesn't actually score that many points per game even though that his accuracy is quite high because
he makes a few attempts.
He doesn't score that many points.
So that's an inside we could drive right away and probably basketball.
People have a lot of knowledge about basketball could comment on this and could say why exactly he doesn't
make that many attempts.
Maybe he's on the court in a position that is not designed to make that many attempt.
Or maybe it's not the case maybe he can start making more tense and then because his accuracy is so
high maybe he'll start scoring more goals.
So that's something to look into that requires more as it's called domain knowledge or knowledge of
basketball.
Now we're going to move on to some more interesting observations.
Let's say minutes played per game.
So I thought this was quite interesting.
You can see that the minutes played per game for these top ten players has been dropping overall so
you can see the trend here it's going down and I couldn't explain that I can explain why so I understand
if it was for one or two players but overall these players seemed to play less minutes per game on average
.
As we move from earlier years in their career to later years and that would be interesting to find out
why.
At the same time if you plot the games you can see that they haven't the number of games that they've
been playing is actually pretty consistent.
Not that they're playing more games and therefore they're playing less minutes.
They're playing pretty much the same number of games but they're playing less minutes per game so that's
that's an interesting one.
OK so time is valuable since they're less on the court less minutes per game on the court.
There are times available let's see who uses that time most efficiently so who scores the most field
goals per minute played.
Let's run that one.
And here we can see that it's actually Kevin Durant.
He is quite young.
When I was gathering this data I noticed that he joined the NBA quite recently.
A coach like relatively recently.
So he's young and you can see that his goals for minutes played have been increasing with time so I've
seen a few articles calling him the rising star.
So we'll see how it goes.
But so far the data does confirm that he's using his time on the court.
Valuably and that's what we're seeing.
And also we see in kind of two groups we've seen some players are here and we've seen some players over
here so players that fall into this group.
Kevin Durant Dwayne Wade cover Melo Anthony and LeBron James.
Very interesting to see this type of grouping.
And finally one more interesting disposition that I found was points divided by field goals so it's
kind of player style.
So in baseball you can score a two point goal or he can score a three point goal.
And also you'll see that some of the the averages here actually above three points.
That's because our field goals are all points Dadda includes both goals field goals and also includes
the free shots that they get.
So we would need to subtract the free shot points from points to exclude that effect but unfortunately
we don't have that data in in our data set so it's just Beruf this we can still see that player playing
style is changing with time so a good example that jumps out right away is Kevin Durant you can see
that first.
He used to score less points per field goal so he was going for the two point shots more and then he
started scoring more points.
So that means he was started to go for more for three point shots or he was getting more free throws
.
And then it dropped and then went up.
So it's interesting to see how some of the players have a change in style like that or Kobe Bryant for
instance like the average dropped and then it started going up again or what's another one.
Here we can see Chris Bosh.
You can see that his average was dropping consistently and then started growing.
So it'd be interesting to see what is the cause of these changes are that there trainers telling them
to change the style or other trends in the basketball the sport that change over time and things like
that it would be interesting to observe that.
OK so there we go that's some analysis of the stats that we have and what you can do is you can perform
a take a similar approach and explore some other things because there's so many things that we haven't
explored yet here you can just try and normalize different matrices by different matrices and plot some
of these things and find some insights of your own and see what you're able to discover.
I hope you found this article interesting and exciting.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy coding
.