Hello.
Welcome back to the course in Python programming I hope you enjoyed the previous couple of tutorials
.
We definitely looked at some very interesting styling techniques for dashboards.
We went from a dashboard that looked like this.
First of all we created a dashboard that looked like this which is great step already.
And then we moved on to a dashboard that looks like this so we learn how to style our dashboards.
And it's definitely a very powerful skill to have with styling and with visualization.
Just like with any concept in Python you can keep going on and on and on forever you can always learn
new things along the way and that's kind of the idea behind this course that we cover all of the fundamentals
all of the absolutely necessary techniques.
And then when you need something you'll be able to quickly learn it adapt it on the fly pick it up from
it.
In practice while you are applying those techniques so it's it's always a good idea to be open minded
to look hard for new techniques.
And having said that I would still like to throw in a few more techniques just so that you are even
more comfortable with visualizations.
So as mentioned we can keep going forever with the different types of turkeys but it would still be
beneficial to cover off I think that I would be very happy if you pick these couple of techniques germane
to kill yourself from this course and took them away with you because it will save you some time searching
for them in the future.
So that's hence that's why we have this tutorial another tutorial on missiles.
All right so what are we going to be talking about.
Well today we're going to be talking about modifying some thematic of that realization and in fact we
are going to not going to keep working with this dashboard any more we'll just go back to one of the
tools that we had previously because it doesn't really matter which one we take as an example.
We're going to work on this one so this is a powerful resolution but at the same time it can be visually
improved so it can look much better than it is than it looks now and that's what we're going to work
on so we're going to work on adding a title we're going to work on changing the Xs font size adding
an Access title here Access title here working with the legend making it more visible changing the color
so all those things are going to discuss today and those are all kind of semantical edits so we already
have the data on this chart is really telling us a story but at the same time if we want to include
a chart like this in the final report then it definitely should look better and sooner or later if you're
going to be working fine and you'll find yourself needing to find ways of changing these things that
we talked about them takes the labels and titles of the chart so it's just better to put all of it in
this one tutorial so that you can save some time.
So we're excited about that.
Let's get started so I'm going to actually copy this whole chart and I'm going to put it over here.
So first let's make this a marker and then let's zoom in of course to 200.
And here will say this is going to be thematic edits.
There you go.
So you get a second.
There it is.
So there's our chart.
What can we do about it.
How can we improve its position.
So obviously we're not going to be working with this.
This is the way we create the chart.
And that's a bit of coding exercise that we had.
How can we now improve this chart itself.
So first of all where we can start with is the style of the grid.
So if I say yes and has not said underscore style and don't forget that actually let me and let me type
this out first so let's say we want dark and we run that so you can see that even though we're not using
seaborne to create this char we're using just the Pipelet package and the histogram function from there
.
Seaborn is still affecting the chart so that is why sometimes I say that seaborne is an add on on top
of pipelined because it even affects styles of non-C born exaltations.
So in this case what we actually want is we want white grid.
All right.
That just makes it look neater and cleaner.
The next thing that we would like to do is to change the size of this chart and I want to show you a
very useful hack here.
There is a convenient way of changing charts sizes which can be applicable to many many different charts
or many different graphs that you might be creating.
So we really learned that you can sometimes you can specify certain parameter inside the function to
change the size but the key is to actually to create a subplots like we have here.
But we've only one item.
So what we do is would say it say instead of a fig and then don't say X equals fealty to subplots and
we won't specify any parameters of what that will do is it'll create a subplot with one just the one
item so I'm just going to delete this for a second.
If I run this you'll see that we've got the subplots So they've got a plot of one subplot in it.
And now as you remember if we just plot something it'll always go into the last box or the last space
in the subplots like we had previously when we didn't specify where something should go.
It would always go in the last box or here.
So here if we just plot this now it will go into that subplot.
So even though you might not notice it here this chart has been created inside this figure which consists
of one subplot.
I know it's a bit tricky but.
And so why are we doing this what's the whole point of this Carol.
Well that is because now we can easily change the size of this figure because we know how to deal with
them so we can just say fig Daut and say sets.
So in this case we'll set the size in inches so set size inches.
And here you can specify how many inches.
So for instance if you specify eleven point seven and eight point two twenty seven that's going to be
the size of a four paper.
So if you're on this you'll see that we've changed the size you can definitely make it even larger than
natural and smaller.
For us it's already pretty large so in here I'm actually going to get rid of the header and the toolbar
so we have some more space so you can see it.
Now we're controlling the size of a weasel zation by controlling the size of the figure of subplots
.
It's a pretty handy trick to do it that way.
All right so there is opposition.
Now what else can we do it how can we improve it.
Well first thing that pops to mind is that we don't have a title we don't have a title of this nation
.
We don't know what like we know what it's talking about.
But other people that might be looking at it might not have the same information.
So it's a good idea to add a title to a title what we're going to do is so after we've done the subplots
and create the plot what we're going to say is we're just going to say BLT Daut title and here we're
going to give it to Tunnell movie budget distribution so far and that you'll see that the tail appears
here of course is a very small title so let's increase the size here let's say coma and he'll say font
size equals 35.
And by the way for a shift tab you'll you'll notice that the arguments are not listed here because we
are right now parsing these keyword arguments and Pipelet or the function title is able to recognize
them along the way.
So if you encounter a situation where you need to change something about a chart and you don't know
what the argument is the best way to go about it is just look it up just Google.
How do you change the font size of the pipeful a title or how do you add a Pipelet title.
Or if you are looking for more parameters like for instance we're going to change the color of the title
Soehardi to that.
So if you google those things and then after a couple of times you'll get used to them and you'll remember
what the parameter names are and most of the time they're pretty intuitive.
So if I say font size 5 around that you'll see that there it is there's my font size 35.
And what else can I add here I can add things like color that say dark blue.
And then I can add a font name so use things like Times New Roman Aeriel and going to console.
So let's run that.
There you go you can see that that's changed to different font name different color.
So those might be useful for your styling of your charts.
What else can we change about this chart.
Well now that we're talking about titles How about we add labels to the x axis and the y axis and is
done very in a simple matter in a very simple matter.
So same thing Piazzi.
And then you just say white label and then you pass on the parameter.
So while labels are going to be number because this is a distribution white label is going to be a number
of movies and we're going to say font size right away equals 25 and that's a color he calls a red number
of movies.
And now these are the same thing for the X label.
But this time will say X label equals budget font size 25 color let's say green because money is green
.
So there you go.
So you've got number of movies we've got budget.
And now what we want to do is we want to change the size of the font size of these takes right so because
they're quite small right now.
If we increase the size of these ticks then they will definitely be more visible.
They'll be they'll look better so let's do that will say peel T Dot X ticks or say what sort of white
ticks white ticks.
And here we want to say font size equals 20.
And same thing for X-Tex All right so there you go.
Mistake it should be an S not an R.
As you can see the font size has increased.
And you can look up the function more information on Fante on the X ticks and y ticks.
What it can do is you can actually set the ticks itself when going to do that now.
But you can if you research a bit more about these functions and you can actually set the ticks that
you want.
You can change them quite a lot of flexibility that by Plaut provides two.
All right so there we go that's a couple of those actions.
Now what else do we see about this plot.
So if I zoom out what is wrong with this plot right now.
What can we further improve.
Well obviously the legend it's it's quite small.
Let's see if we can increase the size of the legend How would we do that.
How would we go about changing the size or some parameters of the legend.
Well there's another parameter that we have.
So we really are calling the pill teed up a legend function.
All we have to do is now add some parameters into it to monophyly.
So first thing we're going to do is modify the size and the sizes modify using the phone crowd and so
broad equals.
And then you pass the keyword argument size call on 20 for instance that only increase the size of a
legend.
You can see it's now very very visible.
So there's just something that you need to kind of remember that that's how you change the size of a
legend for people.
Then what we want to do as well is we want to change some things about legends for instance it really
looks good.
But at the same time like it's not as steadily pleasing that you can see these this grid going through
the ledge and so let's try to fix that up.
Let's see if we can add the background to the legend and let's start with the parameter which will say
which is called frame or let's say let's press shift tab.
All right so let's have a look through this as you can see it is just args and keyword arguments which
are going to go through them and find the actual arguments that we were interested in.
So we've got this here frame on fancy box shadow frame Alfar those parameters that we want to check
.
So let's see what what they do.
Let's start with frame on equals.
True.
So as you can see frame one has added a frame.
Wonderful.
What else can we do here.
Then we can say fancy walks equals true that will round the edges of all criminals.
Now it's a square frame of we say fancy box.
It'll have a bit rounded edges.
That's considered fancy.
That's awesome.
Then we're going to do now the one is a good one the shadow equals true.
So now drops the shadows so you can see it much better.
And another one.
So frame Alpher Let's put that in.
So it shouldn't really change much because it is not transparent now.
If you want to make it transparent you can try 0.5 something like that.
It's semitransparent.
But personally I don't like it.
It becomes kind of grayish So just from Alpha One is good.
It's also good to keep that in mind because some other packages might might change your frame modified
so it might make a transparent.
So then if you want to regain control of that you can just use for it all.
All right so there it is our charge if I zoom out.
Now let's have a look at it.
What it looks like.
So as you can see there is a final version of the chart and it looks much better than what we had previously
.
And one more final thing that you might want to do is you might want to go to the ultimate HST.
And here you might want to specify the color suits say color equals.
But here you'll need to post a list of colors because we have seven colors so you need to pass a list
of callers you need to say something like red then salmon blue and so on.
So you need to parse a list of colors because it's expecting seven different colors so if you want to
do that go ahead and do that and have a look at how you can add some additional control or some extra
control.
But other than that our chart is finalized this is a chart that you could include in our report.
Of course you wouldn't use green red and blue for your titles you'd make them more subtle but at the
same time this is a proof of concept that we can control our chars and we can control that they're all
visible that the text isn't very tiny.
So there we go.
Hopefully that's going to be useful to you and that'll save you some time.
You don't have to research all these things separately.
You can always come back to this tutorial when you need to edit a chart and just review how it's done
.
And that brings us to the end for today.
I look forward to see you next time.
Until then happy coding
.