Hello.
Welcome back to the course and by the programming to day now that we've loaded the data set into Python
we're going to learn how to explore how to perform that initial exploration of your data set in Python
.
And the first thing I'd like to do is to get rid of the top bits because we're going to need some space
This is going to be quite a heavy section on in terms of how much we're going to be creating So let's
remove the header or before we move the head and let's give this file a name so we'll call it working
.
Let's just call doorframes reframes And now we can remove the header or we can remove the toolbar and
yourself some space.
All right so today we're talking about exploring your data.
All right enter Number one what we already know is how to bring up the full data.
Well except for some parts that are going to be omitted that are going to be in the middle usually.
So there we go.
So that's the full data frame we can explore it like that.
And we got some information on them.
All right.
So that's a good start.
Now how what are the other ways we can get some information very quickly about.
While it's looking up to the Mattew is number of rows.
Let's have a look.
Len stats so stats is our daughter.
And we're going to apply the land function to stats so for on that you get for one ninety five rows
which is correct.
We do have 185 rows.
Important thing about the function even though it's a tiny little function.
It's a tiny little call over here so it doesn't look like anything significant but in reality it's a
very important skill to know and very important habit to have to check your land so your daughter said
so the size and number of rows and also know when you need to check it when you should think about it
.
Because from a size perspective it can be very very telling very important to do.
And why is that.
Well back when I worked in consulting we had to do it constantly and we were importing daughter sets
into sequel most of the time for analysis.
But every time we would import data we would always check the size or the number of rows.
And in fact we would actually put in a comment in the code or would say 195 rows imported.
Why is that.
Well that is for traceability so that later on you can always go back and check.
Was this number actually equivalent to the number that was supplied by the client that was supplied
in the file.
Did anything happen during the import.
Maybe something didn't get imported maybe some rules were corrupt maybe something was wrong.
So for audit ability and traceability purposes we would always specify this value and it's a good idea
to check especially if you have like large files that you're importing.
And if you have information on how many rows they're supposed to be after they import just quickly around
this line and check how many rows were actually imported and if it's all good then you know you're safe
in that sense you know that you've done the check and you can proceed with your analysis.
But if you find something is wrong then there'll be a red flag and you'll be able to fix it up quickly
rather than finding out about it at the end of your analysis.
All right.
So number three how do we do something with the column.
So one thing we can do with the columns that we can see the columns right.
Let's go back up and let's run the line here we're going to say stats.
Very simple Daut columns for on that.
You'll see the actual columns that we have.
We have country named country code birthrates for small loads of lower case users Internet users income
group.
So in this case it's kind of obvious because we already have.
When you look at the data.
We already have the calls you can see them here but sometimes you get doorframes or Excel files history
files.
So I've worked with files definitely over 20 columns sometimes over 50 and it depends on the structure
of your data set.
So sometimes they can be lots and lots of columns.
So in order to bring them up in a very nice neat fashion you could just call stat start Kolb's.
And another way to quickly college McCollum's just use the end function.
So let's quickly say for a number of columns and say stats data columns.
So basically passing this value into this object into here.
So let's run this.
You'll see that we have five columns.
Again here it is very easy to tell.
Sometimes they can be a lot of columns.
So you will need to check like that.
But if you do need to check.
All right now we're going to move onto the fun stuff top Rose.
How do we see the top rows of adults.
Because we notice that it's quite cumbersome when we print out the whole Holder said something the most
the time you don't need to see the whole dataset you just need to get a feel for it.
So in that case you just do stats head and here remember the brackets.
So in case of columns you don't need the brackets right for heads you need the brackets because if you're
on the brackets you would get a jibberish result.
So there's our stats head what it does is it prints out the top five rolls remember numeration starts
from zero so it goes zero to four to five rows.
And the other thing you can do is you can actually say stats head.
And you can specify and equals six right.
So is the parameter X-Fi specify here 6 or any other number.
Ill give get that many rows and by the way this functionality is the same as the head function.
In our IT ACTUALLY returns you six every time just looks different.
So in that case headcount is a function here.
It's a method inside the stats object so this function our method is carried around with this object
so you can always call it from inside the object.
That's the difference between object oriented programming and vectorize program which is our.
And other types of programming as well.
All right.
So that's a very useful function.
You'll see us using it all the time we'll be using it pretty much every single tutorial.
Most of the generals in the section we're going to be using this function so we can see what's going
on in our data center.
All right.
Number six you guessed it bottom morose stat's tail run that's there you go that's the bottom five.
Because you can see 1 9 1 9 2 2 1 4.
Or you can do bottom six or however many you like.
So that's that's tell a story I always tell him in this in this case likely head and tail are the same
as have the same names as in are.
So if you've done it's going to be easy to remember if you haven't and this is something I struggled
with Originally when I came from sequel to are that in sequel they're called top and bottom instead
of head and tail so hard you remember them.
Well just think of a fox.
A Fox has a head and a tail and whole Fox is a random animal to think of but whenever you're going to
be wondering you're going to remember Kiril said Fox aitches which is orange which is like a random
animal to say you're going remember that a fox has a head and a tail.
And that way you'll be you'll remember which functions you need to call.
But with time especially if you finish this section of the course you're going to be so used to typing
the names of these functions that you won't even need to remember that story.
So we've done that.
Let's have a look at a couple more.
So we've got a few more left.
Number seven we've got to get some information on the columns.
So how do we do this.
Well they're easy stats to add info.
So sure on this you will see some information.
So it's got a columns total five columns actually 195 entries so tells us some quite some years.
A lot of useful information and here tells you OK Object object floats 64 for 64 object.
Basically all floats 64 means a number of decimal points.
Object is in this case because they're strings.
It's identifying them as just objects.
What we need to know is that this is just going to come in here.
This is like the str function in our.
So not exactly the same right there.
Our function gives you a bit more information and can tell you about categorical variables which are
cold factors.
So in our I would say that this function is a bit more powerful but nevertheless this one still gives
you quite a bit of information.
The other function that we want to know is get stats on the columns so that information is going to
be stats and are going to say stats describe the function we need is describe your that and what you'll
get is count means standard deviation minimum first quarter second quarter third quarter and maximum
for all of the columns which have numeric data in them and we only have 2 of those.
So therefore we have two results here.
And this is quite a powerful thing.
It is similar to.
Can you guess it.
It is like summary the summary function in our scroll back up like this was is our function.
So the summary function in our.
And also if you want to maybe change it around a bit.
So this is like the names of the columns are on the top.
Then it goes downwards if you want to transpose it.
Very easy done.
So stats describe and then just press dot this is the object that we got right.
This is the new the result and here we're going to say transpose Also in with brackets and that way
you transpose the Matrix might be easier to read this way sometimes.
In this case I think it's easier to like this because we only have two of these columns and now they're
rows and now you can just read it very simply like that and supreme from top to bottom.
All right so that is how we get information on our daughter said some basic information.
Let's quickly recap what we learned.
We learned quite a few functions today.
So first way you can get information is of course print out the full frame by calling its name.
Then you could get the length of doorframe by using the len function.
So that's the number of rows.
Also very important if you want to maintain audit ability and traceability.
Number three get the visibility of the column Stanstead columns then Lenn of sets of Dotcom's gives
a number of columns.
Stats knothead gives you the top x rows of the women you specify 5 by default stats that tell same thing
but for bottom rose stats info gives you information on the columns what they are what types and how
many etc. and stats that describe it gives you a summary or some statistics on your numeric columns
and also you can transpose it.
So there we go.
Hope you enjoyed this tutorial.
Have a play around with that.
Just practice those functions a little bit.
And then I will see you in the next tutorial Conwy TSR and that one until next time.
Heavy coding.