Hello and welcome back to the course and fight and programming in today's tutorial we're going to discover
the main types of variables that exist in Python and that we'll be working with throughout this course
.
So let's get started and dive into it right away here.
I've created a folder on my desktop which is called Python programming course and all my algebra notebooks
are going to be saved there.
So I advise that you go ahead and create something similar somewhere in your computer so that they're
all in the same place.
And if you click then you better go here and select Python.
All right.
Beautiful So this is our very first Jupiter notebook and first thing we do is we're going to get the
title.
So here we're going to say types of variables as a title for today's tutorial here which is going to
start coding.
So first thing you'll notice is that the browser is quite zoomed in and that is only for the reason
so that you can see better while I'm typing in code.
Your browser is probably not zoomed in so you don't have to zoom in that much.
Just keep it at a comfortable for yourself level.
All right so let's start typing the code.
We're going to be talking about four main types of variables that we're going to be working with.
And the first one is integer.
So I'm going to put a hash tag and a hash tag in Python means a comment.
So basically this line will be ignored when the program is running and that is a way for us to com into
our code.
The first step variable that we're going to look at is integer so let's create one.
It's very simple in Python.
If you're coming from a background in C or other programming languages there you'd have to declare the
type of the variable or initialize the variable first.
Here you don't have to do that.
Python will automatically know that this is going to be an integer just because of this assignment part
of this call.
So there we go that's our first into traversals.
All right so how do we now run this line.
Well very simple on a Mac or Windows just press a shift enter and that will run the line as you can
see we've got this one up here over here.
That means that's the order in which this cell was run.
And now we can see the result of X because we just assigned it.
We didn't actually print on the screen.
How do we put this value onto a screen.
Well we basically just type in X and that's one of the ways a simpler way.
And we just press a shift and again to run that cell.
As you can see the value has appeared over here.
OK.
Wonderful So X is indeed equal to two.
And if we type in type of x and press shift enter again you will see that it is an int stat which stands
for integer.
So those are integer types of variables and they kind of just exist to represent whole numbers so whether
it's 2 is 100 0 it's minus 50.
Those are all integers.
Now let's look at the next step.
First thing we're going to do is we're going to I'm going to write a delimiter here so how do I added
to limit.
Well I want to change this cell.
I don't want it to be code.
I just want it to be a delimiter between this part of the code and the next part of the code so what
I'm going to do is I'm going to change this to markdown and here I'm going to type in the three minuses
.
And if you click shift enter it'll automatically change to a delimiter.
I find it's a convenient way to segment your code especially when you're just learning Python or any
other programming language is it.
So it can be a way for you to not get mixed up in the different parts of your code.
All right so the next time we're going to look at is a float and in some programming language it's also
called a double.
So but in Python it's called a floating point data type.
Let's look at the flow.
What is a float.
Well here's an example of floats 2.5 for instance.
And basically what that is it's a number with a decimal point.
Once again let's print out why click shift enter.
There it is 2.5 for look at type of Y.
You will see that it is a float.
OK so that's the second type.
Obviously you need integers and always you need flod Sometimes people think that why do we need integers
of have flows because you can represent the same number 2 as 2.0.
Sorry.
The reason is that because you still need integers for counting things and also they take up less space
in terms of memory and storage.
So sometimes it's more convenient to have an integer.
All right.
Let's add another delimiter and I'm going to show you a handy shortcut now.
Like right now I can enter something in the cell that is called the edit mode.
Now I can exit the edit mode by clicking escape on my keyboard and you can see that this has turned
blue and I can't edit anything I can just move around around across the cells.
I don't want to get back into the edit mode.
I just click enter on the cell I want to edit and now I can add more text or code into that cell.
So I'm going to click escape and a quick way to change the type of the cell from code to mark down which
we did over here by clicking this dropdown is by just selecting M on your keyboard while you're not
in edit mode.
So if I click them then you'll see that it's changed to mark down.
And now if I enter it and and to the three minuses click shift enter.
You'll see that this line appeared.
So there are quite a few handy shortcuts here in Jupiter and you can learn more about them if you click
this button or not that button.
If you click help and you click keyboard shortcuts you'll see all the shortcuts and they're also tailored
to your machine whether it's a Mac or it's a Windows machine.
So have a look at them and I'll be mentioning the ones I'm using throughout these tutorials but basically
what that will allow me to do is to get rid of this toolbar because as you can see it's taking up some
space and I don't really want it to take that space.
I'll druther see more code so that's what I'm going to do now I'm just going to toggle toolbar and get
rid of it.
Makes it gives us some space.
And in fact I'm even going to get rid of that very top line as well the hitter.
And so now we have all this space all this real estate for us to keep our code in.
All right.
So what's the next step that we're looking at.
The next type is the string and string is a type that stores words and letters and different characters
.
So let's have a look an example A equals Hello.
And you can see the quotation marks at the star at the end.
They were present that a string is starting let's click enter shift enter and if and imprint a is got
the word hello and also Type A.
You'll see that it is an a star which stands for string.
Now important point to mention here is that in Python it doesn't matter whether you use double quotation
marks or single quotation marks.
So in some programming languages it matters in Python it doesn't.
And you could do the same thing here.
For instance say B equals in single quotation marks hello to fire on that line.
And then I print out somewhere here you'll see that B is also represented as as a string.
So sometimes you would choose to use double sometimes single.
It really depends on your preference and the specific string that you're working with.
But in general it doesn't really matter which approach you take.
So that is a third data type and it is used to store words and letters and anything basically that you
want to put history.
You can even put a number like we did over here you can put a number in a string you can just put the
number in the string by itself.
So you click shift enter there and if I order on this scale now you'll see that it's it's a two but
it's different to the two that we had over here.
This too is an integer and you can see its type in it.
And here if we look at Type B you'll see there's a string says basically a number represented by a string
.
OK.
And let's do that marked down again so m Enter three dashes shift enter or gives us that line.
And finally the fourth daughter type that will be working with quite closely.
It is the logical data type.
So what is the logical logical is basically true or false.
So answers to questions.
In short let's have a look at one so let's say one equals true.
So in python there are two logical values true starting with a capital T and then.
Lowercase Little's letters are easy and false.
The same thing starting with a capital F..
So if I run this line you'll see.
Now I can call Q 1.
It is equal to true and the type of q 1 is Boolean boolean logical.
It's assumed.
So we're just going to say Boolean OR here.
And so that's pretty much it.
That's the four main datatypes that we need to know about and everything that we're going to be talking
about further down the course is going to be built upon that.
So once again the integer float which is a decimal point the string and the logical or boolean type
of variable.
So I hope you enjoyed the story will have a play around with that.
Create a couple of variables of your own and try to print them out in the next tutorial.
We're going to learn how to work with them and a look for you next them.
Until then be coding