Hello.
Welcome back to the course on Python programming.
Today we're talking about basic operations with doorframes.
All right.
So let's get started.
We've already spoken about one type of operation and let's recap on that already spoke about subsetting
refresh.
So if we have our stats data so say stats and and here from here we want to subset CRN columns and rows
Rose let's have a look at that.
I will say stats and then inside a list is going to be a list we need to parse the calls everyone a
subset let's say for a change we're going to subset country code Colma freight and then coma.
Internet users are net users right.
So that's how we can subset just all the three columns and all of the rows if we want a subset set of
rows we can say 4 to 8.
Run that.
And there we go.
We've got the fourth to the eighth row so 8 non-inclusive that's how we subset doorframes.
I think the next thing we're going to talk about so that's number one spoke about subsetting.
Next thing we want to talk about is mathematical operations.
You'll notice that they are very similar to operations with matrices.
So if you want that say result equals and let's say we want to take birth rate and multiplied by Internet
users now it has absolutely no meaning.
This parameter or the resulting calculation has absolutely no meaning whatsoever.
But just for practice sake we're going to multiply these two columns that say result equals stats dot
birth rates multiply by stats Daut enter that users run that as a result.
Same thing head there we go.
So we've got the multiplication of the two hundred and eight is about 10 times.
So an 8 9 or 10 10 something to 70 or 9 which is correct.
OK there we go.
That's how we multiply the two.
You can do division addition subtraction and all those sorts of things.
Very simple so basically Python will know to perform this element by element or row by row.
This operation that's a very powerful feature so you don't have to cycle.
The other option would be to create a loop and go through these rows one by one and do the multiplication
one by one.
Don't have to do that you can just specify the multiplication of column by column and Python will know
what you're talking about.
Similar to what R does.
So now we're going to learn another trick is how to add a column into your doorframe.
So let's have a look at a column.
I'm going to say stats and I'm going to call at a call them my calc.
So basically what you have to do is just pretend that the column already exists.
Now you can do that.
Quick quick approach you can just say that's not my call that won't work.
But you can do the normal approach stats square brackets might cholic equals stats.
And this is basically just take this and copy it.
So we'll say that's where we're going to put our multiplication.
And now if I look at stats dot head you'll see that my calc has appeared here.
So we basically added a column to our doorframe.
Beautiful.
Very very nice.
Now here I want to show you a comparison.
So as we go into this quarter comparing it to our.
And if you haven't taken the of course here had or if you haven't played around with are not a worry
you will be able to recognize these things when you do start learning.
And they'll probably help you or you can always come back and check these things out again when you
are learning.
So in comparison to our You will notice that in our we could have done something like this we could
have said stats x y Zed the section examples directly from the our programming course you could have
said one two three four five.
Right.
And that would have worked.
Let's see if it works here.
It doesn't work here.
Why doesn't it work here.
It says lenth overvalues values does not match length of index.
And basically what that is saying is that you only have five valleys here Carol.
And in your doorframe you have won 95.
What are you thinking how am I supposed to deal with that how am I supposed to put five values into
a column into your daughter frame.
If you have to have one many five you're supposed to give me 195 values.
Right like Logically it makes sense that it doesn't win.
But why would it work in our work.
Well in our we had that concept of recycling vector so in order this would have been a vector and because
it's a vectorize programming language it knows to recycle the vector so long as you supply some values
here what will do is it will take this and it will just basically copy copy copy copy base base base
base base until it has enough values to populate your column with the required 195 values.
As you can see Python does not do that for you.
And there you go that's a nether example vivid example of the difference between a vectorize programming
language A and a non vectorized programming language error.
Let's just type it in the OT.
No recycling option.
All right.
Good.
Good to know.
So what are we going to do next.
Well next we're going to learn how to remove a column.
So let's look at removing a column.
So what.
What are we going to do.
We're going to first look at stat's dot head.
That's our data frame and now we want to remove this call in my calc.
It has no meaning whatsoever.
What were they thinking when they put this column in here.
Let's get rid of it.
So how do we do that.
Well there's a very useful feature and the feature is called stats don't draw.
So the drop method sort of feature it's a method we can specify which Holen we want to get rid of.
So my calc and here see if I run this just like that it'll give me an error why all that.
Because by default it's looking for rows.
So this is used to draw Brosy you can specify which rows you want to drop out of your daughter's frame
.
And now case we want to drop columns.
So we're going to type in one here.
So what I'm going to do is actually I'm going to show another way.
I miss a comma and I'm going to press shift tab on my keyboard and it gives me information.
That's why there are notebooks so lovely gives me information on this function.
So here's his stats.
Return the object with labels requested access removed Stetzer drop labels or display the label my calc
.
Now X is by default is zero then we're not going to worry about these axes for the zero and the zero
is this axis.
Are we here.
Yes they are called axes.
So this is zero.
This is X number 1.
So we are going to say X is 1.
And you notice I don't have to.
I can see if I could shift tab again.
I can say axis equals 1 around that you'll see that that column has been dropped or I don't have to
say axis equals 1 or shift tab because it's going to take them in the order they come.
First of all look for the labels with either one label or a vector or a list of labels and then it will
look for the next parameter in this case one.
It will be like All right so what's the next parameter in the function signature it's axis so that one
must refer to that as was another parameter and would refer to Lebel and other one refer to false.
So you either specify the name equals the value or you can just pass for the value if you know in which
order they come.
So in this case we just say one and that has been dropped.
Which you will notice though is if I look at stats dot head.
It's still here.
How so.
Why didn't we just drop that colon.
Well let's have a look at the function again.
So first shift tab you'll notice here it says return a new object with labels and requested extremum
so returns a new object doesn't modify the previous one.
Let's go down here and look at this.
So how do we fix that up so how do we actually drop it from our object.
Well we'll just replace say stats or drop or actual did here stats equal status.
Drop my calc and now if we look at stats head you'll see that it has been dropped.
So we have to overwrite our doorframe with this new object in order to actually drop it in the door
frame that we working with.
All right.
So those are the things we learnt today about working with doorframes that's quickly recap.
If we go to the top of basic operation so we really know about subsetting and there is a whole tutorial
that we devoted to this topic we just refreshed on it here.
Then we talked about mathematical operations where we learned that you can just multiply columns by
columns and sort of creating a loop and going through every single row and performing that calculation
.
Very powerful feature very similar to what we have in our in terms of vectorized operations.
I'd call them we can add a column just pretend that it's there and populated.
Don't use the short quick method uses a standard method like that and also we quickly compared to our
that there's no recycling option in Python Python does or recycle or lists if they're shorter than your
doorframe.
And finally we learned how to remove a column very very simple process.
Just use the dot drop method and don't forget to specify the access to equal one.
That means columns.
There we go.
Hope you enjoyed today's tutorial and I look forward to seeing you on the next one.
Until then happy coding