Welcome back to the Python programming course this is Carol or Menko as always.
And I am super happy that we've gotten this far in this section of the course.
We have already looked at the kernel density estimate Plaut that we've got over here which is very interesting
to create something unusual.
And today we're going to continue working with a few kernel as the estimates.
But at the same time we're going to introduce a new concept we're going to talk about sub plots in Python
.
It's a function that allows you to create more sophisticated whistles or has to combine these allegations
together.
So let's see how subplots works in action.
All right.
So first thing I want to do is I'm going to create a new kernel as estimate using our seaborne library
.
So Katie Plaut by the way just a reminder we are using seaborne so seaborne was imported as import seaborne
as S and S.
And that's what allows us to create these beautiful visualizations.
It's always good to refresh on what exactly we're using.
So if I scroll up here you'll see that's our standard imports.
So in fact might as well just copy them here.
It never hurts to rerun them.
Not that it changes anything.
But if you're say jumping into the course at this part this tutorial then you'll definitely need to
have these imports.
So the go that's the imports we're using.
So let's go ahead and create our kernel density estimate.
so sns dot kde plot movies dot budget millions come to movies.
Daut audience rating.
All right so far on this.
What does this current estimates show us whether the budget of the movie affects the rating that the
audience gives it.
So basically Is there any skew of this Alsation to the right or to the left or up or down.
And so what we can see from here is that basically if you slice this viz. an audience rating of say
40 you'll see that the budget millions is located somewhere or here mostly if you slice it at 60 then
you can see that it does stretch out a bit more or if you slice it another way if you say for example
let's take a budget millions and take a slice at $20000000 you can see that it's straighted rating audience
ratings stretches all the way from 20 to nearly 100.
But if you take budget millions and slice it at for example 60 you can see that the lower bound of the
audience rating or the lower density is a bit higher.
But also the higher density is a bit lower so the movies are more likely less likely to get ratings
around 20 30 is also less likely to get ratings over 90 and closer to 100.
Very interesting observation.
So it kind of narrows down in both ways.
As you go into the higher budgets of movies.
One thing I wanted to change here is I wanted to change the style so this type in essence set disco
style and here we're going to say dark.
So if you're on that then we've gotten rid of that grid and it kind of looks a bit better.
This particular chart looks better without the grid.
And then what we want to do as well is we want to do the same thing but this time as you can imagine
for critic rating serve her on that this is a bit more interesting.
So you've got a chart so how do we read this.
You can see that the critic rating even though it goes below zero here that is just because the way
the kernel density estimate is constructed of course in reality creating doesn't go below zero.
What it's showing us is that critique ratings are most concentrated here between the 20 and 40 mark
and then they stretch out and if you take slices and different movie ratings or movie budgets you can
see that as you go over a budget of 50 million they create the maximum critic rating drops quite substantially
and it does pick up on the bottom as well so kind of similar observation to here.
But as you can see the audience rating is a bit tighter here whereas a critic rating is spread out.
And that's something we discussed that is closer to normal distribution the audience ratings closer
to normal distribution whereas a critic rating is actually closer to a uniform distribution.
So that's an interesting charge.
You can also kind of observe it or analyze it by slicing by critic creating and observing how the budget
is changed.
So I'll let you do that and try to play around with that conceptually see if this is a charge you like
it also is a matter of personal preference.
Some people might like a resolution like this some people might enjoy it less because it isn't as straightforward
for example as a scatterplot.
So today what we're focusing on is not just analyzing or creating these realizations today we want to
talk about the subplots function what exactly does it do and how do we use it.
Well in order to call subplots we would we need to do is say for example say F and this is a coding
convention that you will see quite a lot in Python code.
F dot f my X and then he goes P.L. T Dot subplots.
So subplots comes from my plot lib or pi plot which we're importing a specialty BLT called subplots
.
Here we're going to say one two.
So if I run this you'll see right away what it does so it's saying one row two columns I can say one
row three columns that will give me three shots it creates three empty chairs and say three rows three
columns will create nine empty chairs that which we can then populating and say three to eight.
Three call three rows two columns.
So in either case we're going to say one row two columns.
Why is that.
Well you guessed it right.
Would you want to do is we want to place this chart in here and this chart in here.
And that's what we're going to be working on now.
All right so there we go that's a that's a good start.
So another parameter that is quite useful is big size.
It's the size of the whole figure and you specify it and a tuple is say 12 for instance 6.
And the first one is how long it is.
The second parameter is how high it is.
All right so now we want to just take these two beautiful beautiful Katy plots and put them in here
.
This is supposed to be OK to take this and put it in here.
And so if I just run this nothing is going to happen.
Nothing good because they're actually plotted on one chart.
How do I control where they go.
Well the way to control it is you take a x and then you always hear you say comma A-x which is actually
a parameter that you can pass into Katie plot's or into other functions of Seaborn.
And then you say X which is this X in fact just to make it easier to follow along with you get to rename
as we say access here and say access and here we're going to say zero because it's.
I'll explain why are we doing this in a second to just create this code.
And here we can say one.
So now they've been split.
All right.
So what happened here.
Let's quickly analyze it.
First of all we've never seen this before right so we've got one function on the right.
Yes we understand how we calling a function we're one to these parameters.
That's number of rows number of columns in fact you press shift tab and I'll show me a number of rows
number of columns.
Then Fig's size this and another parameter that you can pass to this function.
It isn't specified here it's it's a bit tricky it's kind of like one of those parameters that you got
you got to know about in order to pass it here.
And what's the function returns is this.
So this is the important part.
So fig and X this function actually report returns two objects or turns a tuple of two objects.
Fig is the well basically the chart that you created to figure and X is either a single x x or this
is important part and I will reiterate this just now.
It can be either a single axis object or an area of Access objects.
If more than once a point was created.
So the dimension of the result and area can be controlled if the squeeze Kure.
See above.
So we're not going to worry about the squeeze keyword.
What this basically means is that we are reaching the function returns two values so f is the figure
that's the whole object that we're working with.
And then AXS is going to be and array specifying how it's how you axes these or how you can access each
one of these.
If I say access here you'll see that it's an array and it's got two parts to it.
So this first bit is associated with the first shock.
Second bit is associated with the second chart.
So that's how we put each chart HKT plot on the associated chart.
On the one we want so here is zero space for one.
All right so another thing I wanted to show you and this is something I need to definitely we need to
color off is that if for instance you said two two here you'll get an error.
All right so why is that.
Well the reason is let's just calm these out for now.
If you say two to first of all I'm going to do that.
So if you say two to now you've got four charts and as soon as you have a two dimensional number of
charts or subplots are called subplots since you have like a matrix of subplots as long as it's not
either just one row one column of them.
Then this object has been returned.
Access becomes a two dimensional area.
So in this case if you want to place it let's say I want to place K-1 over here because it's not enough
to say zero because what is that zero mean does that mean this chart on this chart or this chart which
chart does it mean you've got to specify 0 0.
And this is something that definitely can be a bit tricky.
So you've got to always remember is it's a two dimensional set of subplots or a one dimensional set
of subplots.
So here if let's say just this video quickly and how as you move this kitty plot to this subplot What
would you type in there.
OK.
One two three.
I'm going to show you now so I would just basically say this is on row 0 but in column so rows 0 but
in Column number 1.
So here I replace that was 0 1 and now it's been moved over there so I can move it even further down
1 1.
So there we go.
So and K-2 same thing I can say 1 0.
That one has ended up over there.
So that is how you control it when you have a two dimensional set of subplots.
In our case it's a 1 2 and therefore now for on this card then I'll give you an error of course too
many indices for an aere naturally.
So here we're going to have say just 0 and 1 right because we only have a single row of these subplots
.
So that's a very important distinction to remember because it not only changes the number you put in
actually changes the number of dimensions of the object and therefore you have to supply more indices
.
OK.
What else can we do here.
Well let's make these look a bit prettier.
We're going to say K.
One set Exel him he calls minus 20 to 1 succeed.
So there's only to go all the way to 300 will just go to 160.
Run that.
So there you go you can see that this one its limit is from 1 to minus 20 to 60.
This one's limit is still large.
We can copy this line and create the same line for this second chart.
So for k to but we're going to do that because we're going to just use a parameter.
Here we're going to say Khama share X equals true so that they have the same x axis and that means the
second will just be copied from the first one.
So you can see now it's also 160.
Now it's kind of like zoomed into the chart and the other thing we wanted to do is share.
Why.
Because right now they're not the same so that's minus 20 and that doesn't even say minus or any difference
goes up to just 110 and goes up to 20 so it can be a bit confusing.
They're not aligned.
Sirius's share Weikel is true that's another prominent can pass and the ghost and now they're aligned
and you can compare visually the two side by side you can see that audience rading more compact Kritik
creating more spread out.
And then we've got well we've already done pick sides actually.
There it is.
OK so that is how you work with subplots.
It's a very very powerful tool.
It's good to have practice with it.
It's definitely a good idea to experiment a bit more so try to create a like a vertical subplot for
example or create a subplot or applause with nine subplots and try to place these in different locations
or maybe even add some more chars some more kid E-plus and populate them even if they're the same it
doesn't matter.
It's more about now practicing the subplots function because woofs subplots you can create some very
interesting relations and subplots is often used to create some tricky realisations in Python.
And moreover this tutorial about subplots is a stepping stone for us for when we talk more about how
to create dashboards in Python.
So it's a very valuable skill to have and we'll expand on and further down in this section of the course
.
Hope you have a chance to play around with that and I'll see you on the next tutorial.
Until then happy coding.