Hello and welcome back to a course of Python programming.
Today we're talking about arrays in Python.
Now this is going to be a short tutorial because we're going to be working with arrays in much more
depth in the further sections of this course.
But for now it's important for us to get a basic understanding of this concept.
All right.
So let's quickly create a list very talked about lists and we know them quite well so just create a
list of totally random numbers.
There you go so there is a list.
So if I press shift enter I have that list there.
And we've already discussed that lists in Python are very similar to arrays in other programming languages
like C C++ or two vectors in our.
But at the same time lists have that property that they can store any mix of data types so into this
list that could have easily put words that could have put floating numbers as well as integers and it
could have put logical values and so on.
But in Python there's another concept which is actually called arrays so let's say another data structure
is different to list it's similar in many ways but it's actually different.
And that's what we're going to explore today.
So how do we create an array.
Well in python there are two types of arrays that you can use.
There's arrays that are built into the core of Python they're called the array arrays.
There's also the name Pyra.
So numb pie is a package that comes pretty distributed with Anaconda.
It's a package that you'll be using.
We very actually touched on some pie in the previous section on the course already when we were working
with random numbers.
Generally speaking you'll be working non-pilots is basically a package that you include in most of your
code especially as a data scientist or data analyst.
Pi is just included pretty much all the time and therefore using array arrays that exist in python in
the core isn't the best option when you have the numpad raise which are much more versatile and they
have much more flexibility to them and much more control.
So that's why we're not even going to bother with the array arrays in Python which is going to go to
the non-players array arrays right away.
So I'm going to add to the pie package so I'm going to say imports NUMP pie.
As we discussed previously but here I'm actually going to say as MP that's convention for dumpsite basically
So we don't have to type up and NUMP every single time we could just use N.P. and you'll find that in
most scripts that are written you will find that end p is used instead of NUMP.
So which is going to run that code.
And now if I say P Daut array I have this function that will convert a list into an array.
So if I pass in our list L you will see that as an output I have an array.
So let's give it a name let's say a equals an array of L.
And now if I type in a here you'll see that that is our array.
So now what's the main difference between lists and arrays so why would we use arrays instead of lists
.
Number one very important difference is that you cannot have an array of different data types.
So an array is like a vector an R.
You cannot have different data types on an array.
Let's have a look let's say we have a array called B.
And we'll say and P-Dog array and into this array we want to parse the following list.
We want to say 12 4:55 than 60.
That is the sixty three point three.
So we've got integers we've got a flow.
Let's say a logical and let's say a word so letter A.
Or ABC for instance.
So for on that.
And now we look at B you will see that it is an array.
But if I print B you'll see that actually they've all been put into quotation marks meaning that they
have all been converted to characters or two strings because they had one string in there already so
everything was converted to strings.
That's because you cannot have different data types and Center-Right everything has to be of the same
data type.
So that's number one.
And then the question is will Kiril why would we use an array if it's less flexible than a list in a
list we can have different data types and array we Collin's or why wouldn't we just stick with lists
all the answer that question is there's a few benefits of using arrays and they're quite substantial
.
For example if I take my list and I press l and then press Dot and I press tab because the list isn't
we aren't an object oriented programming language.
Well what happens is they are functions or methods that are included in this object that they're being
stored alongside with the data.
So the data that we have let's just press escape.
We have this data in the list.
Right.
Well actual alongside the data because it's a list inside Python it also stores these functions inside
this object.
So I can actually call these functions right now from inside this list so let's say for instance I could
say l dot pop What will that do.
So if I run this function you'll see that it gives me a minus 1 two 3 4 it gives me the last value of
this list so it shows it to me and it actually pops it out of the list.
That's why it's called pop.
So if I look at Al now you'll see that it doesn't have that value anymore.
So I actually called a function from a the list.
Well arrays have the same thing so if I look at a dot tab but you'll see that they have way more functions
and that well actually they're called methods way Mumbai that's available.
So for instance I could write a way say a max or a means.
So let's try it the mean I can just calculate the mean like that very quickly.
I have the mean of this array that I have created here.
So the average of those values is 4 5 5 9 very versatile and very powerful functions available inside
arrays or for a race that's come with Nampa and so because you have that very strong package of NUMP
by backing this whole concept of arrays that means that you have all these powerful tools at your disposal
.
That's number one and number two is that further down the course you'll see that we will start creating
multidimensional objects or start creating specifically two dimensional objects which don't go much
further than that.
Don't worry I won't go into five dimensions and so on we'll be creating multidimensional objects and
and specifically we'll be creating matrices and a matrix is a two dimensional array.
And we'll talk more about that further down the course.
But it's just important to understand that we will need to work rephrase just because we want to start
working of tables and then eventually we want to move on to that will help us move on to doorframes
and so on.
So just for data analytics purposes it's inevitable for us to start looking for ways that's a good thing
to get introduced to them here.
So that's how you create arrays to just basically take a list and you parse it into NPR-A.
There you have it there.
After that you have an array that you can work with.
So just to get familiar of the concept I encourage you to quickly practice this and maybe create a few
different REZO see for yourself example for example what happens if you don't include a string.
What will happen if you include a mix of data types that are just integers floats and logicals what
will that array converts all those values to.
So things like that and just practice create some arrays.
Check out some other functions that exist in there and that will help us get a head start into the concept
of multidimensional arrays.
When we get to it.
Hope enjoyed this tutorial and I look forward scenics them.
Until then happy coding