Learn.
Welcome back to the Python programming course in the historial.
We created a fascinating facet grid which tells us about how audience rating versus critic ratings evolved
throughout the years from 2007 to 2011 based on the genre.
So we're going to perform some preliminary analytics here.
However before we finalized this report or chart what we do want to is we want to tidy it up so let's
zoom in a bit first.
And what specifically I'm talking about is that you can see for example that the access here goes from
minus 20 to 120.
It's not really necessary given that ratings can only be from 0 to 100.
And same thing for the x axis and also one thing that we are definitely interested in is how the audience
ratings are comparing to critic ratings.
That's that's the reason why we built this chart and what would help us really help us is a diagonal
across each one of these parts of the Fassett grid which would show us which would help us very quickly
to visually assess where the dots slide to the line above the diagonal.
Or do they live below the diagonal so if they're above the diagonal then the audience gives higher ratings
than the critics if they're below the diagonal.
And the critics give higher ratings than the audience.
So how do we add or how do we make those changes.
Let's go ahead and find out.
So we're going to just copy this code here and the top is say.
Say controlling axes and adding diagonals.
All right so how are we going to do this.
Well the first thing that we want to do is we want to say let's set the limits for our x and y axis
we'll say gee Daut set X slim equals.
So here in a tuple you say zero to 100.
And while him he calls.
Same thing.
Zero to 100 for on that and give it a second for me.
There you go.
So now what you can see is that they are from 0 to 100 and 0 to 100 here as well.
So that's the first step.
That's a good thing.
Raggles is going to be a bit trickier.
We have to iterate and we have to go through each one of these and add a diagonal to each one of these
.
And once again another example of us having to use loops because Python isn't a vectorize programming
language unlike our in our you rarely use loops in Python.
As you've noticed we've used them for a couple of times.
So you get a greater loop and we're going to iterate over g Daut hak says we're axes Daut flat.
Let's start off our axes What does that axes do.
Cheater axes is an aere of the subplots or all of the elements of the five faceted grid that we are
working with for an area of an area object or presents a multidimensional homogeneous array of fixed
size items and so on.
So basically we actually that are irrelevant or the main point is that it's an ashtray which represents
each one which contains each one of these.
And now what we can do on top of that is we can say Daut flat and what it will do is will flatten out
the array.
So if you just press a shift explain it as well so flat iterator object to trade over areas.
So basically what it'll do is it'll iterate over the area.
Even though this is a two dimensional array Woodell it will do is Ill iterate over it as if it was just
a simple list.
And there's going to be easier for us.
And that's exactly what we want so that we don't have to think about the two dimensionality of this
object or iterating over.
I know it can sound a bit complex but basically what we're doing is we're taking G.
We're using ADOT axes to access all of these elements of the Fassett grid or all of these little plots
and then we're using flat to flatten out this area that we have so that we can iterate over it.
We're using this variable in a simple matter.
And so now we're going to say X dot plot and we're going to plot a line onto each one of these.
So let's just for fun say 20 to 60 and that's the x axis and then here we'll say 20 to 60 as well.
That's the y axis and let's have a look at that.
See how that just works out for us.
You can see that's a line from 20 to 60 on both axes on x and y.
And now we're going to actually replace it with the one we want.
From 0 to 100 0 to 100.
And as you can see it's a blue line we're going to replace the caliber of see he calls gray and then
line style We're going to just do dash dash dash line.
So if you're on this now you can see that we've got that dashed line and it does definitely simplify
our analysis.
We can much easier to understand where exactly the dotted lines are right away.
Here you can see that in 2009 in the genre of action the audience gave much better ratings and the critics
overall.
So each one of these dots is a movie.
And here you can see that whenever dot is above the diagonal It means that audience rating for that
movie was greater than the critic creating.
Very interesting if we can find an opposite situation.
So in this scenario for instance in a drama or in 2011 looks like the critics were more prone to give
better ratings.
And the same thing and Thriller in 2011 critics gave better ratings and then the audience especially
in the higher numbers and 60s 80s and hundred or close to 100 out of 100 in the lower spectrum.
The audience gave better ratings so it's definitely a very convenient very simple tool but a very convenient
tool just a diagonal that helps us analyze these charts better.
And just as a quick bonus.
One more thing I wanted to show you how to add to this plot since you've powered through these tutorials
and you're all here.
How do we add age.
A legend.
It's very simple just say Gee Dot add legend.
I know it can be complex.
It can be a bit confusing sometimes.
So for instance why is it add legend and not just legend.
We've we've already seen that type of use case.
And also why is it seen at color like there is sometimes you find that there isn't consistency throughout
but these are just things that with time you'll either remember or at the point where you need to use
a search function you'll just look it up and very quickly get the hang of it.
So there we go.
We've added a legend as you can see over there.
So it may seem a bit blurry or not crisp if I zoom out it will become better right away.
So there we go.
The chart is much more crisp and on its own this whole chart is you can just drag it like an image and
it can act as a whole report on its own.
You can spend at least half an hour just analyzing this if not longer.
It's a very very powerful chart on in its own right.
So this is going to be our chart number five that we're going to include.
It's big but it does carry a lot of insightful information.
All right so hopefully you enjoyed these tutorials on creating working fast grids and creating this
monster of a chart.
And if you fall along and create this chart then congratulations.
This has been quite a feat to get to this result.
Definitely enjoyed walking through this creation process together and I look forward to seeing on the
next after.
Until then I'd be coding