Defining your value stream endpoints is a critical activity
for the success of your Kanban system.
We already defined and discussed what a value stream is,
and I gave you some examples in the module Kanban 201,
but in this section we want to talk about the endpoints where the
stuff comes in and where the stuff goes out.
Let's start by defining the endpoints of your value stream.
Determine where to start in in your value stream.
That's important.
That process is what you will visualize from the step when you
receive work until you deliver that work.
Hence,
you need to define your interface points upstream and downstream with
your coworkers or possibly other external partners.
Recommendation.
Adopt your workflow within your control.
You will likely not be successful by enlarging the workflow value
stream to areas where you cannot control the work,
cannot control someone else's team, their resources,
and budgets, and things like that.
Now that could be different if the upstream partner,
for example, was also a Kanban team, think about that,
but that topic is outside the scope of this course.
Now let's look at an example of a value stream with endpoints.
You will discuss and negotiate with your upstream
partners who are providing requirements,
prioritization,
and other project artifacts such as budgets and resources potentially as well.
Here is your value stream, and in this example,
I am showing a simplistic value stream composed of specify,
implement, and validate.
This is where you have control and influence over analysis,
design, coding, and testing.
Lastly, your downstream partner could be operations,
those who put things into production release,
or even your end users.
So as this bracket is showing, the orange boxes are what's in your control,
and therefore, in your value stream.
Here are the key points of value stream endpoints.
By defining boundaries,
you are asking your team to adopt limiting work in
progress only for your value stream.
You can't ask your upstream or downstream partners to do that.
You are asking your partners to interact in a way that supports Kanban.
Again, you don't need to tell them that you're using Kanban,
but you are asking them to provide you what you need
that would support a pull system, and on the other end,
a way to deliver what you have produced.
Value stream mapping is an extremely valuable component of Kanban.
It is a significant part of achieving continuous
improvement of the way you work.
It allows you to visualize and bound your process, your value stream.
It helps you optimize the way you deliver value to your customers.
So designing your value stream in conjunction with determining those
endpoints and negotiating with your upstream and downstream partners is
critical to the success of your value stream.
So don't just map your value stream and forget all about the
endpoints and your up or downstream partners. That would be a grave error.