Push versus pull.
It is quite typical for us to receive work from others,
and we might even say our customers are pushing demand on us.
Kanban is a pull system because new work,
or demand, is pulled into the system when there is capacity to work it,
and is only pulled when there is capacity to work it rather than
pushed into the system based on the upstream demand.
This is likely to be quite different from how you work today.
My guess is that you might be simply overworked or there may be a queue of work,
but you must start on it even if you are still working on
other work and your management may expect you to work
concurrently on several items.
As you have experience,
that is not likely to be very productive or result in quality work outcomes.
Here is a quick and simple card wall or board example.
And I stress simple.
There is so much more to a true kanban board system,
but just to be sure we are on the same page, here's an example.
Here is our grid with three columns.
This is the To Do column, or demand, things we will pull from.
This is the Doing column and the work in progress. And our Done,
or completed item, column, items ready for delivery. N ow here are
our To Do or demand items,
and here are our items that are work in progress. And lastly, our done items.
Now, if we have identified the purple ticket as our next priority item,
then we are ready to move, or to better say it,
pull the ticket into the Doing column.
So let's pull it.
Okay,
now this is a very simple example and a card wall does not equal
kanban, it is only one attribute of a kanban system.
I would like to make an important point.
Card boards and visual workflows that are common in agile
methodologies are not kanban systems.
They may be great things to use and be very productive as
well, but don't confuse them for kanban systems. They are
merely visual control systems.
It is a subtle distinction, which you will come to realize soon in this course.
Besides being visual, kanban systems need to meet of following constraints, so let's check that out on the next few slides.