Think visual at all times with Kanban.
Think about how you could enhance the visual aspects of the
board so as to provide more information,
but with less clutter to ensure the smooth flow of work. You may want
to use as many visual cues as possible to make it very easy to glance
at the board and see what's going on.
For example, maybe the color of the card maps to the work type.
Here's some examples.
Change requests may be green, user stories are orange, suggestions and
research blue, bugs and production defects violet, just to name a few;
you may have more. And maybe you want to use icons or badges that
would be placed on the cards, such as, here's one for bugs,
hot production issues, big dollar value, and lastly,
maybe an org chart represents a request from senior
management, so I assume this may be a high priority.
You know your business and your customers, so be creative and be sure
whatever you do makes sense to the team, and don't be afraid to
change things as you need to along the way.
Here's an example of a board with color and refined swim lanes.
Here's our board.
Here's our backlog.
Let's say we want to make it very clear what the priority backlog items are.
Here are items in priority one, here are priority two items, and here are
priority three items. And the rest, remember,
are nice‑to‑haves that we may work on sometimes. Priority
one items are very visual and clear.
Also, based on our last slide, we see we have one change request, green,
one research item, blue, and one bug item,
and that's violet.
Learning the visual cues is very simple and easy. Just as
you track the type of work, such as a bug,
for example, you may want to track the source of the work type.
In other words, where's it coming from?
This may be important as well.
For example, the work source may be from the executive suites,
from sales and business development, from engineering,
maybe even from internal IT, or many other organizations or departments,
maybe even vendors and suppliers.
Now you could also use color. Again, Kanban means you can do whatever
you need to do to optimize workflow. But also you could use additional
swim lanes, and let's see an example. Now, let's see how the source of
the work type may affect the board.
Here's our board.
Here's our backlog.
Now we want to make it real clear where the source
of our backlog items come from.
Here are our items from engineering, and so we use an E.
Here are the work items from sales, and we use an S.
And here are the executive, or C‑Suite items,
and we will use a C here. And the rest of ours are just
nice‑to‑haves again in the backlog.
There are endless ways to lay out your board to meet your needs, so use
my examples as ideas only. Please come up with your own that make sense
to you and your team and your value stream.
Now let's see how we can morph the board to accommodate
setting limits on our work in progress.
Here's our board,
and we have widened the three middle columns to
accommodate some additional detail.
We will add an additional vertical line to allow for two
vertical buckets for each of our steps.
Now let's label them, the first being work in progress, or WIP, and the
second part of the split column, complete, or done.
You can see, though,
that the first step, backlog, and the last step,
deliver, do not have two columns.
They are not needed necessarily,
since they are the hand‑off areas between upstream work
and downstream delivery of the work.
Now let's look at a backlog item.
We're going to pull it forward to work in progress and begin working on it.
When complete,
it is placed in the done area and is basically queued up
waiting for a free resource to pull it forward.
I do recommend strongly having two columns per workflow step Now,
as another way to segment the board, you can see on the right,
there will be two areas in the deliver step. One is production
stage and one is production.
And maybe that makes perfect sense for your downstream partners.
The important point of this slide is that you can be as
flexible as you need or want to be,
and once you set it up, be open and willing to change and
modify the board as it makes sense. Remember,
business is dynamic, and so should your board be. By the way,
the done column, in this case, is also known as a buffer,
and we'll talk about that more later in this module. You have the
freedom to design your board any way you want,
as long as it adds value to the business.
This is why Kanban has immense power. You are not constrained like some other software development methodologies.