Now let's begin setting up a kanban project. First,
let's define what a value stream is. It's the workflow that
takes you from value demand, something is required or wanted,
to value delivery, the requirement is satisfied. And you're
doing this by minimizing time, effort, and cost.
Here is an example of a simple value stream.
Specify the work that is necessary to implement. Then implement the work.
Next, validate that it works properly against the
specification or expected outcomes, as defined in the specify step. And lastly,
deliver it to your customers.
Very simple, very straightforward.
Here are some rules of thumb, or guidelines, when defining the value stream.
Now the previous example was very simple, and yours could be much more complex.
You may have, for example,
multiple steps and variations to implement or validate a work item.
Okay,
here they are. Only include the steps your team is responsible
for. Leave out any steps that occur before your value stream
begins and after your value stream ends.
If you are not sure what steps to start with,
well,
just start with the ones on the previous slide. Combine steps if they
are sequential and will be done by the same resource.
If, for example,
a developer writes unit tests, codes, and does user acceptance testing,
maybe all those are contained in the implement step. Hmm, you say, but what
if my team members don't have all the same skills,
technical, or business knowledge?
Great question. You're catching on. More on that later in this course.