Let's see what the attributes are that make up a good card.
A card represents a discrete work item that adds value to the business,
plus contains additional information.
The design of the card is important, you want it to be easy to read,
understand, and to take action upon.
The card must convey enough key information to facilitate a smooth
workflow and support a clear decision‑making process.
And lastly, the card typically varies by work type or work source,
skills needed, and other attributes,
and those variations should be visually evident, so
you definitely want to be creative.
You can annotate your kanban cards to contain a brief
but rich amount of information,
choose annotations that make sense to you and your team to
help you make timely and quality decisions.
Now let's pull a card forward in our value stream,
and let's blow up the card so we can see some detail. First,
maybe we want to have an item number for reference,
an item title or name, maybe the backlog date,
the start date when we first pulled it forward,
days and work, hey, who's working that item,
who owns it, related or independent tasks or dependent tasks,
the estimate of the size of work, and in this case,
medium, and maybe in the upper‑right corner,
an alert symbol,
an exclamation mark, if the days and work is greater than the average lead time.
Now,
be creative. It is up to you and your team to do whatever you
need to have the most relevant information to maximize the
smooth running of your workflow.
So if you are selecting a digital kanban tool, be sure you pick one with the greatest flexibility to meet your needs.