Now let's talk about estimation.
Here's a quote, "I just love to make estimates." by every engineer I have known.
Of course, that is not true.
Almost everyone I have ever known professionally does not like making estimates.
I truly believe though, making estimates has value to the
business, but just don't go overboard.
Making estimates is certainly challenging.
Backlog items come in all different shapes and sizes, challenge
your domain of business knowledge, as well as test your
technical promise. This can be daunting.
Customers or your managers will ask how soon will the backlog
item that is near and dear to them be completed.
Senior management may also ask, when will the next major release be completed?
I have customers waiting, so you will feel the pressure. Waterfall,
Agile, Scrum,
kanban, or any other approach all share the same degree and the same
challenges of making quality estimates. Estimation is essential.
Customers want to know,
and it is a reasonable expectation because in the real world you may
still be faced with deadlines and release dates.
Hence,
estimating is a valuable tool that not only will address the
customers or your manager's questions,
but also provide performance feedback to the team.
So let's decompose work items into tasks.
The time needed to complete tasks is easier to do and
likely more predictable than a larger, chunkier work item,
like a user story.
So one backlog card is now going to be multiple tasks that are required to complete the work item.