Stand‑ups are different in kanban, and let's see how and why.
Let's compare and contrast between a typical Agile/Scrum
stand‑up and then a kanban stand‑up.
First, I'll go over the cadence or pace of the Agile/Scrum stand‑up.
The team assembles daily or more at a predefined location.
Of course, stand‑ups can happen any time you think you need them for reviews,
demos, customer discussions, or how you might improve your processes.
Any team member can run or lead a stand‑up.
Typically, a round‑robin approach is used. Also, typically,
each member states what they accomplished since the last
stand‑up, what they plan to accomplish today, and,
most importantly,
talk through any of their blockers. Blockers are anything that
is impeding their progress, anything at all.
Team members may split off afterwards to solve
blockers or discuss any other issues.
The person running the stand‑up now asks,
anyone need any help? They may last between 5 and 15 minutes,
but if you need a little more time, well,
take it. Now, you are likely very familiar with this type of stand‑up.
Now let's take a look at the kanban stand‑up. Now let's
review the cadence of a kanban stand‑up.
The team assembles daily, usually in the morning.
This is my preference, but maybe a different routine would work better for you.
Now there's no need to go around the room. With a well‑designed
board, you can see what people have done,
what people are working on, and what is blocked.
So why waste time doing that?
The lead or project manager will walk the board,
though anyone should be able to do this role.
You typically start from the far right of the board
and work your way to the left.
The facilitator will be looking for any indicators of issues,
validations, and status and generally asking questions of the team.
The focus of the stand‑up and of any kanban system is the smooth flow of work.
Don't forget that. All activities,
including the stand‑ups, they are no exception, the emphasis will be
to identify and remediate blockers and any defects.
Typically,
all work items will have color monikers so that it is easy to
identify the type of issue to concentrate on those.
Certainly people can meet up and further discuss issues,
blockers, or other items after the meeting or any time they are working. Now, let's summarize this module.