Let's talk about forecasting in kanban,
which really means getting good at making estimates We did
touch on estimation in the module Kanban 201,
and let's revisit.
Forecasting really means estimation.
Now it's important that you have the ability to make forecasts to
inform your customer when something will be done.
They will want to know.
Respect your customers.
They have milestones, due dates, deadlines, and budgets to worry about.
So partner with them for the best mutual results.
To provide forecasts,
you need to be able develop reasonable estimates in order to maintain a
quality professional relationship with your customers.
You don't need to make full‑blown,
nitty‑gritty spreadsheet estimates necessarily,
but you do need to make reasonable estimates.
Now let's talk about estimation thresholds.
First, well, are estimates a waste?
There is a school of thought in the kanban and agile
world that estimates do not add value.
I believe they do.
They help in prioritizing work and in determining
if the work is worthwhile to do.
And there is a host of other excellent reasons to make estimates as well.
But you don't need to estimate everything, of course.
Set a threshold policy that you have agreed to with your customer,
something like anything that's roughly 3 weeks or less,
we're just going to put it in the backlog and do it as normal. Now, obviously,
producing the 3‑week value is an estimate in and of itself,
but only spend 15 minutes tops on it. Now for larger ones,
say the work is greater than 3 weeks, because it is the
right professional thing to do,
you will spend a little more time breaking down the work to
provide more insight for the customer.
Now let's see an example on how that might work.
Here's an example of estimation thresholds we determined at a client of
mine. Less than 3 weeks, add to the backlog, and only spend about 15
minutes to determine that estimate. Between 3 and 8 weeks, I'm probably
going to spend around 1 or 2 hours. Again, add it to the backlog with
the customer's approval.
With less than 3 weeks, just throw it onto the backlog.
If it turns out that that time I spent, the 1 to 2 hours, led me
to believe that it was greater than 8 weeks,
then I'm going to add work to the backlog as just a specify
step only with the customer's approval.
In other words, we need to do more work to break down the tasks.
This approach saves time making estimates,
but does require a good working relationship with your
customer and trust that you can deliver.
Okay, let's look at another approach.
Here is an example of a scatter plot,
and we will see how we can use it to forecast work types.
Each dot corresponds to a single completed task in your kanban board.
The key is at the top of the graph.
The color of the dot relates to the work type,
and, in this case, I've chosen three work types, bugs with blue diamonds,
normal work with red squares, and hot work as green triangles.
The X‑axis is time, and I used days as my time period.
The Y‑axis is the number of hours to complete that
task through the entire value stream.
The height of the dot represents its lead time. The higher the dot,
the longer it took for this task to be completed.
So, for example,
this bug, this dot, took about 15 hours to complete on April 16th.
So if 85% of all bugs took 7 days to complete, we could
probably use that as a forecast measurement,
and we could tell our customers that the average bug takes 7 days.
Don't worry about having to make these complex
spreadsheets yourself and these complex charts. Many kanban products come with these tools all built in to help you.