Hello, and welcome.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the module, What You Will Learn,
in the course, Kanban for Agile/Scrum Practitioners.
Think you haven't used Kanban?
Well, think again.
If you've been to a typical coffee house,
you've experienced the following: Someone takes your order and
marks your cup for the kind of coffee you want,
how much room at the top for cream you want,
and the temperature, and maybe even other things.
The cup is placed in a queue.
The barista will pick up the cup, read the cup, and make the coffee.
The finished cup is placed on a shelf.
The store is using kanban to speed your order through.
And guess what that coffee cup is?
Well, besides holding your favorite cup of joe, it is acting as a kanban card.
Well, more on cards in the next module.
Let me start by telling you what kanban isn't.
It is not a software development lifecycle methodology.
It is not a project management methodology.
Yet, kanban improves developing software and managing projects.
Okay, I'm intrigued.
So what is it?
Kanban is a framework to allow you to create context‑specific process solutions.
Kanban does not follow a rigid software development lifecycle process.
So if you walked around a company or multiple companies that
practice kanban and you looked at each board,
each one would be different, look different,
with different cards, different colors, different columns and steps,
yet all running smoothly.
Are you still intrigued? Then this course is for you.