In this course, Kanban for Agile/Scrum Practitioners,
you will learn the skills, approaches,
and techniques to advance your essential kanban capabilities to the next level.
First, we will explain that kanban is not a process in and of itself,
but is a practice that symbolizes a principle and is
flexible and adaptable based on the challenge at hand and
the necessary resources. Next,
we will discuss the approaches to moving from both waterfall and
agile/Scrum to kanban. Though agile/Scrum greatly improves
development over waterfall, we will explore how kanban takes it a
step further in improving product delivery.
We will also compare Scrum events with kanban events and how kanban will
increase the workflow and productivity of development.
Next, we will go into detail on defining your value stream,
managing work types, understanding what done means, limiting work in progress,
adapting to variabilities,
the benefits of cumulative flow diagrams, and how to
forecast future work dealing with bottlenecks,
blockers, and spikes.
Finally,
the course will take you through the process of
implementing kanban at your workplace.
This will include developing a pilot, applying metrics, and provide the
awareness to challenges that may obstruct or impede your adoption of kanban and
offer recommendations and techniques to mitigate them.
When you have completed this course,
you will have the skills and knowledge on how to design, execute, and deliver high‑quality kanban systems.