Here are the key points of this module to hold near and dear to your heart.
The kanban approach is to deliver value to our
stakeholders efficiently and with quality.
Kanban enables greater predictability by constraining work in progress.
Remember,
this helps manage disorder. By limiting work in progress, your team can
react more quickly and thus prevent issues from building up.
Demand is pulled, not pushed,
and therefore that is why kanban is known as a pull system.
Limiting work in progress also constrains your team size,
therefore your cost, and reduces your lead time, the time it
takes to go through your value stream.
Lastly, shorter lead times benefits quality, agility, and customer satisfaction. Coming up next is Transitioning from Waterfall to Kanban.