As we just learned, bottlenecks are not blockers, so let's dig into blockers.
Blockers.
A blocker is a blocked or impassable work item that
is restricting the flow of work.
It is the work item itself.
Here are just a few examples of work item blockers.
Clarification of requirements.
You are unclear as to what is really meant in the spec,
and you need it to be clarified, and the subject matter expert
is not available, so the work is blocked.
Company policy change. Since the time you specified the
work and when you actually did the work,
the company policy changed.
Now you need to discuss the issue back with the product owner,
the customer or maybe even senior management, so the work is blocked.
Laws and regulations.
Things change fast, for example,
in the health care industry, and you are at an impasse in how to
handle a work item, so the work is blocked.
The business owner is unavailable.
This one might be somewhat common, unfortunately,
and you need her guidance before proceeding.
Your work is blocked.
How about someone on vacation?
Well,
no, that situation is not a blocker, that is just further
limiting your work in progress from, say,
12 resources to 11.
No work item itself is blocked.
You have just fewer resources to perform the work. You want
to easily recognize which work items are blockers so you can
focus your attention on them.
Therefore, visually identify your blockers.
Mark the blocked work item with a special color or visual cue.
This way, you can easily see the blocked items and discuss them at each standup.
Ensure you track the reason, status progress, and other
pertinent information for each blocked work item.
For example,
reason, the algorithm to determine if multi‑tendered
transactions should be allowed is not clear,
and the subject matter expert, Mary, must be consulted.
Blockers are not bottlenecks, and bottlenecks are not blockers.
A blocker is an individual work item that is stuck
and cannot be worked any further, and we previously gave you several examples.
A bottleneck is an issue with capacity,
and you have a buffer filling up with too much completed
work and you can't work it fast enough.
What is similar between the two is that they both impede the flow of work,
but what each one means is different.
Here are some approaches to removing blockers.
Blockers are discussed at daily standups,
discussing the status of the blocker and any ongoing
actions underway to mitigate the blocker. You must have
strong issue escalation processes.
This means you need to know who in management or which stakeholder
may need to be consulted for each type of issue, escalation
policies clearly defined and documented,
and all members clearly understand them,
since not everyone may be available to initiate the escalation.
Escalation policies are jointly agreed to by up or downstream
partners or other management and stakeholders.
This should go without saying, but track all your blockers.
Keep them visible, and in front of you each and every day when you do your standups.