Now let's talk about handling spikes in the kanban world. Spikes are
typically controlled experiments to provide key or research information or
hopefully to clarify any technical issues by setting aside the complexities
of the production code. You would develop small, isolated experiments when
you need to prove a method or approach or just to seek additional
information and/or clarifications.
For the Agile/Scrum practitioners,
it's basically the same as your spikes. Using spikes in
kanban is no issue at all and is simple,
so spikes work with kanban just fine.
Need a spike? Well, simply make a card.
Place the card in the backlog where it makes the best sense
priority‑wise or work type category‑wise. A spike would
likely be at the top of the backlog,
especially if the spike was inhibiting workflow or was tied to a blocker.
Some spikes are created to solve a blocker issue, therefore. Maybe
the blocker was a very tricky technical challenge,
so you can create a card, tie it to the work item, and
put it at the top of the backlog.
Spikes do not flow through completely.
Spikes are doing research, testing maybe
third‑party APIs, or something like that.
Maybe a spike moves through the specify step and maybe the
implement step and maybe even the validate step.
But at the end, its results do not go into production code.
Maybe you have a swim lane in the deliver step where spikes get archived when complete.