Now for my point of view and the module summary.
Here is my point of view.
Here is an interesting thought.
We are likely expected to do ROIs, return on investments,
for projects or determine ROIs for large features or large use cases.
Certainly not a bad idea,
but only if it adds value to the business and if the ROIs are
really used to make business decisions,
and why waste time doing ROIs on everything,
but instead trust the business owner's judgment in prioritizing the backlog.
That works, too.
If an item is important and adds value to the business,
then select it and work on it, don't question it.
How about aging backlog items,
maybe remove those items from the backlog after say x
months, or 6 months, or 9 months, you come up with your own threshold.
If it's just been sitting there for that long, just remove it.
Remember, if the business thinks it's critical important to the business,
that item or something like that item will be added back in later.
And here is another reason why detailed estimates of
everything in the backlog may, in fact, be a waste of time.
Since if items have age and are never implemented,
then why do the estimate in the first place?
It might be that a product owner or customer puts an item in the backlog list,
which is a very large level of effort, indeed,
maybe it appears it is a whole new system.
Basically, you will need to make a judgment call and push back professionally.
If you have a PMO, or a project management office,
that organization should take a closer look and decide if a
whole new project needs to be approved, funded,
and resourced.
Remember, we talked about thresholds earlier in this module?
Some backlog items may be just too big to do without
better fiscal oversight first.
As you can see,
this list has a flavor of overarching policies you will need to define
and they will help guide your work from a macro level.
Kanban has a different way of measuring progress.
Kanban is a continuous flow system and may not be
fully understood by management.
So check out the next module where I discuss how to best
prepare for organizational challenges.
So with Kanban,
there may be less focus on is the project on time, is the plan being
followed, and more focus on is the Kanban process predictable?
Is there a focus on workflow,
and is there a clear continuous improvement with the business? You can see
those are both significantly different from each other.
Here are the key points of this module.
A very important first step in setting up your Kanban system is
determining your value stream, define your boundaries,
the beginning and end, and then all the steps in between. Don't spend
too much time since as you will use the system,
it will evolve quite nicely on its own.
Now that you have your value stream defined, what is the kind or type
of work that will come in, and in the IT world,
they will come in all shapes and sizes.
Hopefully, you can narrow them down to use use cases or user stories,
but be prepared to get all sorts of backlog work types.
The more visual the board, the better. Use colors,
icons, columns,
sub rows, or whatever you want to make the value stream easy to read,
easy to understand, and easy to take action upon.
Remember,
you have the freedom to design the board any way you want that
makes sense and adds value to the business.
Are you done done?
Well done rules are critical to the success of your quality.
Don't just write them down, actually follow them, and if you
pull a task forward and it's not done, we'll give it right back.
Kanban limits the amount of work in progress by doing a couple of
things. First, each resource is working on one and only one work item
at a time. A resource pools or takes new work only when they have
completed their current work item.
And lastly,
the maximum number of work items is set for each workflow step, also
notice, capacity. A bottleneck in a process flow is anywhere that an
accumulation of work builds up waiting to be processed. By visually
seeing the bottleneck, you can quickly take corrective actions by moving
or adding resources or re evaluating other things that you're doing. And
spikes are pretty much handled just like any other piece of work, make a
card,
put it in the backlog, and place it in an order that
makes priority sense. Up next, preparing for organizational challenges. See you there.