Now let's talk about waterfall and traditional development.
Here's what I mean by waterfall.
Waterfall is the practice or approach from writing
specifications through customer delivery over a sequence
of milestones that can cover months, if not years.
Let's talk about a typical traditional waterfall process.
The waterfall model illustrates the software development process in a linear,
sequential flow. The waterfall model is one of the earliest software
development lifecycle approaches that was used for software development. This
means that any phase in a development process begins only if the previous
phase is complete. As you can see, requirements must be done,
signed off, approved, budgeted, and so on before design begins.
As you know, herein lies the key flaw of waterfall, a sequential serial process.
Lastly,
the time to get from requirements to maintenance, that is the lead
time, is just too long in today's business world.
Also, in order to implement a waterfall project,
there's also the need to have a project management methodology driving
the project forward. With traditional development projects, we had
five process groups, initiation, planning,
execution, performance and monitoring,
and lastly, closure. The waterfall development approach works hand in hand
with this traditional project management methodology.
I spent much of my early career using various forms of waterfall.
Let's face it,
it is natural to try and understand the requirements before you write code,
of course,
but do you need to know all of the requirements to the
nth degree before you write code?
I say no.
So, kanban is not only a potential replacement for waterfall, but also for many of the traditional project management methods as well.