It all matters ‑ Michael's three Ps.
So what are Michael's three Ps?
Plan, prepare, and present to management, teammates, and even customers.
Don't just walk into someone's office and say, Hey, let's use Kanban.
It's so cool!
Plan, prepare, and present in a professional style,
and you will be successful at either establishing or
growing Kanban in your organization.
Plan and prepare your case for Kanban.
Have the outcome in mind before you start your presentation.
Know exactly what you want to accomplish and fully
understand your message before you begin.
Who is your audience?
Know your audience and what they may expect from your presentation.
Maybe who you thought would be there is not, and maybe others have showed up.
Always be prepared to adapt.
As long as the core message is in your presentation,
you can use your words to evolve or adapt to reengineer your message if need be.
Research your topic.
It's important to spend enough time collecting and confirming information in
order to speak with confidence and knowledge about Kanban.
Organize the main points in the most appropriate order.
Avoid writing complete sentences or paragraphs and prepare note cards
to help you elaborate on the information presented.
Align your presentation with business interests and objectives.
We've talked about that.
Align the benefits of Kanban to business value. Tie in in how
the application of Kanban may help meet your audience's goals.
Determine your delivery medium.
Use something like PowerPoint.
Your format must be easy to read and understand.
And what I have just said will be a critical element in
delivering your business case for Kanban.
Prepare your presentation.
Okay,
I know. You thought this was a Kanban course, and now I'm
talking about how to deliver a presentation.
Okay, here are a few pointers for you.
Design your presentation to enhance comprehension, know your
audience, maintain good eye contact, engage your audience, speak
clearly and with confidence, look presentable.
Yeah, it matters more than you think.
And be sure the content of your presentation and the words you
choose include Michael's five Cs: Be clear,
concise, courteous, and compelling.
Okay? At the bottom of the screen,
you'll see another one of my Pluralsight courses,
Leadership and Communication Skills for Software Engineers.
So I have a whole bunch of more information in that course if you'd like to pursue that for your presentation.