Let me pose a question to you.
Is time‑boxed iteration dead or obsolete. With waterfall, one iteration
of say 1000 requirements was the approach to get a project done. With
Agile/Scrum, maybe it was 10 iterations of 100 requirements with each
iteration being about 2 to 3 weeks.
So, would maybe 50 iterations of 20 requirements be
better? Hmm, where does this end? Well, the answer lies in this course.
Well, I'll give you the answer, so join me on our
journey into the world of kanban.
Let's cover the key benefits of using kanban. Kanban
enhances a team's ability to focus.
I think we all focus better when you have a visual dimension
with only the critical data on the board.
Kanban offers flexibility and ease of use.
There is no perfect way to do kanban.
Shape it for your team's effectiveness? Sounds agile to me.
Kanban provides easy‑to‑comprehend visuals.
Visuals are simple and clear and therefore easy to understand.
I am a very visual person, so I love it.
Kanban focuses on continuous delivery. With kanban, you see the flow
of work from backlog to delivery or completion,
and you see each step of your delivery process very easily.
Kanban reduces wasted work and time.
I truly believe it saves time and money. And kanban
also enables great team collaboration.
Kanban increases productivity and efficiency.
Because of the items I mentioned above,
you will see an increase of productivity. Also,
what people don't always realize, doing the wrong work
at the wrong time isn't work at all.
It's just waste. Kanban helps doing the right work at the right time for the right reason.