In this section,
we will discuss the Agile/Scrum events and how they map and compare with Kanban.
Let's compare the Agile/Scrum project planning event with Kanban. With
Scrum, the backlog is created by the product owners.
This happens at project initiation at each release and at each
sprint planning meeting. With Kanban, the backlog is created
by the product owners as well,
and this happens once at project initiation and updated as
needed throughout the entire project.
Let's compare the Agile/Scrum sprint planning event with
Kanban. With Scrum, the product owner prioritizes and
selects backlog items for each sprint.
This happens during sprint planning, about every 2 to 3 weeks,
depending on the length of your sprint. With Kanban, items are
pulled from the backlog in the order needed.
The product owner or customer still provides inputs,
of course,
and this happens in no particular frequency, but may be reviewed
daily and is not tied to any 2 or 3 week event.
Let's compare the Agile/Scrum daily standup event with
Kanban. With Scrum, in the standup, you discuss what you have done,
what you plan to do, and if you have any blockers,
those are discussed as well.
This happens daily. With Kanban during the daily
standups, the board is reviewed,
and you'll mostly focus on discussing blockers that
are impeding the flow of work.
You see, the board itself reveals what is being worked by each person,
so discussing what you did and what you plan to do may
be redundant and a waste of time.
Everything is on the board. Now, you do this in no particular
frequency, but usually is reviewed daily.
Let's compare the sprint demonstration/review event with Kanban.
With Scrum, you demo and discuss the working software demonstrated
to the users to get their feedback.
This happens at the end of each sprint,
about every 2 to 3 weeks. With Kanban, customers see
the working software as delivered.
No reason to wait for a special event, and no particular frequency,
either, but usually daily. Let's compare the sprint retrospective event
with Kanban. With Scrum, process improvements are reviewed and discussed
as a team during the retro event.
This happens at the end of each sprint, about every 2 to 3 weeks. With
Kanban, process issues are discussed and corrected as encountered; no
particular frequency, but maybe daily,
so no better time than the present to discuss process issues when they are discovered, and no extra event required.