You must, this is not an option,
measure your success through metrics and reporting.
This will instill confidence in management and be a
big morale booster to your team.
Okay, so let's touch on a couple of simple examples.
Over time, you may want more metrics than I'm about to show you,
but here's a start.
I love metrics,
since I need to understand if the processes we use
to run a business actually work.
I would begin with very simple metrics.
Maybe track just two or three indicators.
Don't go overboard.
You apply metrics to measure productivity, that is how well is your team doing?
The feedback is essential for a few reasons; your team,
so they can see and understand what's happening; your management,
so they can trust that you know what you're doing,
and since they backed a proposal to implement or enhance your use of Kanban,
they want to know if their decision was right; your customers as well,
since they may see a dip in productivity initially as you come online or
change your current Kanban usage. Always provide feedback,
whether good news or not, and if your metrics and reports are showing issues,
well, to me that's a type of good news in a sense,
since you found something in your value stream that needs attention. You always
use the feedback to further enhance and improve, perfect.
Okay, now let's check out some examples.
There is much material on metrics in the Kanban world,
but here are a couple of simple ones to get you going
and jump start your use of metrics.
The first is our favorite, bugs, also known as the flip side of quality.
The algorithm is simple.
Number of bugs worked each day, say four,
divided by the work in progress limits, and in this example,
30. So bugs as a total percent of work in progress for a
particular time period is 13% or 4 divided by 30.
Now,
if you are using a digital Kanban board, then you just need to tag each
work in progress element as either a bug‑related task or not. The tool
will automatically create charts for you,
or if the tool you use does not support metrics,
you might be able to add a plugin to get this information. Okay,
next is throughput.
Throughput is the number of items that were
delivered in any given period of time.
So if we are producing 14 features per week,
well,
that's the throughput. Or another throughput measurement
could be the number of tasks per week,
and you would simply track your throughput over time for each task.
Just these two simple metrics would be very valuable to show your
management, customers, and your team members.
So now that you know my simple algorithm, let's show you some sample charts.
Here are my chart examples. Here is the bugs metric in the chart format.
You can see here that bugs went up to 23% of our workload in these two periods.
We can then discuss and reveal the causes in order to make future improvements.
The other chart is our throughput example looking at features per month.
Plus, I added the moving average.
You can quickly see that May's throughput was less.
This allows you to have a discussion to see what the cause may be.
For example,
it could have been that two people were out sick, then maybe
that's just totally fine and expected.
Also, report and share this information with your team for obvious reasons, but also your management as needed.