Hi and welcome to this course.
First of all, did you know that your B2B web applications and websites are susceptible to so many attacks
from hackers?
Well, if you don't know now, you know, there are so many ways by which hackers could attack your
Web applications and your websites and cause so many problems to your websites that are built using
the HP.
And in this course, I'm going to be teaching you the most important techniques you need in order to
protect your application from these attacks.
There are so many ways that hackers use in order to attack a web application or a website that's built
using B2B.
And many B2B developers and and programmers think that the problem is with the language itself.
They think that B2B is the problem.
And this is absolutely wrong.
This is not right at all.
The problem is not with the language.
The problem is with their code.
The problem is that they don't they didn't learn the best practices and they didn't learn how to protect
their websites and their web applications.
And just to name a few problems that you could face.
And just to name a few attacks that hackers could use to attack your your Web application or your website.
We have the injection.
We have the session and cookie hijacking.
We have the stealing passwords.
We have the reforms that we could inject many things into your forums.
They are so many things by which hackers could attack and cause so many problems to your application.
And in this course, I'm going to teach you the best practices that you need to follow in order to protect
your application against and from these attacks.
For example, I'm going to teach you how to create a log in system that is going to take into account
all necessary measures in order to protect it, to protect it completely against these attacks.
Also, I'm going to teach you how to protect any form you have in your application.
Against injections.
Whether you have a simple website or a big website, you will learn how to protect how to protect it
against these vs attacks.
And then I'm going to also I'm going to also teach you how to protect your database itself from these
attacks and how to make sure that the data that are being displayed through users will not harm users.
So the the problem that the attackers could could do to you could extend to hurt your users, users
who use your applications.
And they're going to teach you how to protect your users from these attacks so that hackers will not
be able to harm users who use your website or websites and your projects and web applications that are
built using P2P.
So by the end of this course, you will have learned the most important techniques that you need to
take into account whenever you are working with BHP.
And you will have learned the most common attacks that hackers use all the time to cause harm to so
many projects and websites and web applications that are built in B2B.
And most importantly, you will have a lot of fun in this course.