Welcome back.
Now it's time to work on connecting with the database.
So in order to connect to the database, you need to edit over to localhost for a dashboard and make
sure that you are about your web server as well as your database are up and running.
You need to make sure that your app is is up and running your skill as well as an Apache web server.
And then you need to click on BHP, my admin.
And then you need to click on user accounts and you will find so many here accounts.
So the one that I'm going to be using is the root, root one 1 to 7 .0.0.1 or the root localhost.
You can use either of them.
So let's use this, for example, root localhost.
So the user name is root, the hostname is localhost.
The password is no, there is no password and the global privileges is all privileges.
So I will be able to use it on the database.
So let's now use these credentials.
So I'm going to hand it over to the project.
And in the project I'm going to create a new file called Called Your.
Called Lamy.
Keith, and you will file.
Gone.
Nation that.
BHP or config, you can name it even config that BHP.
You can name it connection or config can name it this or this.
There is no problem.
And then name here say BHP.
I'm going to say BHP, then I'm going to close the beach.
B And then what we need to do is that we need to say my ask you l I underscore, connect, underscore,
connect.
And then we need to pass four parameters.
So the first parameter is the first parameter is going to be the host name.
So the host name is localhost.
So I'm going to say your local host.
The second parameter is going to be the.
The second parameter is going to be the username.
So I'm going to say here comma and then root because the username.
The username is this username that I chose to use and then the password.
The third parameter is the password and the password is nothing.
So I'm going to say comma and then empty court sequence where with nothing I'm not going to type anything
inside it.
The last parameter is the name of the database.
So what is the name of the database?
Remember?
If you go back, you'll find that I have named my database P2P underscore project.
So I'm going to say here comma and then BHP underscore project.
And then I'm going to say a year or die and then I'm going to type an error message.
And then I'm going to say problem?
Connecting to details and then semicolon.
So let me explain what this is going to do.
I'm going to store this in a variable.
I'm going to say you're going to store this in a variable called con.
Double in is going to be equal to this.
So let me explain what this is going to do.
So what this is going to do is that this is going to attempt to connect to the database.
So here, Michael, I underscore connect is going to try to connect to the database using these credentials.
It's going to try to connect to the b b underscore project database using the localhost and root this
password, which is nothing to the database, to this database.
And if the connection is successful, then this is going to return success and everything is going to
be fine.
Else or die.
If we for some reason, if we couldn't connect to the database, then this is going to return from linking.
Connecting to the to the database.
So this is what
what this is going to do.
This is going to either connect or fail to connect to the database.
And if it fails, it's going to a problem connecting connecting to a database.
Otherwise, it's going to tell us that connection was successful.
Finally, you need to click on file and then save all.