Welcome back.
In order to run our project, you need to open up the terminal that comes with the visual circuit.
So if you click on View and then Terminal, this is going to open up a built in.
As you can see, this is a building where you can run your comments.
And then in this same hall, you need to type the following command.
You need to type B three and then minus S capital S, and then you need to type local hosts.
And then colon 8000.
Or any port you want.
Usually we use 8 hours if you can use 80, 80 or 5000 or 8000 or any port you want.
But usually reports that we use is 8000.
And then once you are done, you need to hit enter and make sure that this command is correct.
BHP minus is localhost calling 8000 and if that is is successful, it's going to say here development
server and this server started, it's going to say that the server is started.
You can now copy this, see what else you can copy this your and let me show you that you can copy this.
You are ale and then you can head on over to the browser.
And in the browser just type localhost colon 8000 or just base that the URL and then hit enter.
And as you can see, what you are going to get is that you are going to get this navigation bar and
this page has been returned because this is the code that we have in the index left BGP.
So this is how it works and this is how you can run your BHP good.