Welcome back.
Now, what I'm going to do is that I'm going to create a table for the sake of explanation.
So I have here this code, this ill code.
I'm going to copy it and then I'm going to paste it in the scale you need to use to select your database.
And then you need to click on scale and then you need to paste this code.
This code is going to generate a is going to create a database table called users.
And it's this table is going to have a user ID, user name, email and password, and it's going to
fail that user.
It's going to fill that table with a few users with like I think five users.
And this is the, this is the command.
And by the way, you can give that manually using BGP, my admin, but using this method it's going
to be easier.
So I'm going to provide this to you so that you can you can create this as well.
Or you can pause the video right now and type this command so you can pause the video and start from
here.
And then you need to type this.
And then you need to tie this.
And finally, you need to type this.
But I'm going to provide this code to you, so don't worry about this.
And then once you are done, click on Go.
And this is going to create a table and insert a few users.
And if you click now on the database, if you click on it, you will find that we have a table here
called users and it has these users one, two, three, four, five.
And each user has ID, user, name, email and password.
And again, you can keep it.
If you don't want to create the table using a scale, you can create a table by clicking on the database.
And here just click on Adjust Your Type, the name of the table and specify the number of columns and
then click on Go.
But this is going to take a little bit more time because you need to do everything manually.
You need to type the name of the database.
You need to specify the columns.
And I recommend using a serial.