Welcome back.
Now I'm going to talk about the most common type of attack that could hurt your application.
And and we need to protect our applications against that attack, which is a skill injection.
This type of injection or attack is super harmful to your application, and it could destroy your application
completely if you don't protect your application against it, because it's probably the easiest way
to hurt somebody or a developer's application because it's popular.
It's easy to use for hackers.
It's easy to to to do it.
Hackers can come up with some clever ways to attack your your your database and destroy your database
or cause any kind of harm to your database.
First, we need to know what is Google injection?
So is IL injection is a way of injecting bad commands into your application that goes to your database
and could either delete or get data or do some kind of party to your database.
And hackers could in inject a commands that could delete things, important things from your database
or could delete your database completely so you will lose everything you've got you have in your database.
Or they could get important data from your database and use it against you to harm you.
So there are also other ways to do harm developers do harm applications and cause detrimental effects
on your database.
But these are the most common ones.
So let me explain what good hackers do to your database.
First, imagine that you have a database.
Usually databases look like this like a.
Cylinder like this.
So imagine that this is your database.
So this is your maybe here type data based here data base.
So this is your database.
Imagine that this is your database and.
Lamy removed this.
And imagine that there is a hacker here.
This is a hacker.
So a hacker is over there.
So the hacker, what a hacker could do to harm your application is that they could inject bad ill commands
to your database.
But how could they do this?
They could do this by using your own application.
So you might have a website.
So suppose that you have a website here.
I'm going to here draw a website.
Suppose that this is your website.
So this is your website.
Web site or Web application or whatever kind of application you have that has connection to the database.
So your application has connection to the database.
And the only way for hackers to get to your database is the easiest way is to use your website because
your website obviously has connection to a database.
So they use your application as a normal user.
And then instead of using your application or website, ethically, they inject a skew ill commands.
So they inject.
Askew ill comments so we know that commands
the major four commands are select.
Select Insert.
And update and delete that.
So these.
These are the most important for coal mines.
And also there are drop for tables and there are also other commands, but these are the most common
commands.
So they they could use select to select data selected.
They could get important information from a specific table or from from the complete database.
They could insert a piece of code that could hurt your database when you when when you get the data
from from the database to your website, they could answer something.
When you when somebody uses your application, they will get that bad code so they could harm other
users.
The, the, the, their, their intention might not just to harm you, but steal other people's credentials
and passwords.
They could also alter your your database fields by using the update.
They could delete data as they told you, and they could drop tables so they could delete a complete
table from your from your database.
So this what a hacker could do.
And there are also other so many other things that they could do.
But these are the most common harms that they could do to your your database.
And I'm going to be showing you examples of how they they could do this and how which is important to
us as developers, is how to protect your application against these attacks.
And then I'm going to give you practical solutions to these attacks.