Welcome back.
So now I'm going to be showing you how to protect yourself against the the cross-site scripting attack
and how to protect your application from being attacked that way.
So the easiest way the easiest way is to use a function called HD Email, a special character.
The solution is to use.
The easiest solution is to solution.
Is to use a special function in it, in each be called the email.
Special.
Character.
So this function is going to check whether the code that has been inserted into your into your website
is a simple text or or if it contains special characters such as scripts, scripts or simple email code
or whatever or any other code that is not recognized as a simple text.
So this function is super powerful when it comes to preventing the excess attacks.
So let me use this function and show you the difference.
So here before before echoing this, if you say here, if you say HD mail, special, special cars,
special characters, and then if you passed the code that has been inserted into this function and then
if you click on file and in stable now.
So now let's test.
Now, if I test me here, try to inject a JavaScript code.
So first, I'm going to remove this completely.
I'm going to remove this and I'm going to refresh my website and I'm going to type here a JavaScript
code.
So here I'm going to say a script and I'm going to try to inject a script here.
I'm going to say here.
Saying Alert like before, I'm going to get hurt and then I'm going to say black cat.
Now if I click on find, guess what?
The card will be displayed as a text.
It's not going to be executed as a JavaScript cut.
Why?
Because this function now, this function, this function recognized that this code is a script.
This code is not a simple text.
So it converted that code into a script and it stopped that card from being executed.
So the code will will just be a simple text.
It's not going to be executed as a as a female code or JavaScript cut.
Let me show you another example.
So here, if I say etch one, if I say it's one like before, and if I say hat, if I say here hat,
and if I click on find, guess what?
The code will be displayed as as just as a text.
It's not going to be displayed as a female code because again, this function took care of this and
recognized that this code is not a simple code and this code could hurt our application that could cause
any kind of damage to our application.
So this, this was just a simple and easy and fast way to, um, to prevent excess attacks.
And it's super powerful because it's easy, it's fast.
You can use it immediately.
You don't have to have a lot of knowledge.
You just need to read what this function does.
Of course you need to be you need to read about this function.
So this function converts a special character to its name HD HTML entity.
So in other words, if you don't understand what this means, it just converts any thing that is not
recognizable as a text to entities to to text it, just going to display that as a text rather than
displaying the actual email.
So this is a super powerful solution to the Axis attacks.