So what tools do you need for this course?
Well, for this course you need, first of all, you need a reliable I.D. or text editor.
And my recommendation is that you install visual Visual Studio code where you can install it from code,
that Visual Studio icon.
You can head on over to that link or that Visual Studio that come and then install it for Mac.
It's going to say here, download for Mac and you can just click on this and install it as if you are
installing any MAC program on your MAC.
If you are using Windows, you can select it from here and it's going to say here download for Windows
by default or you can click here.
If it doesn't say that and you can select your windows here, you can select windows and download the
version from here and you can also install and you should also install it as if you are installing a
program on your windows.
So this is the first thing.
And if you already have a reliable text editor or it is that you feel comfortable going with, then
you don't need to install visual record.
But if you don't, I recommend using Radio City.
So this is the first thing that you need.
The second thing that you need is that you need to install Zap.
Zap is going to is going to allow you to install B2B in order to use B2B for this course.
And you can install it from Apache friends that or you can hear about your friends network and they
will be showing you how to completely install Zap on Mac and also on Windows in the next tutorials.