Welcome back.
Now, suppose that you have a year, a form that allows users to update their email addresses using
their I.D. so the user would provide you with their email and with their ID and their new email in order
to update the current email.
And let me show you the code for this.
So this is the code record is just going to take the ID from the user and the new email and then it's
going to get the ID and the email and store them in variables.
And then we have here a statement that says update users, set user email, question mark, and then
where user IDs is equal to question mark.
And then here I'm using the bind bar and I the S for string because the email is a string and I for
integer because the ID is integer.
And then here I just have a very simple
script out here says echo email.
And here I executed this query and then I, I printed the email.
So let me show you the problem with this.
This so far is great.
There is no problem with it.
The prepaid function is going to take care of the the injection problem.
So you don't have you don't have to worry about anything.
But we still have a problem with the with displaying the data.
So let me show you the way the problem is.
So here.
Suppose that they want to edit my email and suppose that I am a user number 31.
So I'm going to say here my email, my current email, this is admin for at the example dot com.
So here I'm going to say my ID is 31, so I'm going to say 31.
And then let me you type in your email.
I'm going to say my new email.
At example dot com let me click on find I should by the way I should say instead of find I should say
update here update.
So anyways, here is going to be the email and it's going to print the new email.
So as you can see, if you refresh the database, you'll find that my email has been updated and it
says my new email.
However bad users.
Good.
Instead of using this like this, they could inject HD email or JavaScript.
So here, for example, I could say 31 and then I could say script.
And then.
Script.
Let me say here.
Alert.
I'm going I'm going to say hi.
I'm going to click on Update.
And if I click on update, as you can see, the good the JavaScript code was executed, which is a problem.
And, and in the database, if I refresh if I refresh here, my new email is a JavaScript, which is
also a problem.
However, if the effect of this has been taken care of by the repair.
However, we still need to use two functions.
First, we need to use the my.
They make the real scape spring.
So we need to say here Mai Mai is your ally.
Then we need to call a function called real scape string.
And then we need to pass the email.
We need to pass the email.
And whenever we are whenever we are displaying something, we need to use the HD email entities.
And it is.
Let me remove this.
Let me say female entities, and then I'm going to pass the email.
So as a rule of thumb, whenever you are inserting something critical to your database, you need to
use the real shape string.
But the main problem is with displaying something.
So displaying something.
Whenever you are displaying something, you you cannot you cannot guarantee that the user who is using
your application is an ethical user.
A user who is using your application could be a hacker.
Therefore, you need to always use the email entities and also recommended it's recommended to use the
real scape string.
So let me now show you the difference when it comes to displaying something.
First, let me your remove this and instead I'm going to type an email.
I'm going to say admin.
31, at example.
Dot com.
LME now trying to update my email.
So here I'm going to say 31 and again I'm going to try to inject a JavaScript.
I'm going to say script.
Scripts.
Script.
And then in between, I'm going to say.
You're alert.
Black.
At Alamy.
Click on.
Update.
If you click on update, as you can see, the card will not be executed.
The card will not be executed.
As you can see, the code will be displayed as a text.
So the JavaScript good has been blocked by the function.
It has been locked by the email entities because if you are using the email entities, it will block
this code from being executed.
So the main problem here is other users, because if you are storing this in your database, if you
are storing about God in your database and somebody gets that code into their browser, it could hurt
their their their account or their browser or any other thing as long as it's interpreted as a JavaScript
script.
But if it's if it has been interpreted as a text, it is not going to do anything.
As you can see, it's not going to do anything because because party now knew that this code is a bad
is about code and it used the email entities to block that code from being executed.
So whenever you are whenever you are setting something, something into the database, it's very important
to use the real scape string.
And whenever you are displaying something, you need to use the HD email entities or the female
characters of HD special characters that they have already shown you earlier.
So this is how you can stop any bytecode, any bytecode from being executed, especially JavaScript.
Good, because JavaScript code is the most common code that a hacker could use to insert into your system.
So again, use the real scape string, the entities they prepare.
You can also use the DDR, as I have already shown you, the PDR, PDR take.
You need to take everything into account, and you need to apply all techniques that I have shown you
always to take these things into account.
Never use a code that is that that assumes that your customer is a good user and has good intentions.
Always assume the worst.
Whenever you assume the worst, you will take security seriously and you will apply all the techniques
that are needed in order to protect your application and websites against any kind of attack.