Welcome back.
One of the best ways to protect your pages against excesses attacks is to use the header and specifying
the x axis as protection to one and then want a block.
So what this does is that this good is going to try to find if there is a cross site attack against
your against that specific page, and it's going to block that if it happens.
So it's a good practice to add this line of code at the top of a page where where it's where you think
it's vulnerable to these types of attacks.
However, it's not going to happen.
It's going to it's not going to block every excess attack.
So if this can be used just in combination with other methods that I have shown you.
So you shouldn't rely on only one method.
So you cannot just rely on one method and and ignore other methods.
You need to take every single method as a and use it in combination with other methods.
You shouldn't rely on one method.
And unfortunately, many developers rely on one method and ignore other methods.
And this is not correct.
You should always use all available methods that you have in order to block any kind of attack you have.
And this method is a good method that you can add again, you can add to your security tools, so to
speak.