Welcome back.
When it comes to security, one of the most important topics is uploading files.
Why?
Uploading files is important.
It's important because it works as a path between you and users.
Users can reach your back end, so to speak, using you, using files by uploading files.
If you have the if you have if you if you allow or accept uploading files for some reason, for some
functionality or feature in your website, then you are opening the door for users to upload stuff to
your to your back end.
And some users, unfortunately and hackers, unfortunately, could use this to attack your website and
web application.
So whenever you are, you are developing a uploading feature you need to take into account.
You need to take the security seriously into account.
And there are many ways in which the in which hackers could use the uploading feature in your website
or Web application to harm your your software or Web application.
So let me explain what hackers could do.
So suppose that you have here a Web application.
Suppose that this is a Web application and you have your uploading feature that allows users to upload
images, for example, or files.
So this is a button and this is the form.
And the hacker could come over to your website or not just a hacker, any user.
Let's assume that it's a hacker could just come over to your website and use your website, but instead
of uploading what you want them to upload, maybe you are again.
Maybe you are accepting images.
For example, maybe you have a social media
website and you are accepting images.
But that hacker, instead of uploading an image, that hacker could upload a script or a a harmful software
that could cause bad things to your back end or your website or even your database.
Or they could even upload things that are super big and that is is going to take a lot of space.
And maybe your, your website, your or your database has a specific limit you cannot accept.
You are.
File sizes.
Therefore, it's important to take security into account when it comes to uploading files and uploading
harmful softwares.
And Files has been there for quite a long time, and still many web developers and many, many people
who have own websites and web applications suffer from this because they don't know how to protect their
application against these types of attacks.
And unfortunately, Hacker might not necessarily harm your application.
Again, the hacker could upload something and then maybe another user.
Another user is using.
Let's say a good user is using your website and that hacker uploaded maybe a harmful, harmful, harmful
software or file.
And that user unfortunately downloaded that file.
So maybe that user comes over to your website and maybe you are allowing users to download files in
your your website and that user downloaded that file.
And unfortunately, that user's P.C. was destroyed because of that piece of software.
So this is why it's important to take security into account when it comes to uploading files.
And they're going to be showing you how to limit the types of files that you accept so that hackers
cannot apply to any type of file.
And also, I'm going to teach you how to limit the size because because you wouldn't want to allow users
to upload any type, any size, any file size.
You need to add a limit.
You need to be very restrictive because otherwise many bad users would use this against you.
So when it comes to uploading again, when it comes to uploading files, you have to be you have to
add restrictions and barriers in order to block in order to add a wall like this so that hackers cannot
break into your system and cause so many detrimental things to your Web application.