Welcome back.
So now let's test this flooding feature and let me show you what's going to happen when I try to upload
a file.
That's not an image, because as we have shown you here, the script, I have made this script to allow
only images, files that don't have these extensions.
And these are the four most common extensions for images.
Yes.
Being G, G, big and JPEG.
So let me now test this.
So I'm going to click on Choose File and this can see I have here two files.
The first file is obviously an image because here, as you can see, the extension is big.
The second file is female.
So let's try to upload the female file.
I'm going to click on the female file and see what's going to happen.
So I'm going to select the female file and then I'm going to click on Submit.
So if I click on segment, guess what?
I'm going to get this message here.
It says, This is not an image, this is not an image.
So the execution of uploading this image has been stopped.
It has been blocked by my script.
So here, as you can see, this code has been executed.
This is not an image and nothing else will be done after this.
This is going to stop uploading the file because this is not an image.
Let's now try to upload an image.
So here, let me click on to this file one more time.
And now let me select the image.
I'm going to select the image and then I'm going to click on Submit.
And as you can see here immediately, here is this file, upload it successfully.
So let's verify whether the file has been uploaded or not.
So in my in my directory here in my folder uploads, as you can see, this is the image and if I open
it, this is the image that I uploaded.
So it has been uploaded successfully and it means that the script is working and the script is going
to allow only these extensions.
And you can, by the way, you can remove maybe you want to upload, maybe you want to allow users to
upload images, but you accept only being in this case, you can remove the VEGF, you can also remove
the JPG and you can also remove the jpg.
So here this array is going to allow users to upload only being you and you can use this script for
your.
Uh, for your project or in any of your projects to do to allow users to upload a specific type of file.
It could be an image, it could be an email file, it could be a PDF.
It doesn't matter.
You have control over what type of file that the user can upload.
And this is very, very important when it comes to security.