Welcome back.
There are so many ways in which hackers could reach your database and they could steal your database
completely or part of your database, depending upon your level of security that you have implemented.
So the more secure your database is, the more secure your web application is, the harder for them
to get or steal data from your database or from from your web application.
And one of the most sensitive information is the passwords.
Passwords are very, very important.
And as a developer, it's your responsibility to secure passwords.
And in order to secure passwords, storing passwords is very, very important because you cannot store
many developers.
Let me explain this.
Many people developers think that whenever a user whenever let's say that this is a user, whenever
a user gives an account, suppose that you have he suppose that you have a web application and here
you have a registration system.
This is a registration registration system.
Many developers think that when a user comes over to their application and registers, they think that
that's it.
They only need all they need to do is to get their password.
Get the password.
This is the password.
Password and probably probably email, email and password.
And just to store that email and password, store that email and password in a database.
In a database.
Suppose that this is a database.
They think that that's it and unfortunately, that's not it.
You cannot store passwords, passwords, especially passwords like this.
You cannot just throw all passwords in the database.
And I think that they are secured and nobody will be able to get a hold, so to speak, of these passwords.
Hackers can easily access your database if you if you don't have if you didn't implement security measures
that you needed and if you did not increase security measures to a level that would prevent them from
accessing your database.
So what hackers could do is that they could get hold of your database.
They could steal information from your database.
Suppose that this is a hacker.
Hacker.
A hacker could steal your database or part of the database.
And that part could contain passwords.
It could contain passwords of users.
Therefore, you need to kind of encrypt these passwords.
If you encrypt these passwords, even if a hacker if a hacker steals these passwords, that hacker will
not be able to do anything with these passwords because they are encrypted.
So one of the most important measures that you think you need to take.
Is to encrypt passwords.
And the good news is that there are so many functions that provide encryption and they have different
levels of security.
But the good news is that there are so many of them.
So you can use one of these functions.
And trust me, if you use one of these functions, the the any hacker that steals passwords from your
database will not will not will probably not be able to work on kind of on encrypt passwords.
The, the algorithms using are used for, uh, for encrypting passwords are so complicated and hackers
will not be able to encrypt passwords.
Of course, again, there are different levels of encryption.
Some functions don't don't encrypt passwords
securely, I should say.
But there are functions that are so strong and would encrypt your your passwords in a way that hackers
will not be able to do anything with these passwords.
And it would be very difficult, even if they try to encrypt these passwords, it would be very difficult
for them to do so.
So a great solution when it comes to passwords is to encrypt passwords.
This is one of the most important things that many developers, unfortunately, many B2B developers
and many developers in general don't do.
They just store.
They just store password.
You're supposed that this is the email field in your database and this is the password field here pass
word.
They just store the email and password as as they are.
So here at a store, for example, example.
At example dot com and they saw the MLB password, for example, the password is one, two, three,
four, five.
They store them in the past in the database like this.
They saw them in the database like this.
And I'm going to be showing you an example of what many developers do and what and how you can encrypt
passwords and secure your passwords so that hackers will not be able to do anything with these passwords.
Even if they steal these passwords, they want to be able to encrypt these passwords.
So it's a terrible practice to store passwords as like this, like text like this.
You need to encrypt passwords.
And I'm going to be showing you a great example of how you can encrypt passwords.