Welcome back.
One of the ways that hackers used to steal things from your Web application and hurt your application
or users is to do what's called the station hijacking.
So what is session hijacking?
A session hijacking is stealing information from a currently logged in user.
So normally whenever you whenever you have a log in system usually and most websites app log in and
registration system users would log in.
And once they log in, their information will be stored in your in the browser, not, not in the database.
So let me explain this.
So suppose that you have your A website.
This is a website.
And here a user comes over to your website and logs in.
This is a user user.
So a user would come to your website and log in.
So a user would log in.
So of course, in order to log in, they type their email and password.
And you would normally bring things from the database such as their name, their information, and store
them in a session.
You would normally store that in a session.
Why?
Why would you want to do this?
Because you want to display information.
Maybe you have a profile page and you want to display their information so that they know their information
or want to update their information.
But unfortunately, a hacker, a hacker could use aka could use the this this technique, the session
hijacking to steal this session.
So there are so many ways to do this.
And hackers, again, come up with new ideas and techniques to do to do session hijacking.
But the point is that you as a developer, you need to protect your application against session hijacking.
So what would you do?
Well, first of all, first of all, you need to use.
You need to use session or sessions in a B2B.
Sessions.
You need to use sessions wisely.
And not just wisely, actually effectively, I should say.
Effectively, because I think.
Tively because about.
Good, good, good, good, good.
You're good.
Could hurt you could hurt your application.
So you need to write an effective good effective good that that always checks the session and how long
the session has been and who is logged in and when did when did that person log in?
And always, always, always, always, always destroy.
Destroy session.
We never.
Whenever.
Something.
It wrong.
Whenever something is wrong.
Whenever something is wrong, you need to destroy the position.
Unfortunately, many, many developers think that stations is a secure way to store data because the
data will be deleted automatically if a user logs out, looks out, or if a user leaves the browser
and logs down, the browser decision will be deleted.
And this is not correct because a hacker could still steal the session and hijack sessions.
So this is a one technique which is destroying the station and using your could effectively.
The second solution is to use is to use H.
The ETP s always use https, especially whenever you have a payment system.
So this is method number one.
Let me hear say one.
And to reduce it.
If you don't use it or use it, if you don't use HDP, just stupid use HDP, it's always third.
You need to warn users.
Unfortunately, this is this method is the user is the user responsibility.
It's not unfortunately, it's not your responsibility.
Because if you do everything and a user doesn't use the the the your application wisely.
And if the user doesn't use your application the right way, they could put their data in in jeopardy
by not by not following best practices.
So a user could, for example, log in and leave their phone or their PC open.
So this could allow other users to or or hackers to steal their information.
If a user, for example, logs in and never logs out again, a hacker could still steal a user's information.
And you need to warn users.
To.
Look out when ever they are done.
So if they are done, always tell users to look out here.
Always let them know that they must look out whenever they are done and never log in and stay logged
in.
When they are.
When they are finished, they must look out when they are done.
A fourth method which is regenerating the session.
So many developers only a session and store it in in cookies and they don't regenerate decision for
a very long time.
And this is not a good thing.
You need to regenerate.
Session.
So.
Three he married cision, so whenever a user logs out you need to remove the station and then whenever
they log in, you need to you know, you need to.
Three visionaries, you need to recreate their cookie or session and or session and always remove the
cookie or session after a specific amount of time.