Welcome back.
So what are the other measures that you should take in order to protect your application and websites
against any potential attack?
Well, one of the best ways is to use B2B frameworks.
And why would they recommend using frameworks?
Well, there are many reasons for this.
And I by the way, I wouldn't recommend using all frameworks.
I'm going to be showing you examples of great frameworks.
But first, let me explain why you should be using B2B frameworks and when to use frameworks.
The reason why I recommend some frameworks is because the code has already been created.
First, could the project the mean it mean code.
Let's say you got the main code and the essential code is already created.
Is there?
It's there.
You don't have to recreate the code.
Second, many frameworks take security into account.
Security.
Is.
They can.
Gear up.
And of course, with many with different, it depends upon the framework and the security measures that
they have taken.
So basic security measures have been taken care of by so many frameworks such as SQL injection access,
S attacks, excision, hijacking.
So many things are taken care of by many framework, by many PDB frameworks.
The third reason why I recommend using frameworks is because it would it would allow you to follow.
Follow specific.
Specific.
Procedure or procedures when it comes to developing so you don't have to your team, if you are working
with a team, don't have to work or create a code that is different from one another.
They will be forced to follow a specific techniques and a specific a specific pattern usually.
In many B2B frameworks, the M, the C, the MVC design architecture.
MVC is used and the MVC is going to make your code very organized and easy to debug whenever you have
bugs and whenever you want to add an extra layer of security.
MVC, which is which stands for Model View Controller, is going to take care of this because you will
be forced to follow a specific design pattern.
Also by using frameworks the logic system usually many frameworks provide a pre created a pre developed
logging system.
So the logging system has already been created and it's very, very secure in many frameworks.
So you don't have to create a logging system from scratch.
The logging system in many B2B frameworks is mainly from what many frameworks provide their logging
system, and usually the logging system is very secure and it will hash passwords properly without without
the need to hash passwords and encrypt passwords.
So this is one of the reasons why I recommend using frameworks, but what are framework works that I
recommend?
The first framework that I recommend is Laravel.
Why would they recommend using a Laravel?
Lara Lavell Lavell is a great framework and it takes care of security, and security is probably number
one priority and security is their priority.
Whenever you are trying to create a forum, they will force you to use.
The CSR is going to protect against excesses and also they have a great logging system.
The, the, the design act architecture that is used to develop Laravel is the MVC.
So this is why I recommend using Laravel and you don't have to reinvent the wheel.
And by the way, if you are passionate about developer and want to learn Laravel I have created so many
courses about Laravel and how to create so many different applications using Laravel, how to create
e-commerce website after a car dealership website.
How to create a chatroom using Laravel.
So many applications I have created courses around where you can take.
So this is the first framework that they do come in.
Another framework that I recommend is symphony.
Symphony.
Symphony is another agreed framework that I recommend using.
It also has so many amazing features that you can use and and you will not be you will not you will
not need to reinvent the wheel because many things are taken care of.
And also security is is a priority in a symphony framework.
So a symphony is also a great framework that you can use.
There are also other frameworks such as cake, BHP cake.
BHP is also a good framework that I'd recommend if you don't want to use Laravel or Symphony, but in
in some cases you might want to use your own BHP code.
In this case I wouldn't say you should use a framework.
In this case I would say you just use your code, but you need to follow the techniques that they have
taught you in this course and you need to always be up to date when it comes to security and you need
to take security seriously because if you are creating your own code, you are the you are responsible
for everything.
If you.
Again, if you create.
You were on guard then.
Take.
Please take.
Security seriously.
Because you are responsible for your good and you should take security seriously and avoid these in
order to avoid these attacks.
So again, if you want to use your own card, that's fine.
There is no problem with this.
In fact, some of my projects, some of my beach projects, I didn't I did not use any of the frameworks.
I created the codes from scratch because because they wanted to create my own code for for for many,
many reasons.
However, in some projects I use Laravel a lot because it it takes care of many things and I don't have
to reinvent the wheel.
But some customers still want to create their own B2B code.
And you as a developer, you might want to create a script, a B2B script or a B2B project from scratch
because of many, many reasons.
There are many reasons why you would want to create your own B2B good.
But either way, you should take security seriously.
Even even if you are using a framework such as Laravel, you need to double check security and you need
to follow best practices in order to avoid any attacks.