So once Zoom is installed, you will find it among your applications.
So if I click on this manager, it will open it for me and it might ask you for your PC or Mac password
and then I'll go to manage servers.
And first of all, you need to run the Apache Web server.
Click on Start and we wait until here.
It says Running.
And once here it says Running, you can start your MySchool database, click on check it or click on
it and then click on Start.
Once a year, it says running, you'll be able to work with the Apache Web server and you are my skill
database.
And by the way, if it forcefully goes back to stopped either the Apache Web server or the MySchool
database, then you might need to restart your PC or your Mac.
Once these two are running, go to welcome again here.
Head on over to go to application and click on it and it will open the localhost and this.
And here in the localhost you can check information about your PHP installation and your database as
well.
So if I go to BHP, my admin.
Well up in BHP, my admin where I can manage my databases and tables and do operations on their.
And by the way, whenever you are working, just keep the Apache Web server up and running.
And also the MySchool database running all the time, because otherwise you won't be able to work with
the database and insert data and get data and all of that good stuff.