First of all, to download the app, we are going to download Champ, click Champ inside Google and
now you have this website about your friends.
Click on it.
And now you have all the downloads for all the operating systems available, like the ones that you
are using.
I'm going to I'm using Windows, so I'm going to click on Windows.
And here it says the version of BHP, it's 7.2, click on it and it's going to start downloading.
And after it, it's finished.
What you need to do is just click a few next and you are good to go.
And this is here a short video that tells you how to do so.
It's just a few a few nicks.
It's not difficult at all.
I'm going to stop here downloading because I already installed it.
So after installation, you should find it here.
As you can see, I already have.
I already have it.
So if you click on the if you search after installation or chance.
You have the control panel, click on it and you have this panel.
And the one that we are going to use is the Apache, the server, so that we make our our computer as
a server, you need to click on start and be my is q l as well so that we can use my ask you L for Laravel.
You need also to click on Start.