So in order to add to your environment first falling into the environment variables from your start
menu and then click on environment variables and then scroll in the system variables and then select
path and open the path.
And then he or you should find that you have Zam BHP, you should have backslash some backslash.
B If you don't you need to click on you and then you need to add it.
You need to add C and then colon backslash, zap backslash, BHP and once you have done that, all you
need to do is that you need to click on okay and then okay, this is going to add BHP to your path where
you will be able to use BHP from any location in your windows ten.
Now if you open the seam the unti BHP minus V, it's going to work.
And here if you open the terminal in reduce recurrent and just type B minus V, it's going to print
out the BHP and it's going to here tell you that BHP exists.
So this is how you can add BHP to your path in Windows.