So in order to add but B2B to your environment variable, first of all, let's check if B2B exists or
not.
I'm going to open this e-mail and then I'm going to type B minus B and as you can see, it says here,
B2B is not recognized.
So let's first of all get the path of B2B.
And in order to get the path of B2B, I'm going to open my local desk.
And then in the local desk we have jump up and jump and then up in B2B.
And as you can see, this is the location of B2B.
I'm going to get that location.
I'm going to copy that location.
Copy it.
And then I'm going to open the I'm going to open the properties of the computer and then I'm going to
open the environment variables from the advanced settings.
And then I'm going to add, I'm going to scroll and then I'm going to add B2B to the path.
I'm going to click the path and then click edit and then just add here, just add semicolon and then
paste paste record that you got, which is C and then and then B2B, I think like, okay.
And then okay.
And this is going to add B2B to your environment variable or path.
Now let me open up this in the one more time and then in this end I'm going to type beach B minus B,
now beach B exists as you can see here, it's displaying the beach B version.
So A beach B now exists.
So this is how you can add B2B to your path.
And it's very important to add to added to your path in order to be able to work with it.