Valuation now that you understand financial modeling we can move on and discuss valuation.
So by the end of the section you will have an even better understanding of growth versus value and valuation
best practices in general.
So what are we going to do.
Well we're going to look into how to value companies on several different basis.
OK so price to earnings price Cirebon discounted cash flow Okay.
Why.
Why are we looking at different ways to value companies because different types investors value companies
different ways.
OK so a value investor doesn't value companies the same way that a growth investor does.
When it comes to picking target prices and the reason we look at several different valuation methodologies
is because one of them is going to be wrong.
I don't know which one.
Right.
But if you look at three and take an average of all three you can normalize the error OK minimize the
error.
OK.
All right so how are we going do this.
Well I'm going to talk a lot more about growth versus value.
OK.
Very important topic and I'm going to show you examples within Excel and we're going look at G-III right
which is value ish versus Tesla which is definitely an expensive growth company.
Okay let's get started.