You understand how to model companies how to create financial statements how to value companies.
We're going to take it to the next level which is analyzing companies using formulas.
And so by the end of this section you'll be able to understand why being able to read financials like
a good book is crucial for analysts when assessing the health of the company.
So what are we going to reassess the health of companies.
Why are we doing it.
Because we want to look out for red flags before they occur.
Or at least know about them as they're occurring.
And you're also going to have a number of exercises yourself to do.
I hope you enjoy the section