Let's talk about the income statement but hold on a second.
I'm going with the income save on hold for a couple of sites.
I want to give you a very quick accounting introduction.
There's three financial statements that we'll be looking at.
There's the balance sheet which tells you what do we want.
Then there's the income statement that tells you how much money do you make.
And then there is the cash flow statement and hold on a second.
How much money do I really make.
See the income statement doesn't tell you how much more cash you're getting in your pocket cash.
It's actually not accurate.
Right and so we knew third final statement called the cash flow statement and that will tell you how
much you really have cash wise.
OK.
And it will basically look at the income statement and correct it for you.
I want to put that in your.
I want to put that on the radar screen.
We'll come back to that shortly.
OK great.
Back to the income statement.
So by the end of this section you will understand why an income statement is really important and how
to analyze an income statement so that you can create and understand financial modeling.
OK.
So we're into an accounting background for the next three sections.
The income set the balance sheet the cash flow statement.
Okay.
And then once we tie all that together then we can model companies.
OK let's just start with the income statement.
So in the section we're going to talk about what is the income statement and what purpose does it have
.
We're also going to talk about why we create the income statement and the reason is if you don't create
an income statement and model into the future you'll never know how much a company is worth and what
the target price is going to be.
And the way we're going to do this is we're going to go through a number of different Excel spreadsheet
examples