Let's talk about financial modeling best practices and I'll include a PTF of all these best practices
for you to take with you.
The two most important rules are very very easy.
Rule number one.
Almost every single projection on your financial statements is a percent of revenue.
Rule number 2.
Look for patterns in the data.
One data point doesn't make a trend but a couple does right.
And so a good way to think about it is this.
If I throw a ball across the room an object in motion will stay in motion for a long period of time
.
Right.
OK.
So most public companies have revenue growth that is slowing right that objects in motion right.
Revenue growth is slowing.
It's not their fault.
They're just big companies and so private companies that are backed by venture capital firms have revenue
growth that accelerating.
And once revenue growth is decelerating a bit the company goes public.
And so a lot of great companies that are publicly traded have revenue growth that's slowing.
So it's their fault.
So if you see that revenue growth is really accelerating for a company that publicly traded there's
a very good chance they bought a company.
OK.
They made an acquisition and that's not or cannot grow.
That's nonorganic growth.
And you have to know the difference between the two of them.
We'll look at that in an exercise.
Number five.
If revenue growth is down a lot what happens is the company focuses on improving profits.
Why.
Because the growth investors want revenue growth to be high but revenue if revenue growth is slowing
too much then growth investors will buy the stock.
And so management will basically try to make profits go up more.
So value investors will buy the stock.
Number six Don't talk to the CFO or CEO or I are.
Until you built your model we covered this before.
They're great salespeople.
Number seven if a company has a lot of cash they'll buy shares or other companies and sometimes issue
a dividend as well.
And if the company has too much cash then what happens is activist investors might buy the stock get
on the board and force the company to restructure or issue big dividends or heck somebody could take
a private event.
OK number eight forecasting tax is really really hard.
Just use the historical tax rate.
OK.
And you can find that in the S.E.C. filings which will cover will cover sin.
Number nine hard coded items right and you'll see these on all the financials statements.
We're in a great hard quarter I'd items mean non formulas.
They should be in blue means you hardcore and the type that don't worry this makes sense soon.
Number 10 items linked to another Excel tab should be in green.
This is just a standard I created.
I really think it makes sense because the whole modeling process gets so complicated if you don't have
different color coding.
I'll show you in a minute and many comments on your model.
Right.
In Windows you type shipped up to an Excel and you can add comments in iMac.
What you do is you right click on a cell and you can add a comment.
And the reason you do this is because you'll come back and revisit this model in the future.
And it's really confusing if you don't know what you were thinking at that point in time when you entered
information in that model.
Okay.
And if you work in on big teams and you entering comments you should put your initials first at the
beginning and the date as well just so your team knows who wrote what number 12.
If the model is too complicated for you dumb it down by grouping items together and I'll show this to
you in the example.
Modeling isn't art and science and I promise you you'll never be 100 percent right.
You want to be directionally correct.
OK.
Don't get worried if you're not 100 percent right.
Nobody ever is number 14 when you're done with your model.
Sleep on it and then revisit it the next morning.
Right.
And if you still feel great about what you've created then you're done.
Number 15 No the size of the markets right.
The total addressable market for a sanity check and I'll be doing this with the LinkedIn case study
soon.
Number 16.
Add every little piece of data that the company provides you in the quarterly earnings press releases
to your model.
Even if you don't use it.
Number 70 percent item should be italicized right.
Number 18 spend a lot of time printing up your model make it look perfect right.
Even the formatting and everything I know it sounds crazy but just take pride in having a perfect model
or a model that's easy to read I should say.
Number 19 you have the same access as the professionals do.
OK.
Have fun doing this.
They don't have an edge on us anymore.
Right.
You get access to the same information that they do because of the Internet and because of government
regulations called Reg F.D. or fair disclosure.
You have the same access as everybody else.
Name your rose cat.
And this is what I mean.
What you can do is you can highlight a row like Row 9 see and then go up to the top left corner of Excel
and type in revenue.
And that way it's like using English instead of code.
Right and searcing divide.
X by so why whenever you can say divide it by revenue.
Right.
And Eckels in your formulas