All right this is my favorite part valuation.
I absolutely love it.
And you need to know what kind of an investor you are though or what kind of investor your clients are
.
And quite often they're quite different from what you are.
And so let's look at two real examples here.
You've got General Electric I'm one in the spectrum and Tesla on the other end and General Electric
is for value investors meaning investors that like to get a dividend yield and buy stuff that's relatively
cheap.
And on the right side on the other end of the spectrum you've got Tesla which is for growth investors
and growth investors love companies that are growing very fast and they don't want the companies to
be very profitable today because they wanted to grow they wanted to hire a lot of sales people grow
revenue quickly and they can be profitable one day many years from now kind of like Amazon.
OK so you need to know who you are and what your investors are and of course the quintessential example
of a value investor is Mr. Warren Buffett.
So just know where you are on the spectrum and in the middle of the spectrum.
Sometimes people are what are called Garp.
They're not value they're not growth in the middle.
And that stands for growth at a reasonable price growth at a reasonable price and all growth investments
eventually become value investments and so for years and years and years Microsoft was an incredible
growth investment and then it entered a period of purgatory for 10 years.
It wasn't growth that wasn't value was stuck in the middle and now it's finally more of a value investment
than it was before and stocks that get caught in the middle are never worth investing in.
Ok cool.
So this is the end product don't get too bogged down in this yet.
OK.
I just want to know that there's three different valuation methodologies that we're going to tackle
in this section.
OK.
Three of them let me cover it up though.
So there's three different types of methodologies we'll be looking at.
The first is price to revenue.
Okay.
And that's basically for companies that don't have earnings and so obviously growth investors love it
then there's a price to earnings ratio which will we'll analyze as well.
That's my favorite.
And then there's something called discounted cash flow which is what the value investors like and we
can look at a gazillion different types of valuation methodology.
If we wanted to like price to book or enterprise value or even multiples as well.
But let's just keep it simple.
Look at these three for now.
Okay great.
So price to revenue is again one that growth investors love to look at.
Okay and it's great for value on profitable companies.
Great for companies or pardon me for comparing to similar firms especially those that are also not profitable
.
And again growth unless investors love price or revenue.
And then we've got price to earnings and this is really good for valuing relative earnings growth rates
and this is called a PEG ratio.
And so if a company is growing earnings at 10 percent and it Taitt trades at 10 times earnings it's
kind of peg of one.
If a company is growing earnings at 10 percent and has got a price earnings ratio of 20 times then it's
got a peg of two.
You've got it.
So growth and value investors love P and then the last one here is discounted cash flow.
This is where cash is king and this kind of cash flow is really all about what future money the company
is going to make is worth today.
And so you have to discount future cash in today's terms and we'll do this in a minute or so.
Value investors love DCF and and growth investors do not.
Ok cool.
So what we're going to do is we're actually going to get the average of all three of these methodologies
to come up with our target price.
Price to earnings plus discount cashflow plus Prester only divided by 3 is de-value rent.
We're going to get here for our company and the reason I like to choose at least three different valuation
methodologies and investment bankers do this a lot to an IPO's is because there's going to be a margin
for error.
One of your valuations is going to be off.
You don't know which one it is.
But this will kind of normalize your margin of error so to speak.