Price to earnings and this is pretty simple it's just pulled directly off of the income statement tab
you see there and it's green because it's coming off another sheet and this is the annual year over
year growth.
Now remember we're assuming because revenue growth is decelerating LinkedIn wants to make certain shareholders
happy.
Right.
Because they're going be losing some shareholders here some growth investors might you know jump off
ship here.
They may not want investing more because growth is slowing.
So some of the more gossipy investors right are happy to see hey check this out.
You've got yearly growth earnings growth is accelerating That's pretty cool.
OK.
So how do you come up with the right valuation for a company on a basis.
Well remember before I mention the PEG ratio right.
So if we assume that a company trades in line with its growth rate.
Right.
Which is what the market usually does over time.
The market usually trades at about roughly 15 times earnings because the market's growing at 15 percent
.
And so if a company is growing at 30 percent earnings it's titrated 30 times.
That's actually a good rule of thumb.
In fact if a company misses earnings by 50 percent then usually the stock was down close to 50 percent
.
Right.
It's a one to one ratio.
Usually there are exceptions.
And so here what we do is this market cap right.
You basically take you basically take the price this year price her right you take $9 and 64 cents and
you multiply it by 30 times or 30 percent times higher.
OK.
And that's a peg of one.
It's 30 percent here 29 times here 27 times.
Get that up here in the bullish scenario.
Sometimes you get this in bull markets where companies trade at two times that earnings growth rate
get terror and it happens.
So here two times earnings growth rates are 60 times earnings which is too high.
We'll get to that target price and then the just right cap is in between 1 and 2 which is 1 1/2 times
earnings growth.
And so in this year here we see that one and a half times earnings growth times our EPS get to higher
price of 434 let's discount this guy down to today's terms like we did over here and basically that
means we take this divided by one plus the whack to the power of four.
And that is our just right price earnings target price