It's really important to do your own due diligence on companies meaning try the product if you can.
And so let's do this with linked and let's do advanced search and let's search for people that work
at Google.
See if we know anybody there.
And so there's three red line items when it comes to in.
And the first line item we look at is the premium subscriptions which basically gives the opportunity
to send messages.
The next one is talent solutions so let's look into this.
Let's check this out.
It looks like this is for our professionals or human resources professionals to be able to find candidates
or post candidates online.
And you can get a free trial as well I do this all the time when I'm doing due diligence on companies
.
Oh good question Mo.
What is linked in marketing.
Let's check it out.
Well when you go to Linked In There are commercials on the sides of the pages sometimes.
So what I did was for one of my courses an entire MBA and one course I tried to promote it.
And you can set the audience so in this case I said a bunch of states and then I also explained what
industries to use or to target and the age group is actually pretty powerful.
Do they have competitors.
Good question.
We've covered this before but just go to as you see talk of do a search on the 10-K.
Open up that document and just search for the word competitor and then you can just search through the
rest of the document to see who their competitors really are.
Let's see if Facebook really has a competitive product.
So let's just do a search to see if they have competition.
And here's a force article talking about Facebook at work.
I know there is a plug in for Facebook years ago called branch in I believe that was a dud.
They try to compete.
But the problem with Facebook is that it's just not as trustworthy as linked in as OK so looks like
there's a competitor here called for a day of dot com.
Here we go.
Let's check it out for the group.
All right.
So I've got 720000 recruiters and professionals.
We can try it and we can sign up for free and let me sign up here and so funny I told you I don't trust
Facebook privacy and yet here I go I'm signing up.
Anyway I think you get the idea.
Just trying to test as many competing products as you can.