Why does net income not equal the increase in cash.
If we look at the income statement that we did two sessions ago we had 375 thousand seven hundred fifty
dollars in net income.
And if we look at the balance sheet that we did last exercise the increasing cash from 2014 is 2015
is $200000.
So why the difference.
What explains the increase in cash by $200000.
Well we need to have another statement to help us with this and that statement is called the cash flow
state.
So what we're going to do is we're going to look at the actual income statement and balance sheet examples
from the previous two sections and then we're going to create a cash flow statement right now from scratch
before we do that though let's just take a quick look at the three sections of a cash flow statement
.
So the cash flow statement is made up of three items as false.
Number one cash flow from operations and this basically means stuff that has a duration of under one
year meaning stuff from the income statement and the balance sheets current assets and current liability
sections except for debt.
And I know that sounds like a lot but basically we're just going to look at the cash flow from operating
our business for less than a year.
Okay so the income statement is always for a period of a year or less.
And if you look at the current assets and current liabilities on a balance sheet for the most part those
items all have a duration of less than one year.
Okay that's the first part of the cash flow statement.
Cash flow from operations.
Remember what we're trying to do here is to try to reconcile the difference between net income from
the income statement and the changing cash from the cash flow statement.
Okay.
Now we do is we add cash flow from investing and basically you go to long term assets and if we spent
money investing in stuff like machines or land then we're going to deduct that from our cash flow statement
.
So think of this always as cash in your pocket or cash out your pocket.
And remember a while ago I said that the income statement is a lie.
Well I was half joking because income statement does not tell you the increase in cash.
And neither is a balance sheet the balance sheet will tell you the change from one year to the next
in the cash balance but it will explain how to get that increase in cash.
And that's why we're doing this exercise.
That's why we're creating this cash flow statement.
And the third part is Castro from financing from debt or changes in common stock.
OK.
And let's look at the previous two financial statements the income statement and the balance sheet and
let's create a cash flow say from scratch.
OK let's kick it off with cash flow from operations.
What we do is we always get net income right because what we're trying to do is we're trying to say
why the income statement is not a good representative of the increase in cash that we have.
Okay.
So we we get net income and then what we do is we add back the non-cash items from the income statement
.
So take a look there on the right and tell me what is not cash depreciation and amortization.
Okay those are non cash expenses.
All right so it's not fair it's not a benefit that we get per an increase in cash.
It just decreases our taxable base.
Okay.
So we added that back in then what we do.
Step three Remember we're just looking at stuff that's less than a year.
We go the balance sheets current assets and current liabilities section and we get that on cash items
.
So let's do that.
OK.
So we've got accounts receivable So check it out there on the right accounts receivable increased by
$50000.
Right.
And that means that somebody owes us 50 grand.
From a sale we made.
But we should not have gotten the benefit of getting that 50 in our pocket because we haven't received
that cash yet.
By the same talk with inventory.
We spent an extra 25 grand on it Sasha come out of our pocket and then look down there on the liability
section of the balance sheet accounts payable went up $5000.
And that means that we have five grand more in our pocket because we haven't paid that amount yet.
So let's add this now.
OK.
So what we get is we deduct those first two items because that's cash out of our pocket.
And then we add accounts payable because it's cash in our pocket.
And then what we get is cash flow from operations.
Okay.
So we're done with one third now.
The cash flow statement.
I really tried to understand why this is the case don't just memorize this.
Please try to look through the financial statements and understand why this exists.
Why is it 310000 1750.
What is the purpose of this financial statement.
So if you understand finance and accounting statements then you'll remember them don't memorize them
please.
OK.
Now we move on to Step Two of the cash flow statement.
Right.
So we like cash flow from investing.
We invested in stuff like we bought machines or land that's cash out of our pocket.
So let's check it out.
So of course we get this from the balance sheet.
Let's do this.
So there we go we've got land.
We spent 10 grand more in the past year on land and 50 grand more on the machine.
And so that becomes 60 grand.
OK good.
So we're getting there.
We're two thirds of the way there now.
So we've got one more thing to do in the cash flow statement which is cash flow from financing meaning
if we got a loan or we had a change in common stock.
All right let's check this out.
So we get this from the liabilities and equity section we can see that short term debt went down.
That's a good thing we paid off debt.
But you know what.
That's 10000 and bucks out of our pocket because we paid it back.
Long term debt went down by a hundred grand.
Again it's good we're paying off debt but that's 100 grand out of our pocket and we issued $60000 worth
in new common shares let's just add all of that stuff up right now.
And so for cash flow from financing taking into account all of that that's minus 50000 750 out of our
pocket most of that came from long term debt.
Ok cool.
Now let's add these three items together and what do we get.
There you go.
That explains a $200000 increase in the cash balance.
That explains the increase in the $200000 in our cash balance from 2014 to 2015 and cash.
And I'll show you what that looks like on the balance sheet.
Right.
So there you go.
200000.
That explains the difference.