All right we're almost done with DCF.
One more thing though and that one more thing is the interest rate.
Remember before it was 7 percent we just accepted that.
Well now you're going to calculate an interest rate.
OK.
And that's called the weighted average cost of capital.
So your interest rate was seven we also call that the discount rate.
Right.
Just another word for it.
The discount rate was 7 percent OK.
So now that was your whack also by the way the discount rate is also called the whack.
OK.
So from now on when we talk about the interest rate which is the same thing as discount rate.
It's called the whack.
OK.
The weighted average cost of capital.
So how do we calculate the work.
Well the weighted average cost of capital or the W.A.C.C. equals the cost for your company to use debt
plus the costs for your company to use equity.
When that door will go in more detail in a second.
All right.
So you take the costs for your company use debt and then you multiply it by the percent of capital that
you're going to use that's debt.
OK.
So your capital is either debt or equity.
Stay with me here.
OK.
Simplify it.
So the cost used that times the percent of your capital structure that's debt plus the cost use equity
times the percent of your capital structure that's equity.
Okay.
So costs are used at plus the cost use equity.
Okay costs to use debt times the percent of that cost to use debt including tax benefits times the percent
of debt.
Now we use debt you get a tax benefit for using it.
Right.
So cost used at times when my tax rate.
Now let's assume that 40 percent of the capital in our company is debt and 60 percent is equity and
cash.
So we'll replace that there. Times 40 percent and we'll put 60 percent there for that.
Boy OK.
And let's assume that the tax rate is 30 percent never calculate tax rate.
Just ask the company or look at historical tax rate they use this to heart.
So 30 percent right cost used debt times one minus 30 percent which is point three times 40 percent
.
All right.
We're getting there now.
Let's assume a bank loan would be 5 percent.
OK someone's going to give you access to that right.
They set the terms because you're getting a loan from that.
So 5 percent.
So 5 percent Times point seven percent times 40 percent . OK OK we're getting there. We're getting there
.
All right so we're done with debt.
Our debt is 1.4 percent.
Let's focus on the cost to use equity now.
OK.
So the cost to use equity time 60 percent is the remainder of the equation.
And once we calculate that then we have the weighted average cost capital.
So let's just tuck away the debt up in the corner of Erica.
All right.
So.
So how do you calculate the costs of equity.
Well here's how you do it cost.
Equity equals 60 percent.
Right.
Which is remember 60 percent of our capital structure is equity 40 percent.
That 60 percent times the cheapest rate out there.
Plus how volatile the stock is compared to the stock market times what we think the stock market will
do.
Mine is the cheapest rate out there.
Let me add to this to simplify it.
The cheapest rate out there is called the risk free rate and it's basically the government rate of interest
.
OK you can use one two or three percent.
I've seen people use 1 percent and two and a half percent recently in cash.
So let's just use 2 1/2 percent.
Then you add how volatile the stock is.
That's called the base of.
What is the beta.
Let's talk with us.
OK well the bay that measures how your stock that you're analyzing moves relative to the stock market
.
OK.
And let's look at a little example here.
You've got time on the x axis and the price of a stock on the waxes.
OK.
That is the S&P 500 that's the index let's just say.
And that represents all stocks out there in a certain index.
There it is.
The stock market.
So the beta of the stock market is one.
OK.
It's always one because we're going to calculate or actually we're going to show you what the fate of
our company is.
Our company is at orange line there is really volatile right.
It's a high risk company.
So we're twice as volatile as the market right.
It's just calculous the rise over the month were prices of all time as the market.
Right.
And so our stocks Bayda in this case is too right.
And usually you can get Beta's from free sources out there but you can even calculate if you wanted
to.
But it's not worth your time.
So again our stock is twice as risky as the market right.
So we're going to multiply two times the rest of the stuff there if our stock was less risky than the
market so it was only a beta a point eight right then our overall weighted average cost capital be lower
cut.
So we're factor in volatility here.
Pretty cool.
All right.
What do the stock market will do now.
OK so this is debatable and I'm I'm not the hugest fan of DCF to be honest because there's so many independent
variables.
You know if X plus one equals four we know exis three.
I tell you x plus why post Q plus W. equals for what is X Exactly.
There's a lot of independent variables here.
All right now what do we think the market will do.
And this is debatable.
Just assume eight and a half percent over time.
And then we've got 6 percent there and we're getting there almost or wait for it 14 1/2 percent is our
cost of equity.
Right it's high that's pretty high cost of equity.
But if our beta was lower right if our stock was less volatile than our cost you'd actually be a lot
lower.
So 60 percent times that's right.
Plus the debt you've seen already.
That means our weighted average cost of capital here is ten point one percent.
That's our discount rate which is the same thing is that's our interest rate which is the same thing
as that is our whac weighted average cost of capital.
All right.
Now that we've covered how to calculate free Cashell and how to calculate the terminal value and how
to calculate the weighted average cost of capital.
Now let's look at DCF valuation.
Okay.
And we are going to use LinkedIn as our example and the next exercise.
And then there'll be an exercise for you to complete