Now that we know what an income statement is let's take a look at an example.
And so it statements always start with revenue at the top and that's why they call it the top line.
What's your top line at the bottom.
Is earnings or net income that's called The bottom line.
Because it's on the bottom.
And so let's take a look at all of our expense items.
And so we always start off with the first expense being the cost of goods sold which is basically what
it costs us to make that stuff make our product and then revenue minus that cost is called gross profits
and gross profits divided by revenues called gross margin that we have these three expenses which are
expenses to operate our business and that sales and marketing research and development and general and
administrative.
And so whenever I don't know where to put something.
Expense wise I just throw it in this bucket.
That's G and A.
And so revenue minus all these expenses so far is called operating profit or E.B.I.T.D.A.
And it stands for earnings before interest.
Right.
Their taxes their depreciation and amortization there.
And the reason we have this line item is because in many countries the interest rate and tax rates are
different versus other countries.
So how do we compare two companies that might be similar but are in different countries and have different
tax rates and different interest rates.
Well we look at this line here and I'll show you a lot more information on this later in the course
when we model and value our companies.
All right next up we have interest that we're paying on debt or interest we're receiving.
And then we have depreciation and amortization.
And these are non-cash items.
And what that means is basically in the last lecture when we were talking about that truck.
Right.
So if we buy a truck or a piece of machinery the government is basically giving it a tax incentive to
do that stuff.
They're saying hey go spend money on cool new equipment and you'll pay less taxes.
What does that mean.
Well you'll pay less taxes because depreciation is a non-cash expense.
It doesn't really exist but it's basically wear and tear on an annual basis on a machine or a truck
and it makes your taxes less.
And he's got profit before taxes and the taxes.
And then here is net profit which is also called net income or just profit or just income it's all the
same thing.
And so earnings per share is just this earnings basically divided by the number of shares.
And let's go through an example now.
OK.
So we're going to monitor what our income statement numbers were in 2014 and then 2015 and then we look
at it all or change year over year and a percent change year over year and then we'll talk about whether
or not that percent change is a concern or not.
And the reason I really want to talk about this is when you're looking at financial statements I just
want to look for trends in the data right.
One data point does make a trend but a couple does.
And later on in this course we'll do financial modeling financial modeling is really easy.
It's basically predicting the future.
What's the company going to look like in the future.
What are their numbers going to be in the future.
Well we'll cover this in great detail later but I want to put this on your radar screen right now.
All you got to do is forecast all revenue numbers in the long run many many years from now and then
almost every other line item on every financial statement becomes a percent of revenue and you're done
right.
It's really easy and he walked through that in more detail later.
All right.
Now let's take a look at the numbers.
So let me just delete a couple of these boxes.
OK so we've got our numbers there in there and we're going to be analyzing the year over year trends
.
OK so now look at that increase in earnings per share.
Amazing.
Okay.
And let me just uncover this so that dollar change year over year and I'll provide you with a spreadsheet
as well if you want to play around with it.
If you just double click it's that your mind is saying it's just that sort of thing it's pretty understand
.
And if I get rid of this box here this is a percent change over year.
It's simply the percent change year over year from 14 to 15.
So he tells of 14 to 15.
And then we'll talk about it.
Are any of these line items concerns or not and why.
Okay so let's kick it off by analyzing revenue.
Wow check that out.
Man revenue increase.
An astonishing 38 percent year over year.
That's incredible.
Let's look at the bottom line here is the bottom line.
So we had a 133 percent increase wow in earnings.
That's amazing.
OK.
Why the heck did net income increase 133 percent in revenue increased only 38 percent.
It's a good thing it's amazing.
Well let's find out why.
Whenever you see that when we see net income or earnings or profits going up way higher than revenue
on a percent basis we call that margin expansion or leverage in the model.
Okay.
And so the cost of goods sold me and the cost to make that stuff we sold only went up 17 percent.
Wow that's incredible.
It went up basically half as much as this.
The revenue growth.
So we're being much more efficient I guess in producing our product.
Now let's look at sales and marketing and research and development.
They both increase 20 percent which is about half of the revenue growth that's amazing so I guess that
means our sales people were twice as effective as they were in the previous period.
And then DNA increased only 13 percent that's even better.
So you had even a smaller increase in general and administrative expenses yet a much bigger increase
in revenue that's incredible.
And then operating profit.
My goodness look at that it grew over 100 percent that's incredible year over year leverage right.
The Ebbitt or operating profits same thing grew over 100 percent here.
And the reason it grew much faster than revenue is because the expenses grew at a much slower pace.
Right.
That's astonishing and it gets even better.
Why is net income even better than operating profit.
Well because our interest is lower it looks like we paid off five thousand five hundred dollars of our
debt here.
Right.
That's incredible.
And depreciation amortization is the same and our taxes remain.
What does our tax rate at 25 percent.
Right.
Yeah yeah.
Okay.
So are our taxes the same and that is where you get the leverage from so this is an absolutely perfect
perfect income statement and there's there's really no concerns there's no concerns at all.
And before you go to the next lesson I want to show you one more thing we love to look at the rate of
change and the percent of revenue for stuff.
Check this out.
OK.
So it looks like our gross margin right which is gross profit divided by revenue.
Right.
I was double clicking that cell here.
I'm sorry to that that my site and it's just that divided by that and see what I do I named my rose
.
Right.
So right here I clicked on this and that's called revenue.
And the reason I did that is because it just gets more intuitive.
I can kind of speak English to excel by saying this divided by revenue instead of remembering that line
there.
And again you click in there and then you enter in whatever you want that text to be.
OK.
So our gross profit margin right went from 45 percent to 54 percent that's incredible.
Let's look at the other margin numbers are operating profit margin or Ebbitt margin same thing went
from 27 percent of revenue all the way up to 37 percent.
That's incredible leverage.
Great leverage and we'll cover margin structures in much more detail later in this course.
Okay let's take a look at a couple of more line items so our profitability margins are improving materially
now.
Never before I said look at everything as a percent of revenue.
Let's take that out.
Well we already talked about this gross margins a percent of revenue so that each expense of sales and
marketing as a percentage of revenue went from 9 percent down to 8 percent.
That's incredible.
Right.
That's called leverage.
And the same thing can be said for research and development right there as a percent of revenue.
Right.
It went down from 5 percent to 4 percent.
Okay.
And the same thing with GNN expenses.
Right general minister I went from 7 to 6 so net net if we look at the year over year change in expenses
they're way lower than the over change in revenue and we love to see that and stuff as a percent of
revenue went down as well meaning expenses and that basically led to a lot of margin expansion and there's
absolutely no issues with this income statement at all this is an absolutely perfect income statement