The most successful financial analysts are very good at figuring out the size of the market that they're
going to invest in.
And we call this the Tambe or ATHM which stands for total addressable market and it's good to calculate
the total addressable market before you do due diligence on a company.
And after you make the financial model for that company a good sanity check is to make sure that the
revenues for that company in the long run are way way smaller than the total addressable market.
And so our case study in this section is linked and linked in is got three separate divisions right
so it's a little bit complicated to calculate the total addressable market for LinkedIn but those are
the three segments and I'll explain to you exactly what they do and then we'll discuss how to calculate
the TAM.
So after we look at the total addressable market we'll look at the financial model which is in the next
lecture for Lankton.
So let's kick off with the enterprise market the enterprise market for LinkedIn is basically human resource
managers that use LinkedIn.
In fact you can actually replace sometimes a bunch of human resources executives by just using LinkedIn
to find potential recruits.
So for recruiting prospective LinkedIn is amazing.
Secondly we've got what's called the prosumer market and many of you and I actually use LinkedIn for
this which allows you to contact strangers using in emails which is a great way to network.
And number three the last total addressable market will be looking at is just the advertising market
which means on the right hand side in LinkedIn you could see commercials or advertisements.
It's that market.
Ok cool.
Let's size these markets and we'll kick it off with the enterprise market.
Let's look at the total addressable market for this.
How are we going to calculate that.
So let's go to the World Bank's Web site and we can see the number of new companies being registered
every single year in every country.
OK.
And so the average number of companies register as you can see there in each country is roughly 200000
You could say it's to 50 or to 60 let's be conservative let's say 200000 companies are registered each
year in about 200 countries.
That gives you 40 million new companies every year.
Okay great.
And now we have the number of companies.
Next up we need to find out the number of human resources employees that work at these 40 million companies
.
OK let's see how we're going to quantify this.
OK.
So in the Financial Times we can see here that the average company in Europe for example has six employees
.
OK.
All right let's use that.
Let's use that.
OK.
Here we go according to Business Management Daily It looks like if you take 2.4 percent of every company
is an H.R. executive OK let's play around these numbers.
Cool.
I think what we're getting somewhere.
All right.
So if we take 40 million companies being created every year and we multiply those 40 million companies
by six people and then 2.4 percent of those companies are H.R. executives then that's 5.7 million H.R.
executives.
Ok cool.
Great.
Now it looks like the average human resources employee makes about 50 grand per year.
So let's just simply multiply those together to get our total addressable market and there you have
it.
It's $288 billion.
That's the total size of the enterprise market for Linked In.
Okay great.
So we've done one third of the work here for our TAM or total just bull market.
Next up let's look at the prosumer market and within the prosumer market.
We can see that linked in has about just over 400 million subscribers right.
They're not all paying subscribers but they're their users on the platform it's an amazing platform
I love it in.
It looks like their user total goal according to LinkedIn is $3 billion people I guess at a $7 in the
world that they figure that just under 50 percent are potential customers.
OK so if we look at for example how many credit cards if you're I don't think so.
All right.
So if we look at my LinkedIn account we can see that I pay twenty nine dollars per month.
So if we assume that we have 3 million potential users if you get 100 percent penetration which will
never happen but it's you know something we can aspire to here.
Times 29 times 12 months equals a total addressable market of wait for it wait for it.
So I'm trying to lose a little bit of humor here.
I'm not sure if it's working out.
Oh well here comes.
Really.
OK.
It's jabbing here but it's there we go ah it's one point oh eight trillion dollars.
Wow.
That's a crap load of yeah.
Anyway so that is the prosumer market.
OK two for three now.
And now let's calculate the advertising markets.
OK.
All right.
Here we go.
So this one's a lot easier.
There's a ton of statistics out there so according to Zenith up to media there is an advertisement size
of fifty seven point six billion dollars as of last year a little bit stale that's OK for the Internet
ad spending market and so and of course linked they will never go 100 percent share of that but if you
add up all three of these total addressable markets then there you go the total addressable market for
LinkedIn is about 1.4 trillion dollars which is absolutely enormous.
OK.
So from a quantitative analysis perspective we've just done the total addressable market.
And so the next step is to build the financial model which will start in the next section.