Let's go to our model and let's do our DCF remember in our cash flow statement we got ahm I'm sorry
here these free cash estimates right.
We calculate those.
OK.
So let's look at a discount of cash for evaluation analysis.
So remember green means it's coming from other Tapps.
Step 1 Get free cash flow from the cash flow statement tab.
Here it is.
That's just link directly there.
See.
Step two is calculate what's called the weighted average cost to capital which is the discount rate
that we're going to use to discount these free cash flows.
These free cash flows today meaning in 2016 should be worth less than they are then because you have
to pay for money there's interest rates we have to discount it but what interest rate do we discount
these values to.
Well there's two things we have to take into consideration here.
There's a cost of equity right.
And then there's a cost of debt.
OK.
So the cost of equity will go with that one first.
The cost of equity is just the risk free rate right.
Which is basically the government rate or a little bit above that plus the Bayda which is how volatile
your stock is times what you think the market return is going to be longer term minus that risk free
rate.
And so in this example LinkedIn oddly enough has a beta below one which means that it's less volatile
than the Standard Poor's 500 and then the stock market return in this hypothetical example is 18 1/2
percent over time minus the risk free rate which let's just call roughly two and a half percent and
that means our cost of capital for equity is 8.2 percent right now.
And that's just just math Mathare and we calculate that there.
Now we have to multiply this right times.
What percent of the enterprise value or value of linked in is equity versus debt.
And so you can see there the market cap is roughly fifteen point nine billion.
It's a little bit off.
I'm not sure exactly when it's actually right now but it's touch off and debt from the balance sheet
is 1.1 3 billion.
So that means the percent of the capital structure for LinkedIn that is equity is fifteen point nine
billion divided by the debt plus equity 1.3 billion plus fifteen point nine billion.
That gets down 3.4 percent so ninety 3.4 percent.
Right.
Times that's OK is the cost of equity at some point 10 percent.
And because we know that ninety three point four percent is our equity as a percentage of our capital
structure we know that debt is just one minus that amount.
Okay.
Thats it.
Okay great.
So lets get to the cost of debt.
Okay so the cost of debt is basically the costs that were calculated a second times one minus the normalized
tax rate because we do get that benefits of having debt.
Okay thats from a tax perspective but it looks like according to this comment they got I wrote this
or I would have forgotten all the debt that LinkedIn has and LinkedIn has is convertible.
Therefore I assume the cost of debt is the same as the cost of equity which is a point 2 percent.
Now we're in a tax effect.
You get a tax benefit for having debt and that gets you to 5.5 percent.
Okay good.
And we take 5.5 percent right and we multiply it by the percent of our capital structure which is that
it's just basically is the or miss the equity portion.
So as a percentage of cabel structure and that gets us to 8 point 0 2 percent.
Okay.
And that's our cost of capital and we're going to use this to discount all of these items back into
today's terms.
Okay cool.
All right let's do it now.
I love this form.
It's the coolest thing ever.
It's called Net Present Value DoubleClick and NPV is equal to the rate and then the discount of all
those amounts in the future and the rate is.
We've already got it's this dude here.
OK.
And he's here.
See that guy.
And then these here are going to be all of the future values were in discount to.
Yes discounted cash flow.
That equals that amount.
However what the heck do we do with years 2021 all the way up to infinity.
Certainly that has to count for something and a much larger portion as well because that's the million
years of free cash flow for Illington.
Well the way this is done is as follows.
You take what you think is the long term growth rate and the long term growth rate for any company is
is 1 2 or 3.
It's usually pretty low and the reason is because when you get a very large entity you get the Law of
Large Numbers and so you look at the U.S. economy.
For example the U.S. economy is big it's mature.
So it's never going to grow more and just say a couple of percent per year.
OK.
So what you do is the terminal value is basically you take the last year which is this guy here last
year the plus one times the growth rate divided by this whack right weighted average cost capital which
is 8.0 2 percent number from up here back to minus minus.
This dude here.
OK.
That's a long term growth and you will never have your long term growth higher than your cost of capital
.
It just doesn't happen.
And so we're discounting this amounts right now.
And this next step here.
Right.
That's the term lie in today's terms.
And we do it over four years is four years in the future whatever.
And then we've got our weighted average cost capital there.
OK good.
So our target equity value the firm is that plus that.
Okay that's discounted in today's terms.
My guess is that that's our target value there.
And then divide it by the number of shares was just from the income statement.
That means our price target for LinkedIn is 157 bucks.
Okay.
Okay cool.
And that's at a growth rate member of 2 percent to long term and a way the average cost capital of 8.02
percent.
That's the whack and 157 bucks.
That's our base case.
Then I create what's called a sensitivity analysis table here and a lot of analysts love to use this
.
Right.
And it's basically breaks you can show your clients Here's a menu of where the numbers could be.
You tell me if you're bearish or you're bullish.
OK so if you're bullish on the economy or this company linked in then longer term you take a 3 percent
right 3 percent long term growth rate and a lower cost of capital which means that your price target
be 320 bucks.
And if you're bearish then linked in is only going to be worth a hundred in one box at a long term growth
rate 1 percent and a weighted average cost capital which is higher of 10 percent.
OK.
So these three numbers are our bullish base and bearish case.
So if we go here to value metrics this will feed into there.
And of course they'll be green.
And just look here don't look anywhere else.
Thanks.
I'm sorry Ray here.
This is the DCF methodology.
Bullish was that amount.
Bearish is that amount and just right was adamant.
And that came from that the previous tab here that's why it's increased