Let's look at the answers together for the formula exercise.
Let's kick it off with these ones here and I'm sure he took all these off.
Let's do it right now.
All right cool.
And we'll start off here.
So before I go into too much detail here I want to talk about these formulas and so these are profitability
formulas and they're from the income statement and the other reason I bring that up is because you start
at the top gross margin than half way down.
You look at operating margins right.
How profitable is your business after deducting operating expenses.
And then what's the bottom line profitability net profit margin on the bottom.
These are from the income set and these ones here are awesome because they're from the income statement
and the balance sheet.
And this is basically telling you for every dollar in assets you have.
How much money are you making.
And for every dollar an equity you have how much money are you making net income.
So these are profitability formulas.
All right.
And I include a couple of different years because I always got to look at trends in the data.
One data point does make a trend but a couple does.
All right.
So gross margin improvement look at that 200 basis points each year member 100 basis points is 1 percent
200 basis points each year.
That's finance and or talk.
All right.
So I should probably freeze these pains and you go to view so on view unfreeze freeze panes that we
got all.
And let's actually because we're going to be looking at it's here for King 15:16 right.
Cisco here I mean make it a bit bigger so we can also sorry about that.
All right here go.
So gross margins look at that getting better.
And remember we are modeling this.
We assumed it would just keep getting better because you take a couple of data points in the past and
member an object in motion stays in motion.
So it looks like it's improving.
Okay.
Done.
Next step we've got operating margins.
Okay.
There you go.
Well it's good get better to healthy looking chart ups.
Okay.
So operating margins we got down here and operating margins is just E.B.I.T.D.A. margins.
And we could looked at non E.B.I.T.D.A. margins like this one here.
And the reason I don't like doing that right is because this includes non-cash stuff like depreciation
right into what I'm looking at profitability metrics.
I like to look at as close to cash as possible and even that is close to the cash then not even the
operating profit cut.
So it's a pretty sales like most things and we improve from 37 to 42 to 47 that's great.
That's great.
What is driving that improvement in operating profit.
Let's see here sales marketing pro-development.
Okay sales and marketing is improving a percent each year looks like all three of them are kind of almost
equally helping out.
Okay.
That's called leverage in model.
Great.
So let's go back here then what is the net profits.
And that's obviously at the bottom it looks like it's getting well really good really good.
And what's interesting here is you can tell that this one is usually lower than that and this one's
usually lower than that.
And the obvious reason is because up here you've only deducted one expense line.
It's gross you know gross profits are caskets Walsh said and here you deducting caskets sold as well
as sales of market research development in R&D.
And down here you're deducting all that stuff I just mentioned plus taxes and interest.
Okay.
So 23 percent net profit margins let's go here and check it out.
Right down we go here.
Okay so we've got some to get a lot better with that each year we ran it up to 30 there.
Okay crates.
Next up we've got what's the return on assets that's net income divided by assets.
And what's the return on equity that's net income divided by equity.
It looks like this has cost us down.
I'm not too worried not to worry that kind of looks on change.
Anyway is going here.
Let's return on equity
Calix say return equity is getting a bit worse.
Inventory days on hand.
Can you believe that shows still on TV.
This is amazing.
Ok cool.
All right.
83 days on hand to 90 to nine nines a bit of a concern.
It is a concern but given our amazing profitability is not the end of the world.
All right.
So we've got 99 days of amatory on hand.
Our profitability is pretty decent.
I'm not too worried about it.
And then we've got debt to assets.
Right.
We're looking at tunnelled that
debt to equity and debt Tass that's very similar to these formulas here.
Right.
Except you don't have the income saved in corporate.
All right.
So we know how much debt we're finds actually going down very healthy debt to equity.
It's healthy as well.
We're in good shape here.
We are a healthy company.
All right.
And then we've got the price earnings based on this dude here.
I mean just get rid of all these at the same time for us.
OK.
So price earnings getting dramatically better because we are a high growth company very healthy.
What's our peg.
This is ridiculously low.
Look at that bargain bargain you'll never see rarely see a pegged that low anything under one's a screaming
bias.
You obviously know I like this company a recovery us as we just met up price to revenue looks pretty
darn cheap as well given the growth rates.
But it looks decent decent Right.
But obviously even if it is higher than price earnings because you've got it that doesn't include a
lot of the expenses that we have a net earnings here.
And so even you but is remember investment bankers love it.
But in sort of big companies corporate finance departments because big companies have corporate finance
departments are looking to buy other companies.
And the reason we look at it that it's our favorite formula is because the enterprise value is market
cap plus debt minus cash and short term investments and what that means is this if you're looking to
buy a company that is publicly traded you get to pay for it well you're not going to pay whatever the
stock is out on the market usually plus 30 percent that's a going rate usually.
And then what you do is you figure oh gosh I got to figure if they have decks are going to pay that
debt back.
So I'll add the debt and then you're like well if I add the debt I could probably pay back some of that
debt with some of the cash and short term investments have on hand.
So let me deduct cash and short term assets.
That's why you look at that right and if you work in M&A this is more important to you than this.
Right.
And you always assume at least a 30 percent increase in the price of the company in the market cap at
least when you're looking at a potential like this.
OK.
A sales looks looks pretty good as well.
And also we have price to be cash flow it looks healthy as well.
It's pretty got a lot of high growth companies like ours here don't have free cash flow or it's very
low.
We're in healthy shape here.
Price to book is attractive because we're a growth stock.
Our company is not cheap right.
And that's why our price to book is way way way above 1.
All rights and I right here.
Company X is the biggest competitor of the company that we are analyzing in this exercise and has the
following three competition metrics.
Okay so comp company X is our biggest enemy.
That one's got a P of some point nine times each year.
Okay.
I guess earnings aren't growing right.
Debt to equity for that company is 99 percent US.
It's pretty darn high.
And the net profit margin for all three years is 10 percent.
OK.
They got a heck of a lot of debt.
Way more now with our debt issue anyway.
We're at WOW or we're really low man.
OK.
And their net profit margin is 10 percent when we had the profit margin.
Now we're kicking their butts and we're growing too.
Right.
This means they're not growing.
They have a lot to and they're not growing.
What's the peg of the company.
Right.
So 16 I don't think it's really a placable because there's no growth used to be divided by zero.
We're not here
yet.
Zero no growth based on the P.
Is this a better investment than a.
I would say our company is a better investment because they're at seven point nine times right.
But there's no growth.
So if there's there's some point i'm times for all three years in a row and they're probably not going
to go next year and you're after then in a year or two will be cheaper than them anyway.
Right.
Let's show you.
OK.
So if we go up to here we're right here.
Sorry about that.
OK.
So we're right here.
But this has fallen by 50 percent every year right now.
So that means next year if the stock stays flat probably won't but if it does that means we'll be at
like eight a point four times and then 4.2 times etc..
So no way man we're way better investment than this one.
That one's not growing trap.
All right.
Is the debt to equity of X better than the company we're looking at.
No way no way.
Their debt is 99 percent.
Ours is single digits
is a net profit margin for this company better than ours.
No 10 percent we're way higher.
All right.
There you go.
That's the conclusion of the excess