So what you can do is you can either go to LinkedIn Investor Relations Web site or you can go to as
he said.
And look at the press releases and hard code or manually type in your model with all the numbers are
.
Or you can do something else which is you can go to the Web site and you see the top left hand corner
there on the left hand side it says export financials what we can do is we can actually export the financials
and then point them into our model and then build the model from scratch.
So before we build the model what I want to do is just give you a quick introduction to my model.
And so I have always put a little introduction here to the model what we're looking at and then we'll
do is we'll talk about the revenue drivers income statement a bouncy castle statement and just how to
value a company and I'll break it down into very easy to understand components.
Now before we get started I wrote here please note that every model for every company is different.
And so not all companies provide the same amount of data.
You want to look at all the press releases and all the filings on the FCC website and listen to all
the earnings calls and then just kind of build that into your model before diving in the model.
I always love looking at charts and this is live data from the model.
OK.
I love looking for patterns.
Pattern recognition is always great and so this is total revenue for the company you can see growth
is great up to here and this is the future were in a forecast together.
This is revenue for the first line item enterprise which is also called Tower solutions.
Its pretty good marketing solutions.
So that looks pretty good.
And then the last section here is pre-New subscriptions which looks great as well.
And then we can look at the percent growth rate of change and because this is a big publicly traded
companies company you see that growth is slowing and that's perfectly normal.
In fact companies usually go public when growth is slowing and this is another revenue line item growth
is slowing here.
And the third revenue line is ooh what happened here.
It looks like growth accelerated temporarily.
Well good analysts would look into why and you're a great analyst.
So it looks like LinkedIn bought a company called Linda da comp for $1.5 billion here in 2014 and that's
why revenues spiked.
Okay.
It's important to always understand why revenues spiking because usually growth is pausa but it's slowing
for companies that are big publicly traded and that just shows you what happens and this year we got
premium subscriptions slowing and that's actually a bit of a concern.
Okay.
So that's the revenue side.
Let's look over here on the expense side.
So this is operating margins are basically revenue minus most expenses that are repeatable.
Okay.
At least before taxes and interest depreciation amortization.
So revenue minus most of repeatable expenses and although revenue growth is slowing we saw over here
that might be a concern.
It's okay because we believe the company didn't tell us this.
We believe that the company will cut expenses at least as a percent and margins will expand.
If this doesn't make perfect sense you don't worry we'll cover in great detail in sales and marketing
as it presents just sales.
This is all data from our model is going to decrease a little bit.
Right so I'll help out to drive these higher margins up here.
And then there's some called product development or research and belt and R&D that's going to decrease
.
We think as a percent of revenue as well and then Same thing with General administrators.
And you'll notice that everything in a model is just a percent of sales and so modelling is actually
pretty easy.
Scott to have two rules in mind number one.
Everything almost as a percent of sales.
Right so I spent a lot of time working on predicting sales.
And secondly just look for patterns.
It's not that hard.
And then here we can see our EPS growth analysis and it seems to be accelerating because we think the
company is going to cut expenses.
The blue line here is revenue from model and the light blue line or that's like gray or whatever is
expenses or I should say margins.
And so although revenue growth is slowing which is okay it's big company margins are going to increase
which is normal when growth slows.
Usually you get margins increasing