Let's discuss the answers to the income statement exercise.
OK.
So let's just look at trends in the data.
So I'll kick it off with the top line which is revenue.
So it looks like revenue decreased 120000 or so year over year down 8 percent.
That's obviously a concern.
It's always a concern when revenue declines.
Let's take a look at the cost of goods sold or the cost.
It took us to produce our stuff.
And wow that's brutal.
OK look at that.
We had an increase of 14 percent year over year in the cost of goods sold despite the fact that revenue
was down.
So obviously that's concern the cost of make our product increases despite a decrease in revenue.
And then gross profit obviously is down as well because that's just a formula that minus that revenue
minus the cost to produce that stuff for Coggs concern sales and marketing increased at a pace of 17
percent year over year.
Frightening because revenue is down 8 percent but this expense item was up 17 percent year over year
and it gets worse.
R&D was up 33 percent year over year despite an 8 percent decline in revenue.
Gina was bad as well.
And so what happens is our operating profit margin went down from 37 percent to 20 percent.
Leverage can work against you big time as well so we have a 50 percent decline year over year in our
operating profit despite a revenue decline of only 8 percent and it looks like we took on more debt
here.
Right.
So we're paying $10000 more in interest.
So we had a spike in our profit before taxes was down 58 percent year over year which is worse than
the operating profit year over year decline because of the increase in interest.
Okay.
And then so are our net income was actually down 58 percent your Veeru still positive.
Right.
One hundred fifty seven thousand eight hundred seventy five.
But it decreased that much year over year.
So Ouch 58 percent decline year over year in earnings per share or net income same thing or net profit
same thing.
Despite the fact that revenue is only down 8 percent.
So the results from this exercise is basically the opposite from when we looked at the income statement
.
Example right in the example there is no concerns but in this case there are many concerns obviously
so play around with the data like DoubleClick on different entries and just see how how we got to those
numbers and how all of this flows through.
That's the best way for you to really learn and master the whole income statement process.
And now that we have this nailed what we can do is go on to talk about the balance sheet.
And then much much later in the course after we understand financials perfectly well we'll talk about
modeling and then we'll talk about valuation which is a lot of fun