Hello everyone and welcome to the arithmetic and numbers lecture.
This is our first lecture in the Scala basics section of this course and we're going to start off just
by using the shell or the ripple.
That's the read evaluate prints and loop.
We're going to explain basic arithmetic and numbers of Skala if you want.
You can write these commands as a script but for right now since we're just going one line at a time
it makes more sense just to go ahead and use the shell later on we're going to expand to more lines
and use an actual text editor.
But for now right now one line at a time and the shell should be fine.
I'm going to go ahead and jump to my command prompt.
Or if you're a Mac user you're terminal.
In order to get started.
All right here I am at my command prompt.
Are your terminal if you're a Mac user.
Let's go ahead and start up the spark shell.
If you want.
You can either use CD to change the rectory to your SPARC folder or you are saving all your scripts
or if you follow the installation instructions properly you should be able to call Spark's shell from
anywhere on your computer.
So let's go ahead and just start the spark shell.
You can do this basically in any folder you want if you follow the instructions and the pending whether
or not you actually turn off the warnings you may receive some warnings as I'm showing here.
But here we have it the sparks shell and we're ready to type in some Scollard code.
So let's go ahead and just walk through the very basics of numbers in arithmetic using Skala.
This is just going to be a few lines of code nothing too intense.
So there's two main types of numbers.
We're going to be working with throughout the course.
There's integers which are whole numbers and that can be something like 100.
So if I hit enter.
You'll notice an output you get rez 0 for.
Result zero.
You get a colon integer equals 100.
And basically this is called telling you a couple of things you have.
Result zero.
It's an integer and it's equal to 100.
And the other type of number we're going to be working with our floating point numbers are what are
known as doubles and basically those are going to be numbers with some sort of decimal point in them
for that resolution.
And here you can see we have read 1 for result 1.
Double is equal to 2.5.
Now we're going to tackle Resler on Rezwan how we actually use those later on.
But right now let's go ahead and just go through the very basics of arithmetic.
So right now we're just treating this Skala shell or interpreter as a basic calculator.
If you want to do addition for example one plus one just adding You wanted the subtraction to minus
one.
It's a dash there.
Multiplication is just an asterix to Asterix five is two times five division will depend whether or
not you're using integers or doubles.
So if you say one divided by two.
So that slash there.
Notice I get integer equals zero.
As a result.
And that's because division with integers in Scala is going to perform what's known as classic division.
So if you actually want truth Division One of these numbers is going to have to be a double or a floating
point number.
So I don't need to say one point zero divided by two or I can say 1 divided by 2.0 or we can have them
both be double so point 1.0 divided by 2.0.
And here we get that true result that 0.5 so won the vote by 2 in classic division becomes zero because
it rounds it down.
But true division which is probably what we're usually looking for you're going to have to use a double
there and know how Skala actually tells you the type of data that's return back and we'll discuss data
types more thoroughly as we encounter more of them as we go along.
All right.
So we just cover in addition subtraction multiplication and division with integers and doubles.
Let's go ahead and show a few more examples.
If you want to do exponents there's no base for exponents.
So we actually have to import that and you can just call math.
P o w.
You don't need actually call an import statement just call p O.W. for power from the math library and
then pasand as a first argument with parentheses here.
The number that you want as the base.
And then what you want to raise it to the power.
So for instance if I want four to the power of two I'm going to go ahead and say math.
P o w and then pass and force the power to.
That's going to be 16.
And notice here that even though I pass in integers I get a double as a result.
So that math library and Skala is going to translate that to a double as an output.
OK.
Now something about these results this aria 6 or 7 is Scalia's actually remembering these results.
Meaning I can call them back.
So for instance I can say yes 0 can actually get back that initial result.
Remember the very first thing I typed was 100.
And note that it also gives me read 10.
So I can actually say read 10 plus Reserva and get 100 plus 100.
We won't really be calling results like that too often but I want you to know that it is possible.
OK.
Couple more things I want to go over.
You can specify order of operations with parentheses.
So for example if I were to say one plus two times three plus four order of operations will actually
make the multiplication happen first.
So in this case if I run this I get 11 which is two times three which is six plus five which is 11.
If I actually want one plus two times the result of three plus four I can use parentheses to specify
that.
So one plus two times three plus four.
And then I get 21 which in this case was the result I was looking for.
OK.
Let's go ahead and do a quick understanding check.
Go ahead and see if you can convert three feet to meters using Skala.
So for instance I have three feet.
See if you can convert that to meters using Scala.
Go ahead.
See if you can figure that out.
You mean to do a google search for the actual factor that you need to multiply three by I'll let you
go ahead and try that out.
OK.
Hopefully you able to do a quick Google search and notice that one foot is zero point 3 0 4 8 meters.
So I can say three times zero point 3 0 for eights and then that gets me this results.
Notice the precision here because it's a double it's actually going to try to give me the max precision
possible and it's going to end up rounding off to a one at the end and later on we'll show you how to
deal with that.
If you want to cut down on that precision.
OK.
So that's the basics of arithmetic and numbers in Scala.
We've seen how sculler reports back data types such as integers and doubles and also has these variables
or values such as rest 13 or 12.
Etc..
Later on we're going to go ahead and show you how to actually create variables and values with Scala
and how to assign data types to literal values.
OK so that's all coming up next.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.