Hello everyone and welcome to the Scala collections section of this course.
We've already discussed tuples as a method to hold various objects.
And now we're going to actually discuss four more basic collections objects and that's going to be lists
sets maps and arrays.
So we're going to go ahead and do is get started here this section of the course.
We're still going to be using the spark shell and then putting one line above the time into the Skala
interpreter.
But this will be the last section we're actually going to be doing that in the next section of the course.
First color programming we're going to actually then move on to use a text editor and write out multiple
lines of code.
Okay.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.