Hello and welcome to the Scala and sparked development environments lecture in this lecture we'll be
discussing development environment options for school and Sparke.
We will also explain how we actually progress through them throughout the course.
If you asked 10 different developers what the best development environment is it's likely that you're
going to get 10 different answers.
So keep in mind that personal preference plays a large part in choosing a development environment.
It feels right to you in this course.
Will progress through several development environments so that you can get a feel for them and choose
the one that feels right to you.
There are three main types.
Development Environment options for Skala and SPARC.
Those are text editors full ID ease or integrated development environments and the notebook systems.
Let's go ahead and discuss them text editors are simple environments that allow you to type text formatting
and save a specific extension.
In our case that Skala they also support extensions and plugins for syntax highlighting Sublime Text
and Adam text editor are very common examples of text editors used in development environments.
Then there's full ID is a complete or full integrated development environment is usually language specific
unlike text editors which can be used for a multitude of languages.
These ideas include things such as code completion syntax highlighting package poor etc..
There are much more expanded to a specific language as far as our capabilities Intelli Jay and Skala
the free clips are the most common examples of full ID IIS for Skala and spark.
Then there are notebooks systems notebooks provide an interactive environment for developing code.
They allow you to see the output directly into the notebook by separating code into cells.
The Jupiter notebook system and the Zetlin notebook system are the most common notebook environments
available for Scala.
So let's discuss how we actually approach development environments in this course and this course.
What we're essentially going to be doing is as our knowledge increases we'll be leveling up to a more
advanced development environment.
So we're going to start off by simply using the ripple or the revaluate print loop which is just a single
command line interface for Scala.
Then once you learn more about Skala will progress to writing full Skala scripts in Adam which is a
text editor and we'll add some Skala plugins to make Adam easier to use afterwards.
Then we'll show you the Intel Ejay IDC which will allow us to use a full ID with Skala.
Then when we move on to distributed datasets we'll actually move to a notebook set up keep in mind that
all the Skala and spark code right write works for any environment you want.
So if you feel you found your favorite Go ahead and feel free to stick that development environment
throughout the rest of the course.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.