Hello everyone and welcome to the regression with SPARK section of the course.
Let's go ahead and finally begin to learn how to use Spark's incredible machine learning capabilities.
We'll start off by walking you through the documentation for the machine learning section specifically
the regression section of the documentation Spark's machine learning documentation is actually much
better than the rest of its documentation has really nice examples there.
So we'll go ahead and start off by walking you through some of the simple examples so you can get used
to referencing the documentation on your own in order to fill in any blanks you may have in the future.
Then we'll go ahead and code out our own example.
Walking you through step by step in the example that's different than the documentation.
And then finally you'll go ahead and have a project exercise to fill out on your own.
Will you be given a data set a set of instructions and you'll have to follow along and solve the problem
yourself.
All of the relevant files for this section are under the machine learning sections folder under the
regression folder.
All right I'm excited.
So let's go ahead and get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.