Hello everyone and welcome to an introduction to Kamins clustering in this lecture.
We're going to discuss the K means clustering algorithm which will allow us to cluster and label data
in an unsupervised machine learning algorithm.
You want the full mathematics behind this algorithm.
Go ahead and read Chapter 10 of an introduction.
Just learning k means clustering is an unsupervised learning algorithm meaning it takes an unlabeled
data it's going to attempt to group similar clusters together in your data.
So what is the typical clustering problem look like.
Well a few examples may be things like clustering similar documents together clustering customers based
off of their features trying to perform market segmentation or even trying to identify similar physical
groups.
The overall goal is to divide data into distinct groups such observations within each group are similar.
Here you can see a diagram of unlabelled training data and k means clustering trying to attempt to cluster
the data into five distinct clock colored clusters here.
How does the algorithm actually work.
Well you first choose the number of clusters K and we'll discuss how to choose k later on then you randomly
assign each point in your data to a specific cluster then until the clusters stop changing.
You repeat the following steps for each cluster you're going to compute the cluster centroid by taking
the mean vector of points in the cluster.
Then you assign each data point to the cluster for which the centroid is the closest.
Let's go ahead and take a look at the state of visualization or this plotted out visualization of k
means clustering algorithm you first start off of just the observations that's shown on the top left
then in top center we have Step One of the algorithm.
Each observation is randomly assigned to a cluster in the top right of step to a the cluster centroid
are then computed.
These are shown as large colored disks.
Initially these centroid are almost completely overlapping because the initial cluster assignments were
chosen at random in the bottom left and step to be each observation is assigned to the nearest centroid
in the bottom center.
Step two is a once again perform.
You can see that we've led to new cluster centroid and we basically keep repeating the steps until there's
no new clusters meaning data points aren't being reassigned to a new cluster centroid at the bottom
right.
We have the results obtained after about 10 iterations.
Let's discuss choosing a k value as we just saw before.
K means clustering.
We also decide how many clusters we expect in the data.
The problem of selecting K isn't actually that simple.
There is no easy answer for choosing a best case value.
However one way to try to do it is using something known as the elbow method.
First of all you compute the sum of squared error otherwise known as s s e.
For some values of k.
For example 2 4 6 8 etc..
The sum of squares heir's is defined as the sum of the square distance between each member of the cluster
and that centroid.
If you plot K against the SS e you will see that the error decreases as Kagiso larger just because of
the number of clusters increases.
They should be smaller so distortion is also smaller.
The idea of the Elbel method is to choose the K at which the s s e decreases abruptly.
This produces an elbow effect in the graph as you can see in the following picture.
Here we can see an example of they plotted out Elbot method on the X horizontal axis.
We have the K value which stands for the number of clusters you choose for the algorithm on the y axis
you have the within groups sum of squares you want to try to choose a K where you won't get that much
more information by increasing the number of clusters.
Are not going to significantly decrease the within groups sum of squared error by increasing number
of clusters.
And that's why this is called the elbow method.
As you can see an elbow occurring around the number let's say six to seven clusters.
That means that's a good number to choose for your clusters.
Again there's no correct value.
So you want to use your domain experience or domain knowledge in whatever field you're working with
in order to try to choose a correct or reasonable case value.
Now that we know the theory behind K means clustering we're going to explore the documentation example
in this particular case the documentation example is actually straightforward enough that we don't have
to show our own custom example.
So after seeing the documentation example afterwards you're going to go straight into an exercise project
to complete.
Thanks everyone and I will see at the next lecture.