Hello everyone and welcome to the machine learning will spark lecture.
In this lecture we will be discussing the basics of how to use Spark's machine learning library sometimes
known as MLA lib and other times shortened to just sparks m-L.
We will explore its documentation and discuss her approach to learning how to use m-L.
In this course let's get a quick review of The Fool machine learning process before we begin.
Remember that the machine learning process has several steps.
First you need to acquire your data then you need to manipulate and clean that data to the correct format.
Afterwards you split that data into a test set and use your training set to actually train your model
and build your model.
Then you will test that model against your test set and then reevaluate what you need to fix in your
model.
And once that loop is complete your model is ready for the placement and in between the model testing
and model deployment phase.
There is also some times what is known as a hold out set that is a third set of data not your training
set.
Not your test set that a hold out set as a last measure of how well your model perform before you actually
the point.
Now let's talk about Spark's MLA Sparke currently has two machine learning API.
It has the r d d API and the data from an API.
The r d d API will soon be no longer supported and is considered outdated.
Which is why we focused so much on learning how to work with data frames in the earlier section.
The course the documentation for Spark's MLA is actually very good it's much better than its data frame
documentation which I'm sure you're happy to hear because the documentation is so good.
Let's take a quick tour of the documentation.
I'm going to jump to my browser now and show you the documentation for Spark's M-L it or it here and
at the documentation for the machine learning library guide we will be visiting the documentation often
as we go throughout the machine learning section of the course.
Right now I just want to give you a quick overview of what it looks like at this current state.
You can find this documentation that sparked that Apache the org slash doc slash latest slash M-L bash
guide the HTL or you can just come here to programming guides.
Go to the version of sparkie white and then click down to MLM machine learning when you come to this
page you'll notice that there's essentially two guides.
One is the main guide which is the data frame guide and the other is the RTD based API guide.
Now right now they are still showing the RTT based API guide but by the time SPARC 3.0 is released the
d based API is expected to just be removed from the latest versions of SPARC and once SPARC reaches
2.2 that version 2.2 the Ardi the base API will just be considered outdated.
Right now it's kind of on the cusp of being outdated.
So they're still showing a lot of that information.
Since a lot of people still use it but really the future of machine learning was SPARC is really with
data frames.
Now there's lots of reasons for this why we're switching to the data frame base the API for one reason.
It's just much much easier to work with the data frames than it is with the DS.
There's lots of benefits including getting Sparke data sources of data frame's a lot of optimizations
and a uniform API across multiple languages.
That way the data from API looks relatively the same whether you are working in Java Scala or Python.
So you can quickly jump using the same skillset.
The data frame based API also allows for uniform API across M-L algorithms and across multiple languages.
They just noted and it also facilitates the use of pipelines which we will discuss later on.
You can read more about the general information about the machine learning library guide here on this
main page but I also want to just show you that what we're going to be going over as we explore the
documentation throughout this section of the Course is right here under M-L main guide.
There's pipeline's extracting transforming and selecting features classification regression clustering
collaborative filtering for recommendation systems model selection tuning and then advanced topics.
We're going to start off with just simple regression.
So if you come over here a classification or regression you'll notice that there is a regression here
section and basically we are going to be focusing on this main topic and an example algorithm.
Once you understand the main topic regression in a sample algorithm of regression it's very easy to
switch out that machine learning model for another algorithm.
So if you already understand how to use linear regression for the regression type problem you can easily
switch out your linear regression for something like a random forced regression depending on your data.
That may be a better fit and once you understand had due classification of logistic regression.
Again it's very easy to change it out for something like a naive base or decision tree classifier etc..
That's why in this course we're just focusing on the main big picture ideas so that you with your extra
knowledge or particular datasets can come in and choose whatever algorithm is right for you.
Once you understand how to do the main concept of spark.
Now once we learn how to actually implement some of the machine learning models we'll also talk about
extracting transforming and selecting features.
There's a ton of ways to actually manipulate your data using Spark's API for data frames.
And this is just a few examples of them we'll be exploring these as we go on throughout the course.
Then there are also pipelines.
We will also be exploring pipelines.
It basically allows you to put in multiple steps together into a single pipeline object and then train
that pipeline object.
You may be familiar pipelines with Python's like learn and then we'll also talk about model selection
and tuning model selection.
Tuning is a little different than most other languages.
It does have a train validations split but the easiest way to use this is with that pipeline object
so we will show you how to use that later on this course.
OK that's really all I wanted to show you for now.
We're coming into the documentation later as you may have noticed this documentation is much much better
than the data frame documentation only that data from documentation gets better.
But you can rest easy knowing that you have a lot of examples here.
Free to explore under the machine learning library documentation.
For example if you click here on classification go to random forest classifier.
Click on that it will take you down and it has full code examples with actual example data sets and
it will actually also show you.
If you scroll down here where to find it in your installation of SPARC.
Now these file paths are pretty long so I include a lot of these documentations already in the downloaded
zip file that you have.
But we'll discuss that later on in the same lecture.
OK let's go ahead and go back to the presentation.
All right.
We're back.
We just had a quick tour of the documentation.
Now let's go over an example of process to use Spark's M-L lib.
And again don't worry about memorizing any of this.
We're going to get plenty of practice and review all of this when we actually start coding and subsequent
lectures First you need to get all your data into a data frame using what you've already learned.
Next you need to deal if your features and find your label and supervised learning you'll find your
label for unsupervised learning you will actually just use your features but you already know how to
grab data from a variety of sources.
You have to do next.
There's actually a deal of these features.
And if using a supervised learning algorithm find your label and this is where sparks and Madlib library
is a little different than other libraries.
Usually before you even get to your features and your label you need to manipulate your data that raw
data and spark separates this process into three categories.
Extraction transformation and selection extraction is just extracting features from the raw data selecting
what columns you want to use then transformation is actually either scaling and converting or modifying
certain features of your data then selection again is selecting that subset from a larger set of features.
So you have these three main street steps extraction getting from that raw data the features you want.
Transforming this through scaling converting or modifying features and then selecting the transform
objects.
Everything that you want to keep from that subset of transformations once the data is in the correct
format you need to select your machine learning model and you can check out the research links in this
lecture for guides on how to actually choose the correct model.
Well we will show you later on different models for classification regression etc. and once you've chosen
that model you need to get it into the correct format as far as your data is concerned.
For Spark's M-L lib and this is it works works pretty different from other languages.
This is a data frame with two columns a label column and an array of features column.
Let me explain what that actually means.
This formatting means you will convert all your columns of features into a single column consisting
of an array of all those features.
And as I mentioned this formatting isn't very common for most other languages.
They have machine learning capabilities.
That means at the end of the day once your data is ready to go into the machine learning library model
it actually just has two columns a single label column and then a features column of arrays of all the
actual features.
Now we'll show you what that looks like when we actually program this out.
And that's for supervised learning.
I should clarify if you're using an unsupervised learning algorithm then you actually just have one
column of just a features or a column.
The main reason for this sort of formatting is that it actually allows you to immediately distribute
these models across your cluster.
And we're going to be covering how to create clusters later on.
For now we will still stay on your local computer.
And this also saves the money that we want to pay.
Amazon Web Services are a data Brick's to actually create your clusters once you have all your data
in the correct format you need to train your model and evaluate your model.
You can also do this of just a simple test train split which will show you later on.
But Sparke has a full model selection suite of tools that we showed you a little bit of in the documentation
and we will show you how to use the train test validation splits later on we're going start off with
the basics a model evaluation and then slowly introduce train to split.
As I just mentioned as well is the full train validation split with holdout data afterwards we're going
to show you how does set up this entire process into a pipeline object.
This is going to it to easily set up a pipeline of data transformations model selection's parameter
tuning etc. so that you just train your pipeline at the end of the day and save all your work in certain
steps.
This allows for a much cleaner syntax which is why it's so important to begin to learn the data from
API for Sparc.
The best way to show any of this is just to dive straight into some examples throughout the machine
learning section for Sparc.
We're going to stick to a general format.
We'll start off with a general discussion of that machine learning concept and show an example algorithm
for that concept.
Then we will go over the official documentation example so you can get a quick taste of what the actual
code will look like.
Then we'll walk you through a more realistic example with data from a real data source such as Kaggle.
And then I'll give you a project exercise for us complete where you actually have to type in and fill
out the code on your own and then check it against a solutions lecture this course is going to stay
like a mathematical theory and there's basically two reasons for that.
One is that not everyone has the same background.
And two is that sparks and the Lib library actually makes it very easy to adjust parameters.
So if you have that mathematical experience for a particular algorithm you can quickly set options for
particular parameters and if you don't have that background that's OK too.
You can just leave the default options as set.
OK so I hope you're excited start using SPARC for machine learning.
This is really the latest in Sparc and the latest in big data technology.
So this is going to be a very great tool to have in your toolset.
All right thanks everyone.
And I will see you at the next lecture.