Hello everyone and welcome to values and variables in this lecture.
We're going to be discussing the differences between the value of a variable and how you can create
them in Scala.
You basically have two options when you're creating a new object in Scala.
You can either declare as a value using VHDL or as a variable using V-A are values the A-L are immutable.
Once they are assigned they cannot be changed variables however they are can be reassigned.
You should know however when you're doing this reassignment you must use the same data type the data
types are going to be discussing in this lecture are int or integer double for floating point numbers
strings and then boolean values such as True and False.
We're going to learn about collections such as lists maps and arrays later on.
Let's go ahead and discuss the general format when you're creating an object in Scala.
You should take note that if you're coming in from a language as Java that already uses the sort of
format this will feel pretty natural to you.
However if you're coming from my dynamic programming language such as Python this is going to be a little
strange to you at first.
You'll go ahead and help you make this transition as smooth as possible when you're learning Skala.
Like I mentioned the general format is going to use VHDL or V-A are as a keyword indicating whether
you want this to be a value or a variable.
Then you'll have your name.
The name is your chosen name of the object.
Things such as my num my list my value etc..
So that's your custom name.
Then you're gonna have a colon the data type.
Those are things such as int double string and boolean.
The actual label their equals and then the literal literal is what you're actually trying to assign
to the object name.
That can be a string such as Hello world or a number such as 11 or double such as twelve point five
etc..
Later on we're going to see that Scala can also infer the data type so well later on Skip defining the
data type and be a little less strict with that sort of general format.
Let's go ahead and get started with some examples so we can further explain these concepts.
I'm going to go ahead and jump to the command prompt now for using Mac jumped to your terminal.
All right here I am at my command prompt for using a Mac to your terminal and I've already started a
spark shell in order to open this Skala interpreter.
Let's go ahead to start off the very basic example of creating a variable.
We say the A R for that variable the name we want this to be.
So I'm going to go ahead and just call this my VAR then we'll say Colon the data type we expect this
to be.
I'm going to go ahead and clarify.
This is an integer data type.
By saying I.A. in there will say equal to 10 enter and notice now you have my VAR colon is an integer
equal to 10.
And when you're learning this if you're coming in from a dynamic programming assignment it may help
if you actually say those words out loud.
My variables and integer equal to 10.
OK now let's go ahead and create a value.
I'll call this my Val colon.
We'll say this is a double anoda time capitalizing d here I will say that's equal to 2.5.
Now I have my avowe is a double.
That's equal to 2.5.
I have my declaration of VAR or Vau the name hole and the data type equal to and then that literal.
Let's go ahead and discuss reassignments remember I said that variable's can be reassigned to FISA.
My VCR is equal to.
Let's go ahead and try to reassign this to a string.
Hello.
We're going to get an error.
And it says Type mismatch and that's because even though this is a variable and it supports reassignments
the assignment that you're reassigning to has to actually be the same data type.
So notice that it actually says required integer.
In this case we can go ahead and then say my VCR is equal to.
Let's go ahead and make it 100 and now we've successfully reassign that variable.
Let's go ahead and try the same thing with my value.
So if I say my vowel is equal to hello I'll get an error again.
But notice the error is different this time.
Even though there's a type mismatch it actually says error re-assignment to now which means you cannot
reassign a value.
You can only do that for variables so even if I say my vowel is equal to and we are using doubles so
I say maybe ten point one I'll still get that error.
Re-assignment to.
Well now as you program along we'll usually actually use just values in order to try to take care of
possible re-assignment errors as we go along for larger chunks of code.
Now really depends on what you're doing whether you're going to use a variable or a value.
And we'll talk about those situations when we actually make larger scripts of code.
But throughout the majority of this course we're going to be using now a little more often than variable's
OK.
So let's go ahead and show you how Skala can actually infer data types that we don't have to constantly
the Klare it's double boolean etc. so we can go ahead and in this.
I'm going to go in and clear this council say control L here since I'm on Windows.
Now it's clear that OK.
So I'm at Scala.
I'll go ahead and say the vowel of C is equal to 12 and I'll hit enter.
So notice here how it says C is an integer equal to 12.
So Scala is actually inferring the data type based on the literal that it gave it.
And this is going to save you a lot of time and a lot of effort.
So you don't constantly have to say it's double or boolean.
And throughout the course this is the kind of assignment we're going to be working with.
The majority of the time we'll go ahead and show you a couple more examples of this.
Maybe you want to go ahead and create a string so you can say my underscore string is equal to and then
in double quotes here I can say something like Hello.
And then I have my string is equal to and in first that string data type based off those double quotes
and it says equal to Hello.
Now is a quick know there are rules as far as what are valid names and invalid names for an object in
Scala.
You can't have names start with some sort of special character or a number so you can't say something
like two.
My string is equal to hello.
Otherwise you'll get an error because you'll get an invalid literal number so you can't start off values
or variables of a number.
The other thing you should also try to avoid doing is using periods instead of underscores so you can't
say something like my string is equal to.
Hello.
That's also going to give an error.
Now I want you to be aware that you can avoid this error if you use these sort of Dasch these dasht
quotes here we can say my string dash and this is actually below that tilde sign on your keyboard and
then say hello and this will actually work.
However I don't recommend that you actually use this will just use underscores throughout this course
because that's usually the main way skald developers will assign names.
OK.
So go ahead and review the notes.
But main Maine thinks the take out of this are values versus variables that variables can be reassigned
values cannot.
And also valid naming schemes such as using underscores and starting with lower case letters instead
of starting with numbers or using dots.
OK.
Hope you found this pretty straightforward.
Go ahead and post any questions you have to the Q&amp;A forums.
We're still keeping it pretty simple just using the command prompt but later on we're going to expand
our knowledge and actually use a script in the next section of the course.
OK.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.