Hello everyone and welcome to the booleans comparison operators lecture.
This is going to be just a brief lecture on Bullen's and how to use comparison operators and Skala.
Let's go ahead and chumped the Scala interpreter to get started.
OK so here I am at my Spark's shell I have the SQL interpreter running.
Let me go ahead and show you how to do a boolean in Scala.
For a true it's just lower case true.
And then for false it's just going to be lower case false as far as comparison operators.
It's going to be basically what you would expect.
So we can say one greater than two that's going to return the ball in true or false.
Less then it's just that Leston symbol.
You can also do greater than or equal to or less than or equal to.
So is one greater than or equal to one that's going to be true is one less than or equal to 30.
That's also true.
And then we can also do checks for equality with two equal sides.
So it's going to return true.
And then it can do checks for any quality using exclamation mark and an equal sign so as to not equal
to four that returns true.
And that's really all you need to know as far as the basics of booleans and comparison operators.
Something else I wanted to quickly note is the motter modular operator and that's going to allow you
to check the remainder based off of arithmetic operations.
So for example if we say something like 4 percent sign 2 we get the result of zero sets for Matu which
basically means when you divide four by two.
What is the remainder in this case it's going to be zero.
But if we do 5 mod 2 we get remainder 1 or an integer result of 1.
We're going to be using this later on the course for simple things such as checking if a number is even.
So you can check the numbers even just by saying the number mod to never return 0.
Then he notes even when you can also do things such as check for prime numbers using that sort of modular
notation.
And again that's just the percentage sign as it is in many other languages.
All right.
That's really all there is for this lecture.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next one.