Hello everyone and welcome to the Intelli Jay I-T lecture.
Now that we're approaching the machine learning topics for this section of the course you may want to
begin thinking about switching to a fool ideally from a text editor.
In this lecture we're going to briefly go over the installation process for Intelli J.
It's actually quite simple so we won't show it for all the operating systems because it's basically
just downloading a file and then running through the installer.
However I wanted to note that we're actually going to continue using atom for teaching purposes in the
section used to its display being better suited for it.
So the Adam text editor has a larger fought display in the terminal lines up nicely so that it's actually
better suited for teaching and for screen casting but I highly encourage you to explore using the Intel
g idea anyways as you may find it a much more powerful option rather than just using Adam's text editor.
Also make sure to check out the resource links in this lecture for more information on how to really
utilize Intelli J to its full capabilities.
So I want to note that even though I'm going to be using Adam text editor it's really only because it's
better suited for my screen casting.
If I were to actually write my own Scala project I'd probably be switching to either Intelli J ID or
switching to a notebook which actually to discuss later on in the course lets go ahead and jump to your
browser to show you how to download until Ejay ID and walk through the installation process.
OK here I am on my browser at dot com.
Go ahead and search for Intelli day ID.
Thats going to be Intelli J.
Id.
And you should see the very first link its from Jepp brains that com slash ID CA
go ahead and click on that link and then you should see until the G idea or the integrated development
environment then go ahead and click download scroll all the way down and there is an ultimate version
and you have to pay for that so lets go ahead and download the community version.
I've already downloaded it so I'm going to go ahead and jump to my downloads folder so I can open up
that download.
Should we just say that executable file or if you're on a Mac it's probably not the AMG file.
Let's go ahead and get that file.
All right here I am at my downloads.
My very first file here this ID.
I see.
Go ahead and double click on that.
It's the application.
So we're going to go ahead and open that up and then walk you through the installation process.
There's really one main thing that I want to make sure you set up correctly in that setting up until
Ejay idea in order to use Skala.
And it should automatically prompt you to do that.
So go ahead and just click next here choose install location go ahead and choose the default that's
fine.
Then depending on what you want you can have associations so if you have java files and you want to
use until day or Java you can go ahead and do that association.
I'll go ahead and leave these blank so I don't want to stop short either.
Go ahead and just say install and install Intelli ID are going to go ahead and jump forward in time.
This finished installation OK it looks like the installation finished.
Let's go ahead and run the community.
And then show you how to set up the Scala plug in for Intelli Jay.
Go ahead and click run and then you'll notice it says you can import your settings from a previous version
of Intelli J.
You don't have a previous version just go ahead and click.
I don't have a previous version and then hit OK there.
Privacy Policy go ahead and accept that.
Otherwise you can't operate this.
And then you can set a UI theme either.
Basically light or dark.
I personally prefer dark.
So will go ahead and click next year and then you'll see that it says there's build tools version controls
seeing Android etc. We want to click next on a feature plug ins and you should see here a scholar.
So we want to install plug in first gulling which support.
So make sure you install that.
That's basically the key thing I want you to make sure that you click on when you're installing Intelli
J.
Ideally on your first run through you should get this feature plugins.
If you don't find the feature plug ins you can go ahead and go back to the vault plug ins or if you
still don't find it there you can go ahead and click on the resource link for this lecture which has
a fool your L description from intelligence.
How to do this all manually but this should be the simplest way to do it just under feature plug ins.
Go ahead and install the skull plug in.
Now if you're them editor user maybe you like the them editing environment you can go ahead and install
idea them which emulates of them.
Editor environment inside of this Intelli J.
A.J..
All right.
I'm going to go ahead and jump forward in time for this finished plug in instillation right now that's
done.
Go ahead and start using an Haly idea.
Go ahead and click on that and then it should start up the ID for you then you can go ahead and create
a new project import a project or open up a new folder.
You go ahead and click on Create new project.
All right.
Once you've started a new project you'll go ahead and come over here to where it says Skala click on
that and you'll note that it says Skala.
There's also options here for Datti and SBT.
We'll discuss later on what those actually are.
These are basically going to be ways to actually package a group of Skala scripts and dependencies all
into a single it's in a jar file and then call it from the command line.
But right now we're going to go ahead and just say Skala it next.
And then you can call your project whatever you want in this case.
I've already called it my first project and what we need to do is point Skala to where the SDK is for
our project as well as where the skull STK is basically just a point to where you installed a Skala
in Java.
Let me go ahead and show you where that should be.
Review the installation lecture her Skala and Sparc and Java in case your memory is a bit fuzzy on where
you actually save these.
So the project SDK if you follow along with me on the windows installation lecture at the beginning
of the course you just go ahead and say new Slik home directory for JDK and it should take you automatically
to brains.
What we need actually do is fine under program files.
Java so the on version of Windows you're running.
For me my giallo files are actually under C. Program Files and then go down to where it says Java and
open up my program files scroll down to Java and then click here on JDK 1.8 point zero underscore one
to one.
I want to go in and click ok there and that's going to let it know that my Java version 1.8 is located
there.
So that's my project X.
OK.
Now I want to go ahead and finalize Skala SDK.
So go ahead and just click on Create here.
And depending on where you download this it may be a little tricky to find through the browser.
So if you want you can actually just download one so you can click download here download Skala version.
The latest should be fine.
Click OK and it will download Skala of course here.
Now we should have already had Skala set up depending on how you actually install it.
It may be difficult to find everything.
So I encourage you just to go ahead and download Skala instead of using browser because you may have
to look at your head and folders and make it tricky.
The easiest way to do this is just click download and then download the latest version of Scala.
OK we're going to go ahead and fast forward to this finished downloading and installation.
All right.
So that has finished downloading and we have a Scala SDK ready to go so that you can just go ahead and
click Finish and you'll have your new project open up.
You'll get some tips you can go ahead and just not show tips on startups you want up to you.
Go ahead and then click close.
And then it should eventually look like this.
Once it's done indexing you'll see a little index timer go away here at the bottom and you can expand
this.
Check out the idea the source file and then right click here go to New and you can do a scarlet worksheet
or a Scala scripts.
We've been working on a script so let's just go ahead and use that file name and say My first it OK.
Once you have that open you can just begin to type out scul code as we've been before so you can say
something like ballocks is equal to 23 and then you'll notice as you begin to play around these values
you can say X dots and you'll see that you actually start getting a lot more options and code completion
help than we did in a normal text editor because as a rule ID you have all these options.
You go ahead and explore.
All right.
Now let's show you how to actually create what's known as a Scala worksheet which is an awesome tool
to use when you're typing out Scarlette code for Sparc.
So go ahead and Right-Click click on my first project folder it myu and then go to Skala worksheet ask
you to name it.
We'll go ahead and call it my work is OK.
And then you notice that you get this my work.
SC So basically what a worksheet is is it's going to allow you to continually compile your Skala code
and see the output in another pane.
Let me go in to show you what I mean by that.
I'm going to say vowel x is equal to 10 and then say Val Y is equal to 20.
And I have an interactive mode right now which means it's auto saving and it's actually showing me the
output in this right hand tab here.
And then I can do other things such as create an array.
So say valpré is equal to array will say one two three and then I can begin to write a for loop to print
all the numbers in the erase all say for let's go in and say and U-M are now will say print.
Alan numb.
And notice I'm getting a lot more code completion help there.
But notice what's really interesting is I'm actually getting the results so here one two and three.
So this is an interactive environment that you can see the output directly as you type it which can
be really useful.
Now I've been guilty of deliberately hiding these worksheets from you because they can almost be crutches
for you when you're first starting out how to learn how to program in Skala and spark.
But now that you've learned how to program in Scala how to use Sparke data frames it's time to give
you the full access to all the tools you need in order to really create full functioning programs.
All right so I really encourage you to explore the full power of this fool idea in Intelli J.
Now as I noted we're going to keep using atom text editor just for the purpose of screen casting because
the font in the terminal looks a little nicer.
We set it all up.
But as you fall on I would actually encourage you to create worksheets in Skala these C files.
So you go ahead and fall on my videos and in case you ever want to run this in the terminal you can
actually do that in intelligence.
You just come down here to the left and then select terminal in a terminal here for you.
Again I'm going to be using Adam text editor.
Not because it's better than the Intelli J ID just because it works a little better for a screen casting
purposes.
OK.
Thanks everyone.
Hope you enjoyed the lecture and I'll see you at the next one.