Hello everyone and welcome to the project exercise overview lecture for the principal component analysis
section of the Course.
This lecture we're going to briefly explain what you're going to be doing for your project exercise.
Let's open up the skull a script file and get started.
All right here we are at the Adam text editor I've opened up the PC underscore project underscore exercise
that Skala script and if you're looking for the solutions you can check out the next lecture or you
can just open up the exercise underscore solutions that Skoll a script and this project you're going
to just be completing the tasks below to try to transform a data set with 30 features into a data set
with fewer principal components.
And keep in mind there are some things here that we haven't actually explicitly shown.
And this is because part of this project is to discover how to do something on your own by reading through
the documentation.
And if you start off there's a data set description which is just a brief description of the data so
we're going to be using the number of characteristics.
Number of instances number of attributes and in this case it's 30 numeric attributes about ADD cancer
and tumors so you can see the radius of a tumor or texture perimeter area etc..
So there's a lot of actual features here that we're going to be checking out and you can see the minimax
values here for all of them.
So just keep scrolling down through this and eventually you will see the project exercise tests here
and you're just going to follow along and do what it asks you to do import spark you spark to read the
file print the schema the data etc..
And eventually as you go down here there's one line of code that's actually filled out for you.
And this is because there are so many columns that you're going to find this line useful when you want
to do something like set input columns on a feature assembler or a vector Sembler object.
So I've already left this little convenient array here for you.
That way you can just past call names if you ever need to pass in an array of the string names of the
columns in that data frame.
So I'm just gonna leave that there for you to figure out how to use that.
But that should hopefully save you some time from writing out 30 column names.
Now if you come down here you'll notice that there's a little section talking about normalization.
Now often it's usually a good idea to normalize each feature to have the unit standard deviation and
or zero mean when using principal component analysis it is essentially just a pre step to principal
component analysis is not always necessary to do this sort of normalization.
But sometimes it's a pretty good idea.
So what you're going to be doing is looking at the meld of feature documentation.
So to spark that Apache or check out the documentation that we're always referring to and figure out
how you can standardize the cancer dataset and you can refer to the solutions for hints if you get stuck
on the step.
But basically you're going to be trying to figure out how to use this standard scaler on that data.
And there's more tasks for you to do as you figure out more and more how to reference documentation
to figure out how to use that standard scalar scalar.
Once you've done that you can come down here and continue on with the rest of the project using PCA.
All right.
Hope you guys enjoy the project and I will see you at the next lecture where we go over the solutions.