Hello everyone and welcome to part two of the walk through example of a logistic regression problem
for classification with SPARK.
Let's jump right back in where we left off last time OK.
Here we are right back where we left off when we left off we talked about using vectors vector assembler's
string indexers and one hot encoders to actually deal for categorical columns.
Let's actually use those in this case.
We are going to import what we need to start off with.
And as I mentioned all the time you usually put these imports at the top but I'm separating out in this
format so you can see what goes with what.
So I'm going to import org that Apache that spark that emal that feature and then to import multiple
things you can just put it in brackets here.
I want to import a vector assembler the string indexer and then the vector indexer.
And that's going to allow me to actually deal with these categorical columns.
And then the last thing I want to do here also from feature is one hot encoder OK.
And then finally I want to import Orrick Apache spark M-L Lin alge vector's sometimes you know import
that you may get some errors.
Ok moving along we want to first deal for categorial categorical columns that are in string forms by
using the string indexer.
So I'm going to say Val create an object called gender indexer is equal to a new string indexer and
then very similar to what we're using vector assembler's we set an input call.
In this case it's going to be sex and then use sets up McCollum's so set output call and I would just
call this sex index OK.
Once we have that we also need to do the same for the embarked column.
So we can say Val Embarq indexer is equal to New Street indexer input call to.
In this case it's Embarq
and then I also output call
to something like Embarq index.
All right.
So just to label this this is converting strings into numerical values.
And then after that we need to convert numerical values.
Into some sort of one hot encoding and basically what that means is 0 or ones in order for a logistic
regression function to actually deal with this we will say Val gender gender in KOTOR is equal to new.
And then I'm going to actually task one Hutten Khoder I will set the input call to be equal to what
we outputted last time.
In this case sex index.
And then I will set the output call to be called something like encoded or something.
Or we can actually just say.
It's going to be a vector we'll say sex we see.
So that sex vector and then we'll say well Embarq encoder is equal to new lips.
One ha encoder in very similarly we will say set the input to embark index and then we will set the
output call to embark vector.
So severely Embarq we will just say VTC OK.
So so far what we've done is we've taken in that string column.
If we check this out we have these two string columns sex's which is male and female and then disembarks
which is letters.
We want to take those using the string indexer create and a new column called either sex index or Embarq
index that converts these into actual numbers.
So something like mail is one.
A female is to offer these locations as one cue is to see is three.
And we want to take those singular columns and use one one in coding to actually create some dummy variables.
So we will take as input these sex index and embark index and then set some output columns.
Now it doesn't really matter what you call this but hopefully this sort of naming convention is a little
more clear for you.
All right after that we want to put everything together into the classic form that we have been dealing
with that label features form so we need to put everything into label features.
And as we've done before we will create a value called the Sembler and create a new vector assembler.
And then I want to set my input columns.
This is actually pleural to be in train of all the columns are going to be working with.
And in this case these are going to be my passenger class the sex column that output at the end of that
gendering coater.
And later on we'll show you how to actually implement the indexers and encoders then is the age column.
And I'm just passing on strings here.
The sibling spouse column the parent child column or parch and then let me check what else we have.
We also need the Fair column and then the Embarq vector column.
Make sure it's a comma there.
So the Fair column
and then Embarq the PC.
All right.
So we have those input columns and then as we always do with a vector assembler we need to set these
as an output.
And in this case the output will be just features.
So I will do is put a print C's here so I can write this in multiple lines.
And as long as this is all on under that group of parentheses should be fine.
So then I will say that set output call.
In this case features they make sure that princes are balanced and you can see the highlighting here.
Looks like we're good to go.
All right.
Now I have my assembler.
Let me just run this and make sure everything actually worked.
So I'm going to save this and then say load log Rick X scholar enter and make sure everything's working
all right.
OK print out that example row my feature in coder's and stree indexers are OK.
Dr. assembler's Okay so it looks like we are good to go.
Keep in mind I haven't actually done anything yet.
I need to call these indexers and encoders.
Right now we're just creating them.
Up next I want to split the data into a training set and a test set.
So I will say Val Auray training test equal to my log Regg data.
Not all of it.
Remember we want to drop the missing values and then I can call random split and this takes in an array
where you decide the ratio.
So I want 0.7 to be so 70 percent of this logarithmic data is going to be this object training and then
everything else.
Or 0.3 30 percent will be test and you can actually add in a seat value here if you want to follow along
exactly with me.
I recommend you do so.
Put in a seed of.
In this case I'm just going to put one two three four five and just make sure that the random split
is the same as mine.
So remember this is a random split.
So if you don't put in the seat value your split may be different than mine which means your confusion
matrix at the end of everything will be different.
But if you want to make sure you get all the same results if you run this one two three four five you
should get the same result as I do or at least extremely similar.
Next up is to actually set up the pipeline.
The pipeline is going to allow us to put all these encoders assemblers and indexers into a pipeline
so we can just feed in our raw data into the pipeline and take care of everything.
So I will see import or that Apache that sparked the M-L pipeline.
You've noticed that we're importing a lot of stuff from m-L.
So probably if you're putting this all in one object script you are just at the very top say M-L and
then in brackets have a bunch of imports they're coming from that machine learning library but this
will allow us to play around often spark a little more.
I will say well L-R is equal to new logistic regression.
So I create this logistic regression object and then this is something we haven't seen before.
The pipeline.
So I will AUPs create this value pipeline.
Call it new pipeline and the next part of the pipeline is to set the stages and the stages is just going
to be an array of all these indexers encoders assemblers.
And then finally the model.
So I will say new pipeline set stages and then passen an array of all the stages I want in this case.
I'm going to basically be doing everything I wrote here in order it will do the gender indexer roomer
that's a string indexer.
It grabs the input column called sex and then sets an output column called sex index.
The next thing I have is the embark indexer grabs a string column called embarked sets the output to
embark index.
The next thing I have over here is the gender and coater those these very similar things up in this
case it takes in the output of those indexers and outputs those vectors.
Now we have Embarq and coater does the same thing.
And then I finally have my assembler that takes in all those feature columns sets a single output column
called features.
Then I go ahead and I put that array.
So let's put that all in in here.
First thing I want to do is put in the Jinder indexer then the Embarq indexer then the gender in coater
then the embark and coater And then once we have the indexing and the encoding set up we just need to
assemble it.
So I will say assembler and then you can actually just passing your model here as well.
So LR for logistic regression model.
And that's your whole pipeline.
You've set up all the stages that you're actually going to do for your data.
Then you can fit the pipeline just as if it was a normal machine learning model.
So you'll say Val model is equal to pipeline that fit and this case will just fit it to the training
data and we can later on test it against the test data.
So that fits it to the training data to get results in my test data.
I just say Velle results take that model I just trained from that pipeline and transform my test set
OK let's run this and make sure it all works.
So I will load that script and while this is running it shouldn't take that long the machine learning
part may take a little while.
But let's actually review what we've done so far.
We've taken in our data as a CSP file printed out an example of what it looks like grabbed all the data
then dropped the missing values imported What we need to import create the indexers the deal of string
objects then convert the string objects into numerical objects convert those numerical columns into
one hot coded columns basically dummy variables take that get label and features in the right order
with assembler and then split the data into training and test called the pipeline create a model and
then set the stage for the pipeline fit it to the actual training data and get some results off of that.
All right.
Looks like that all ran just fine.
Have results here as a data frame.
Now it's time to actually evaluate how well our model performed on the test data going to start a little
bit of a new section here called Model evaluation.
And basically this is where we're going to have to pay a price for dealing with the latest and greatest
of Sparke the absolute newest stuff.
The reason for that is a lot of this metrics and evaluation stuff is still only available for our D.
Make sure you check the documentation.
After viewing this lecture to actually check if what I showing you here has been updated to data frames
I will make a note somewhere either before this lecture or after this lecture to links to the documentation
in case this ever gets updated for data frames.
Right now unfortunately it's still an art form so we will have to do is select our prediction column
in our label column off of our results and transform that to an R D.
First I want to actually import what I'm going to be using in this case.
It's going to be Org the Apache that spark that M-L lib.
Note the difference there not a male but a male lib.
And then call evaluation and call multiclass metrics
and then north to use this.
I need to convert our prediction results into an R D.
So I will create an object called prediction and labels and set equal to results select and I just want
to select the prediction column and the label column
and then set that as and this is where we can actually type it in as a data frame.
In this case I want to say as passen a tuple here double comma double and hopefully in the future once
this has been moved to M-L you will have to do this kind of tedious process and then say Dot r d d.
Basically what this is doing is if you look at results right now the results the print schema and hit
enter.
We have this probability this prediction and scrolling up here we have the label.
You also note that we have some of the original columns such as sex and embarked.
Those were actually not used during the model being trained because of the assembler only accepting
the scroll back up here the sex VEC and the embark thick and setting it out two features.
So the model only looked for a label and features it didn't actually look for the rest of these columns.
Essentially you could have just selected features and label before doing the train test split over here.
But kind of optional to you the machine learning algorithms are smart enough to understand that you
really only care about the label and the features column the ones that are actually called that.
All right moving along because of that we want to select just a prediction and just the label select
them as double double because that's the data type.
These are zeros and ones.
And then we want to set that as an r d d in order to use this multiclass MIT metrics because it's still
limited to ARDE these unfortunately.
Then I will say avowe metrics is equal to a new multiclass metrics and then passen the object they I
just made in this case prediction and labels and this allows me to actually create a confusion matrix
print.
Ellen confusion matrix prints Ellen and right off of this metrics.
Objects that I've just created I can say metrics dots confusion matrix.
Let's save this.
And then I want to walk you through a couple of things.
Be careful when using this semi outdated evaluation.
Going to load this and hopefully at the end of this we should see a confusion matrix printed out for
people who survived that people who didn't survive.
And you can review the theory lecture on logistic regression to understand what the confusion matrix
look like OK great.
Here's the confusion matrix we wanted.
Using these values you can actually calculate things such as precision recall and accuracy.
Type 1 error type 2 error.
Well we just discussed in the theory lecture now there's a caveat to this because it's under the older
male lib RTD.
If you say metrics dot and then hit tab here you should see a bunch of objects come up or methods.
Theoretically you should be able to call accuracy precision and recall a true positive rate etc..
Often this metrics object unfortunately because it's the older RBD.
If you say metrics that accuracy enter you will get an accuracy here but you have to notice something.
If I say metrics the recall I also get the exact same number for recall.
And then if I call metrics stop precision I will get the exact same number for precision.
Unfortunately recall and precision are actually just showing the accuracy as well.
And you notice that there's actually a warning here and you can rerun it to actually check what the
details are.
Basically multiclass metrics right now is broken.
And in the future probably won't be updated because it's under the old ardy method.
So if you want to calculate things such as precision and recall you should do that straight off the
confusion matrix the confusion matrix itself still works but always keep in mind that when you're dealing
with something that's basically on the edge of the newest available technology you're going to have
to be dealing with this sort of stuff often and check the documentation to make sure everything is still
working and always double check your answers.
So I apologize that that can be really annoying especially as you're just beginning to learn how to
use all these tools.
But that's the state of the language at this point in time.
And keep in mind I will try to make announcements in this course or set up extra notes or extra lectures
when I find stuff like this has been updated.
All right.
With that all being said that's basically all there is to performing a logistic regression in Sparke.
I'm going to minimize this terminal and just walk through everything we did because we did do quite
a bit of stuff.
First off we imported logistic regression as our chosen classification algorithm which started a spark
session set the logging level to not see so many outputs and the errors read in our CXXVI data explored
a little bit.
Then we grabbed all the data that we were going to use dropped all of the missing values that we didn't
want to deal with imported the features we were going to be using including Lin algebra vectors then
we used to separate string index or objects to deal to categorical columns that were strings so we converted
these strings into a single column and then these single index calls we convert using one hot encoding
to actual vector or array columns.
Then we want to use an assembler to grab all those features and set the output column as features.
You can go ahead and then split that array into training and test data or that data frame I should say
create a pipeline create a new logistic regression object and you can add parameters if you want.
Right now we're just keeping it simple but I encourage you to play around these parameters if you want
to then create a new pipeline object.
Set the stage is an array including your indexing your encoding your assembler and the actual model
you're working with.
Fit this pipeline as if it was just a normal model on your training data and then use the model to transform
your test data.
And right now you can use this semi outdated model evaluation technique.
If you're concerned about using these older evaluation techniques you can just get everything yourself
manually off the results.
So if you ever see the results and say that show these last columns here we say results stop print schema
are available to you.
So you have the probability and predictions including the label column all to yourself in case you ever
want to do any of the maps of type 1 or Type 2 errors yourself to make sure everything is correct.
All right.
If you have any questions feel free to post them to the Q&amp;A forums and I'll be happy to help you out.
Thanks everyone and I will see you at the next lecture.