Hello everyone and welcome to lecture on sets in Scala.
A set is a collection that contains no duplicate elements meaning that each element in a set is a unique
element.
And there's actually two kinds of sets in Scala.
The immutable sets and the mutable set.
Let's go ahead and jump to the Scala interpreter using the spark shell to get started.
All right.
Here we are at the interpreter.
Let me go ahead and start off by showing you how to build an empty set and create a value called S.
and I'll set it equal to this command set close parentheses and notice that this is a capital S and
this is going to return back Skoll duck collection got immutable.
That said nothing.
So basically this is telling you that we've created an immutable set which falls under the Scala collections
library and it contains nothing right now.
So we can say that S is equal to set and actually passing some values here such as integers 1 2 3.
And when we pass that in we get skald the collection immutable set but Scheller reports back that it
contains integers.
Now as I mentioned a Scala sets are a set.
In general is a collection that contains no duplicate elements.
So if I define a set with many duplicate elements so we'll go ahead and put many instances of ones and
twos and threes.
I run that I get the exact same thing as I did last time.
So it contains no duplicate elements.
It's just the one the two in the three.
Let's go ahead and show you how you can create a mutable set.
So now that I've created immutable sets it means that it can't add anything to them.
I want to go ahead and for instance add another number to a set.
I need a mutable one.
So in order to do that I can say Val S is equal to.
And we're basically going to almost copy the output curve that we got last time we'll say collection
dot mutable that set and then passing the numbers for instance one two three here.
So now we have Skala that collection that mutable that set.
And you'll notice that basically a lot of things and Skala as far as the collections are concerned have
a mutable version and an immutable version.
Kind of in the same way that vowel is immutable and variables are VAR or mutable.
So there's kind of this two way system here.
OK.
So we have S and a reminder that S is now a mutable set that contains the integers 1 2 and 3.
They can go ahead and add another integer to this by saying s plus equals four.
And then we'll notice as is now equal to a set of 1 2 3 4.
If you try doing that with an immutable set so I'm going to go ahead and clear that and hit up on my
arrow key to get back to this original set.
So now s is immutable.
If I try to add that for again note.
Notice what's going to happen here.
I get an error it says value plus equals is not a member of skald a collection immutable set which makes
sense because it's immutable.
We can't actually make any adjustments to it.
All right.
Let me go ahead and show you another method for mutable sets.
So just to review.
Let's go in and say Val immunise s are.
IMO it's funny how you want to read it and we'll go out and call this from collection dot mutable dot
sets and I'm going to pass in one to three.
And now if I call that immutable Esser I'm nuts I can say.
Plus sequel's for if I call it again.
Notice I have one two three four.
Another way of adding another number or another item to this saying add and then go in and put in a
5 there.
Return back True and true is basically telling you that adding that five successfully.
So if I call it mutes or I'm nuts.
Now I have 1 5 2 3 4.
So notice here that a set doesn't actually retain an order.
Kind of works in the same way that a hash table does.
As far as the location of those items.
So you cannot grab from an index from a set.
So that's a very important distinction to make versus a list or an array that does have an order.
Sets are an unordered collection of unique elements.
Now there's a few more useful operations I want to show you.
For instance if I go in and clear this if I show what I am says right now has 1 5 2 3 4 I can go ahead
and call max and min offer that set to ground the minimum and maximum values.
And another important operation they are probably going to be using later on is actually let's say I
have a list of 1 2 3 1 2 3.
So it has duplicate elements.
I can actually cast this to a set and the way I can do that is just by calling the two method off of
it.
And if I click tab here you'll notice I have a lot of options as far as where I can cast it to.
But I'll just say cast two sets and now I have my list to set which means I can actually set this equal
to something.
So for instance I can say thou my new set is equal to my list thought to set.
And there it is.
Enough I call my new set.
I get that set and notice that the list had multiple elements in it 1 2 3 1 2 3.
But the set version gets reduced down to 1 to 3 since it does not contain duplicate elements.
So the main things to get out of this is how to create a set how to add items to a mutable set and the
differences between an immutable immutable set and the fact that a set doesn't retain any sort of order.
It's also important to notice.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.