Hello everyone and welcome to the section on Skala and Sparke on AWOS EMR or Amazon Web Services elastic
map readers in this section of the course we're going to be showing you how to set up Skala and Spahr
to run on a cluster that you specify on Amazon Web Services elastic map reduce or AWOS EMR.
We've already shown you data Brick's notebook system and now we're going to show you the Open Source
zipline notebook system.
Keep in mind that we're now going to be doing tasks that are beyond any free tier of service following
along with this video is going to cost you money in Amazon Web Services is going to charge you what
we show in this section of the course costs really only a few dollars per hour of runtime.
So at most you should be paying $10 maximum.
But if you forget to terminate your instance you're going to be continually charged so please keep that
in mind.
Only follow along if you feel comfortable spending some money on Amazon Web Services and you know you're
going to remember to terminate your cluster if you feel uncomfortable with this or tend to be forgetful
than just watched his lectures and don't follow along.
So please keep in mind I'm not personally responsible for any costs you may incur when Amazon Web Services
charges you.
There's lots of horror stories online of people forgetting to turn off their cluster and leave it running
for a month.
And at the end of the month they get charged hundreds or thousands of dollars so really keep that in
mind.
It's really easy to forget things and have those charges stack up.
Now with that being said let's go ahead and get started.
Go to AWOS thought Amazon Dot Com and set up an account there.
You're going to need to provide some sort of debit card or credit card for billing information.
But other than that should be a pretty straightforward set up process.
And then once you set up that account go ahead and log into the main W-S con..
You can also check out zipline patch.
The word we're going to be talking that zipline open documentation for just a little bit before we actually
get started.
Cluster.
All right.
Want to jump to my browser have those two links open and explore them a little more with you.
All right so here I am at my browser I've logged into my AWOS console.
I have my services ready to go and I also have another tab open.
Zipline Apache the org which is the official documentation page or official Web site for the Apache
zipline open source project.
Now before we get started actually creating a cluster I want to just give you a quick tour of zipline
not a patch or scribe just a little more detail what Apache's applet is.
It's basically just the web based notebook that enables interactive data analytics.
You can almost think of it as an open source version of data Briggs's notebook now data Brick's does
offer a lot of convenience things such as uploading other tables or setting up clusters or just couple
of clicks but you get an additional charge for that convenience so keep in mind you can think of Zeppelin
as just an alternative option where you're trading off a little bit of convenience for the fact that
it's free on top of AWOS you start to pay for AWOS.
But zipline is open source.
It's also a multipurpose notebook so it supports multiple language beckons.
Not just the Patchi spark of Skala but it supports things such as Cassandra our post-career sequel Hadoop
DFS cetera.
You can check out more information here as Epling that a patch that org.
There are other types of notebooks if you're familiar of other programming languages you can think of
this as almost like a Jupiter notebook type interface.
But keep in mind that Apache Zeppelin in particular was really designed for big data type notebooks
and it was especially designed for Apache spark integration.
So you don't need to build a separate module plug into a library for it.
Apache's Zeppelin of SPARC integration provides a lot of those dependencies already loaded up for you
and it also has the capability to do some sort of basic chart visualization.
So you can explore this documentation page a little more has a nice community link you can just click
here on docs and you'll notice that currently at the filming of this video the current release.
Is there a point six point to Amazon Web Services does a really good job of keeping up with the latest
releases of not just pacis Zetlin but also Skala and Spark's usually have no problems getting the latest
releases to Amazon Web Services.
You won't usually get the development just because there may be bugs in that.
But as far as the latest release in our case 0.6 point 6.2 that will be available to you on Amazon Web
Services so you can click here go to the quick star.
It'll tell you how to install stuff exploring the UI gives you a little tutorial basic feature guides
etc. but right now let's go back to our AWOS cons..
You can explore the rest of this documentation on your own and actually set up a cluster OK.
So coming back to this AWOS Amazon Dot com.
Well we want to do is actually find EMR.
Now if you want there's usually a search box here we can just type in EMR and find the Minnich framework
or classic map reading service if for some reason the UI has changed.
You can usually just click here on this icon and it will take you there excuse me.
Click here on services and you can search services here.
Then again it should be under analytics EMR or you can just type in EMR and it should show up.
So just find the lasting map read his page and you'll see something that looks like this.
Let me zoom out a little bit so we can see the whole picture.
And basically this is Amazon's elastic map reduce and it's a web service that allows you to create clusters
very easily.
So click here and create cluster and we will have some quick options.
Now in the past used to have to go to advance options to make sure everything was set up properly.
But actually a classic map reduce Amazon Web Services has a really good job of including Sparc and zipline
as some sort of base configuration.
So call your cluster whatever you want to call it my cluster.
You can turn logging off if you want.
It's basically just going to copy the cluster's log files automatically to some S-3 which is just Amazon
Web Services storage.
When it turned that off we're not going to be necessary and we're going to go to launch mode have clustered
there and then software configuration.
We're going to choose Amazon as our vendor have this latest release that's fine whatever the default
he is here that should be fine and if we come down we should see Sparke on Hadoop with Zeppelin here.
And you'll notice that it's actually the latest version SPARC 2.0 point two ends up Blin 0.6 point two
which is nice.
Now for some reason you don't see anything here with SPARC and zipline you can always come here to go
to advanced options.
And if you go here then you can actually click on Hadoop pig hide et cetera and you should see options
here to then click on things such as zipline and Sparke.
Now I'm going to go back to quick options more likely than not under quick options you should see something
pre-configured has Sparc and zipline ready to go for you.
So that's what we'll be choosing and I'm going to turn logging back off since I came back too quick.
So I'm calling it my cluster logging is off.
Have that looked at cluster vendors Amazon and their other applications and their quick options just
using this one to spark Hadoop and Zetland that they have my hardware configuration and basically here
this is where are you going to manually choose how big you want your cluster to be.
So I'm going to choose just the default which is M3 x large with number of instances equal to 3.
And basically that's going to be what is your master node and how many core nodes do you have on top
of that the Pentagon what instance you use.
You're going to be charged more or less.
So keep that in mind.
There's also different generation so there's the previous generation and the current gen generation.
But right now we're going to just use the default N3 that x large number of instances just to be in
one master in two core nodes.
Obviously if you go a larger or more expensive hardware you're going to be charged more than you're
charged per instance hour.
So that means if you choose a more expensive instance every hour you going to get charged more.
All right.
Now security and access you're going to need to log in to this Amazon Web Services EMR by using what's
known as an easy to keep hair this easy to keep perience going to make sure that you're able to actually
log on and connect to your cluster through your command prompt.
Now if you've never created an ISA to keep there you can click here and learn how to create an easy
to keep here and you just come over here follow these instructions to actually create an easy to keep
here.
It's pretty straightforward.
Just come here to the Amazon easy to con..
Go to click keep peers create a key pair click create and save the resulting file in a safe location
and then you're going to need to modify your pen file.
If you are on a Windows or Mac so there's instructions here on how to do this on Windows.
And if you click here on this tab there's instructions on how to do it on a Mac since you may or may
not have done this before.
I'm going to briefly create a new key pair that you can actually see how this works.
I'm going to open my Amazon easy to con. In a new window and click on key pairs in the navigation pane.
So if I come here to my console I'm going to see Pierce here I've already created some but let's just
make another one point click here on create key pair and type in your create keep your name.
So for instance we'll call this my sparkie click on Create.
Once you created that new key pair.
It should automatically have downloaded that PMS file.
It's really important that you remember where this PTM file is.
You basically don't get another chance to download another one.
So make sure you know the location of this PTM file you just created and downloaded.
All right so once you have that file make sure you save it to a location that you remember I back here
to our set up keep there once you have that pgm or pen file in a safe location you're probably going
to need to modify your pen file in order to S-sh or securely connect to your cluster.
Now modifying this pen files a little different depending on whether you're on a Mac or Linux or Windows
computer.
Amazon Web Services actually has really nice instructions for either version but basically if you're
on a Mac or Linux you're just going to open up your terminal and type this command you're going to say
S.H. maade space O.G. dash RW x and then Mikee pair that PM or whatever you're called your key pair.
Now remember you have to be at the same directory directory location where you saved your PMS file.
Now if you're on Windows it's going to be a little more involved.
You have to download Agent X to your computer.
There's a link right here to download it.
You're going to launch the gen click load.
Select the PM file you created earlier click open then click OK on the page and notice telling you your
key has successfully imported enter a passphrase in the key passphrase field.
Click Save private key save it in a PPK format the format Windows needs for S-sh into a cluster and
then you're going to name your petty private key such as my key pair that PPK click save and then exit
the PATTI-JANE application.
OK so go ahead and do that whether you're on a Windows or Mac.
Take care of this M-file.
I'm on Windows.
I'll be using this putty generate now.
Windows is a little more involved but again Amazon Web Services is really good documentation on this.
If you ever get stuck you can either just look at the steps it's pretty straightforward or just google
search AWOS S-sh easy to keep there.
Or something similar.
And Amazon EMR has a whole management guide on how to do this step by step.
So I'm going to close this.
Again the instructions are always here for you.
Just learn how to create an easy to keep there.
I'm going to choose the one easy to keep.
I just made which was my spark key and then I'm going to come down here and click on Create cluster
and that's going to be creating your cluster right now.
Now it usually takes a couple of minutes to actually fully create the cluster.
So you may need to just wait a little while it's going to say starting for a little bit but it's actually
creating a cluster right now and it has the my spare key for security and access.
OK while you're waiting for your cluster to actually initialize what you want to do is make sure that
you're going to be able to s s h into your Zeppelin notebook.
And for that you may need to change the security settings so what are you going to do under security
and access.
Come here and click on security groups for Master that we'll take you to this de-link on security groups.
All right.
Once you're on this security group page where you're going to do is select the map reduce M..
Click here and you should see the security groups.
And if you click on inbound tab where you want to do is click here on edit.
Now we're going to open up some ports here so click on edit and then click here where it says add rule
and you'll get a new little rule pop up.
And we want to select SS h and then make sure that the port is 22 and over here on Kustom we can either
select any where or my IP.
Now if you select my IP that means you can only connect to this cluster from your actual IP address
location.
That's probably the most secure way of going about this.
You want to click anywhere.
That means anyone will be able to connect to this cluster which could be dangerous for the most secure
thing.
Just click on my IP and then we want to do is open up one more rule so say add rule and then have this
be a custom TCAP rule.
And then what I want to do is open up the poor 8 8 9 0 and I get I'm just going to say my IP.
So if those two things selected click save.
All right so now that we have our security groups for it to go or we needed to just wait for the actual
cluster to start.
So come back here to the AWOS cluster in probably still waiting right now may take a couple of minutes.
But basically we have everything set up.
OK.
Coming back to the Amazon AWOS counsel for your cluster.
Once you see the masters running and the Corps is running you should see something like waiting here
and that means your cluster is waiting for you to actually do something with it which is good to know
what we can do here is you have basically two options depending on how strict you want your security
settings to be.
You could S-sh.
And that has to do all the stuff I was talking about earlier using that dot PM A Your key or yours PPK
if you're on Windows and setting up the actual S-sh connection.
But if you did the security settings that I showed you here you can actually access your zipline notebook
directly through this public your Airlink.
Now keep in mind this is a pretty open way of accessing a cluster.
So this may not be the right setting for you or your organization that pending on how important security
is for you.
But I can just copy and paste this public DNS into my browser and then write Colan 8 8 9 0 remember
that was the port we left open for Zeppelin enter and you should see something that looks like this
the Zeppelin notebook page.
And now you're ready to actually create your own notebooks and run whatever you want on your cluster
on a W-S.
You can hear it create a new notes.
We'll call this my first notebook.
It entered create notes and in here we can actually type in Scurlock code.
So for instance I can say print's Ellen and I will say something like Hello world.
Now if it's your very first note book you can do shift and try to run the cell.
And it may take a little while to actually run.
Here it took one second for me.
If you're just running this note book for the very first time it's probably going to take about 30 seconds
to a minute just to connect your cluster and load up Skala.
But after that every other cell should take very little time.
The Peniel what Operation doing.
Your very first cell even if it's a simple command will probably take around 30 seconds to actually
run.
But I already ran a note book on this previously.
So I'm ready to go.
And now I'm going to just show you an example of how you would maybe access and S3 bucket.
All right.
So let me just walk through the generic settings you would probably use to connect your clusters to
some data you were hosting on Amazon Web Services S3 storage you would just say something like Sparc
or Apache that spark the sequel spark session then you would create your values spark just as we've
done before.
Sparks session it we can say builder or creates and then offer this Sparke session that we're running
right now you would actually read in from your S-3 data.
So for example let's say you have a publicly available bucket Well that makes things pretty easy you
would just say something like that all for your data frame is equal to spark read maybe you set up a
couple of options et cetera.
But at the end for instance working for CSP file you would just type in your path here S-3 your bucket.
You know your file CXXVI etc..
Now if you're using something that's privately hosted and you need a key access to it it would look
something more like this.
You would still start off with S-3 but you may need to do S-3 and colon slash slash and then your access
key colon and then your secret key atts and then you type in your bucket and whatever your file was
or you have to your files CSP.
And then once you're able to read that you'd have your data frame loaded to your cluster.
Now keep in mind every and a have to match up to your limitations so if your cluster is too small to
hold in your data it's not going to work and you're going to be charged depending on how big your data
is or how big your cluster is so keep that in mind.
If money is an issue for you you really want to keep a handle on that.
Otherwise your prices will skyrocket.
Now if you're looking for a more concrete example.
Zipline actually comes with one.
You can click here and go to Leppla tutorial and it actually has an example of reading in from S-3 you
are l not for you or I'll link you have to do a little bit of a different aspect to it.
But you have to call in New York L because you can't read it as a fill is just a direct three bucket
link.
But basically here they have loaded data into a table and you can check this out.
If you're looking for another example.
Now this uses the R D D techniques for actually reading in the data.
But it's essentially the same thing as far as connecting a cluster to S3.
And here they actually show you examples of how to use the visualizations as well.
All right.
So that's basically it as far as the basics of using the zipline notebook on your own cluster.
And as I mentioned many times already but keep in mind you will be charged for every hour that this
notebook is running.
So the most important step out of everything is to remember how to actually terminate your cluster.
So you just go back to your AWOS consul and click here on terminate.
It's going to ask you Are you sure you want to terminate this cluster.
All the data stored on this cluster is going to be lost.
You can go ahead and click terminate.
And now it's going to be terminated and you're not going to be charged for it anymore so.
Remember to do that.
And if you want to verify that it's being terminated you can visit that your Allegan and make sure nothing
pops up.
All right.
Hope you enjoyed the lecture.
Basically you have all the tools you need to analyze big data.
You can check out Amazon Web Services public data sets if you're interested in uploading and analyzing
very large data sets.
Remember the larger it gets the more you have to pay.
So keep that in mind.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.