Hello everyone.
Welcome to the project.
Exercise overview lecture for the classification section of the Course.
This lecture will briefly go over the project exercise and the questions you have to answer.
We're going to jump to the exercise script now.
OK here I am.
I've opened the log Regg project Skala.
It's under the classification folder and basically in this project what you're going to be working with
is a fake advertising dataset which indicates whether or not a particular internet user clicked on an
advertisement.
We're going to try to create a model that will predict whether or not they will click on an ad based
off the features of that user and this data set contains the following features.
It has a feature column for daily time spent on the site.
So that's the consumer time on a particular Web site in minutes.
The age of the customer in years the average income of geographical area of that customer the average
minutes a day consumer or that customer is on the internet.
Then there's an ad topic line which is this a string the headline of the actual advertisement.
The city of the consumer customer mail which just indicates whether or not the consumer was male the
country of the consumer a time stamp and then clicked on AD 0 or 1 in the kid and clicking on ad that's
basically your label there what you want to do is actually build a logistic regression model that based
off of all these features can you predict whether or not clicked on ad is a zero or one and basically
just complete the commented tasks below.
You get the data do some exploration of the data display the data set up the data frame for machine
learning.
There's some stuff you have to do.
Import vector assembler etc. do a random split.
Set up the pipeline and then evaluate the model.
OK that's basically all there is to it.
Best of luck.
If you have any questions.
Make sure to check out the solutions lecture.
Coming up next.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.