Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on maps and Skala maps allow us to have a key value pair storage.
These are sometimes known as hash tables or dictionaries.
Let's go ahead and jump to the skull interpreter to get started.
OK so here I am at the Scala interpreter and the sparks shell I'm going to create a value called my
map and I will set it equal to and will call the map keyword of capital M and basically are going to
pass in what look like key value pairs in the form of tuples.
So for instance I'm going to say A and then one.
So the key is A and then the value associate of that key is one.
And we can continue to do this so have B to and then we'll have for instance C three OK.
And here we have sculled a collection that immutable that map and we can see here we have that string
integer pairing for that key value pair.
And what's also important to note is that Scala uses this dash operator for an arrow.
So the stash and then greater than or less than sign for that arrow.
And that actually points the key value pair so later on we'll see how we can use that to actually create
additions to a dictionary or a map.
In this case.
So let's go ahead and show you how we can do things such as look ups in this map so I can say my map
an imprint sees I can passen the key.
So for instance if I want the value for the key of A.
It returns back the integer value.
So for instance passen see it returns back the integer 3.
So this sort of indexing or look up is really similar as far as print parentheses wise to looking something
up in a list but instead of passing an index or passing in a key since it's a key value pair match chain.
Now let's go ahead and show you what happens if you try to get something that is not present.
So for instance if I say my map and type and D for the key I will get the sort of error here that no
such element exception key not found the.
Now there's another method I want to show you if I go ahead and clear this for my map I can use the
get key word to pasan a key so I can say my map or my map get a returns back 1 here.
If I did the same thing my map get.
But in this case try to put in a key that does not exist.
I get back this option.
Int equals none.
So that's where the difference lies between doing something like my map of a versus my amap gets a notice
in one we get back the integer that original parentheses notation we get back.
The integer that actual value when we use that keyword we get that option ints and then it's inside
this object called sum.
And we get that one.
The difference here being if I actually call my map for a key that doesn't exist for instance capital
D I get back this exception.
But if I use get instead.
So I say my map get the I get this option equal to none so I basically get an empty value there.
So that's an important distinction to know.
We don't really use it that much during the course but you should be aware of it.
All right.
Now let's go ahead and show you how to do mutable maps in order to add new key value pairs to a map.
So I'm going to go ahead and clear that console and I will say Velle my map is equal to.
And just like we did earlier for other collection objects we can say collection mutable dot map.
And then I can go ahead and pass in some key value pairs.
Let's go in and say X to 1 and then we'll say y to.
And then we'll say Z three and there we have a mutable map collection.
And again no this arrow notation here because we're going to use that in order to actually add in elements
to this map so have Z to 3 y to 2 and then X to 1.
And like I noted before the map doesn't actually retain any order it's just a hash table.
So let's go ahead and show you how you can add to a map a new key value pair.
You'll say my mutes map say plus equals and then say you're Nuki or whatever you want it to be comma.
Actually not a comma you'll say this arrow symbol nine nine nine or whatever value you want.
And this will be permanently added to your mutable map.
So that's why that arrow is so important to realize because if we try to do this using what I was actually
accidentally starting to do that comma so if I say brand new comma 12 you'll actually get an error.
You'll get a type mismatch.
So you need to do is instead replace that comma with that assignment operator for that arrow and then
it will be added in so we can say Miamians map and we can see we have those brand new keys in there.
OK.
Let me go ahead and shoot just a few useful methods such as grabbing the keys and values off a map.
So if we go in and clear this I say my map that was the original map of ABC 1 2 3 I can say my map key
is to get the keys of a map as a set and I can say my map values.
So you get this sort of map like object that has the actual values themselves.
In this case they're just integers and these are iterable meaning later only learn about four loops
I can actually iterate through the Keys or the values they should note that they won't actually retain
any sort of order.
OK that's it for the lecture on maps again maps basically just have a key value pair storage and they're
also known as hash tables or dictionaries and other languages and you have an immutable version and
the mutable version the mutable version.
You're going to add a new pair of values to it using that plus arrow notation.
So again one more time for a minute map and say plus equals and then the new key.
So we can say new one.
And then you're going to put the arrow notation and then you're going to put in some new value for instance
one two three.
And there we have it Miami map.
We'll go and see my map keys and we can say z y x brand new and Yuuki and new one.
All right.
Hope you enjoy that lecture.
I'll see you at the next one.