Hello everyone and welcome to the solutions lecture for the skull a basic assessment test questions.
Now there were just a few questions.
They were all pretty straightforward.
Well let's go ahead and jump to the spark shell actually answer those questions.
All right.
Here I am I've already started a spark shell and I'm at the scal interpreter.
Our first question is what is to to the power of five.
So hopefully you remember from the arithmetic and numbers lecture that you can just use math that p
o w for power and then just type in 2 and 5 in the return back 32 which is to the power of 5 OK the
next question was What does the remainder of 180.
Divided by 7 Pothier remember that when we were covering booleans in comparison operators I mentioned
the Maatta operator which is that percent sign operation.
In that case you can just say 180 Mada 7 and you get that the remainder is 5.
OK let's go ahead.
Move onto the next question.
All right.
That next question was given the variable underscore name is equal to Samie.
You string interpellation to print out my dog's name is Samie.
So let's go ahead and create that variable Larpent underscore name is equal to Sammy.
So we get that string variable and then we can just use that notation quo.
And then we can type in my dog's name is and then a dollar sign.
And then our variable name in this case it's pet name OK.
And you could have also used value there or Val if you wanted to.
Let's go ahead and move onto the next question.
All right that next question was to use golf to find out if the letter sequence x y z is contained in
this long string.
So sad.
Whatever.
And you'll notice that X Y Z is actually there.
Now let me go ahead and show you how we can do that.
And then to create a value called us and said equal to that long string just go ahead and copy and paste
it in there enter and then we'll go ahead and say S contains X Y Z and check if it's true or not.
And in this case it is true.
So it wanted you to figure out.
Here is to remember that contains keyword from the strings and regular expressions lecture.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next question.
All right.
Next question was What is the difference between a value and a variable.
So remember that a value is an immutable storage unit meaning you can assign it data when you're defining
it but you can't reassign that data to it and a variable is a mutable storage unit meaning data can
be assigned not only at definition but it can be reassigned later on.
Let me go on to show you a quick example or say Valot A is equal to two.
Ill make a variable.
Be equal to three.
So if I go ahead and take my value and try to reassign it so we'll say actually a let's going to try
to reassign it to a string.
Hello.
Well we know that's not going to work because we can't reassign it to different data type.
But we also can't reassign it to even the same data type in integer because it'll always report back
that you're trying to reassign a value which is not possible.
However for the variable in this case it was B.
We try to reassign it to a string.
We'll go ahead and receive an error type mismatch but we can reassign it to the same data type.
In this case it was an integer.
So if we say physical 1 to 3 now B has been reassigned since it's a variable.
And that's really the main difference.
Remember a value can't be reassigned.
A variable can be.
All right let's go ahead and move on to the last question.
That last question was a little tricky because I didn't exactly show you how to do something as far
as indexing from a nested tuple.
And it was given the tuple one two three and a nested tuple inside of four five six retrieved the number
six.
So hopefully you remembered that you can use the dot underscore notation to actually retrieve numbers
or objects from a tuple.
Let me go in and show you what I mean by that.
I'll say a vowel of T is equal to this tuple.
So you want to come up three and then we'll have that nested tuple inside of four five six.
And here we have the integers.
Now remember we want to grab 6 but it's actually nested inside another tuple in that tuple is that element
for cause tuples indexing starts at 1.
So say t underscore.
For now we can see there that we actually have that tuple.
So there's various ways you can do this.
You can actually re-assign see the underscore for to another value and do the indexing again.
Or you can actually just stack the index so you can say t underscore for the underscore three since
it's at the third position there and then you get the integer 6.
The other way you could have done this is just split this up into two steps by re-assigning Teeka underscore
four to another value such as it's going savey.
Well go ahead and say nest is equal to t the underscore four.
And now if I call nest I have that so I can say nest underscore three.
And that's the same thing.
So it's up to you how you want to do it.
I didn't specifically say that you can stack those index operations on top of each other.
So kudos to you if you're able to figure that out on your own.
All right.
Hopefully those six questions weren't very hard.
Should have been pretty straightforward given what we've covered is just the basics for now.
OK.
Coming up next in the next section we're going to discuss collections such as arrays and maps and sets
to see how we can work with data.
We want to store in some sort of sequence.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next section of the course.