Hello and welcome back to the course of machine learning.
Previously we talked about the support vector machine algorithm and we are going to talk about the kernel
support vector machine algorithm and the intuition behind it.
So as you recall in the support vector machine situation we had a set of observations which belong to
different classes and the point was to find this decision boundary between them so that any future observations
could be identified which Clauss they fall into.
And in this case we can see that there a decision boundary and the support vector machine algorithm
tells us exactly how to find that boundary.
But what happens when we cannot find a boundary.
What happens in a situation like this for example what do we do here we can't just draw a line through
these points right we can just separate them with a straight line.
We can separate them of a horizontal line concept broom with a vertical line whatever we try to do.
We cannot separate these points in the same way that the support vector machine algorithm told us to.
And so what happens in this situation.
And why does it happen.
Well this happens because in this case the data is not linearly set separable.
So here we've got the two example side by side on the left the linearity separable data and on the right
the nonlinear separable data.
And what's the support vector machine algorithm does is it helps us find that decision boundary or correctly
place that decision boundary.
But it does have an assumption.
The assumption is that the data is the new is separable So basically saying that it is possible to place
the decision boundary so the port vector machine algorithm helps us choose the optimal decision boundary
or the multiple decision boundaries or we can draw whereas in that non linear separable case we can't
even draw one single decision boundary or linear decision boundary so therefore the support vector machine
algorithm just won't work by definition.
And so what are we going to do.
Well this is what this section is about.
This section is about coming up with an algorithm that will help us deal with situations like that where
we have to extract this class when it is surrounded or in other situations where we can just simply
just draw a line.
And the way this section is structured or the intuition tutorials of the section is first of all we're
going to explore a method we just called Going to a higher dimensional space where we will learn how
we can take this dataset and add an extra dimension into our space that we're dealing with and make
our data a linearly separable So we'll have to look at a couple of those examples and then we will discuss
the kernel trick which allows us to do these things in a more can be patiently efficient way without
having to deal with multiple or higher dimensions.
And finally we will talk about the different types of kernels that exist.
So quite an interesting section ahead and I can't wait to see the next tutorial.
Until then happy analyzing