Hello and welcome back to the course on machine learning.
Today we're talking about the multi armed bandit problem.
Don't you just love these names and they come up such cool names for machine learning algorithms and
problems.
Well today we're indeed talking about this problem and it is the example that we're going to be using
in this whole section on reinforcement learning.
We're going to be looking at different ways that we can solve the multi armed bandit problem and comparing
the results.
But before we can do you I just wanted to mention that the Malte armband The problem is not the only
problem that can be solved with reinforcement learning reinforcement learning is actually really really
cool reinforcement learning for instance is used to train robot dogs to walk.
And I'll give you a quick example for instance you can once you've created a robot dog you can implement
an algorithm inside the robot dog which will tell it how to walk you can tell it.
All right.
Move your front right foot and then move your left back foot and then Front Left foot right back foot
and so on you can actually give the sequence of actions that it needs to take in order to accomplish
a task which is walking.
Or you can implement arean Forsman learning algorithm which will train the dog to walk in a very very
interesting way.
So basically what it will do is they'll say hey dog here are all the actions you can take.
You can move your legs like this you can move your legs like that.
And your goal is to make a step forward.
Every time you make a step forward you are given a reward every time you fall over you're given a punishment
and a reward is basically a one in the arm you don't actually have to give it a carrot or you know something
to eat.
You just give it a 1 in algorithm and a punishment is zero.
And basically every time he takes a step forward it knows it's got a reward and it will just that's
good for it.
So basically you will try all these random sets of actions and see what they lead to every time it takes
a step forward.
Remember that those were good actions and will try to repeat them more and more and actually dogs like
that can learn to walk.
So you don't have to program an actual walking algorithm into it Ill figure out the steps it needs to
take on its own.
I think that's really mind blowing and really cool but unfortunately that is a more a topic more of
on the side of artificial intelligence rather than just machine learning.
And that is you know there can be a whole course on its own.
We're not going to delve into the training robot dogs to walk inside this section inside this section.
We are going to talk about the multi armed bandit problem which is a bit of a different application
of this machine learning branch of reinforcement learning.
And plus of course there's other lots of other applications of reinforcement learning as well.
So moving on to our multi armed bandit problem.
So first of all what on earth is a multi armed bandit right.
So the first thing that comes to mind is like a robber going into a bank and so on and or somebody for
gun but actually a bandit or a one armed band the sort of thing let's simplify things.
A one armed bandit is a slot machine.
Right.
It's one of these.
And why is it called the warm one arm bandit.
Well has got a bit of a history there.
Back in the day they used to have this handle on the right and you could still see their movies and
maybe some places you can still find these slot machines where you actually have to pull the handle
because now they're all electronic and you just press a button right there push push push slot machines.
Whereas back in there you had to pull the lever to make it work to like initiate the game.
And so hence the arm.
But why is it called the bandit.
Well because these machines they would actually you know these are this is one of the quickest way to
lose your money in a casino.
They would take.
I think it was like a 50 percent chance that they would take away your money back in the day so they
would of course you earn less than your.
You're actually winning.
And it was about you know a 50/50 chance whether or not you actually make a or you get a win or you
lose money but then they put a bug into them.
They could read up a little bit on line they put a bug into them that people who were playing them were
losing even faster than were even more frequent than 50 percent.
So hence the name bandit because it was basically robbing you of your money.
And you know one of the quickest way to ways to lose your money hands them all to oh that's what's called
the one armed bandit.
And what does the multi-hour bandit.
Well the a multi armed bandit problem is kind of the challenge that a person is faced when he comes
up to a whole set of these machines when he doesn't have just one has like five or ten hour programming
examples will have an example of 10 but we won't be talking specifically about these machines of course
this is this is the historic problem you'll see just now we'll see that there are many many other applications
that even though it's called the multi are problem it's actually used to solve many other problems as
well.
So basically here you're faced with challenge you've got five of these machines right.
And how do you actually play them to maximize your return from the number of games that you can actually
play.
So you've you know you decided you're going to play you know a hundred times or a thousand times and
you want to maximize return.
How do you figure out which ones of them to play in order to maximize your returns.
Well the problem to describe the problem in more detail we've got to mention that's the assumption here
is that each one of these machines has a distribution behind it so there's a distribution of numbers
out of which or outcomes out of which the machine picks results right.
So it has it has like H1-Bs machines has its own distribution and it picks out a result.
You could you pull the trigger and it just picks out randomly out of its distribution result an outcome
you know whether they win or whether you lose and how much you win.
How much use or could you lose the same money you just put in the coin.
But basically it tells you whether you win or lose based on the distribution that's built into the machine.
But the problem here is that you don't know these distribution right.
You don't know in advance what the distributions are and they are assumed to be different for these
machines.
Sometimes it can be similar or the same in some of the machines but by by default they are different
and your goal is to figure out which of these distributions is the best one for you so let's have a
look.
So there are these this should be sions right.
So for example we've got these five machines the five distributions and as you can see right away just
by looking at this which is the best machine right away.
Obviously the one on the right.
The orange one is the best machine because it's got the best.
You know it's the most left skewed left cues because the tails on the left.
So it's got the most favorable outcomes.
Got the highest mean median and mode.
And you if you knew these distributions and was you would obviously just go to the fifth machine and
you would bet on the machine with machine just on the machine all the time because it's got the best
distribution right.
So on average you would get the best results but you don't know that you don't know that in advance.
And your goal is to figure out you know this is like a it's like a mind game.
You know there's all these movies about machine learning and really cool all the cool mathematics on
how they're using they're cool.
Really good movie was imitation game right about Alan Turing and the and how he was solving the enigma
and so on but a similar kind of concept you don't know which one of these is the best you're going to
figure it out.
But at the same time you are already spending your money doing this right.
You can just you know the longer you take to figure it out there's a tradeoff right.
The longer you take to figure it out the more money you'll probably spend on the wrong ones.
And therefore you have to figure out very quickly.
So there are these two factors that are in play exploration and exploitation.
So you need to explore the machines to find out which one of them is the best one.
And at the same time you need to as soon as you can already start exploiting exploiting these machines
exploiting your findings to make the maximum return.
So basically and there's another methodical con. We finally had all this which is called regret and
regret is it is mathematically defined.
And if you can read more about this is a goal is a really good white paper on it.
It's called using confidence bounds for exploitation and exploration of tradeoffs.
And it is by Pyrrha a lawyer or a PR from Graz University of Technology in Austria really like the white
paper it goes into a lot of detail like I didn't read the whole thing but the first couple of chapters
are pretty good.
If you want to go into detail but basically regret is is when it suffered when you're using an non alternative
not optimal method.
Right.
So the one on the right is the optimal or the one underwrites the optimal machine whenever using the
non-option machine you have a regret which which can be quantified as like as the difference between
the best outcome and the best outcome and you know all of those sums of the money that you put like
your opportunity cost of actually exploring other machines.
And so the longer you explore other non-optimal machines the higher regret.
But at the same time if you don't explore for long enough right.
If you explore if you don't explore for long or long enough then your and a suboptimal machine might
or might appear as an optimal machine.
So for instance this machine or here writes If we explore explore explore but we don't spend enough
time exploring we might think that this is the best machine because it's got quite a good return right
close to this one and we might start exploiting this one for the rest of the time.
But in reality this one was the best one.
So the goal is to find the best one and exploit the best one but spend the least amount of time exploring
all of them.
And while you're exploring you're still earning money but not from the opposite machine right.
So that's the goal.
That's the point of this whole exercise and it's important to understand here that there is the best
one.
So that is where even though these machines you know they have like jackpots sometimes and so on.
But we are assuming that there's just that.
These distributions are finite there and out of them.
There is a best one that you are looking for that's kind of the emphasis or the whole assumption on
this problem if there are more complex options and versions of this problem.
And again check out some additional reading on that topic.
That's that's more even more advanced.
But what we're going to be using this for is that's going to be sufficient.
And why is it going to be sufficient for us.
Because the most common modern application of this that we can think of is the one that we're going
to be exploring is advertising voila.
So let's have a look at some ads going to be fun.
So just a disclaimer this there is no affiliation with Coca-Cola examples are used just for educational
purposes.
All right.
So let's have a look.
We have let's say Coca-Cola or some company wants to run a campaign and it's going to be called Welcome
to the Coke Side of Life campaign.
And if you search this campaign online you'll see that they had you know hundreds of different ads that
they came up with for this campaign.
And here's here's one example them.
These are just some images I pulled from Google so maybe these are even drawn by people but we're going
to assume that these are legitimate ads that we're going to go into the campaign as well we want to
find out which is the best ad which is the ad that it works.
So we've got options.
Number one.
Number two three and before and number five.
And so now our goal is to find out which ad works to maximize our returns.
But right now we don't know which has worked the best right.
So there's no there is a distribution behind it but that distribution will only become known after thousands
and thousands and thousands of people.
Look at these ads and click or not click on these ads and this is actually going to be very similar
to the example that we're going to be looking at.
The example that had LUNs going to be walking you through in the programming tutorials in that example
actually going have 10 ads.
So even more.
And so what can you do here.
Well one way to approach a problem is just run an AB test drive.
So take your five or 50 or 500 ads and run a huge AB test with multiple AB test and wait until you have
enough of a large enough sample and then conclude which is the best right with certain confidence.
But the problem of that is that you would spend a lot of time and money doing that right.
So an AB test is pure exploration right.
You're not exploiting the best option you are exploiting the best option but to the same extent as you're
exploiting the non optimal options right.
So if if we go by our previous distributions if this is the best one if you just want an AB test then
your uniformly distributing or you uniformly using these 5 options and therefore as much as using this
one you're using all four.
All four of them so basically all five of them.
So basically you are exploiting it a bit but on unconsciously you arrive in a random way and therefore
AB tests are just for exploration.
So the challenge is to find out which is the best one but do it while you're exploring.
While you're not to exploit the best one while you're exploring for it dries so find out which of them
is the best one in the process of.
Hold on fire.
Find out which is the best one in the process of the actual launch campaign.
So not don't have two phases.
You do the AB test and then use them most.
The best one but actually find out the best one in the quickest way possible and start exploiting it
along the way.
So that's the challenge here and that's what we're going to be solving.
And that's the modern application of the multi armed bandit problem.
So hopefully you're excited about this.
We've got two great algorithms coming up.
Can't wait to get started.
I look for in the next tutorial.
And until then enjoy machine learning.