Hello and welcome to this art tutorial.
So in the previous tutorial we predicted our test results and now and just to tell you all we are going
to evaluate those predictions by making the confusion matrix which will count the number of correct
predictions and the number of incorrect predictions.
So let's do it let's make the matrix.
It's very simple.
It will just take us one line.
So let's call it C M equals.
Then very practically We're going to use the table function in R and in the table I will first input
the real values which are the test set brackets and then I have to select the columns of the real results
which is if we go to the test set this column because this column contains the real results whether
the use bought yes or no.
The SUV and this column has an x 3.
So here I will put come up and three.
All right so that's my first argument that's the real values.
And then as a second argument I'm going to input the predicted values which is of course the widespread
vector here.
So here I'm going to add y pred and I don't have to select an index because white bread is already the
vector of predictions.
So in short this is the vector of real values for all the observations.
And this is the vector of predictions for the same observations as in this vector.
OK and that's it.
The confusion matrix is ready.
So now let's select this line and execute.
Here is table created.
Now let's go to the console and have a look at it.
CM.
And here it is the most important thing to understand here is that the 57 and the 26 Here are the correct
predictions and the 10 and the seven Here are the incorrect predictions.
So what's interesting here at first sight is that the classifier made 57 plus 26 equals 83 correct predictions
and 10 plus seven equals 17.
Incorrect predictions.
All right so 17 incorrect predictions on the test set.
That's not bad but we can do better and we will do better with other classifiers.
You'll see that in the next sections.
OK so we're done with the confusion matrix.
And finally now it's time for the best part.
Because in the next tutorial we will be graphically looking at our results because we will plot this
very cool chart that will allow us to make an awesome interpretation of the results.
So I look forward to seeing you in the next tutorial where we will make this chart.
Until then enjoy mission learning