Hello and welcome to this art tutorial.
So let's pick up where we left off that is let's try to figure out why we're using this upper bound
sequel to this very large number 10 of the power of 400 given to this upper bound variable here in this
Elle's condition.
Well let's see what happens.
You know let's see what happens at First Round.
One of the first round we will go through the 10 versions of the add things to this for I loop here.
And since the first round no ADD was selected.
Well this condition here if numbers of selections I is higher than zero will never be true and therefore
we will directly go to this else here.
And accordingly the upper bound will be set equal to 10 at the power of 400.
Then we move on to this condition because this is the next step of this fault here.
And it says that if upper bound is larger than max rebounds which is true of course because of about
10 of the power of 400 and Maxo we're going to zero.
So this condition is true.
So what happens next is that Max supervillian is equal to upper bound.
So Max pre-ban will be equal to 10 at the power of 400 and add equals.
And so since we're at the beginning of the fold here I equals 1.
So I will be equal to 1.
And then what happens then we go to the next step of this for I loop here which is I equals 2 and I
do response to the second ad and the second ad hasn't been selected yet.
So numbers of selections I hear will not be larger than zero.
So this condition will not be true here.
So again we will get to this out here.
And therefore Appelbaum will be equal to at the power of 400.
And then we go to this if here.
So now let's see if this condition is true upper bound is equal to 10 at the power of 400.
And remember from the previous round Max upper bound was said equal to 10 at the power of 400 because
it was said equal to upper bound.
So this condition translated in real terms as if 10 of the power of 400 is larger than 10 at the power
of 400.
And that is not true.
Ten the power of 400 is not larger than 10 of the power 400.
So that condition is not true and therefore add is not set equal to 2 because right now equals two.
But it remains equal to 1.
And that's why at the first round the ad that will be selected is at equals 1.
That is the first that you can try with the other values.
I hear a pre-ban will always be equal to 10 or the power 400 and Max upper bound will stay equal to
10 of the power 400.
So therefore this condition will never be verified for the nine remaining here.
And therefore we keep this at equals 1 and that's the same principle for the next rounds up to 10 that's
round and he goes to this number of selections I hear will be larger than zero only for the first and
because the first ad was selected at Round 1 and therefore this condition will be true only for the
first.
So upper bound will be equal to this average reward plus delta I hear.
But then we'll move on to I plus one which will correspond to adversion 2.
And since adversion 2 wasn't selected yet well this numbers of selection's I hear will be equal to zero
and therefore this condition won't be verified and therefore we will go to this.
Else here an upper bound will be equal to 10 at the power of 400.
We will forget this upper bound value here computed at the previous eye here.
And therefore what happens next is the same upper Belang will be larger than maksud rebound because
Macs are preven was equal to the upper bound at the previous AI and the upper bound of the previous
I was average reward Plus Delta II which is of course lower than the standard the power of 400.
And that's why by the way we said it to a very large value it's in order to have this upper bound here
lower than the center the power of 400 and therefore Maxo preven will be 10 at the power 400 and we
will select as equals.
That is at number two and then same principle as before when we'll move on to the next eyes upper bound
will be equal to 10 or the power of 400 Max or pre-ban will also be equal to 10 of the power of 400.
So this condition won't be verified and therefore we'll keep at number two.
So that's why this nice little trick here works perfectly well for us and gives us exactly what we want.
All right so the 10 first round selected 10 adds and then after around 10 we used the strategy to select
the adds.
All right so now the only thing that we need to do is to append the selected at here and this selected
vector here.
And that's exactly what we'll do now.
So let's do it.
We just need to get out of the for loop because we're done with this loop.
We did exactly what we had to do that is to select the right add.
And now we need to get out of this for a loop but remain in this for loop because we are still at a
specific route.
And and what we have to do now is a band the ad that was selected here to this huge vector and selected
that contains all the different ad selected at each round.
OK.
So now things are easy.
We just need to use the append function on these ads selected huge vector and then a pen.
Here it is.
All right.
And now in this append function we enter as input first input selected and second input add because
it corresponds to the index of the ad that was selected in this for loop here.
All right so done at appended.
And now since we've just selected and you add here what we need to do is to update this vector number
of selections here.
That is you know the vector telling for each add the number of times it was selected.
So since here we know which index of the albums just selected what we need to do is to add a plus one.
In this particular index of these numbers of selections vector to update this vector.
So let's do it right now.
We will stay of course in this for end loop because this vector will contain the numbers of times each
add was selected at this specific run.
And so we need to stay in the loop and we will simply take this vector here.
Copy and pasted here to update it.
And so what we need to date is the ADD index of this numbers of selection's vector because this add
index corresponds to the index of the ad that was just elected here a selection that's based on all
the strategy.
And so what we simply need to do is increment by one this vector here.
So we will copy that again.
Copy equals paste.
And then a little plus one here.
All right.
So now this numbers of selections vector is well updated.
And that's all we need to do for this vector at this specific round because of course only one ad was
selected.
OK and now we need to take care of the rewards because indeed we have this sums of rewards vector here
that we need to update because this vector contains the different sums of rewards of each of the 10
adds at each round.
So we need to update it.
And of course afterwards we would like to get the total we wanted that unit will be a variable containing
the unique sum of rewards we accumulated over the end rounds.
So let's first take care of this.
Some of you want to here and then we'll take care of total we want.
So today some of the words factor here.
What we need to get now is the reward we get at this specific round.
And because you know we just selected this ad here but we haven't got it's we yet.
We just selected the ad so for now we need to get the reward.
So in real life what happens is that you know we showed the ad to the user and then the user clicks
yes or no on the AD.
But here we are not in real life as much as I would have loved to show you a real experiment of this.
Right now in front of your eyes this would not be that simple.
But we have this simulation data set you know this data set here that you know contains the real results
only known by God you know because we have no idea of which add each user would click on.
So as a reminder the first user clicks on one at five and at nine not the rest of them.
So that's just a simulation data set.
And so what we have to do now is get the reward at each round and based on the ad that were selected.
Thanks to this dataset.
So let's do it which will simply do is get the word that is either 1 or 0 at this specific round and
where we are at.
And so to get this it's really simple which we need to do is you know take our data set and in the brackets
will need to specify the index of the line where we are at.
Which is you know the round and corresponding to the round where we are right now.
So since all the lines of this dataset here are nothing else but the rounds.
Well the first index will be the round.
So for example let's say we are at Round 9.
Well we will need to take the line index 9 of the dataset and then for the columns since the columns
here correspond to the rewards of the 10 different ads.
Well we will need to take the index of the ads that were selected that is nothing else and this add
index here so that's the idea that what we have to do.
But of course in real life you'll get what really happens with the users.
So I'm going to close this and right now I'm going to get the real reward at round.
And that's we get with the selection of this ad index here.
So let's do it.
We will call this real reward simply reward.
All right.
And now as I just explained we need to take the data set and then the brackets and we need to take the
index of the line that corresponds to around.
And so and here and then we need to take the index of the column that corresponds to the index of the
ad that was just selected.
So it's out here and that's all.
We simply get the reward at around.
And for this specific selection of this ad by using this.
OK.
So great.
We've just got the real reward and now we can update this sums up reward vector here that as a reminder
gives the sons of rewards of each of the 10 ads at each end.
So we will take this copy and then just below we will increment this vector.
And of course we need to take the added index of this vector because only the ADD that was selected
at this specific round.
And we'll have it some of the words changed.
So that's the only some of words we need to update and therefore what we need to do is to incremented
by the we Word not by one of course only by the reward because the reward is either 0 or 1.
So equals here and then we take that again and then plus reward.
So if we go to zero reward the sum of rewards for this specific add won't change and we were equals
one.
This some of the worst for this specific ad will be incremented by 1.
OK.
And now we just have to do one last thing.
It's of course to get the total reward accumulated over the end rounds.
Well the total reward is not very interesting for us at any round end but at the last round.
And that is that the 10000 is around because we're all compared of course to the total we we got with
this random selection algorithm which as a reminder was 1200 on average.
So that's why we're very excited to find out about this total we work.
But at the end of the ten thousand rounds so of course we need to initialize this total reward very
Because you know we are updating it at each round.
So we need to give its initial value like in physics and this initial value will give of course zero
because at around zero at the beginning of this experiment the total reward is of course zero.
We haven't actually related any reward yet.
So let's declare this new variable total reward right here and then set it equal to zero and now very
simply what we need to do is to compute the total reward that we accumulate at a trout.
And there is something we need to do another increment the same as the one we just did.
So I'm copying all word here pasting in here and equal and then pasted again and adding a plus and then
according to you what do we need to add.
Of course we need to add the word that we get at each round and.
And that's done the UCB algorithm is implemented.
Congratulations.
This is the first algorithm we implement from scratch in this course.
That's very exciting.
And as you notice we built and implemented this algorithm as if we would do it in real life.
No we didn't.
Adeline's one by one we implemented it as a developer we do it step by step you know with the same logical
thinking process.
So congratulations.
Now I'm so excited to look at the results and find out by how much they use the algorithm will beat
the random selection algorithm.
So as a reminder the random selection algorithm gave us a reward of 1200.
Let's see how you beat that.
And let's hope we get a nice result.
So I'm going to select everything from here to here.
All right.
And there we go.
Here it is.
Let's immediately have a look at the total reward.
We can see that the total reward is two thousand one hundred seventy eight.
We almost doubled the whole word earned by the random selection algorithm.
So that's great you know if you are Zino and if the ads are not ads but you know slot machines that
means that you will earn twice as much money and that's not all because this is just the total word
of the experiment.
But what's very interesting to see now is the specific ad that has the highest conversion rates you
know simply what is the best ad to show to the users and how can we find out about this.
Well what we simply need to look at is this as a selected vector here.
So let's have a look first what we can see is that as expected you know as the expected result of our
implementation here will we can see that during the first round the tent ads are selected you know round
one we select and one round to add to round 3 at 3 up to around 10 at 10.
So that's exactly the result of what we did here with this huge value trick to get this 10 ads of the
10 first rounds.
And then the strategy starts.
You know since we get some information based on the selections of these 10 ads here during the 10 first
round then we get the sums of rewards and food and the numbers of selection's info and that's when the
strategy can start.
And that's exactly what happens here from here the strategy is running and different selections appear.
And what's really interesting to see now is to look at the last round.
There is you know the rounds close to 10000 because if the strategy works well logically this algorithm
should select always the same ad during the last rounds because you know there is one ad that is the
best that has the highest conversion rate.
You know maybe it's the ad where the car is on a beautiful bridge.
So there is this winner ad that we don't know of course but that's what this ad selects vector will
tell us.
If we look at the last round so let's do it.
We will go down and down and down.
OK.
Here we go.
So as you can see as I'm going down it appears that there are more and more five different ones as you
can see there are more and more five that we're selecting and a drought.
And if I go down again and go down more and more well we get even more 5 and that their last rounds
that is during the last thousand rounds.
Well we select only five as you can see right now we are at around nine thousand eight hundred and we
can only observe five.
So clearly the best.
And we should pick to show to the use and that has the highest conversion rate is number five.
So great.
Not only would almost double the total we would with this two thousand one hundred seventy eight total
reward but also we get to know what is the best ad to show to the users.
And of course we're interested in both.
We're interested in knowing what's the best.
But also to optimize this told we were here because you know experimenting this placement of these ads
on the social network costs money.
And you know I said at the beginning we have a limited budget and that's generally the case for departments
of marketing or any business.
We have a limited budget so we need to optimize this all we want here to compensate the costs and hopefully
already earn some money.
So these two results are very important.
And so thank you very much to this UCB algorithm.
And now as usual as promised we will finish this UCAP algorithm section was the last step.
The exciting step about visualizing the results and simply what we will do is plot a histogram showing
for each add the number of times it was selected.
So we'll do that in the next tutorial and until then enjoy machine learning.