Hello and welcome to this art tutorial and the tutorial was a lot of interesting things to learn about
our and what it can do to provide insightful information of your model.
And now we only have to do left is to predict the test results ask for a simple in their aggression
.
It will be very quick.
We will just need one line for this and it's going to be why I'm introducing the vector of predictions
here why pred and then I'm going to use to predict function and then to predict function I will just
use two arguments.
One is to regress or you have to specify with which regressors you want to predict your test results
.
And of course it's with our multiple in our regression regress or that we define here.
And the second argument is new data which is the set of the new observations.
You want to predict the result you want to predict a profit and so of course this new data is going
to be the test set.
Don't worry.
So far we're only making predictions about the test set.
You will see that in the next sections we'll be making predictions of new observations which won't be
the tested observations but some single observations you will understand why we will do this and you'll
see that the purpose of doing that is actually going to be pretty fun.
So okay so that's ready to predict function is ready it has it's two argument to regress.
And the new data.
So we're ready to select this and execute.
All right.
And now our White predator vector predicted results of the test set is ready.
So what I'm going to do now is to type Y parade in the console to have a look at it.
Here it is.
So as you can see this contains ten predicted results.
These are the 10 predicted profits of the ten observations of the test set.
So for example let's compare the real profits and the predicted profits so let's look at our test set
here.
OK so let's look at our startups.
Let's get started on them of course and started them before has a hundred and eighty two thousand dollar
profit.
And what about the prediction.
A hundred and seventy is $3000 profit.
So that's the predicted profit which is not far from the real profits.
That's pretty good.
OK what about the second one.
One hundred and sixty six thousand for the real profit and a hundred and seventy two thousand for the
predicted profit.
Not too bad either then third observation.
A hundred and fifty five.
160.
Good.
146 135.
Not too bad then.
Ok then for example let's look at the start number 24.
Number 24 had a real profit of $180000 and our predicted profit is a hundred and ten thousand dollars
here we're pretty close.
That's an accurate prediction a good one.
OK.
And oh that's even better for the last two ones because here it's 99000 here it's almost ninety nine
thousand and ninety seven here for the last one and almost 97.
So that's pretty good.
That's a good model and remember that's the model with all the independent variables.
But as we saw there is only truly significant viable which was the R&D spend.
And so if we try to reconsider regressors by only putting the R&D spend in the pen and variable here
you will see that the predictions are going to be the same with the same accuracy because the R&D spend
is the only strong predictor of the profit.
So you can try that yourself it can be a good practice.
You can play around with the different independent variables.
So I will let you do it yourself and continue to analyze interpret and play around with the multiple
regression.
That's the end of this tutorial.
I was very happy to teach you how to make a multiple in their regression model.
I look forward to see you in the next section when we'll be talking about a new kind of regressors because
this time you're going to see that it's not a linear regress or it's going to be a polynomial regress
or.
And I can't wait to show you how it can give powerful predictions and we are going to use it on a very
funny example.
So there will be quite a challenge here.
And just to give you a teasing of what we are going to do we are going to make kind of a line detector
so I look forward to seeing you in the next section.
And until then enjoy machine learning