Multiple linear regression the same thing but many variables so bizzarro one constant and then many
combinations or many pairs of B and X and it can go up to quite a lot depends on how many regressors
you have here.
Once again you've got a dependent variable y.
So something you're explaining but this time the difference is that you think there might be a few causation
so.
So in the case of salary for instance it could be how much years of experience you've done how many
other courses you've done how much you know how much time you spend at work or things like that or how
valuable how much money you make for the company in terms of a student and his grades if you depend
variable.
What grade does a student get then in the independent variables could be how much the student has studied
for the exam maybe how much he has slept before the exam how many lectures he has attended throughout
the course and the things like that.
The constant is still there.
And also you've got the officials