Hello and welcome to the art of Tauriel.
So we just trained our artificial neural network on the training set and now time to make the predictions
on the test set.
So lucky for us we already have everything ready here.
Thanks to our classification templates that we pasted in the first tutorial.
So actually this section predicts the tests that result.
And this section makes the confusion matrix thanks to which we will obtain the accuracy on the test
set.
That is some accuracy on new observations on which artificial neural network model wasn't trained.
So first let's take care of this section and let's see what we need to change.
So first of all this first line gets the predicted probabilities thanks to this predict function but
that's was the product function used for built in our packages.
But here since we are using the H2 package that is kind of special There are actually some things that
we need to change here but a very few things.
So first ask for all the functions we used with this age to a package.
Will you notice that when we use a function we first take the H2 package then a dot and then the name
of the function.
Well we need to do the same here for the predictive function.
So here we just need to add h to o dot products.
OK.
So that's the first thing we need to change.
And then let's see let's go inside the function.
So the first argument is classifier.
Let's press here and one to get some information about the Predict function of the H2 model.
So let's go down to have a look at the arguments and let's see what they are.
So as we can see we have only two main arguments and then some additional arguments but that we will
not focus on.
Instead we will focus on the two main arguments here which are the object and new data.
So the first thing we can see is that there is no type argument so here simply we will remove this type
because response argument and input because we actually don't need it.
All right.
And now we are left with the two arguments we are required to input.
That is the object which is our classifier here that is the ancient model itself that we have just built
on the training set and then the second argument new data and this new data argument is expecting of
course the observations of which it has to make the predictions.
All right so that's exactly our test set.
And here we remove the dependent variable called him.
Thanks to this minus three here.
But we need to replace this three because this number three here corresponds to the index of the dependent
variable of the dataset that we worked with in part 3 classification.
And of course the index of our dependent variable is not 3 but is 11.
Remember we already replaced the index three here in this feature in part so we replaced the 4 indexes
three that were here by 11.
And so here we need to do the same.
We will replace this three index here by index 11.
All right so now this is taking the tested observations as new data that it will predict the probabilities
that the dependent viable exited equals one for the observations in the test and therefore it will predict
for each customer in the test set the probability that this customer leaves the bank.
And since we have the real results of whether the customers of the test set left or stayed in the bank
Well we will compare our predictions to these real results.
These actual results and that's how we'll get the accuracy by computing the number of correct predictions
divided by the total number of observations in the test set that is 2000.
And then if we get a good accuracy then maybe we'll get a good and powerful model and if that's the
case we will give it to the bank on the plate and tell the bank.
OK now you can rent all your customers all the customers in the bank by their probability to leave the
bank.
That is for each of your customers.
You can predict with a good accuracy and we'll be able to tell them precisely what the accuracy is.
You'll be able to predict with a good accuracy the probability that the customer leaves the bank and
then you can add therefore I can give you a ranking of all your customers ranked by their probability
to leave the bank from the highest probability to the lowest probability and therefore you can do some
customer segmentation and consider for example the top 10 percent probability that the customers leave
the bank.
And in this segment you can analyze deeper the factors that lead the customers to leave the bank by
using some data mining techniques like for example doing her chi squared test or applying to that summary
function on your independent variables to understand which independent variables have the most impact
on the dependent variable that is which independent variable explains the most why customers are leaving.
Well you know how to do that.
That's exactly what we did in part two and three when we used the summary function to get values and
statistical significance levels to see which independent variables are the most autistic the significant
and therefore explain the best the dependent variable.
That is why customers are leaving.
So that's the purpose behind making these predictions on the test set.
It's just to get the accuracy on your observations to validate the model so that we can give this model
to the bank.
All right so now let's make the predictions.
So we are almost done here.
We just need to add one more thing which is again related to the fact that we are using the H-2 package.
And as you can see in this new data arguments well this new data is of course the test set but this
test set is expected to be an H2 frame.
Right now it is a standard data frame but our H2 o product function is expecting an age to overwrite.
So how can we convert this data frame into a page to a friend.
Well by doing exactly the same as what we did to convert this training said data frame into this age
to frame that is by applying on the test set as that age to function.
All right so I'm putting the test that in the function like that.
And here we go.
Now I think everything is ready we are ready to make the predictions which so far will be the prediction
of the probabilities that the Classic was one that is the probabilities that the customers leave the
bank.
So let's select this and get the predicted probabilities.
And here we go.
We now have the problem Fred vector containing all the predicted probabilities in the form of an environment.
So that's good but we cannot have a look at these predicted probabilities yet.
We will need to convert it back into a standard vector.
But before we do that convert it into a vector.
Well we need to apply this line as well which will you know transform the probabilities into the predictions
in the form one or zero.
That is exactly the predictions of the dependent variable exited.
And to do this we're using this if else function.
And basically what we do is we choose a threshold such that if the predicted probability is above the
threshold then we predict one.
And if the predicted probability is below the threshold then we predict zero.
So that's a natural threshold to take when we get our predictions in terms of probabilities know that
it is not necessarily always 50 percent 0.5.
That's the case.
For example in medicine when we have to predict some sensitive information like for example predicting
if a tumor is malignant.
Well that's more sensitive.
So in that case we'd better be sure of our predictions and therefore we would choose a higher threshold
like for example 80 percent.
But here we are predicting if a customer leaves the bank.
So we are fine with the 50 percent threshold.
So that's OK.
And by the way there is a more simple way to get these predictions in the forms you're a one without
using if else function it's by simply removing this one in zero here and removing this if else and by
using this spread larger than 0.5 because this will return a boolean which will be true if property
is larger than 0.5 and false if Prop red is below 0.5 and why spread in the form of these billions.
True and False will be accepted in this confusion matrix here.
So that's more simple.
And now let's get this predictions in the form of billions.
All right so I'm going to select this line and execute.
All right.
Now we have our white print in the form of billions but it is still a nature to object because it is
the result in the first place of this age to predict function.
So it is still an age to object and therefore Now what we have to do is to convert this age to object
back into a vector because the stable function here will only accept a vector a standard vector.
And of course we'll never accept this age to object.
So let's convert it back into a vector and that's actually really simple.
It's actually kind of the same as converting a data frame into a nature to frame.
But instead of using age to here we will use vector.
So here we simply have to type Y pred equals as Dot vector and the parenthesis of course whitebread.
All right so let's check it out and we're going to select this line and Exiguus.
And now as you can see why press became this vector of integers containing 2000 elements.
And that's the standard vector are we were used to working with.
So we can actually have a look at the predictions of the test observations by typing here in the console
y present.
Here we go.
That's all the predictions of the tested observations 2000 predictions.
So here we go according to the model the first customer stayed in the bank.
The second customer stayed in the bank.
The third customer left the bank.
The fourth one stayed the fifth stayed etc..
So if you win you can actually compare these predictions with the real results that are in the last
column.
To set this column here.
So for example 0 0 1 0 0 0 are the real outcomes of the first first customers.
And if we compare that with the predictions Well we see that the predictions are quite correct because
here we get as well 0 0 1 0 0 0.
So the Pfeiffer's predictions are correct.
So that smells pretty good for our accuracy that we are about to compute because when we look at the
first observations we can only see correct predictions.
So now actually I can't wait to see the accuracy.
So let's computed right now.
We will start by making the comparison metrics and of course here we need to replace this index 3 here
by 11 because this corresponds to the index of the dependent variable.
And so now we are ready to make this comparison matrix.
So I'm going to select this line and execute.
Here we go confusion matrix created.
So now let's have a look.
I'm going to type CME here in the console and press enter.
That's our confusion matrix.
We can see a lot of correct predictions.
That's good.
1536 correct predictions of customers who stayed in the bank and one hundred and ninety five correct
predictions of customers who left the bank and then we have two hundred and twelve plus fifty seven
incorrect actions of customers who either left or stayed in the back.
So this looks pretty good.
And now let's not wait anymore.
Let's compute the accuracy.
So the accuracy is the total number of correct predictions.
That is one hundred five thousand thirty six plus one hundred ninety five divided by the total number
of observations in the test set.
That is the total number of predictions actually which is two thousand.
All right.
So let's check it out.
Let's see if we can offer this model to the bank.
Let's see if we'll get the bonus.
Let's find out about its accuracy on 3 3 2 1 GO eighty six point five percent.
That's actually not bad at all.
Eighty six point five percent well let's say 87 87 percent means that on one hundred observations 87
predictions should be correct.
So this is pretty good.
And besides we haven't done any parameter chilling and you will see that by doing some parameter tuning
using some techniques like k fold cross-validation.
Well we can get an even better accuracy score.
No worries.
We will do that in parts and you can actually already practice to improve this accuracy score.
And please let me know if you get an awesome one.
And now just one last thing since we were connected to this H-2 instance it's better to disconnect from
it now and to do this we only need to apply a last function of age 2 which is the age to oh Dot shut
down.
Here it is with no arguments inside.
You just need to select this and this will disconnect you from the server.
So let's executes.
Are you sure you want to shut down the H-2 instance running at this address then you just need to type
here.
Keep it or why.
And then answer.
And now we are disconnected.
True means yes we did disconnect.
So congratulations.
You have built your first artificial neural network on our using the H2 package.
I was very happy to build this first deep learning model with you and we're getting to the end of this
section next section will be about convolutional neural networks.
Another branch of machine learning specialized for computer vision because it will consider spatial
structure and the data exactly as it is the case for images where the position of the pixels matters.
So we will see that in the next section.
And until then enjoy machine learning