Here I've got a confusion matrix and this confusion matrix has 10000 records in it and it represents
scenario number one which we'll be looking at as you can see this model has made 150 type 1 errors and
50 type 2 errors.
And but overall it's predicted quite a lot correctly.
Now let's calculate the accuracy rate in this scenario the accuracy rate is the total correct word.
But overall total and it's 9800 divided by 10000 which is 90 percent.
Okay great but what are we going to do now is we're going to tell the model to stop making predictions
whatsoever which is going to abandon them all completely.
And we're going to say that from now on our prediction is always zero.
We're always going to predict that the event is not going to occur.
So basically what will happen to the confusion matrix is these records will move from the right call
them to the left column and our new confusion matrix will look like this.
Nine thousand eight hundred fifty 150 and then nothing in the predicted column where we predicted that
something will occur.
And of course that moves against all logic right.
Why would you abandon a model but let's calculate the accuracy rate in this scenario.
So in order to accuracy rate has the same formula in this case accuracy rate is nine thousand eight
hundred fifty divided by 10000.
So it's ninety eight and a half percent the accuracy rate went up by half a percent.
And as you can see what we did is we just completely stopped using a model but the accuracy rate went
up.
And that is why you should not base your judgment just on accuracy right because things like this can
happen and even though obviously you're not using a model any more which means that you're not applying
any kind of logic into your decision making process your accuracy rate is going up so it's misleading
you into a wrong conclusion that you should stop using models and this effect is called the accuracy
paradox.
And starting from the next tutorial I will show you a much better way to assess your models using the
cumulative accuracy profile of forcing you then.
Until next time happy analyzing