Hello, my friends.
Welcome back to this moral selection section.
In the previous editorial, we implemented the K4 cross-validation technique, which is a new tool you
now have in order to measure the most relevant way, the performance of your moral.
And now I'm giving you an extra tool, which is grid search and which will allow you to find the optimal
values of the hyper parameters in any model to therefore get an even higher accuracy than, you know,
the standard version of the model.
So we're going to work on the exact same data set Social Network ad.
So I'm not going to remind this again.
And therefore, let's open our grid search implementation either in Google Collaboratory or Dupere and
Notebook.
As you wish.
And actually, this grid search implementation is exactly the same as this one.
Only we're just going to implement one extra cell, which will be, you know, the cell applying grid
search to find the best model and the best parameter, the best model version, actually, of the kernel
as yet.
All right.
Are you ready for this?
I am sure you are.
So let's create right away a copy, because this file is in read only mode and we're gonna, you know,
reimplement that cell building the grid search technique.
Okay, let's now remove this because we're going to work with our copies and there we go.
Now let's crawl down, you know, to find that cell implementing grid search.
Let's remove it.
You know, put it in the trash.
And there we go.
Let's apply grid search to find best model and the best parameters.
All right.
So let's create a new coattail.
And now the first thing I want to do is actually go to dislike it, learn API.
There we go to show you actually again the class that implements the kernel as your model, because
I actually want to show you the hyper parameters which we can tune to find the best version of the kernel
as your model.
So here, take the first link.
That's the psychic.
You're in Web site.
Then please go to API here, you know, to find all the classes and the functions.
And remember, Colonel, as VM is actually in the as v m section.
So we have to scroll down to find the S letter and we should find it very soon.
We support vector machines as Kaylor and DOT as VM as V a module by the Cycler Library.
And remember, the class is this one as VM dot as we see.
Right.
If we check on our implementation, you know, we import this SBC class to build this kernel as VM moral
with a radial basis function kernell.
Okay.
All right.
So K4 cross-validation grid search.
There we go back in the cycle and API.
Well, the thing I wanted to show you was that indeed the kernel as VM model has a lot of hyper parameters.
I remind that hyper parameters are the parameters which are not learned during the training process.
You know, these are different parameters than the weights or, you know, the coefficient of the model.
And these hyper parameters are well, you know, there are many of them.
You have the C parameter, which is the regularization parameter that you can tune to actually improve
the training performance by reducing overfitting.
I reminded Overfitting is a situation where you have a high accuracy on the training set, but a poor
one on the test set, which means that your model was overtrained on the training set.
You know, two well trained.
And we definitely want to avoid this so that Perama is actually very important.
And we will tune it to find the best value.
The default value is 1.0, but we will try several values.
We will try.
Oh point twenty five point five or point seventy five and one.
Because as you can see, it's important to notice this.
The strength of the regularization is inversely proportional to see.
Meaning that the lower is C, the stronger will be the regularization.
So, you know, we're going to try the value of O point twenty five, which will be therefore a strong
regularization.
We'll try open five as well.
Still quite a strong regularization O point seventy five.
Less strong regularization and one.
And we can even try.
No.
Open twenty.
Open five as you want.
Feel free.
I will actually improvise this a bit.
I'll see where I end up choosing as the values of.
Experiment.
And then we have the kernel also.
Of course, that's a very important hyper parameter.
And we will actually tune it.
Meaning we will find the best kernel of the kernel as a model among these ones.
So we'll actually try both the linear one and Arbie F one.
But you're free to also try.
For example, the pulley or sigmoid one.
And then I would also like to tune this parameter gamma, which is a parameter you only enter when you
choose either arbi f kernel or polynomial kernel or a sigmoid kernel.
And since we're gonna tune the linear and IBF kernels, well, for the RBA of kernel, I would like
to tune, you know, different values.
Gamma to actually find the best one.
And actually we will try all the gamma values from zero point one to zero point nine.
OK.
And Gamma is, of course, the coefficient in, you know, the formula of the kernel, which Carol and
I have already showed you in part three classification.
All right.
So let's do these three parameters.
And if you want to tune, more of them will feel totally free or if you want to tune more values of
them.
But you will see that already with this tuning, we will get an excellent performance.
And speaking of performance, actually, it's important to highlight that each time we will try these
different combinations of these hyper parameter values.
Well, the accuracy of the model will be evaluated through careful trust validation and not on a single
test set.
OK.
So we will have super relevant measures of the accuracy's for each of the combinations of these parameters.
And therefore, we will be confident that the best set, you know, the best combination of parameters
we end up with is indeed the right one.
All right.
So let's do this.
Let's implement grid search now.
And of course, as usual, we're going to start from Saikat.
Learn from cyclone.
By the way, let's upload a notebook now so that we can, you know, benefit from Google cloud assistance.
Let's click upload here and there we go.
We already have the right folder and we select social network ads, dot CSC.
That's the data set with which we're going to experiment grid search.
And so there we go.
Now we should get the help of Google Kulab.
So we're going to start from Saikat here and and then saying we're gonna get access to the model selection.
There we go.
Module from which we're going to import this time a class which is a grid search civic class.
Okay.
And now, already in the next step, we're going to enter the different combinations of parameters.
We want to experiment.
And so I'm going to create a new variable here, which I'm going to call parameters, and then I'm going
to enter these combinations of hyper parameters.
We want to experiment within a list.
So, you know, this parameter is viable here will simply be the list of the different combinations
of hybrid parameters.
We want to test.
And then within that list, I'm actually going to create two dictionaries y two, because actually I
want to test two different kernel.
So in one dictionary we will have the linear kernel.
And in a separate dictionary, we'll have the RPF kernel.
And the reason why I have to separate these two dictionaries is because, you know, the gamma parameter,
which we want to tune, can only be used with the RBA kernel and not with the linear kernel.
If it could be used with the linear kernel, then I wouldn't have to make two dictionaries.
Only one would be fine.
And I would just enter the different values of all the parameters which we want to experiment.
But that's not the case.
So indeed, I have to create these two dictionaries, which I'm gonna put, you know, below each other
just like that.
And there we go.
Now let's enter the first dictionary.
So how are you gonna do this?
Well, just the way dictionaries work.
First, we have to enter the key and the key is actually the parameter itself.
So remember, we want to tune first, see the regularization parameter, then the kernel, and then
in the case of the RBA girl, the degree.
And so in my dictionary here, I'm going to enter as the first key in quotes.
Well, this parameter C and then I'm adding here some Cullin and right after the colon, I have to enter
the value of that key.
And the value of that key is exactly the values of C.
We want to experiment and we have to enter them in a new list in a pair of square brackets.
And as we said, we want to try the following different values of this regularization parameter C,
which are, as we said, first four point twenty five, then O point five.
Then O point seventy five.
And then one.
Right.
So here on the left, we have strong regularization.
And the closer we get to one, the less strong is the regularization.
All right.
So that's for this parameter C, then we can enter a second key within this dictionary.
And we have to separate.
With a comma.
And that second key will be, of course, that other parameter which we want to tune, which is the
kernel.
And therefore, in quotes here, I'm going to enter Colonel.
And then for the value of that key, which has to be separate.
By Colin.
Well, this value will be once again in the list.
Therefore, in a pair of square brackets, the different values of the kernel.
We want to experiment.
However, since we have these two dictionaries to separate the case of the linear kernel and the RBA
kernel, because, you know, if this gamma parameter.
Well, here in this COL list, I will only enter in quotes once again.
The Lynnae are.
Colonel.
And now check what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna copy all of these, you know, inside this first dictionary.
I'm going to paste that inside this second dictionary.
And then here we're gonna test the same values of the parameters, see?
But we're gonna test them with an RB if, Colonel.
And therefore, since now we're experimenting the army.
Colonel.
Well, then we can add this extra hyper parameter to tune, which is the gamma parameter, which is
a Newquay of this second dictionary.
So Gamma and the value of that key will be the list of the different values of Gamma.
We want to try.
Right.
And as we said, these are 0.01.
Then oh point two, then four point three and point four point five or point six or point seven.
Open eight and open nine.
All right.
Good.
So you see how this works.
We have to enter our parameters into a list.
And then inside each list.
Well, either we don't have to separate some cases and we can put all the hyper parameters and their
values into a same dictionary, or we have to separate some cases and we enter them with two separate
dictionaries.
This way.
All right.
Excellent.
And now that we prepared correctly are parameters, you know, our hyper parameters, combinations.
Well, time to call that grid search silly class, because indeed, as you can guess, this list of
parameters will be one of the inputs of that grid search class or, you know, the instance of that
class we will create.
And well, speaking of the instance of that class, that's exactly our next step here.
And so I'm going to create a new object, a new variable, which will be an object of this grid search
theory class and which I'm going to call simply grid underscore search.
All right.
Then, of course, we have to call a class to create such an instance.
So grid search.
There we go.
Was waiting for Google Kulab.
Then in parentheses, let's enter the parameters.
You can find them on the cyclone API.
But I'll just give them to you now.
So the first one is estimated.
All right.
And this will be equal, of course, to your classifier.
You know, just like the estimated argument in the Cross Vänskä function.
So classifier and which is, of course, your kernel as yem classifier.
Then next argument.
Well, next argument is actually our parameters.
You know, the different combinations of the hybrid parameters.
We want to experiment and try to find the best value.
And so the name of that argument is Boram Underscore.
Great.
And this will be of course equal to or parameter is variable, that list of all the combinations of
hybrid parameter values.
Then next argument.
Well, the next argument is an important one.
That's the scoring.
And that's basically the metric with which you want to evaluate the performance of your model for each
of these combinations of hyper parameter values.
And well, since now we're doing classification.
Well, the value for this argument will be in, quote, accuracy, of course.
All right, then, next argument.
So as I told you, you know, each of these combinations of hyper parameters will be evaluated through
K4 cross-validation and not on a single test set.
And therefore, here, the next argument is just to choose the number of trained test force that will
have when applying careful cross-validation for each of the combinations.
And that parameter, his name is the same as right here.
It is S.V..
And once again, we will choose the very common value of ten trained test force.
And finally, a very optional parameter, which you don't have too much worry about.
But I'm adding it here in case you run this code on your machine.
This is a parameter that will set how to run your processor, as you know, in your machine.
And I'm just adding it here with the parameter value minus one, which means that all your processors
will be used, you know, in your machine, which will optimize the grid search process, because you're
going to see that it can be a very long process, you know, to test all these combinations.
Well, it can actually take some time.
OK.
So that's it for this grid search study class.
We now have our object.
And as you might guess, the next step will be to connect this object to our training set.
I remind that grid search has to be applied on to training set only because the test set once again
is something you want to have separated whenever you want to test your moral or, you know, your tuned
model.
You know, after you tune it on a set of new observations to see how it performs on a data set like
in production.
OK.
So we will apply now grid search to the training set only and to do this.
Well, we're going to call our object grid search from which we're going to call once again that very
famous method, which you're so familiar with now, which is the fit method.
And of course, this fit method takes two arguments as input, which are, first, the features of the
training set, meaning X train and then the dependent, viable vector of the training set.
That is why train just like a classic training ride.
Because actually now we're going to do a lot of training.
You know, a training for each of these combinations of hyper parameter values.
OK.
So that's basically the multiple training.
And then there we go.
This multiple training is done.
Well, we'll get all the final results, meaning all the different accuracy's resulting from all these
combinations of happy parameters.
And therefore, after getting all these accuracy's will, we'll get the highest of them and we'll get
mostly the set of parameters that led to that highest accuracy.
And so first, let's get that best accuracy, which we're going to put into a new variable, which we're
going to call best accuracy.
And to get this, well, we're actually gonna get it from an attribute of the great search civic class,
which is called best score, I reminded an attribute is just a value we can get from a specific object.
And that value here is, of course, the best accuracy taken from that.
Research objects.
I'm gonna copy this and just below gonna paste it from which I'm gonna call that best on the score score
and then we have to add an underscore again.
That's usually how our named attributes are to best score, meaning best accuracy.
Because we chose an accuracy scoring.
And now now that we have the best accuracy.
Well, let's see which parameters led to that best accuracy.
And to do this well, we're going to put that best set of parameters once we get into a new variable,
which we're gonna call best underscore parameters.
All right.
And once again, to get them.
We're going to call another attribute of our grid search city class or, you know, our grid search
instance of that class.
And therefore, I just copied this.
And we'll be that here because this time the name of that attribute is best, perhaps best Baran's.
OK.
And now we're going to finish this with two beautiful prints.
And these prints are actually very similar to the ones we did for K4 cross-validation.
So I'm just copying this.
And right here, basting them.
And now instead of printing, you know, accuracy as string, we're gonna print.
Best accuracy.
Then we're going to keep the same format of, you know, the two decimals after the comma in a float.
And for the variable that will get us this, well, of course, this won't be the mean of the accuracy's
here, but simply that best accuracy, variable value.
Right.
This gives directly the best accuracy resulting from the best combination of hyper parameters.
So let's just take this and let's just replace that accuracy's dot mean, you know, the main function
by this best accuracy variable.
And then we have to multiply it by 100 in order to get the accuracy in this format, you know, with
the precent format, which we have here once again.
And then we don't want to print the standard deviation, but the best parameters.
And then I'm just gonna print these best parameters the classic way, you know, the simple way of printing
something.
So I'm just gonna remove everything here, you know, that format function and that variable.
So because it will be a different variable.
And then, look, I'm just going to do this.
This is the string that will be printed and then to print the value of that strain or the best parameters
themselves.
I'm just gonna separate that string with a comma and then adding the variable that will give us these
best parameters.
That's just a classic way of printing something with, you know, a string indicating what we're printing.
And so here we just need to add best parameters.
And there we go, my friends.
We're done with this implementation.
Well, we're almost done.
We just forgot to remove one parenthesis, which was, I think, coming from this format function.
But there we go.
Now, the implementation of grid search is done.
So we're going to experiment this now.
And I look forward to see which combination of all these hyper parameters will lead to the best accuracy.
And of course, we'll compare that best accuracy to the relevant accuracy we got with the standard version
of the kernel as your model, you know, with the RB of kernel and the default value of one for that
regularization parameter C and then the same default value of the gamma parameter.
So let's see, we have our data set.
So we are ready to do this.
Restart and run.
Oh.
So there we go.
Three, two, one, go.
And yes.
All right.
So now the sales will be running.
There we go.
Grid search is now running and we are about to get.
OK.
So very, very interesting.
We get a best accuracy of ninety point sixty seven percent, which is slightly better than this ninety
point thirty three percent.
But you will see in your future machinery projects that even a slight improvement of the accuracy can
make a difference.
And the best combination of parameters that led to that best accuracy is the following first regularization
parameter C of all point five, meaning that indeed it was necessary to reduce a bit that hyper parameter
C to reduce overfitting.
Then of course, we got the best accuracy with an RB F colonel, meaning with the kernel as VM model
instead of the classic linear as.
And the best value of this gamma parameter, you know, when we have a Arby F kernel isn't it.
Or point six.
All right.
So it was actually good to test all of them.
And that's what we get as the best model.
So now feel free to try some other values, you know, if you want, and maybe some other hyper parameters.
And if you get a better accuracy than ninety point sixty seven percent, which I'm sure you can get
easily, you know, I haven't tried all the combinations.
Well, once again, feel free to share this in the Q&amp;A section or in private message.
But Q&amp;A section is best so that other students can see how you did it.
All right.
And now we're going to move on to the very exciting final section of this caution of the bonus section,
which is about extra boost and which will basically give you an extra super powerful machinery model
that you can actually both apply to classification and regression.
So you definitely want this as the final tool of your huge machine learning tool kit.
So I look forward to implementing this final model with you.
And until then, enjoy machine learning.