Hello and welcome back to the course on machine learning in the Bruce tutorials we learned quite a lot
about the Kamins algorithm we talked about how it works in the background we actually performed.
Emmanuel Kamins algorithm which was lots of fun.
Then we talked about the random installation trap and what the Kamins plus plus is and it all the scenarios
we kind of worked with a pre-determined number of classers where those two clusters of three clusters
and we talked about somehow finding out the correct number of clusters for a given data size problem
.
In today's tutorial actually going to talk about the algorithm behind finding out the right number of
clusters.
So we'll learn how to decide what number of clusters to input into your Kamins algorithm.
So let's get straight into it.
Here we've got a challenge or a design problem.
Again we've got only two variables x and y coordinates.
Just for simplicity's sake inreality can be any number of columns or variables and you have got the
scatterplot for presenting our daughter said.
Now if we are Iran the K means clustering algorithm on this dataset with three clusters or with K pre-determine
to be three then the result will look something like this.
And not just something like this but exactly like this we've got the three clusters that have been identified
and we already know that we would need to run the Kamins plus plus algorithm just to avoid the random
selection trap.
But again for simplicity's sake which is going to call the Kamins algorithm.
So we've got three clusters.
No.
In order to understand if for instance two clusters would have been better in this scenario or maybe
10 clusters would have been better.
We need a certain metric we need a way to understand or evaluate how a certain number of clusters performs
compared to a different number of clusters and preferably that metric should be quantifiable.
So what kind of metric can we impose upon our clustering algorithm that will tell us something about
the final result.
And there is such a metric is called the within cluster sum of squares.
Hence the WCR says on the left hand that is the formula how it's calculated.
This is an example for three clusters.
No.
At first glance this formula might look a bit overwhelming or complex but in reality it's super simple
so in line with our mission making the complex simple let's break it all down what is going on here
.
Well we've got the three elements and each has some so this symbol stands for some each sum is calculated
for each cluster in fact it's calculated within that cluster hence the W at the start.
So let's look at one of them.
Let's look at the central one for instance.
Here we are taking every point inside cluster 2.
That's exactly what is written out here and this is not a valid way to write this obviously just write
up P with the index eyes and cyclists or two and we go and take a summer across those points and what
we're summing is a distance between each point inside closer to and the centroid of cluster 2 and then
we squaring the distance.
So we taking some of those squared distances.
So now if we have a look at our chart I'm going to keep the WCR says on the left.
So for instance we're closer to there it is we're taking the centroid and we're calculating the distance
to every single point so to that point then we're square with squaring it to that point then risk wearing
it to that point then we're squaring it to that point we're squaring it.
And so on.
So we take the square the sum of all the squares of all these distances and we're summing it.
And then we're doing that.
So we're doing it for the first cluster.
We're doing that for a second closer and we're doing that for the third cluster as well.
And so as a result we get this total of some.
So the full sum and that is going to be our metric.
And actually it's a quite a good metric in terms of understanding or comparing the goodness of fit between
two different Kamins cluster rings and how do we know that.
Well let's have a look let's rewind back to when we had one closer let's see how that metric WCA says
it's going to change as we increase the number of clusters.
All right.
So there is our chart with just the one cluster as you can see that is our centroid.
And for every single point we have to measure the distance between that point and the centroid then
you have to square that distance and then we'll have to add all those distances up as you can see it
will get quite a large value because this centroid is quite moved away from the points they all have
to reach towards it.
So let's just visually remember what this looks like and that will help us kind of remember what that
distance is not in terms of absolute value but just what it feels like.
It's quite a large distance right now so I'm going to increase the number of clusters to two and let's
see how everything changes.
So there we go that's two clusters.
And as you can see now sort of having once intro in the middle we have to centroid.
So each one of these points no longer has to reach all the way to the middle or the distance doesn't
.
Isn't that great.
All you have to do is just calculate distance to this centroid as it gets less and then for the Central
is for all of them here as well the distance to this centroid is less They don't have to reach all the
way to the middle when you're calculating a distance.
So there we go.
That means that the total distance or the total WCA says that we see here is going to be less than when
we had one central.
Now once again we're going to increase the number of clusters this time to three.
So just remember visually what two clusters looks like.
And then we'll compare to the next image.
So there we go.
Now we have three clusters.
And as you can see nothing change in close one so this does this some is going to be the same.
These two sums have changed so now it's sort of a one cluster.
These two groups of points are recognized as separate clusters and therefore they have their own centroid
and the distance has again decreased because you can see now all these points are closer to their own
centroid than they were to the century which is in the middle.
And again these points are closer to this centroid overall than they were to the centroid here in the
middle.
So therefore as you can see that WCA says distance is decreasing.
And what is the limit of that.
How far will it keep decrease decreasing.
Well let's think about it let's say we increase the number of clusters to 4 5 6 and so on.
How many clusters maximum Can we have.
Well we can have as many clusters as there are points or elements in our data set.
So as many points as we see on our chart that's how many cluster we have we can have so if we are 50
points we can have up to 50 clusters because after all we're 50 or after you go over the number of points
there's no more points to actually cluster every single point has its own cluster.
So and in that case what will the WC assess equate to.
I'll give you a second if you wanted.
You can pose this video just to think about that for a second if if we've reached the number of Klosters
equivalent to the number of points in our chart or the number of which is the same thing as the number
of elements and our daughter said then what does WCA says equate to.
And exactly right.
The WC assessed will equate to zero because every single point has its own cluster and therefore has
its own centroid and that centroid is going to be exactly where that point is and therefore the distance
between the point and centroid is going to be zero.
If you square that is going to be zero and if you add up all the squares is still going to be 0.
So as we can see the WC SS will decrease from a substantial value when we have one closer all the way
down to zero as we increase the number of clusters.
So it is a good metric.
But at the same time it's constantly decreasing right so it's constantly getting better and better and
better.
And that's because as you can see the less the WCR says or the higher the number of close is the better
the goodness of fit we were fitting our data better and better and better and therefore the lesser the
WCR says the better.
The goodness of fit is deemed to be.
But how do we find the optimal goodness of fit.
Yes it keeps getting better.
But is there a sacrifice that comes with that improvement and that is exactly the case.
Let's have a look at this visual chart.
This charter presents how the WC assessed changes as we increase the number of clusters.
And as you can see at the start the WCA says starts at quite a large number.
It doesn't really matter what this number is measured in what the absolute value is and things like
that.
What matters is how it changes so the relative comparison between different k means clustering methods
with the different number of clusters.
So you can see here that it jump from 8000 down to 3000 that's a massive change of 5000 let's just call
them units 5000 units and then from 3000 as we increase the number of close from two to 3 they jump
from 3000 to 1000.
Again quite a large drop.
And then from three to four what's going to happen is going to jump from 1000 to maybe eight hundred
and from 800 to 600 600 to 500 and so on so as you can see the first two improvements or first two changes
from one cluster to two from two to three created some huge jumps or huge drops in the WTS going forward
.
The WCR says drops not substantially.
And this is our hint at selecting the optimum optimal number of clusters and the method we're going
to use is the elbow method and it is actually very visual.
All you have to do is look at your chart and look for that change or that's kind of like it does look
like an elbow.
Look for that elbow in your chart where the drop goes from being quite substantial to being not as substantial
not as proven is not as great and therefore that point in your chart is going to be the optimal number
of clusters.
In this case it is indeed three clusters.
That is the optimal number.
And as you can imagine this method is quite arbitrary.
So sometimes the situations are not as obvious sometimes the elbow might not be as evident as in this
case and therefore somebody might pick one number of clusters someone else might come along and pick
a number.
Another number of clusters.
But that is a judgment call that you need to make as a data scientist.
Sometimes you need to decide on how your Narses going to be structured.
And this is one of those cases because you are deciding what type of k means clustering algorithm to
run your inputting that value of k.
And yes it can be arbitrary but if you're not really sure then you just need to kind of run the Kamins
for instance with three look at it before look at it refer to and see what the difference is and make
that judgment call on which k you think is optimal for your analysis because ultimately you are the
person creating this analysis and you need to decide which number of clusters optimal so the Elbel method
is just a an approach that can help you make that decision.
But at the end of day it is your decision.
So there we go.
Hopefully you enjoy this tutorial and now your arsenal of k means clustering is quite broad.
You have quite a few tools in there and I can wait for you to jump into the practical application of
this method had the lean has prepared some very interesting code challenges for you and you'll be working
with this method BAHFEN our Python is going to be very exciting.
So good luck with that.
I'll see you next time.
And until then in Germany learning