Hello and welcome back to the course on deep natural language processing.
And today we're going to talk about the types of natural language processing.
So we've got to then diagrams here.
We've got a Ben diagram of two circles in it.
And we are going to look at the different areas of natural language processing that are going to come
up in discourse.
So on the left, we've got natural language processing overall.
And this refers to the whole circle on the left.
So the reason why we've called in just this green part is because that's the non overlapping part.
So we know that anything in here is just natural language processing.
We've followed with disregard to the second circle.
But natural language processing is indeed everything that is in this first circle.
Then we've got on the right deep learning.
So these are all algorithms that have something to do with neural networks, deep learning.
Basically, anything that's called a deep learning algorithm falls in here.
They don't have to be natural language processing.
They can be classification.
They can be anything.
So they can be.
That's deep learning here.
And natural language processing is any algorithm, any model that has something to do with processing
of natural language into machine terms.
And then finally, in the overlap, we have deep MLP.
So these are models which have to do with natural language processing, but also which are deep learning
models, which are neural network models.
And so that's the part that we're going to be aiming for.
But it's also very good to have visibility of all three, because in this course we will be talking
about some models that fall just in here.
And then we'll be talking about models here.
And it'll be good to compare and see how the world has changed over time and why these models are often
better than these models.
And the other thing to note here is that the size of these diagrams is not reflective of the importance
or the volumes of these different fields.
So I just said circles of the same size simply because we want a visual representation of of the overlap
and that these fields exist.
But don't take this size into account.
It's not to scale at all.
And finally, there is a another part, another part of this event diagram, which is very important
to us.
And it is this part of a here a sub section of the deep and LP called sequence to sequence.
So sequence to sequence models are the most cutting edge, the most powerful models that exist right
now for natural language processing.
And that's what we're going to be looking at.
So as you'll see throughout this course, we will make our way through the national language processing
side of things in too deep an LP.
And then we will go into sequence to sequence.
It'll be a fun and exciting journey.
And the other thing that I wanted to mention is you will also notice that throughout this course, even
though it's focused on Chadbourne, so we won't be talking about just chat bots.
We'll be looking at different examples of how these models from here and from here and from here can
be applied to different things because the applications are huge.
We can or we can apply them in our natural neural machine.
Translation We can apply them in image captioning.
We can apply them in speech recognition, questions and answers.
Summarization, lots and lots of models.
So we will be looking at different ones.
And they will be of different types.
So this map will come in handy as we go through the course and it will be popping up here and there.
So I think it was very important for us to set the foundation right.
So that now we're ready to proceed.
And I can't wait to see you on the next material and until then, enjoy and deep and natural language
processing.