Hello my friends and welcome to this new practical activity.
The first one of Part 6 reinforcement learning where we will be implementing the UCB algorithm upper
confidence bound.
It is one of the most exciting branches of machine learning because you know it is the one the closest
to artificial intelligence in the sense that you know we're making some programs that play some actions
just like a robot.
So this is very exciting.
This is one of my favorite branches if not the number one and so I'm so excited right now to teach you
about the fundamentals of reinforcement learning especially.
I'm so excited to implement two of the best reinforcement learning models with you which are UCB and
Thompson assembling.
So first A.S. we will implement UCB uproot confidence bound and once again we will apply it on a business
case study which you know will be the next part of the story we had in Part 3 classification.
You remember that SUV you know that brand new luxury SUV that this car company was trying to optimize
the targeting thanks to classification.
Well this time we're going to optimize the online advertising meaning that we're going to find the best
ad you know among different ads designs the best ad that will convert the maximum customers to click
on the ad and you know potentially buy the product by the car.
Okay.
So I will explain the story a bit more later but before let's just make sure everyone here is on this
same page.
I give you the links to this whole folder right before this does oil in the article.
So make sure to click it.
And now we should all be on the same page so let's do this let's end to Part 6.
Reinforcement learning.
And we're going to start as we said with upper confidence bound UCB.
And so this time you'll not only see the two folders by then in orbit you also see the full slide of
the UCB algorithm and you will also see the full slate of the Thompson something algorithm in the other
folder.
So let's have a look at it.
Make sure to download it.
And if you want you can print it and post it on your wall.
There you go.
You have the three steps of the UCB algorithm which we are going to implement together.
You know I will actually give you a lot of exercises in this implementation I will tell you before we
implement each of the steps to implement it yourself.
So at first you will have to implement step one then one step one is implemented we will implement step
two.
You will do it first before we do it together.
And then step three.
So you see it will be a very learned by doing process.
All right.
So that is the slide.
Make sure to download it.
And now let's go into Python first to implement the UCB algorithm.
All right so as usual you have two fouls here you have the data set at City are optimization city are
means click through rate and that's what we are going to optimize things to uproot confidence mount
first and then Thompson sampling and then we have the implementation of course upper confidence bound
in the IPO and B format which can open with either Google collaboratively or Jupiter notebook.
All right so as usual let us start by explaining what this dataset is about.
So as I said we are doing the next part of the story of this car dealership trying to sell that new
SUV.
We've already done the targeting you know we've already optimized motoring thanks to classification
in part three and now we're going to optimize the click through rate of some ads.
We're going to make for this car.
Okay.
So what happened exactly is that the advertising team prepared 10 different ads you know with 10 different
designs for example on one ad we will see the SUV in a beautiful mountain on the other ad we'll see
that SUV in a futuristic city and another ad we'll see that SUV and a charming city you know like a
charming city in the south of France or Italy.
And another ad will see the car on the moon.
You know why not.
And another ad we'll see the car on a beautiful countryside cornfield you know something like that.
So basically all the ads have different designs and advertising team is wondering well which ad will
convert the most you know which ad will attract the most people to click the ad and then potentially
buy the SUV.
So we have these 10 different ads and what we're going to do and that is the process of online learning
we're going to show these ads to different users online.
You know once they connect to a certain Web site or to a search engine you know it can be ads that appear
at the top of a page when you type of research on Google.
We're going to show one of these ads each time the user connects to the Web page and we're going to
record the result whether this user clicked yes or no on the ad.
OK.
So just to recap there is a first user that connects to let's say a web page.
Our algorithm which will be here first UCB will select an ad to show to this user and then the user
will decide to click yes or no on the ad.
If the user clicks on the ad we will recorded as one.
And if the user doesn't click on the ad we will record it as zero.
Okay.
And then a new user connects to the Web page and same the algorithm selects an ad to show this new user.
And if this new user clicks the ad then it's a one and if not it's a zero.
OK.
And we're going to do this for lots of users actually.
Ten 10000 users.
And that's what this dataset is about.
However now there is something you must absolutely understand and that is very very important.
Make sure to understand it and make sure to rewind.
If this is not understood.
Okay.
So I'm going to explain this.
Please listen carefully.
So you know in reality what happens is that users connect one by one to the Web page and for each of
them we successively show them the ad right.
So everything happens in real time.
You know it's a dynamic process.
It's not a static process with a static data set which was recorded over a certain period of time.
It's a real time process.
And therefore the only way to simulate this would be either that I you know make ten real ads right
now you know 10 real hours of a car that I open a Google AdWords account and then I show the ads for
real to some users you know real persons connect to the site.
Of course I'm not going to do this because first of all this is costly.
And then you know this would deceive the users.
Well you know I would have to really sell a car somehow.
So of course this is not an option and therefore I have to make a simulation.
OK.
I have to make a simulation in this simulation is exactly given by this dataset because in this dataset
what happens is that each row corresponds to the different user is connecting to the web page.
And to whom we're going to show the ads.
And then each column of this dataset corresponds to the different ads.
OK.
From add one to ad 10.
And this dataset is assimilation in the sense that each time a user connects to the web page.
While this dataset tells us even if we wouldn't know in reality this dataset tells us on which ad the
user of the row would click on you know.
So for example this first user you know this corresponds to the first user to whom we're going to show
the ad and what these sales mean is that this user would click on Add 1.
If we show this user at one then it wouldn't click at 2.
If we show at two because there is a zero here then the user wouldn't click at three.
If we show at three it wouldn't click at four.
If we show at four but then it would click at five.
If we showed at five and etc..
So in other words we know thanks to this simulation you know this dataset doing a simulation we know
that this user will only click Add one at five and at nine.
If we showed these ads and then if we showed all of the other ads at 2:00 at 3:00 et cetera up to at
8:00 and at 10:00 Well this user wouldn't click the ad.
Now I know we wouldn't know that in reality but that's why I'm saying that this dataset is a simulation.
And this is the only way we can actually run the UCB algorithm or the Thomson something algorithm if
not doing it for real you know with a real advertising campaign.
Okay.
So I hope it's clear.
Please we if it's not clear because I think I've said all the keywords you know this dataset is a simulation.
Therefore for all the user as you know corresponding to these ROVs we know on which ad the users will
click right.
This user for example would click only on ad number two or ad number eight.
Right.
But wouldn't click on all the other ads.
And so that's the only way we can indeed simulate the Thompson sampling or UCB algorithm.
All right.
So I hope it's clear then we have let's see let's scroll down to the bottom we have in total ten thousand
users as we said.
And so we're going to run that UCB algorithm first and then add something something algorithm to figure
out the ad that has the highest conversion rate.
Right the ad on which the users click the most.
So I know that we could do it for example with a naive strategy you know a naive algorithm like a simple
one where we collect some simple statistics to see which ad is most frequently clicked on.
But remember as Carol explains in the tuition lectures each time we imprison ad on the Web site or the
Google search engine.
Well this incurs a cost right.
It has a cost to impress and therefore we need to figure out as fast as possible you know in the minimum
number of rounds because you know the users here are represented as rounds because we show the ads for
the users one by one as in one round after the other.
So we need to figure out in a minimum number of rounds which ad converts to the most meaning which is
the best ad to which the users are most attracted to.
And that's why we need a stronger algorithm than a simple statistics algorithm and that stronger algorithm
will be first UCB and then Thompson simply and we will even see which of the two is the most powerful.
All right.
So I think that's enough explained for it this data dataset.
Now we're going to start the implementation.
I can't wait.
This is a very exciting and actually widely used algorithm in online advertising or digital marketing.
So let's do this.
Let's click this implementation and then let's open it with Google collaborate tree or Jupiter notebook
adjuvant all right so now it is loading it it is loading the notebook laying out the notebook.
And now here you go.
Welcome to the UCB implementation.
All right so as usual we're going to create a copy because this is an read only mode.
So in order to re implement it from scratch we're going to click file here and then save a copy and
drive.
This will create a copy inside which we will be able to read implement the whole algorithm from scratch.
All right.
So it is opening you notice that I have my data pricing template opened.
That's because we will use it very quickly you know just to actually import the libraries and the data
set.
And so now before we start let's delete all the code cells here but not the text cells and very soon
we should be able to start.
Okay so that's a simple intimidation you know a simple structure but this cell will actually be long
and that's where you will practice by doing first some steps of the implementation before we do it together.
And so let's have a look.
Welcome to the UCB implementation.
We will start first by empowering the libraries.
Then we will impose a data set.
Then we will implement the full UCB algorithm just following the steps on the slide.
You know with the three steps.
And finally we will visualize the results and by that I mean that we will plot a histogram where we
will clearly see the add that was the most selected you know and that of course it added was identified
as the strongest ad you know the most attractive ad for the users.
And one thing I forgot to say and which is really really important.
This dataset actually suppose that each ad has a fixed conversion rate so ad number one has a certain
conversion rate at number two has another conversion rate.
And then same for all the other ads.
And that's of course because it is a required assumption of both the UCB and Thompson sampling algorithm.
Basically reinforcement learning algorithms for online learning.
And that's you know anyway the case in reality for example with the slot machines in the casino.
Well they all have a fixed conversion rate unless they change it over time.
But that's another question.
There you go usually an ad that you show online has a fixed conversion rate because it will convert
over time the same rate of people.
So we will assume this.
And besides it's close to reality.
But there you go.
That's an important assumption of online learning.
All right.
So now we're ready.
We're ready to begin this implementation.
I hope you're excited.
I hope you understood this data set.
And the fact that we're doing a simulation because we actually don't have too much of a choice.
And so if everything is all good.
Well my friends let let's begin this implementation in the next tutorial.
And until then enjoy machine learning.