Hello my friends all right here we are at the final very exciting step of this implementation where
we visualize the results so we're going to clearly visualize the rules and see for each of them you
know their support their confidence and their lift.
And mostly we're gonna see which are gonna be the best deals by one product and get another one for
free.
We'll clearly see which food goes well with some other food for these French people in the south of
France.
Okay so let's do this.
We already have the rules here which were the output of this primary function so you will see that it
will be very simple to display them.
Therefore Let's select that cell in order to create a new code sale just below and indeed in order to
have a first look at these rules well we simply need to create a new horrible which we're going to call
results.
You know the results of this primary model which are nothing else in the world but see what I'm gonna
do.
I'm going to set this results variable as a list of the rules which will just put these rules into a
list right.
As simple as that we just want to have our rules into a list so that then when we display the results
you know by just calling this variable and executing this cell indeed we will get in the output.
All our rules in this list you recognize the square brackets here and at the end as well.
All right.
So all these rules are listed one by one you know in different rows.
So there you go.
These are all the rules you know all the rules following these criteria a minimum supportive or point
three percent minimum conference of open to a minimum list of three.
And of course two products in the rules you know one on the left and one on the right.
All right.
So let's have a look at them one by one starting with the first ones.
That's the first rule here.
And what do we see.
Well I'm just going to highlight it.
All right.
So that's the first rule.
So let's see first we see that the two products in this rule are like cream and chicken but be careful.
The order is not if customers buy like cream then they will buy chicken.
No it's actually the other way around.
Because indeed if we are cruel to the right.
Well that's important you see items Baz is equal to like cream and then items add is equal to chicken.
So that means that actually the left hand side of the rule is like cream and the right hand side of
the rule is chicken.
OK.
So that means that if people buy like cream then they will have a high chance to buy chicken and that
high chance is actually measured by the conference which is open 29 here.
So that means that if customers buy like cream then they will have 29 percent chance of buying chicken
which makes sense right.
Well at least in France because usually French people love to put some nice light cream with lemon as
a source for their chicken.
Right.
It's a common traditional French meal.
I actually really enjoyed myself.
All right.
And then we can also see the lift which is a very good one.
Four point eighty four.
I remind that all our rules here will have lift larger than three and then whereas the support the support
is right here the support is open Oh forty five.
Meaning that the rule containing these two products appears in open forty five percent of the transactions.
All right then let's see what we have.
So the second one Eskil up motion cream sauce.
But same the items Baz is mushroom cream sauce and the items add is escrow meaning that if customers
buy mushroom cream sauce and they will have a high chance of buying Escalade and that high chance is
30 percent right 30 percent and lift is three point seventy nine three point eight.
And the support is open 0 5.
OK good.
So you see you have all these rules.
They look great but we would actually appreciate a nice way to have a look at them because here you
see we have to do these crawls to the right and therefore it's a bit overwhelming so don't worry.
I actually found a good code snippet online I think was from Stack Overflow or another source like that.
So we're going to use that code snippet to actually put the results well organised into a this data
frame.
We won't have to re implement that code snippet from scratch because you know it is very specific to
this association rule learning implementation and therefore you will just see that once in your life.
So it's not essential and therefore we'll just copy and paste it here from our original implementation
but of course I will explain to you the code.
So let's get it first.
It's actually at the bottom and it is this one.
All right.
We make an inspect function which will return the rules meaning these rules well organized into this
data frame and the cool thing about this is that we will even be able to sort the rules by a descending
metric.
Right.
Because if we notice here.
Well they're not sorted.
You know the lift start at four point eighty four then goes down to three point seventy nine and then
goes back up to four point seven.
And here five point sixteen.
And remember that the lift is actually the most relevant metric to measure the strength of a rule you
know.
So if we want to store the rule you know to get the strongest one if we want to you know select a few
deals.
Well we would rather do it with the lift.
So what will be really nice here.
You know when putting these results into a well organized pendants data frame is that then we will be
able to sort easily the rules by the lift or another metric.
All right so let's get this function.
I'm going to copy it here and we will paste it inside are implementation right here there we go.
Paste.
And now let me explain to you how it works.
So as we can see it is a function that takes as input the results meaning these results.
The rules as they are right now you know organized this way and then it will take separately.
The left hand side of the room and in the product at the left hand side the rule then the product at
the right hand side of the rule then the support of all the rules then the competences the lives of
these rules.
And then it will return all the rules with the left hand side and the right hand side.
And there are supports confidences and lived inside the list right.
That's why we have this list function here again.
All right.
So that's what this inspect function will do.
And then at the end we create the final Panda's data frame which takes as input the output of this inspect
function.
And besides we add the column names you know the first column will be the left hand side of the rule.
The second column will be the right hand side of the rule.
The third column will be the support for the confidence.
And finally the lift.
So we will have a super nice table with these columns and giving all the important informations for
each of the rules.
OK.
So that will be super practical.
And now let me explain how you know we get each of these elements.
You know the left hand side and then the right hand side.
All right.
So the first thing to notice is that for loop inside a single row indeed we take the full list of all
the rules here.
You know that the full list of results and then for each of the rule in this full list of rules.
Well we're going to access each of these elements and take them separately.
And so let's start with left hand side.
How do we take that left hand side which is you know right here the items base frozen set like cream
basically light cream.
Well let's see.
So first we take the single rule you know let's say for example this one to explain how we're going
to get these elements.
So we take these rules and then in this rule we first access the index too.
All right.
So let's axis it step by step.
This element here you know up to the comma is the element of index 0.
Okay then this element is the element of index 1.
This is a second element and then this fool element you know up to the closing square brackets here
is actually the element of index 2.
All right.
So all I've highlighted here is the elements of index.
So now in that element of index 2 then we're going to access the element of index 0 meaning the first
element and the first element is actually the first element of that list.
You know in square brackets and that is of course all this you know ordered statistic up to be careful
you know up to the closing parenthesis here.
Meaning right here.
So all this is the first element inside that you know big element which I've just highlighted before
you know from all statistics up to actually the end.
All right so this is the element of index 0.
And then in this new element of index 0 we're going to access the first element of index 0 again.
And well you know we have to look inside this parenthesis and that's of course this element which is
indeed the left hand side.
Right.
Because this is what we want to get left inside item space.
That's the same.
And that is light cream.
And then for the right hand side that's the same.
You know we took the same first element of next to then that whole element of index zero inside this
first element of the next two.
And then instead of taking the index zero here we take the index 1 which is that element items add frozen
set chicken.
All right.
So that element is you know that element of next to then zero.
Then next one and then that index is to indeed catch what's inside you know chicken.
And same for that index zero here there was to catch light cream.
All right so you see we just play with the indexes to assess what we want but really you will only have
to do that once in your lives.
Don't worry too much about this kind of overwhelming code even if it's quite funny to you know follow
the indexes path to find the products but then the good news is that for the support is going to be
much simpler indeed.
We just need to take the full rule you know the single rule so you know this whole rule and then very
simply we access that element of index 1 directly.
So remember this full single rule well all this is the element of index 0.
And then all this is the element of index 1 and that's exactly the support which is what we want and
we do this for each of the rules in this whole list of rules.
Okay.
Then confidences once again it's a bit more complicated but just like before for us we get the element
of index too.
So let's take it again.
This is the element of index 0 then this is the element of the next one and then all this is the element
of index 2.
Okay.
Then inside this whole element of index 2.
Well we're going to access the element of index 0 which is let's take it again so we start from here
in the ordered statistic and then we go up to actually the closing parenthesis of here which should
be right here right.
Let's check the parenthesis here.
That's the first opening one.
Then the second opening one closing here.
Then this is a new opening one closing here and then there you go.
Okay.
So that's the closing parenthesis of indeed this element of index 2 then index 0.
And then inside this element.
Now we're going to get access to the element of index 2.
So that's the element of index 0 then that's the element of index 1.
And then finally that's the element of index.
And that's exactly the confidence which is what we want to get right now.
And then same for the lift.
So same same path for us we get access to the index to then zero so just like we were right now but
then instead of taking the index to like for the confidence we take the next one which is the index
3 and which corresponds to of course the left.
All right.
And that's how we get the lift.
So you see the idea just a game with the index is we assess the elements inside this whole complicated
list of rules but at least we will get a nice result in the end and really you don't have to worry too
much about this code is very unique very specific and you will probably not have to re-employment it
again in your life you can just take it you know I just took it online and indeed it is very practical
for what we're doing right now meaning association with learning.
Okay.
So good.
Now let's have a look at the beautiful result.
So we are going to play the cell first to you know build that inspect function and then create that
new data frame which I called results in data frame and which will contain the same rules here but better
organized and more beautifully organized let's say.
And so now we're going to create a new Kotel here just before this tech sell to first display the results
non sorted and to do this well we simply to call what we created here meaning results in data frame.
All right.
And then when pressing play you will see that we will get a very nice table containing all the rules
with the different elements in separate columns.
So that's the left hand side of the rule the right hand side of the rule.
And then the support of the rule the confidence of the rule and the lift of the rule.
So let's have a look at the rules one by one for the first one as we saw earlier.
If customers buy light cream then they will have actually twenty nine percent chance of buying chicken.
All right.
And this rule appears open four percent of the time you're not an open four percent of the transactions
and it has left a four point eighty four which is indeed very good.
Then the second rule if people buy mushroom cream sauce then they have a good chance at buying Asciano
and that good chance is 30 percent and it has a lift of three point seventy nine.
Pretty good still.
Then if people buy pasta then they will have a good chance of buying escalate up and that good chance
is actually pretty good indeed if customers buy pasta then they will have 30 percent chance of buying
scallop and the lift is four point seven.
Then check this out we have a good lift here for from us one honey.
Yes of course from us on honey is a delicious French dessert.
I actually really enjoyed that dessert is one of my favorites.
And indeed when you buy from each block as a French person you will definitely enjoy putting some honey
on it.
All right so indeed that's a great rule and I would definitely make this deal you know buy from Hezbollah
and get honey for free right because indeed the lift is five point sixteen so very very good.
Then Herb and pepper ground beef.
Yes of course French people or even you know other people from other nationalities love to put Herb
and pepper on ground beef this is actually exquisite.
And indeed we have a good confidence for that rule and actually well not that high of olives.
OK.
Then same for tomato sauce.
It's nice to put tomato sauce on ground beef.
The lift is still close to four light cream olive oil.
Well I don't really see that association but why not.
I'm not really a good cook but maybe there is a recipe where we can combine olive oil and light cream
not so sure about that.
But however this one is definitely something I would do whenever I buy whole wheat pasta.
I also get olive oil and indeed the left is pretty high and then passed and shrimps.
Yes that's a very good specialty of South of France especially near the coast French people of course
love mixing bass and shrimps all right and the left is 4.5.
So very good.
You see these are much better to observe but then we still don't have them solid which here is fine
because you know we don't have that many rules but in other situations you can end up with many more
rules and therefore you would like to sort them for example by descending lift because the lift is a
very relevant measure.
So I'm going to show you right now how to do this is very very simple things bend.
So let's create a new coat sail.
And here we're going to take again.
Well our new beautiful data frame results in data frame and now we're going to use a pre-built function
by the library to indeed sort the results of this data frame by a specific column which we're of course
going to specify here.
All right so let's do this.
To do this we need to add a dot here because we're going to call a specific method of the data frame
class you know because this results in data frame is actually an object of the data frame class by pendants.
And that method is called and largest.
There we go this one and inside we just have to enter three arguments as we can see here you know you
have all the info thanks to Google collapse of the three parameters are first and which has a number
of rows we want to return.
So I'll just put that as you know if I was doing a coat on plate I'll just put an equals 10 to you know
in general return the 10 best rules to an equals 10 then keep we will keep the default values you know
that's in case we have duplicates but that's fine for us.
I actually checked them and then columns.
All right.
So that's the other parameter I want to input here and that's of course you know to specify by which
column you want to have your results sorted.
All right so columns equals and well you know the most rather than metric is perhaps to lift.
So we're going to sort these rules by the left and to do this well we simply need to specify the lift
value in quotes for that columns parameter.
So in quote I'm going to enter here lift.
All right.
And that's it.
This is simply what you have to do in order to sort your rules by the column you want here.
Lift if you want to order them by conference which is also great.
You would just specify here in quotes confidence.
All right.
Let's try.
Let's play this cell.
And there we go.
Now we have indeed two rules sorted by the lift.
This is the highest lift five point sixteen down to the lowest lift three point eleven.
And so let's see well as I told you you know that very popular association especially for French people
they love to put honey in French Hezbollah.
Any time you go to a French restaurant you will see in the dessert menu.
Well from along with honey and even if you don't see it you can always ask the restaurant.
They always have honey not too far.
So that's definitely a very strong rule here.
And you know if I was the owner of the shop I would definitely make that deal buy from my blog and get
honey for free.
Then same.
This is the second strongest rule like cream chicken.
So another great deal would be if you buy like cream you will get chicken for free.
That's actually a very good deal.
But you know as I told you the owner can put some smart prices that you know would amount to a good
price for you know buying the two right but that's another story here we're doing.
Association rule not pricing strategy.
So there we go.
Let's move on to the next rule.
If people buy pasta then they will enjoy buying Escalade as well.
So a third great deal would be buy pasta and get as close for free and then same with best and shrimp.
Of course if you buy pasta you can get shrimps for free.
Then if you buy whole wheat pasta you can get olive oil for free.
You know these deals will be very attractive to the customers because indeed customers buy these association
of products.
OK.
All right.
There you go.
These rules you know for most of them actually makes sense.
And there you go my friends.
Congratulations.
You built your first association rule learning model to identify clear rules that will create some added
value to a retail business.
So your job is done.
Now you can enjoy the beautiful days of South of France after completing successfully this new data
science mission.