Hello and welcome to this tutorial.
Okay so we are halfway our data repossessing phase.
We learned how to import the libraries to import a data set.
We learned how to take care of missing data.
And today we're going to learn how to encode categorical data.
So the first thing that we're going to do is that we are going to explain why we need to do this.
So I'm gonna go to google sheets here to find my data set.
And in this data set we can see that we have two categorical variables.
We have the country variable here and the purchase is variable.
These two variables are categorical variables because simply they contain categories here the country
contains three categories.
It's France Spain and Germany and the purchase variable contains two categories.
Yes and no.
So that's why they're called categorical variables.
And now you can guess that since machine learning models are based on mathematical equations you can
intuitively understand that it would cause some problem if we keep the text here in the categorical
variables in the equations because we would only want numbers in the equations.
So that's why we need to encode the critical variables that is to encode the text that we have here
into numbers okay.
So in this tutorial we're going to encode these two variables country and poor chased and you're going
to see that the technique is quite different.
So here we on are we're going to use something very practical and are.
That is the factor function and the factor function will transform your categorical variables into Numeric
categories but it will see the variable as factors and you will be able to choose the labels of those
factors.
And due to the specific reason we will need to create three columns for each category we will just transform
the country column into a column of factors.
And we are going to specify what the factors are.
So let's do this.
Let's start by encoding the country column.
So we just need to take the column country and to do this we type data set $ country equals and then
we use the factor function factor and in factor we are going to specify three things.
So let's have a look at the fact a function to do this we click on F1.
OK.
So this contains some info about the factor function.
Let's look at the arguments the first argument is the data that we want to transform into factors.
So this is of course going to be our country column from our dataset.
OK then the second parameter is levels and that's the names of the categories in our country column.
So let's add here levels equals.
So we're gonna write the vector of levels here see parentheses and then we will input here are three
categories.
So that's France Spain and Germany.
All right.
So by the way C here is a vector and R so by creating this C France Spain Germany we are creating a
vector of three elements.
There is France Spain and Germany again.
The last argument that we need to input is labels because we want to choose which number we want to
give to France to Spain and to Germany.
So we're going to add here labels and then since we transform our country categorical variable into
factors we don't really care what numbers to use.
So let's use one for France to for Spain and 3 for Germany.
So this has nothing to do with my preference it's not because I'm French that I choose one for France.
It is absolutely non order related.
So it's just by default that I use one to three.
Okay so that's it.
We just I just forgot one parenthesis and I think this should disappear.
Yes.
Good.
Okay.
So the encoding of the country categorical variable is ready.
It's actually more simple than in Python.
So before selecting and executing this let's look at our dataset our dataset contains our country written
and text.
And now let's select this execute.
And now let's look at our data set.
Perfect.
Our country contains our encoded variable and as you can see one is France to Spain and 3 is Germany.
Okay so that's all good and now we need to do the same for the purchase column and it's exactly the
same we're going to use the factor function we're gonna transform the text category into numerical labels.
So let's do it right now.
We're going to copy this pasted here.
Here we're gonna replace country by pur chased.
All right.
Same for here.
Here we need to change the levels because there are new categories so the liberals are going to be no.
And yes.
OK.
And now of course we need to change the labels.
So we're gonna put 0 4 no and 1 for yes.
I think that's what actually makes sense and parenthesis again.
That's right.
Let's look at the data set the data set contains no one yes and the purchase column.
And now if I select this and execute the data set contains now 0 and 1.
Perfect.
We're all good.
We we are encoded or categorical data and are and now you know everything that there is to know about
encoding categorical data in Python and R so congratulations we almost did the most difficult part.
We are approaching soon the fun and exciting part about making models.
So we are almost there.
Hang on for one or two more tutorials and this is gonna get very exciting.
Thank you for watching this tutorial and I look forward to seeing you in the next tutorial.
Until then enjoy machine learning.