Okay my friends we have three steps left and the one we're about to implement is the confusion matrix
which is a simple to The Matrix you know two rows two columns which will show us the number of correct
predictions we did.
In both case you know predicting 0 or 1 and how many incorrect predictions we did in same both cases
0 0 1.
All right.
So that will be a nice way to see quickly where we did right and wrong and also in that same could sell
we will compute the accuracy.
And now.
Well at the end of the previous tutorial I actually asked you to try to figure it out on your own by
looking at the psychic learn API.
So that's exactly what we're gonna do first here.
I'm going to show you how to navigate it and find the information we want.
You know the tool that we need.
Let's go back to the welcoming page site.
Learn then remember you have to go to API here which contains all the classes and functions from the
different modules.
And I actually gave you a hint in the previous tutorial I told you to go to look into a module called
metrics remember.
So we just have to scroll down a bit here and we will find very soon metrics.
It's in the alphabetical order.
So there it is metrics and then it's very well organized as you can see have the regression metrics
in which we already covered the most important ones.
And the classification metrics.
And here we are of course dealing with classification.
Therefore you had to look into here and now we're getting closer we're getting warmer.
What do we see inside.
Well we actually see metrics confusion matrix and that's exactly what we'll take in order to build this
confusion matrix.
All right.
And then what I usually do is simply have a look at one of the examples because it usually contains
the code on how to build such a tool.
You know the computer matrix but I usually give you this example on some random values of dependent
variable vectors.
You know that's like why test you know the vector containing the real results.
That's why pred containing the vector of predictions.
And it tells you how to apply this confusion matrix function onto the vector of real results and effective
predictions.
Okay.
So in order to implement this well let's just take this so we can import indeed that confusion matrix
which belongs to the Matrix module from the second library.
So there we go.
Let's face it at first I just copied it.
Let's create a new code sell and paste this.
So that's how you import a computer matrix and then let's grab that other piece of code you know.
This particular line where indeed we apply the computer matrix function onto the vectors of predictions
and real results.
Let's base this.
So you see what I'm trying to do here.
I don't do this because I'm lazy.
I do this in order to train you to be independent.
You know whenever you need a new information or a new tool that you need and training you on how to
find it in the cycle learn API and I will do the same later on when we start working with tensor flow
you know in the deep learning part of this course part 8.
But.
So you see this is very important.
I really want you to be independent and figure things out on your own.
And now inside this computing matrix function what do we have to replace.
Well you know they called the vector here of real results y true but us since we actually want to distinguish
the vector of real results in the training set and to set well we actually called are y true vectors
let's say y trained for the training set and Y test for the test set.
So here since of course the confusion matrix is usually evaluated on the test set you know for new observations.
Here we have to replace y true by white test so that we will get indeed the confusion matrix showing
the correct predictions and the incorrect predictions for both cases 0 and 1 on the test set.
Great.
So we will actually put the output of this confusion matrix function applied to whiteness and white
bread into a new variable which we're going to call C M which stands for computing matrix and which
will be exactly the output returns by this confusion matrix function.
So there we go and then we'll add a final print c m in order to print indeed that confusion matrix.
Okay.
So these are the three lines of code that allow indeed to build that confusion matrix and print it.
And now remember that I also asked you to compute the accuracy and well to do this we just had to do
exactly the same as what we just did you know to find that information actually try to press pause on
the video and find it yourself if not already.
So we're going to go back to that matrix module.
You know remember the metrics module from the secondary library and we're going to look back into this
classification metric section to find the accuracy.
So according to you where is it.
Well it's hard to miss it.
This is actually the first one accuracy score which computes indeed the accuracy classification score
which is just you know the rate of correct predictions.
So let's do this.
Let's click this link and we will get indeed all the documentation on this accuracy score function which
returns the accuracy of your model on whatever set of data and will apply it of course to the test set.
So first of all here as we can see this accuracy score function belongs of course the same matrix module.
So we don't have to take all of this again we can just take that name of the function here and I will
show you what to do here.
Just next to confusion matrix you add a comma and then you can paste this other function you need you
know which you have to import still from that matrix module from the cyclone library.
OK.
So now we have it and now we can use it.
And therefore just below we will actually call it and in order to do this efficiently we can just take
the example here and right below we paste it and we just replace once again y true by Y test so that
we can get indeed the accuracy under test it.
Okay and here we don't have to do a print because this accuracy score will directly return that accuracy
and that rate of correct predictions.
So there you go.
We can just play this sound you know run the sail and here you go.
Congratulations you have here.
The confusion matrix showing that we have indeed 65 correct predictions of the class 0 meaning the customers
of the test who didn't buy the new SUV then 24.
Correct predictions of the class 1 meaning correct prediction that the customers who bought the SUV
and then three incorrect predictions of the class 1 meaning three incorrect predictions of the customers
who.
But in reality the SUV but were predicted not to.
And finally 8 incorrect predictions of the class 0 meaning 8 customers who in reality didn't buy the
SUV but were predicted to buy it.
OK.
So you see the confusion matrix has no mystery.
It's very easy to read and in a flashlight we can indeed get the main information of our predictions.
And finally that little number that we have here is of course the accuracy.
And here we get 0 point eighty nine which means that we had 89 percent of correct predictions in the
set and actually remember that they are 100 observations in a test which means that we had indeed 89
correct predictions actually 65 year plus 24 is equal indeed to 89.
All right.
But for any size of the test set this would mean that you had 89 percent of correct predictions and
that's exactly the accuracy the accuracy is the rate of correct predictions.
All right.
So now you know how to quickly evaluate a classification model.
You know the accuracy is usually the right metric to use when evaluating your classification models.
So now you have it in the tool kit.
And so here we go for final step of the journey.
We're going to visualize not only the training set results but also the test results.
And this will be super interesting because we will actually see how the logistic regression classifier
was actually trained to classify our customer as you know our observations in to the two different classes.
You know 0 0 1 we will have super nice results showing all the real results in both the training set
and a test set and also the prediction regions.
You know the regions where operations are zero and the other region where the predictions are one and
you will see that as a curve that separates these two regions is exactly the classification curve and
you will see that it will be a straight line for linear models and something else in a straight line
for non-linear models.
I really really can't wait to show you this because you will really see and visualize the difference
between linear classification models and non-linear classification models.
So there you go take a little break now and we'll tackle together this final step to visualize indeed
these two results.
And until then enjoy machine learning.