Hello my friends.
I hope you digested well the previous tutorial where we tackle this big but yet important tool of our
data repressing toolkit.
Indeed.
Now you know how to handle the case where you have some category called data in your data set which
is a situation you will encounter many times in your future mission or in Korea.
And now we have two tools to cover the first one being splitting the data set into the training set
and the test set and a second one being feature scaling.
So before we start I'm about to enter one of the most frequently asked questions in the data science
community which is be ready for it.
Do we have to apply feature scaling before splitting the dataset into the training set and to set or
after I've seen this question many times and you will find that question in many forums of the data
science community.
Some people will say that we have to apply features killing before it split.
Some people will say after the split and now I'm about to reveal the right answer there is only one
right answer which is by the way totally obvious.
After you get the explanation so the answer is we have to apply feature scaling.
After splitting the dataset into the training set and a test set and now let me explain.
So first just to make sure everybody understands.
Let me explain the what.
First and then I'll explain the why.
So of course splitting the dataset into the training set in a test consists of making two separate sets
one training set where you're going to train your missionary model on existing observations and one
test set where you're going to evaluate the performance of your model on new observations.
And it's important to understand that these new observations are exactly like you know some future data
that you're going to get and on which you're going to deploy your machine learning model.
All right.
So that's this first tool and now feature scaling simply consists of scaling all your variables or your
features actually to make sure they all take values in the same scale.
And we do this so as to prevent one feature to dominate the other which therefore would be neglected
by the machine learning model.
All right.
So that's the what for both of these tools.
Now let me explain the why we have to apply feature scaling after splitting the data set into the training
set and instead it's really obvious it is for the simple reason that the test set is supposed to be
a brand new set on which you are going to evaluate your machine learning model.
So it's exactly like you know you're training your machinery moral on your training set and then later
on you know after it is trained you are going to deploy it on new observations.
So what this means is that the test set is something you're not supposed to work with for the training
and features killing is as you will see a technique that will get the mean and standard deviation of
your feature.
You know in order to perform the scaling.
So if we apply feature scaling before the split then it will actually get the mean and standard deviation
of all the values including the ones in the test set and since the test set is something you're not
supposed to have you know like some future data in production.
Well you know applying pictures killing on the original day you said before the split would cause some
what we call information leakage on the test set.
You know we would grab some information from the test set which we're not supposed to get because it
is supposed to be new data with new observations.
So remember this the essential reason why you should not apply features scaling before the split is
to prevent information leakage on the test set which you're not supposed to have until the training
is done.
All right.
So I think I have explained enough.
Now I'm relieved and we're relieved that at least it's 100 percent clear for everyone.
And so there you go my friends.
Let's implement one of the last tools of this data processing toolkit which is indeed the split of the
data set into the training set and the test.
All right.
So how are we going to do this.
Well we're gonna do it with a function a function by psychic learn you know the most popular and useful
data science library because once again this library contains a module that is called model selection
which contains itself a function called trained test splits.
And this function will exactly do what we want which is to create four separate sets.
Actually not two but four because we will actually create a pair of matrix of features independent variable
for the training set and another pair of matrix of features and opinion been invaluable for the test
set.
All right so we're basically going to get four sets X strain which is a matrix of features of the training
set x test which is the matrix of features of the test set y train which is a dependent variable of
the set and white test which is a dependent variable of the test.
That's exactly what we want.
And now why do we want this.
While it's not us.
It's actually the future machine learning model that we will build in the next part which will be all
of them expecting this format as inputs you know for the training it will expect extra train and Y train
as inputs in a method actually called the fifth method and for the predictions also called inference
these models will predict x test.
All right.
So that's the reason it is simply the format expected by the future imaginary models.
And now let's get these four sets.
So we're gonna get them from Cyclone learn of course there you go from which we're going to get access
to model selection.
I really like Google collab.
And then from which we're going to import that train underscore tests clit function perfect.
You see how we can be so efficient thanks to the assistance of Google collab.
I hope you really like it as well.
All right.
So now that we have this functional Well we're going to use it.
And since we already know what this function will return as I've just explained.
Well let's create these four variables returned by this trend tested function.
And as we said they are first X train the matrix of features of the training set.
Therefore containing all the countries one hotel encoded ages and salaries of the training set so extreme
then accessed the matrix of features of the test set.
Then why train which is the dependent variable of the training set meaning all the poor chaste decisions
of the customers in the training set.
Why train and then why test which same content all the purchase decisions of the customers in the test.
All right.
So that's the four variables returned by this train tested function and since it is the function that
returns is variable Well let's take that function right away and let's add here and equals and train
test pit and then some parenthesis.
And now the question is what do we have to input inside this function.
All right.
So actually there are some parameters that we can guess right.
Because indeed this train test split is supposed to split something.
So one of the inputs will be that's something which we're about to split and which is of course our
data set.
However of course this function does not expect the data set as a whole.
It expects Well the combination of the matrix of Features X and that have been invaluable vector Y in
that the first two inputs of this function so let's input them here x4 as the matrix of features and
why the dependent variable vector.
Great.
Y yes then come up and then next arguments.
So we still have to input two more arguments which are going to be first the split size you know because
we're not going to split this dataset into a training set and a test of the same size.
Actually we need a lot of observations in a training set and a few in the test set but we need a lot
of them in the training set so as to give the future machinery model more chance to understand and learn
the correlations in the dataset.
So let me just tell you the recommended size of the split.
Well I recommend to have 80 percent observation in the training set and 20 percent in the test.
All right.
This is a very good split and therefore here we are going to input a new parameter which is test size
and we'll set that equal to 0 point 2.
Right.
20 percent observations will go into the test and therefore here since we have 10 observations in this
data set that means that eight observations will go into the training set many eight customers will
go into the training set and two in the test.
And this is not necessarily the last two you know they will be taken randomly but eight of them will
All right.
And now we'll add one final argument just for teaching purposes so that we can have the same results
displayed in here you know in the notebook because then I'm going to run some prints to show you these
four elements returned by this train test dysfunction you know the training set in the test set and
since there are some random factors there are going to happen during this split right because the observations
will be randomly split it into the training set in the test well to make sure we have the same random
factors will just at year random state equals one right we're just fixing the seat here so that we'll
get the same split and therefore the same training set and same tested.
All right.
And that's it.
Right.
This is the code to split the data set into the training set in a test.
Let me zoom out a bit so that you can see it.
All right.
So that's the full code.
This will return indeed.
These four new sets composed of the training set an extra and white train and a test set in excess and
white test.
Let me show you this right away.
So we're going to add four new code cells here right.
And we're going to print each of these created sets.
So first we're going to print x train.
Let me copy this.
Then we're going to print x test then we're going to print.
Why train.
And finally we're going to print why test.
Perfect.
All right so now let's execute everything starting with this cell here spreading the dataset into transit
and has it done.
Perfect.
Run successfully.
Now let's run the cell to print x train.
And as you can see indeed we have now eight observations industry and.
Right.
One two three four five six seven eight which correspond to eight customers taken randomly from this
data set and we clearly recognize the features here with first the three columns being the one hot encoded
variables that encode the country categorical variable we also call that dummy variables.
Then we clearly have here the age as the second variable as the second feature you know.
And then the salary.
So we clearly have a great matrix of features for the training set.
All right.
Perfect.
Now let's print access to we'll get here two observations containing the same features here as here
right.
This is the matrix of features still.
So we have the dummy variables here in the first three columns then the age and the two salaries of
our two customers taken randomly from the data set into this test set.
Then why train.
So here we'll get eight per chased decisions right with the zeros and ones here that were encoded before
with label encoder.
And of course make sure to understand this these eight per chased decisions correspond of course to
the eight same customers of this matrix of features extra in the training set right.
These features correspond to these purchase decisions.
These are the same customers here.
And finally why test which will output to result meaning to purchase decisions right 0 and 1 corresponding
of course to the same customers as in this matrix of features of the test.
All right.
So there you go.
Congratulations.
Now you have a new tool in your data processing tool kit splitting the data set into the training said
Ed said not only you have this tool but also you have the final answer to the ultimate question.
Do we have to apply feature scaling before or after the split and it's clearly after the split to avoid
indeed information leakage because simply the test set is supposed to be something you write something
on which we evaluate our model on you observations.
All right great.
So I'm glad that you are really making progress here with new tools and new knowledge that actually
reduce any kind of confusion.
So now we're going to move on to our final tool right feature scaling which now you know must be applied
after the split and you will see what we'll get with some other prints after we deploy this tool on
our data set.
So I can't wait to show this to you and I can't wait to give you this last final tool in your toolkit
because then what does it mean.
That means that we will be 100 percent ready to start building our future machine learning models.