Hello my friends and welcome to this new practical activity on multiple linear regression.
So in this new section we're going to learn together how to build a multiple in our regression model
on the same data set that was introduced by Carol in the previous lecturers.
And just before we start I just want to make sure that everyone here is on the same page.
This is the whole machine learning it is that folder containing all the code and data sets and right
before this or I give you again the link to this folder.
So make sure to connect to that link.
And now we should be on the same page ready to start this new machinery model which is of course in
part two regression and now we're going to go of course to multiple in our regression folder and we're
going to start with Python to implement this model.
All right.
So this is the data set and this is the Python implementation in IP Wendy format which you can either
open with Google collaboratively or Jupiter notebook.
Make sure you also have the folder downloaded on your machine so that you can indeed get these files.
All right.
So before we start implementation let me just explain again what this dataset is about.
So remember a venture capital is fund hired you as a data scientist to train a machine learning model
and actually a multiple in our regression model to understand the correlations between these features
which are the spend in R and D administration and marketing as well as the state and the profit of what
of 50 startups.
So in this dataset it's very important to understand that each row corresponds to a certain startup
and for each startup.
Well you data scientists collected the following data are bent administration spend marketing spend
and the state of these trips and of course their profit because the goal for this V.C. fund is to figure
out in which startup to invest based on these informations.
So these are all information that we already know from 50 startups.
And therefore if you managed to train a machinery model that can understand well these correlations
well for the next door app you'll be able to deploy this model on these features to predict what sort
of profit this new star might generate.
Okay.
So for this fund you definitely want to build an accurate model.
All right.
And now we can start the implementation but before we start I would like you to figure out what are
going to be the first steps of this implementation.
You know before I show it to you.
All right.
So first I hope that the first thing that came to your mind is that indeed the first step is the data
repricing phase.
And remember in a data pricing phase we start by empowering the libraries.
That's for sure.
Then we're going to import the data set that's even more for sure.
And then we will split the dataset between the training set and the test set because indeed we want
to train separately are moral and evaluate its performance on a separate test.
Okay.
So that's always required but then is there something else that we have to do here.
Well to answer this question let's have a look at the cons one by one starting with oranges.
So oranges spend is an American column you know containing numerical values.
And when we scroll down you know we can't scroll down because there are only 50 observations corresponding
to 50 strips and we can see that here there is no missing data.
So all good.
Then second column the administration spend all the spending administration like paying employees salaries
or anything else.
So this column is once again numerical with numerical values.
And there is once again no missing data.
Perfect.
So so far are three steps of the day would be pressing template argued the next one column in marketing
spend.
Well same numerical column with no missing data.
Oh good.
And now this column you know the last feature I noticed once again that all the features are in the
first columns and the dependent variable which you want to predict in the last column.
So back to this state's future what reflex Do you have in your mind now you should have the reflex if
you paid attention to parts one they would be pressing.
Basically the question I'm asking now is do we need to apply a certain tool of our data repressing toolkit
which would built in part 1 into this dataset.
Well here the answer is obviously yes.
Because indeed this state column is not numerical.
It actually has some categories it has three categories which are New York California and Florida.
And therefore that's exactly the same situation as in part one data processing.
There is no order relationship between these three states New York California and Florida.
And therefore we will have to apply one HUD encoding to that state column and therefore we'll have to
grab a tool of our data pricing toolkit.
And that's why I prepared it here in order to indeed one hot and cold that category called variable
the state variable.
All right.
And then the profit is fine.
It is numerical.
And besides there is once again no missing data.
So that's what you know you must do first.
You need to have a look at your data set.
If it is not too long you can check that there is no missing data.
Like we just did.
If it is too long then I recommend to apply your data pricing tool that handles missing data and deploy
it on this data set and then you must check if any feature is categorical.
And here we could check that very easily.
The state is getting a.
So we're going to apply our one hot encoding tool of our data repressing toolkit on the state column
and then of course we will apply all the rest of the three essential steps of our data processing template
and once again we will do that in a flashlight because this is a template where we only have one thing
to change which is the name of the dataset.
Are you ready.
Let's do this.
Let's start implementing are multiple linear regression model.
So I just double clicked on it if you like Google collaborate.
Feel free to open this link with me open with Google laboratory and if you don't like Google collaboratively
that's totally fine you can open this file with Jupiter no book but from your folder which you downloaded
on your machine.
All right.
Choose your favorite.
And here we go.
Let's implement are multiple in our regression model.
All right.
So first remember that this file is an read only mode which means that we can't modify it.
But no worries we're going to create a copy right away by going to file here and then click Save a copy
and drive.
This will as you can see create a copy in which we will be able to reemployment this multiple in our
regression mill from scratch because indeed I remind that this course is an action based course in which
I want you to take action as much as you can.
And therefore we are going to reemployment this whole model from scratch together step by step.
And I really want you to code with me at the same time so that you know the practical skill can really
be well integrated in your head.
OK.
So let's do this.
Let's first start by removing all the code sales here and only the code sales not the text sales because
I want to keep that well highlighted structure for this implementation.
So here I am just removing all the code sales.
There we go.
And perfect.
So this is the whole structure of this implementation we can have a look at it here.
And indeed that's why you know I wanted to brainstorm on the dataset with you first before showing you
the structure in order to make you think what we must do in the data repricing phase.
And as we said we need for us to import the libraries that import the data set.
That's for sure.
And then here we go.
We need to encode the categorical data and more specifically that state column which contains needs
three categories.
And then of course we split the dataset into the training center and test it.
That's a must.
And that will close the data repricing phase and we will all be ready to start training while first
building and and training the multiple in our regression model on the training set.
And by doing this our model will understand the correlations between all these bands of you know those
strips and they're generated profit.
And so there we go we will get a smart model which we will be able to use on new observations.
And that's exactly what we'll do as a last step here to predict the test that results.