Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
All right, so in the previous tutorials,
we took care of the data pre-processing phase,
the common data pre-processing phase for both,
our Boltzmann machines and our RBM coders,
because we're starting with the same data set,
but then to predict two different things.
Now we're going to predict
if the users are going to like, yes or no, a movie,
and in the next part with the (mumbles)
we will predict the exact ratings
given by the users to a movie.
So, from now, from this tutorial until the end of this part,
we will make what is specific to Boltzmann machines.
And so, the first thing that we have to do,
for what is specific to Boltzmann machines,
is to convert the ratings.
Because right now, we have ratings from one to five,
in our training set and test set.
Well, we have to convert these ratings into binary ratings.
One, that is liked, or zero, that is not liked.
And, so why do we have to convert these ratings?
Well, that's, of course, because we want to predict
some binary ratings.
Zero, if the user didn't like the movie
and one, if the user liked the movie.
But, why do we also need the inputs
to have the binary format zero or one?
Well, that's simply because,
the RBM will take the input vector,
and inside this input vector,
it will predict the ratings for the movies
that were not originally rated by the user.
But since these predicted ratings are computed,
originally, from the existing ratings of the input vector,
well, then the predicted ratings in the output
must have the same format
as the existing ratings in the input.
Otherwise, things would be inconsistent for the RBM.
All right.
So, let's convert all these ratings
into binary ratings, one or zero.
So, we have to do this
for both the training set and the test set.
So, we're gonna start with the training set.
And then, we'll just have to copy, paste
and do some Command + Ctrl + Replace
to replace everything in one shot.
So, let's start with the training set.
So, we have to take our training set.
And, first, what we're gonna do,
is replace all the zeroes in this original training set,
by minus one.
Why's that?
It's because all the zeroes in the original training set,
all the ratings that were not, actually, existent,
these corresponded to the movies
that were not rated by the users.
But now, since the ratings are gonna become zero and one,
well, the original zeroes, must now have another value.
And this new value that they're gonna have, is minus one.
Now, minus one will mean that there was not a rating
for a specific movie, given by a specific user.
So, let's do this.
To access to these original ratings
that were zero in the original data set,
well, we need to add some brackets
and inside these brackets, we simply need to add
the condition that we want to get these ratings.
And so, simply, we need to add
training set equals equals zero.
You know, this can be interpreted as
we want to take older values of the training set,
such that, the values of the training set
are equal to zero.
So, basically, we are taking
all the zero values of the training set.
And for all these zero values in the training set,
these zero ratings,
well what do we want to do?
We want to replace them by minus one.
And so now, all the zero ratings will become minus one.
All right, so that's the first thing done.
Now, we're gonna do the same for the other ratings,
that is, the ratings from one to five.
So, I'm going to copy this line,
because now, things are going to be very easy.
I'm going to paste it below.
And now, let's take care of the ratings
that we want to convert into zero, that is, not liked.
So, it would make sense to say
that the movies that are not liked by the users
are the movies that were given one star or two stars.
You know, if you give one star or two stars out of five,
then that means, you rather didn't like the movie.
So, that's the idea.
Now, unfortunately, the Or doesn't work with Torch.
You know, in Python we could have said
that training set equals equals one
or training set equals equals zero.
But, here, remember we are with some PyTorch tensors
and the Or operator doesn't work like that for PyTorch.
So, what we're gonna do is, just separate the two
that is, the ratings that were equal to one
and the ratings that were equal to two.
And we will both, convert them into zero,
because in our new ratings format
zero corresponds to the movies that the users didn't like.
So, here, we put zero instead of minus one.
And now, we're gonna do the same
for the ratings that were equal to two,
in the original training set.
So, two here.
So, with these two lines here,
well, all the ratings that were equal to one or to two,
in the original training set, will now be equal to zero.
So, that way, we convert all the ratings of the movies
that the users didn't like, into zero.
And so now, we simply need to do the same
for the movies that the users liked.
And again, it makes sense to say
that the movies that were rated at least three stars
were rather liked by the users.
So, three stars, four stars, five stars
are gonna become one.
And so, how can we access these three, four, five stars?
Well, we simply need to replace the double equal here
by larger and equals, to include, not two but three.
All right.
So, that means that all the values
in the training set that are larger than three,
three included,
will get the rating, one.
So, three, four, five, will become one, in the training set.
And that's it.
That will convert all our ratings into training sets,
as we should for our RBM.
We want the RBM to output the ratings in binary format,
zero or one,
so the inputs must have the same binary format,
zero or one.
All right. So, perfect.
Now, we have to do the same for the test set.
And so, what I'm gonna do, to be very efficient,
is copy all this, paste it here
and now, we're gonna do everything in one shot.
We're gonna take the last four lines,
press Command + Ctrl + R to replace.
And, so here, we're gonna take,
we're gonna remove all this.
We're gonna type training set
and we're gonna replace by test set.
And now, we just need to click several times here.
And, as you can see,
this replaces all the training sets by the test sets.
Perfect.
So, we can get rid of this.
And now, we have everything ready.
All the ratings from one to five
will be converted into binary ratings
in both the training set and the test set.
So, we're getting our inputs ready.
So, this is ready to be executed.
And so, I'm going to select this
and press Command + Ctrl + Enter to execute.
And now, our inputs are ready to go into the RBM,
so that the RBM can do its magic
and returns the ratings of the movies
that were not originally rated in the input vector.
So, that's Unsupervised Deep Learning,
and that's exactly how it works.
All right, so now, good news.
We can move onto the very exciting step.
That is the step where we build
the architecture of our neural network.
That is, the architecture of the RBM.
And so, we're gonna make a class.
For those of you who don't know what a class is yet,
well, don't worry,
this is all going to be very intuitive.
A class is just a model of something we want to build,
or, you know, some instructions of something we wanna build.
So, we will make this class,
which will define the architecture of the RBM.
And then, there is, simply,
we will create an object of this class,
and this object will be, nothing else than, the RBM model.
So, I can't wait to do this in the next tutorial.
And, until then, enjoy Deep Learning.