Hello, and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So, in the two previous tutorials,
we added three layers: the input layer,
the first hidden layer, and the second hidden layer,
and now in this tutorial we're gonna add the output layer.
So again, it's going to be very easy because
we only need to copy the previous line here
and paste it here, and now change a few things.
So try to guess what we are going to change,
it's pretty straightforward.
The first thing we need to change is of course,
the output din parameter, because of course
in our output layer we want only one node,
because our dependent variable is a category
called variable with a binary outcome,
zero if the customer stays in the bank,
and one if the customer leaves the bank,
and when we have a binary outcome
there is only one node in the output layer,
and therefore here we need to input
output din equals one.
So good, then we will keep this uniform
initialization method that is still
used to initialize the wait that comes
from the second hidden layer,
but moving on to the third argument,
well, if you remember what I said
in the previous tutorials,
we need to change the activation function here,
because right now we are in the output layer,
and since we are making a geodemographic
segmentation model, we want to have
probabilities for the outcome,
because we wanna have the probability
that each customer leaves the bank.
And so in order to get these probabilities,
we need to replace this activation function,
which is a rectifier activation function,
by the sigmoid activation function,
because remember in the logistic regression intuition
tutorial given by Carol in part three,
while the sigmoid function is the heart of this
probabilistic approach, and that is thanks
to the sigmoid function that we manage
to get some probabilities in the logistic regression model,
and that will actually be the same here,
if we choose a sigmoid activation function,
it's the exact same principle.
So here we're gonna replace relu, corresponding
to the rectifier function, by sigmoid,
and by the way if you are dealing
with a dependent variable that has more than two
categories, like say for example three categories,
then you will need to change two things here.
First is the output din parameter
that will be set as the number of classes,
because it will be based on the one viesol method,
while the dependent variable is one hot encoded,
so here you would need to input three,
if you have three categories for your dependent variable,
and the second thing that you would need to change
is the activation function, that in this situation
would be softmax, and softmax is actually
the sigmoid function, but applied
to a dependent variable that has more than two
categories, so just keep that in mind
if in your work you are dealing
with a dependent variable that has
more than two categories, like three or four
categories, you would need to choose the softmax function.
But here, we have two categories, two classes,
so we are fine with the sigmoid function,
exactly like for logistic regression.
Alright, so basically we are ready,
we are ready to add the output layer
that is eventually the final layer
of our neural network, that's pretty exciting,
that means that we are done building
the neural network, well then we'll need
to compile it, but basically we're done
adding all the different layers.
So let's do it, let's add the final layer,
the output layer, and so I'm going
to select this line and press command or control
plus enter to execute, here we go,
the output layer was successfully added.
Great, so now we are ready to move on
to the next step, which will be to compile
our artificial neural network,
that's going to be very easy as well,
since it will only take one line of code,
and so we'll do that in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy deep learning!