Hello and welcome this Python tutorial.
Okay, so far we've got our input of real ratings,
our target, which is the clone of the input
and we also got our output of predicted ratings.
And now the next step will be, again, about optimization.
That is optimizing the memory and the computations.
As you notice we have two variables
representing the same thing.
The input and the target,
because the target is a clone of the input.
And so, when we apply stochastic gradient descent,
we want to make sure the gradient is computed
only with respect to the input and not the target.
To do this, we will use this trick,
which will reduce the computations
and save up again some memory,
and that is target.
We take our target vector, then we add a dot,
and then we're gonna use require_grad
and we will set it equal to False.
This will make sure that we don't compute the gradient
with respect to the target and that will save
a lot of computations and that optimizes the code.
Alright, perfect.
And now, let's move on to the next step.
The next step is also about optimization.
That is, that's in the future computations
of the gradient and stochastic gradient descent,
we only want to include in the computations,
the non-zero values.
We don't wanna deal with the movies
that the user didn't rate,
where the ratings are equal to zero,
but that is only for the output vector.
The vector of predicted ratings.
What we're gonna add now is output,
that's our output vector of predicted ratings,
and now, remember we're gonna add this such as
which adds a condition exactly as we did here,
where we wanted to take our movies
such as the movies were rated by the user.
Now, the condition that we'll add is such as the target
is equal to zero.
That's exactly the same as in here.
We wanna take the values of our output vector
that is the predicted ratings in our output vector,
such as the corresponding ratings
in the target vector are equal to zero.
We're just taking the same indexes of the ratings
that were equal to zero in the input vector.
And for these indexes of the output vector,
we will set the values corresponding
to these indexes to zero.
Now question is, why are we allowed to do this?
Well, that's because these values will not count
in the computations of the error,
and so they won't have impact
on the updates of the different weights
right after having measured the error.
After we've measured the error, the weights are updated
by the RMSprop Optimizer and updating these weights require
some computations and in these computations,
these values here don't count.
Even if they're not equal to zero,
they don't count, and so,
to save up some memory, again, we set them to zero.
Okay, so perfect.
We have an even more optimized code,
so you will perfectly be able to use it
on larger data sets.
Okay, and now, next step.
In this next step we will eventually
compute the loss error.
We're gonna compute the loss,
and, actually this is going to be very easy,
because we already created a criterion object,
which we will use, of course, to compute the loss
and we will use it this way.
We first introduce a variable for the loss
that I'm calling loss and now we use
the subject criterion and this subject
takes two arguments that are very intuitive,
you can guess them.
It's basically the arguments you need to compute a loss.
So, that's, of course, the vector of real ratings,
that is the truth, and the vector of predicted ratings,
that is our predictions.
First argument, we're gonna input our vector
of predicted ratings, which is output,
and second argument is the vector of real ratings,
that is the truth, which is our target.
And that's all,
the loss is ready.
Next step.
In the next step, we're gonna introduce
a new variable that we're gonna call mean_corrector,
and this new variable will be equal to the number of movies
over the number of movies that have positive ratings.
Let's get this and then I'm going to explain.
The number of movies that have non-zero ratings,
we can get them this way.
We're gonna use first the float function
to make sure it's a float
and then inside this float function
we're gonna use torch, the module, then dot,
and to get a number of movies that
verifies a certain condition, we can use the sum function
that will count the movies that have non-zero ratings.
We're gonna use the sum here and inside the sum,
we're gonna input target.data,
larger than zero,
And that, exactly as here, we're considering all the movies
that have non-zero ratings.
And then I'm just going to add
a plus one times ten at the power of -10,
and according to you, why do we need to do that?
That's for a mathematical reason, it's very important.
This is a denominator, so we need to make sure
that this denominator is non-nil.
And that, even if we have this condition here.
That's very important to make it, any way,
never equal to zero and with this,
this will always be the case,
because this is always positive, because if by any chance
the denominator is equal to zero, well that will lead
to a pretty important error that has
an infinite computations that we really want to avoid.
I'm just adding this very, very small number here
that will not create any bias into this computation,
but that will make sure the denominator
is different than zero.
Okay, and now, why do we need to create this mean corrector?
Basically, try to think what this represents.
I'm gonna tell you right now.
This actually represents the average of the error,
but by only considering the movies that were rated,
the movies that at least got one to five ratings.
And that, we need to do this because we only considered here
the movies that have non-zero ratings.
Since then we will compute some mean,
this mean has to be computed
only on the movies that we consider.
That is, the movies that got non-zero ratings.
This mean correcter variable is just
to adapt to this consideration of the movies
that got non-zero ratings.
We need to do this because this will then be
mathematically relevant to compute the mean of the errors.
Okay, then, next step.
In this next step, we're gonna call
the backward method for the loss.
This call of the backward method will just tell
in which direction we need to update the different weights.
Do we need to increase the weight or decrease the weight?
That's what the backward method
will make sure of doing properly.
So, to use it we take our loss, then dot,
and then we use backward and then we just add backward.
Alright, so we're almost reaching the end.
We have a few steps left.
The next step is to compute the RMSE.
The next step is to update the train loss
that we initialized to zero here,
but you know after each observation going to the network,
this train loss is modified and therefore,
we need to update its value right now.
We're gonna update it, train loss
and I'm going to update it this way.
I'm gonna add a +, then an =, and that means
that we're incrementing it by something.
We're adding something to the original value of train loss,
which, so far, is zero.
So, basically what I'm adding here
will be the new value of train loss.
And then at the next round,
that is for the next user, the new value of train loss
will be the old value of train loss
plus what we're gonna add here.
So, what are we going to add here?
We're gonna take the loss that is generated
after the prediction was done.
That is basically the difference between
the real rating and the predicted rating.
And so to get this, we need to take our loss object,
then add a dot and now we're gonna get
the part of this loss object that contains the error.
We excess to the data in the loss object
and then we need to take the index of the data
that contains this train loss,
and this index is actually zero.
That's when we're gonna use our mean corrector,
because in order to get this adjusted mean over the movies
that got non-zero ratings by the user,
we need to multiply our loss here, by this adjustment factor
which is our mean corrector.
So, we're just adjusting this loss
with this mean corrector factor
to compute this relevant mean,
and then since this loss data is the squared error
and we want to get the state of the art error,
that is the one degree loss, we will take
the root of this loss.data.mean_corrector.
That is this adjusted square loss.
And so we're gonna use here NumPy.
It's been a while, but we still need NumPy
and that's because we wanna take
the square root function, which is S-Q-R-T.
Remember, we already used it,
so we're gonna put that in parentheses.
And that is just to get the state of the art error,
including that adjustment here.
Okay, and then that's almost over.
We now need to increment this s here
that corresponds to the number of users
who rated at least one movie,
and so if that's the case,
if this is the case for this user here,
that is if this user here rated one movie,
we need to increment s because we need
to keep track of the number of such users.
So, s and then to increment it by one that's the same,
we use += and then one point,
because remember we want s to be a float.
Okay then, almost the next step.
Sorry about that, it's quite long and technical,
but we're almost getting to the end.
This almost last step is to use the optimizer.
The optimizer that we created here,
because as you notice, we haven't used it yet
and, of course, we need it to update the weight.
I'm gonna explain right now the difference
between backward and optimizer.
You're gonna understand, it will be very clear.
First, let's use our optimizer.
We add optimizer,
then dot, and then to apply it,
we just need to use this method of the optimizer object
from the RMSprop clause, which is step.
That will just apply the optimizer to update the weights.
And now, what is the difference
between backward and optimizer step?
Well, backward decides the direction
to which the weight will be updated.
That is, will they be increased or decreased?
And optimizer step decides intensity of the updates.
That is, the amount by which the weights will be updated.
So, that decides the direction
and that decides the intensity, the amount.
Alright, and now, finally, the next step.
Actually, optimizer.step was the last step
of both the if condition and the first for loop,
so we're done with dealing with our observation,
taking care of all the actions
that happened into the network.
Now, we're getting back to this first loop here,
and so I'm back here to here, because here I'm outside
of this for loop and inside of this one.
Now, that's the last line of code of this training
and this last step consists of printing what's gonna happen
at each epoch, that is what we wanna see,
when the action will take place here in the console.
We wanna see the loss at each error,
and of course this epoch where we're at.
So, let's do this.
We're gonna use the print function.
Let's say that we first want this train epoch,
colon, space.
That's just a string that will appear all the time.
And then, after this epoch and string,
we add the number of the epoch where we're at,
and this, we get this with +str.
So, str is a function to make the epoch a string.
Now, we need to get the epoch where we're at,
which is given by this epoch variable in the loop.
Since we're still in the for loop,
we can add this and that epoch.
Alright.
And then + and then we add some new quotes,
because then we would like the loss,
with colon and space again.
After this loss we'll add the value of the train loss.
And that is +, so we're gonna convert that
into a string again and inside the parentheses,
we input the value of the train loss, which is train_loss.
Since we want the average, we divide this train loss by s,
the number of observations that we considered in all this.
That is in all these computations,
and these are the number of movies
that got at least one non-zero rating.
That is given, of course, by s,
that we made sure to increment here.
So, we add here s.
And here we go, that's ready!
Alright, congratulations,
because this was actually pretty technical.
But the good news is that now you don't even
have to take care about this,
and if you wanna build an autoencoder model
for one of your problem, whether it is a recommended system,
or anything else, well you just
have to change the architecture here.
And maybe if you wanna try
some other combinations of activation functions.
That's all.
You don't have to worry about this,
except maybe trying different number of epochs,
but in that case you just need
to change the number of epochs here.
Since we're getting close to the 20 minutes
where we will see action taking place in the next tutorial.
That is, we're gonna see the 200 epoch going on,
and we will see how the RMSE evolves,
and mostly what we'll get in the end.
So, this is definitely going to be the exciting tutorial
of this section, and I can't wait to see you there.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.