Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
And congratulations for making it to Volume Two
unsupervised deep learning.
So today we will implement our very first unsupervised deep
learning model, which is the self organizing map.
And we will implement this model to solve a new kind of
business problem, which is fraud detection.
So this business problem goes this way.
Let's imagine we are deep learning scientists
working for a bank and we are given a data set
that contains information of customers from this bank
applying for an advanced credit card.
So basically, these informations are the data that customers
had to provide when filling the application form.
And our mission, is to detect potential fraud
within these applications.
So that means that by the end of the mission,
we have to give the explicit list,
of the customers who potentially cheated.
So our goal is very explicit, we have to return something
however, to return this something, that is the list of
potential fraudulent customers,
we will not make a supervised deep learning model
and try to predict if each customer potentially cheated,
yes or no, you know, with a dependent variable
that has binary values.
No, this is not what we're gonna do.
What we're gonna do is unsupervised deep learning,
which means that we will identify some patterns
in a high dimensional data sets
full of nonlinear relationships.
And one of these patterns will be the potential fraud.
That is the customers who potentially cheated.
So to understand better now what we're gonna do is to import
the data set, so that you understand clearly,
what those patterns are.
So let's go to File Explorer.
And let's go to the right working directory folder.
So deep learning A to Z Volume Two
unsupervised deep learning
and now we are in the first part of Volume Two part four
self organizing maps.
By the way self organizing maps is the simplest
unsupervised deep learning model we'll
implement in this Volume Two.
So that's why I put it first and then after will have these
very powerful deep learning models
that we will use to implement a recommended system.
But for now let's make a fraud detector.
And so we'll go to Part Four and section 16 building an SOM.
Alright, so the data set that contains these applications
for the advanced credit card is this one,
credit card applications that CSV,
so we're gonna start this mission by
importing this data set.
But before let's set the right folder as working directory
that is this folder.
And so we click on this tool button here,
and set console working directory.
Now everything's fine,
I will explain afterwards what are these two Python files.
All right, so two important data sets,
first let's import the libraries, the essential libraries to
implement model and now let's import the credit card
application status set.
So as usual, we'll call our data set data set equals then
pd.read_csv and in parentheses and in quotes.
we input the name of the data set which is
credits_card_applications.csv.
Alright, perfect, so now let's select this line
and import it.
Well import it, let's go to variable explorer
and let's open it,
So first this data set is taken from the
UCI Machine Learning Repository,
it is called the Statlog Australian Credit
Approval Data Set, and it is available at this address here.
So first, let's see the basic information
about this data set,
so this file concerns credit card applications,
all attribute names and values has been changed to
meaningless symbols to protect confidentiality of the data.
Okay, so that makes this problem even more complex
and difficult to solve for human,
indeed when we see the data set,
we feel totally incapable of detecting any fraud.
So we clearly need a deep learning model
to find the cheaters,
and then we have some attributes informations here.
Basically, the independent variables
are some categorical and continuous independent variables.
And inside all these variables are hidden SOM frauds
that we have to detect.
Okay, so let's go back to Python and let's make the link
between this data set and what I've just explained to you.
So the first thing important to understand here is that
the columns are the attributes,
that is the informations of the customers.
And the lines are the customers.
For example, this line seven here corresponds
to one customer.
And when I said earlier that the unsupervised deep learning
model is going to identify some patterns.
Well, by patterns, I mean customers,
so it's going to do some kind of customer segmentation
to identify segments of customers
and one of the segments will contain the customers that
potentially cheated.
So after having seen intuition lectures made Kirill,
can you try to guess what this segment is going to
be on the self organizing map.
It will actually be very explicit,
it corresponds to one specific range of values
in the self organizing map.
So try to think about it,
I'm going to provide a solution very soon.
Now let's go deeper into the details of what
this first unsupervised deep learning model
is going to do, with all these customers.
So first of all, all these customers are the input,
these customers are the inputs of our neural network.
And then what happens is that these input points
are going to be mapped to a new output space.
And between the input space and the output space,
we have this neural network composed of neurons,
each neuron being initialized as a vector of weights
that is the same size as the vector of customer
that is a vector of 15 elements,
because we have the customer ID plus 14 attributes.
And so for each observation point that is for each customer,
the output of this customer, will be the neuron
that is the closest to the customer.
So basically, in the network, we pick the neuron
And remember, this neuron is called the winning node,
for each customer, the winning node is the most similar
neuron to the customer, then, you know,
we use a neighborhood function like
the galch neighborhood function,
to update the weight of the neighbors of the winning node
to move them closer to the point.
And we do this for all the customers in the input space.
And we'll repeat that again.
We'll repeat all this many times.
And each time we'll repeat it, the output space decreases
and loses dimensions.
It reduces its dimension little by little.
And then it reaches a point where the neighborhood
stops decreasing, where the output space stops decreasing.
And that's the moment where we obtained our
self organizing map in two dimensions
with all the winning nodes that were eventually identified.
And so now we're getting closer to the frauds.
Because indeed, when we think about frauds,
we think about outliers because the fraud basicly is defined
by something that is far from the general rules.
The rules that must be respected when
applying to the credit card.
So the frauds are actually the outlying neurons
in this two dimensional self organizing map,
simply because the outline neurons are far from the majority
of neurons that follow the rules.
And so now the question is,
how can we detect the outline neurons
in the self organizing map?
Well, for this, we need the MID,
the Mean Interneuron Distance.
That means that in our self organizing map for each neuron,
we're going to compute the mean of the Euclidean distance
between this neuron and the neurons in its neighborhood.
And so what neighborhood is that?
Well, we have to define it manually.
But we define a neighborhood for each neuron.
And we compute the mean of the Euclidean distance
between this neuron that we picked
and all the neurons in the neighborhood that we defined.
And by doing that we can detect outliers,
because outliers will be far from all the neurons
in its neighborhood.
And so this is this exact information that we'll get
on the self organizing map at the end of this part
that will allow us to detect outliers,
and therefore, to detect fraud.
And then we'll use an inverse mapping function
to identify which customers originally in the input space
are associated to this winning node, that is an outlier.
Alright, so the mystery is solved.
Now let's implement all this.
So I'm gonna close the data set here.
And we just need to do something now
is to split the data sets into two subsets,
the sets that contain all the variables from customer ID
to attribute number 14,
and the class that is the variable that tells if yes or no
the application of the customer was approved.
So zero is no, the application was not approved.
And one means yes, the application was approved.
And so we want to separate all these variables here
and the variable class here,
so that's on the self organizing map,
we can clearly distinguish the customers who weren't
approved their application
and the customers who got approval,
because then that will be useful, for example,
if we want to detect in priority, the fraudulent customers
who got their applications approved,
that would make more sense.
And therefore, now we're gonna do is
create those two subsets.
So we're gonna call the first one X.
So x equals dataset.iloc to get the indexes
of the observations we want to include an X,
and so we start with the indexes of the lines.
And since we want all the lines,
because we want all the customers
we're gonna use the column here, then come up
and then remember we want all the columns
except the last one, so we use here Colon minus one.
And then as usual, that values which will return
all the observations indexed by these indexes here.
Alright, perfect now, let's create the last column.
Let's call it Y, here we can take that again
and we'll just change the index, right?
And so here remember the trick to take the last column well,
we just need to take minus one.
Alright, so now let's select these two lines
and execute, and now x and y are created.
We can check x contains all the variables
except the last one, and y contains the last variable
that tells if yes or no, the application was approved.
So now there is an important point to make,
we splited our data sets into x and y.
But be careful we did not do that because we're doing
some supervised learning, we're not trying to make a model
that will predict zero or one in the end.
We're just doing this to make the distinction in the end
between the customers who were approved
and the customers who were not approved.
You will see that when we train our self organizing map
we will only use x because we are doing some
unsupervised deep learning,
that means that no dependent variable is considered.
Alright, so it's important to make that clear
and now just before we train our self organizing map,
we just need to do one more thing,
its feature scaling because, you know, most of the time
feature scaling is compulsory for deep learning
for that simple reason that they're high computations
to make because we're starting with
a high dimensional data set,
with lots of nonlinear relationships.
And so it will be much easier for our deep learning model
to be trained if the features are scaled.
So let's do that quickly.
We're actually going to do the same as
for regular neural networks, we will use normalization
that means that we'll get all our features
between zero and one.
So let's do this, Remember, we need to import
the MinMaxScaler class from a sklearn.preprocessing,
here it is, import MinMaxScaler.
All right, then we create an object of this class
that we call SC equals MinMmaxScaler
and inside this class well,
let's inspect it here, it is MinMaxScaler
the parameters our first feature range
so feature range here,
equals then in parentheses we specify that we want the
range of our scales features between zero and one
that's normalization
and that's all, we don't need this copy parameter,
we got everything we need with this feature range parameter.
So now as we gotta do is first fit this SC object to x,
so that SC gets all the informations of x like the minimum,
the maximum, well all the informations that it needs
to apply normalization to x.
So we finished first sc.fit
and remember after this object is fitted to x.
Well, we need of course, to transform x
that is to apply normalization to x
and therefore we use here to fit transform
method that we apply to x.
So you know this and therefore since the fit transform
method returns, the normalized version of x.
Well, we need to add here x equals and sc.fit_transform(x).
Alright, so that's will do the normalization
it's ready to execute.
Select like this and execute, perfect.
Now if we look at x well you can see that x is
all normalized, can indeed check that all the values
are between zero and one.
So perfect, now our first unsupervised deep learning model
will be able to learn in the best conditions.
And speaking of learning,
that's exactly what will happen in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.