Hello, and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So in the previous tutorial, we pre-processed
our data to make it ready for our model,
and therefore today we can start fitting
logistic regression to our training set
and that's what we're going to do in this tutorial.
So as usual, let's import the correct library for that job,
which is gonna be the linear model library.
And why linear?
It's because logistic regression is a linear classifier,
which means that here, since we're in two dimensions,
our two categories of users are gonna be separated
by a straight line.
So you're gonna see your intuition of logistic regression
is even going to be better shaped when you will find
out about the graphic results.
So let's import this library by typing
from S-K learn
dot linear model,
that's the name of the library, here it is.
Okay, and then import, we're gonna import the right class
for it, which is the Logistic
Regression class.
Once again, a very intuitive name, we like it.
And then, as usual, we are going to create an object
from this class, which is gonna be our classifier
that we're going to fit on our training set.
So let's do it.
I'm going to create a new variable classifier,
which is actually our logistic regression object.
And to create this object, I'm gonna call the class
Logistic Regression,
and here we go.
The logistic regression class has several parameters,
we can check them by inspecting the logistic regression
class, we type command I, to inspect the class,
here we go.
As you can see, there is several parameters,
but we're not going to use any of them, we're only gonna use
the RandomState parameter here,
just to have the same results.
So here, I'm gonna input random state equals zero,
so that we all get the same results.
Alright, so our logistic regression object is ready
and now I'm gonna take it, classifier,
and I'm going to fit it to the training set.
And to do this, I'm gonna use this method here, which is
the fit method to fit it to our training set.
Okay, so Enter fit, and then we want to fit it to our
training set, so here, we input x train
and y train,
because remember, what this means is that we're taking
our logistic regression classifier object,
we're fitting it to the training set, x train and y train
so that our classifier learns the correlations between
x train and y train.
Then by learning those correlations, he will be able to use
what he learns to predict new observations.
And we're gonna test it's predictive power on a different
set, which is gonna be the test set.
And that's what we're gonna do in the next tutorial,
so I'm just going to select here
this, command and control plus enter to execute.
And here we go, now our logistic regression model is fitted
to the training set.
Okay, so that's perfect and now in the next tutorial,
we will be predicting the test set results with this
logistic regression model.
So I look forward to seeing you there and until then,
enjoy Machine Learning.