Hello and welcome to this tutorial.
In the previous tutorials we learned
how to import the libraries and to import a dataset
and now we are finally going to start preparing the data
so that our machine learning models run correctly.
And the first problem that we have to deal with
is the case where you have some missing data
in your dataset.
And that happens quite a lot actually in real life,
so you have to get the trick to handle this problem
and make it all good for your machine learning model
to run correctly.
So, let's have a look at the dataset.
So, here is the dataset
and as you can see, there is two missing data.
There is one missing data in the Age column here
for Spain and one missing data
in the Salary column for Germany.
So, how can we handle this problem?
Well, a first idea is to remove the lines,
the observations where there is some missing data,
so what we could do is to remove this line
and remove this line
but that can be quite dangerous
because imagine this dataset contains crucial information,
it would be quite dangerous to remove an observation,
so we need to figure out a better idea
to handle this problem
and another idea and that's actually the most common idea
to handle missing data
is to take the mean of the columns.
So, here we are going to replace this missing data here
by the mean of all the values in the column Age
and that's the same for every feature
that contains missing data.
We replace this missing data by the mean of the values
in the column that contains this missing data.
So, as usual, we are gonna take a library
to do this job for us.
We're not going to implement a function mean ourself.
We will make it as simplest as possible,
so the library that we're going to use for this one
is called scikit-learn preprocessing
and from this slide we're going to import
the Imputer class.
So, let's do this.
So, to import this library in Python,
we need to type from sklearn dot
and then preprocessing,
here it is,
import Imputer.
So, I'll just explain what this is.
So, sklearn is scikit-learn actually
and it contains amazing libraries
to make machine learning models
and from scikit-learn we import this preprocessing library
that contains a lot of classes, methods
to preprocess any datasets,
that is exactly what we're doing right now
and from this library we're importing the Imputer class
which will allow us to take care of those missing data.
And now, now that we imported the class,
we now need to create an object of the class.
So, to create this object,
we are going to start giving a name to this object
and we're gonna call it imputer, let's make things simple.
Imputer equals and now we're gonna call the class
that we just imported which is Imputer with capital I
and then now a good thing to do
is to press Command + I to see the Object Inspector here.
Command + I is like Command + Inspect,
so we're inspecting the Imputer here
to get some info about this class
and see what parameters we have to input.
So, here we have the parameters
and the first parameter is missing_values.
So, in parenthesis we're gonna input missing_values
and so, for missing_values,
we are going to choose NaN and why is that?
It's because when we go to our dataset
in Variable Explorer here and go to Dataset,
we can see that the missing values are called NaN,
so by putting NaN here with capital Ns actually,
it will recognize the missing values to take care of.
So, let's press OK.
Now, what is the next parameter?
The next parameter is strategy,
so that's good, let's add strategy here
equals and what strategy are we going to use?
Of course we are gonna use the mean strategy
because we're gonna replace missing values
by the mean of the column,
so let's choose here mean.
Mean and actually mean is the default value
for the strategy parameter,
so we wouldn't need to input strategy equals mean
but let's put it anyway to understand
what we are doing.
And then what is the next parameter?
The next parameter is axis,
so if axis equals zero,
that means that we're taking the mean of the columns
and if axis equals one,
that means that we are taking the means of the rows.
So, if course it makes much more sense
to take the means of the columns
because it's the mean of the feature,
so course we're gonna choose axis equals zero.
Good and we're not going to take care
of the rest of the parameters, they're not important.
We have the essential parameters here
and we're ready to go to the next step
which is to fit this Imputer object
to our data x, to our matrix of features x.
So, that's what we are going to do right now.
So, to fit this Imputer object to our matrix
of feature x, we need to do this,
we are gonna type imputer.fit,
you see it's quite intuitive,
and then in fit of course we are gonna input
what we want to fit the imputer to
which is x of course.
However, we are not going to fit the imputer
on the total matrix,
let's have a look at the matrix again.
The matrix is here as you can see
and we're not going to fit the imputer to all the matrix,
we are only going to fit it to the columns
where there is some missing data.
So, here we're going to add some brackets,
brackets here and as usual,
we want to take the whole columns,
so we will take all the lines
by putting column here, then comma
and then here that's where we're going to choose
the right column, that means the column
that contains missing data.
So, this column here is the second column
and the third column,
that is the age column and the salary column.
So, we need to put the indexes of this second
and third column and do you remember
what indexes we have to use?
Indexes in Python start at zero,
so this column here has index one
and not two and this column here has index two.
So, here to input those two indexes,
we're gonna type one column
and sorry about that guys,
it's not gonna be two here, it's gonna be three
and the reason for that is that the upper bound is excluded.
By putting one column three here,
that means that we're taking indexes one and two
but the lower bound one is included,
so you just have to get used to this syntax in Python
and you will soon be much more comfortable
but for now, I agree that it's sometimes quite confusing
but that's how it is.
X taking all the lines and columns one and two,
indexes one and two
and so, you can use imputer.fit this way
or you can also use imputer equals imputer.fit.
That will work the same.
You will get the same thing.
That's all to fit the imputer object to our matrix x
and now we just need to do one last thing
which is to replace the missing data
of the matrix x by the mean of the column.
So, to do this, we need to do X bracket,
then we need to select the columns
where there is some missing data,
so as usual, colon to take all the line,
then comma and then the same we need to take the two indexes
of the columns that contain missing data
which are indexes one and two,
so here, it's the same as here,
we type 1:3
equals and then we're gonna use our object imputer
and we are going to apply the method
of the imputer object which is transform,
so here the transform method is here
and this is the method that is going to replace
the missing data by the mean of the column
and here what we only have to do
is to take the two columns of the data X
and put it in the parenthesis here and that's it.
That's how you take care of missing data with Python.
So, now we are going to select this block of code,
execute, all good,
you can see that the code ran properly
and now let's look at X
and let's see what happens.
X, enter, great the missing data
were replaced by the mean,
the salary that was missing was replaced
by $63,777 and the age that was missing
was replaced by 38.7 years old.
And let's check that.
Let's check if it's the right values.
So, the first missing value
was the salary here, so let's compute the average,
so we have to type equals average, here it is,
we take all the observations of the Salary column,
parenthesis, Enter and here's the average,
so it's 63,777.
Let's check in Python.
Yep, here it is, it's the right value.
It's the mean, so it was replaced correctly
and now let's check it for the age.
Let's remember 38 years old .7.
Let's compute the average here, equals average.
Here we take all the values,
parenthesis and 38.7, all good.
That's perfect.
So, congratulations, now you know
how to take care of missing data in Python.
You can have fun and try to use another strategy,
for example, you can take,
let's go back to the Object Inspector,
you can take the median strategy
which will replace your missing value by the median
of the column or you can take the most_frequent value
of the column which could also be a good idea
depending on the context.
That's the end of this tutorial.
And I look forward to seeing you in the next tutorial.
The next tutorial will be about categorical data,
so we will learn how to encode categorical data.
You will understand why we have to do this,
so I look forward to seeing you in the next tutorial
and until then, enjoy machine learning.