Multiple linear regression,
same thing but many variables.
So B, zero one constant and then,
many combinations or many pairs of
B and X,
and it can go up to quite a lot.
Depends on how many regressions you have.
Here once again you got a dependent variable, Y
So something you are explaining,
but this time the difference is that,
you think there might be a few causation here so,
in the case of salary for instance it could be,
how many years of experience you've done?
How many other courses you've done?
How much, you know?
How much time you spend at work.
Or, things like that,
or how valuable, how much money you make for the company?
In terms of a student and his grade so if your dependent
variable is what grade does a student get?
Then the independent variables could be,
how much the student has studied for the exam?
Maybe how much he has slept before the exam?
How many lectures he has attended throughout the course?
And things like that.
The constant is still there
and also you got the coefficients.