Hello and welcome back
to the course on deep learning.
I hope you enjoyed the introduction into RNNs
and today right away off the bat we're going to jump
into a huge problem that exists with RNNs.
All right, so, what is this problem
called the vanishing gradient?
It was first discovered by Sepp Hochreiter
and I hope I'm pronouncing that right.
I know we have students from Germany,
so, you can comment if the pronunciation is incorrect,
but he, Sepp or Josef is his full, is a genius scientist
who back in the '90s while he was still,
you know, not a professor.
This is recent photo, so he was much younger
when he actually came up with this concept.
He found that there was a big, big problem,
and we'll talk about the problem itself just now.
I just wanted to point out who are the people
that spotted this, and basically as you'll learn
from the further tutorials Sepp is one
of the founding people in the modern
way that we use RNNs and LSTMs
and we'll talk about that further down,
but this is Sepp Hochreiter.
So, I just wanted to make sure you know
who is behind all this.
And the second person is Yoshua Bengio.
He's a professor at the University of Montreal.
He also discovered that this, this problem,
I think a bit later in 1994.
So, Sepp was, discovered this in 1991.
Yoshua wrote about this in 1994, but again,
this is another person driving this whole,
pushing the envelope in the space of RNNs
and if you go to the University of Montreal
and you look up Yoshua's profile you will find
that Yoshua has over 500 research papers,
and by the way there's Yoshua Bengio
just hanging out with (mumbles).
As you can see, they all know each other.
It's a very tight knit community,
and it does sound like a conspiracy,
these people that are driving or pushing the envelope
in terms of deep learning.
These are just a select group of people
who are all, all in it together.
They all know what's going on.
They've all been doing it since the '80s or '90s
and now it's all popping out into the world.
So, there you go.
That's just to give you a quick idea
of who's behind all of this, and today,
and now we're proceeding to the vanishing
gradient problem itself.
So, as you remember, this is the gradient descent algorithm.
We're trying to find the global minimum
of your cost function, and that's gonna be
the optimal solution, optimal setup
for your neural network.
As you also recall, your gradient,
or your information travels through your neural network
to your answer, to get your output,
and then the error is calculated
and is propagated back through the network
to update the weights.
And here we've got some weights written out.
So, what happens in a recurrent neural network
is a similar thing, but here you've got
a bit more going on, right?
So, when your information travels through the network
it travels like that.
You've got lots of, it travels through time
and information from previous time points goes,
keeps coming through the network,
and remember that every node here,
it's always very important to remember
for neural networks that every single node here
is not just a node, it's a representation
of a whole layer of nodes.
Remember, we were looking at from,
from the top or from the bottom.
They are, they actually extend through this chart
down there into this presentation.
You can (mumbles), there's lots more
neurons behind the ones that we can actually see
because each one represents a layer.
Very important to remember that.
And so, at each point in time you can calculate
your cost function, or your error.
So, basically your cost function compares your output
which is in the red circle to your desired output,
to what you should be getting, and this happens
during the training.
And so, and you have these values for,
throughout the time series.
So, for every single one of these red circles
you can calculate the cost function,
and let's focus on one, just to understand
what's going on.
Let's focus on this one specifically at time T.
So you've calculated the cost function epsilon T
and now you want to propagate your cost function back
through the network.
Well, how is this going to look?
Because you need to update the weight.
So, every single neuron which participated
in the calculation of the output associated
with this cost function should be,
should have their weight updated to,
in order to help it better calculate the output,
to minimize that error.
And the thing here is that it's not just the neurons in,
directly below epsilon T, directly below this red circle.
It's all the neurons that contributed,
and there's many more of them.
There's all of these neurons as far back as you go.
Depending on how many time steps you take,
you might take one time step, you might take two,
you might take 50 time steps, depending on how
you set up your network, and this is where
the problem lies, that you have to update
or you have to propagate all the way back
through time to these neurons.
And when we talk about time it's not that
the problem is that we can't travel through time.
Not at all.
We've unraveled this network, so this whole propagation
can be facilitated.
The problem lies in something else,
and as much as I don't like putting math
on the slides, on the intuition slides,
we're not gonna go through this math,
but I will point out one thing here.
So, this is the math behind RNNs
and we'll definitely direct you to more additional reading
which you can do to up-skill on all of these maths.
So, here we've got W rec, and W rec stands
for weight recurring, and that is the weight that is used
to connect the hidden layers to themselves
in the unrolled temporal loop.
And as you can see here on the left your,
in order to get from X T minus three from this
layer, remember, this is a layer, to X T minus two
you need to apply W rec.
Then from here to here apply W rec,
and in simple terms, and intuitive terms
what you're doing is you're simply multiplying
the values here as you remember to get from layer
to the next.
We multiply the output by the weight,
and then we get to the next layer,
and then we multiply the output by the weight
and get to the next, and then we multiply
the output from here by the weight you get here,
and the thing here is that we're multiplying
by the same exact weight multiple times,
many times, as many times as we need to go through
this temporal loop, and this can be set.
This, you can set this in your network.
Do you wanna do it once?
Do you wanna look back one step?
Do you wanna look back three steps?
Do you wanna look back 50 steps?
But as many times as we do it,
we have to multiply by the weight.
And this is where the problem arises,
because when you multiply by something small
your value decreases very quickly,
and this, the multiplication comes from this P here.
You can see that P is, stands for multiplication.
So, we have to multiply, and that's what it's representing,
that as far as you go back you multiply,
and as you remember weights are
assigned at the start of your neural network.
As you see in the practical tutorials
your weights are assigned at a random value,
but random values close to zero,
and from there the network trains them up
and identifies what they should be.
But if you start with random double,
a random W rec close to zero then because you're multiplying
by it many times the more you multiply
the lower the value gets.
So, if you start off you might have a certain gradient
going through your network being back propagated
through your network.
Then you move backwards.
Your gradient becomes less.
Then your gradient becomes less,
and then your gradient becomes even less,
and what does that mean for the network?
And this is the important part to kind of get your head
around, that what does a vanishing gradient like that,
why is it bad for the network?
Well, because the gradient as it goes back through
the network, it is used to update the weights,
and we know that already.
Well, the lower the gradient is the harder it is
for the network to update the weights.
It cannot, it can still understand what kind of contribution
each of these outputs has towards the error,
and therefore it can update the weights,
but the lower the gradient the slower it's going
to update the weights, and the higher the gradient
the faster it's going to update the weights
and get you the final result.
And so, therefore if you have for instance 1,000 epochs
these weights for this layer might be updated
towards the end of the 1,000 and they'll,
you'll have some final results.
But these weights, because the gradient's so,
so much smaller, they're gonna be updated slower
and therefore by the end of the 1,000 epochs
you might not have the final results there,
and therefore this part of the network is trained.
This part of the network is not trained,
based on this cost function.
But the problem here is not just that half
your network is not trained properly,
but also that these weights, or this layer,
its outputs are being used as inputs for further layers.
So, the training here has been happening all along
based on, based off of inputs that are coming
from untrained neurons, untrained layers.
So, it's kind of a vicious cycle.
You're training here and you think you're getting
good results, but because you're gradient's so small here
this is training so slow and the outputs it's giving
is so, are incorrect, are not final outputs,
and therefore you're training on the non-final output.
So, because of this balance because of vanishing
gradient you have a problem in your network
which is not just that these weights
are not being trained properly.
The whole network is not being trained properly
because these weights are not being trained properly,
and that's, there's like a domino effect like this
wherever you look in the network.
Always the ones at the very back
are going to have that problem,
and this is in a nutshell what the vanishing gradient
problem for recurrent neural networks is,
and that's, that was kind of the main roadblock
to using recurrent neural networks,
and let's summarize this in a short slide.
So, if W rec is small, then your,
you have a vanishing gradient problem.
If W rec is large you have an exploding gradient problem,
because same thing, but then it's just gonna explode.
And here an important thing to point out here
is that of course there's more to it, right?
There's, as you can see, there's in this formula
there's other things like the activation function,
and so on.
So, it's not as simple as small or large,
or less than one, greater than one, but as a rule
of thumb if you have very small weights
you're gonna have a vanishing gradient,
and if you have very large weights, you put 100 in there,
the value of 100, then you're gonna, by step two
you're gonna have 10,000.
By step three you're going to have 1,000,000.
So, then you have an exploding gradient problem.
So, hopefully this summarizes the exploding gradient
problem on an intuitive level, because, so,
in short, because you're unraveling the temporal loop
the further you go through your network
the lower your gradient is and the harder it is
to train the weights which has a domino effect on all
of the further weights throughout the network as well.
And so, how do you combat the vanishing gradient problem?
There's a couple of solutions.
For instance, for the exploding gradient
you can have truncated back propagation.
So, you stop back propagating after a certain point,
but as you can imagine that's probably not optimal
because then you're not updating all the weights.
But if you don't stop, then you're just going to have
a completely irrelevant network.
So, it's better than the original approach.
And then you can have penalties.
So, you could have the gradient being penalized
and being artificially reduced.
You can have gradient clipping.
So, you could have a maximum limit for the gradient.
You could say never, never have the gradient go over
this value, and then if it's over that value
it just stays at that value as it propagates
further down through a network.
You can have, for the vanishing gradient problem
you have certain other solutions.
You have weight initialization, where you are
smart about how you initialize your weights
to minimize the potential for vanishing gradient.
You can have, there's a type of network
called the echo state networks, and we're not
going to talk about that, but they do somehow
solve that, or they are designed to solve
the vanishing gradient problem,
but there's also a different type of network
called the long short-term memory networks, or the LSTMs
for short, which are extremely popular,
which are considered to be the go to network
for implementing recurrent neural networks,
and that's exactly what we're going to be talking about
in the rest of this section.
So, that's gonna be very exciting.
We're going to look at a brand new architecture
for recurrent neural networks.
I really can't wait to get started on that.
It's a very interesting topic to get into.
But for now, this is, this brings us to the end
of the vanishing gradient problem tutorial,
and some additional reading.
So, additional reading, you can definitely reference
the original works by Sepp Hochreiter and Yoshua Bengio.
So, this is Sepp's paper in 1991, from 1991.
It's completely in German, so,
I'm not even going to read the name,
but if you understand and can read German,
then definitely this could be a good read for you.
Then there's Yoshua Bengio's paper
which is called Learning Long Term Dependencies
with Gradient Descent is Difficult, 1994.
Also you can reference that, but what I would recommend
looking into is a paper called On the difficulty
of training recurrent neural networks
by Razvan Pascanu.
It's just newer.
It's 2013 and it's also got Yoshua Bengio
as the co-author.
So, probably he was supervising some of this research,
and here it summarizes a lot of the things
that Yoshua Bengio talks about in his paper from 1994.
So, why not look at something newer.
I would recommend checking this paper out.
So, there we go.
That's the vanishing gradient problem.
Hope this was fun.
Can't wait to see you on the next tutorial,
and until then, enjoy deep learning.