Hello and welcome back
to the course on Deep Learning.
Now that we know a bit more about LSTMs and how they work
and what their architecture is like,
today we're going to look at some practical applications
or specifically we're gonna look at how LSTMs work
inside practical applications.
And it's gonna be quite interesting and at the same time
a bit magical I'd say so let's get started.
Here we've got LSTM architecture.
And we're going to be, to start off we're gonna be looking
at the standard function and how it fires up.
So according to, the images that we're gonna be using
are all from Andrej Karpathy's blog,
so thank you very much to Andrej for doing all of this
amazing research.
So you can see here, it's just incredible.
They've got some examples where they've created
some bogus algebra using trained up LSTMs.
And then lots and lots of stuff.
These are the images we're gonna be looking at just now.
These ones as well.
And there's lots of information here.
Lots of comments so definitely check it out.
We'll link to these at the end of the tutorial.
This blog is called The Unreasonable Effectiveness
of Recurrent Neural Networks.
And the paper that Andrej published along with that,
we'll also link to that paper as well.
So basically we're looking at the standard function
to start off with.
According to the paper, minus one means, is gonna be red,
plus one is gonna be blue.
So let's get started.
All right, so here's some text, which is given to an RNN,
which learned to read text and kind of create text
and predict what text is coming.
And here, this is a snippet from the War and Peace,
the huge novel by Tolstoy,
and so here you can see that this neuron is activating,
well it is sensitive to as it says here,
sensitive to position in line.
So you can see that when you get towards the end of the line
it's activating.
And how does it know when it's the end of the line?
Well, in this novel,
you have about 80 symbols per line
approximately, so it's counting how many symbols have passed
and that way it's trying to predict when the new line
character is coming up.
Because the new line, new line is just a character.
It's an invisible character and it's trying to predict
where that character's gonna appear.
Then you've got a cell that turn on inside quotes.
Well this says inside quotes.
I think it's actually outside quotes,
because here you see it says, you mean to imply that I have
noting to eat out of, on the contrary, I can supply.
So basically, somebody's talking and they say warmly replied
Chichagov, haven't read that in a long time,
who tried to by, who tried by every word.
So basically, this is the inside the quotes,
this is outside the quotes.
I'm not sure if this is correct, but either case,
one way or another, it's activating either inside the quotes
or outside the quotes, and you can see, so this one
is keeping track of what's happening.
So very similar to what we discusses previously,
where we were keeping track of the subject,
when that would help us understand.
And if the subject is male or female, we would be able
to understand things like if it's a singular or plural,
that would effect our verbs, and our translation,
similar things.
So it's important to know if you're inside or outside quotes
because that effects the rest of the text.
And for instance, the easiest way you can think of
that affects text that if you're inside the quotes
then there has to be another quote to close the quote.
So you're anticipating another quote, on something.
Here's another one where the input
was the code of the Linux operating system.
And here, you can see that a cell activates
inside if statements.
So it's completely dormant everywhere else.
But as soon as you have an if statement, it activates.
If statement, activates.
So, and it is active.
You can see it stops being active over here
at the next, at the actual body of the if statement.
So it's only active for the main part, or for the condition
of the if statement.
You know that can be important because you are anticipating
that condition's going to close if a bracket.
And then it's gonna be a bracket current embrace
to open up the body of the if statement.
That's pretty cool.
And here, you've got another one where this cell
is sensitive to how deep you are inside
of a nested expression.
So as you go deeper and the expression gets more
and more nested, this cell keeps track of that.
So it's using this memory to keep track of.
So it's very important to remember that none of this
is actually hard coded into the neural network.
All of this is learned by network itself.
Through thousands and thousands and thousands of iterations.
It learns that okay, I have this many hidden states,
I have, and out of them, I need to identify
what's important in the text to keep track of.
And it identifies for instance, in this case,
that being, understanding how deep you are
inside a nested statement is important and therefore,
it assigns a, one of its hidden states
to keep track of that.
So it has these resources, hidden states,
or the actual memory cells, and it assigns them
to keep track of certain things based on what it thinks
is important.
So it's really evolving like that on its own
and deciding what's important and what's not,
and how to allocate its resources to best complete the task.
I think that's very fascinating.
And then here's an example of a cell
that you can't really understand what it's doing.
And according to Andrej Karpathy, about 95% of the cells
are like this.
They're doing something, but it's just not obvious to us
what is happening.
And it's like that example of CNNs where the filters
or the features we're looking out for,
by the time they get to the last layer,
they're completely unrecognizable to the human eye.
But they make sense to the machines.
Same thing here.
Most the time, 95% of the time, you can't really tell
what's going on.
But those five percent of the time,
those were the examples we looked at,
and they should be helpful to better understand
what is kind of going on in the neural network
when it's processing text.
So again, now we're back at our architecture,
and now what we're gonna be looking at
is we're going to be looking at the actual output.
So we're gonna be looking at this value.
So after it's going through the tangent,
the valve or the output gate and now were gonna be looking
at what's being produced over here.
So, here's an example again, from Karpathy's,
Andrej Karpathy's blog, and we're looking at
a neural network, that is reading,
so this is a bit more detailed.
So here, it's not just showing us if it's active or not.
You can see that you've got, at the top, if it's active
or not every first line, and then in the other five lines
it is saying what's the neural network is predicting,
that's going to happen next.
What letter is going to come next.
What symbol is going to come next.
So, you got the combination of the two here.
And just by looking at this, what do you think
it's predicting.
So I'm gonna, I'm going to outline the colors.
Green means, for the top line, green means active
and blue means not active, and red means a very likely
prediction, and light red means unlikely prediction.
So, let's talk about the top line.
What do you think this specific hidden state
in the neural network is looking out for?
When do you think it's being activated?
Well I guess this one is pretty obvious.
It's activating inside URLs.
So here you can see, that inside w w w, the hidden state
is being activated just like we saw in the previous
examples of War and Peace and Linux kernel.
Here you can see it's being, it's activated
inside URLs, but now we have some additional stuff
to look at.
Now we can see what it's actually predicting
that's going to be the next character.
So for instance, under this W, you can see that
it's predicting that the next character's going to be a W
with the highest probability, and it's correct.
It is a W.
Then under this W, you can see that it's predicting
another W, and it is correct.
And under this W, this is what the whole neural network
is predicting, under this W, what you are seeing
is a dot, and that is correct, it is predicting a dot.
So that's how its gone up to here, and then after this dot,
it thinks the next letter will be a B,
but it's actually a Y.
But now knowing that it's a Y,
it thinks there's gonna be an A.
Now knowing it's an A, it thinks it's going to be an N.
And you can see that these are less,
these are not as red as these, because it's not sure
about these predictions, and fair enough,
it could be absolutely any website.
Why would it be a B?
It could be an N, you can't tell.
Maybe it could, based on the context, but still
it's very hard.
But then when it gets to Y net new, N E W, it predicts an S
with a very high likelihood, and it is indeed an S
because it kind of knows that the word after you have new
very likely you'll have an S.
Or based on everything it's learned before,
that in this particular type of text,
it's, news is mentioned quite often,
because as far as I understand, this is Wikipedia text.
And then you have the dot, and after dot,
it predicts a C, it is a C.
After C it predicts an O, it's an O.
After O it predicts an M, it is am M,
and then a slash and it is a slash.
So beautiful.
So then it's done its job, and it's not active anymore.
And then this is what, but the neuron that we're looking at
is not active anymore.
But the neural network is still predicting things.
So here you can see E and the N, so it's incorrect.
And then after the N, oh no, after the E it's incorrect.
After N, so after you have E N, it predicts a G, it's a G.
And then it becomes more confident
that it's the word English.
Language you can see that the predictions
become more confident.
After the L it didn't predict correctly,
but after the L A, it's really predicting N G and so on.
So it can actually predict the whole word,
based on just a few first letters.
Websites, and so on and so on.
The actual neuron is still dormant, still dormant.
And then here, you've got again, off we go.
W W W it's predicting and this one is getting active.
This one is pretty interesting, because it goes C O
and then predicts an M,
but it's not an M, it's a dot.
And it's like, the neural network, or this,
yeah this is a neural network is probably a bit upset
at this stage, thinking whoa, where's my M?
And then it takes another shot, it's says okay,
so probably U because dot co, dot U K.
That's the UK websites.
But here, instead of a U, it's got an I and an L
for Israel dot C O, dot I L, and therefore
it didn't guess this time.
But it's not even trying to guess.
You can see it's not even trying to guess an I
because from what's it's learned, dot C O, dot U K,
are much more likely to come up than dot C O dot I L.
And we're not even looking at these other ones here,
which you could look at them.
They are the second best guess, the third best guess,
fourth and fifth, but you can see that they're not
that red and it will always put it's highest likeliest
guess at the top on the second line overall.
So there you go.
This is how to look at these pictures that Andrej
has created.
And for more, check out his blog, karpathy.github.io.
There's a couple more of these examples there
and more of the previous examples that we looked at.
And yeah, so hopefully this is helpful to show you
what's going on inside the neural network
when it's thinking and when it's processing information.
In terms of references and additional reading,
we've got the Andrej Karpathy blog and we'll link to it
in the resources for this course.
This is the URL, otherwise, and also,
we've got Andrej Karpathy and others research paper
which was published in 2015.
It's called Visualizing and Understanding
Recurrent Networks.
Very interesting read actually,
because there's not too much math
and you can probably skip it, but even the insights
and parts and chapters are very interesting.
They make you kind of feel that, and they say this
in the paper, that they're like neuroscientists
trying to understand what's going on.
So they open up the brain of the neural network
and monitor what's happening in one specific neuron,
or different neurons.
And you actually feel, from the language,
they way that's it's written, that it's as if they're
exploring some alien, as if they're exploring some kind
of extra-terrestrial being and how it thinks.
Because if you think about it, humans created these LSTMs
and RNNs, these are just things that work on our computers.
But because they are so advanced, because they involve
so many different elements, so many different parts to them,
they're so complex, we now need,
we've created them, now we need to study them
as if they're separate beings, separate something
that exists on its own.
And it's just reading through it, it's kinda like
if you think of it that way, it gives you
this mysterious feeling or magic,
if you feel like it's something magical happening.
At the same time you feel that a few more years
or maybe a decade from now, these things
are going to be able to think completely on their own.
So if you want to have some fun reading a research paper
this one's pretty cool I think.
Maybe you don't have to read the math, skip the math.
I didn't really dig into the math myself.
Yeah, so that's pretty much it.
I hope you enjoyed today's tutorial.
And hopefully it give you a bit of a better understanding
of how the architecture actually plays out in practice.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then, enjoy Deep Learning.