Hello, and welcome back
to the course on deep learning.
I hope you're tracking along
with these intuition tutorials just fine,
and that you had a chance to play around with everything
we've learnt so far.
And today we're talking about flattening
and the good news is that this is a very simple step.
And this tutorial's going to be very quick
and then we'll be able to move on to
the next interesting things.
Alright, so far we've got
the pooled layer, pooled feature map.
And that is after we apply the convolution operation
to our image and then we apply pooling to the results
of the convolution which is the convolved image.
And so, what are we going to do
with this pooled feature map?
Well, we're going to take it
and we're going to flatten it into a column.
So, basically just take the numbers row by row,
and put them into this one long column.
And the reason for that is
because we want to later input this into
an artificial neural network for further processing.
So, this is what it looks like
when you have many pooling layers,
or you have the pooling layers with many pooled feature maps
and then you flatten them.
So, you put them into this one long column
sequentially one after the other.
And you get one huge vector of inputs
for an artificial neural network.
And so, to sum all this up, we've got an input image,
we apply a convolution layer, and let's not forget the ReLu
or rectified linear units function that we apply
after the convolution layer as well.
And then we apply pooling, and then we flatten everything
into a long vector which will be our input layer
for an artificial neural network.
And exactly how that works we'll
find out in the next tutorial.
Hope you enjoyed today's session, and I look forward
to seeing you next time.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.