Let's first demonstrate the problem that we're going
to solve with this particular demo.
If we fire up our application,
this is just where we left it off after the previous module,
I've just closed down all of the open files, we're going to see
that when we have an error message,
it will not display that even though we are capturing
it and returning it to the user, it won't display that error message on the UI.
And so once our application's launched, we go ahead and click Add
Registration and it goes to a login page, if I put in a bogus
username and password and click Login, we have a login error.
In fact,
you can see up in the address bar, it changed our parameter
to login?error, added that error parameter on the end. We
should be displaying something.
Well, we put all the code in there to do it,
but we haven't quite configured it yet. So let's look at what it's going to
take for us to do that and some minor changes inside of our application that will make it a little bit more user friendly.