From our security configuration that we had before, we have
already defined the failure URL, and we're going to verify that
you have this in your project as well.
And that is simply a /login? error=true.
We need to send that error message as a URL
parameter back to the servicing page.
This isn't the only way to handle errors, but it's definitely the most common.
As you can see here in our configuration section,
we just add two pieces to our security configuration.
First is the .failureUrl where you can see that we appended the
error=true parameter on the end, and then the .permitAll which is just
saying that we want to let everyone be able to see it. Let's add this to our code now.