I've gone ahead and shut down all of the servers and everything else I had
running just to have a clean starting point for this module.
We're going to start off by opening up our pom.xml.
I'm going to go to the bottom of the dependency section,
and it doesn't really matter, but before the test artifact,
I'm going to give myself some whitespace here.
I'm going to start adding those three dependencies that we need inside of here.
So the first one is the org.springframework.ldap groupId
with the spring‑ldap‑core artifactId.
This is for our Spring application to do any type of interaction with LDAP, and
it's actually the libraries that the Spring Security artifact that we're going
to copy in here in a minute will require to do those interactions. So these two
are kind of dependent upon one another.
We're going to specify both of them.
They could be pulled in as a transit dependency,
but by specifying them, we're sure of which
libraries we're going to be importing.
The next one is the org.springframework.security groupId with the
spring‑security‑ldap artifactId. And this is just what does the
binds and searches and things that we're expecting underneath the
hood in LDAP for our Spring Security application to authenticate
our user against it.
And then we'll finally have one more here, and that is the unboundId artifact
for the LDAP SDK. So it's a group idea of com.unboundId and an artifact of
unboundId‑ldapsdk, a little bit of a weird name,
but it's actually the preferred LDAP server if you go researching
the Spring Security documentation about what to test your Spring
Security LDAP against. Let's look at the next configuration pieces that we need inside of our app.