One of the best reasons to use Spring Security is its integration strengths.
Its roots are in just securing web applications,
but it's a great client when used in a CAS installation as well.
Many people think that when using CAS that you just
have to use their client tools.
The hooks in Spring Security are actually great for integrating with CAS
and are one of their preferred methods. Similar to CAS, Spring Security
makes handling the tokens of OAuth great.
OAuth can be a very complex animal,
but Spring Security can help manage its complexities.
LDAP is also a great authentication mechanism.
Using Spring Security,
we can authenticate and authorize against LDAP or just use it for
authentication and then authorize against a database.
This is, in fact,
one of the most common uses of Spring Security for internal apps.
And not to leave out web services, Spring Security is great for wrapping them with security as well.