Let's cover the architecture of Spring Security a little.
We'll go into more detail in some of the areas as we
continue throughout the course,
but I want to give you a baseline for the start of this course.
Spring Security is built on top of and uses Spring.
It is centered around web apps and uses a filter entry point.
It is built around multiple authentication models and
handling the various roles inside an app.
It also encourages apps to be inherently more secure
through encouraging the use of salts.
If you don't know what a salt is, don't worry, we will cover it later.
But suffice it to say it helps hackers not be able to crack stored passwords.
One of the main reasons I began using Spring Security years ago is
it helped to avoid session hacking. Session hacking, or a
man‑in‑the‑middle attack, is where someone can fool the server
into thinking it is someone else.
Spring Security has a few mechanisms in place that help
safeguard against that. And, lastly,
Spring Security is very full featured, from authentication and
authorization to 'Remember me' services and email confirmation.
It's all baked into the framework.
Let's look at some of the prerequisites that we will need to complete this course.