I want to go ahead and open up our src, main,
java com.pluralsight.conference package and open up
our ConferenceSecurityConfig class.
I'm going to make this full screen while we work on this for a little bit.
Let's scroll down to our jdbcAuthentication dataSource,
and I'm going to comment that out.
Now, below that, we're going to start putting in our LDAP configuration.
So we're going to say auth.ldapAuthentication.
And underneath here I can give it the new line and use that builder pattern
approach that we did before. So I can say .userDnPatterns.
And then here,
we're going to put in the contextual string of "uid". And that
is equal to a search parameter base of 0.
So this is the first character we're going to pass in
for our search, our first parameter.
We're going to use an organizational unit equal to people.
And this will make more sense when we set up our server here in a
little bit. We're going to specify all these things.
We're going to do a groupSearchBase, and for the groupSearchBase,
we're going to do an organizational unit equal to groups.
Now we're going to build our .contextSource, and then from that
.contextSource, we're going to pass in the URL.
And as I mentioned in the previous slides that this
can be passed in as a variable.
But to not make this example any more complex than it needs to be,
I'm just going to put this string in here.
That's a standard practice of using a variable to pass those in,
and we can just inject that resource.
And if you've gone through the Spring Fundamentals course,
you saw how we did that inside of there. You could also
look it up out of a database.
There are a lot of different ways that you could go about doing that.
So we'll do pluralsight, and we'll have a dc, or directory context, =com.
Now once we have this,
we can now start building upon this with our password compare feature.
So we're going to do .passwordCompare and do a
.passwordEncoder. And we're going to call the
passwordEncoder that we have defined down below.
And last but not least,
we're going to pass in the .passwordAttribute, and that is userPassword.
At the end of this line,
put a semicolon because we're done using that builder
pattern, and I'm going to save that.
Make sure you save your pom.xml as well so that it will
do those automatic imports for Maven.
Now your application is all configured to go against the LDAP server that we need to set up.