All you need to do to run Docker is to have the Docker Desktop installed,
and you just go to docker.com for that,
and download the version specific to your operating system.
From there, we're going to add this docker‑compose file to your application,
and it will set up everything.
And in this case,
we have a database, is image type is of mysequel5.7, the
container_name is conference_security.
We're going to bind the ports that are exposed on your operating
system to this port inside the container of 3306. It's going to show
us where it's going to store the data,
which is underneath our project in a .data directory /db. And then for our
environment, we're going to say that the MYSQL_ROOT_PASSWORD is pass, and
the DATABASE name is conference_security.
So we have all of our stuff set up and configured right here. Let's add this to our application now, and we can start up our Docker instance.