There are a few prerequisites you'll need to do the examples in this course.
I am using Java 11.
Java 11 is the current long‑term support version.
There are already other releases that have been
published since doing this course.
Realize that they are not long‑term support versions.
Spring is very strategic,
and we've tried to be very strategic as well about picking the
correct versions to line up with those to guarantee a
longer‑supported version of this course.
So we encourage you to use the same versions that we
have chosen inside of this course.
I'm assuming that you already know how to install Java,
so we won't be covering that.
And I'm also going to use Maven in this course.
Just like Java, I pretty well assume that you already know how to install that,
so we won't be covering that here.
Spring no longer offers up a way to just download the jars,
and you're forced to use Maven or Gradle to download those dependencies.
There is a Pluralsight course on Maven if you have more questions about that,
and you can research and follow it.
The next thing you'll need is an IDE.
This course has now been updated to use IntelliJ.
We got feedback that the majority of our users wanted to
see and use examples with IntelliJ, so we've changed the course to use it.
We are using IntelliJ Ultimate, and if you do not have that,
there is a trial version, as well as student versions
are available for fairly cheap,
and a lot of our users have it supplied by their work.
If you don't want to use IntelliJ, you can ask questions on the forum,
and I will help you go through Spring STS or Eclipse.
Just realize that every example we will be doing and the videos
will be showing IntelliJ Ultimate. And, finally,
Tomcat.
We will walk through the deployment of our project through Tomcat.
I've had people ask me why we don't just use the bundled application,
how Spring Boot originally ships it,
and it's because of a lot of external factors.
Suffice it to say,
if you are using JSP Pages, you have a lot of external security pieces in place,
and generally how you deploy your application inside of an environment, you're
typically still doing that with a WAR to Tomcat, so we will use Tomcat inside of our course.