I've opened up our MySQL workbench that we used earlier in the previous module.
I'm going to right‑click on users and say Alter Table.
This will bring up a table editor that I can just click to edit here.
And it will give me a column, which I'm going to call nickname.
And I'm going to change that to be a VARCHAR of 50.
And by default, we don't care if this is null.
That's all I actually have to do to edit this users table.
I'm going to click Apply.
You can actually see the SQL that it's going to run to do this.
So this is just a nice, convenient helper through the UI to do this.
This is the actual SQL that gets run behind the scenes.
So now our table has that column added to it.
Go back to our query editor that we had earlier,
and I've already typed in an update statement in here,
and I can say update users set nickname = 'bigb', kind of a nickname
that some people call me, where username = 'bryan'.
So I'm going to highlight that line and run it here, and make sure you choose
the option that says to run the one that's underneath the current cursor. And
then I'm going to execute that commit statement again.
So now we should have a Select statement for users.
If we execute that, you'll see that it has updated that user bryan,
and it still has our password there,
even though we're going to be authenticating against LDAP now,
it says it's still enabled,
and it has updated the nickname to store that in there as well.
We have our database set up. Let's go build that custom context mapper.