I've gone ahead and opened up our project,
how we had it from when we downloaded the scaffold application.
We want to open up our pom.xml.
Now,
our pom.xml file has this dependency section in here where we've added in
all of the dependencies that our application needs.
And if you've used Maven before and you followed my other classes,
this shouldn't be new to you, but we'll go through it still.
I'm going to go down below org.hibernate.validator
and give myself some whitespace.
And yours should be pretty similar to this as well.
And I've already copied,
and I'm just going to paste these two dependencies in there,
and I'll walk through them with you.
And it's just so you don't have to watch me type these in.
I've got two dependencies inside of here.
I've got spring‑boot‑starter‑security and spring‑security‑test.
And you'll notice they were red for a second while they
downloaded those versions in there.
And so now I have these two pieces in here,
and I want to point out these two different classes,
what they're doing, or what these artifacts are doing for us.
We have the spring‑boot‑starter‑security which will add
some default configuration files for us.
In fact, we'll have a login page out of that by default,
and then the spring‑security‑test,
which will enable us to go through and write tests against our application.
Notice here on line 48 in my app, there is a scope of test in here,
so spring‑security‑test will not get bundled with our WAR when we deploy it.
That's what that scope is associated with inside of Maven.
So now we have this in here.
Let's go ahead and look at the other pieces of our app and what we're going to start wiring up.