All right, to create our test‑server.ldif file,
I'm going to be real honest with you, you'll probably just want to download it
out of the Exercise files or fork the source code that I have at GitHub and grab
it from there and add to your project. Hand typing this all in here is going to
be very monotonous and very error prone.
So to do this,
I am going to go to our src, main, resources directory again,
right‑click, and add a new file, and the file name is going to be
test‑server.ldif. And I am going to do exactly what I just said
and paste all of this in here, but I'm going to walk through this with you.
First off, we have our context.pluralsight.com.
You can see that we have next defined our users
groups, and it's tied to that structure.
And then we have subgroups down below. And then we define
people inside of here. And, finally, halfway down here,
you can see that we have created a user.
So I'm going to point out a couple of specific things here.
If you want to add your own user or change it to your name and
password, you're going to want to go through and search where I have my
name inside of here and replace it with yours.
So the UID of bryan up here,
you would want to change to whatever your name is, bob
or whatever else you're doing there.
So I'm going to change that back to bryan. And you can see that
it's all over throughout this application.
In fact, if I do a search inside of my file here for Bryan,
you can see that I have six matches inside of here where it is
throughout this because I'm part of the managers group and
sub‑managers group and all of that different context.
Now this is a little bit of an overkill for this simple example.
I could have not had them join these groups and other things, except
for if we do more complex stuff with this user,
they will need to be in those various groups.
So as we do some of the role‑based stuff later in this course,
I will need this stuff.
So I've gone ahead and set up the server from the get‑go the right way.
If you want to add your password in there,
remember that we got that encrypted password by running that unit test that we
created earlier that had the system.out.println of our encoder.encode with your
password in clear text typed in there so that you can see what the encoded value
looks like so we can do a compare on it.
And that's exactly what's happening is in our
ConferenceSecurityConfig, we do a passwordCompare on that password
from that attribute. So you can see things tie together.
Here we have our passwordAttribute of userPassword that's under
test‑server.ldif where our userPassword's defined. You can also
see inside of here that we are going to use that compare with
the exact PasswordEncoder,
which is how we can encode our clear text password and store in that file and compare those two up.