For the UI portion of the rememberMe services,
we want to open up our login.jsp page,
and I have mine open from our previous example.We want to scroll
down to our form where we perform our login,
and underneath our password input,
we want to give ourselves some white space and add in another div label,
Remember Me input type= checkbox name= remember‑me label div.
So this checkbox, it's really simple,
it's just basic HTML. This checkbox that we're adding in
here is just the box that we will select on the UI to
enable these rememberMe services.
I've said it multiple times,
but I'm afraid you're going to miss it, yours does have to be named the same,
remember‑me.
If not,
it will not work when we add the backend configuration. Let's start
our server up and see what this does on the UI.
Now that our app is up we can click on Add Registration, and we'll
see our checkbox down here. Currently it won't do anything, it'll
submit it to the backend, but we haven't configured that security
config to accept those yet. Let's look at that configuration now.