The configuration in our security config is actually in two parts,
and you can see that we've got these separated out with a
comment in between to show you the break.
We need to add in our configure section the rememberMe method call using
that builder pattern. We'll give it a key, and I just put in there
superSecretKey, you can actually put one in there that is unique to your
organization, and the call to tokenRepository where we reference this
being we're going to define down below. The being that we're going to
create returns an instance of PersistentTokenRepository, which inside
that method uses a JdbcTokenRepositoryImpl where we pass in our data
source, and this will actually be used to communicate with our database,
which will actually be one of the next steps that we
configure to enable rememberMe services.
Let's add these two pieces to our security configuration, and then we can look at the changes we need for the database.