Inside of our ConferenceSecurityConfig in the previous demos,
I had you space out from your antMatchers anyRequest.authenticated and the
next section which starts off with the .and method builder call to give
yourself some logical space and breaking those up.
I'm going to go ahead and do that again.
I'm going to go in between that last line and that semicolon and
give myself a little extra space here and create another .and using
the builder and another line below that.
And inside of here, I want to say .rememberMe,
and this will start building out the Remember Me services.
I'm going to do another line below that,
and this is where we'll pass in that key.
And our key is going to be, for my example, the superSecretKey.
You can change that to something unique to your organization.
We have one more line inside of here, and this one, as we type it in,
it is going to break because we're going to have to define a method down below.
So we're going to say tokenRepository,
and that is going to call the method tokenRepository,
and this doesn't exist yet.
We're going to define this down below inside of our code.
So it'll give us an error right now.
I'm just going to go below that method and add a new bean.
So we're going to say @Bean, and this is a public bean that is going to
return an instance of a PersistentTokenRepository.
And for the signature,
we're going to match that name that we have up above there of
tokenRepository, and it takes no arguments in its method signature.
And this is an instance of a JdbcTokenRepositoryImpl,
and we can just call this token.
This will be a new JdbcTokenRepositoryImpl.
And on our token, we want to set the data source.
And we have already defined a data source inside of this class,
so we'll say dataSource and then return that instance of our token.
So we'll say‑‑‑ It's really not the token itself.
It's the implementation of that class.
And that class implements the PersistentTokenRepository interface.
So now we have defined our tokenRepository, and we've
configured our Remember Me services.
But there's one last step we need to add a database table that
this JdbcTokenRepositoryImpltalks to on the back end, and then we'll be able to run our demo.