Logout configuration is very similar to the Remember Me
configuration in our ConferenceSecurityConfiguration file.
We start off by defining the logout functionality. We
then have a logoutSuccessfulUrl.
And in this instance, we are returning back to the login
page and adding a parameter of logout=true so that we can
display a successful message.
From here, we will invalidate our session and then delete the cookie
associated with the login and the Remember Me services as well.
Lastly,
we want to allow everyone to be able to log out so we add a permitAll configuration to the end of that logout configuration.