All right, in this module,
we learned how to display error messages a little bit cleaner in our
UI. We had most of the functionality in there,
but we weren't fully utilizing it.
We then added Remember Me services, which are a nice benefit.
Most standard UIs now have this where it creates a cookie on your
local machine and then on the back end stores a reference to that
token in our database. So we added the database tables and tied that
all together. And then you almost immediately need to implement the
logout functionality because once that cookie is created, every time
you revisit that page, it will try and log you in automatically.
And if you want to test something different or change anything,
you need to be able to break that cycle.
As part of that,
we implemented the AntPathMatcher so that we could go ahead and implement
a GET instead of a POST for that logout functionality,
which is, by default, requiring a form to be built.
And then we also looked at utilizing bootstrap messages.
We did a successful logout bootstrap message. And if you want to go
ahead and change your alert messages on a invalid username and
password to utilize that bootstrap message, it's a little bit
cleaner UI, and we already have all the pieces built inside of our
application to do that.
Next,
we're going to go ahead and implement a registration or an account creation page and do that programmatically inside of the app.