I wanted to point out one specific difference that we made in
this module over the registration module,
and that is that we opted to make this overly secured by
requiring people to enter both the email address and
username associated with their password.
We could easily change it to just look up one or the other if
you only want that for your application.
But for example, we're going to use both for now.
Let's start off by creating the UI for capturing these two pieces,
and we will also need to create the backing model objects
for capturing those data fields as well.
I've shut down my server and closed all the open files we
had from previous demos just to get everything to a
baseline for us to start up with.
Let's open up our login.jsp page to begin with and go ahead and,
next to our Submit button, enter in,
we're just going to add a simple anchor tag in here that, when we click on it,
will request our password JSP page,
and it's going to display that text of Forgot password.
I'll go ahead and test this by saving this page and starting up our server
or restarting our server if yours is currently running,
and it will pull this up.
And when we go to click on our login,
right next to our text for the Submit button will be a Forgot password link.
Now when we click on our Add Registration page,
which is a page that requires us to log in,
you'll see that we have our text next to it that asks us if we want
to click to enable our Forgotten password page.
But if we click on this right now,
I'm going to tell you it's just going to refresh this page because,
one, we don't have security set up to allow it to go to that page,
and, two, we don't have a controller to capture that.
So let's fix both of those.
We'll add the security configuration to point to our Forgotten password page,
and we'll have a controller that's going to capture that
information for us and redirect us to that page as well.
That password controller we're going to put alongside of our other controllers.
Just go ahead and right‑click on our controller package and say New,
Java class, and give this a name of PasswordController.
Hit Enter.
And then inside of here, I'm going to add a method,
and it's just like the other ones we've done in the
AccountController or some of our other controllers that is a
GetMapping that is tied to the URL password.
And you'll notice in here that I'm asking for a password object.
We haven't created that object yet.
We're going to cause that's what's going to back the form on our page.
Before we create that object though,
let's go ahead and annotate this as a controller.
And now we can begin creating that password object, and it's really simple.
It's just like we did with the account with a few variations on the fields.
For that password object,
let's go ahead and open up our model package and right‑click on it and say New,
Java class, and we'll just call this Password.
And inside of here, we're going to add a handful of fields,
and we want to make those not null, just like we did with the account object,
and we'll also make them not empty as well.
So we've got our password, our matchingPassword,
our email, a username and a token.
Very similar.
In fact, if you wanted to,
you could go ahead and extract some of these up into a parent object.
But for the scope of what we're doing,
we're going to try and keep it as simple as possible.
I'm going to give myself some white space down here.
Right‑click and say Generate.
Getter and Setter, and I want to select all of these.
Click OK. And now we have our password object for everything that
we need to capture off of the screen, as well as pass around from
request to request. We can save this.
Go back to our PasswordController. Since we did use that account page,
we can actually just chop out the firstName and lastName here, as well
as the Password and Confirm Password here.
And we actually have the two fields that we care about inside of
here to go ahead and submit back to the page. And just make it a
little bit better of a user experience, let's change this value
from Submit to Reset Password,
and we'll also change this h1 and the title of the page as well.
Let's get all the fields inside of here changed that we want to.
We have one last piece before all of that life cycle of requesting the page
and going to the controller and going back to this JSP page that we've
created and allowing us to round trip that. We need to change our security
config, just one line inside of there.
So let's open that up, and we'll go to our ConferenceSecurityConfig. And inside
of here, we need to add a permission for our password page.
So I'm just going to grab one of those lines and give myself a
new line below that and type in password here.
And what this will do is it will display anything that matches /password*.
It will permit anybody to see that. We've done this a couple times now, but
just to remind you of what that's doing. Now if we restart our server, now
if we click on our Add Registration page again,
click Forgot password,
it will go through and display our password page that we've just built.
So we've gone through that round tripping of showing the login page,
clicking the Forgot password link, going up through our server,
which is actually going through our security that we just added,
going to the controller, and then building that password object
and displaying this page back out.
So we actually have everything put together to do our post,
as I just barely mentioned that we now go through those steps.
But that's going to tie in some of our service tier and firing off an event.
So let's go through a few more of those details before we just dive into that just yet.