As mentioned before, we moved this module to the end of the
course because you may or may not be using JSP or Timely for
your UI, but the same principles apply.
We showed how to use the Spring Security Tag library to display
an element when the use of I is authenticated or is not
authenticated inside of the application.
We then showed an interesting technique of injecting the current
logged in user to methods that are called by Spring.
We could use the old static approach to grab the current logged in user,
but this injected model is actually an easier way to both unit test your
code and not have static access inside your‑app.
And this module actually concludes the updates for this course.
I want to thank you for following along, and I hope to see you on some of my other courses here, on Pluralsight.