Just like we did when starting work on the document model,
we will first take a walk through our MovieRank application,
looking at what code we have removed that relates to the document model.
We are removing this code really so we can add the
low-level model equivalent code.
We want the ability to allow our users to get all items from our data,
to get a specific movie using only the first letter or first word of the movie,
we want to get what movies a user has ranked based on the movie name,
we allow our users to rank movies,
we will also allow them to update an already-ranked movie,
so they are able to update their ranking,
we want the ability to get an overall movie ranking,
taking in all user's rankings and then providing us
with the average of those rankings.
As mentioned earlier,
the low-level model is the only model where we can create and delete tables.
So we will add the ability to create and delete DynamoDB tables.
Inside our application, if we start off inside our MovieRankRepository class,
you will see that I have removed all code in this class and interface.
The MovieRankRepository class is the main class where
we'll be adding the low-level model code.
Jumping over to our Mapper class,
I have also removed the code from this class and interface.
If we look inside our MovieRankService class, I have left most code as is.
Inside the AddMovie method,
we now call off directly to the MovieRankRepository class.
We have removed the code needed to map our request into our DynamoDB object.
I've done the same thing for the UpdateMovie method as well.
We will now call off directly to the MovieRankRepository class.
Inside our GetMovieRank method,
I've replaced the existing code to work out the overall
average with the code that will work based on the response that we get back from DynamoDB.