Let's now have a look at how we can use the DynamoDB document model.
Previously, we were using the Object Persistence model.
This model allowed us to map our classes that we had created
in our application to our DynamoDB tables.
Out of the three models,
the Object Persistence model requires us to write the least amount of code.
The document model still wraps the low-level model,
but we are required to write a little more code to add,
load, and query.
If we have a look at our MovieRank solution,
I have removed all of the code relating to DynamoDB's Object Persistence model.
Let's have a look around our solution to see what code I've
left then and what code I've removed.
I haven't touched anything inside our MovieController class.
We can reuse all the code that we have created previously.
Inside the MovieService class,
I've renamed a couple of the methods that we were using to map our request
that a user was making to the model that DynamoDB expects.
Previously, we were mapping our object into our MovieDb model,
whereas now we need to map our object to DynamoDB's document model.
These name changes happen in AddMovie and UpdateMovie.
I've also deleted the code that we used to get the
overall ranking of the specific movie.
This is due to the fact that to get items from the
response that we get back from DynamoDB,
we need to change this code slightly.
We will cover what the changes are when we get to implementing this endpoint.
I've deleted all methods inside our Mapper class.
We will cover how to map out items to our contracts as we go through
implementing our DynamoDB document model code.
I've deleted all methods and code inside our MovieRankRepository class,
as this is the main class that we'll be changing to
work with DynamoDB's document model. I've also deleted the MovieDb model that we created previously.