Before creating our tests, we need to do a bit of work to spin up our
application and memory to pull down and run the local instance of DynamoDB and
to set up the DynamoDB table ready to run our tests against.
We want to group our setup classes together so
we'll create a folder named Setup.
Then we'll add a class named CollectionFixture, and
we'll set our class to public.
When running our tests, we want to do some setup the first time the
tests are run and share the setup among other tests.
This saves us having to do the tested up each time a test is run.
Actioner gives us the ability to create a class as our entry point when
we first run our tests. We can then add classes to this entry point that
will be executed the first time our tests are run. Inside the
CollectionFixture class, I'll add the collection definition attribute to
the top of our class.
Inside this attribute, we'll add the name API.
We need to add the XUnit using statement.
We will implement the ICollectionFixture interface and add the class
TestContext. We'll create the TestContext class shortly, but what we're
saying here is that when we run our tests,
we want the TestContext class to be run before we run our
tests. The CollectionDefinition and ICollectionFixture
interfaces are all part of the XUnit library.
If you want to know more about the collection fixtures, then you can read more about it on the XUnit page.