Let's create our TestContext class.
This class will contain the code to spin up, an in‑memory test server.
It will configure how HTTP Client and download and run our local DynamoDB Docker
image. In our TestContext class, the first thing that we'll be adding is these
IAsyncLifetime interface. Adding this interface allows us to bring in the
initialize async and dispose async methods.
These methods will run straight after our constructor of the class.
You might be thinking,
why might we need this when we can call or initialize any
method from inside our constructor?
Well,
the next piece of code that we'll be adding to this class will be to pull down,
run, and start our local instance of DynamoDB inside a Docker
container. The InitializeAsync and DisposeAsync methods are
asynchronous and calling asynchronous methods from a constructor is
tough work when trying to avoid async deadlocks.
Thankfully, XUnit has us covered.
Let's create the InitializeAsync method and add the appropriate using
statements. Using the Docker .NET library, we are going to set up our
client that allows us to interact with our Docker engine. To quickly
explain what the Docker engine is, the Docker engine is the underlying
client server technology that builds and runs containers using Docker's
components and services.
At the top of our class, we will add a field with the type
DockerClient named _dockerClient, and we'll add the Docker
.NET using statement. Next,
we will initialize and configure our client inside our class'
constructor. Using our field that we have created above,
we will say _dockerClient new DockerClientConfiguration, and we need to pass
in the URL required to talk to the Docker engine. To do this, we can use a
named pipe and we'll chain onto this method CreateClient. Now we have our
client set up, we can write the code needed to pull our Docker image. We want
to use a local instance of DynamoDB, so we'll pull down the Amazon DynamoDB
‑local. We create a method named PullImage, and using our dockerClient, we
were used the method .Images.createImageAsync. We need to new up an
ImagesCreateParameters where we can pass in our Docker image name. Using the
FromImages property, we will add the image that we want to pull down. Because
we'll be using this image in multiple places, we will add a constant to the
top of our class that will store our image name.
In our case, we want to use the Amazon DynamoDB local Docker image.
As you might have seen, we have passed this into our FromImage property.
We will also add the property name Tag.
We want to grab the latest DynamoDB image so we'll
add latest to the tag property.
We new up an auth config.
If we needed to add a username and password to access our Docker image,
we could add that here.
However,
we are able to download the DynamoDB local Docker image
anonymously, so we can lead this empty.
We are also required to initialize the Progress class.
This gives us the ability to check on the progress
of pulling down the Docker image.
For now, we'll leave this blank.
Finally,
we'll add a call to our PullImage method inside our InitializeAsync method.
Remember that this method will be run directly after the class's constructor.
Now that we have our image, we want to create and start our Docker container.
Let's create a method named StartContainer.
Inside this method,
we will create a variable named response, and using the dockerClient,
we will say Containers.CreateContainerAsync and new
up a create container parameters.
This is where we are able to set up our container parameters.
We will pass in the Docker image that we've just pulled down.
We want to expose the port 8000 to allow us to interact with our
Docker container. Inside the exposed port property,
we want to new up a dictionary with a key of string and value of empty strut.
This is what's required by the exposed port property.
Then we'll add to the dictionary the key 8000 and default EmptyStruct as the
value. We next want to add to the hostconfig property.
So we'll say new HostConflg PortBindings and add the
dictionary string list port binding.
Inside this dictionary,
we will add the key of 8000, and for the value, we will add
PortBinding assigning it to the HostPort property of 8000.
We need to ensure that all of our ports are
published when our container starts up.
So we'll add PublishAllPorts = true.
This ensures that all ports are published and we have access to them
allowing us to interact with our Docker container.
Using the response that we get back from the
CreateContainerAsync call, we store the container ID into a
field named _containerid and say = response.ID.
We don't have a container ID field yet,
so let's add that to the top of our class.
Now we can add the code needed to start our
container. Again, using our dockerClient,
we will say Containers.StartContainerAsync and pass in the containerId
and we don't need to add any container start parameters so we'll just
say null. And we add a call to the StartContainer method inside our
InitializeAsync method. When our tasks are finished running, we want
to kill our container.
Let's add the DisposeAsync method to our class.
If you remember,
this is part of the IAsyncLifetime interface that we added to our class earlier.
Inside this method,
we will first check to make sure that the container ID exists.
If the container ID exists,
then we'll use the dockerClient to call .Containers.KillContainerAsync and pass in the container ID in an empty ContainerKillParameters.