Let's add the GetUsersRankedMoviesByMovieName.
Inside our Controller class, we can leave the existing code as is.
Inside our MovieRankService class, we call off to our Repository class,
and store the response that we get back inside the Response variable.
We then map the response we get back into our MovieRankContract class.
If we head over to our Mapper class,
we need to add another ToMovieContract overload method.
We will create this overload method to have a return
type of IEnumerable MovieResponse, and inside this method's parameters,
we'll use the QueryResponse.
We use the same call that we have in our method above.
Using the link Select method, we call off to the existing method below.
We then need to add this new method to our interface.
Inside our MovieResponse class,
we need to create a method with a return type of Task QueryResponse,
and call our method GetUsersRankedMoviesByMovieTitle,
and pass in the userId and the movieName.
Any time we use DynamoDB's QueryAsync method,
we need to create a query request to be passed in.
Inside our method, we'll new up a QueryRequest, and set the TableName.
We will now add a KeyConditionExpression.
This is where we tell DynamoDB on what conditions to query on.
If we say UserId equals :userId,
this is saying that for the table property UserId,
we want to equal the UserId parameter argument that
is being passed in to this method.
Notice I have a colon set before my parameter argument,
this is really important and something that DynamoDB expects.
If you don't have this, you'll get an error when executing this method.
We also want to query on the first letter or first word of the movie name.
We add and begins_with and in parentheses, MovieName, :movieName.
We now need to set the expression attribute values.
This is similar to the key that we set in our
GetItemRequest in our GetMovie method.
We say ExpressionAttributeValues equals new Dictionary
of type string and AttributeValue, then set :userId as the Dictionary key,
and new AttributeValue set to our parameter arguments.
We do the same for our movieName.
Using the _dynamoDbClient,
we use the QueryAsync method and pass in the QueryRequest, and we add this to our IMovieRankRepository interface.