Let's add the ability for users to add a movie's ranking.
Inside our Controller class, we can see we already have the method inside here.
So we can head straight over to our MovieRankService class.
We'll call off to our MovieRankRepository class,
and pass in the userId and the MovieRankRequest.
Heading over to the MovieRankRepository class,
we want to create a method named AddMovie that takes in two parameters,
userId and MovieRankRequest.
We also need to add the MovieRank.Contracts using statement.
We will create a PutItemRequest that will build up the requests that
we'll be passing into the DynamoDB's PutItemAsync method.
We will say new PutItemRequest, and inside the request,
we will add our TableName,
then we want to build up our items that we want to add to our DynamoDb table,
MovieRank.
We will add Item, and new up a Dictionary of type string and AttributeValue.
We will add each property inside our MovieRank DynamoDB table,
and map them to the parameter arguments that are being passed in to our method.
We want to make sure that we specify the type for each of these.
For example, N for number, S for string, and SS for list of strings.
When using DateTime, we need to add the System using statement.
Using the _dynamoDbClient,
we will use PutItemAsync and pass in the PutItemRequest.
We will add this method to our interface, and add the MovieRank.Contracts using statement.