Before we move off this class,
I want to add one more call inside the InitializeAsync method.
I call to the TestDataSetup class, and also, we'll
chain on a call to CreateTable.
Once we have our container running,
we want to add a table and data to our local instance of DynamoDB.
We don't yet have the class or method to do this, so let's create that now.
Inside our Setup folder, if we add a class and call this TestDataSetup. We need
to make sure that we've set our class to public, and at the top of our class, we
want to create an IAmazonDynamoDB client.
This will allow us to use DynamoDB operations.
We will also add the IAmazonDynamoDB using statement.
We want to add the service URL that our DynamoDB client will be using.
In our case,
we want to use localhost with the same port that our local
DynamoDB has been spun up on, port 8000.
We want to create a MovieRank table inside our local DynamoDB
instance. We first need to create a method named CreateTable. We'll
also add the Threading.Tasks using statement.
Inside our method,
we want to new up a CreateTableRequest and add the DynamoDBv2.Model
using statement. We covered creating our table and the working with
items and DynamoDB using the low‑level model.
So, I'll copy and paste the code needed here to
first create our CreateTableRequest.
If you want to see creating tables in more detail and you
haven't already viewed the previous module,
I'd suggest watching that as it better explains what we're setting up here.
If we have a quick look at what we're setting up, in our request,
we have added two attribute definitions, a UserId of type number
and the MovieName of type string.
We want to set our UserId as the partition key,
which is sometimes referred to as the hash key, and
the MovieName as our sort key, which is sometimes referred to as the range key.
We'll set our read and write capacity to 1. And we
have set our TableName as MovieRank.
There is one part that we didn't cover in the previous module,
and that's adding our secondary index when creating our table.
We need to set up a secondary index, as one of our tests will be
using the secondary index. Inside our CreateTableRequest, we will
set the GlobalSecondaryIndexes property.
We want to add our secondary index name,
MovieName‑index, and then set our KeySchema, i.e., the
partition and sort key of our secondary index.
We only have a partition key set for our secondary index,
so we'll set that to MovieName, and we set the read and write capacity units.
We need to set the projection.
This specifies the attributes that are copied or projected
from the table into our secondary index.
We want all of these copied into our secondary index,
so we'll set this to ALL. Using the DynamoDB client, we will use the
CreateTableAsync method and pass in our CreateTableRequest.
When creating tables, they won't be created instantly.
We want to add some code that will wait for the table
to be created before continuing on.
Otherwise, we could run into the situation of running our
tests against a table that doesn't exist.
Let's create a method, WaitUntilTableActive.
We want to add a parameter of string tableName.
We will add a string variable and set it to null and create a
do while loop. Inside this loop, we want to set a Thread.Sleep
and set it to 5000 milliseconds.
This is so we can wait for 5 seconds each time before checking if the table
has been created. We will add a try catch statement. Inside our catch
statement, we want to catch ResourceNotFoundException.
We're adding this catch as we're about to do a DescribeTable.
And since DescribeTable is eventually consistent,
we could get back a ResourceNotFoundException.
So we catch this and handle it.
We will set our while to be of (status != "ACTIVE").
When the table is ready for us to use, we will get back a status of active.
Let's add a check inside our try statement that uses the description
table operation to check if the table was active.
We will call off to a method that doesn't yet exist named
GetTableStatus and pass in the table name.
We save the response that we get back from the status to our local
variable. Let's create our GetTableStatus method.
This will have a string parameter named tableName. Using our
DynamoDB client, we will use the DescribeTableAsync method and
new up a DescribeTableRequest and set our tableName that is
being passed into this method.
Once we have been returned a response, we want to return the table status.
So, we will say response.Table.TableStatus.
And we want to add a call to this method to the
bottom of our CreateTable method.
This will wait for the table to be created before continuing on and running our tests.