Now we want to be able to add movies with the user's ranking.
Inside our Controller class,
we'll use the same code that we created previously and
head along to our MovieRankService class.
Inside our MovieRankService class,
we need to add code needed to map the request that we get from
the users into a document model that DynamoDB expects when
adding items to our DynamoDB table.
We'll head over to the Mapper class,
and we'll add a method with a return type of Document named ToDocumentModel.
This method will have two parameters, userId and MovieRankRequest.
Inside our method, we will return a new document,
and map each of the properties in our MovieAddRequest class to our
corresponding DynamoDB properties inside our MovieRank table.
We will add this method to our interface,
and we'll head over to MovieRankRepository class.
Inside our MovieRankRepository class, we will add a method,
AddMovie, and add the document that we created in our mapper.
We will use the PutItemAsync method,
and pass in the documentModel to add our movie to our MovieRank DynamoDB table. We will also add this method to our interface.