Our final method in our MovieController class is the GetMoviesRanking.
This gets us all user's rankings for a specific movie.
This uses our secondary index.
Inside our Controller class, we call off to the MovieRankService class.
In our method, GetMovieRank,
we call off to our Repository class to a method that we'll be creating shortly,
GetMovieRank.
This method will return us back all user's rankings for a specific movie.
Once we get the movie back with all the rankings,
we want to take all of these rankings and get an average in an
overall ranking to pass it back to the user.
Once we have our overall ranking,
we can pass back a MovieRankResponse that contains the
MovieName and the overall ranking.
Inside our MovieRankRepository class,
we want to create a method with a return type of Task QueryResponse and a
method name GetMovieRank with a parameter of movieName.
Inside our method, we create a new QueryRequest and set our TableName.
We want to set the IndexName property with our secondary index name,
MovieName‑index.
We want to set the KeyCondition. This is the condition
that we want to query our database with.
In our case, we want to query on the MovieRank MovieName property,
and say equal to the movieName argument that's being passed in to our method.
We now need to set the ExpressionAttributeValues.
Remember this is similar to the key that we set in our
GetItemRequest in our GetMovie method.
We say ExpressionAttributeValues equals new Dictionary
of type string and AttributeValue,
then set :movieName as the Dictionary key and new
AttributeValue set to our parameter arguments.
Using our _dynamoDbClient, we can use the DynamoDB QueryAsync method,
and pass in the QueryRequest that we have just built, and we'll add this method to our interface.