We want to allow our users to update movies that they have already ranked.
Starting off in our Controller class,
we can use the existing UpdateMovie method that calls
off to our MovieRankService class.
Inside our MovieRankService class,
we first call off to DynamoDB to get an existing movie using the code that
we have already implemented in our Repository class.
We then need to map the response that we get back from DynamoDB,
and also add our updated values from our user.
We need to open up our Mapper class and add an overload
method to accept three parameters, userId,
MovieResponse, and MovieUpdateRequest.
Inside our method, we'll return a new document,
and we'll map our items to the corresponding DynamoDB properties.
The only property that we'll be updating will be the Ranking.
I have mapped the Ranking DynamoDB property to our
MovieUpdateRequest parameter argument,
so we can add the new ranking that the user has given the movie.
We'll add this method to our IMapper interface.
Inside our MovieRankRepository class,
we create a method named UpdateMovie with our
documentModel that we created in our mapper.
Inside our method, we can use the UpdateItemAsync method,
and pass in our documentModel. As usual, we'll add this method to our interface.