Hi,
and welcome to the Working with Items in DynamoDB Using the
Object Persistence Model from the Developing .NET Core
Applications with DynamoDB on AWS.
My name is Daniel, and I'll be taking you through this module.
The DynamoDB SDK for .NET offers three models that can be used,
the Object Persistence, document, and low-level model.
In this module, we'll be focusing on the Object Persistence model.
We will discuss why this model exists,
what DynamoDB operations we have access to from within this model,
and what operations are missing from it.
We then jump into our demo where we will continue to add to our .NET
Core template that we created in the previous module.
We'll be adding the endpoints in the DynamoDB calls
using the Object Persistence model.
The Object Persistence model is a wrapper around the low-level DynamoDB model.
We are able to store, load, and query DynamoDB using this model.
Out of the three models,
the Object Persistence model is the easiest to code against.
This model enables us to map our client-side classes to our DynamoDB table.
Each object instance then maps to an item in the corresponding table.
While we're able to do most things with this model,
one of the big missing features is the ability to create, update, and delete DynamoDB tables.