In our demo, we will create a new .NET Core web application.
We will then create the folders and classes that we will use in the next
module to add the code needed to interact with DynamoDB.
We will install the AWS SDKs and set up our DynamoDB client.
We will then jump into the AWS Management Console where we will create an
IAM role. This will allow us to get credentials. We will add these
credentials to our credentials file that our DynamoDB client will use.
Here I have Visual Studio 2019 opened.
We want to create our MovieRank application so head along to File, New, Project.
And if you're using Visual Studio 2019 and have the .NET Core SDK installed,
you'll be able to search for and find the ASP.NET Core Web Application.
We're going to select this and click Next.
We will enter MovieRank as our solution name and click Create.
When creating a .NET Core project, we are offered different
starting templates that we can use.
We're going to use the Empty template.
Once our solution has loaded,
we're going to head along to the Startup class. In .NET Core 3,
Microsoft has changed the way that we add our MVC pipeline.
Previously, we would add services.AddMvc. This would load up a bunch of stuff,
including stuff that you might not need.
Microsoft has decided to split this out. For us, we're
creating a web API, so we only need to load up the
controllers. Inside the ConfigureServices method,
we can add services.AddControllers.
And if we head down to our Configure method,
we can replace what's inside the UseEndoints with endpoints.MapControllers.
This is going to map our controller endpoints for us.
So when a request comes into our web API, our API knows where
to direct this request to. Now we are ready to add some
classes and folders to our Solution.
We'll first add a folder in a controller class.
If we right‑click on our MovieRank project,
select Folder, we'll name this Controllers. Inside this
folder, we'll add a controller class.
We want to add the API Controller ‑ Empty option and
name this controller MovieController.
We will now add a folder named Services. If we
right‑click on our MovieRank solution,
select Add and Folder, and name this Services, this folder will contain an
IMovieRankService interface and also a MovieRankService class.
We will right‑click on our folder and select Add, New Item. Here we'll
select an interface and name our interface IMovieRankService.
We will set our interface to be public.
Once we have created our interface, we will add a new item and select
Class. Here we'll name our class MovieRankService.
Once we have our interface and class created,
we will implement the IMovieRankService interface inside our MovieRankService
class. We will now add another project to our solution.
If we right‑click on the MovieRank solution,
select Add and New Project,
this will be a Class Library, and we'll name it MovieRank.Libs.
This project will hold code that we will write to interact with AWS
using the AWS SDK for .NET. There are a few reasons that I like to
separate this out into separate projects,
one of them being that if we keep all code that we write that uses the AWS SDK,
then we could, at a later stage, decide to swap out
the AWS SDK code for something else.
We would simply remove this project and add another that contains the
code relating to whatever we've swapped it out for.
We will delete the Class1.cs file that was
automatically generated for us as well.
Inside our MovieRank.Libs project, we will add a folder named Repositories.
And inside this folder, we'll be adding an interface named IMovieRankRepository.
We will make sure that our interface is set to public.
Then we create a class named MovieRankRepository.
We make sure that that implements our IMovieRankRepository interface.
We'll also want to make sure this class is set to public. We'll
be mapping the results that will be returned by DynamoDB into
properties that we want to return back to our user, so we'll add
a folder called Mappers.
And inside that folder, we'll create an interface called IMapper.
We'll make sure that's set to public, and we want to add a class named Mapper.
We need to be sure that that implements our IMapper interface, and we
also need to make sure that our class is set to public. We'll be now
creating a Contracts class library project.
We'll be adding four classes to this project,
a MovieRankRequest, MovieRankResponse, MovieResponse, and a MovieUpdateRequest.
We'll make sure that each of these classes have been set to public.
These are the contracts that we'll be using inside our application.
These will contain properties that we'll be using for
what we accept inside a request or what we want to pass
back to the user as a response.
Normally,
I would create classes and interfaces when I need them, as I'm writing the
code to interact with AWS' DynamoDB, but I want to try and separate out
creating our classes and interfaces so we can focus as much as possible in the
next module on the AWS‑specific code. We will now install our AWS SDKs. First
will be the DynamoDB SDK. Remember, this provides us with .NET APIs that we
can use to interact with DynamoDB. If we head to Package Manager Console and
use the install‑package command to install the awssdk.dynamodbv2 NuGet
package, we also want to install this in our MovieRank.Libs project as well.
So if we select our default project to install this in as
MovieRank.Libs and use the same install‑package command as above,
we'll install it in our MovieRank.Libs project.
We now want to install the extensions.netcore.setup NuGet package. This
package allows us to integrate with the .NET Core's configuration and
dependency injection framework to load our AWS credentials into our .NET Core
client. In Package Manager Console, I'll set our default project to MovieRank
and install this package as well.
Now we can head back into our Startup class. Inside the ConfigureServices
method, we need to add the AddAWSService and bind that to our IAmazonDynamoDB
interface. AddAWSService has come from our extensions.netcore.setup SDK and
the IAmazonDynamoDB from our DynamoDB SDK.
If we add services.AddAWSService and bind that to IAmazonDynamoDB.
We also want to set the region where our DynamoDB table
lives. Using the awssdk.extensions.netcore.setup library
that we installed previously,
we'll add services.AddDefaultAWSOptions, we'll new up the
AWSOptions, and will set the Region.
We'll do this by GetBySystemName, and we'll set it to us‑west‑2.
This is where our DynamoDB table lives.
Once we have our region set,
we need to ensure that we add all the appropriate using statements.
I've hardcoded the region in here; however,
you might want to look at moving this into the appsettings.json file and reading it from there.