We will start off with implementing the Object Persistence model.
We will add to our MovieRank template the code needed
to get all items from our database.
we add the ability to get a specific movie using only the
first letter or the first word of the movie.
We want to get the movies a user has ranked,
we will do this based on the movie name.
We need to give users the ability to rank movies,
and we also want to allow them to update an already-ranked movie.
This will allow them to change their mind and update
their ranking score on a specific movie.
We want to allow the users to get an overall movie ranking,
taking in all user's rankings,
and then providing us with the average of those rankings.
If we load up our .NET Core template that we created in the previous module,
we will now add the code to interact with DynamoDB.
We will start off in the Startup.cs class where we want to
register our IMovieRankService interface,
and bind that to our MovieRankService class.
A new feature with .NET Core is that it comes with its own
simple dependency injection container,
which provides us with basic functionality for
registering and resolving dependencies,
making it easy for us to register our dependencies and use
dependency injection inside our application.
We've already used this to register our DynamoDB client.
Let's register our IMovieRankService, we'll register this as a Singleton.
We also need to add the MovieRank.Service using statement as well.
I'm going to delete the unnecessary using statements at the top of our
class because they can become a little distracting.
Heading into our MovieController class,
we can dependency inject our IMovieRankService interface into our controller.
I will add an IMovieRankService field at the top,
and make sure that we add the MovieRank.Services using statement.
We then want to create a constructor.
Inside our constructor, we want to declare our IMovieRankService dependency.
We also want to add a route decorator to the top of our class.
We need to include this route name as part of our request. We'll add the Route movies.