Let's introduce our story and the task that we need to complete.
Movie Rank is the one-stop site that allows people to ran movies,
and it exposes information on what the rankings are for each movie.
We are tasked with creating a .NET Core Web API that will allow either a
mobile app or website to consume this information.
We'll be using DynamoDB as our database to store and
retrieve information from our users.
We want to make sure we understand the use cases before we start
building our DynamoDB data model and creating our table,
so let's go through this now.
For our first use case, we want to allow users to rank movies.
We want to be able to get a full list of movies a user has ranked.
We also want to list all movies a user has ranked for a specific movie name.
And we want to list all movies a user has ranked where
the user isn't sure of the movie name.
We want to provide an overall rank for a specific movie
that combines all user's rankings.
For administrative purposes,
we also want to list all movies and all users stored in our database.
And finally, we want to also allow a user to update an already-ranked movie.
With all that information, we are now able to create our DynamoDB data model.
On screen shows what our data model will look like.
We will set the partition key as the UserId,
and we'll set the MovieName as the sort key.
Both of these combined create a composite primary key.
We will also create a global secondary index,
setting the partition key of this index to MovieName.
As we go through the course and create our application, I'll show you when each of these keys that we have set matter.