We will now start adding the code needed to get all items from our database.
This will be an HttpGet method,
so we'll add the HttpGet decorator to the top of our method.
Then we want to create a method, so we will say public async,
we will set our return type as a Task IEnumerableMovieResponse,
and name our method GetAllItemsFromDatabase.
We need to add a reference to our MovieResponse class
that lives in our Contracts project.
We want to make a call off to our MovieRankService class,
install the response that we get back inside a variable called results.
Because we're using async, we want to add the await keyword.
This awaits the completion of the task, in our case GetAllItemsFromDatabase call.
And we'll call off to our MovieRankService class to a method that we'll
be creating shortly called GetAllItemsFromDatabase.
We'll also return the results that we get back to the user.
And we'll remove the unused using statements at the top of our class.
Heading over to our MovieRankService class,
we want to dependency inject our MovieRankRepository interface.
We'll create a field at the top of our class,
and we'll also want to add a constructor and declare
our IMovieRankRepository dependency.
We need to add a reference to our MovieRank.Libs project,
and we also want to register our IMovieRankRepository
interface in our Startup class.
We'll register this as a Singleton, and bind it to our MovieRankRepository class.
And we'll also need to add a using statement to our
IMovieRankRepository inside our Startup class.
Heading back to our MovieRankService class,
we will now create a method with a return type of IEnumerableMovieResponse,
and call our method GetAllItemsFromDatabase.
We'll be adding a using statement for our MovieResponse contract,
and inside our method we will call off to our
MovieRankRepository class to a method named GetAllItems.
I'm going to add a return null to our method.
This is temporary code that we will change once we know
what we are being returned by DynamoDB.
We're going to have to map our results that we get back from
DynamoDB into our MovieResponse contract.
I've added a return null so our solution will build.
Let's add our GetAllItemsFromDatabase method to the IMovieRankService interface,
and we'll also add the MovieResponse using statement.
I like to clean up the unused using statements as I go,
so let's remove the unnecessary using statements at the top of both the
IMovieRankService interface and our MovieRankService class.
Heading over to our MovieRankRepository class,
this class is where we'll use the methods inside the AWS SDK to
call off to our MovieRank DynamoDB table.
AWS requires us to add the DynamoDB context class.
This is the entry point to the DynamoDB database.
We will create a field at the top of our class private
readonly DynamoDBContext_context.
Inside our constructor, we will new up our DynamoDBContext.
We also need to pass in the Amazon DynamoDB client that we set
up in our Startup class in the last module.
In the constructors parameters, we will add IAmazonDynamoDB dynamoDbClient,
and pass dynamoDbClient into our DynamoDB context.
We will add two using statements.
First the Amazon.DynamoDBv2 .DataModel and also the
Amazon.DynamoDBv2 using statement.
Let's create a method with a return type of IEnumerable MovieDb,
and call our method GetAllItems.
We haven't created the MovieDb model yet, so let's create that now.
We'll add a folder named Models, and Add a MovieDb class to that folder.
Inside this class,
we want to add the properties that our MovieRank table contains.
So we'll add UserId, MovieName, Description, Actors, Ranking, and RankDateTime.
We also need to add a couple of decorators, the first being DynamoDBTable.
The DynamoDbContext will read this model and use the
attribute to get our DynamoDBTable name.
We also want to state what our partition key is,
so we'll add DynamoDBHashKey above UserId.
We'll also add the DynamoDBv2 using statement.
Back in our MovieRankRepository class,
we can now add a using statement to the MovieDb model.
We also want to add a using statement for
System.Threading to allow us to use async.
Inside our method, we can say return await,
and using the DynamoDbContext that we initialized above,
we'll be using the ScanAsync function,
and passing in our MovieDb as the type argument.
Remember, the scan function will scan all items in our database.
This is an expensive process in terms of speed and cost.
We want to try and avoid using scan on queries that we would run often.
The scan async method requires a scan's condition,
even if it's an empty ScanCondition.
So here we'll new up a list of type ScanCondition.
We will also chain the GetRemainingAsync method that will get us
all items from our MovieRank DynamoDB table.
We also want to add the GetAllItems method to our
IMovieRankRepository interface,
and we want to add the appropriate using statements.
Let's also remove the unused using statements from
both the interface and our class.
Navigating back to the MovieRankService class,
we want to map the object that is being returned by
DynamoDB to our MovieResponse contract.
Let's add a field of type IMapper to the top of our MovieRankServices class,
and declare our IMapper dependency.
We'll add the appropriate using statement.
We also want to register our IMapper interface inside our startup class,
and add the appropriate using statement.
Inside our GetAllItemsFromDatabase method,
we want to call off to a method named ToMovieContract.
This doesn't currently exist.
We'll create this shortly.
We'll pass in the response variable as well.
If we head along to our Mapper class,
the object that we get back from DynamoDB is a collection.
We need to run through each item in this collection and
map it to our MovieResponse contract.
We'll add two methods,
the first will have a return type of IEnumerable MovieResponse,
which is the contract that we want to return back to our users.
We'll be taking in a parameter, the IEnumerable MovieDb.
Using the link Select method, we will call off to another method,
each item will then pass through the second method that we're about to create.
And we'll want to also add the appropriate references and using statements.
The second method will be an overload method,
meaning that it will have the same name as our first method,
but the parameters and the return type will be different.
We'll have a return type of MovieResponse,
and we'll pass in MovieDb as the parameter.
Before we go any further,
we want to first create some properties inside our MovieResponse contract.
If we head to our MovieResponse class, and add five properties.
Using the keyword prop and hitting Tab will save me
having to write these out in full.
We will add a string property and call it MovieName,
the second string with the name Description,
third a string, which will be a list of Actors,
the fourth will be an int named Ranking,
and the fifth a string named TimeRanked.
Heading back to our Mapper class, we can now add a return new MovieResponse.
And each item that we are given back from DynamoDB's results will map to a
corresponding property on our MovieResponse contract.
MovieName that is in our MovieResponse contract will be populated
with the results we get back from DynamoDB.
So we can use the parameter argument that our method is using, movie.MovieName.
We will map the rest of the items to our contract properties.
If we head along to our IMapper interface,
we now want to add both methods that we've just created in our Mapper class.
So we're going to add the ToMovieContract, including the overload as well.
We also want to add the appropriate using statements,
and we're going to do a little bit of clean up,
so we're also going to remove the unused using statements
from both the interface and the class.
Let's now save our project, and we'll build it.
Now we want to check that our GetAllItemsFromDatabase is working correctly.
So let's run our application.
I'm going to grab the localhost and the port number, and I'll copy that.
To test each endpoint, I'm going to use the tool Postman.
You can use any HTTP client that you're comfortable with.
I'll grab the localhost and the port that we've just copied earlier,
and paste this into Postman.
Remember we added the route Movies to the top of our Controller class,
so we need to add this to our endpoint.
The method we are trying to hit is a Get,
so we don't need to change anything in there for Postman.
Hit Send, and we're returned back all movies.
Excellent.
I'm going to save each of our queries as we go.
So I'm going over to this Save drop-down arrow, I'm going to select Save As.
In our Request name,
I'm just going to name the same as what our methods are inside our controllers,
GetAllItemsFromDatabase.
We also want to Create a Collection folder,
so we'll select Create Collection, and we'll name it MovieRank. Select the tick, and we'll Save our request into this folder.