Now that we have our table set up,
let's have a look around the DynamoDB service inside the AWS Management Console.
If we start on the left-hand side and we select Dashboard,
this is the main landing page that we will see when
navigating to DynamoDB from the main page,
providing we have a table set up.
This page allows us to create more tables,
it also shows us if we have any Recent alerts from the CloudWatch metrics.
We'll be covering metrics shortly.
We can also see what our Provisioned read and write
capacity that we have set for our tables are.
Let's talk about provision capacity a little more.
DynamoDB allows you to set read and write capacity for your DynamoDB tables.
Settings these will assign resources for your table.
This ensures that the read and write requests to your table have enough
provision resources to serve this amount of requests.
The higher your throughput capacity, the higher the costs.
One read capacity unit represents 1 strongly-consistent read per second,
or 2 eventual consistent reads per second for items up to 4 KB in size.
For anything larger than 4 KB,
then DynamoDB will consume additional read capacity units.
One write capacity unit represents 1 write per
second for items up to 1 KB in size.
Again, if you need to write items that are larger than 1 KB in size,
then DynamoDB will consume additional write capacity units.
Back in the AWS Management Console,
we are able to set our read and write capacity by heading along to Tables,
and selecting our table, MovieRank in our case.
Then heading along to the Capacity tab,
here we can set the Read and Write capacity units for
both our table and our secondary index.
DynamoDB also shows you an estimated cost associated
with your set read and writes.
For our demo application, let's set our Dynamo read and writes from 5 to 1,
and hit Save.
A good way to see what your read and write capacity is versus what your
consumed read and writes are is by looking at the Metrics tab.
If we head along to the Metrics tab,
we can see both the Read and Write capacity graphs.
Since we have only just created this table,
and we haven't yet started using it, our consumed rate is at 0,
but it would be represented as a blue line,
whereas the red line is our provisioned amount.
If we scroll down the Metrics page,
we can see the Read and Write metrics for our secondary index as well.
Scrolling down a bit further,
we get Latency metrics letting us know what the request times are,
and further down we can also see what the Scan and Query counts are.
Another useful metric is the Errors metrics, where you're able to see if we have had any errors being returned.