For our next endpoint,
we will get all movies that a user has ranked using the UserId
and the movieName like we did previously,
but this time we'll use a sort filter with a ScanCondition of BeginsWith.
This will allow a user to query a movie that they have
ranked by entering only the first letter or the first word
of a movie they have ranked, as they might have forgotten the full movie name.
This is also a good opportunity to show how the query filters work.
In our controller class, we will add an HttpGet decorator,
and add a route, the route that we will use will be Route user/ curly braces,
userId, so we can pass in the userId/rankedMovies/ curly braces,
movieName, so we can pass in the movie name as well.
Our method will have a return type of Task IEnumerable MovieResponse,
and our method name will be GetUsersRankedMoviesByMovieTitle.
We'll accept two parameters, userId and movieName.
Inside our method,
we will call off to our MovieRankService class to a method inside
that class called GetUsersRankedMoviesByMovieTitle,
and pass in our userId and movieName arguments.
We will also return the results back to our user.
Heading over to our MovieRankService class,
we want to create a method with a return type of Task IEnumerable MovieResponse,
and a method name of GetUsersRankedMoviesByMovieTitle.
This method will also accept a userId and a movieName as parameters.
And inside our method,
we will call off to our Repository class to a method
named GetUsersRankedMoviesByMovieTitle.
And we'll also pass in the userId and the movieName.
Like in our previous methods,
we want to map the response that we get back from DynamoDB
into our IEnumerable MovieResponse contract.
We also need to add this method to our interface.
Heading over to our MovieRankRepository,
let's create a method that will have a return type of Task IEnumerable MovieDb,
and we'll call our method GetUsersRankedMoviesByMovieTitle.
We'll add a userId and movieName,
and in this method we're going to use DynamoDB's query function.
We'll pass in a ScanCondition,
and we'll set up our ScanCondition to query movies from a user based on the
movie name where the user wasn't sure of the full movie name,
but they might know what it begins with.
We'll first new up a DynamoDBOperationConfig.
Inside here, we can set a query filter.
We then new up a ScanCondition list, and new up a ScanCondition.
Inside our ScanCondition, we will specify our DynamoDB table's property name,
in our case it's MovieName, and we'll add the ScanOperator.BeginsWith.
The ScanOperator is borrowed from the DynamoDB's document model.
So we need to add a using statement pointing to DynamoDB's document model,
as the Object Persistence model doesn't have a ScanOperator that we can use.
This also shows that we can use different models and combine them together.
I would normally try and use one model and stick to it,
unless I run into situations like this,
where a certain model doesn't contain a function that we need.
The ScanOperator contains other operators such as greater than,
less than, contains, etc.
And we'll also query on the partial movieName that was passed through to us.
We will set a return await, and using our DynamoDB's context,
we will use the QueryAsync method.
Our search is based on the userId,
so we'll add userId inside the QueryAsync's parameters,
and we'll also pass in our config that we created
above that contains our ScanCondition.
We also add GetRemainingAsync to tell DynamoDB that we
want all items that it finds back.
We also need to make sure that we've added our new method to our interface.
I'll save our application, and I'll build it as well.
If we run our application, head over to Postman,
we will add our localhost, and using the route that we created,
I'll add a userId of 1 and the first letter of a
movie name that user has ranked.
So I'll add F.
Hit Send.
And we're given back results based on the userId and movieNames that
the user has ranked that start with the letter F. I'll also save this query to our Postman collection.