[Autogenerated] in this module,
we're going to focus in on the key topics that you
need to understand to pass the exam.
At this point,
hopefully you've been through the first module and
taking the time to prepare yourself,
build your mental model and get a better understanding of labs.
This module will assume that you have your mental model in place.
We will go through a fine tuning process to help you prepare for your exam.
The topics in this module will be very high level and exam focused.
Let's get started.
AWS consists of many types of services,
and new services are being added all the time.
Since this is an associate level exam,
the focus is more of breadth of knowledge rather than depth.
That being said,
the sheer number of services available in AWS can be overwhelming.
This diagram is meant to summarize all the categories of
services available within a to be us.
However, within each of these categories, there are many individual services.
Fortunately, you don't have to know anything about many of these services,
so let's break this down a little bit further to
make it a little easier for you.
I've taken the list of 19 categories of services and broken them down to 10.
This is a much more manageable group of key services for the exam.
Even within this list,
there's still far too many services to master for this exam,
and the exam blueprint does not map 1 to 1 with many of these knowledge areas.
But these are the topics that you must learn to fit into that
blueprint to be successful on the exam,
and my goal is to help take you through that process and
fit those services to the blueprint.
Let's go through the exam blueprint in the key knowledge areas and
start to break it into easier to understand objectives.
As you can see,
the exam is broken into multiple knowledge areas and built
around the well architected framework.
From this chart,
you can see that three of these objectives make up 82% of the exam questions,
even though it might be tempting just to focus on these areas,
I do not recommend this approach for two reasons.
First,
these three categories will have some of the most
difficult questions from the entire exam,
and secondly,
cost related questions are among some of the easiest questions on the exam,
so you want to give yourself the best chance to pass the
exam by studying all the exam objectives.
Let's review the exam blueprint and then break each
objective into more tangible parts.
The first exam objective is designed resilient architectures.
As you can see, it consists of four areas of focus.
The second exam objective is designed high performing architectures,
and it also consists of four areas of focus.
Our goal will be to relate each of these objectives to specific AWS
services like elastic block Store or S3 or E C.
Two.
As examples.
58% of your exam questions will come from these two objectives.
The third exam objective is designed secure applications and architectures,
and the final exam Objective-C is designed cost optimized architectures.
These two objectives each have three areas of focus, and we will also look at examples of specific AWS services for these