[Autogenerated] you may be surprised to discover that the initial pass
rate for AWS certification exams is less than 25%.
Ouch!
When some of you here this statistic, it may discourage you.
And for others, it will feel like a challenge.
The primary reason that students fell the exam is because they try
to treat it like any other certification exam.
If you approach the exam this way, you will likely fail as well.
Hello and welcome everyone to demystifying the AWS
Certified Solutions Architect associate exam.
My name is Dustin.
Bring Berry.
And in this course I'm gonna show you strategies that I used to
achieve A W s mastery and how I then prepared to pass the AWS
Certified Solutions Architect associate exam and the other AWS
certification exams as well.
In this course,
I'm gonna begin by talking to you about what it means to achieve A W s mastery.
And I'll offer recommendations on what I did to become
an AWS master in the final module.
We will deep dive the exam itself and focus on the exam blueprint
and review strategies to help you pass the exam.
Now that we've over viewed the content for this course,
let's move into the details.
AWS has designed their infrastructure around services,
and there are many categories of services within AWS.
As you can see from this diagram to the novice,
this can feel really overwhelming because there's so
many different components to AWS.
Even within each of these categories where we see these service categories,
there are multiple services in many cases.
So it would be really nice if AWS told us what specific
services were covered on the exam.
But unfortunately they do not.
Looking at the exam blueprint,
you will discover their ARF knowledge areas that are
required to succeed on the example.
But again,
AWS does not provide us with a breakdown of what services are involved in this.
Instead,
they give us categories based off of the well architected framework model,
and questions will be scenario based on the exam using these categories.
If you're completely new to AWS,
these breakdown will not make a lot of sense to you.
So if we're trying to master AWS itself,
this category approach is not really going to help us.
We'll refer back to this diagram later in the course when we
actually get into discussion of the exam itself.
To help you dissect this information,
I would like to present you with a more refined A list of AWS services that
you can focus on to pass the exam with this new view.
Instead of looking at 18 categories, we're only going to need to focus on 10.
Initially, this still might seem like a lot,
but many of these services inter operate with each other as we're going to see is we go through this process.