[Autogenerated] So we started this module discussing the exam
blueprint and how did decipher its cryptic meaning.
We then took the five objectives from the exam and broke
them down into services or concepts.
As part of the discussion in each of the sections,
we went over some practice questions for each Objective-C.
We concluded the module the brief discussion about the exam
itself and talked about some strategies and best practices to
maximize your score on the exam.
If you did everything we talked about throughout this course,
you should be ready for the exam.
When you get into the testing center, just relax.
Take a deep breath.
You did all the hard work.
You are prepared and you're qualified to pass the exam.
Your attitude going into the exam can impact your score
on whether you are successful or not.
So have a positive attitude.
And if you come to a question that you don't understand,
skip it and come back to it later.
Now go crush the exam. Good luck