(videogame whirling)
(coin dinging)
(videogame chiming)
(videogame whirling)
- [Instructor] Sometimes you do a commit,
but you immediately realize
that you need to change one more thing.
Instead of doing a new commit with a different message,
how do you add something to a previous commit?
I'll give you a couple of seconds to think
about how you would do something like that.
(videogame whirling) (8-bit music)
(videogame chiming)
(videogame whirling)
Now, again, this one's pretty easy,
and it's called amending your commit.
I'm updating the version of this project to Bootstrap.
So I'm going to start by going to the package.json file
and bumping up my version to 2.0.0.
So I'll save this, and I'm going to call this.
So I'm going to add this, and I'm going to commit this
with a message of "Bumping up Bootstrap Version."
Now, what I need to do next would be add
the Bootstrap CSS and JavaScript.
Already downloaded them from the Bootstrap site.
So I'm going to come in here, and let's look
at what's in the css folder.
Add the bootstrap min and the bootstrap css map.
So let's go ahead and add those.
Here is all the bootstrap CSS files.
There's quite a bit of them. So we'll add the Bootstrap.
So we'll add the bootstrap min.css
as well as the bootstrap min.css.map
that I already have in here.
These are the older versions.
So I'll just replace them in here,
and then I'll do a git status.
I'll see that there's two files to add.
So I'll go ahead and add those.
Now, I can't commit this, but if I want to just add them
to the previous commit, then I can issue.
Let's go ahead and clear this.
I can issue a git commit with the amend option.
Now, for some reason, I'll always want
to type two Ms for amend, and sometimes
I forget about the two dashes.
So just be careful there.
Now, if I do this, it will open up a text editor
and allow me to add a message.
If I want to change the message
I can rename this message something other
than what I've already typed.
So I could say something like
"Added New Version of Bootstrap" here.
Now, if I clear this out, and I do a git log,
you'll notice that my last commit is now added
a new version of Bootstrap.
If you would've done this git log command earlier,
you would've noticed that this hash is
different than it was before.
Now, I know that I also need
to update the JavaScript version,
and I forgot to do that.
So I'm going to open up this JavaScript folder, lib,
and then there are files in here
that I need to update, this bootstrap bundle
and the bootstrap bundle min js map.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Come over here. It's editor.
So it should be here.
Let's come over here,
and we'll open up the JavaScript folder,
and we need to do the bootstrap bundle min.js
as well as the map.
We'll copy them here,
and we'll just hit Replace a couple times
and again, if I do a git status,
it's going to show me those two new files.
I'll add them and in this case,
I'm going to do a git commit, amend,
and I can include a no-edit option because the message
that I had written previously is just fine.
Now it updated the files,
and I was able to add something to my previous commit,
and this only works with your previous commit.
So if I do a clear, and I show the Git log,
you'll see that even though I added
a new set of files, it rewrote this commit.
Again, notice that it is a different hash
than it was just a minute ago,
and it included the previous message
since I added the no-edit option.
So this is quite a handy command when you need
to just add something else to the previous commit.
Now, this isn't really safe for commits
that have already been pushed.
That's because someone may have already cloned
an old commit with the previous messages.
So that would get a little bit confusing,
but if you're just working on your local directory,
this is one that I use all the time.