(electronic computer game music)
- Sometimes it's good to be able to send your work
to more than one location,
but how do you manage to send changes
to more than one repos?
I'll give you a couple
of seconds to think about how you'd something like this.
(electronic music)
Now the answer is understanding remotes.
You're probably used to adding your remote
when you first open a project,
by issuing a git remote
and then add, then plus a name that's usually origin,
whenever you get started,
and then you use a URL right here.
Now there's a number of other commands
that you can use in addition to this.
So you can change of course
the name to something like "working"
if you're working with a specific project,
and then add another remote.
You can just push to more than one place if you want to.
Now, you can also remove an existing origin
and also do things like "get-url"
and also for example,
get or change the URL of a specific remote.
So let's do a get-url
and I know that I already have the origin set right here,
and this is the link to the current origin.
So if I want to,
I can go to github and type in something like github.new
to create a new remote
and I'm going to call this one parallax_working
and this will let me create a working project
for this parallax repos.
So I'll hit Create Repository
and notice that here, it's going to tell me
the usual sort of how I would add the project.
So normally I would say "git remote add"
and then I would put the name "origin"
and type in the URL of this project.
So now if we go back here and we say,
"git remote add"
and I'm going to call this "working"
and then I'll paste that URL,
and now I have a new remote that I can push things to.
So now I can say "git push"
and instead of origin, I can say "working"
and now this is all being pushed to my working remote.
You can add as many remotes as you want,
and this is useful
for when you want to work in different places.
So for example, you can have the remote that you use
for a different purpose,
and I don't like to keep things on my local directory,
it's safer to create a local remote on GitHub
that I can push to and I can feel safe,
and then whenever I feel that the project has been tested,
then I can push it to my sort of final URL or final remote.
Usually I use the origin name for that
and it can be a much safer way to work.