(electronic music)
- [Instructor] Let's say you're working hard
on a new feature
and your boss calls you
and all of a sudden you needs to jump
on another feature branch.
Is there a way to work on more than one branch
at the same time?
I'll give you a couple of seconds to think about
how you would do something like that.
(bouncy playful music)
Now you may have been thinking about using stashes
and that works okay,
but worktrees are a lot more powerful.
So you can issue a git worktree command
and you can see all of the options.
We can add,
we can list,
we can remove worktrees if we want to.
Now let's clear this out,
and I'll show you that I have a couple of uncommitted files.
And it doesn't even matter.
If I want to pull something and...
Let's take a look at some of the branches that I have here.
So let's say that I wanted to work with 04_01b locally
and not have to stash anything,
just very quickly jump into that branch.
I'm not even going to check it out from here.
So I'm going to do a git worktree add.
So I want to work on a folder that's at the same level
of this current folder called parallax.
And so I'll do 04_01b
and that's going to create a new worktree.
So if we take a look now at our desktop,
you can see that it added a new folder right here.
And this is the folder for this new worktree.
So I can do a git worktree list,
and it's going to show me two different worktrees.
If I went to switch to that folder,
I can do a cd and then go to that folder.
So dot, dot slash means go back a directory,
and then I'm going to go back into this directory.
And now I'm in this other folder
and I can work on my changes.
Now you would have to issue an NPM install
because this doesn't have any of the node modules in it
if you wanted to,
but this is a great way of working
on more than one branch in your project
at the same time with minimal effort.
If you want to get rid of this,
let's go ahead and go back.
Let's go ahead and go back to the parallax folder.
So I'm going to do cd ../parallax
and now we're back in the parallax folder.
I can do a git worktree list
and then do a git worktree remove 04_01b
and that'll get rid of that other worktree.
So we'll do a worktree list again.
You can see that it's gone.
This is a really cool and quick way
of working on different parts of your project.
Again, especially useful when you need to work
on another branch,
but you don't want to do anything to the current branch
where you've been making a lot of changes.
And perhaps you just need to, maybe...
I know that in my blog I often...
I'm working on new features,
but I want to sort of add a new article
in the current version of the site.
So you can have as many worktrees
as you want in your folder.
And it's sort of cool
because Git lets you manage those directly in its interface.