(video game music)
- [Instructor] We all do quick fixes on our work,
and that can create a very messy look in history.
So how do you rewrite your commit history
to clean or combine quick fixes
that you may have made along the way?
I'll give you a couple seconds to think
about how you would do something like this.
(video game music)
All right, so anytime we want to rewrite history
in a more complete manner,
you want to use a command called a rebase,
and it look something like this, git rebase.
And then you can choose an interactive option,
which is really always the best one to use.
And then we can also specify how many commits
we want to go back to.
You can see that I'm in the fixup branch.
Let's take a look at the log,
and we'll do a oneline option here.
And I've got three different commits
that I've placed right here,
and I want to rewrite them so that they are a single commit.
So let's go ahead and hit Q to get out of here.
And so I'll go ahead and issue a git rebase
with the minus i option for interactive.
And then I'm only going to be looking at the last four commits.
So when I issue this command,
it's going to open up your default editor.
Now, that can be just an editor in your terminal
where you can modify that if you want to.
I happen to use one called Atom.
It's a little bit easier.
You can also configure Visual Studio code
to be your editor.
I like to have a separate place that I use
rather than the editor that I'm working with,
and that's why I choose Atom.
It's just a different editor, right?
So from here, you can see
that we have these different commits, last four commits,
and they are in reverse order.
Remember, this one was sort of at the top before,
and now it's kind of at the bottom.
And then we have these other commits.
You'll notice there was a keyword called pick
at the beginning of all these.
This just means that you are not going to really do anything
with those commits.
You can see the explanation here.
You're just going to use the commit whenever you say pick.
If you wanted to do something with these other commits,
you can then change what it says instead of pick
to something else.
You can see the different options right here.
The one that we're interested in is called a squash commit.
It's going to use the commit,
but it's going to meld it into the previous one.
So if I want to, I can type in squash right here,
or just type in the first letter right here,
it's just an s, so we can just do s here and s here,
and then we'll leave this one alone.
Now, this editor lets you pretty much do whatever you want
with your commit history.
So I can reorder the history
by just putting it somewhere else.
So I can maybe move this pick right over here,
or whatever else I want to do.
And you can see that all these different other options
are available to you, as well.
But what I want to do is squash these two into this commit,
and I'm going to save now,
and then I'm going to close out of here.
So when I close, it's actually going to open up
the editor again to let me edit the commit messages.
And so because I'm combining three commits,
it's going to let me edit the messages
that would go into this new commit.
And what I really want to do here
is just go ahead and have a single message.
So I'm going to comment the commit messages out,
and then just change this one to say update it
to bootstrap 5, right?
So I'm going to save this,
and then I'll close out of this again.
And you could see that it's going to create a new commit
for me and rebase everything.
You could see that it's going to do a lot of things for me,
including combining all those files
and making everything into one commit.
So if I do a git log --oneline here,
I'll be able to see that my three commits
are now combined into this single commit, new hashtag here,
and then the other commit that I had after that
is still there.
All my commits before are also still there.
And I'm able to completely rewrite the history of my project
using this technique.
And that's usually pretty good to clean things up
whenever I have a complicated commit.
It's better to create a lot of commits
and then come back and clear your history
because that way you're just making small changes
at each commit.
And then you can really control what you want
your history to look like with this rebase command,
knowing that you can use squash whenever you want
to sort of get rid of extra commits
and combine them all into one.