(tones ringing)
- [Instructor] Most projects have
what we call a main branch,
and this is where the canonical history
of the project lives.
Now, occasionally, you need a way to establish
that certain commits in that main commit history
are finished versions of the project.
How does Git help you do that?
I'll give you a couple of seconds to think about
how you would do something like this.
(tones ringing)
(upbeat music)
Now the answer to this is tags,
and this is how you can create an identifier
for a specific commit that will show you later
that you have reached a version of the project.
So if I do a git log command,
you can see all of the different commits right here.
So I can choose a specific commit and identify it
as a current version of the project.
Now if you just use the git tag command
and then you add a version,
and typically the versions are named like this,
use the keyword v,
and then you specify a large version number,
and then sort of another medium version number,
and a small version number.
This is called semver and it means that,
the last number means that you're creating a change
in your project that doesn't break the project.
The second number would be a new version
that is not a major version of the project,
so it's sort of a little bit better
that it's not like a bug fix for the current project,
but some sort of big change that may break some things.
And then updating this first number means
that this is a major change in your project.
So I'm just going to hit return right here,
and it doesn't look like it did anything,
but now if I just issue the git tag command by itself,
I can see that there is one version
of this project, version 2.0.1.
So I'm going to hit Q and I'm going to do a git log.
I'll do the one line version here, and that's going to show me
that the last commit that I have has a tag of 2.0.1.
And that's going to show up on GitHub as a release.
I can pick another version here.
So let's say that I wanted to identify this
as maybe version 2.0 of that project,
and then I'm going to hit Q,
and once again I'll do a git tag.
I'll do v2.0.0, and this time I'm going to paste the ID
of the commit that I want to specify as having that tag.
So if I hit return,
again, it doesn't look like it did anything,
but I'll issue the git tag command again,
and now I can see that there's two versions.
Let's do one more.
So git log --oneline.
It's going to show me this long history
and I'll just keep on scrolling until I see
that there is sort of a place where I appear
to have finished my project right here.
So this is say the final state.
So I'm going to consider this as version one.
So I'm going to copy that hash, hit the Q key,
and I'll just back up, hitting the up arrow until I get
to this right here, and I'll paste that new commit.
I want to make sure that I say that this is version one,
not version two.
I hit Enter, and now in my git tag command
I can see three different commits.
Now, if I want to delete a commit
because these can be rearranged at any point in time,
then all I do is git tag -d,
and then one of the names of the tag
that you want to delete.
So this will be like v1.0.0.
And now that tag is gone, so if I issue a git tag command,
it's going to no longer be on this list.
So tags will help you identify a point in your main branch
where you have reached a version of the project.
And again, if you go to GitHub
that's going to show up as a release,
and you can always rearrange these, rename these,
or just assign any part of your commit as a new tag.