(video game music)
- [Instructor] In the old days, it was common
to name the main branch master and today it's common
to call it main.
Now, how do you change an older project to
use a different name and also set
up your environment to use main as the default?
I'll give you a couple seconds to think
about how you would do something like this.
(game music)
The first part is pretty easy.
All you have to do is go to your reboot
and rename the default branch.
So you can see right here
that my default branch right now is named master.
So I could just hit this edit button right here
and just change the name of this to main.
However, notice that it does say that rename in
this branch will not update your members' local environment.
So you do need to let people know that you are
renaming the project's branch from master to main.
So if I refresh this page, you'll see
that now it's called main, all is good in the project repo.
However, I need to take care of things locally.
So let's go ahead and close this out.
Here's my project locally notice the branch right now
is called master.
Now to change the name of a branch is actually pretty easy.
Use a git, and then branch, then you say MV for move.
And this is sort of weird to me.
And actually this needs to be a flag.
So minus MV, and then you just give it the name
that it used to be called.
So we're going to change master
and then we're going to take that to main.
So if I hit return, notice that the branch is renamed
to main.
Now that doesn't solve the problem of what happens
if I did a git init in a new project.
Whatever I have set up as my default for the configuration
of git is what name would be assigned to a new repository.
So let's go ahead and clear this out.
To change that, I can change the global configuration
right from the terminal.
I can issue a git config and then do a global command here.
So this will mean for any project that you create
in this machine, I'm going to change in it
default branch and change that to main.
And that's all you need to do from now on.
Anytime you do a git init on a folder, it's going to assume
that you want to use main as the name of your branch.
And since you already did it at the project level,
now everything will be in sync.