(video game music)
- [Instructor] Let's say you're working on a branch
to update some of the libraries
that you're using in your project.
However, after a bit you realize
that it would be fine to bring some of those commits
over to the main branch.
How do you bring only specific commits
from one branch to another?
I'll give you a couple seconds to think
about how you would do something like this.
(video game music)
Now, what I would do here
is use a feature called cherry picking.
Now, cherry picking allows you to pick specific commits
from one branch and move them to a different place.
So if I do a git branch right here,
you'll notice that I have two different branches,
main and updates.
And if I go into the updates branch,
you'll see that some of the changes that have been made here
are importing a different JavaScript file, different CSS,
and there's some other changes to make this dropdown work
'cause that's one of the things that we'll break
from bootstrap 4 to 5,
which is the library that I'm using here.
Now, if I take a look at the log for this branch,
so oneline, you'll see that I made three specific commits
that I want to bring into the other branch.
So I updated the JavaScript and CSS files.
Then I modified some of the margin and padding,
and then I fixed this dropdown.
And I started making some additional changes,
so I'm working on updating the version
of another library called GSAP,
but I realized that I can actually go ahead
and bring these other changes into the main branch.
So what I'm going to do here is I'll copy these,
and then I'm going to just make a new file.
And what I want to do
is bring in these three commits in order,
so I'm going to delete all these sort of comments
and just paste these commits in sequence
one right after the other.
So these are the commits,
and I want to make sure that I do them in the order
that I want them to come in.
So I'm going to copy this,
and let's go ahead and come over here.
I'll hit Q to get out of here,
and I'm going to go back into my main branch.
So I'll checkout main, right, back into main.
And now let's clear this out.
I want to do the git cherry-pick,
and I'm going to paste these three commits
that I want to bring in from the other branch.
Now, if I just do this,
what it's going to do is bring in those three commits
as three different commits.
If I don't want to bring in the commits
as separate elements,
what I can do is just bring in the changes
without the commits.
So by adding this minus n,
it's going to let me sort of bring in all the changes,
and I can take a look at what's actually different
from this particular main branch
and the commits that I've made.
So let me just go ahead and do that.
And you'll see that my Visual Studio code
has given me some indication of what I have modified.
If I do a git status right now,
you'll see all of the different changes
from the previous commit that I had on this project.
And they're just the things that you would expect,
new index file, a new bootstrap, JavaScript, and CSS
as well as there's always a few little modifications
on the package-lock, that JSON file,
so we can ignore that.
But those commits are fine.
And I want to test out to make sure
that my dropdown is working.
Everything looks pretty much like it did before.
So now I can go ahead and git add all these files
and git commit and go ahead and say
just update it to bootstrap 5.
I like having the n option there
so that you can actually test things out
and make sure that you're comfortable
with whatever changes were made.
I can close out of this.
I really love this ability to cherry pick specific commits
from all over the place.
A lot of times people use this
when they actually commit something to the wrong branch.
You don't realize that you are in a different branch,
and then you want to just bring something into main
that you have done in a separate branch.
This is really useful in a lot of different ways.
And there's also, just like with anything else in git,
a lot of options,
so you can check the documentation
for some additional features.