I'm back on the Speaker entity,
and I'm ready to deal with setting up the speaker photo.
This ultimately means that we have binary data so that we can store the photo.
And working with binary data can be a pain,
and we need to handle a couple of gotchas to get things running correctly.
Let's begin by defining a class attribute for the speaker photo column.
That will look like this.
Notice its data type is a byte array,
which is well suited for binary data in Java.
Next, we'll go ahead and add the getters and setters in IntelliJ,
right-click, and generate those, and save the file.
To get JPA to stream the binary data into this field,
we need to add a couple more annotations.
Import the type class as the org.hibernate .annotations and make
sure that you're Lob class is imported as well,
and let's quickly talk about what these annotations do.
The first annotation is a Lob, and it stands for large object.
Binary data can get really large,
and this annotation helps JPA deal with the larger data.
The second annotation is needed to help Hibernate deal with binary data.
In our case,
Hibernate is the JPA implementation that we're using under the covers.
Without this annotation,
you'd ultimately end up with an exception when JPA queries the data
and tries to push it into the Session instance.
Finally, there's one last piece of configuration needed to get JPA,
Postgres, and binary data all happy.
I'm going to jump back to the application properties file,
which if you remember, is in src, main, resources.
Open that.
I'm going to add a new property that looks like this.
This property is needed so the Postgres JDBC driver can
create a Lob correctly on the Java side.
Again, without this property configuration,
you'll get exceptions when you try to run the application.
A note on binary data,
these little issues can be troublesome when you're working through your app
from scratch and you have not encountered them before.
Hopefully this part of the course gives you enough of a background that
you can get past these problems and have a solid app base to work on
some of your own app needs going forward.
We're finally finished with the JPA entities. Let's go ahead and move up the architectural stack to repositories.