Creating a Spring Boot starter configuration class of your own is not that hard.
If you're a company that has lots of projects,
you'll probably want to have some core JAR files that provides utility or
helper classes that all of your other applications can use.
Auto-configuration classes are useful in this scenario.
These classes work very similar to the Java
configuration class that we just built.
You'll need to create a basic class and annotate it
with the @Configuration annotation.
Next,
you can add methods that define beans and functionality
that you want to provide for your starter.
Last,
you'll need to add a declaration in the spring.factories file
that you're registering in auto configuration.
Spring Boot will inspect JAR files on your class path for this
spring.factories file and then bootstrap your auto-configuration files.
The spring.factories file typically lives in resources/META-INF.
Finally,
there are a host of annotations that Spring Boot provides that allow
you to specify conditions on your auto configuration.
For example,
if you're building some auto configuration that is
dependent on a Postgres JDBC driver, you could specify that at the class level,
it's conditional on the driver being present.
If it's there, your auto-configuration will magically wire stuff up,
and if it's not there, your configuration will simply do nothing.
This is one reason why starters are so powerful and do so much simply by
including the dependency on your project in the class path.
Clever teams and developers will already have the gears turning in
their heads on how they can utilize this concept in their projects and organizations for their common functionality.