Now that our controllers are created and updated, we're ready to test this out.
So I'm simply going to start up the application, and let's see what happens.
In IntelliJ, if you want to start the application,
you can find the ConferenceDemoApplication object,
double-click on that or just select it in the Project explorer area,
right-click and go to the Run menu.
If all is well in your application,
you'll get a notification that we have our application started on port 8080,
and it's ready to try out.
I've jumped over to Postman,
and Postman is a tool that allows you to work with API endpoints.
You can get it from the URL getpostman.com.
Once you have it installed, you can enter endpoints and URLs to test and try out.
If you remember, our application is running on port 8080,
and I'm running locally, so I'm using localhost port 8080,
and our session's endpoint begins with api/v1/sessions.
I don't need to pass in any headers or body,
so I'm simply just going to try this out.
And before I do, note that we're using the HTTP GET verb.
You'll notice that we'll get a payload down here,
and you'll see that we have a lot of information pulled back.
It's actually pulling back a bunch of nested data.
You can see this here.
It keeps getting deeper and deeper, and this is kind of a problem.
This is actually a serialization problem.
You can try out speakers as well.
And again, we get the data back,
but it's looping cyclically over our many-to-many relationship.
So let's jump back over to IntelliJ and see how we can handle this.
So sometimes your cyclical payload serializations will actually get so large
that you'll get exceptions because it'll just go infinitely,
and it'll blow up the stack on your Java stack.
So to help with this,
you can jump into your models and place some annotations on there that Jackson
library will look at and help to serialize your payload.
The other option that you could do is to create DTOs,
or data transfer objects, but I'm simply going to use my entities for entities,
as well as data transfer objects.
So if you remember on the session,
we have a many-to-many relationship set up that's going out to speakers,
and this is what's causing that cyclical problem.
Because as we go out to the speaker, the speaker is on multiple sessions,
and as we go into the session, the session has multiple speakers,
and it keeps going over and over.
Since we defined the session as the dominant side of
the bidirectional relationship,
we'll go ahead and leave this alone and jump over to the
speakers version of the many-to-many relationship.
On this one,
we can add a new annotation that will prevent it from
back serialization back to the sessions.
We can do that by adding the @JsonIgnore.
You'll need to import that,
and you'll see that this comes from the Jackson library.
So Jackson is going to look for this and ignore that
when it goes to reload the sessions.
I can now go ahead and restart the server and try the call again.
To restart the server,
you can just click on this encircle or recycle arrow to restart the server.
Once that's up, we can jump back to Postman,
and let's go ahead and try the sessions again.
At this point, you'll notice that the payload has changed.
The payload loads in a session.
It loads in the relevant speakers for that session,
but it does not continue to go deeper and deeper because of that
JsonIgnore annotation we put on the speaker entity.
Let's go ahead and test a couple of the other controller endpoints.
So the next one is the GET where we need to pass in a specific id.
You can see that we have one here, session_id of 2,
so I'm going to pass that in on the URL,
and we should just get this one session back.
Uh, oh!
You'll notice that there is an error that's occurred on our call.
This is another serialization issue with Spring and Hibernate.
Let's jump back to IntelliJ, and we can see how to fix this particular problem.
You'll notice that it's complaining about the ByteBuddyInterceptor.
So again, we'll deal with serialization issues on our models.
So I'm going to go to the sessions model or entity,
and I'm going to add a new annotation at the top at the
class level that looks like this.
The @JsonIgnoreProperties, we'll go ahead and import that class.
This time,
we're ignoring a property called the
hibernateLazyInitializer and the handler property.
When you create an entity and you have a relationship on here,
Hibernate adds a few stub methods to handle lazy loading
and eager loading of the relational data.
When you go to serialize a Hibernate object,
you do not want to serialize this because this will try to
load in all of your relational data with SQL,
and it can cause problems.
And in fact, our problem right now is we have an exception.
So I'll save this file, and I want to add this as well to the Speaker class.
Again, I'll save those files and restart the server.
So back in Postman,
let's go ahead and try to get the session with the primary key id of 2,
again, by calling Send.
This time, you'll notice that we did not get an exception,
and we have a valid payload back, and it's just the one,
it's just the one for primary key of 2.
We'll go ahead and test out the Create.
In Postman, when you're creating something,
you want to set the HTTP verb to POST, and you need to pass in a body.
You can do that on the Body tab here.
I've selected the raw with the JSON payload so I can pass in a payload here,
and we can see that I have given my new session a name,
a description, and a length.
Down at the bottom here, you can see that we have a status of 200,
meaning that it succeeded, and we have a new session.
It's been issued an id of 94.
This is what the sequence on the Postgres database automatically did for us.
And we have all of the data that we passed in.
We can try an update.
Again, if you remember, the update takes the PUT verb,
and let's go ahead and update the session that I just created,
which was 94.
We'll take a look at the updated attributes.
Again,
we're requiring all three of these attributes because
it is a PUT rather than a PATCH.
We'll send that off to the server.
Again, our status is 200 OK,
and you can see that the data coming back was we updated
session 94 with the new data we passed to it.
And finally, to round out our CRUD endpoints, we can try the DELETE out.
Since we created a new session with id 94,
I'll just go ahead and delete that because I know it
does not have any children data.
We don't need to pass anything into the body,
and we change the verb to DELETE, send that off,
and we got a 200 back.
So if you got a 400, or a 404, or a 500,
those are all problems that have occurred.
Either the URL is wrong for a 404.
If you've got a 500, there's some kind of a exception happening on your server,
and that's where you'll want to go ahead and jump back to
IntelliJ and look at the console output.
This is where all of the problems will show up,
and you can see anything that has happened here that might have caused an error.
And that's it!
I'll go ahead and let you try out the speaker endpoints.
Assuming everything is working for your speaker endpoints as well,
we have essentially built a full-blown application on the
server side in the last 25-30 minutes.
You can see that Spring Boot is very quick at building things,
especially, if you're familiar with the other Spring frameworks, like Spring MVC and Spring Data JPA, as well as JPA and entities.