At this point,
you should know enough about Spring Boot to take your app from creation all
the way to app deployment in a production environment.
Here's what we covered in this last section of the course
and what some of your takeaways should be.
First, Spring Boot uses a containerless architecture.
SharePoint utilizes an embedded container under the covers,
which supports Tomcat, Jetty, and Undertow servers out of the box.
Spring Boot provides a Maven plugin that can then package
your application as a standalone executable JAR file that
can be run anywhere Java runs.
This enables your Spring Boot app to run nicely in cloud environments,
and Spring Boot and Spring supports the major cloud offerings.
Finally,
Spring Boot provides a way to package an app as a WAR
file rather than a standalone JAR file.
This allows you to deploy the app into an external
container if your need arises.
And that's it!
Thank you for taking the time to learn Spring Boot with me.
I really do appreciate the opportunity of helping others pick
up new skills and techniques that can help them with their
projects and software problems.
I encourage you to take the time to continue on the Spring framework
learning path to get a deeper understanding of each of the framework pieces that we've worked with in this course.