This is the homework solution for investigating tenure and credit score and seeing if that impacts the
choice of people to leave the bank or stay in the bank.
So let's get straight into it.
We're going to duplicate this sheet that we have estimated Sellery duplicate sheet and we'll call this
one the sort of credit score credit score.
Two words.
OK.
And now we'll create a full credit score.
So here it's a bit like you create a bid and obviously it offers you 10 but you don't know unless you
live in the U.S. You don't know exactly what the credit score ranges from and to.
So let's have a look at credit score you Dharam And here what you want to do is you want to find your
column credit score.
There it is.
You want to order it so from minimum to maximum.
Right.
Also remember that if you have more.
Quite a lot of records here.
The default value might be less than the number of records so just in case check for more.
We know that there's 10000 So there's that's all good.
We know that these are all the records and here so you can get the kind of limits so it's minimum 350
maximum 850.
All right cool so let's use those bands would you want to break it up by maybe looks like maybe 50 would
be a good step.
Let's start with 50.
So credit score grade been.
And I'll step off the bin will be 50.
OK we've created I've.
We've got our chart.
All we have to do is take credit score and drag it over here.
There we go.
Change the color and let's do like a dark blue something like I don't know maybe like this kind of dark
blue light.
OK.
So what can we see.
There's 19 people with a very low credit score and they all left.
But as we talked as we discussed this looks like an anomaly 19 very low number 100 percent very suspicious
and the rest are quite uniform.
So maybe there is some something going on here but overall they're about average.
So credit cards distributed well.
So there's a normal distribution.
And at the same time it doesn't have an impact.
So people with various credit scores are as likely to leave the bank.
Well you have to do is and your report may make sure that you specify that you excluded this anomaly
.
And next we will move on to tenure so let's duplicate this sheet now.
We'll call this one 10 year and same thing.
Tenure is how many years the custom has been if a bank is probably we're going to look at a one year
bond.
It's never a very high.
You can check your daughter said but let's start over one year bad and then we can check it change it
.
If it's too low or too high.
So we'll start off one year.
We've got to been copy the been here.
And once again let's change the color to make things more vibrant.
OK is a good one.
Let's try purple.
It's a magnetic
plie.
All right.
Great.
So what can we see here.
Tenure is interesting it looks like it doesn't matter what age or how long the customer's being in the
back.
It doesn't matter what you feel or care doesn't matter whether it has an impact whether or not the customer
leave the light.
The other thing we can say is that there is a very odd distribution it's it's a uniform distribution
across all bands except for 0 and 10.
So the extremes but otherwise it's pretty uniformly distributed.
So this does look like something suspicious.
It could be.
It could happen maybe the bank is targeting customers in all.
You know all constantly getting new customers and somehow holding onto old customers or like that's
something you would discuss with somebody who knows more about this who has some insights or some business
knowledge about why they are customers who've been in the bank one year and four years and nine years
and they all have equal numbers.
So that's that's a very interesting observation but the conclusion here is that tenure does not impact
the probability or probability the choice of somebody to leave the bank.
It looks like it's pretty well distributed pretty uniform across state.
And right away that's a major point of concern for a bank at the same time because you would expect
that customers that have been banking with you for longer.
So nine eight seven 10 years there would be more likely to stay right as customers to bank with you
.
They develop loyalty.
And the one to stay with you.
But it does seem like the case for this bank this bank seems like they're not doing a good job in helping
customers develop loyalty.
So therefore you would raise this as a red flag maybe you would talk to somebody I'm sure somebody in
the bank would already know about this problem.
But here you've got some actual evidence you've got some hard data suggesting that there is an issue
and it needs to be addressed and that's it.
That's how you solve this homework.
Hope you did well I'm sure you did fine.
And I look forward to seeing you back in of course.
Until then happy analyzing