In the previous tutorial we successfully completed creating our first Proc..
And I thought I'd throw in this short tutorial to quickly recap on what prox are and how we're using
them and what the advantages of using them are just to make sure that we're on the same page before
we proceed to creating the proc for our second row table.
All right so here we go.
This is the part of the diagram that is responsible for transferring a role table into a working table
in e-tail face 3.
And you can see here that in order to save our BLD process we're using a proc.
Now what we did in the past few tutorials is we in our Proc. we created the table and brand new empty
table for all working Daro we specified the columns as we wanted with their correct types.
Then we took the raw table and we use the select statement to select the data that we want from that
were on table.
And before that's like say when there was an insert statement that allowed us to insert what we selected
into the empty columns of the working table so that's important to understand.
That's the way our construction.
It's got two parts.
First part is it's creates the table that we want to insert into and then the second part is broken
down into two bits.
If you select the data from the RAW file and then you insert it into the working table.
Even though it all happens all together.
But that's how it's all broken up into those two major parts create the table and select an insert and
then the selected answers obviously consist obviously of two bits the select and insert.
And now let's quickly recap on the advantages of using prox so we've mentioned them briefly but now
this put put a line under them.
Advantages of using stored procedures.
Number one it allows you to save your script in a secure server management studio.
And that is important because there are other ways to save your scripts.
For instance you could save it as a file on your hard drive as a text file.
You could copy the code and things like that.
But this in my view is the most quickest way to save your files or your scripts through prox And also
it allows other people to access your scripts.
They don't have to ask for them.
They're all in that same place where the tables are located as well.
The Mattew is you can easily modify your building process when you need to change something.
And we will see this later in the section of the course how we can easily come back and change our stored
procedures so that the upload or the conversion from raw to work is a bit different to what it was previously
.
And finally what procedures allow for audit ability repeatability and reliability.
So the main things here are that you can always get somebody to queue a work and check your work.
Also if something if somebody else needs to do your work for you then they can easily repeat the process
because the code is saved and you know if you are comments in your scripts as well that will help them
out.
And if you even need to perform this work this kind of a similar upload or similar conversion from raw
to work in another table then you can just copy most of the code from this where you can copy the whole
proc and be basically you're just repeating the same code but you don't have to type it up again.
And reliability.
So all of that together Presby of reliability that code is saved that you can you know that if you need
to you can easily modify the proc and so other people can Q8 your work.
All of that all together gives you reliability and your confidence in what you're doing with all this
data.
So hopefully that all makes sense.
And in the next tutorial we will start creating our second proc.
You'll be much faster from there and we will learn a few tips and tricks and the toils after that as
well.