All right so today we're going to recap on the multiple linear regression modeling section of the course
.
It is a fun section.
We learned a lot actually built a robust model and I really hope you enjoyed the terminals in the section
.
And before we do a recap and continue I wanted to ask you for a quick favor if you enjoyed the course
so far if you like what you're seeing and if you're having fun and you're learning a lot then I hope
you don't mind leaving a review for this course.
It's very easy to do you just go to the course you have to go to the course on a computer I don't think
you can do this on mobile in the top right corner there's a button here writer view might be called
liberating and might be highlight in white.
So all you have to do is click that button and then a window will pop up where you can select the number
of stars you think the score deserves.
And that's that's totally enough for me but if you want to write a small note then please feel free
to do so to let me know how it went with the scores.
And you know if your expectations were met and if you had fun or not.
And I really hope you can do that.
It would mean a lot for me.
And now let's continue on with the course.
All right section recap in this section we learned number one how to create dummies for categorical
independent variables.
We went through the whole process of how you look at the categories you create new columns you've populate
them of ones and zeros and then you use the categories instead of the actual categorical variable in
your modeling.
Number two was how to avoid the dummy verbal trap.
Remember that you can for any set of dummy variables for one aspecific for one given categorical variable
.
You can't use all of these dummy variables you have to always omit one.
Otherwise your model won't work and you'll fall into the dummy variable trap.
We don't want that to happen.
So just remember that always use and minus one dummy variables for any given set of variables.
Number three we learned the backward forward the bi directional and the all possible methods of creating
models.
The all possible method here is the one where you create all the models and then just compare them and
find the best one.
So we actually went through step by step blueprints for every single one of these methods and hopefully
can take them away.
And whenever you need to reference them you will know exactly where to find them or you will already
know how to perform these methods.
Now before we actually build a model step by step and you can see that I'm very proud of that.
I put two exclamation marks.
Step by step we actually manually built a model using the backward elimination method and we learned
a lot along the way we had variables that dropdown variables that changed their significance variables
that you know we didn't want to drop or we looked charts.
Personally I really enjoyed it and I enjoyed explaining it to you I hope you learned a lot from that
part of the course.
Next we learned how to use the adjusted R-squared in modeling so we actually learned how to not only
bluntly follow our significant level threshold but also apply a criteria in this case to our squared
metric to understand if we're on the right track through our modeling and that helps create more robust
models and not just blindly exclude or include variables just because the rules say so.
And finally point number six we learned how to interpret coefficients of a multiple linear regression
model.
Once again there was a tip there that use per units of variable per unit of independent variable poignance
of dependent variable.
And that will keep you out of trouble because you that way you don't have to make sure that the variables
are on the same scale.
If you start talking about dollars telomerase or actual absolute values then you have to make sure that
you're in some sense count.
And one last point there is that this interpretation method works for multiple regression later on the
course will be talking about logistic regression interpretation there is different.
So just keep that in mind Pope enjoyed the section.
Don't forget to rate the course if you haven't done so yet.
And I really look forward to seeing you in the next section of the Course.
Until then happy analyzing