Pay and welcome back to a course in the previous tutorial we learned how to use a conditional split
to filter out bad records.
And today we're going to take it a step further.
We're going to use two conditionals splits in one Sosias project and to start off with what I wanted
to show you is that you don't have to first upload your daughter to school to then understand what you
need to filter out and then go back to sucess and redo that.
Not at all you can do that right away.
If you know what you're after you can right away create the correct says package and to demonstrate
that we will first truncate our table in escarole so I'm going to open up a skill.
And because we're going to be uploading the data I'm going to truncate this table so fake names.
They're all tableful fake names so we're going to create a new query.
And I'm just going to write up the truncate script right away.
There it is.
You already know how to do this by now.
And now I'm going to execute that.
And so if I look at the table now it's empty so it's prepared for the upload but it is empty.
So we can get rid of us for now.
And back in s.c.s we want to add another conditional split and let's say for instance that you already
know what you're going to be doing if there's not a you know that you are required to analyze this data
set.
And for instance visualize or analyze how different zip codes are spending money so you need to understand
how the money spent is distributed across zip codes and therefore you definitely know that you will
need these two fields and your daughter.
You will need the amount spent and you need the zipcode.
And if a record does not have either of those two then you can do nothing with that record it cannot
participate in your analysis and therefore you need a conditional split to filter out those records
.
So let's create that conditional split.
Now I'm going to go into other transforms and I'm going to look for my conditional split.
There it is.
And I'm just going to drag it over here onto the chart.
And now we want to delete this arrow because we want our daughter to first go into the new conditional
split and then we wanted to go into the old conditional split if it does meet our requirement for those
fields.
So now I'm going to out of Florida this nation this is where we're going to keep all the records that
don't have sufficient data.
Now we're going to set up our conditional split here.
We want obviously in an output name and we're going to call it insufficient data and the condition is
going to be we're going to analyze the columns.
So we need a string function the len function which we used previously and here we're going to look
at this time.
First of all amount spent or amount paid and it has to be if it's insufficient data that means that
this amount is or the length of this column is equal to zero.
So we need our operators are equal operator and equal to zero or so the logical or the zip code where
is it because so we also need lenth land of zip code is 0 as well
or not as well or is zero.
So one of the two is either this one or that one.
If that is the case then there is insufficient data.
This record does not have sufficient data to participate in the analysis and otherwise we're going to
call it check pass so we can really call them good records yet because they still have to pass another
check.
And now we're going to click OK.
So first of all we're going to really matter in which order to do this check pass to go there.
And the other ones insufficient data they go there so make it a bit better like that.
That looks good.
So now the question here is
the question is which in which order do you put this place.
Well it's up to it's up to your specific project do you want to filter out the bad records first and
put them into a separate file and then look for a sufficient or insufficient data or do you want to
check for insufficient data.
First it depends on how you're going to be processing these errors.
Is somebody else going to be populating them for you.
You have to send different departments are going to be fixing up manually because for instance in this
case if there was insufficient data then I can do anything with this record even if I'm able to fix
up some anomalies or get rid of the corruption in those records then I will still not have that correct
data to perform my analysis.
On the other hand the bad records here I might be able to fix up the data since the conditional split
is telling me that the fields are in place so the amount spent or amount paid and the zip code are in
place I might be able to fix up the data quickly and then include in my analysis but if these ones most
likely I won't be able to do anything.
There's still a chance that the door is in there it's just been shifted around.
But you can have a look at that once the file is ready but there is a possibility is higher that probably
the data is just not there.
So that's that's how we split our data we reach on the table so the only thing left that we have to
do is set up this flat file destination we're going to double click new manager.
As usual it's going to be a delimited file here for the manager by the way we haven't been specifying
names doesn't really matter but if you want a bit more order in your connection managers then go feel
free to specify name here we're going to go to our correct folder.
So in this case it's analysis data errors.
This is automatically exclude results and we're going to paste that in here.
And we're going to create a new field our new text document.
And this one we're going to call
We're going to call it fake names.
Insufficient data.
So it's different we don't want to put in the same obviously file so they don't get mixed up we want
to put in this file click open and we want the text qualifier column names checked columns.
They're advanced.
Everything's good feedback has 5000 preview.
OK.
Good mappings good.
So before I launch this I wanted to show you something.
If you go into your automatically exclude results folder remember that we already have data in this
file.
Well you don't have to worry about truncating these files because by default when this package is run
flat file disconnections will be truncated.
On the other hand this is different to what happens to the database tables.
They don't get truncated so you have to do that manually.
So there we go everything set up so let's go ahead and run this.
You can zoom zoom in a little bit so you can see that quite a lot of records went into the insufficient
data file and only four records now went into the bad records file.
So let's go and have a look at these files over here.
I'm going to open this up with Notepad.
Plus plus as you can see there is exactly four records as we specified.
And these are the ones where you do have the information on the money spent and the zip code somewhere
here I think.
That's zip code.
But at the same time something's wrong with the file in general.
And then the other one fake names insufficient data.
Here you can see that there is no data on for most of them there's no data on the amount spent.
And at the same time some of them also don't have the zip code specified for these records.
So like here for example got them on spend but you don't have the zip codes so you can't do anything
of it.
So this file you would send it back to the person that gave it to you and you would ask them to put
it in the correct dot that you require for your analysis.
So that's how you use to conditional splits together.
Very powerful you can use as many as you want just keep adding them on.
And as we saw you don't have to first upload your daughter to a Kill if you know already what you're
after.
Then you can set all of this up and then upload the data to us.
Also you have a nice clean table in your database ready for you to start working with