This time we have two data sets.
We've got churn modeling and churn modeling test data.
So let's go ahead and download them.
And once you've done a lot of them put them into a folder and let's open them up and use Excel.
And I'm going to direct churn modeling in here.
And if you've done the section on where the part of the course in his possession this data set will
look extremely familiar because it's actually the same data set.
The only difference is that the stance we file that was an Excel text file.
And well if you haven't it doesn't matter.
We can't will still go through it now.
So I'll just make some space here so we can see everything and.
OK.
Off we go.
So this data says it's got a few columns.
He's got row number customer id surname.
So what we're looking at is a data set of a bank.
Of course it's all fictional.
It's not a real bank but it's very realistic.
And they hear we've got a snapshot of if you scroll down to the bottom.
There's got to be 10000 customers.
So 10000 rows in this data set.
And the what the bank did is they measured some things about these customers.
Right.
Why did why did they undergo this whole thing and what's the challenge.
Well the bank has been seeing unusual churn rates so churn is when people leave the company and they've
seen customers leaving at unusually high rates and they want to understand what the problem is and they
want to assess and address that problem.
And that's why they've hired you to look into this data set for them and give them some insights.
And how did this data set come to be.
Well six months ago the bank said all right there's a big problem.
We've got to take a sample of our customers by the way this is a sample that 10000 is a tiny number
for this bank.
This bank has millions of customers it operates this fictional bank operates in Europe in three countries
France France Spain and Germany and they have lots and lots of customers so what they did is they took
this sample of 10000 customers and they measured six months ago everything they knew about them they
a customer id their surname credit score their geography their gender their age their 10 years so how
long they've been with the bank the balance of the customers at that point in time the number of products
they had at that point in time.
So a number approaches things like how many products do they have to have a savings account have a credit
card do they have a loan.
How did the customer have a credit card or not so there's no yes no flag.
Is the customer an active member.
Another yes no flag active member can be measured differently by different organizations.
It could be whether or not the customer logged into their online banking in the past month whether they
did a transaction in the past two months or some other measure like that and estimated salary so the
bank doesn't know the salary of the customers but based on the other things they know they could estimate
a salary for that customer and that also gave you this information.
So six months ago they measured all of these things and said All right.
So for these 10000 are randomly selected customers are we going to just watch them so we just going
to wait six months and six months on the track we're going to check who all those customers left and
who are those customers state.
And that's what this call them exited or presents here.
It tells you whether or not the person left the bank within those six months.
So this person over here sometime within the six months he left the bank.
And as of a couple of days ago he's no longer with the bank.
This person over here on the other hand is still in the bank.
So there's a Zuri here.
This person left the bank this person stayed and so on.
So if you see a one that means the person is no longer the bank as that person still the bank and your
goal is to create a job demographic segmentation model to tell the bank which of their customers are
at highest risk of leaving.
So we're going to talk more about your demographic segmentation in the next tutorial.
The other thing that I wanted to look at now is the test data set that we have here.
So what is the test data set.
So if I copy it here you'll see that it's exactly the same type of data sets same columns but the only
difference here is that it's different customers so you can see the phone numbers are higher.
The customers idea these are different these different customers and there is there's only a thousand
of them here.
So why have we been given this data set.
Well basically we are going to use this data set as a validation for the model we build using the other
data set and the way this data set was constructed is that is exactly the same six months.
So same periods of time same snapshot.
So basically the bank just literally separated this data set from that one so you have two separate
data sets and that will allow us to assess how much but more on that later when we get to the correct
section.
What I wanted to mention today is that this skill that you're going to learn in this section and upcoming
sections is very transferable.
It doesn't have to be for a bank.
It doesn't have to be for churn rates.
Demographic segmentation models can be applied to millions of scenarios so here for instance even in
a bank the same scenario could work should the person get a loan or not.
Should the person be approved for credit or not.
And once again you'd have a binary outcome so based on prior experience you would know whether or not
a person is reliable and you build a model and say which people are more likely to be reliable and which
people are more likely to default.
And that could govern the bank's decision on whether or not to give loans.
This could be in terms of fraudulent transactions not even in a bank in a different financial institutions
you could find out which transactions are more likely to be fraudulent which are less likely.
There's lots of scenarios where you could apply a demographic segmentation and it doesn't even have
to be your demographic.
So we know that we're going to be using a logistic regression.
And whenever you have a scenario when you have a binary outcome and you have lots of independent variables
you can throw all of that into logistic regression.
And as you'll see in this part of the course.
Build a proper robust logistic regression and that will tell you which factors influence the outcome
.
So go back to our example two brushes you can have here whether or not it's a faulty toothbrush.
And here you can have a myriad of independent variables like as we've discussed what what plastic was
used what temperature at what temperature the to the brush was build.
You could have what other components you added whether or not you added other components to the plastic
or what electrics you used in the tooth brush you could have how long the tooth brush was being created
for you could basically have anything even the humidity in the factory at the time we're making too
much.
So basically it doesn't have to be a customer centric organization.
That's what I'm trying to explain here that you can apply this knowledge is going to learn in any kind
of scenario.
We have biner outcome and lots of independent variables.
And on that note let's jump straight into our modeling section. I'll see you on the next tutorial.
Until then happy analyzing