In this tutorial we will talk about folder structure for your Dotson's project and I will show you the
tried and tested method that I use folder structure is important for many reasons.
For instance if you have a smartphone a structure then you will know exactly where things are located
and your efficiency will go up.
Also good for the structure will allow you to quickly audit any data errors that you might find.
Let's assume that this is your folder for Alderson's project.
Let's open it up.
Inside you will see that I have already created a template.
Ignore the exclamation mark at the start.
It's there simply so that the template is always at the top of the folder.
You'll notice that the name of the template folder starts with a date in a specific format and then
the project name the date is when you commence this project.
Once the date is set it can be changed.
Not that it is important to set the date in this exact format because in that way your folders will
automatically sorted by chronological order when you sort them by name.
Let's click into the template.
Inside you will see the following six folders original data prepared data uploaded daughter analysis
insights and final Let's go through them one by one.
The first folder is for storing data extracted from other systems.
You can only add data to this folder and you should never under no circumstances modify any data stored
in this folder.
The second folder is for any modifications you may make to the raw data.
This includes cleaning the data which will look at further in the course folder 3 is for uploading data
.
Think of it as the temporary stop for your data.
Once you are ready to upload a file inside this folder you create a subfolder with just the date of
the upload for the name and from within that folder you upload the data.
We will see all of this in action in the next section.
The analysis folder is for any code scripts etc that you create during the course of your analysis and
the insights folder is for any preliminary results.
Finally the final folder stores your draft and file reports.
This brings us to the end of today's tutorial.
Feel free to copy this for the structure template as we will start using it already in the next tutorial
.