Plan of attack.
All right Carol what is this all about.
What are we talking here.
What kind of attack is going on.
What are we going to be talking about in the next couple of tutorials is an advance topic and that's
why the trolls are marked as advanced.
And we will be looking at a very specific thing.
Let me explain.
Remember we previously talked about the do's and don'ts.
All of a logistic regression.
And we specifically said that you cannot interpret magnitudes of the coefficients to quantify associations
between the dependent variables and independent variables directly.
And this is very different to a multiple linear regression.
So this is a logistic regression here and we can't look at the magnitudes of these coefficients to compare
the different variables between each other.
We could totally do that in a multiple linear regression was very handy to tell us which independent
variables are more are having more and more significant impact on the dependent variable and which are
having less So basically comparing independent variables between each other and also actually quantifying
physically quantifying the effect of the change in the independent variable and how that will affect
the dependent variable.
But here for logistic regression we can do that.
And that just hurts that hurts so much we have to we have to be able to do it.
And that is why we have this special part of the course the special couple of lectures or tutorials
which are advanced because they will involve quite a bit of mathematics and some advanced understanding
of possibilities and alteration and things like that.
But if you can power through them with me I have broken them down into manageable sections or manageable
topics which we will cover often and next to trolls.
And today is about setting that plan of attack and it's pretty pretty straightforward.
So first we'll talk about the odds ratio.
It's an important topic.
You will see what odds are in sports betting So that's kind of like a side effect of this section of
the Course you'll learn a bit more about odds in sports.
But the main focus of this tutorial will be to link odds and probabilities.
Then we'll talk about coefficient So this will be the math havey tutorial where we will actually understand
how to plug ords into our logistic regression and then see for ourselves how a 1 unit change and occur
in a independent variable translates through the coefficient into a change in the odds.
So there's your hint wink wink into a change in the odds not in the possibility so that's going to be
interesting.
And then finally in the third tutorial after this plan of attack we will see the practical application
.
I will show you how to get the odds ratios and Grettel I will show you how to export everything into
Excel how to prepare your report Excel and then actually how to put it into PowerPoint and the way I
would go about presenting your logistic regression or your demographic segmentation to your manager
.
So we'll have a heat map and it'll be very very evident what the main insights are from our genome demographics
competition and what the bank in this case what the banks should do in order to address the issue of
increased churn.
So it's going to be an exciting couple Torez.
Bear in mind there are going to be advanced.
So prepare yourself for some advanced mathematics.
Well I wouldn't say good ones but some mathematics are going to be in there but we'll definitely part
through them together.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing