Come to me with a business problem this is an interesting one because all the time you will have it
on the scientist you will have people come to you and say hey I have this data can you give me some
insights into it.
That is the worst thing a person can possibly come to you with the worst requests you can get from persons
.
Give me some insights into my dad.
What are we looking for.
What are you interested in.
What are the challenges you faced no admissions just give me some insights insights are not born out
of nothing the way people should approach and you should make this clear as you are building this data
size capability or you know becoming important in an organization to people the way people should approach
is a business problem is much easier to find insights and data when you are looking.
You're really looking for something so the person might come to you and say hey look I have this bottle
neck we're not able to service our customers on time and I don't know what to do.
The problem is that we are not being able to deliver these communications our customers or the products
or customers on time or a factory is not delivering enough good.
So here's the data can you help us look for it and solve that problem.
So when you're solving a problem when you have a starting point which is your data set or data sets
and all the interviews that you have to conduct and all the ground work that you have then you have
a finishing point ending point where you find the solution to the problem has been identified.
That journey that is there a sense that is the fun part and along that journey you will find so many
insights even insights that are completely irrelevant to the problem that will add additional value
to the business.
And as I mentioned through out the course at times those insights will be even more valuable will drive
even more value than the solution to the problem you're actually solving.
So make sure that when people come to you talk to them and try to identify the pain points their problems
that they're facing exactly what they want from you because that will allow you to structure your approach
and understand what to look for in the data.
And along the way along the way you will find the insights that they aren't even expecting