Pillow ladies and gentleman and today we're starting a fun bit.
We're going to upload our data.
So let's quickly go to our data science project and we're dealing with fake names.
Canada which we put in here in the previous tutorial so original data there is our file.
Are we going to copy this file before we open it and we're going to put it into a prepared data and
we'll look at it here.
So let's open it up in a notepad.
Plus plus to start off with.
What does the file look like.
Wow.
It's very different to what we expected.
It's not a comma separated file.
It's a tab delimited file.
So here are the delimiters tabs.
And be careful of these files because here it's much harder to understand what is going on because there's
no commas.
Still you have those text qualifiers to separate the commas from the rest of the world.
But in this case the commas aren't actually the delimiters.
The tabs are delimiters So very interesting format and be careful with that because it's a good example
.
There are different types of delimiters pipelined delimit pipe delimited files comma separated tab delimited
semi-colon delimited.
You can pretty much use anything as delimiter.
So in your homework at the end of this section in the super hardcore homework you will have a surprise
delimiter which won't be a comma or a tab so be careful that you will have to figure out how to deal
of that run on your own.
And now what we're going to do is we're going to close this file and we will proceed with Excel.
But first before that we do we have to check the number of rows there is two hundred thousand rows in
this file including the head of the 200000 and one.
So just checking to make sure that Excel will be capable of opening this file Excel can manage files
up to 1 million for forty eight thousand and 576 rows I think.
So let's close that and proceed with our bulletproof blueprint.
OK so we're going to open the file now by looking at all files fake names.
Canada to exceed that forces the text import wizard which we want delimited by default it's tab.
So if I change to comma here you'll see that it's messed up the file so leave it a tab.
Once again you have to be careful know what your delimiter is.
Next select all the columns.
Change them to text.
Finish.
OK so there is our file.
And one interesting thing we can see in our way there is an interest rate column where the percentage
column which we haven't dealt with before but the treatment will be similar to the balance column.
Similar but not exactly the same.
So what are we going to do now.
Well right away three things that you do fix updates fix up anything with a decimal point and basically
commas dollars percentages and check for long winded comments that we might need to change back to a
general type.
So they don't get cut off.
So looks like all the rolls are under or all of the columns are under 1000 symbols 1000 characters or
even 250 characters because Excel cuts off at 250 if either a long or this column would have expanded
.
So that's fine we don't need to fix anything up then this question marks as you see here that's totally
fine.
So what I'm going to do actually I'm going to zoom in a little bit so we can see everything a bit better
.
All right.
So that should be better.
So where are these question marks.
It just means that there was like an a foreign symbol there.
We can't really do anything about that.
It was like that already in the in the original data.
We can go back and get the person who gave us that or to correct it but that's not going to be our focus
in this.
And this Tauriel or in this section.
So let's fix up the dates.
First of all we're going to go to data text to columns delimited no delimiter.
Next date this one as you can see it's an American date so month day year finish.
There we go.
Dates fixed up and now right away we'll format cells and change them to the date that we want which
is y y y m m d d.
The canonical date.
And there we go.
So that's that comb's ready next column is the balance column.
We really know what to do here.
Same thing.
Text two columns delimited.
No delimiter.
Next we need to change it to a general type.
So basically just click through here and now we want to format cells and we want to change this to a
number of faults any separators and two decimal points.
Good.
And then into straight.
So this was going to be interesting as well we're going to takes two columns same thing same thing click
through finish and now we want to change the interest rate format Seltsam we want to get rid of the
percentage sign but that implies that we divide by 100 so we want like 0.1 to 4 here or a 0.1 6 6 here
so let's see what happens when we select number decimal places we have to put 4 because we don't want
to use any decimal places from here.
And we click OK and that automatically fixes fixes it up for us.
So that's good.
Then we can just zoom through a file if we want to just just in case are not looking for anything specific
.
We've done oral all while fixing up so now we need to save the file.
We won't press control s because we want to save it as a CSP file instead of a text file so I'll go
save as and we don't want to touch that one.
We want to create a new one which is going to be called fake names.
Candidate C S B.
OK.
Yes and no we can close this.
So let's have a look at that.
So here you can see that tickety file this is his free file says he falls a little bit smaller here
because that's how it works sometimes it can be much smaller depends on how many columns you have what
types of data have in them.
So let's open this one up with notepad plus plus and have a look.
So here now we have all coma's looks really familiar to what we're used to working with.
Great.
So now we can go ahead and start uploading and this file actually it's a copy.
It's basically a copy of the original file.
We don't need it anymore because it's not prepared for it's not something we're going to be working
with.
We delete that then we take the we file we put it into uploaded data so today's date there is our CC
file and now we're going to go kill server.
So this management sorry we're going into my official studio.
So we're going to open a project or not open we're going to a new project and we'll give it a name fake
names.
Canada integration services project.
Perfect.
Let's get this started.
And so this data set is designed has been designed by me in a way that it doesn't have any errors in
this upload phase just to save us some time however and we'll get to this later.
Your homework will have errors in this face your homework.
Trust me you don't want to do it.
It is going to be hectic.
So we'll get to that later.
So browse.
We want to find our file.
Let's make sure it's a sci fi file open it up.
You can copy the name here if you like.
Doesn't really matter.
Give it to Tick's qualifier column headers.
That's good.
Just look through.
Look for an anomaly.
It doesn't look like there's any anomalies although they are but not for this phase of the upload advanced
as we're used to.
Everything gets a thousand preview have a quick look.
OK.
Columns done.
Error output.
OK destination new.
OK.
New this create a file or I mean a table
rule will call it's fake.
So trophic name is canned.
All right so that's done we click OK.
OK the fall the table be created.
Everything looks good.
Mappings.
OK.
Output.
So we won't have any.
And any splits conditional splits because right now we're not focusing on that.
Although in your homework you will be required to do some conditional splits.
So we're ready.
Let's launch this and see how we go.
Okay so off it goes.
There's 200000 rows so we'll just skip to that and right away.
In this video.
All right.
So the upload has been completed and now we can go check our table.
So we'll just quickly finish this.
And as we remember we disable and now we just save.
All right.
So how about now we go open up as or a management studio and have a look at our table connect databases
DSTraining tables.
Where is it.
Fake names can select the rows.
All right.
Perfect.
So there it is.
That's top thousand if we select everything.
It will be much greater.
So here you can see that whoops we do have 200000 rows and they have been actually uploaded an order
which is great and everything looks fantastic.
So this is us finished of e-tail faces one into Wasn't that very quick.
It took less less than 10 minutes and total around 10 minutes.
You can get much faster at it.
But anyway they are still anomalies in the data which we haven't picked out yet and it's quite impossible
to pick them out manually so starting from the next Tauriel we going to find or we're going to define
a blueprint how to surgically remove anomalies that can affect your analysis.
I look forward to seeing you next time