So how did you enjoy that.
Did you find the intro to the presentation interesting.
It was pretty cool how we added some comments along the way so I wrote them written down here and let's
go through them one by one just so that we were definitely covering everything.
So the big one was lots of arms and yeah.
That's true.
I was a bit nervous and nobody's perfect.
I'm still learning how to present especially to live audiences.
So but definitely you would want to take them out of your presentation and practice to get rid of all
these arms and butts and extra words that are not supposed to be the number two overall outline of what
will be discussed so at the start you could hear me say or you say to the audience exactly what we're
going to be talking about.
And it is a major data science project so get them excited to tell them that this is like a major success
and downsides.
And then right away we talk about the journey so you could see me right away.
Outlie early on what the journey will be.
Actually I actually said the word journey.
I want to take you on a journey and that is what downsized presentations are about.
We'll talk more about this in the next trial but in short you don't want to give them the hard facts
you want to take them on a journey so that they feel that they are part of something inside.
Like a they're engaged in it they're they're feeling emotions as you go along through the presentations
.
That's what it's all about and says it's OK to say at the start you want to take them on the journey
I use that trick all the time.
In fact I'm taking you on a journey right now.
Number four explain what they will learn.
Highlight what's the value they will get from this.
So you could hear me say at the start that I will tell them what data science is what data data mining
is all about and how they can use their daughter to help their business.
So I outlined exactly what they're getting from this presentation and why they should listen to it.
So what they will have at the end and I delivered on that so that's important to outline and then to
deliberately get them engaged early on e.g. make them laugh so and the other one is get them engaged
or don't ask it ask the question.
So that's important.
If you if you want people like people have short attention spans these days.
Some people say that human beings are the invention of iPhones.
Now we have like attention spans.
One second less than a goldfish something or something ridiculous.
But anyway people have short attention spans.
You want to increase their attention span.
How do you do that you wake them up you get them get their brains working stimulated you make them focus
so when you're talking maybe or not they're listening to you maybe they're somewhere else.
But if you ask a question right.
So the first one was make them laugh right.
When people hear other people around them laughing like whoa what's happening is if they were zoned
out they'd get back in there.
So it's a good idea if you can make a joke like the one I used was.
You're going to become data scientists for the next 15 minutes or so and I find it pretty exciting so
that you know I really did find that exciting.
So it's the truth and at the same time they found it funny because none of them are data scientists
or anything that goes by the way I should've mentioned this earlier.
There was a completely non-technical audience so those were executives very high level audience have
no idea about dollar signs.
Some of them were this was the first time they heard about dollar signs and yet I did my best to get
them engaged and break it down for them so they could follow along.
So making them laugh.
That's perfect.
If you can make the audience laugh you're winning them over and you know you're not.
You don't want to fight them.
You want to be on their side.
You want them to be on your side.
You want them to be opened up so that you can you know put knowledge into their minds or get engaged
get them engaged early on ask questions so ask the questions.
Other techniques that you can use even especially works with far smaller boardroom so it is harder to
make.
Like it is hard to make a small audience laugh.
They have like five people or even three people one to one.
It's harder to make them laugh and it's easier to make a large audience laugh.
But at the same time it's you can always ask a question.
It's even easier to answer a question of a small audience.
Right so because you can dress people individually.
So if you ask a question that gets them thinking that gets them you know creates a silence creates a
pause and they start feeling maybe a little bit uncomfortable so you have to be you have to be comfortable
with the fact that there's a bit of silence and a little silence doesn't you know doesn't ruin anything
even if nobody answers your question we'll just move on.
But if you do get them to put their hand up like in my example ask the question I said How can people
who are not familiar with this concept of this campaign which is called The Superman.
Can you please put your hand up.
And that's all I ask for putting their hand up.
And some people did like it.
At first nobody did because it's always a bit scary to put your hand up first but then some people did
put their hands up and that got the audience engaged and I pointed that out and I said thank you thank
you for putting your hand up like because I want to reward that engagement that they're you know exhibiting
a lot of behavioral stuff going on in the background like psychological stuff.
So you want to reward that engagement so that others subconsciously want to be more engaged in your
presentation as well.
Actually what I wanted to say here is Tony Robbins I'm sure you've heard of Tony Robbins.
Robbins he does a really good job of engaging the audience.
And I'll put a link to one of his TED talks that I really like I'll put it in the tutorial with the
links at the end of the section.
So make sure to check it out.
Talk about Dallasites at all.
It's about motivationally you might actually pick up some cool stuff from there about motivation but
at the same time he does a really good job engaging audiences making them you know responds to his requests
making them feel excited about what he's presenting.
So that's that's a very good place to learn some good to meet the other one was make sure everybody's
on the same page.
So that's the other thing I did.
Because you do present technical things we do tend to plan technical things.
Your audiences might be different.
Right so they might be really prepared to some level of about what you're presenting maybe they're the
people that ordered this project and they were you know a lot of the foundations so you don't have to
explain it but do make sure that everybody knows where you're starting from and that's what I did in
this presentation.
I asked that if everybody knows what a superman campaign is because that was the basis of what was going
to talk about and I wanted to make sure even There's like three people in the audience and don't know
I tell them about it.
And that allows you to refresh the memories of the other people about this specific topic.
All right so what else do we have.
Number eight was.
Use your eyes to connect with people with multiple people when you talk.
So it's a it's a very powerful.
I connection I contact a lot of data scientists and analysts.
They lack this right because we don't come from creative backgrounds.
Normally we don't come from arts and crafts and so on.
We come from way more of a technical background like I'm sure you can associate or relate to this.
And we're a lot of wow thinking is a left brain thinking right.
Well most of the time we're inside ourselves.
A lot of us are introverts right.
We look at the ground like I used to find myself always like when I'm talking to people I'm looking
at the ground where I'm walking the street I'm looking at the ground level and kind of like in Saigon
thoughts nothing wrong with that but you don't get to connect with the audience and it's a skill you
have to develop.
You have to push yourself to look at the person you're talking to don't don't stare don't make it awkward
but connects through eye contact especially if somebody is talking to you.
You can look in their eyes.
And that way you can make better when you're talking to an audience whether it's five people 200 people
.
Make sure you're looking at one person then another person another that don't stare at just one person
all the time because other people feel alienated.
If you move your eyes around the audience or pick one two three or five people that you that are looking
at you as well and just look at them once in a while so move your focus around so people can see that
you're engaging everybody.
That's that's a good technique that I picked up along the way as well.
And finally use intonation and to add emphasis to important parts and also pauses so intonation and
pauses how you raise your voice how you lower your voice when you're talking about important things
or when you speed up when you want to get some somethings.
Go through some things quickly or slow down when something is very very important.
So things like that that's a very powerful technique.
Why why are we focusing on all these like definitely can pick up a lot of these techniques from a book
on presenting something like that.
But I've highlighted the ones that you saw me actually use right and also is because data science is
complicated and you've got to break it down to be very simple like like like it if you're reading a
book to a child right.
You're not going to you're going to make it interesting.
You don't just get to read through it like it's a fact you're going to make it interesting.
And you know use your voice use use pauses make them you know make them anticipate what's going to happen
next.
Same thing here in your Dallasites presentations make it a journey make it like an adventure for your
audience the people that you're presenting to.
So that brings us to the end of what we talked about in the intro in the next tutorial we're going to
talk about why storytelling is important.
There's going to be a fun story as well.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.