In this tutorial we will set up our flat false source connection.
The first step in this process is to take a file We're going to be uploading and place it into the uploads
folder.
Let's do that.
This is our project folder.
We have already prepared the file in the previous section of the course.
Currently it is located in the prepared folder.
Let's go and copy it.
Now we need to go to the uploaded data folder here.
We will create a subfolder with today's date as the name.
Now paste or fall into this folder.
This is the file that we're going to be uploaded to the database.
Copy the folder path and go back to Sosias Now double click the flat file source box in the flood file
connection manager.
You need to click and you click Browse and paste to Poth you cannot see any files right now because
by default the tool is looking for the X Files.
Click the dropdown at the bottom of the window and select CSFB files.
Select your file and click open.
Now that we have found the file we will set up the flat file manager.
First give the connection manager a recognizable name.
I prefer to simply copy the name of the file the next change the text qualifier from none to quotation
marks.
This ensures that data in your CACP file is recognized correctly.
Also it is important to make sure that the checkbox saying column names in the first row is checked
.
This simply means that the first row of your file contains headers and the actual data starts from the
second row.
It is checked by default for us.
However in earlier versions of Visual Studio this option was not selected by default.
We don't need any of the other controls in this window.
Now let's click columns in the options on the left.
Here you have a preview of your daughter.
The beauty of using a c a c file is that it's very very simple.
We know for sure that the row delimiter will always be the carriage return line feed sequence and the
column delimiter will always be a comma.
This means that we don't have to worry about these two menus and should leave them at default.
Now preview your data.
This is quick and easy scroll as far to the right as possible.
You need to check for two things.
Check number 1 make sure that the last column is the same one as in the file that you prepared and that
there are no extra empty columns to the right.
If you find extra columns on the right that shouldn't be there.
That means that you see every file contained empty columns and you should revisit the previous step
preparing your CAC file before the load.
If those columns are not required they should be deleted.
Check number 2.
Now scroll down as far as you possibly can and while you're doing this look at all of the cells in the
last column and see if they have the correct type that you would expect based on the columns name.
In this case and number.
This check allows you to make sure that none of the rows available in the preview got skewed because
of a data anomaly.
A lot of data scientists skipped this step considering it too trivial.
However I still always do it.
I have done hundreds of these uploads and still I perform this check.
Finding an error this way will save you a lot of time down the track.
If all is good then move onto that one step in the menu on the left.
This is a vital part of your upload.
If you wanted to here you could specify the data types for your columns.
A lot of analysts do that right here.
However I will show you a much better method.
The method I will show you is way more reliable and safer.
I won't go into all the details right now.
You will see how the whole picture will fall into place as we progress through this part of the course
.
However what we will be doing here now is uploading all of our columns as text.
It doesn't matter if it's a name or a date or a number.
Everything will be uploaded into the database as text and then in the database we will sort it all out
.
If you click through the columns you will see that all of them have already been recognized by Sosias
as text.
This is indicated by the datatype string over here.
That's a good start but there is one little problem.
SSA wants to save space and therefore has only allocated 50 characters to every single data element
that is not much at all.
And if we have a cell that contains 51 characters then our upload will produce a truncation error.
We need to increase memory allocation and I always said 2000 characters.
This is the safest bet by far.
You can still come across data that has more than 1000 characters but that's rare.
An example of that would be if your column contains freeform text such as customer complaints or comments
hold down the Shift key and select all of your column headers.
Double click the current column with and replace it with 1000 and hit enter.
Now all of your daughter elements will have 1000 characters of storage space.
Go to preview and check your data one more time.
Click OK click ok again.
Now your flat file source and flood file connection manager are ready.
By the way it is important to understand the difference between the two.
The connection to your file is called The Connection Manager.
You can see it here at the bottom.
If you double click on it you will see the menu.
We spent most of our time in now the flat file source is what you see in your diagram.
If you open it up you will see that the flat file source uses the flat file connection manager.
This is just how Sosias works.
The flat file source and connection manager are separate and this means that you can use your connection
manager in many different sources without having to recreate it.
This is applicable to other Sosias projects and we won't be using that in our work but it's good to
know these things.
All right I'll flat file sources ready and you can see that the Red Arrows sign has disappeared in the
next tutorial.
We will set up the destination