Cap analysis we've talked about cap a lot and in fact we've talked about cap that much that I'm no longer
even saying cumulative accuracy profile because I am assuming that you're entirely comfortable with
this abbreviation and the whole term and what it means.
So let's see how to the cap as we've discussed.
There are three lines that are important on the Kepcher of the blue line which is the random line when
you select your samples at random.
The red line which is our model line the and different models will have different red lines but basically
look something like that.
And the gray line which is the perfect model or when you have a crystal ball when you can select all
of the future turners or purchaser's or whatever action takers and you can select them right away on
the dot before even selecting one single person that you don't want to select.
And so these are the three main lines and how do we analyze this cap Kaveri know how to build it but
what can we derive what insights can we derive from here.
Well it's kind of intuitive that the closer your red line is to the gray line the better you model the
closer to the blue line the worse.
So how can we quantify this effect.
Well there is a standard approach to calculate the accuracy ratio and to calculate accuracy ratio and
you take the area under the perfect model or the perfect line which is color in gray here and it's called
a pea.
And then you need to take that area under the red line which is colored in red here which is a R and
then you need to divide one by the other.
So you need to divide a r by AP and then this ratio that you get is obviously between 0 and 1.
And the closer this ratio is to 2:1 the better the further it is away from one close to zero the worse
.
However it can be quite complicated to calculate this area under the curve statistical tools can do
for you.
But how can you assess the cap curve by just looking at it so visually it's not that easy to get this
quantifiable metric just by looking at the curve.
So there's a second approach and that's what we're going to discuss.
Now let's get rid of areas and instead of looking at the area what you can do is look at the 50 percent
line on the horizontal axis and look where it crosses your model and then look at where that line the
horizontal line from there crosses the vertical axis So basically how many turners will you pick up
or action takers or how many positive outcomes are you going to identify if you take 50 percent of your
population.
And in this case we can see it's around 90 percent or something like that.
And just by looking at that there's like a rule of thumb how you can assess your model based on that
X number and here it is.
Are you ready.
Here we go.
So if x is less than 60 percent the model is rubbish.
Basically it's not useful at all.
You have.
You can create a better one probably you can create a better one and you need to try again.
If you model your X is between 60 percent and 70 percent then the model is considered to be poor poor
or average and by the way these are my this is my rule of thumb.
Other people might have a different rule of thumb but this is what I go by.
If is between 60 percent and over and it's it's a poor model to be honest like you can you can do better
than that.
If it's if X is between 70 percent and 80 percent that's a good model that's already where you should
be aiming for anything above 70 percent that can deliver good quality insights to the business and actually
deliver value.
Anything between 80 percent and 90 percent like we see here is very good.
It's extremely good.
That's if you can get a model over 80 percent.
That is an amazing result.
And anything above 90 percent up to 100 that is just too good.
It is too good to believe and the are there is one option that there should be very careful here with
his overfitting.
If your model is showing you results like 90 percent or safe emulsion you're 100 percent then the obvious
answer there is that one of your independent variables is actually a post facto variable meaning that
it shouldn't be in the data because it's looking into the future.
The person who supplied that variable forgot to take it out or forgot to explain to you that you know
their credit score actually is turned into zero after they leave the bank and therefore everybody offer
zero credit score obviously has left the bank and therefore your model is picking them up like like
it's super easy.
So if you have 100 percent that's definitely something on a few variables even if you have 90 to 100
percent you have to check that there could be some forward looking variables.
The other thing is overfitting you could be overfitting a model and what that means is that you your
model has been so well fit that specific data set that you supplied it that when you try it just heavily
relying on the normal is in that data set.
And when you feel it's a new data set like you know in a month time or something like not not training
data not the data that you trained your model on.
We'll talk about this a bit a lot more actually in the coming tutorials.
But so if you feed this model some data that you want to actually predict on then you will crash it
all it won't crash and it won't perform as well perform you know at the 60 percent mark or something
.
So that means a model is overfit it and be very careful about that.
We'll talk about overfitting more in fact in the coming tutorials we will learn how to avoid that problem
.
And finally if you can get an x or this parameter to be between 90 percent Harmsen and you're not using
for looking parameters or you're not overfitting then give me a call because I might have a job for
you people like that are rare and I have a lot of head hunters looking for people who can do modeling
like that.
So definitely keep that in mind and know to finish off today's Tauriel we're going to jump into excel
and have a look at our model and see how it compares how it actually performs on that scale so we're
going to take a line very simple visual analysis so there's a 50 percent line we're going to drag a
vertical line or here as you can see it crosses the model at about 80 percent or 80 and a half percent
.
Very good model.
So all we have to do now is make sure we're not overfitting it and then we can start using it.
So in the next tutorial what is going to happen I will give you a cap template that I promised.
And then after that we will learn how to check for overfitting and models and learn how to use test
data and the differences between training and test data.
I look forward to seeing you then.
Until next time happy analyzing