Go incipit them a real life example.
This is going to be a very interesting one.
Now a lot of people think that a data scientist is like a magician who can get everything out of the
data everything of the numbers.
That is not entirely true.
A lot of things can be derived.
A lot of insights can be derived from the data and numbers but some things cannot.
Some things are just not in the data and there's no way you can get them out of there.
And that is why it is extremely important for you Roger project to communicate with people on the job
.
So I'll give you a a pretty example of the main example I want to share with you but I'll give you a
smaller example.
So if you're doing some research for how efficient a call center is working I did do on those projects
you go.
And after you've done all the work you've done some research you've gathered some initial data.
You go and you sit with the people in the call center.
In fact actually said with them for half a day and I listened to them talk to customers and it's all
legal by the way because you know they tell the customer that this has been recorded or Montral and
so on.
But I listen to them and I want it to be like them for one day.
I wanted to get insights into the work they do.
I wanted to feel the pain points that they feel the experience is that they go through I want to go
through them as well because that is the art of art science.
Like anybody can crunch numbers right.
But the creative creative part the ideas ideas come from you know we're going to have ideas unless you
open up to the world unless you engage in this same activity that you are trying to optimize or add
efficiency to or you know analyze the more exposure you have where you get to this activity or to the
people there.
For this to be the better for you know for the really cool example that I wanted to share with you.
So I was doing some analytics around how customers respond to a request to consolidate their funds so
basically a customer has lots of accounts in different organizations say this was for a pension fund
so a customer has lots of different pension accounts in different funds which are comparison each other
of course.
And then at some point during the year they get a letter in the Post say hey you have lots of accounts
why don't you consolidate them and put them all into one.
And so I put it together a chart which speaks to how likely people are to consolidate depending on the
number of accounts that they have.
So people would have anywhere from 2 to 13 15 even up to 17 different accounts and different pension
funds and of course they're paying additional fees and it's in their best interest to consolidate.
And so if we look at this chart you can see that the more accounts people have the less likely they
are to consolidate up to a certain point.
And this is like a mock up charge.
So it's not the real thing but this is what it approximately what looked like this is to convey the
message.
So.
And but then when you see that once you get to 13 accounts it spikes up.
It's like people are very likely to consolidate their accounts at 13 accounts but at 12 and 10 and 11
they're not as likely.
So what was that.
What does it go there.
Like how how can you explain something like that.
There's no logical explanation right.
It looks like the more accounts you have the more work it has to do to consolidate them right.
And the less likely you are to consolidate.
And yet at exactly 13 it spikes up I could not explain it for the life of me I could not understand
what is going on.
So how did I find out the answer.
Well I went and sat with the people who process these forms and the forms come back in the process them
they you know manually enter them into the system and do the cancellation requests.
And while I was sitting with these people I asked one of them like what do you think of this problem
like why would this occur.
And for him it was a no brainer.
He actually gave me a paper so I've got I'm going to muck up for you which I do of myself.
And he showed me one of these forums and what I found the forum was which is you can see here that there's
three accounts here on each page is three accounts so three accounts and the first page three accounts
and the second three accounts.
Right.
So that's six.
That's nine.
That's 12.
So 12 is two pages.
Once you get to 13 that's a third page.
So it was a psychological thing.
When people see two pages of accounts it's like it's for them it's it's they thinking oh this is you
know too much work I got to I got to really spend time on this I can I can do this I'll do it.
But when they see three pages they're like whoa that is too much fees that I'm paying that is way through
the roof.
So this jump from two pages to three pages the psychological phenomenon actually prompted people or
forced people to go ahead and console that and that's why there was a spike at 13 accounts.
So insights like that you can get from data you can only get from the people on the job and it is their
business knowledge their internal experience in the business that you can and should leverage in your
nonsense.