S..
Recap.
So what did we learn in the section about model maintenance.
First of all we saw what model generation is and what model is duration actually looks like.
And I think that that was very important for you to see how that will look in real life so that you
can easily detect a situation when it occurs.
And I think we really drove the point home with those interesting visuals that we had in that tutorial
.
There were two white models DCR 8.
So we looked at why they deteriorated over time.
That spontaneous iteration.
So although there is no blueprint here there can be myriads of reasons why models deteriorate we still
throw around some ideas that will help you understand why a model is iterating if you do come across
a situation.
Then we talked about the three levels of Bonnell maintenance or the H R R process assess retrain rebuild
.
Its not a complicated process.
All you have to do is make sure that you assess your models quite frequently at least once every six
months maybe a bit more frequently in some industries and for some types of models.
And then we talked about the Champion challenge or set up.
So if you do decide to build a new model and your old model is not performing too poorly then you might
want to run them side by side to see if the new model is actually performing better than the old model
in real life situations.
And that brings us to the end of this section.
I hope you enjoyed it picked up a lot of useful information and I look forward See you in the next one
.
Until then happy analyzing