And the previous tutorial we stopped after we made this visual AB test and we have the results here
.
So I really hope that it was quite clear what exactly we did.
We have now percentages of the total males that left the company.
So those are the orange and the percentages of total females that left the company 25 percent.
Also an orange and so not just comparing them visually.
You can say that females are more likely to leave the company than males all other things held equal
.
However do bear in mind that once again this is not a full fledged statistical AB test.
We didn't check for statistical significance and but it does give you some insights into the data.
So today what we're going to do is we're going to learn how to work with alias's.
But before we proceed Let's quickly fix up the format of this tab.
So we're just going to right click somewhere not on the data and we'll click Format and we'll change
this to 12.
So 12 overall.
Now the beauty of using Tablo for data mining rather than visualization is that you don't have to always
make things look great because you're not going to be presenting every single chart that you're creating
.
For instance I'm not going to change this header over here like if I was going to put in a report I
would change it.
And but in this case it's just for our sake so I'm not going to rename the y axis over here.
So now what I want to do is I want to rename the sheet.
So here we'll call it gender and now working with alias's.
So here you can see that we've got exited 0 and 1 meaning 0 is people who didn't exit and one is orange
.
People who did X and now even for our sake let alone when we put this into our if we decide to put this
specific charge into report this is a bit.
It's not quite it's not that obvious So why is it a one way a zero.
People don't think in binary terms.
People think in words.
So how about we change these and give them some aliases.
So one way is to create a calculated field.
Another way is to actually change your dimension or your column you know changing in the data set.
We want to change it in Tablo because we know that for every single child we create we want this to
actually say words rather than numbers we're never going to use the numbers we're never going to add
them up or do anything with them.
So we're going to right click this exited colon and we'll go to alias's over here.
And so now in alias's you can specify what alias to use for certain values.
So let's say if our value is 0 then we want to say stage right that person state and the value is what
we want to say that that person exited.
OK.
And so right away you can see that the values changed over here in the color legend and they're going
to be like that through out every worksheet that recreates is going to be much more convenient for us
.
And now because we have these aliases we can even drag them this column onto our label as well.
So here you can see it's much better now.
People don't have to look at the code legends to understand which state which people exited so you can
do it either way if you feel that this is sufficient for you then go ahead with that if you want to
present and perhaps you want to make it more clear what exactly is going on.
Then I would put exited in here.
Of course you have to make sure that it fits and we'll see that.
We'll talk about that later when we're creating more of these.
So that's how you work with alias's hope that was useful and I hope you do find ways to use aliases
in your work.
They can really make life easier and make your presentations more legible.
And I look for it scenics them.
Until then happy analyzing