In the previous tutorial we had quite a lot of theory about logistic regression and even though we were
talking about intuition of the logistic regression we had to look at a few formals anyway.
So today it's time to make up for that with some practice.
And finally today we're going to build our very first logistic regression.
I hope you're excited.
So here I've got Grinnel opened up and a very loaded the data set which is e-mail offer.
And I have even created two dummy variables for the gender categorical independent variables so please
go ahead and do that.
And once you've done that we will start creating the model in order to create a logistic regression
model you need to go to model and then go to limited dependent variable and then go to logit and then
go to binary.
And so here you need to take your binary dependent variable into and put it into the dependent variable
option and also that set as default because you'll need to rerun this model in a bit.
And we're just going to run the model with one variable.
We're only going to use age so we won't worry about gender at this stage.
And before you click ok make sure to change show slopes that mean to show p values because we are used
to using p values and we'll continue doing that.
So click OK.
And there you go that's your model.
It's been run.
It's ready as you can see it's very similar.
So here you've got your Similar to go just to the linear regression here you've got two variables there
are efficient and p values.
Here you've got some stats about the model as how it's running how it's been fitted and so on and some
additional information at the bottom which we won't worry about right now but we will get back to it
after we're more comfortable.
The confusion matrix Now what I would like us to do is to look at the graph the charts of the logistic
regression which we spoke in-depth about in the previous detail.
So just go to graphs and then go to fitted actual plot and select the one which is against age.
And here you can see the logistic regression graph.
It's exactly the one we talked about previously.
So vaguely at the bottom at the top you can see the actual observations there be imploded in red and
in blue you can see the chart for the logistic regression or the life logistic regression.
So let's take a random age here.
So for instance for age 39 which is over here you've got some verbals.
You've got a variable over here you go to a red line and you go red line over there so some people did
take up the offer some people didn't.
But according to our model anybody who's at age 39 their probability of taking up the offer is about
30 percent.
So it kind of makes sense right even if the probability is 30 percent.
Some people most people probably won't take up the offer without probability but some people still will
and that gives credit to our moral.
All right so now we're going to close that up and we're going to move this model to the side and will
run a new model with the second variable included.
So let's go ahead and do that model limited dependent variables logit binary.
And here just add in your new variable in this case you can add male or female.
Doesn't really matter.
We're going to add male and then just click OK and here we'll look at the chart.
But we'll do that later.
For now let's look at something else.
Let's go to analysis.
Go for costs I referred for causing anything.
Let's just run the model and see what the results will be.
So here what you get is a table which includes your actual took action or didn't take action variable
or dependent variable so you know what the result was and you have the prediction for the same person
here it only has the wrong numbers or doesn't have the gender or age.
And that's not very convenient So what are we going to do is we're going to save this new variable by
creating the plus up over here and right away gives it a name.
So the name is quite funny in this case it's as took a hat and that's just just a because it abbreviated
or shortened our variable.
The name of the variable took action.
So we're going to say took action underscore that.
And as you recall this is exactly what we were talking about previously.
Hat means prediction.
So this is OUR a white hat that we looked at in the previous tutorial.
So if we click OK now we can close this and leave the mall open just move to the side.
You can see that a new variable has been added to the data.
Took action underscore hat and now we can have a look at all of them together so just highlight the
variables.
And as you can see the dummies won't be highlighted that way.
Well if you keep this closed so the dummies are not highlighted which is good.
And we go to you or no let's go to Dora display values.
So here now you can see more information.
You can see the age the gender of the person and whether or not they took action and took action.
So let's have a look at a couple of examples here and why we're doing this well.
I'd like you to be a bit more prepared for the next tutorial when we're talking about false positives
and false negatives.
And if we look at this now it will make more sense what we're talking about in the next toilet.
So age this person the first row person the first row was 38 female.
They didn't take up action.
And what our model actually predicted for them is a 1 percent chance of taking action.
So that's good.
So basically means that our model is in line with not taking action.
Next person 32 female didn't take up action and particular very low value which is good.
Next person 46 male took action.
Yes.
And our model predicted a ninety nine point nine percent chance of taking action.
Great.
Next person 34 male didn't take action.
Our model predicted a 2.7 percent chance good so so far so good.
Next person for the male did not take action.
But our model predicted an 85 percent chance of them taking action.
So here you can see that our model made an error if we applied that logic where we derive though why
had value so this is the probability of we derived the Y had value so that 1 or 0 and we use the 50
percent line for us.
This would mean that the person is predicted to take action but in reality they didn't take action.
There is a zero here meaning that they ignore the offer.
So this is an example of when a logistic regression makes an error and that's fine.
This is normal.
No model in the world will always predict 100 percent correctly once in a while errors will be made
.
It's about controlling users and making sure there isn't too many of them and we'll talk about errors
a bit more in the next tutorial.
So that's what I wanted to show you over here.
That's pretty much it's for this tutorial.
The last thing I want to show you was the chart for the model with two variables.
So let's go ahead and look at it now.
I go to graphs and I got fitted versus actual plot and I plot against age.
What you'll see here is a bit of a different picture.
And you see here two of the sigmoid functions or two of the logistic regression curves.
And the question is question of the day is why is there two occurs and I'll let you think about that
on your own.
So it's a little challenge for you to figure out why there is two curves on this chart and I look for
the next time.
Until then happy analyzing