In the first tutorial we learn how to work with aliases.
And today I'll show you how to add a reference line to a chart.
But before we continue I wanted to show you another cool trick in a Tablo.
So here you can see that your labels are order in a specific manner.
First comes the label for the percentage and then the label for the actual class or the classification
.
So if you want to change them all you have to do is drag one on top of the other or change the order
here in the marks pane.
So I'm going to exit and put it above some number exited which is our table calculation.
So now here now you can see that first we see the classification.
And then we see the percentage.
Personally I think this looks better for this type of analysis.
And we'll leave it like that.
Now I'll show you how to add a reference line.
So why would you need to add a reference like.
Well in order to compare your results that you see here with some benchmark and what will our benchmark
be.
Well how about we check how many people exited the company from this sample on average.
So generally speaking we're far out looking at any kind of classification male female country credit
score anything.
We just want to see what is the percentage of people that actually left this company from the sample
and we can create another chart so we can do a simple procedure but omits a classification however because
Tablo so convenient and it's so easy in terms of drag and drop all we have to do here is just take a
gender and remove it from the columns and let's just make some more space and right away you can see
that we've got on the chart so there's no classification here and out of the whole sample there's 80
percent that stayed.
And 20 percent that left.
So now we know that the exit rate is 20 percent and we can always get back to this simple way just to
remove your classification and your chart will collapse into just the overall picture for this whole
sample.
So I'm going to press controls at twice now to return gender.
But now that we know that 20 percent of people left.
How about we add a reference line so that we can then look at look at it and compare our exit rates
and we see four different classes to the overall exit rate.
So we're going to right click the access and here we'll check or select Add Reference line.
And here you've got a couple of options.
So you can add the line you can add a band you can add a distribution you can add a box plug.
Pretty self-explanatory.
We're going to work with a line and we want to add the line for the entire table.
So not per page or per cell.
And here it might be a bit confusing because you've got the first you have to choose the value and it's
it's a bit like nonintuitive which you've got to do here.
Well actually you've got to change this one first here so you can either do the same over a certain
value and this value has to be present in your worksheet.
So that's why you only see this table calculation because that's the only measure that we have present
in our worksheet as when you have more you'll be able to select different ones.
But in this case we don't want some we don't want minimum maximum average median what we want is a constant
and that's why it is a bit confusing because Carson has nothing to do with this specific value of all
the other ones.
Yes they work with the specific value that you choose but it's just like constant the value disappears
and you can enter a constant.
And that's what we need.
So we're going to change this to zero point two.
So that's our average.
Here you can change the label so what will that show we can show nothing you can show the value in show
the computation.
So that's when you have like a computation here you can you can add a custom label.
So in this case we don't want any label because we already have an access which tells us 20 percent
line and so what type of line do you want Joe on the dotted line.
Do you want a small online can change the color.
I'm just going to leave it at the standard line.
So for 20 percent and that's pretty much it.
So once we click OK we've got our 20 percent line and we can see that females exit or female customers
are more likely than customers on average overall and male customers are less liked.
That makes sense because we only have two categories here.
So obviously if one is greater than the other than one is going to be above average one's going to be
below average and that is how you add a reference line to your chart and in the next tutorial we're
going to start replicating this chart for other classifications.
And it's going to be lots of fun.
So I look forward to seeing you then.
Until next time happy be analyzing