Previously on House of Cards you saw how to deal with the numeric error.
I'm joking.
We pray it previously we in our course Brucey you know a science course we learned how to deal with
errors where a
supposedly numerical value is not conforming with the format of an American value and we use the ISM
function to figure out what it is and we found that in our balance column we had a lot of whoops where
is the balance column.
We had a lot of anomalies.
So 10 anomalies and then used in the metric function in its inverse version where it is equal to want
to exclude these rows from our insert and now we're faced of another era where a string of binary data
would be truncated.
So something is getting cut off and I'll show you a quick trick to that.
That'll fix this error right away.
I'm just going to take this and I'm going to replace it with 10 and let's let's do this again so we'll
recreate the table.
And so now we're saying in the zip code you can have up to 10 characters.
Interesting.
What's going to happen.
We don't really need to truncated because there's nothing in there anyway.
So now we execute.
Ha ha.
And now we have a different area.
Carroll has put in so many errors into this one single file right.
But anyway what's what we achieved is we got rid of that era.
What does that tell us.
That tells us that in the zip code there was a value at least one value that was longer than seven characters
and it was being truncated.
And so what happened is our quality assurance mechanism worked.
We put in seven here to prevent anything beyond certain characters to be being inserted into this table
because we know that the zip code has to be 7 and if it's more than 7 then it's an error.
And it did error out so we called an error that way and now it's up to us to get rid of the error and
not insert it.
So we'll execute that.
And here I'll show a different approach.
So selects are from the same table.
Where and what is all culms zipcode.
And we know that it's a text column right.
So how we look at it's length right length is greater than 7.
So let's see what we pick up that way.
Aha there's two rows.
You see this zipcode there's an X or symbol is a W on the end and there's this SuperCoach there's a
one on the end and I'm actually using that analysis.
I'm guess I'm doing analysis liberally very liberally.
You can't really say that this is the symbol that's not supposed to be there that you're the one.
Maybe somebody put an extra five in the middle or the KS and supposed to be all the C's and supposed
to be there and everything is double up.
Maybe this is completely wrong value that's not even related to zip code so if you if you are thinking
of fixing this manually because the rest of the roll looks good right you think you are fixing this
man by just removing one letter from the end.
I would think again I would seriously consider taking this data back to where it came from because there's
obviously an error or at least excluding this column from analysis if you don't need it.
So always be careful with manually fixing things because then the responsibility is on you that you're
100 percent sure that that is the correct way to fix it anyway.
Going back.
So that's how we exclude these columns.
These are all.
So how about now we take this filter.
So we'll take Len zipcode Greg and so on we added into our filters and then zip code regrind 7.
So here we're going to have to say how many rows were excluded.
And you intuitively you want to put two rows here right two rows excluded.
However that might not be the case.
And let me explain why.
Because we're really excluding some rows here.
And what if one of the rows are excluded.
Here is also That's the row here.
One of the rows here.
So in that way you if you put in two rows here then you're double counting.
You've excluded it here and then as if you excluded here.
But it doesn't even get to this stage.
So these filters work you know like one up to the other.
So remember that the total of the rows you excluded Plus the rows affected should give you the total
of the rows in Europhile and that is important.
That is your quality assurance check so don't rush this.
Let's just what we do what you need to do is the proper way of doing it is you obviously truncate table
insert and you execute well.
Here you can't you can't tell because because nothing has been inserted.
Normally what you do is you add subtract the difference of how you go to insert in this case and then
you go to insert in this case and you would see how many rows.
But obviously in this case you can't do that.
So the only other option we have is we have to check so we can see that balance here is OK.
So in this case we can say that two two rows have been excluded.
The other way you would do it is you would you look at this file right so you would say.
All right all of this part I would say I would first apply this filter I would say all right where is
numeric is equal to 1.
Right.
So that excludes those 10 rows and then apply this filter.
So and then let's see how many of the remaining actually are nonconforming with the format of the zipcode
and it's still true.
OK.
So in that case you can say there are two rows and probably less Let's keep doing it this way.
So next next time next time when we build something the next filter we will add onto this and then add
on again again again.
So that way we'll have the correct number of rows are excluding.
All right so that's how you deal with nonconformity of rolls.
So teks columns that are turning into tech Skolem's that are staying text columns but they have to have
a certain format so they have to have seven symbols.
For example we will learn how to investigate zip code even further.
And you know special CRN formats of accommodation further down the track in this section.
But for now we're faced with string or binary data would be truncated.
Well that's that's basically this error because we said is greater than 7.
You have to always do the opposite.
Is less or equal to.
And don't forget the equal.
So the opposite of greater is less or equal to 7.
So we want to keep only these rows.
So let's do that again.
Drumroll and execute.
All right there we go.
So now we have a new era conversion failed when converting and date and or time from character string
.
So that's a datum issue.
We will look at this area in the next tutorial and I'll look forward to seeing you there.