Too quickly recap last time we found two anomalies.
First of all in row 81 all of the columns got skewed to the left.
You can see here that there's nothing after email address inclusive and in row 96 all the columns got
skewed the opposite way.
Everything moved to the right after a certain point over here and there therefore this last record is
now in its own column.
So we're going to investigate that today and we're going to start with 96 because it's the easier one
.
Let's scroll and see where this happened.
Where did the column start skewing to the right.
For now everything is good good.
And then over here you can see.
Thank you.
Great experience and then the e-mail is skewed so that means once again this comment got split into
two.
And there was something wrong with the text qualifier as you can see one quotation mark here so let's
go into our file and investigate this further.
Now we need to open up our project folder and we're not going to touch the file in our uploaded data
folder because as of now our upload has failed and we're going to have to replace this file.
We're going to go back and we're going to move to our prepared data folder.
So here we're going to open this up in Notepad plus plus.
And at the same time what we're going to do is we're going to open up the original data folder but we're
not going to obviously open the file that we have here we are going to copy it once again we will paste
it here.
We don't want to replace.
We want to copy but give it a different name.
And so he will say original so we know what we're dealing with.
OK.
So now we will open this one up as well.
And so let's have a look to look at the both files at the same time you need to right click on the original
or one of them and select move to other view.
Now you've got the original at the bottom and you've got the prepared file at the top.
And we also want to synchronize with the scrolling.
So if I want to scroll this follow this file to scroll as well so maybe let's increase the size here
a bit so that the same size.
That's about right.
And we want to synchronize the scrolling so you go to View syncro nice vertical scrolling and maybe
horizontals or so now when I scroll one file the other one scrolls as well.
And that way it's very easy to navigate and find any changes.
And that's exactly what you want to have a look at.
I want to show you what happened in the prepared file and I want to show you what it looked like in
the original file because it's always good to revert to the original.
You can already see some differences for instance.
There are quotation marks here and there are no quotation marks here.
Well the reason for that is very simple.
In the original file there were quotation marks because this is a CACP file and you had to qualify this
text delimiter.
Therefore saying that this is actually a comma inside the dollar or the dollar amount and therefore
you need these quotation marks to tell in your program that's dealing with this file that this comma
is not a delimiter.
And then when we did we did in Excel is we removed the commas as you remember and the dollar signs and
since there's no Colmar anymore here there's no need for the quotation marks and therefore Excel did
not place any quotation marks.
So nullus scroll down to row number 96 and have a look at what is going on over there.
So there is a row number 96.
There it is.
And we want to find out why the rows are the columns shifted to the right.
We already know that that happened somewhere around the Calment area.
So there is a common here.
This is in the prepared file.
The one that we manipulated in Excel and this is our home cell.
That same comment in or feedback in the original file.
So here you can see several things.
First of all here there's a lot of quotation marks and here is one quotation mark.
And here there's is an extra mark his nothing.
So right away you can see that there was corruption in the original file it was it was corrupted.
It was supposed to be two quotation marks or one here one here and somehow it so happened that the quotation
mark disappeared from the start.
And therefore now we're seeing these errors which you're seeing here in the prepared file is the result
of all manipulations in Excel of course they were inadvertent we didn't want we didn't specifically
target this call cell but this Excel has its own as you realize by now Excel has a life of its own and
does its own thing.
So when excel saw this single quotation mark in it couldn't obviously understand that this is a whole
phrase and it should be fixed so this quotation mark has has to be returned.
Instead what it did is it decided OK.
So there's is a quotation mark here.
And so therefore this part is one one piece of text or one element with a quotation mark so a quotation
mark is not a standard symbol that you see in text.
Usually I use quotation marks.
This is Excel thinking.
Usually I use quotation marks too as text qualifiers.
So what I need to do is this is what Excel did.
It went OK.
I'm going to take this text which is kind of anomalous and looks like it might be an error in here and
I'm going to qualify it.
So I'm going to put another set of text qualifiers around this text like that there.
So meaning that's OK.
This is one block of text including this quotation mark and that's how it should be treated.
But now you can see that there's three over here.
What does that mean.
Well in reality what happens is if you want to unqualified a quotation mark within a text you need to
put another quotation mark before it.
So basically what happened is AAVSO Excel did that put all of this text into quotation marks it said
well actually the user obviously wanted a quotation mark within this text.
So I'm going to unqualified so and it put another quotation mark before and therefore you go now you
have to these quotation marks on the sides.
Qualifying the whole phrase.
Then you've got the phrase with the quotation mark.
But in order for the quotation mark to be displayed it has to be unqualified to have another quotation
mark.
It can be a bit confusing but that is how SEUS view files work.
And those are the rules.
And that is what is exactly what Excel did.
And so I'm just going to return that.
So we don't have this have this file modified at all here so what Excel essentially did is it made this
modification to this part of the text.
That's what you see here and it's doesn't need any quotation marks here because there's no Como's there's
no quotation marks that are part of the text and therefore Excel just left it as it is.
And now we see this as a separate data element a separate column and then this as a separate column
and therefore everything is skewed.
So you see South Africa here South Africa and then this goes in line with the comments or this column
over here where the feedback goes normally and then this text or whatever is inside the quotation marks
this bit here goes where the email is supposed to go normally.
So that's what happened over here.
We're going to correct this now.
I'll just show you how to correct anomalies in a text files.
Good exercise.
So what we want to do we know exactly what is supposed to be in this speech is supposed to be here.
So we want to take this quotation mark and we want to move it to the start of the text and then we know
that there shouldn't be a quotation mark.
Therefore we should delete this quotation mark along with the qualifying symbol.
Another way of thinking about this is let's return that back.
Another way of thinking about this is let's start off with undo whatever excelled at.
So we're going to remove this quotation mark and we're going to remove this quotation mark and then
we're going to remove this unqualified quotation mark of Excel.
And so now you have the same result as you see here as in the original file and now we know how to fix
the corruption we just need to put a quotation mark at the start over here.
And therefore now this is all one phrase and will be treated as the feedback with the comment and will
go here.
And then the rest of the data will be aligned as great.
That is how we fix up row number 96.
By the way it's number 97 here because of the headers so in reality this is number 96 or record number
number six.
Now let's move up to record number 81 and see what we can do there.
This one's a bit more interesting so we've got everyone over here.
We've got 81 over here.
What's going on.
Let's move to the Calment or.
Well first of all we can go to our society's package and have a look here just to make sure we know
exactly where this is happening the era.
So if we scroll this is 81 at the top we scroll scroll scroll and then we see that feedback and after
that everything cuts off and inside feedback you've got this phrase nothing to complain about will recommend
to my friends.
Thanks.
And then there's a comma there's a number and there is more.
There's more numbers.
Numbers number numbers and commas and so on.
So basically everything there is supposed to be here in these columns and more is now inside this one
column.
So it kind of ate up all of the columns on the right.
Let's see how that could have happened.
So now we're in our row 81.
Let's scroll to the right so we're here.
And so what do we see.
Nothing to complain about.
This is the modified file the Excel one.
Then some more text and then has got some.
One two three four more columns and then has got empty columns as got the quotation marks and then it's
got a more quotation marks so a very interesting situation what happened here to understand better what
happened.
Always good to look at the original file once again don't open the original file copy it and then open
it just to be safe.
So here let's have a look.
So you've got a quotation mark in the original file.
Then you've got a comma will recommend to my friends.
Thanks and then you've got another comment so the rest of the kind of information is starting over here
.
What happened there why why is the rest of the information starting here why is whereas this other quotation
marks so you can see right away that this record is also corrupted because it is supposed to have a
quotation mark on the end in the previous scenario.
We lost the quotation mark at the start here you lost the British market then and this is much more
dangerous what happens here is once a quotation mark is lost on the end.
Excel thinks that everything after the quotation marks is still part of this record so it's expects
that actually not excel SOSIAS will think that everything from there onwards will be part of this whole
same text so it will expect a new crash.
Will just keep going.
I think that the cell keeps going and going and going until the next partition mark which can even be
on the next line.
So here another thing you can see is that the original file in this role was actually corrupted quite
a lot.
What happened is this Calment forget about the quotation mark there is should be a quotation mark here
but irrespective of that we're expecting some more information.
So off to the commons we we know we've got to have an email so just like here we've got an email address
and then after that email address it should be like a log in or something like that than a password
and then the type of browser the person is using and none of that is here.
So here we only have 1 2 3 4 columns which look like columns from the very end.
So here you've got these geographical coordinates.
Then you've got some hash code and then you've got some.
I don't at all like meters this is the height of the person because that's inches and if you go to the
top of your file.
This is the height in meters.
So here you've got those four Combs from the end.
Then here you're supposed to have like a lot more columns.
But instead what this file has is has these empty columns so every time you have a column or after column
column that means that there's nothing in that column.
So basically Urooj in the original file the last four columns got shifted over here and everything after
that got deleted.
So it looks like there was a huge mess up and these two issues are not related all they don't.
They're not supposed to be related so when there's no quotation mark here on there not necessarily all
the other columns officer it gets destroyed.
This is just an anomaly that happened here specifically so you will find situations further down the
track where you still have this question mark at the start and there are no quotation marks at the end
and the other columns are still alive so they are still there.
In this case those like major corruption.
This is one of those anomalies that you can't really fix you've got excluded from the file and reported
or investigated separately.
But now let's look at what happened over here.
So here we've got in the prepared file.
That's after all manipulations with Excel.
You've got that quotation mark.
Excel kept it.
And then what happens is you've got the text.
Then you've got your 3 or 4 anomalies so the columns disappear just like here so they're not there.
That's fine.
Then you've got your empty columns just the same amount as over here and there.
What Excel did after that.
Is it actually put a quotation mark for you.
Because Excel you might imagine what excelsis excelsis this and then it's expecting more columns.
So right now there's no qualifying symbol so for Excel.
This all of this once once you open it up in Excel.
All of this is actually one huge cell and then it's expecting more columns.
And so what Excel did is it kind of.
It's quite smart in this way.
It helps you prevent an even bigger mistake or bigger data error.
Here what happens is it put a quotation mark after the end and then it puts these actual empty columns
so filled the rest of the gaps with empty columns for you so that your file has a consistent structure
so every single row has the same number of columns.
That's just how Excel works and works with tables you can have a table where there's not enough columns
so that is what it did.
If you were to try and upload the original file before our manipulations in Excel so if all this magical
benefit that Excel happened to give us which we didn't even know about right for if we filed this if
you tried to upload this file what will happen is you've got this opening quotation mark right.
This is very interesting actually that you got the opening quotation mark and then it keeps going.
So this is all one cell as I'm highlighting this is all one cell for Sosias the Sosias were to look
at this file.
This is all one cell.
This is still one cell with lots of coma's which are qualified because of quotation marks or qualified
symbol.
It gets to the end for SSA as even this carriage return line feed symbol over here it still qualified
so it's within the quotation marks so as Assayas would continue on it would say.
OK so this is still part of that same column.
OK and then it gets to the quotation mark and then it says or writes so that is where I sell ends.
So all of this information would be actually sitting in this one cell over here and then the best part
is then this would be the next cell.
This would be the next cell up to here.
Remember that issue that you discussed so that's a quotation mark at the end it doesn't really for a
sucess.
It doesn't really do much.
It's like the quotation mark has to be at the start of the column to be an opening qualifier so that
would be the next cell.
This is still in.
This is still in row 81 so a row 82 would be completely gobbled up by row 81.
This would be the next cell and so on.
So a huge huge huge mess up until Sosias gets to the end of this row where this carriage return line
feed symbol is not qualified and therefore it will recognize 83 as a separate row.
So basically what would have happened is these two rows would have been combined into one and only normal
upload would continue from royalty 3.
So even if was not knowing it.
Excel actually did us a favor.
Here it protected the rest of our file from continuous corruption by placing this quotation mark here
and stopping from the rest of the rows being.
Or the next draw being gobbled up into this row.
So even though we have 1 corruption in row 8 you want.
It has been stopped so this has been quite a quite a long tutorial but I hope you understand these things
because as a data scientist you will be dealing quite a lot with C S V files and comma separated and
tabulated files and so on.
You will need to know what Tex qualifiers are and this is a great great example of how they work and
how corruption can really damage your the integrity of your file.
So what are we going to do here is we're not going to.
We're not.
We're not going to do any modifications to this slide because obviously we don't have this data we don't
know how to return it.
The only thing we can do is exclude it completely from our analysis and not uploaded and but we definitely
have to still keep it for all records and I'll show you how to do that in the next tutorial.