Confusion matrix don't just of these terms sometimes that they come up with like why would you call
something the confusion matrix when it's designed to explain things.
Anyway let's get into the confusion matrix.
So last time we left off over here where we discussed false positives and false negatives type 1 errors
and type 2 hours.
So the false positive is when you predict that something will happen but it actually doesn't happen
and that's a type 1 error and a false negative is when you predict that something won't happen.
But it does actually happen and there's a type 2 here.
So let's see what we can do with these.
Let's start building a matrix and we'll understand what it is exactly saying as we go along with it
.
So we've got the y hat at the top of the predicted dependent variable so whether or not we're saying
that event will happen at the top and on the left we've got the y y actual dependent variable so there
it's telling us whether or not that event actually did happen.
Now under each one of them let's put the two different options that are available.
You can have a 0 or 1 so 0 for Y had one for Y had 0 for y and 1 for Y.
And in that space between them there's four more squares there.
That's where our confusion matrix will be.
So we'll start off the first square right away here.
That's is the intersection of when y had is 1 so we're predicting something will happen or the person
will take up the offer or the event will occur.
And at the same time it actually did happen.
So let's say for instance we had 50 observations in or out of our observations the ones that we said
will happen and actually did happen.
There's 50.
Now let's look at the ones that didn't happen.
And we also said that they won't happen.
So basically we said that won't happen and they actually didn't happen.
So let's say that in there we have three five.
So 35 of the observations and say we have a hundred and fifty of them actually did happen.
And our prediction was that will happen.
And 35 five of them they didn't happen.
But we also said that they won't happen based on our model.
Now let's look at the other two squares.
So can you guess from here which one is the false positives and which ones are false negatives.
I'll give you a second to do it.
You can post a video if you want to try.
Try this on your own.
So the false positives are the type 1 error are at the top on the right because a type 1 error is when
you're saying that something will happen but actually doesn't happen.
I remember the way the way I remembered is it's not as bad as saying that something won't happen and
actually does happen.
Although that might not necessarily be the case but it's an easy way to remember it.
So that's how Type 1 era it's up at the top over there on the right now on the left at the bottom we've
got the false negative for the type 2 era when we were saying that something won't happen.
But it actually does happen.
And let's say we had 10 and five in them respectively.
So this is your confusion matrix and what it's telling you is it's giving you a quick overview of how
well your model is performing.
If you look at the diagonal the last what it won't be colored probably in in your report that you'll
be studying.
But if you look at the top left in the bottom right just if you just remember that.
That way those are the good things.
So in total that's how much you predicted correctly.
And the other diagonal so the top right and the bottom left those are the bad things those those are
the observations that you weren't able to predict those are your errors.
So the more you have in the first diagonal the better the more you have in the second Agel the worse
you Mallos performing.
And let's have a look at two ratios that you can calculate.
So one the first rate is the accuracy rate and you take the correct predicted divide by total.
In our case we predicted correctly 85 the total is 100 so if we do the 500 we get an 85 percent accuracy
rate.
And you can tell it right away just by looking at the confusion matrix especially if you know the total
number of observations right away so you don't have to do a calculation and add up all the values in
the Matrix.
That way you can just divide by 100.
But even by looking at the confusion metrics you can quickly understand what the accuracy rate is and
also the error rate.
So you take the total that you were wrong about and you divide by the entire total So in this case it's
15 to 100.
It's 15 percent error rate.
That's all for today we'll be using the confusion matrix in our next tutorial.