Hello and welcome back in today's tutorial we will look at the coefficients of a logistic regression
and we will understand what insights we can and what it says we cannot derive from our models.
So let's go ahead and create our model as you can see.
I've already loaded the data it's the email offer we file and I have created dummy variables.
Now I'm going to go to model limited logic binary and the depende variables took action.
I'll set it as default regressors.
I'm going to use H and female the dummy variable for female and Auel click show p values.
So once you've done that click OK and here is our model.
So what we are focusing on today is this top part and there are four main points that I wanted to get
across today and the last will be a bit complex but I'll get to that.
So to start off with the first thing that you can do just in like in a linear regression you can look
at the sign.
So the sign here for female is negative.
The sign for age is positive.
That means that female detracts from the effect.
Age adds to the effect.
What does that mean.
That means that if you take everything hold everything else constant but you increase age by one year
then the probability will increase and the same thing if you take two people the same age and one of
them is male.
Another one is female then the probability for female will be lower the probability predicted by this
model be lower.
Now that is the first thing that you can do.
The second thing is something you cannot do and you cannot use the coefficients to quantify any interpretations
.
Remember how in that linear regression we were able to say because 1 coefficient is greater than the
other.
Then we can understand how much greater the effect of that variable is compared to the effect of the
other one.
So in order to understand this a bit better I'm going to run a new model.
I'll leave this to the side.
We're going to run a new model but I'm going to replace female biner the dummy variable for FEMA replace
it with mail and I'll run it now.
So here you can see that both coefficients are positive.
However what we could have done in a linear regression we could have said that because the coefficient
for mail is five times greater than the coefficient for H.
That means that the effect of this variable as you remember we used to say per unit of of that variable
is greater than the per unit effect of the H variable.
However in a logistic regression you cannot use the coefficients to quantify any sort of effect.
So let's go to the logistic regression formula to understand this.
This is a former for the simple logistic regression.
This is a form of for the multiple The logistic regression and it's also called the logistic regression
just because people don't normally use the simple logistic regression.
In fact the whole share of seegar if you very very often the number of variables in a logistic regression
is can be very high so 5:06 is standard 10 20 is also very normal.
Can go up to huge numbers.
Not saying that that is the best approach to use logistic regression but you will come across situations
when there's lots and lots of variables in a logistic regression.
So what else you can see from here is that the verbal that we're predicting P is actually hidden.
It's not just on the left of the equals on it's inside a ratio which is called The Odds Ratio and it's
inside a logarithm So this whole expression the left is called the log odds.
And people just don't think in log terms.
So this variable or this new expression log odds.
It's not that easy to understand or visualize in your head.
If you look at LOEG odds as a separate variable then this becomes a linear regression for log odds and
that way you could interpret the coefficients.
But if you want to interpret the coefficients for the probability then from here you simply cannot do
that because the formula is so complex.
So we will stop on that that we cannot use the coefficients to quantify any effects and that actually
implies two things.
The first thing is that you cannot use the coefficient to quantify the per unit effect of a variable
or an independent variable to your dependent variable so like we used to say that a $5 increase or one
dollar increase in marketing spend results in a so many dollar increase in revenue you can't do that
.
And the second thing in a second sump part of this is that you cannot use the coefficients to quantify
to compare the quantified effects of the two different Marable's.
So you can't say for coefficient one variable is greater than the other five times greater than the
other than the effects can be five times greater.
Once again is because it's to do with quantification you simply cannot do that because the former Formula
is complex.
So we'll end that part on that.
That is point number two point number three is what you can do which you can do is you can look at the
coefficients and without quantifying the effects you can say you can still observe and you can determine
which effect is greater.
So just generally speaking which effect is greater here you can see that the coefficient for male is
greater than the coefficient for H.
And that means that per unit of this variable it is the effect is greater than per unit of this variable
.
And remember that everything is relative and this is going to be important just now it is relative to
the scale that you are measuring these variables on because we're measuring age in years.
So if we start measuring age in months then the values of age will go up 12 times.
So that means the coefficient and what all cell is same but the coefficient will go down 12 times.
And if we start measuring age in decades then the values of the variable will go down by 10 but the
coefficient will go up by 10 and so we can manipulate the coefficient the absolute value of the confession
and therefore we always have to say per unit.
So you can still do that you can compare per unit and see which of which of the variables has a greater
effect per unit.
So remember is relative.
Now the last thing is a more of an advanced technique.
And for some of you it might not apply so you just ignore it if you don't think that you'll be using
it.
But for those who are more interested in like the advanced type of stats then there is this variable
here Zed score and this score is basically a standardized coefficient and how do you get that score
well you all all that you need to do to get that score is you take your coefficient and you divided
by your standard error of that variable.
Same thing here.
Coefficient divided by the standard error.
And here you get a set score.
So you can think of that score in terms of a standardized coefficient.
And what that means is that it is no longer dependent on the scale of that specific variable so because
the standard error is also measured in years when you divide one by the other you get this coefficient
which won't change if you change the scale on which you're measuring age or same thing with kilometres
in two meters or inches and kilograms into pounds and so on or grams.
So this Zed won't change if you change the scale of the underlying variable.
However it is much more complex to interpret because Zed is measured on its own scale and that scale
is in units of the standard deviation of the underlying variable.
And once again as humans we don't think in those units.
And moreover because it's all relative it can lead to different seemingly different results.
So here you can see that Zed for age is three point eight said for male is two point nine.
Although here we said that the effect of male is greater from based on the xit statistic it looks like
the effect of age is greater.
But it might be confusing if we think of it in absolute terms but it's all relative.
So the effect here was greater for male in terms of relative to the units of each of these variables
.
Here are the effect of age is greater relative to the standard deviation of each variable.
So although there might be more convenient when you have lots of variables in mind the more convenient
because it's standardized and you don't have to remember the different units and always say them.
It might be a bit harder to interpret.
So once again that's a bit more of an advance topic and you can still use your models without having
to worry about that.
Just focus on the coefficient.
Those were the four things that you can and cannot do if logistic regression.
And here's a slide that you can take away after this tutorial.
You can just simply download it and use it for reference in the future so it sums up those four things
.
Now let's quickly recap.
You can interpret signs you cannot interpret magnitudes to quantify associations.
You can still use magnitudes to contrast per unit associations and you can use that statistic to conscience
associations as well.
However the sense that this is standardize so it might be a bit harder to interpret