In today's tutorial I will show you a few simple tricks that will help you find corrupt records and
save you a lot of time.
Let's start off by opening our Roth table.
Now get rid of the top 1000 restriction and click execute at the bottom here.
You can see that there are fifty thousand and four rows in the output.
This is already suspicious because our daughter should only have 50000 rows.
Now this window at the top is called your query window in your query window.
Scroll to the bottom.
Now we're going to make some adjustments after the last line.
Add the following text where then copy column 46 with the square brackets.
Then type in a knot like.
And then just two single quotations one after the other with nothing in between.
I will explain what we're doing in a second.
For now let's add a second line or then copy the longitude.
Then once again not like.
And then a single quotation mark then the percent sign then a period then another percent sign and another
single quotation.
Congratulations you have just added a filter to your select statement.
Now when you execute this script only two types of rows will be allowed in the output.
They either have to be not empty in column 46 and this is specified by the first line you added or they
have to not have a period in the long digit column.
This condition is said by the second row as we saw in the previous tutorials Soros corruption often
causes rows to shift either left or right.
This handy little trick will help you pick up most of these rows that shifted in your daughter.
The first condition will be true for rows that were shifted to the right and now the last column is
not empty.
The second condition will be true for rows and shifted to the left and now there is no period in the
long.
You should call them instead.
It's now empty.
Now let's execute the script.
14 rows have been picked up.
If you scroll through them you can see that they do look suspicious on the end here you can see how
this method picked up these rows.
Some of them had been shifted to the right.
Some of them to the left.
However not all of these rows had been shifted.
Some simply had missing data in them like for example row 4.
Try to figure out on your own which of these rows were actually corrupt and which had missing data.
This is not the only way you can check for data issues.
You can also look at other columns however prefer B.
They have to be towards the end of the table.
Also you can pass for other conditions and you will learn how to do that.
When we talk about the basics of skill a simple example of when you would want to modify this query
would be.
If you want to keep the rows of missing daughter in your table and only exclude the corrupt DROs.
Note that this neat little trick most certainly isn't a 100 percent guarantee that you will pick up
all errors in your data.
However it works like dynamite.
You can use it to find the bulk of the errors and later in the course.
I will show you how to surgically treat the remaining few to finish off now that we have found these
errors what do we do with them.
Well there are two options.
You can either deal with them in a schedule or you can take a step back and deal with them in SSA as
before the load happens.
It all depends on your situation and your personal preference.
I will show you the Sosias method and we will look at it in the next tutorial.