[Autogenerated] So far, we've gone for the entire consumer driven,
contract testing, workflow Wish win cloud contract.
This has involved taking a consumer taking a provider,
a news in a single contract with a single interaction between
the two of them to implement our feature.
Whilst has being a lot to learn along the way,
it's still not really enough to develop a production system.
This is because there is normally more than one
interaction between T micro services.
And, of course,
these interactions will require more and more contracts to be created.
There's no anything we have to do to get this to work,
often create the additional contracts.
When we generate stops,
they will contain all of the interactions in all of the contracts on.
Whenever we create provider side contract verification tests,
they, too will verify ordinance or actions in all the contracts.
So just before using more than one contract together in a demo,
we're going to take a quick look at the matching process.
This is what spring cloud contract or more accurately, y mark goes through.
In order to determine which responds to give for requests to a stop.
It's important for us to understand this as it makes it easy to handle
multiple contracts on D book when something goes wrong.
So we'll start with a table where each row represents a
simple ized view off the request.
Part of a contract.
For example, the first row represents a contract,
which requires a get request to slash matches under query,
Where Mrs Must Equal.
True, The second row represents another contract,
which requires a get request to slash Mrs Onda query where matches must equal.
True, the same rules apply to deferred row.
Let's imagine these are loaded into a stop so we can fire.
Request it it on follow through the table to see what happens.
Let's try a get request to slash matches with a query.
Off matches equals tree oneness.
Request.
It's wire mark.
It will start with the first row on.
Compare each cell to to request the method, get matches our request method.
So why Mark locks and match the path also matches our request path.
So again, why mark locks a match?
But in the case of our query, Mrs does not equal matches,
so we do not lock a match as every single part of the
contract did not match the request wire.
Mark will treat it as a miss on,
then iterated a net contract and tried out again.
The methods match the path is not much a slash mrs does no equal slash Much is.
But this time the query does much again as every single part
of the contract did not match a request.
Why Mark will treat it as a miss.
So again it will Iterating this time said afeard row.
The methods match the paths much on a query matches as
every single part of the request matches.
We can say that this contract was met by the request.
Following this, the response part of this contract will be returned by the stub to the client.