[Autogenerated] when communicating with AP eyes.
It's quite common for the responses that they give to be based on request data.
For example, if we were to do a get request for flights from London to Paris,
we'd expect to get only those airports back in the response.
If we were to change the value of these query parameters,
for example, to Malala and Sydney,
then we'd expect the airports in the response to change to Milan in
Sydney to the same rules apply to all possible requests.
For example,
London to Berlin would always cause London and Berlin to be returned.
So if we think about it, these examples are all of the same request,
with only the query parameter changing.
And again, the response is always the same,
too, only that some values are based on the request data.
Wouldn't it be simple if we could have a single contract
to represent all of these interactions?
So let's take the previous example on See how we can put it into a contract.
Here we have a get request to slash flights on a queer parameter name,
to which can have any value and a query permits and names from which can
also have any value from the request point of view,
were already achieving what we want here,
as any airport can be provided in order for the contract to be met.
The problem, though,
is that regardless of the values of the airport query parameters,
we will always return flights between Amsterdam and Tokyo.
Obviously,
unless you provide Amsterdam and Tokyo as a to and from queer parameter values,
it doesn't really make sense to do this.
Fortunately,
the spring Cloud contract DSL has a way to work around these
issues by providing from request method that can be used to
interplay all data from the request.
So by calling a from request method,
we can substitute the value of the from queer parameter,
and we can also substitute the value of the T query parameter.
This means are generated.
Stop will be dynamically populated based on data in the request.
In this case, that means that the airports returns are the ones past,
in which is a behavior that we want.
This means we can define a single contract that could be used by a wide range
of requests which will always return a sensible response. Based on that request,