[Autogenerated] in this demo,
we're going to start with a failing consumer side test.
The reason it will fail will be because our consumer will now be
dependent on request data being returned in the response.
Well, then, define a contract which we can use to make our tests pass,
making use of the from request method in the process.
Well, then make artists pass and finally will finish up on the provider side,
making our contract verification test pass.
Also starting with far Can Shima project.
A requirement has come in to generate Are you I.
D.
On the consumer side Robin and getting it back from the provider.
Let's modified a credit chat request so it provides one by adding
the fields and also adding a getter for it.
We're now going to skip forward in time a bit by just
quickly writing a check to see if the U I.
D.
We get back from the credit check Service is the same you you i d.
We provide in the request.
It's a little odd to do this, but for the sake of example,
will say that a requirement came in from the business to prevent us from
accidentally given a result off somebody else's credit.
Chat to them.
Now we can go back to our test and modify it slightly.
Well, now use Jason path to a certain response,
making sure the status field is still equal to
grant it and then will assert au i.
D Field is returned by checking its not know we're being a little lady here,
as we should use Red Jacks,
but it's not too relevant for the purpose of this demo.
The point is, so is that a year I D returned is now generated by a service,
so we don't know the value of it in advance.
Finally, we can delete our old assertion, ruin our tests and see what happens.
As expected,
we have our exception stating that the U ideas do not match scrolling up.
We concede that this is because the your I D returned is a
one statically defined in our contract and does not equal the
one that we sent in the request.
Switching to our provider project, we can fix this number.
Get into our contract should grant a credit score of high to a citizen.
We should first declared a year.
I D must be given in our request.
Then, using the Kashima method, we will provide a year I g rejects.
So our stop will still support any randomly generated you
Your i d amusing the producer method.
We will Hard code eu I d for the request in the contract verification tests.
Okay,
now we can move on to the interesting part which is calling
from request and then using Jason Path to pull out the year
i d from the request body.
This means the stub will always return the you your
i d given in the request to it.
The last step is to make our producer method a little stricter or
is requiring the response to equal the one made in the request
Switching to the terminal LaShawn maven clean install skip tests
to regenerate our contracts, Then back in the consumer project.
Let's run those tests and see if they pass.
Great, they dio I'm scrolling up.
We can see that the year i d in the response match the u i.
D.
In the request This is despite the your i d being randomly
generated switching back to our provider project.
Let's run a full maybe install to generate and run
our contract verification tests.
As expected, we have a failure.
So lets navigate to the test and take a look.
The reason it's failing is because of the change to our contract.
We expect the your i d in the response to match a year I d in the request,
but our implementation is generating a response to you.
I d on the fly.
We can confirm this by running the test directly.
Yes, the error message is telling us that the U I.
D does not match so navigate into our base contract test.
The change here is actually quite simple.
This is because we're using marks,
meaning we can cheat and hard code to return GeoEye day
to equal the one in our contract.
Let's paste into your I d and then use alternate er to
make it a constructive parameter.
Well, then change the existing new your i D field.
So it sat via addition.
You construct the argument.
Now let's ruin our tests and see what happens.
Great.
90 pass as a year I d.
We assert, is equal to the u i.
D.
In the response.
Andi, that's it For this example,
it demonstrates a relatively straightforward yet powerful
concept that can help the response in our contract support many types of interactions.