[Autogenerated] The final thing we're going to look at in this module
is how to deal with some of the problems produced by putting
contracts and provided project repositories.
For example,
if we have one team member working on a consumer and enough
a team member working on the provider,
then the first team member may not have permission to
commit contractor to providers repository,
in fact, they may know,
even have permission to see the source code it all ignoring
what may be an organizational mistake.
We can accept that this is simply the case in a lot of places,
particularly in larger enterprises.
Andi, even if the users could access each of those repositories,
having the contract scattered around everywhere could
end up becoming a maintainable.
So as this is a legitimate problem,
we need to think of a solution The way around this,
at least from an architectural point of view,
is relatively straightforward.
We contain the members of our team and give them all access to a shared
contract repository as opposed to each other's projects.
Then, when we generate our stops,
we can do so by running the stub generator in the central repository and
when we generate our provider verification tests again,
we can generate them based on contracts contained in the central repository.
This is known as a centralized contract repository pattern and is a
simple way of getting around any access control issues.
On top of this, when we centralize all these contracts in one place,
the interactions overall becoming easier to reason about because every
famous together So what would this centralize contract repository look
like while was start for base maven project containing the group and
artifact I DS of our applications.
Then for each provider, we create a subdirectory.
Then for each interaction and provider has with a consumer,
we also create a subdirectory putting contracts within it.
There can, of course,
be more than one consumer interacts with the provider so we can add more
directories for each of those consumers on that can,
of course, be more providers, so we can add to relevant directories for them,
too.
We also adds a maven assembly plugging configuration.
In this case,
the assembly plug in will aggregate all the contracts into a jar foul in order
to be used for the provider side contract verification tests,
so to build, install the stops for a service.
We can create a palm foul in its directory,
navigate to it and runny install task.
We can repeat this for the other service and finally,
to be clear,
the palm in the root directory is used to package are contracts into a jar file for use by the provider side for verification tests.