[Autogenerated] So in this module we've achieved quite a lot
following freely entire consumer driven contract workflow and
to end whispering cloud contract.
Taking this Finn sliced view everything has helped us build a
foundational understanding of how we can use it to develop
hates DTP based micro services.
We've learned how to define a hate TTP based contract using a DSL unseen.
How expressive it is an easy to use even without any prayer groovy experience.
We've also learned how to generate stops using
spring cloud contract verifier on.
Also,
we've learned about why mark on how it is why mark stubbed wrappings that we
generate to execute our stops in the consumer side tests.
We've used a stub runner demonstrating how simpler is to use virus,
spring boo or two configuration.
And finally, we've used the spring cloud contract,
verify a maven plug in to create provider side tests to
verify that we can play of the contracts and both to provide a side on the consumer side