[Autogenerated] So what is consumer driven contract testing?
Consumer driven contract testing is a technique which fills
the testing gap in micro services testing.
It removes the risk of false positives caused by stops on
provides dramatically faster feedback, then slow and brittle and two in tests.
It's a technique where consumers under providers are continuously tested
against contracts which are agreed interactions between them.
It's also a test driven approach where the AP Ivor provider
is driven by the tests of the consumer.
Essentially, it takes T d D to the architecture level.
It also helps make micro services independently testable on us independently,
releasable contractors,
ruinous part of a micro services local build and give reliable and a feed about
to verify that they will function with their collaborators.
And finally, it's of course, a pattern that's bring cloud contract implements,
which is why it's important to build this understanding
off it before moving on to a demo.
To begin with,
we're going to start with a higher level architecture diagram of
how consumer driven contract testing might work.
As we know when we work in a consumer, there's also provided it.
It depends on we want to be able to ensure that both this consumer
in the provider will function together correctly.
When we implement consumer giving contract s stain,
we can do this by introducing a contract.
This is something which declares an agreed interaction
between our consumer andare provider.
Once we've created our contract, we can write automated tests,
have verified it,
a consumer functions with that contract and then we can
write automated tests which also verify the provider
functions with that contract by complain.
With this same contract,
it becomes implicit that the two services will be able to function together.
This means that our local contract tests fast and
fully isolated from each other.
Allow us to more confidently promote our micro services
from our local machines to an environment.
This means we can reduce or even eliminate our alliance and end to end testing.
And it also means that our stops are replaced if accurate contracts which represent the rial micro services