[Autogenerated] so let's go into a little bit more depth about what contract is.
A contract is an agreed interaction between a consumer under provider.
Essentially,
it states that when a specific request is made by a consumer than a
specific response should be given by a provider.
For example, in the case of our digital retail bank,
a contract could state when a consumer makes a specific
hate TTP request to an account service,
then it should return a specific hate TTP response
containing the cow information to elaborate.
Any required interaction can go into a contract,
which allows all possible cross service interactions to be fully testable.
One key thing to emphasize is that a contract is continually tested when
a consumer's tests Iran they run against a contract.
When it providers tests Iran, they, too, are run against the same contract.
This continual testing guarantees a local build failure if a
breaking changes made whilst http comes to mind,
the reality is the contract can represent interactions in any protocol.
In fact,
a contract does not even need to represent synchronous
interactions on can represent asynchronous.
In other words,
the core principle of a contract is a guarantees that we're able to produce
and consume data correctly across micro services on a technology choice that
we used to transport that data is irrelevant.
It's also not the same stubing, in fact,
saying,
But we make stops is one of the most common first
arguments against contract testing.
Before people fully understand the concept,
a contract is used to verify interaction on the provider
side as well as on the consumer side.
Continually tested contracts on both sides guarantee that they cannot be broken,
whereas a stop is only verified on the consumer side,
giving the provider free rein to make any breaking chains they want or
maybe no even comply with the stop in the first place.
It's also no AP I documentation.
A contract is a specifications used by a testing framework,
whereas documentation is a description.
Often a P I documentation is not continually tested are no
automatically verified in both the consumer under provider.
This means that you cannot see the impact of change in
something when changing documentation,
whereas if you use contracts you can automatically city
impacts of a change within seconds.
Well, now,
take a look at what contracts could contain in this case
specifically with a hasty T p a p I.
We won't use any specific contract definition language,
but will instead look at the interaction that it could represent.
First of all, we would have an agreed request.
This is a request that must be made in order for the contract
to be complied with on the provider side.
Its contract verification tests would made this request to
verify the contract on on the consumer side,
His test would make this request against the stop generated by the contract.
Second of all, we haven't agreed Response.
This is a response that will be given one knee agreed request is made.
Our stub on the consumer side test would return.
This response when they agreed to request is made on test assertions on the provider side would assert that this response is made