[Autogenerated] we can split consumer driven contrast testing into two sides.
The consumer side,
on the provider side as a convention is for the consumer to drive both
the contract on the implementation of the provider.
That is a side where we would begin to develop a feature.
So taking a consumer, the first thing we like is to house,
um, automated tests, which can run against it and verify it.
It's functional.
Thes tests might spend up in the instance of the consumer on makesem
AP I requests against it on Make some assertions.
The problem we have is that they may trigger an interaction with a provider on.
We need to make sure that this interaction occurs as expected.
In order to do this, we can create a contract I did not contract.
We can define a response free given request.
This request and response will be the specific interaction that consumer
makes with the provider during our test room from a contract,
we can then generate a stop which is done automatically by the framework.
In our case Spring cloud contract.
This stop will return a declared response in the contract when their
declared request from the contract is made to it.
This means it will be simulating our provider accurately
because of the guarantees provided by a contract.
This means we can run.
Our tests are agreed.
Request will be made on.
Then on receiving our response, we can make our Tesco green on verified Arkin.
Shima is fully functional on the provider side.
We want to do what the consumer his driven is to do food a
contract hence the term consumer driven.
So when we first take that provider,
we can take our contract with the agreed interaction
between the consumer and the provider.
A news our framework toe automatically generate contract verification tests.
All these tests will Dio is make the agreed request specified in the
contract to two provider and then a certain the response that provided
gifts is equal to the response in the contract.
Essentially, we're doing the opposite to what we did on our consumer side,
generating tests as opposed to stops.
Once he's test pass,
we can be sure that our provider functions with the contract on therefore,
with our consumer,
everything we've covered so far so be chained
together into the following workflow,
always starting on the consumer side are failing.
Shima test for a feature which crosses most service boundaries,
will be implemented again.
We start here because in consumer giving contract testing,
it's a consumers that drives the contracts off the provider.
If we think about it, that makes sense,
as there's no point in the provider do in anything off
it and what they can share needs.
Following this, we will then define our contract.
This contract contains the agreed interaction that our
implementation code will need in order for test to pass.
A common strategy here is to have a local copy of our provider
project on in store contract inside Out.
Then we can use a consumer driven contracts testing tool to generate a
stop of the agree and interaction in our contract,
which can in turn be used in our tests.
Our feature can now be fully implemented.
On our consumer side, a czar implementation code is able to call out to disturb.
The passing test will ensure every finished functional on the
consumer side as now we know we comply.
If our contract once we've finished with this,
we can switch back to the provider side.
If working across multiple teams a common strategy
here is to issue a poor request.
This,
me and somebody else could take over the work on the other side on
and implement the code required to finish the feature evil way
running the build of our provider would now fail as contract tests
will automatically regenerated, executed and unveil.
The final step is to make these tests pass by fully
implementing everything on the provider side.
A great quote about this workflow comes from our scene.
One of the course been cloud contract contributors.
He stays concious image of in contracts like TD D applied at the A P I level.
If you think about it,
that really is true as what we're doing is TD D only cross the network boundary.
We start with a failing test on our consume sides.
May not test pass and then re factor.
We didn't start with another failing test on the provider.
One that's automatically generated for us made that pass and
then we can do some mori factoring the reality is that if
you're familiar with t d day,
then this workflow maybe a little bit familiar on a somebody
who understands the benefits of TD day.
This could be a libel moment.
And fats, when you think about it,
applying the TDD process across micro services makes complete sense.
It means the implementation could be driven from the outside in,
rippling across the network and helping nothing more than
what is required to be implemented.
We also have their aggression test coverage that comes of TDD for free,
meaning isolated contracts s will fail when we make a breaking change in our provider or consumer.