[Autogenerated] Now we've given an overview of the two core testing strategies.
Let's take a look at how they fit together in a pipeline in
order to see what sort of mess we can end up him after
making a change to a mocha service.
The first thing that would happen is running its individual tests,
where we markets counterparts on passing we would publish it is an
artifact on deploy it to a staging environment.
On this stage and environment,
we would run our into an tests which would test the whole application together.
And finally, when this passes, we will release our Michael Service to production.
So what is the problem with this pipeline?
The first major one is false positives we get from our stops or marks,
not accurately representing the rial counterparts.
Essentially, these cause unreliable feedback,
which lets on Michael Service get favoring the pipeline.
And it should.
The second problem is how slow and flaky and to an tests are.
They end up taken forever to run,
even if we make a trivial change to a single micro
service in software development,
the feedback loop is key as it's what allows teams to
develop in release new features quickly.
One something's broken, ideally, to actually be determined on a local build,
not free hours in the future when we run.
And so in tests.
And of course, when trying to fix a book,
it's easier to do so when it happens sooner rather than later.
As it's hard, it's deeper issues found doing and so in tests.
So what we have here is an extremely weak feedback loop,
which kind of makes our release fade off into the distance and
feel like it's hardly ever gains that happen. This isn't a great situation to be him.