[Autogenerated] So let's recap what we've covered so far in this module.
Micro services come with many benefits such a smaller,
more maintainable co basis on the ability to deliver software more rapidly.
However, they can present new challenges,
particularly in the area of testing and to end testing.
Micro services can be slow and flaky,
and it's hard to diagnose values due to the network hops
of traffic for out the system mark.
You know, stubbing dependencies is quicker,
but those marks and stops can easily become stale and give false positives.
And when everything's put together in the pipeline,
the feedback we get isn't really good enough,
meaning that it can take too long to release a micro service.
And, most importantly,
thes problems at a motivation for spring cloud contract in
the next module will be learning about the consumer driven
contract testing technique, the technique spring cloud contracts implements.
This will help set the remaining context for the course,
after which will start using spring cloud contract to build a real Marcus services application