[Autogenerated] Hi there.
Ah, welcome this module and are designing hybrid age West networks,
cause my name's Mike Brown.
I miss Montreuil wagons cause billing when working in Aid West Hybrid
network out to turn violent in this module we're going to discuss site
site VP in billing 80 West Direct Connect building.
I'm going to take a look a cough summary so we'll start
with understanding site site building.
There's a couple of pricing points to beware off when work with sight
sight v p N's Firstly your charge for each hour,
your VPN connection is up each punch lower your VPN connection.
You are charged for a full hour as well as being charged for VPN connection.
Ours.
You also incur standard 80 West data transfer charges Parliament Lee,
it's gonna stopping chance your VPN terminated all of our price
examples that follow A based on a standard site site VPN Some regions
allow you to critics elevate sites ivy peons.
If you've done that,
you be charged the global accelerators Onda data transfer out premium fee.
So if you're creating next celebrate site site VPN make sure
you take these extra two charges into account when think
about standard VPN connection.
Ours.
Most regions have consistent pricing as an example.
Here we got us, too.
That charge is about five cents per connection.
Our another example is the address of regions that
charge around 6/2 cents per connection.
Our when pulling your VPN connections,
make sure you look up the pricing for your particular region.
So if we had a VPN connection in us, too,
there was a woman upset the time for for two days.
How much would we be charged?
That VPN connection.
If you do the maths around that it should work out about $36
for those 30 days as well as the Holocaust,
the veep in connection.
Then we've got to take into account data transfer.
As you can see here, data transfer in is free.
It's their transfer out that we got to take into account for all regions.
The first gig, a buy out per month, is free.
He's had feelings, proof that that were charged for.
So from the first gigabyte for the next 9.999 terabytes per month,
you'll be charged about nine cents per gigabyte for data transfer out.
So during the mass around data transfer out the EU west to region.
If he transferred out 50 gigabytes per week for three
weeks and then 20 bites out in week.
Far how much would that cost you?
Well, if we do the mass around that, it should work out $15.
21.
We add that to our VPN connection our costs and that would give us
the total cost for a VPN connection for that month.
Earlier on this course, we discussed Ed West Client V.
P N's Client VPN Connection pricing is a little bit different from sight sight.
VPN connection pricing for a dress client cheapens your
charge to fee for each submit association.
Thesame associations are building a dollar power basis.
You're also charged for active client and there's a dollar power
charge for each active client that's connected again,
using us to his example.
Your challenge about 10 cents per hour for each end point association on your
charge about five cents an hour for each active VP and client.
Like other challenges around VP,
ends each part of our council complete our so when
considering client VPN connections in us too.
If we have an average 20 active connections for eight hours a day,
and we have false subject connections.
How much would that cost?
Well, for our day, that should.
Runners to $11. 20.