[Autogenerated] Hi there.
Ah,
welcome this module and are designing a due West hybrid network
architectures cause my name's Mike Brown on in this module.
We're gonna look at designing hybrid network ____ touches
using Ed West Direct Connect in this model where first go
try and answer the question.
What is a depressed direct connect where they're gonna go on to look us
in the components of a direct connect circuit before going on to discuss
how we can make direct connect Resilient.
Finally,
we'll finish off by introducing new to direct connect her see connections.
So start off by discussing what is a US direct connect.
So, following that configuration,
glove Mannix have been using site site VI pens to
collect their offices to AWS Globe.
Mannix has not fallen.
Facilities are many small offices dotted around the globe.
One of the paramount concerns for glove Mannix.
He's making sure that all day that flows between their
offices on AWS is encrypted like Globe Mannix.
Most of us will view site site VP end at some point in the past,
but what's in the drawbacks of using sites Ivy pens?
Well, for starters, traffic is sent across the public Internet.
This limits some of technologies you might want to use and
introduces security concerns that some of our compliance
auditors might not be under percent.
Happy wave.
When using sites like VPN is revered,
breasts are virtual private gateways are limits 1.2 gigabytes of fruit.
This may not be in a family for your needs.
Because we're using the public Internet for our site site connections,
we can get unpredictable.
Followings depends on how busy the different network notes out that
we're going through the mighty periods of congestion.
Another drawback to using sites IVP ends across the public in
that is that bandwidth is not guaranteed.
Hello.
Mannix has found some problems when using site site free pens collected.
I digress, firstly, that larger offices don't have the performance they need.
They did not get the food put required when used in sight, sight, PP ens.
This, in turn, has limited.
The amount of service is the globe.
Mannix is using any breasts.
They're trying to conserve bandwidth for key systems.
Also,
glove Mannix I still can't into s3 on double service is
using their public endpoints of Internet.
This traffic is not going for their sight sight
connection with those problems in mind.
Globe Mannix is considering the use of a D West Direct Connect.
Direct Connect is used to establish a dedicated connection between
your office on AWS through the Direct Connect connection we can
connect about free peces on public service is,
I guess three.
Because we use that connection that dedicate for us,
we should get a more consistent network experience using direct
connect when compared to VPN connections.
Direct Connect provides a dedicated private on always own connective, eh?
There are lots of use cases for direct connect.
For example,
if you got large data sets and you try and transfer those large
data sets over sites like VPN connections,
that could take time and can be expensive.
If you're trying to copy a large amounts of data,
all of your sight sight v P N's.
It's probably taking up a lot your bandwidth.
And while you're using it,
that bandit cannot be used by over business units in your organization.
Using direct connect will speed up the data transfer and
leave my bun for available for over uses.
Real time data feeds such as voice and video come benefit from Direct
Connect Direct Connect provides a little antsy and consistent network
performance that really time data streams need.
Also think compliance because of direct current
connection is a dedicated private connection.
We're keeping all our traffic away from the public Internet that
might help satisfy compliance standards were trying to certify
against when working with direct connect.
Those two types of direct connect connections that we can configure,
first of all, is a dedicated direct connect connection.
These are built by you through a local direct connect location
provided by one of the address partners.
When create a dedicated connection,
we consign it for one gig are tanking part options.
Our second option is a hosted connection.
Instead of establishing the Direct Connect connection ourselves,
we choose one of the AWS Direct Connect parentless
will help us set up our connection.
One of the benefits of a hostage connection is that
we have more bandwidth choices.
We can send it for connections from 50 megabits all the way up to 10 gigabits, so her see connection might fit your budget a little bit better.