[Autogenerated] So now we know what direct connect it can do for us.
Let's spend a few minutes chatting about summer.
Direct Connect components will need to configure our direct connect circuits.
However, we decide to work with Direct Connect,
we'll need to choose a direct connect location.
AWS has partnered with various organizations around the world that
provide hosting for their direct connect equipment.
Each of the partner sites that horse direct current equipment have highly
available lowlands can't have a into eight West regions.
When we're creating our director that connection, we will choose one.
These partners and we will connect from our own premise location.
In fact, direct connection location.
When we set up a dedicated direct connect connection where perching apart
the two part speeds enough for a one gig are 10 gig.
Once we bring up our look, we then build virtual interface.
Is these votes interfaces allow us to identify our traffics,
traversing the direct connect network Private a face is connected to our VP.
Sees public interface is connected to public service is like us three.
We can establish any private verse interface with any virtual
private gateway that's in the same region.
Was a direct connect collection.
If you wanna create a private version of face to a V P C in a different region,
then you're gonna need a direct connect gateway.
These gateways allow those connections across regions.
They also allow us to stop associations with transit gateways.
So if you use a transit gateway, I want to connect that To direct connect.
You will need a direct connect gateway with a dedicated connection.
Are two part speeds a wounded in 10 gig?
But what if you need to get our three gig all 20 gig well
in congregating could help with that.
Lynn congregation allows us to aggregate connections so it can combine
the bandwidth for multiple parts to give us more fruit.
So imagine binding two wounded parts together using link obligation
to give us the equivalent of a two gig connection.
There's actually three types of version of face we can
create when work with direct connect.
The first is a private virtual interface.
We used these to connect Ravi Peces using private I P addresses.
The second is a public virtue and vice.
We use these to collect Public service is like us three.
Using public, I p addresses.
And finally, we have a transit virtually no face.
We have transit boats interfaces when connecting to a transit gateway
through our direct connect Gateway Transit gateways.
Then allow us to access the private dress base of every peces.
There's a few steps involved in creating direct connect connection.
Here we have a high level overview of those steps.
First, he'd can't your location to your chosen aid US Direct Connect location.
There's dozens and dozens of these to choose from around the club.
You're probably choose one that's in the same jug fears you
you'll speak them directly about establishing connection from
your location into their silly.
We can then go and request a direct connect connection
through the console once requested.
We don't love this laugh.
This letter includes all information about your part Allocations on the air
Due West Direct Connect equipment in your chosen aid,
US direct current location.
The idea is that you pass this letter on your direct current location
provider and they will configure a cross connect.
The cross connect is to establish connection between your
equipment in the direct connect location on the direct cake
parts that being assigned to you.
You'll have to make sure that your age of West components are prepared.
So your VP sees, for example, have the right route information.
Well,
the appropriate security groups and knuckles have been
adjusted to allow the new traffic through,
and then we can crack about.
Clinton faces handling congregations again.
These the overview steps involved each one of these were involved.
Multiple steps to achieve the overall goal of establishing
your direct connect circuits in this example were buried The
West on left inside with the U.
S.
Public service is like us three and then your v p c with
virtual private gateway in the middle.
We have a direct connect location on the right.
Inside, we have head office.
I can see a depressive already placed a pair of direct
devices in this part location well established.
Connective it back to the local aid West region.
We will speak the partner on establishing connection into their facility.
This might involve was buying our own equipment and Stalin in the facility,
or renting Rackspace from the provider Well,
then go through the process of establishing direct connect
connection with the end result being that cross connect,
catch will be established between our equipment on the direct connect equipped.
Once the cross cracks in place, the part will come up.
And now we can create our private gifts on our public.
This with these 15 place traffic,
can now be ruined from our promise into red dress.
Here we got slightly different example on in this example.
We haven't drawn in head office,
but that would be off to the right of the screen.
We've got the direct Connect location and we've got across Captain Place.
This time in the Midwest.
We've got three.
VP sees each one in a different region.
Each one has a virtual private gateway on I wanna
establish connections to each these re peces.
It's with this example.
Then when we deploy direct connect Gateway each job is to allow us to
quit direct connect connections the VP sees in different regions and they
could see the connection's established reach.
Vpc on backed one premise.
Think about the previous side.
How many private fish would you need that configuration and
how would don't connect to be a differentiate the traffic
intended for different VP sees Well, we'd need three private.
This one freaked VPC verts interfaces identified using villain ID's so
each of affray VIPs would need a unique feeling i d.
When traffic is sent from head office to V.
P.
C.
One, it'll be attacked with a via an i d for v p.
One by using real and ideas.
Direct connect can identify the traffic going to and from each re PC on
our traffic won't be sent in the wrong direction.
In this example,
we've got three VP sees this time all in the same region you west one I deserve
using virtual private gateways were using a transit gateway.
This reduces the number of virtual gateways we have
to pay for that Manage again.
We've got head office connected to the direct connect
location on a cross connecting place.
In this example, we need a direct connect gateway again.
Whenever we want to use a transit gateway without direct connect collections,
we need a direct connect gateway.
The direct connect gateway then facilitates the connection
from head office through to the transit gateway and ultimately
onto our virtual private clouds.
What about if we want to use transit gateways across regions?
We've already seen Ellen the cost that transit gateways that region specific.
Well, in that scenario, we would use multiple gateways.
So we deploy a gateway to each region that we have.
VP sees.
I don't we configure a pairing connection between those gateways.
That way,
we should bet route package from office to any of the
VP sees across any of those regions.
If you don't appear the transit gateways that you can connect the direct
connect gateway directly to each transit gateway individually,
Direct Connect is very free to rich,
but one of the things it doesn't give his encryption the day you send
across the direct current collection is not encrypted.
If you want encryption for your data that you would establish our direct
connect collection and then quite a sight sight connection of the top of it
when work with direct Connect be GP is a requirement.
Unlike site site, VP ends,
we have a choice of steak or dynamic ruin with direct connect.
We have to use ____ accruing.
If you want to monitor your direct connect connection.
Well, good news. Your direct connect connection is integrated with cloudwatch