[Autogenerated] in this section,
Wagons was working with static and dynamic site to site
B P N's when working site site v.
P N's.
We got two choices when it comes to ruin.
First of all, we can configure static ruin with stack ruin.
It's up to you Truck day and maintain the route tables.
These would include the route tables for your subjects
and your route tables on premise.
Our second option is dynamic ruin.
With dynamic ruin.
We install a ruin protocol on our devices.
The routing protocol then stops routing information that is
used to automatics of day I root tables.
When working,
revered West manage service is the only supported routing
protocol is BTP the border Gateway protocol Stike Ruin is
relatively easy to implement, but it doesn't scale well.
Imagine trying to manage hundreds over thousands of rulers
and having to keep them updated manually.
It doesn't sit well in small scenarios when you might have
just a handful of rulers and you don't own the overhead of
managing a protocol like bdp B G P.
House In on premise device toe advertise I P prefixes
to the virtual private gateway.
The virtual gateway advertises your v P C s i p ranges to your on
premise device the virtual private gateways and I digress.
Use B g p of a TCP part 179 So we have to make sure that's
available for our firewalls on the BTP process.
The age of Westerns supports all of the common bdp parameters
that you might need to manipulate ruin.
This model serves a brief introduction to be GP.
We've got entire BTP module coming up later on in the calls.
When working with dynamic ruining your VPN, we can able route propagation.
Brute propagation allows your virtual gateways to chads routes
they've learned with the VPC route tables.
This 100 routes limit is a hard limit and cannot be changed.
So if you think you're gonna exceed that limit, consider using roots.
Civilization.
Roots immunization allows you to advertise a range of roots as a single entry.
One other thing to consider when you create offsite
side VPN on you configure PGP.
At that point,
you can adjust the BG piece default configuration to suit your requirements.
But once your sight sight connections up on your virtual private gateways
configured the B g P configuration cannot be altered.
To make a change,
you have to delete the site site connection and then reconfigure a new one.
We've already said that Unaided West managed VPN
brings up two tunnels from on premise, we can connect to both those tunnels on.
We can bring both tunnels up.
That means we can use those tunnels in an active, active fashion.
Sending a receiving traffic through ball from we also have the option of
an active standby configuration at his standby should be considered if
we run into asymmetric routine problems.
Asymmetric ruin involved.
Traffic being sent from solves the destination in one direction on the
return traffic being delivered by a different path.
This can cause connective issues using active standby just as one puff your
traffic with a standby path taken over in the event of failure.
Virtual private gateways and head West Support network
address Translation traverse A LL.
That means if we want to establish a site site connection behind that service, we can