[Autogenerated] in this demonstration, we're gonna configure an aide to us.
Manage repair.
We'll be working with the aid US console and you
want to follow Miss Demonstration, You will need an address account.
I'm in the AWS Consul specifically in the VPC dashboard in the London region.
On the left inside, I'm going to scroll down to the VPN section.
The first component I'm gonna configure is the customer gateway.
So if I select that and then I'll select create customer gateway.
Hey, we have a standard phone that we can fill in.
We provide a name fits customer get where?
So I've chosen global hit Q device.
We choose the ruin method I want to use across this connection.
We're gonna be in static ruin this site site VPN and then the public eye.
Pierre, just that we're going to use to connect to this customer device.
Optionally if we want to use a certificate of authentication, we comply.
The details here on details of device itself,
such as manufacturer I'm happy with the second have configured.
So I select great customer gateway.
It shouldn't take long to create and it will then appear on
this customer gateway list the Nets component I'm gonna create
is the virtual private gateway.
So if I slept that I then click create virtual private
gateway no lot to configure here, just the name for the gateway.
And we can also choose how autonomous system numbers
provided even by Amazon off a custom sn autonomous system
was a part of our BDP configuration.
I'm with the entire B G P module coming up later on.
This calls if we're happy with the configuration choices we
click create virtual private gateway.
In no time all our virtual private gateway will be created.
I can see mine here.
I could see it stay as detached.
What we need to do is attach his gateway to our V p.
C.
So the gateway selected we choose actions on attached to V P.
C From the VPC drop down list.
We choose the VPC that we want to attach the gateway to If we're happy,
right choice, we say yes.
Attach on again in no time at all.
The gateway's attached to a V p.
C.
And we could see the attachment status here.
You know, I just meant you to this virtual private gateway.
We'll need to adjust the route tables.
Five vpc Let's go find our VP sees route Table This is the
route table for our globe Mannix Free PC We find under route
table so of the route table selected, I say Eddie roots and then add route on.
We type in the root details.
So here I've added the route and what were turned The
route table is to get to this network.
Send the traffic to this virtual private gateway.
This network address represents our network ahead bars.
I'm half with these roots,
so I select save roots with the roots have adjusted I'm
gonna scroll back down to the VPN section.
The final component then of aid to a Spanish VPN is
the site to site VPN connection.
So I'm gonna slit that and then click create VPN connection.
So here we provide a name for our VPN connection.
We select love.
This VPN connection will connect with virtual private Gateway Transit
Gateway We want virtual Private Gate was selected.
Let me choose over to a buyer a gateway from the dropdown list.
We've already configured a customer gateway so we leave
existing selected and choose our customer.
Get away from the dropdown list.
So where?
Configuring the VPN connection to link this virtual
private gateway with this customer gateway.
If I scroll down a little bit more again,
we have the option of choosing the ruin that want to use across this connection.
I'm gonna to stake and we provide a list of each network
that could be found at headquarters.
Scroll down a little bit more and we find options for configuring at 11 points.
I'm happy, my sayings.
So I click create VPN connection.
Now, this will take a few minutes configure.
So I'm gonna pause the video here and come back once
the VPN connection is created.
That took a few minutes, but now I can see that a VPN connection is available.
If I could contain all details,
we can see the 2 to 11 points the outside I Pierre just there in points on the
address space that's gonna be used inside the tunnel itself.
Right now, both East tunnels are down.
And that's because we haven't configured the on
primitive Aisha to connect these tunnels.
Tell post configure those on premise devices.
We have the option here to download a configuration file if I
select that I can choose from a series of vendors,
and I can download a configuration file too much,
my vendor and platform.
If you choose Microsoft from the list,
you could download a configuration file for Windows Rock Princeton.
So if you deploy a 2012 hour to machine,
for example, into one of the VPC, perhaps in a different region,
you can give that device a public I.
P address,
installed the route through my access service and then use this talented configuration file to establish the VPN connection.