[Autogenerated] one of things you want.
Consider when work with direct, connect his resiliency.
If you are to a signal direct connect part on that part fails,
then your connection will fail,
and it may not be the part on the individual device that fails.
It may be the device itself.
It may be a problem with the direct connect location Evil way if we
can want to avoid single point of failure now,
one of the ways we can do that is to use a site site VPN vinyl.
Turn a path through traffic if the direct connect connection fails.
This is a relatively inexpensive way to provide resilience if your connection.
But we have to remember the reasons why we're using
direct connect in the first place.
We want that dedicated, private, predictable connection.
If we fail over to a site site link, all of that goes away.
But the site site connection is relatively inexpensive and easy,
or so Aws has four resiliency models for direct connect Oh,
my discos and each one of those in the coming slides.
Of course, there's nothing stopping you,
combining one of the direct Connect resilience of methods with a site
site collection back up as a path of last results.
In this example, we can see headquarters on.
We can see how direct current location unaided West six After left inside.
In this example, we start off with one cross connect connection.
Our equipment is connected to one part in the direct
connect racks to provide resilience.
If this link, we can request a second cross, connect a second part.
Now, if there's a single failure in the direct connect rack,
are in the individual direct connect components.
The effects one of our parts, it shouldn't affect the second.
We'd increase his resiliency by having multiple on premise
devices on multiple deployed devices.
In the direct Connect location we call this model classic or deaf test.
The classic model is the original model.
We purchase a single part to begin with and add additional parts for resiliency.
Also accusing congregation to increased bandwidth.
Deaf Test is one of the newer deployment types and
establishes to cross connects right from the start.
As long as we adverse lnc on our side of the connection,
then the single point of failure here becomes a direct connect location itself.
This model is called the high resiliency model No is here.
We're using two different direct connect locations
with this high resiliency option.
We have a single cross connect connection,
each direct connect location, and now we're protected from location failure.
If one of the direct connect location fails, traffic can flow through the ever.
This final model is called Maximum Resiliency.
Again, we use multiple direct connect locations,
and we start off with a single cross connect connection each.
But for maximum resiliency,
these will be supplemented by a second cross
connect connection in each facility.
Now it protected against location failure.
Onda localize part failure as well to configure resiliency.
When Audrey and Direct Connect Connection,
we can use the resilience, a tool kit.
This is a wizard that we can access through the Direct Connect console.
A little guy just threw the choices that we need to make
bay to the far resiliency options.
Again, there's nothing stopping us on a V P M.
Backup for these results of efforts.
If AWS learns about one of our networks from a direct
connect connection under VPN connection, it always prefers the direct connect path