[Autogenerated] Finally, in this model we've discussed,
age was cloud Hope and client VPN endpoints have a little
think about your network right now.
How many locations does your company half do?
These locations need to route to each other.
If so, how is that ruin?
Achieve?
Do you sight sight?
VPN Also, Do you have staff that worked from home?
How do they connect?
Do they use remote access weekends to connect to your corporate network?
Ed West has features that can help with connectivity between your location
and that consist your staff connecting to your corporate network while
they're on the road a while they're at home were introduced in then cloud
hope on client VPN endpoints cloud him,
Connect your science using a hub and spoke design within a depressed virtual.
Get acting is the Hope client VPN endpoints our managed remote access
repeating service that allow your start to secure the connect your VP sees on
potentially through those VP sees back from premise.
Here's an example of cloud.
We have three sites headquarters brunch, one on brunch, too.
Each of those sites has created a site site connection with a
virtual private get where hosted in and breasts.
Now this virtual private gateway is attached to a V p.
C.
But the cloud hope that's not a requirement.
The virtual private gatewaycan be detached for this configuration toe work.
We'll create multiple customer gateways on multiple sites like VPN connections.
Because this virtual private gateway is attached to the VPC.
Not only will our branches and headquarters be able
to communicate with each other,
there will also be a route to the VP sees as well
in out of the cloud up to work,
our site site VPN must be dynamic PPL's So here we can
see the each of our own premise.
VPN points has been assigned a unique autonomous system number.
Autonomous system numbers on the rest of the B G P
configuration will be discussed in detail in the B G P module
client VPN points a manage client base VPN.
They allow you to secure the actor Sadie, Wes and Gunn.
Promise results is each client V.
P.
An End point has a route terrible access to AWS and on premises
controlled by manipulating roots In this route table,
our staff will need a VPN client installed on their laptops and then
they can use T C P R U D P to connect Ryland Point.
Allowing remarks his clients to connect your VP sees is not new.
Prior to client v p M points,
we would use the customized easy to instance to allow these remote
access VPN When we configure a client VPN point,
we can use active director of an occasion to authenticate the
users our mutual authentication using digital certificate client
v p M Points Support Split tunnel.
This means that traffic that's destined for RV PCR on premise.
We'll go for the marks VPN.
Internet bound traffic will just traveled for that normal Internet collection.
Examples of access include provide access to a V P.
C.
Providing access from premise.
Andi buys a combination of root tables, security groups and knuckles.
We can configure restricted access to specific results. Is