[Autogenerated] in the final section of his model.
Let's discuss a divorce.
Transit Gateway Transit Gate was a manage device that
we can deploy toe anade West region.
Once deployed,
we can use that transit gateway to create attachments to VP sees BP ends We
can use appearing to connect it to over transit gateways.
And we can use transit gateway to collect to our direct connect connections.
Once we create these attachments, we can use VPC route tables,
control the flow of traffic towards the transit gateway.
I'm accused a transit gateway route tables to control the
flow of traffic between the attachments.
Transit gateway allows us to build hub and spoke apologies with the
transit gateways the hub on the attachments of the spokes.
We can then enable transitive ruin between the attachments.
In this example,
we've got three VP sees deployed to the EU west one region in a dress,
each free PCs to some nights on.
We want results.
It deployed tweets subject to be a communicator each other.
So, to that end we deploy a transit gateway in the U West.
One region will then create 33 PC attachments.
We would adjust the VPC route tables on the transit gateway route table.
And with that in place,
traffic will be a route between all these different subjects.
Just like with VPC pairing bear in mind we're talking about VP
sees here with non overlapping I P ranges.
If the I P ranges did overlap, ruin wouldn't work.
We could also use transit Gateway too connected to our own premise locations.
Here we've got headquarters and to branch offices,
and each one has got customer from this device that
connects him to the Internet.
Weaken the new transit gateway to configure VPN attachments.
In this example, we would need three VPN attachments 12 week office again.
We did just the appropriate route tables and now traffic could be fully
ruit from our VP sees try physical locations on back.
We can also use the fief in attachments to route
traffic between brunch one French too, and headquarters as well.
In this example, we're using to Ed West regions us one.
Any us too.
We have a V p c deployed to each eat three PCs to sub nets and
you can see I've deployed to transit gateways here transit
gateways of deployed to a region they cannot make VPC
attachments outside of their region, but we can do.
It's quite a appearing connection between the two transit gateways.
By creating this pairing, connection results is deployed to V.
P.
C.
One would be a route to result It deployed to V.
P C two transit gateways got lots of great features.
These include the N s a part so that we can provide de
NS resolution across the attachments.
Equal cost multipath ruins apart with e c M.
P.
If a transit gateways got multiple pass to a destination
on those paths offer equal metrics, then transit gatewaycan.
Use that in an active active fashion transit.
Gateway has a default table who can also configure customer tables.
These beings,
we have different route in policies for different
groupings of attachment transit.
Gateway supports both static and dynamic ruin.
If you choose to stack ruin, it's your job to maintain the routing tables.
Dynamic ruin uses bi G p.
The more complex your design, the more attachments transit gateway has.
The more likely you are to use dynamic ruin.
Also,
it's worth pointing out that transit gatewaycan be shared between
accounts so you can deploy our transit gateways to a shared service
account and then make them available for all the accounts inside and
outside of your organization.
It's resource access manager that used to share results is
between a dress accounts resource actually manage can share
transit gateways sub nets.
Route 53 Resolve rules as well as a host of of results,
is the accounts we share with could be inside or outside of your
address organization on By using resource Access Manager,
we're more easily able to create centralized results.
Is monitor the centralized resources while easily making them available toe over a dress accounts that need them.