The compiler plugin is exactly what it sounds like.
It's the plugin that we use to compile our source code in our application.
We use this compiler for both our source code and our test code,
although it does run in different phases for each.
One thing of note is that it does invoke javac,
but it does a lot more than that.
It does so by setting the class path with the dependencies from our application.
So if you remember from the previous module when we defined
our dependencies and they have scopes that are associated
with them or those types of things,
the compiler plugin will build our class path based off of what those
dependencies are and their classification of scope.
One thing of note is that it does default to an older version of Java,
Java 1.7, regardless of what JDK you have installed.
For this reason alone,
I would say that the compiler plugin is the most overwritten plugin
as far as customization inside of all the plugins.
We can customize this plugin by defining the configuration section.
Now, the plugins documentation or description looks just like this on the left.
This is how we define it inside of our application.
It looks pretty straightforward.
We can see a few things here that we have, our groupId, our
artifactId, and then our version, but then we have the configuration
section where we can specify a handful of things.
We can tell that we want it to fork, which means to spin off on its own thread.
We can set the min and max memory.
So if you've ever run into compilation problems where you
haven't had enough memory on the heap or whatever,
you can specify those memory settings here inside your configuration.
We also have our source and target directories,
which is mainly the two features that people overwrite the most to tell it to use a different target than what we're compiling to.