Since this is an updated course,
we actually had to jump ahead and add the plugin for the Maven Compiler
early on in the course to use a newer version of Java.
This was required after about Java 8.
It doesn't really matter though if you want to specify the version of Java.
Like I said,
this is the most overridden plugin there is inside of a Maven project.
You're going to define this anyway, so we jumped ahead a little bit.
But now that you understand how plugins work and that we have a build section,
let's just review it quickly.
So inside of our build section, again,
we have a plugins section because we can have multiple plugins,
and then we have defined the maven‑compiler‑plugin inside of here.
It has the groupId of org.apache.maven.plugins and the
artifactId of maven‑compiler‑plugin.
The version is 3.8.0 and the configuration and, specifically,
the release is version 11 inside of here.
Now I want to show you one small change inside of here
just for the sake of an example.
If we wanted to compile this down to Java 9,
and we save this,
it'll go through and it will build our project, but it'll give
us a warning or an error stating that the project space isn't
up to date with the configuration.
And you can tell that by our project name having a red X in it,
or if we looked at the Problems section in our application down below here,
the project configuration is not up to date with the pom.xml.
Now, how we resolve that is we go right‑click on our project,
go down to Maven, and Update Project.
Click OK.
And it should go through, rebuild our application,
and you'll notice that it has now configured our
project to be a JavaSE‑9 application.
Well, we know we want to go with the later version,
so we're going to switch it back to 11.
And at the time of recording, Java 12 has been released,
but the plugin isn't working as nicely with the IDE.
So when things are a little bit more flushed out,
you'll be able to change this to 12 and it will embrace the Java 12 JRE.
So let's switch this back to 11.
Save it, right‑click on our project again,
say Maven, Update Project, click OK, it'll do the same thing. It'll go refresh, build your application, and then bump it up to JavaSE‑11.