The entire next module is dedicated towards dependencies,
but we can't talk about our POM and not spend at least a
minute or two walking through how dependencies work in the
bigger picture of our POM.
Dependencies are imported by their naming convention.
This is often considered the most confusing part of Maven,
because you have to know what their artifactId is,
what their groupId is, and what version you want to use.
The nice thing about this, though,
is that it will pull transit dependencies in for us.
Like I said, we're going to go into this in greater detail in the next module,
but adding a dependency to our POM is fairly simple.
We just add it in the dependency section of our POM,
and we just need to list what dependency that we want to use,
and any transitive dependencies will automatically be pulled in for us,
We need to know our three things, our groupId,
our artifactId, and our version.
Let's look what this code looks like for us to achieve this.
The pom.xml that we just looked at a minute ago now has a dependency
section in it and a dependency listed inside of that.
You can see that we're pulling in the org.apache.commons
groupId and the commons‑lang version 3,
and specifically a specified version of 3.8.1.
It's pretty straightforward,
and you don't see that there's transitive
dependencies on the commons‑lang module,
so it will just download this file and any supporting libraries that it needs.
This is all you have to do to add a dependency inside of our section,
but notice it's the same naming convention of our project
that it is for our dependencies: groupId, artifactId, and version.