The goals that we can run off of our basic application are pretty
straightforward. They're much what you would expect to have from just
basic functionality, and since we're using a lot of the defaults, they're
already defined for us. We have a clean goal.
The clean goal deletes the target directory and any of its generated sources.
We have a compile goal. Compile is exactly what you think it's going to
be, we're going to compile all of the source code.
We're also going to generate any files if we're using a library
such as web services or something like that,
that would generate stubs and skeletons or other source code,
and it will place that into our classes directory.
If you have a .properties file or things like that,
they're going to get copied over into our classes
directory underneath our target, as well.
We also have a package command. The package command will run compile first,
so we don't have to tell it to run compile,
but we can daisy chain goals.
It will run any unit tests that we have and package that up based off
the type that we have defined inside of our POM.
The install goal is a little bit different than what some people
think. Install will run the package command,
and then it will install it in your local repository.
It will copy your JAR or WAR file, or however it's packaged,
and place it inside of your repository.
The default of that is your home directory .m2. Now deploy
is a little bit confusing to people.
Deploy does not mean deploy it to an app server.
Deploy runs the install command and then deploys it to
a corporate or remote repository.
If you're using a corporate internal repository,
deploy is going to copy it up to that internal repository.
Now that can be as simple as a file share somewhere or
something else, but install and deploy often get confused and
backwards. As far as you're concerned, install will install it locally, deploy will install it remotely.