The POM overview is the initial view that you
receive when you open up your pom.xml.
I've opened this file up before,
so it keeps wanting to go to the source code, but the first
time you've opened up an application,
it's going to take you to this Overview screen where you can see the
Group Id and the Artifact Id and basic meta information.
There are some other pieces of this. You can define project information,
you can define your source control if you have this tied to your build
process that it's editing some of those things.
Most people don't use these other selections,
though. It is of note if you change this here, so let's say we take
this from com.pluralsight to com.training and click the pom.xml, it
will have changed our groupId here.
And likewise,
if we change this back to pluralsight and change back to our Overview,
it will have updated that there.
So it's real‑time live editing of those features for you to
go back and forth. Not super helpful, but it is nice if you don't like meddling inside of XML.