The last plugin that we're going to look at configuring is the Javadoc Plugin,
and the Javadoc Plugin is almost identical to the Source Plugin in the sense
that we're going to take our javadocs and patch them into a JAR file when we
upload them to our repository. Just like the Source Plugin, you can browse the
Javadoc Plugins website to see any other additional information or goals that
are available there, but it's really pretty straightforward.
We typically tie it to our package phase,
but if we're running package a lot,
we can hinder performance, and so we'll tie it to a later phase like the
verify phase or how we did with the Source Plugin, the install.
Usually, we just use the defaults, but if you have
customized javadocs for your company,
maybe throw in your company logo or change colors or whatever.
You can customize all this inside the Javadoc Plugin configuration.
So this plugin is defined almost identical to the source plugin in the
sense that we have our group ID, artifact ID, and version,
and then we just tie it to an execution section. Let's see what that looks like now.