In this module. we learned that goals are really just configured plugins
inside of our application, and we just accept the defaults that are
actually coming out of the Super POM that plugins are tied to and one of
the defined phases. We can usually override these to do specific things
for our application, though. The Compiler Plugin is defined for us,
but we usually need to change that to specify a version of Java.
The default is six, and that will shortly be upgraded to probably
seven or eight because they are near end of life, and we usually
want whatever the latest version is, anyways.
The jar plugin is one of the default plugins that's also configured for
us automatically, but we can override that to do things like generate
our manifest file or do includes or excludes based upon files we want
to include inside of our jar.
And lastly,
the Source and Javadocs Plugin can easily be configured to
generate our code and install them with our corporate
repository for use by other developers.
This is really a good practice as we're stepping
through code or debugging things.
We usually want to see what code is tied to it and why it's breaking. We
can step through that source code or find help for those Javadocs, and
it makes it a lot easier for developers.
This is becoming more and more important with microservice
architectures and having separate teams work on separate pieces of the application.