We've seen how to add dependencies to our POM using the Dependencies tab.
And you may have even clicked on the Dependency Hierarchy tab already,
and you'll see that with JUnit, there are some
transitive dependencies that it's pulling in,
but we really only have one conflict you may have not even caught that
that junit‑platform‑commons has a conflict with 1.0.2. Let's make this a
little bit more interesting and come back to our Dependencies tab and
click Add, and I'm going to enter in hibernate here. Now, one thing that
I may have not mentioned to you earlier is that if you have not
downloaded this before,
it searches your local repo so it may not be available to you.
So if I click on 5.4.1.Final[jar], and you don't have that,
it's because you're going to have to come up here and
enter in the group ID of org.hibernate,
the artifact ID of hibernate‑core, and the version of
5.4.1.Final, and that is proper case, so capital F and a
lowercase i, n, a, l for Final.
Once you have that entered,
or you have the option to click that in the search results,
go ahead and click OK. You'll have some progress of it downloading
some things and adding that to your POM, but I'm going to show you a
little mistake that people commonly make.
If you notice the top of this tab, I have an asterisk next to *Foo/pom.xml.
If I click on my Dependency Hierarchy tab right now,
nothing shows up, and it's because I haven't saved my POM yet.
It won't build that hierarchy for me until I save it, so you can hit
Ctrl+S or you can come up and click the Save icon.
And once I do that,
you'll notice it blows up my Dependency Hierarchy screen
here, and you'll see that we have a bunch of different things
that it's overridden or omitted.
So my jboss‑logging, it's told you that it's updated for 3.3.2.Final
because there was a older version of that in here.
You'll see that we had the activation API. There's a bunch of little things
that it's overridden and omitted to a newer version, so really handy to
determine what's going on inside of your application.
Another useful feature, though,
is if you've got a .jar inside of your application and
you're wondering where it came from, common problem,
common concern with Java. In fact,
a while ago it used to be that you would just have all of these .jars shoved
in a live directory package inside of your application.
But if you're wondering, why do I need to have the jaxb‑api?
You can click on that,
and it'll tell you exactly where it came through your hierarchy.
So specifically, hibernate‑core wants the jaxb‑api, or you can click on
jboss‑logging, that's also from the core, jandex. So it'll go through and allow
you to determine where this library is coming from and who specifically is
asking for it, FastInfoset, dom4j, byte‑buddy, antlr.
Everything will tell you where it's coming from and who's pulling it in as a transitive dependency.