If we look at the POM for our sample project right now,
it's really quite simple.
We open it up to a full screen, it barely takes up the entire full screen.
In fact, it only does because I'm on such a high resolution.
We've got our three dependencies and our build section that defines which
Compiler Plugin we're going to use for a specific version.
But if you look at the bottom of the screen here, we have the Effective POM tab.
If I click on it, you'll notice that it is quite wordy.
It's very lengthy,
and at first it looks very similar to what our POM is that we
have to find just inside of our application.
We got our model, group, artifact, and version information,
then our dependency section, but as you scroll down,
you'll notice that we also have a repository section,
and this is inheriting from these super POM.
So it is pulling this information in from the super POM that
comes with the Maven installation that we have.
You can see that we have the main repository for
Central Repo defined inside of here.
You'll also notice that on line 30 through 32,
that it has snapshots disabled by default.
Same thing iif you scroll down to the PluginRepository section,
you can see that we're also going against the Central Repo for
that, and it has snapshots also disabled for that,
and it won't try and force any updates.
There is also, inside of our build section,
the defaults for our source directory, test source directory,
that type of information, where are outputs go. It has all
of our information built inside of here.
You'll also see that there's plugins defined inside of here for us.
So the release‑plugin, the dependency‑plugin, the assembly‑plugin,
and you can see specific versions inside of here.
So this is everything that's being built inside of your application.
Now you can override all of this just by editing your own POM,
you don't have to go into the super POM at all,
but this is what's configured for you by default. You can
see our Compiler Plugin, how it adds that in line to the
plugin section that we have.
But then you can see where our test‑plugin's configured at, and how
all of that's all ran, and the clean‑plugin, all of that information
is pulled inside of our application.
We have the install‑plugin for all of those goals.
We have the deploy‑plugin for the deploy goal and the
deploy phase, the site information.
All of this stuff is built out for you and inherited from that
super POM, and if we were using a parent POM,
it would pull that information in as well.
So really wordy,
a lot of stuff going on, but if you're really trying to trouble shoot something,
don't look past the Effective POM tab because chances are you
can find a version of what you're looking for,
or something that you might want to override, or just know how something's working, and it's defined inside of this file.