Versions are the release number of the artifact that we want to use.
There's really only one version that warrants taking time to discuss,
and that is SNAPSHOT.
All of your internal development should start off as a SNAPSHOT.
You should also be aware of using SNAPSHOTS from other third‑party libraries.
Say you're using a version of Spring or some other third‑party tool out there,
and you want the latest code.
You can pull it down as a SNAPSHOT.
Now SNAPSHOT allows us to push new code up to a
repository or a development team every time.
So when we say we're using a SNAPSHOT version,
and it has to be labeled specifically that in all capital letters,
I'm going to show you an example of this.
Every time we go to compile,
it will look to see if there's new code that it should pull down and use.
Besides SNAPSHOT releases,
everything else of a naming convention is left up to the end user.
Here's an example of an application we could create, myapp‑1.0‑SNAPSHOT.
Myapp is the artifactId, as we talked about in the previous slide,
and 1.0 is the version, but it's also a type of SNAPSHOT.
So it's a 1.0‑SNAPSHOT, and it has to be all capital letters, as I've
mentioned a few times. It does not work If it's lowercase. Our changes
are always downloaded by using this convention.
This is the key reason to use it though. It saves us from a
re‑releasing versions of development.
I've worked with a lot of organizations that have started off saying,
Oh,
SNAPSHOTS scare us, so we're going to release every time we make a
change, and you end up having tons of releases, so your versionId
ends up being something like 1.0.143.
There are 143 maintenance releases.
So you've got this long number instead of SNAPSHOT,
which then people aren't always the latest or stuck on an older version,
and it kind of defeats the purpose of it.
SNAPSHOTS are good, you just have to be aware of what they are and how you
should consider using them in your development lifecycle.
You never want to deploy to production with a SNAPSHOT because we can't
reproduce or recreate the code. The next time they go to compile it,
the functionality could be different underneath for
us. As we mentioned a minute ago,
a release doesn't have to be a specific naming convention.
Our final release could be myapp‑1.0.jar,
which is very common for a naming convention.
And as we do maintenance releases, that could upgrade to 1.0.1 just because
we did a bug fix and didn't release any new functionality.
As we release new functionality,
it would maybe be 1.1. Now some industry‑common terms
that don't really affect Maven,
but it kind of helps you conceptualize or wrap your head around how
this works are things like milestone releases.
Often you'll see open source projects use 1.0‑M1 for a milestone release,
or RC1, or RC2, or RC3 for release candidates. Again,
not something that you should probably go to production on, but if you're
tired of SNAPSHOTS possibly breaking your code, and you want people to
know that you're going to release something,
but it's not completely stable yet, then use a milestone or a release candidate.
You'll also see some people, when they do their final release, name it as
release, just because they want the convention of a SNAPSHOT where you can
see whether it's a SNAPSHOT or a release,
and in the final version, they'll name it ‑RELEASE. Also, some people will choose FINAL for the final release.