When we left off our previous example, we were getting a build failure,
and we just talked about why, and that's that as of Java 10+,
Java 5 was no longer supported,
and the default compiled version before was Java 5. So now it's forcing you to
use 7 or later because there is no longer support for 5.
This is done on purpose, and it's actually helping you.
It may not feel like that because you have to jump through
another step to get your application to work,
which previously you wouldn't have had to have done this,
but they're forcing you to understand which version of
code you're compiling your classes to.
Let's switch back to our IDE, and inside of our POM,
we want to go behind packaging,
but before the closing project tag, and we're going to add a build
section in here. Now, I already have this code written,
and you probably don't want to watch me type it all out,
so I'm going to grab it and I'm going to paste it in my application,
and I'll walk through it here with you.
There's a build section, and then you create a plugin section.
Now,
the biggest thing I see people make a mistake doing
here is they add the plugins section,
but don't add the plugin element after that.
So, notice that there is a nested plugins plugin section, and then
inside of there we go through and add everything,
just like we have before.
We add a groupId, an org, apache, Maven, plugins, an artifactId
of maven‑compiler‑plugin, a version of 3.8.0, and a
configuration specifying a release of 12.
Now I am using Java 12 in this course.
If you're using Java 11, that's fine, just change your release to specify 11
versus 12 or whatever corresponding Java release you are using.
Let's save this and go back out to our command line
and run that compilation again,
and you'll see that we now have a compiled class. And we can
verify that by cd‑ing down into our target directory, and
you'll see a classes directory,
we'll cd into classes, and we'll have our
HelloWorld.class here. And we can, actually,
because we're using the default package,
just say java HelloWorld and run that, and you'll see that it prints
out Hello World to our command line interface.
So we have our application fully working.
And let's step through those few steps that we had
to do to get that working again.
We created a simple project.
We added a pom.xml, specified our group, artifact,
version, model, and packaging type.
We did have to add this build section for Java 12 in here.
Then we created our src, main, java directory structure, and
added our HelloWorld.java file that just simply prints out
Hello World to the command line.
From there we were able to run our Maven clean and compile targets that would
go through and download all of the dependencies and plugins that it needed to
for our project to be cleaned and compiled.
We can also do the same thing and run package at that project level as
well, and it will now generate our artifact for us, too. So we can say mvn
package, cd back into our target directory, and it will have our Hello
World jar file already produced for us.
If you remember, the packaging type inside of our POM was a jar.
It will go ahead and create that for us. So we can go into cd
target and do a dir here, and you'll see there is our artifact idea
of HelloWorld, our version of 1.0‑SNAPSHOT, our packaging type of .jar, all specified in our file.