Dependency repositories and plugin repositories can be separate or the
same repository. As we mentioned, projects will often not upload their
snapshot code to central because of the headaches and sometimes
frequent changes that their code will go through before they get it up
to a final released project.
Plugins are usually in the same repository as dependencies,
but can be broken out.
They often are broken out for corporate repositories,
and if you've created your own plugin, should store it there.
Also, as I mentioned,
companies should look at using their own corporate repository to
help lighten the load on the central repo.
You're eventually going to build your own libraries that
you want to have hosted internally and not be posting those up to the central repository.