Hello, and welcome back
to the HTML basic section.
In this section,
we will finally start coding some HTML,
but before we get to the actual coding
we need to first pick a text editor
This is the program that we will use
to write all our code.
A modern text editor should have features
such as syntax, highlighting, and code completion
for quick development.
In this course I will use a text editor
called Brackets.
It is perfect for web development,
and offers some features I really love
and are really useful.
I would even say that this is the best
text editor for web development out there.
It's available for Mac OS X and also for Windows.
And the best thing, it is completely free.
So let's go down on it.
So here in Google it is quite easy
to find it, just type brackets.io.
Okay then download and install it.
Right here.
I don't have to do this because
I already have it installed here on my Mac.
I strongly suggest you to use this editor,
but if you are already familiar with some
other text editor you can of course use that
for this course.
So I hope you managed to install Brackets by now.
So now let's go open our Brackets app.
When you do that for the first time,
you'll see this simple demo HTML file
explaining how the editor works.
We don't need that for now
because I will show you everything
you need to know over the next sections.
For now I just want to briefly go over
the most important parts of the interface.
It's very simple, yet very powerful.
So as you can see right here,
here in the middle, goes all the codes
we're gonna write over this course.
On the left side, we have the files
that are currently opened, named here
the working files
and there's also a file train that shows
all files contained in a project.
In this demo project it's only in HTML
and a CSS file and a folder.
Yeah, screenshots.
And then we have the right side
and there is a plug-in bar.
There are tons of cool plug-ins for Brackets
which are like apps that extend the functionality
of the editor and we will actually use
some of them later in the course.
So very simple, but very powerful
and the most important thing here in the middle
where we will write our code.
So that was a very small introduction
to Brackets.
Now let's get started with some HTML
in the next lecture, see you there.