Now that we have
our super text editor installed,
let's talk about HTML.
Now, this HTML section together with the CSS section
is designed to get you started for our big web page project
that we will be working on later.
Here, we will just cover some very basic things,
like the structure of any web page,
how to use headings, paragraphs, images, and links
just to get you started.
But let me first show you what we'll build
in this section and in the next one using HTML and CSS.
It's a very, very simple, fake blog post web page.
But it looks pretty cool for a first web page, right?
So, starting with HTML.
But first of all, what is HTML?
HTML stands for hyper text markup language.
So it's a markup language and
not actually a programming language.
HTML documents are described by HTML tags
like these three you see here.
Each HTML tag describes a different type of content
such as headings, paragraphs, or links.
We use tags to markup the beginning and end of an element.
Each element is written with an opening tag
and a closing tag, with the content in between.
So the closing tag is just the same as
the opening tag but with a slash.
We will see all of that when we start real coding.
And web browsers such as Google Chrome
can read HTML files we code
and translate them into visible web pages.
All right, now that we know what HTML is,
we can move on to some real coding in the next lecture.