(Voiceover) Welcome to our last lecture.
So now that our website is online,
we can still work on it,
because the launch is not the end of the story.
So, as you hopefully remember,
the seventh, and last step of our plan
is the site maintenance.
This means that you should keep track
of your website's success and monitor users' behavior.
And, how do we do that?
We use a very powerful tool called Google Analytics.
With this software, you'll be able to monitor statistics,
like the number of visits your website receives,
the amount of time your visitors stay,
the average number of page views for each visitor,
and many many other useful statistics.
And then, using this data, you can make adjustments
to the website in order to make it better and better.
So I will now actually install Google Analytics
on the website I just uploaded
to show you how easy that is.
So, of course, you need to start off
by creating an account for Google Analytics,
but that's easy if you already have a Google account.
And once you have your Google Analytics account created,
this is what comes up.
So we now need to add a new website that we will track.
So in my case, so it's a website,
for this case, I will call it Omnifirst,
and then we need to link to a website.
And I can copy it from here,
and now some industry,
well this doesn't really matter, right?
I will say "computers" because we created it
in a web design course, and then the zone
I'll want is for Portugal actually.
That's where I live, so.
And now we just hit guest checking I.D.
So now, all we need to do really
is to copy this script here and edit to our website.
First simple piece of Java script, so it goes down here.
And we just paste it here
and we don't have to do anything else.
Now if you have a website with multiple pages,
then you need to past this script
in each of those pages, right?
Okay, now I take this and I actually will also upload this,
so this is what I showed you in the lecture before,
and as I told you,
this will only upload the files that were changed.
So it now checks all the files, but it doesn't upload them.
It will only upload [Inaudible] HTML files.
All right.
Let me just check if this worked,
so I will see the page source.
And down here is the code
that we just placed it there, all right?
This is exactly what we wanted to do.
Okay, then you can actually
visit your statistics.
So this is what I told you.
You can see all kind of statistics here.
So just go explore all of this.
So the number of sessions, the number of users,
the number of page views, the number of pages per session,
and then how many times the user stayed on the web page,
and the bounce rate,
which is the amount of single page users,
which in our case, of course, will be quite high
because we only have one page.
But you know, all kinds of statistics are here
and down here are even more, where we can see
where your visitors came from,
where if they came from Facebook,
or you can even see which country they came from here,
and all kinds of stuff.
So again, this is a really powerful tool
and you should definitely take the most out of it.
This is, of course, all empty by now,
because I just created a few seconds ago.
So, this was a quick introduction to Google analytics
and how to set it up.
So, now we have put all the seven steps
from our seven step plan into action.
This was quite a long journey, but we did it!
You can now actually open the web page on the internet,
It is exactly the website that we created together.
And you are now able to do all of this
completely on your own.
And that is so amazing.
I mean, what could even be more powerful, right?
But now, stay tuned for one more lecture
where I have some additional information
that you don't want to miss.
So, see you in the next lecture.