Now let's talk a little bit
about user experience, because there can be no course
about web design without
at least mentioning user experience.
So far, we focused essentially
on visual design of user interfaces.
Designing the user interface means to design
the presentation of a product,
like a web site or a mobile application.
It's designing the look and feel of the product.
So that is what we've been looking at so far.
Now, there's also another type of design which
is very important, and that's the user experience design.
User experience is the overall experience that
the user has with a product.
User experience includes the user interface,
but also has to understand the whole picture of the product.
"'It's not just what it looks like and feels like.
"' Design is how it works.'"
That is a very well known quote from Steve Jobs
about user interface and experience design.
Let us picture as a good explanation
of the difference between just designing the presentation
of a product or designing the whole experience.
So the bottle on the left side may be beautifully designed,
but it doesn't solve the user's need to get ketchup
out of the bottle as quick as possible.
So the bottle on the right side tries to solve that problem
by designing a pleasant overall user experience.
It's also beautiful, but at the same time, it works.
We can think of user experience in terms
of user's goals and business' goals.
A user experience designer needs to align those goals
so the business benefits when the user reaches their goal.
Imagine for example that you're running a web site
where you want to give away for free an ebook
in exchange for an email address.
The user's goal here is to learn
about the specific subject of your book.
And your goal is to get the email address of your customers.
For example, so you can try to sell them something later.
Now you gotta make sure that your design makes
the best possible job in achieving both goals.
User experience is a huge field and requires
a lot of things to study and to analyze.
But I felt like I should at least tell you
some very basic things about it.
I will also give you the link to
a great, free user experience crash course,
if you're interested.
Find the link to that course in the ebook.