In this movie, I will show you how to properly manage photographs inside PowerPoint. Together we will
create an employee profile slide using the Acme_16.9 template.
Let's get it started!
As a first step, double click on the .potx file to open it as normal presentation with the .pptx
extension.
By the way, if you want to open the .potx file to format your template, right mouse click and
choose 'Open'.
This is very important,
and you should be aware of this difference.
OK.
Now I have my presentation opened.
Let's create a 'Title Only' slide by placing the cursor here,
and pressing Ctrl M shortcut.
I'm going to add the title.
Let's type
'Management'.
OK, now it's time to add the first text box.
I navigate to my Quick Access Toolbar,
I click on the textbox icon and drag like this.
What I want to put inside is the name and surname of the first employee, as well as his job title underneath.
Let's type
John Smith.
Now, I pressed Shift Enter to enter a soft line break.
And I'm going to type CEO.
OK, once I have the text inside, it's time to format it.
I press Ctrl A to select everything,
and I'm going to change the font size into 22 points.
I also want the first line to be in bold,
and the second one to be regular and gray.
Perfect!
Now I want to create a yellow, straight, horizontal line.
Actually, it will play a role of visual separator between the textbox and photograph, which I am
going to add later on.
OK.
I press Shift and drag.
I want it to be short.
Let's change
it's width to 6 points and change the color into yellow.
Now I'm going to align it center with my textbooks by using their Quick Tools macro.
As a next step, let's group the textbox and the line by using Ctrl G shortcut.
I will position it here on the right hand side.
Once I have these two elements grouped and properly formatted, it's time to use it as textual
placeholder for profiles of another three people.
I make sure the group of objects is selected,
and I press Ctrl D shortcut.
I place the copied element here.
and press Ctrl D two times.
Perfect!
Now, I drag the last element and try to align it with the right hand side of my tagline.
My smart guides helped me to position everything.
Now I make a loop selection.
I navigate to the Native Alignment Tools,
and distribute everything horizontally.
As the last step, I'm going to ungroup all of these elements by pressing Ctrl Shift G shortcut.
And it's time to fill other textboxes with text.
I will type:
Mary Williams,
Head of the Project Department.
Jack Luke
Head of Sales Department.
Emily Jones, Head of Customer Support.
Now I'm going to teach you how to crop an image into a circle.
I will start by copying and pasting the photo of CEO.
Now I make sure the image is selected.
I navigate to the Picture Format tab.
I select the Crop tool.
and 'Crop to Shape' command.
I will choose 'oval' from the list.
As you can see, if I tried to crop this photo into the circle, it's cropping down the entire image.
It's maintaining the aspect ratio, which was a rectangle by default.
If I try to make it a circle manually by just dragging, you can notice that I am actually skewing
the image and to make it look distorted.
I press Ctrl Z to undo.
What I need to do first is to bring this photo into the square.
Then I can turn this square into a circle.
So let's do this once again.
I navigate to the Picture Format tab,
I click at 'Crop',
'Aspect Ratio',
and I choose 1:1 option.
My photograph is still selected and I press Shift and drag to adjust the central point of this image,
which is the face of this man.
OK, it looks good.
Now I release.
As you can see, now I have a perfect square, which means that a circle will have a uniform diameter
the whole way across.
I select the picture once again, navigator to the 'Crop'
'Crop to Shape'
'oval'
Perfect!
Now I'm pressing Shifts to change the size of this picture a little bit and maintain the aspect ratio.
Remember, we don't want to end up with skewed circles.
Now it's time to format other three photographs.
Once I have four photographs properly cropped, I can align them and distribute.
I choose my textbooks as an element to which I will align the photo of CEO.
I press align center button.
Now, I'm going to do the same thing with the last image.
The next step is distributing photos horizontally and aligning them top.
I will also adjust the position of objects a little bit.
I decided to have all these photographs black and white, so I select a photo of my CEO, I navigate
to the Picture Format options.
And here inside color saturation, I choose
'Saturation: 0%'.
Now I select other images and press F4 shortcut to repeat the last action.
The last thing is distributing these yellow lines with textboxes and images.
I just noticed that the distance here and here is not equal.
So I will use distribute vertical option to fix this.
Then I select the other lines and align them
with the first selected element.
Perfect!
The slide is ready.