The standard color palette in PowerPoint is limited to 10 colors and each one of them has five shades.
But what if I need to have more colors?
What if I work with data a lot, for example, and I need to format tables and charts showing the
financial performance of the company. In such situations,
color scales containing green, orange and red shades might be highly desirable.
In this chapter, I will show you how to extend number of color options in your palette and to make
them automatically appear every time you or your colleagues open the presentation.
What is important, by using the methods discussed in this chapter, you will be able to add not 5,
not 10, but actually unlimited number of colors.
Let's first discuss the function of XML code in PowerPoint and what tools are needed to manage this
code properly.
Thanks to XML, we can get to the inside of our .pptx and .potx files, and change things that
are not editable directly in PowerPoint.
XML is a format used to store data and can contain not only text but also binary information or media
like images, audio or video.
Generally speaking, .pptx or. potx files use a combination of XML and .zip to compress its content.
It means that you can easily unzip your PowerPoint files.
In this lesson, I will use one of my favorite programs called 7-zip to unpack our Acme .potx file.
Apart from 7-zip,
I will use the text editor called Visual Studio Code with XML extension.
Both programs are free and you can find all the necessary links listed here.
After completing the installation, let's open the VS Code.
I'm going to install the extension, which later on will help me to format text in XML.
I click on this rectangular icon here,
and I type XML tools.
This is the extension I'm looking for.
Let's click 'Install'.
It will take a few seconds.
If it's done, let's close the program to save the changes and update properly.
OK, now let's create a copy of the .potx file.
Now it's time to unzip it.
This is very important.
Select the file, right mouse click,
choose 7-zip,
'Extract to...' + actual name of the template.
As you can see, the folder appeared. Please keep in mind that removing any files or folders from unzipped
.potx file can irreversibly break the template down.
So, be very careful and always create a backup version before you decide to modify anything.
OK.
Now let's see what can be found inside the folder and how the typical structure of .potx file looks
like.
Just for the sake of demonstration, I open the ppt folder.
Next, I navigate to the media.
And here you can find all the images originally used in the template.
As you can see, this is a great way to get an access to all presentation graphics with just one click.
OK, let's go back.
As you can see inside the unzipped template folder
we also have coded versions of notes, layouts, slide master and slides.
This is how it looks like.
Let's go back.
The folder I am particularly interested in is called 'theme'.
Let's open it.
There are three files inside.
The theme 1 controls the look of the Slide Master's color palette.
I'm going to modify this file in order to add new custom colors to my Acme template.
Let's create a backup version first.
I select this file,
press Ctrl C to copy.
I go back to the folder where I store all Acme template files and I press Ctrl V to paste.
Once it's done, let's jump to the second movie where I will demonstrate step by step how to quickly
program custom color palette interior template.