In this movie, I will show you how to use a Zoom feature in PowerPoint 2019.
For the purpose of this lesson, I created this short presentation about the nuclear power plants.
It consists of four slides.
The first one provides the audience with the general information regarding the nuclear power plants
and its role in the global energy sector. Slide number two, three and four are more specific and give
an overview
which countries have the biggest amount of nuclear power plants and are generating the most nuclear
power.
And this is the zoom effect
I will help you to create from scratch.
Right now, I am on my core slide, which is slide number one.
And as you can see, by clicking on the little screenshots here at the bottom, I actually can go from
one place in my presentation to another in any order
I like.
In other words, the 'Insert Zoom' tool allows me to skip ahead or revisit places of my slideshow without
interrupting the flow of my presentation.
Isn't it great?
Now, let me show you how you can build this nice animation from scratch.
The very first thing you need to do whenever you use the 'Insert Zoom' feature is finalizing all the slides
you need for your visualization.
Next, you need to choose the slide where you want to have the Zoom effect.
In this case, this will be slide number one, the core slide of this presentation.
To create a Zoom effect, I navigate to the Insert tab and under the Link category
I select the 'Slide Zoom'.
Here I get a pop up that shows all the slides in my presentation.
In this case, I'm going to select slide number two, three and four,
and click on the Insert button.
What I get here are actually links to slide number two, three and four.
What is important, if I make any changes on the original version of any of those screenshots,
the changes are going to be reflected in here.
Let's take a look!
I will go to the slide number two and move it up to the bottom of the slide.
If I go back to slide number one, you can see that the screenshot updates automatically.
Let's press Ctrl Z to undo.
Next, I'm going to adjust the size of screenshots and distribute them on slide area.
OK, now let's jump to the slide show to see how the default Zoom effect looks like. I press
Shift and F5 button.
If I click on the first screenshot, you can see that it zooms in to the second slide.
If I click again, I jump to the first slide and so on and so forth.
Now my presentation ends.
Please keep in mind that you don't need to rely upon the default settings and you can fully control
how the Zoom effect works.
For example, I'm going to modify the duration of my Zoom effect.
It seems to me that it's too fast.
The changed that,
I select the first screenshot,
I navigate to the Zoom tab, and change the default duration into two seconds.
Please keep in mind that you cannot select all the screenshots and modify that duration at once, each
and every item must be modified independently.
Another option you should know about is controlling the Zoom background color.
In this particular case, I use a dark, gray background for all the slides.
This is how my Slide Master is programmed,
and it's hard to notice any aesthetic problem here. But, if I make an exception and insert the black
rectangle only on my first slide, and then sent it to back,
you can notice that sometimes it might be vital to make the mini slides' background transparent just
to get rid of the fill color difference.
You can easily do this by navigating to the Zoom tab and selecting 'Zoom Background'.
OK.
That was purely informational,
and in this case, we don't need to use this option.
So, I press Ctrl Z to undo and I will remove the black rectangle as well.
I also want to show you how to modify the ending of the Zoom Effect.
In other words, I want my PowerPoint to always go back to my core Zoom slide and never show me the
black screen informing the audience that the presentation ends.
I can make those changes here under the Zoom options.
I select the last mini slide and I activate 'Return to Zoom' option.
Now, let's press Shift F5 to check how it works.
I click on the first mini slide.
As you can see, PowerPoint zooms in, I click again, and it automatically jumps to the second slide,
I click again to jump to the third one.
And as I click the fourth time, I go back to the main zoom slide.
As you can see Insert Zoom feature is very easy to use, and it makes slides more dynamic and
exciting to the audience.
In the next movie, I will show you how to apply Zoom effect onto the bigger parts of your presentation.
Don't miss it!