In talking to my clients, I have discovered a lot of confusion surrounding PowerPoint themes and templates.
That's completely understandable because themes and templates are quite similar and contain many of the
same elements.
In this movie, you will learn: the differences between themes and templates, which elements make up
a theme,
and which elements make up the template.
The theme file having the .thmx extension is Office-wide, which means that PowerPoint, Word and
Excel can share a set of common colors, fonts, effects and backgrounds styles.
Generally, themes are a great tool when you need to create a document or report by using these three
Microsoft Office applications.
In other words, if you apply, office themes to your PowerPoint, Word and Excel, files are harmonized and
look like they really go together.
Here comes the example of three documents.
Each one is using the same the .thmx file.
A theme, on the other hand, consists of four main parts: colors, fonts, effects and
background styles.
Please keep in mind that all of these elements might be embedded in a template as well.
To find out which theme is used by default inside PowerPoint, navigate to the Design tab,
click the little arrow to expand.
And here comes the color palette window,
fonts, effects and background styles.
The template .potx is a starter file made for PowerPoint.
In other words, a template is the scaffolding of your document, a pre-formatted file that saves you
time and helps you to create consistent looking documents.
A typical PowerPoint template consists of a Slide
Master. To navigate to your PowerPoint Slide Master,
simply go the 'View' tab and select the Slide Master command in your ribbon or use the shortcut.
Do you remember that?
It's Shift + Normal View icon.
OK, we are here.
If you look on the left side of the window, you can see a list of layouts. The top one is a Slide
Master, which I like to call a 'parent layout'.
This one controls the look of the smaller ones called child layouts.
Let's make a test and put the small rectangle in the upper right corner of the parent slide.
As you can see, the shape appeared on some other child layouts as well.
Why, you might ask?
When edit a parent layout, all layouts that are based on it will contain those edits as well.
Also, please keep in mind that inside the typical template, you will find the placeholders for tag lines
footers, page numbers, content and even images.
I know that the concept of theme and template might be quite complex. To help you understand that
even better,
and summarize what had been said in this movie,
I created a slide with a diagram.
It shows elements which make up the typical PowerPoint file.
Let's start with discussing the template. The typical template consists of Slide Master.
Inside it, you can find parent and child layouts.
Layouts might contain placeholders for taglines footers, etc.
In general, a template is your scaffolding.
The starting point for building a good presentation.
Inside a template, on the other hand, we have a theme which consists of colors, fonts, effects and
background styles.
All of these elements define the style and look of your presentation.
And all of that's taken together, plus content you put on your slides, makes a PowerPoint file.
In the next movie, I will show you how to properly format your Slide Master.