This is the palette I want to add to the template's .potx file.
I assume that potential user of Acme template might use these colors in charts and tables showing financial
performance of the company.
As you can see, we have five colors in overall.
Red represents negative values.
Orange represents medium and green
positive values.
I put all these colors into PowerPoint table. In a moment,
you'll see why.
Now I select everything that is inside it by placing cursor like this, and pressing
Ctrl A shortcut.
Next, I press Ctrl C to copy.
As a next step, let's open the Excel file called XML Code Generator.
I'm going to use this file to get RGB values of five copied colors and convert them to HEX.
Also, Excel will automatically generate the XML Code for me.
As a reminder, PowerPoint uses RGB color scale by default.
XML, on the other hand, uses the HEX scale.
HEX color is expressed as a six-digit combination of numbers and letters.
It is a shorthand for its RGB values with a little conversion gymnastics in between.
I select this cell, navigate to the 'Paste Special' options and choose 'Keep Source Formatting'.
As you can see, my macro did the conversion in just one second.
Now, let's change the color names into 'Negative 1', 'Negative 2', 'Medium', 'Positive 1' and
'Positive 2'.
Actually, you can put any names you like.
However, please keep in mind that this cell cannot be empty.
Otherwise, the macro will not work properly.
OK, I have all the names properly inserted and the conversion into HEX is ready.
The next step is extremely important.
Doing it well is actually the key to success.
I'm going to switch to the second tab,
and copy this code here.
OK,
but we are working in Excel right? What we have here is a formula.
Actually, it cannot be copied and pasted directly into VS Code because we will get errors.
Instead, copy the code,
select this cell here,
navigate to the 'Paste Special' options,
and paste everything as values.
OK, as a last step, let's copy everything
once again.
Now, be careful, navigate to the 'Theme 1' file we copied in the previous movie.
Right mouse click and choose
'Open with Code'.
We have a 'Theme 1' file opened in a VS Code.
Now press Alt Shift F
to format the document and get a better view.
As the next step, I'm going to click at these right arrows to shorten the code and focus on the main structure.
This step is very important.
I'm going to paste the code generated by Excel.
I place my cursor after this tag here.
Now I press Ctrl V to paste.
Perfect, our code is here!
I'm going to save the changes.
Now I can close the Visual Studio.
It is time to go back to my template folder.
This is the theme file
I've just modified.
I'm going to build it into my Acme .potx file by using 7-zip.
I right mouse click on the .potx file,
I choose 7-zip,
'Open archive',
I navigate to the 'ppt'
and choose 'theme'.
Now I drag and drop the modified file into the zipped file.
Do I really want to do this?
Yes.
OK.
We did it!
Let's test it out.
I'm going to close the 7-zip window and open my .potx file.
Now I click at a random placeholder and check out the font color options.
Perfect!
All the colors are now here in the correct order, just as I put them in the XML code.