In this movie, I'm going to teach you how to remove background from an image in the latest version
of PowerPoint.
Later on, we will use this knowledge to build a cool modern slide with a quotation.
To start with, I would like to show you some examples of how background that has been removed will
look like.
In the first example, I have a group of logos in the original version.
This image had a wide background
beneath it, which I successfully removed.
Here you can see a photograph of a building.
If I navigate to the picture for my top and reset this image, you can see it actually had the blue
background.
Here you can see a photo taken from an employee profile slide.
If I reset this picture, you can see that it actually has a quite complex background, but I was able
to remove it and apply soft edges as well.
There are two methods to remove backgrounds from a picture in PowerPoint.
First, by using set a transparent color tool.
And second, by using remove background too. Please keep in mind that these tools work on JPEG and PNG
files
only.
Let's now see how set a transparence color tool works in practice.
Generally, this tool works great on images which are very crisp or have a uniform background color
like those here. To remove the white background
make sure the picture is selected,
navigate to the picture format tab,
choose color and set transparent color, which is on the bottom of the list.
Alternatively, you can use the Quick Access Toolbar and click on this icon here.
Now my cursor turns into a little pen with a white arrow. As the next step,
I click on the area that I want to remove.
And as you can see, PowerPoint took that area and turn it transparent.
Please keep in mind that although this method is very fast and might come in handy in many situations,
it has some limitations.
For example, if I switch to the next slide showing the image of a building and try to remove that background,
the final effect is not really satisfying.
Why, you might ask?
Because the photo is not very crisp and has some gradient.
In order to remove it, I will use the second tool called 'Remove Background'.
I make sure my picture is selected.
I navigate to the picture format tab and I click here on 'Remove Background' command.
As you can see, PowerPoint turns my picture magenta.
Please keep in mind that the magenta area is image background
that PowerPoint is guessing that I want to remove. Areas that are in the original color are areas that
PowerPoint is going to keep.
In this example, PowerPoint made quite a good guess what I want to remove.
However, I still need to make a few quick edits.
I'm going to use these two commands.
'Mark Areas to Keep'
and 'Mark Areas to Remove' to modify the selected area.
First, I'm going to zoom in to see better what's going on.
To zoom in
I press Ctrl and scroll with my mouse.
Now, I select 'Mark Areas to Keep' command,
and as you can see, my cursor turned into a small pen that I can use to draw on this picture.
So I'm drawing here, which indicates that I want to keep this area.
I'm going to keep drawing in here aswell.
And a little bit here.
Looks perfect
now.
Once I have it really, I select 'Keep Changes'.
Please keep in mind that if it happens that you want to go back to the original look and to reset
the changes, you can either navigate to the Picture Format tab, click at remove background command
and select 'Discard
All Changes'.
Or you can go to the Picture Format tab and reset the picture
by clicking on this icon here.
OK, let's now switch to the next slide.
In this example, the situation is more complicated.
We have quite a complex background here.
But let's go ahead and see what can we do about it.
I select an image, navigate to the Picture Format tab and click at 'Remove Background'.
You can see that PowerPoint again guesses quite well what needs to be removed.
However, there are still some problematic areas
I want to fix, for example, hair and the upper body.
First, I select 'Mark Areas to Keep' tool. My cursor turns into a little pen, as you can see,
and now I'm going to draw.
Like this.
I will fix the area here.
Ok, as a next step, I want to focus on the woman's head.
I'm going to draw here,
here,
and here.
As you can see, it's quite difficult to fix the area around hair.
The edges look very sharp and as a result, unnatural.
However, I will show you later on how we can quickly fix that. Right now,
let's just focus on the main thing.
I will zoom in to have a better view
by pressing Ctrl and scrolling with my mouse.
I'm going to draw here,
here
and here.
Looks perfect
now.
Once I have it ready, I select 'Keep Changes'.
OK.
Now, I want to focus on this part over here.
As I mentioned before, I don't like the sharp edges around the head.
I'm going to fix that.
I select a picture,
press Ctrl D to create a copy.
I select the copied picture, navigate to the Picture Format tab,
I click at 'Artistic Effects' and choose this option here, which is Blur.
Next, I'm going to make this blur effect more intensive.
I go back to the Artistic Effects tab and click here at
the Artistic Effects Options.
The Format Picture tab automatically appears on the right hand side of my screen.
I change the radius from 10 to 35.
As the next step, I'm going to pick up the size of the first picture by navigating to the Quick Tools tab
and choosing 'Size and Position'.
Now, I select the second picture and I click at the green button to apply.
Once I have these two photographs properly positioned as two layers, I sent my blurred picture back
by using this tool over here.
As you can see, these small adjustments to the picture make a huge visual difference.
The woman's hair look more natural right now.
Before I will use this picture to create a slide with the quotation, I would like to briefly discuss
some limitations and drawbacks of the 'Remove Background' tool.
Sometimes you might find this tool hard to work with.
For example, on this picture, the color of first plan is very similar to the color of the background.
I would like to keep this element here.
PowerPoint does not see any difference between the two.
It might be also hard to remove the background around the strands of hair or fur.
To sum up, method number one, where I used the 'Set Transparent Color' tool is very quick, but works
on a small percentage of images.
Therefore, make sure you're familiar with the method
number two, which, by the way, also has some limitations.
If any of these methods work as you wish, you might consider using the Photoshop or other picture editor.