In this movie, I will show you how to apply Zoom effect onto the PowerPoint sections.
Much like you use folders to organize your computer files,
you can use sections to organize your slides into meaningful groups. For the purpose of this lesson,
I modified our previous presentation about the nuclear power plants.
I added three additional slides.
They might be used to provide the audience with more information regarding the nuclear power plants
located in USA, France and Russia.
You can notice that I also removed the previous Zoom effect. To create a section inside PowerPoint
right
mouse click on the area here and choose 'Add Section'.
Alternatively, you can use the shortcut Ctrl <.
Let's name the first section.
It's going to be 'USA'.
Now it's time to create the second section.
I'm going to name it
'France'.
And the last one 'Russia'.
In this way, we get the logically organized presentation.
Now, I'm going to zoom in on the three sections
I've just created.
Please keep in mind that zooming into sections allows you to move around your presentation in an elegant way.
It gives the audience totally different impression than when you simply scroll through the slides.
This is how you can set it up.
Let's move to slide number one,
which, again, is the core slide of this presentation.
Navigate to the Insert tab,
and under the Links category
select the 'Section Zoom'.
Here I get a pop up that shows all sections available inside my presentation
In this case, I'm going to select sections called USA, France and Russia and I click on the Insert
button.
What I get here, looks the same as what I had before.
The difference is that now I don't have one slide behind each zoom level but actually an entire group
of slides.
Now, I'm going to arrange these elementally a little bit.
I'm going to change the size, align, as well as distribute the mini slides horizontally.
Next, if I navigate to the Zoom tab and check out the default options,
you can see that the 'Return to Zoom' option is automatically activated.
Of course, there is the logic behind it.
Thanks to this option, a presenter can discuss each section independently and then quickly return to
the core slide without scrolling through the whole presentation.
Let's check it out!
I press F5 shortcut to run the presentation from the beginning,
I click on USA,
click again, and as you can see, PowerPoint takes me to the next slide
inside the section. Now I click again,
and PowerPoint takes me to the core.
slide,
and so on and so forth.
Another huge advantage of working with sections is that you can easily add as many slides as you want to
each section without destroying the already set up Zoom effect.
For example, I'm going to create a new slide in section called USA.
Let's change the tagline into 'The new slide'.
Now, I go back to my core slide and turn on the presentation mode.
And you can see that my new content is already there.
That's how Zoom works in PowerPoint 2019. As you can see, this tool is extremely powerful and can
help you to bring your presentation to the next level. In the next movie,
I will teach you how to use Morph, another equally great tool available inside PowerPoint 2019.