To navigate to your PowerPoint Slide Master press Shift and click on the 'Normal View' icon.
As a reminder, if you look on the left side of the window, you can see the list of layouts. The top
one is the Slide Master, which I like to call a 'Parent Layout'.
This one controls the look of the smaller ones, called 'Child Layouts'.
When you edit the Parent Layout all layouts that are based on that one, will contain those edits
as well.
From the point of view of template design, Parent Layout is a place where you want to make the most important
edits that you want to see reflected on the majority of slides.
For example, edits regarding the presentation title, footers or company logo.
The Child Layout, on the other hand, is a place where you want to apply to individual formatting and
ignore the overall look of the Parent Layout.
For example, your so-called 'Thank you' slide, which is likely to be put at the very end of every presentation,
might look quite different from the majority of slides.
That's the reason why it should have its own Child Layout.
Let's also discuss a very important topic:
deleting the Child Layouts.
Although you can remove all of them and build everything from scratch,
I don't recommend it.
The reason is simple.
If you delete all Child Layouts, you're likely to encounter many formatting errors down the road.
What I encourage you to do is to apply changes onto the existing layouts, modifying them to your needs
and deleting only those layouts here are sure you're never going to use.
I've made my decision that I want to delete Child Layout
number two, four, five,
as well as the last four layouts from the list.
OK, let's now concentrate on formatting the Parent Slide, since this is the most important
one which controls the look of Child Layout's.
The very first thing I'm going to do is adding and arranging guidelines on my Parent Layout.
The role of guidelines is to help you with aligning and positioning objects, as well as achieving the
slide to slide
consistency.
If you follow my steps and you don't see these default two guides across the center and middle of your
slide, navigate to the View tab and make sure the Ruler and Guides box is check-marked.
As a next step, I select my vertical grid line and drag it to the left.
Due to the fact that the Ruler is added, I can see the numerical values when dragging and I can be
100% precise.
15.90 value seems to be just fine.
OK, what this guide tells me is that I shouldn't put anything beyond it because it might get cut off
and simply look unaesthetically.
Now, let's do the same thing for the right hand side.
This step, however, is very important.
I hover my mouse over a guide.
I press Ctrl key and drag to make a copy.
I'm going to go to the same distance, which is 15.90.
Remember to release your click first and then release Ctrl key.
OK.
Let's do the same thing for horizontal lines.
850 seems to be fine.
Now I press Ctrl and drag to create a copy,
and put my guide here at 8.50 value.
As you can see, my footers happened to be not precisely aligned with that bottom guideline, but I
will fix that later on.
As a next step, I will add two additional horizontal lines which will determine the position of my
slide title and bullet point placeholder.
I again press Ctrl and drag to make a copy.
I think that 5.40 is fine.
Now let's create another copy.
And this time
I will place it here
at 4.40.
Great!
Now it's time to format the content placeholders on the Parent Layout.
Let's start with formatting
the Title placeholder.
I select it and changed the font size to 36.
I think that the default 44 might be too big for this particular widescreen presentation format.
OK.
As a next step, I drag it a little bit and try to align it to the already created guidelines.
I'm also going to align text top using the vertical top alignment added previously to my Quick Access
Toolbar.
As a next step, I create a soft line break by pressing Shift + Enter,
and I type more letters.
Why am I doing this?
I want to check out how someone might end up putting two lines of text.
Now, I'm pretty sure it looks perfect,
and my text properly fits the placeholder.
OK.
Now it's time to edit the text inside the tag line.
I'm going to change that into:
'Click to add slide title'.
Now, let's adjust the inner margins of this placeholder. I'm going to select my text by pressing
Ctrl A,
Right mouse click, navigate to the 'Format Shape' command,
I choose Text Options,
and click on this icon on the right hand side.
And I set 0.1 cm for left, right,
top and bottom.
As a next step, I'm going to create a line and position it below my tag line.
The reason I do this is that I want to visually separate my tag line from the rest of the content.
So, I choose a line from the list, press Shift and drag to make it
perfectly straight.
Now, I'm going to change the formatting by applying the yellow highlight color.
I also wants to make the line thicker.
As the last step, I position the line bottom using one of my alignment macros.
The next thing I'm going to do is editing the placeholder with bullet points.
I'm going to change the inside margins.
I want to be consistent and apply the same values as I already have in my tagline. To do so,
I navigate to the Format Shape,
I choose Text Options, click on this icon on the right hand side, and I set 0.1 cm
four left, right, top and bottom.
OK.
I close the window.
As a next step, I drag it a bit and try to align it to the already created guidelines.
Now I'm going to make the font size of each line smaller, but I don't want to do this manually
line by line.
Instead, I select the text by pressing Ctrl A and press Ctrl Shift <.
As you can see, it is a real timesaver.
Once I have my two main placeholders set up, I'm going to edit the footers.
I select them all, change the font size into 10 points.
I also want to change the font color into grey.
Decrease the height a little bit,
and edit the inside margins.
Let's again set zero 0.1 cm
for left, right,
top and bottom.
Now, let's change the positioning of each placeholder.
Let's start with the page number.
I want to make it fit to the guide
I've created previously, like this.
I'm also going to decrease the width of this placeholder and align text right.
Now, I want to test it out.
I want to be sure that if I were to type, let's say, three digit number like 150,
I have a plenty of room for that.
OK, as you can see we still have a lot of space and the text does not jump to the next line.
I press Ctrl Z to undo.
Now, let's format the date.
placeholder.
I'm going to position it in the bottom left corner of my slide by simply dragging. My smart guides helped
me to position an object.
Now, let's change the date format.
I have my textbox already selected, so I go to the Insert tab,
I click at 'Header & Footer',
select 'Date and time',
and I change the format to this one.
I click 'Apply to All' to save the changes.
Now, I'm going to adjust the Footer's position.
I'm also going to change the text into:
'Confidential:
'Do not duplicate or distribute'
'without written permission from Acme Company.'
As soon as I have my further, date and page number appropriately formatted, I insert a straight line.
I center it,
And place it above my placeholders with some help of 'Align top' macro.
I do this because I want to visually separate these three placeholders from the main content.
I will also reduce the height a little bit.
Let's also change the color of the line into light gray and change the line width into this one.
Now it's time to decide if I really need to have footers on all my layouts.
In my case, the best solution is to leave them on Parent Layout.
and Title Only layout.
What about unwanted footers on other layouts?
Should I delete them entirely?
I will give you two extremely important tips.
Do not remove unwanted elements from Child Layouts by just selecting them and pressing the delete button.
There is always a possibility that someone might want to have these elements back.
Secondly, do not try to cover unwanted elements with white rectangles.
The best solution is to navigate to the Slide Master, and uncheck this box named 'Footers'.
As you can see, the date, disclaimer and page number automatically disappeared from this layout.
If it happens that someone needs to use them again, he or she can check the box at any time and footers
will automatically show up here in the right format.
Let's uncheck the box on the Child Layout number one, two and four.
Once it's done, let's check out
if all change is applied on the
Parent Layout work on Child Layouts as well.
I close the Slide Master for a moment and create more slides by pressing Ctrl M.
Now I choose the
right layouts.
I need four in overall.
Now, I press Ctrl A to select all of them and press 'Reset' to apply the most recent changes from
the Slide Master.
As you can see, the tag line is nicely formatted, but I don't see any footers on my Title Only layout.
Actually, it is a very common problem and many people face it when creating a PowerPoint template.
This is how we can fix it.
Let's go back to this Slide Master
by pressing Shift and 'Normal View' icon.
As a next step, I'm going to select the date on my Parent Layout,
navigate to the Insert tab,
choose 'Header and Footer'.
Now, make sure that 'Date and time' box is checked,
and click 'Apply to All'.
Now let's do the same, this time for the disclaimer.
So I selected, navigate to the Insert tab,
choose 'Header and Footer',
and I make sure that the 'Footer' box is checked.
Now I click 'Apply to All'.
As a last step I select the page number. I go to the Insert tab again, choose 'Header and Footer' and
make sure that the 'Slide number' box is checked.
Now I click 'Apply to All'.
Now, let's check out if that worked.
I'm going to close the Slide Master, select by pressing Ctrl A,
and now I press 'Reset'.
As you can see, it works really well!
The next thing I'm going to do is changing the default style for Shapes.
Let's create the rectangle.
I will apply white fill color and light gray outline.
Let's also reduce the width a little bit.
I will also change the internal margins into 0.1 cm.
OK, once it's done, I make sure my object is selected,
I right mouse click,
and choose 'Set up as Default Shape'.
Now, every time someone draws a shape, it will automatically get white background, a nice grey
outline and internal margins set to 0.1 cm for left,
right,
top and bottom.
We can do the same thing,
this time for lines.
Let's draw one.
Now, right
mouse click,
and choose 'Set as Default Line'. Perfect!