In this movie, I will show you how to create this fluid and video like slide transition using the new
PowerPoint tool called Morph.
Are you ready?
Let's get it started!
To use the Morph transition effectively, you need to have at least two slides with at least one object
in common.
Actually, the easiest way is to duplicate the slide and then move the object on the second one
to different locations.
Let's do it together.
As the first step, I select the slide and press Ctrl D shortcut two times to create copies.
Then, I put objects on the second slide
to different locations.
To make an effect even more spectacular,
I also change the angle of cubes by pressing Alt and arrow keys.
Now it's time to apply the Morph transition.
I select three slides by clicking at the first one, pressing Shift key and clicking at the last one.
I navigated to the Transitions tab,
and I choose Morph.
As you can see, the little stars appeared inside my slide pane.
They indicate that animations are applied.
What is important,
you can also modify the speed of your Morph animation.
If you feel that it is too slow and you want it faster, change the speed from here.
You can also navigate to the Effect options. In this case,
I'm working with cubes which are objects,
so the default option is just fine.
Now, I'm going to press F5 keyboard shortcut to run the presentation from the beginning.
And here it comes!
As you can see, the Morph tool helps you to connect all the slide elements quickly and effortlessly.