Now it's time to create a Quote Slide.
This is the effect
we want to achieve.
As a first step, let's copy a picture of a woman from this file.
Once it's done, let's switch to the Acme presentation. Here,
I'm going to create a blank slide by clicking over here and choosing the Blank layout.
Now, let's paste the photo by pressing Ctrl V shortcut.
I would like to group two images by pressing Ctrl G.
Now I'm going to make two pictures
black and white.
I navigate to the picture format tab, I choose 'Color',
and click on this icon here.
As a next step, I'm going to create a square.
I choose a rectangle from the list.
I press Shift and drag like this to make it proportional.
I'm going to change the line width into six points,
and change the color into gray.
Now it's time to rotate the square.
I'm going to click at the arrow here,
and drag like this.
As the next step, I create a text box.
I put
the following text inside it:
We value our customers'  success
as much as our own.
This slide is about marketing
of course.
Now, let's create the second textbox where I will put the name of their quotes author. I type Emily
Jones.
Head of Customer Support.
Now I'm going to change the font sizes into 42,
and 34.
I also align the text inside the second placeholder left,
and change the font color into gray.
Now it's time to create a third placeholder and put the quote sign inside it.
OK, I will change the font size into 300 points,
and change the font color into yellow.
As the next step, I create a white rectangle,
remove the gray outline and place it here.
I'm also going to rotate it like this.
Now, I bring my quote sign to the front,
and place it here on my white rectangle.
OK, great.
I also send the grouped photos to front,
and as the last step, I adjust the position of my slide elements a little bit.
Perfect!
The slide is ready.