In this movie, I will show you how to use Merge Shape tools to change the look of your photographs.
Together, we will create this slide with an image in the background.
Let's get it started!
Let's assume that you work in the IT company and your boss decided to raise the qualifications of employees
by inviting them into the conference.
You have been given the task to create a slide informing your colleagues about this event.
You have received this image from your boss as well as some basic organizational info like the name
of the conference time, date and location.
Of course, there are many ways how you can design this slide, but you should always think strategically
to make it look eye-catching and interesting.
If I am about to create the slide, which has a very limited amount of text and there is a need to
use once the thematical picture, I usually decide to work on the Blank Slide layout.
Let's create one!
Generally, it's a good idea to resize the picture in a way it covers the whole slide area.
This is how I can do this.
I select the picture,
navigate to the Picture Format tab,
I choose 'Crop', 'Aspect Ratio', '16.9'.
Once we have the right proportions matching the widescreen format, it's time to align the picture
left and top using the native alignment tools.
Once it's done, press Shift and drag to adjust the image to the slide area.
Now, I send the picture to back.
Once it's done, I'm going to take care of the textual content.
I select everything using the loop selection and I change the font color into white.
Next, I'm going to modify the font size.
I will type 50 points for the title,
and 20 points for the rest of the content.
I also bold the title by pressing Ctrl B shortcut.
Now I'm going to create a straight line.
I choose line from the list, press Shift and drag.
Once it's done, I'm going to change the color into white,
and make it a little bit thicker.
I also adjust the position using the Ctrl and arrow keys.
Now it's time to create the group of purely decorative elements. Instead of boring bullet points
I want each text box here to have a little white square placed on its left hand side.
Let's create the first one!
I choose rectangle from the list,
I drag and press Shift key to keep proportions.
Now, I remove the outline and apply the white fill color.
I also want to rotate it 45 degrees by pressing Alt and right arrow key three times.
As the next step, I'm going to align the square center with my line.
Great!
Now, it's time to create three copies of this square.
I press Ctrl D,
and with my newly created shape still selected, I try to manually adjust its position.
My smart guides help me do this.
Now, with this shape still selected, I create copies by pressing Ctrl D two times.
As you can see, PowerPoint copies and moves objects in a specific pattern.
No additional alignment is needed here.
Now it's time to align squares and text boxes.
That Quick Tools add-in will help me to do this.
Now it's time to create a new decorative element.
I choose the rectangle from my Quick Access Toolbar, and I press Shift and drag.
I want it to be quite big.
Next, I'm going to rotate it 45 degrees by pressing the Alt and right arrow key three times.
Now it's time to position it properly
by dragging and using arrow keys.
Actually, I want it to cover only a part of my slide area, like this.
Once it's done, I want to connect this square with the thin line on the left hand side.
I create a copy of this line by pressing Ctrl D shortcut, and I rotate it 90 degrees by pressing Alt
and right arrow key six times.
Now, I adjust the position of this line.
As the last step, I nudge my square in a way its corner touches the line on the left hand side.
As the next step, I'm going to take care of this background image.
It seems to me that it is drawing unnecessary attention and it doesn't make the text visible enough.
There is actually a great PowerPoint feature which can come in handy here.
It's called 'Blur'.
Before we will use it, let's create a copy of this slide by selecting it and pressing
Ctrl D shortcut.
Now, select the first slide,
click at the picture,
navigate to the Picture Format tab and select 'Artistic Effects'.
Let's click at the 'Blur' option.
As you can see, the image is blurred.
However, it's not as blurry as I would like it to be.
Of course, I can easy modify that. Just select the picture once again,
I navigate back to the 'Artistic Effects' and in the drop down menu, I select 'Artistic Effects Options'.
Here you can see a command called 'Radius'.
Let's change the blurriness of this image into 30.
Perfect!
Now comes the most important part.
Let's navigate to the second copied slide.
I am going to use the Merge Shape Tools to cut this square from the main image.
I select the background picture first,
then I press Shift and click at the square.
Now, I navigate to the Merge Shape Tools command,
and select 'Intersect'.
Once it's done, I select this square,
copy it
by pressing Ctrl C shortcut and I jump to my first slide.
I delete this square here, and press control V to paste the new one.
The last thing that needs to be done is adding the wide, thin outline.
Perfect, this slide is ready!
This is how you can use Merge Shape Tools combined with the Artistic Effects to create visualizations
that can impress your boss and colleagues.