In this movie, I will show you how to create and quickly animate the timeline slide using the Morph
tool.
This is the animation we are going to build from scratch.
Are you ready?
Let's get it started.
As the first step, I'm going to insert the photographs on my slide.
I make a loop selection inside my folder, press Ctrl C to copy,
and Ctrl V to paste.
I select all photographs by using the loop selection, and decrease the size
by pressing Shift Ctrl and dragging to the inside.
Once it's done, let's position all the pictures next to each other.
We don't need to be very meticulous here.
I just try to get some space.
Next, I want to create circles out of these images. As you probably remember from the previous lesson
about managing photographs inside PowerPoint,
I must crop each image down to 1:1 aspect ratio.
Unfortunately, we cannot format all the pictures at once.
Each item must be modified independently.
By doing this, I get the perfect squares, which means that my circles will have a uniform diameter
the whole way across.
Next, I select my pictures once again,
navigate to 'Crop to Shape' options,
and choose oval.
Next, I want to make sure my pictures have the uniform width and height, so I navigate to the Picture
Format tab and check out dimensions.
OK.
Everything is fine.
Now, I change the position of my first and last picture,
select everything,
click at the 'Align Top' macro,
and distribute objects horizontally using the native alignment tools.
Next, I group everything by using the Ctrl G shortcut, and I use the native alignment tools
once again.
This time, I align images center to the slide area.
Once it's done, I can ungroup my objects by pressing Ctrl Shift
G shortcut.
Now it's time to visually connect images.
So, I create a line,
and drag like this.
If you do this precisely, you should see the small green nodes on the both line ends.
Great!
Now it's time to type years.
I create the first text box.
I type 1980.
I make the font bigger.
20 points is just fine.
They also change the font into light gray,
I copy the text box four times using the Ctrl D shortcut.
And now it's time to center the first and the last
textbox with the images.
As I have my two text boxes properly positioned,
I select and distribute everything horizontally.
I also align objects top using the Quick Tools.
I am also going to create placeholders which will serve as descriptions. To save time press Ctrl
Shift and drag.
My smart guides helped me to position shapes vertically.
Now, let's reduce the font a little bit to 16 points.
And let's type the dummy text inside.
Text 1, text 2 and so on and so forth.
Great!
Now it's time to type years.
OK.
This slide will play the role of a scaffolding so to say. Throughout this movie, I'm going to copy
this slide multiple times.
Let's create the first copy
by pressing Ctrl D shortcut.
I will start with modifying the font style of my year.
I am going to change it into orange,
and bold it by pressing Ctrl B shortcut.
The rest of text boxes on the top should stay as they are.
I also modify the color of description.
I change into white.
The next step is removing all the descriptions except for the first one.
As the last thing, I increase the size of the first circle by pressing Ctrl Shift and dragging to
the outside.
By doing this, I fix the center of this image, this is very important.
Now it's time to create the second copy.
I select my first slide, press Ctrl D and move the copied slide to the end of the list.
Now, I'm going to apply the same formatting changes as before, but I will concentrate on the second
group of objects represented by 1988.
So, I modify the font style,
and remove the unnecessary text boxes.
I jump to my previous slide, select the biggest photo, navigate to the Quick Tools add-in and pick up the size.
Next, I go back to my last slide and apply the size
by pressing the green button.
As the last step, I align this image middle with the other circles,
and distribute three images horizontally.
I also make sure my lines are properly connected.
I see these little green nodes on both sides, which means that everything is well adjusted.
Next, I create the third copy.
And move the slide to the end of the list.
Now, I concentrate on the third group of objects represented by 2001.
I modify the font style,
and remove the unnecessary textboxes.
Now it's time to make my third image bigger.
Please keep in mind that I still have the size of the biggest circle in the memory cache, so I can easily
apply it onto other objects whenever I like.
This is very convenient!
Now, I will create additional two copies of my first slide and repeat all the actions I've just showed
you.
OK.
I finished the formatting.
If you follow my steps, please make sure that your slides look in this way.
I use F5 keyboard shortcut to run the presentation from the beginning,
this is slide number one, my scaffolding,
slide number two,
slide number three, four, five...
and six. As you can see, all the shapes are perfectly aligned,
and if I go from one slide into another, the objects do not jump.
OK, before I apply the Morph animation, I would like to change one thing.
I want to make the smaller photos black and white.
This is the quickest method I know.
I select the small picture on the second slide,
I navigate to the Picture Format tab,
click at 'Color' and select the first option inside the pop-up window, which is 'Saturation 0%'.
Now I select each small image separately and press F4 key to repeat the last action.
I do the same thing for the rest of slides.
Once it's done, I can remove the first slide.
I no longer need it.
Now it's time to apply the Morph transition!
I select the top slide, press Shift and click at the last one.
I navigate to the Transitions tab and I choose 'Morph'.
I will also reduce the duration
a little bit.
Now, let's see how it works!
I press F5 keyboard shortcut,
and here it comes!
As you can see, the Morph tool animates and moves your objects in just one click.
Achieving the same visual effect using the standard animations inside the Animation pane,
would take hours.
This is the main reason why so many people, including me, love this new, PowerPoint feature.