The Quick Tools add-in is divided into three groups.
'Shapes and Pictures', 'Align precisely',
and 'RGB Picker'.
Let's start with discussing the first group: 'Shapes and Pictures'.
All these tools will help you to change the size of your objects very quickly.
The red button picks up the attribute and places it in the memory cache, whereas the green button applies
the attribute.
Let's jump to this slide to see these tools in action.
I will pick up attributes of red rectangles, and apply them onto green shapes.
Let's select the first rectangle named 'Size and Position'.
I go to the Quick Tools add-in, and then click at the red button to pick up its size and position.
Next, I select the second rectangle,
and this time, I click at the green button.
As you can see, my macro automatically changes
dimension and position of the second shape.
Now, I'm going to show you how 'Width and Position' works.
I select the first rectangle,
click at the red button to pick up attributes.
Next, I select the second rectangle and click at the green button.
As you can see, my macro automatically changes the width and position of the second shape. The height
stays unchanged.
Now, let's test out 'Height and Position'.
I pick up attributes and apply them on the second shape.
This time, height and position changes. The width stays unchanged.
Now, let's test out
'Size'
I pick up, and apply.
As you can see, the dimension of the second shape changes, but the object stays on the same position.
Next, I'm going to test out 'Width'.
I pick it up, and apply.
Now it's time to test out
'Height'.
I pick up, and apply.
Perfect!
I can assure you, this is a real time saver.
These macros work on virtually all object types inside PowerPoint: shapes, text boxes, images,
charts and tables.
Another advantage which makes them so helpful is that once you pick up the style, the formatting is
in your memory cash all the time.
It means that you can do other things inside PowerPoint, like typing text or creating new slides, and
anytime you select an object and press the green button, you still apply
the initially picked up attributes.
Now, let's get familiar with the second group of macros: 'Align precisely'.
These tools work quite similar to the 'native' align PowerPoint tools. You can use them to align objects
left, right, top, bottom, middle and center.
What makes them different is that the first selected object is the point of reference for the second,
no matter position and size.
The purpose of this group of slides is to visualize this difference.
I select the first object, press Shift to select the second one,
I go to the alignment tools added to their Quick Access Toolbar and click 'Align Center'.
As you can see, the alignment is not precise.
Power Point moves two shapes.
Why? The reason is that the central point of the grey shape is too far away from the central point of the
green one.
Now, let's see how my 'Align Center' macro will perform the same task.
I select the first shape.
Remember, the first selected shape is the point of reference for the others.
Then, I press Shift to select the second one, and choose 'Align Center'.
As you can see, shapes are now perfectly aligned!
Now, let's switch to the next slide.
This time, I will align shapes top.
Let's start with the 'native' alignment tools.
I select two shapes and choose 'Align Top' command.
Now, let's use the Quick Tools.
Select two shapes.
I go to my add-in, and choose 'Align Top'. Perfect!
Now, let's get familiar with the last macro: RGB Picker.
The function of this tool is very simple:
it reads and prints out
RGB values of selected shapes.
What you need to know for now is that PowerPoint by default uses RGB color model.
If this sounds strange,
don't worry! I will explain
this concept in more detail later on, when I will teach you how to program color palettes inside PowerPoint.
Now, let's see how RGB Picker works in practice.
Here you can see a number of rectangles.
Each one has a different color. To get the RGB values in just a few seconds,
select the rectangles by using a loop selection and click at the RGB Picker command.
As you can see, all the values are now here!
Let's make a test and check out
if they are correct indeed. I select, the first color, go to shape fill options, choose 'More field
colors',
and let's compare the values.
Perfect!
Everything is fine.
To sum up, all these VBA tools help me in my daily work, and it is a pleasure that I can share them
with you.
Also, it will be great to hear what you think about them.
Please feel free to leave me a comment.
I also prepared a number of exercises which will help you to get familiar with these macros.
I can assure you that all of these tools will be used many times throughout this course.
This will help you to retain the information and of course, will serve as the additional form of exercise.