In this movie, I'm going to format, in my opinion, the most important and useful Child Layout, which
I need in almost all of my templates.
These are: Title Slide layout,  Title Only,
Section Header and Blank Layout.
As the first step, I'm going to change the order of my layouts
a little bit. Title Only is likely to be used more often than the Section Header layout.
And that's the reason why it should be put as the second on the list.
Let's start with formatting
the Title Slide layout. This one is going to look a little bit different from other layouts.
I want to remove here some of the elements we have already added to the Parent Slide layout.
I'm talking about these two lines on the top and bottom of my slide.
There's simply no use of keeping them here.
So I navigate to the Slide Master tab and select this box:
'Hide Background Graphics'.
As you can see, everything that is not the placeholder already set on the Parent Slide layout is
going to disappear.
Of course, you can easily add it back, like this.
OK, I select this checkbox once again.
As a next step, I'm going to insert an image which will correspond with my current yellowish color
palette.
I navigate to my folder,
press Ctrl C to copy,
and Ctrl V to paste.
As a reminder, all of the files I'm using for the template creation are ready to be downloaded directly
from the course website.
Once I have this image inserted, I would like to change
its dimension.
I wanted to cover exactly 3/4 of my slide area. It can be done very quickly, just select a picture,
navigate the 'Picture Format' tab,
choose 'Crop',
navigate to the 'Aspect Ratio',
and select 3:4.
As you can see, this method is fast and helps you to be precise when changing picture dimension.
Once it's done,
let's align the picture to the right by using the native alignment tools added to the Quick Access Toolbar.
Now, I'm going to send that picture to back by using this button here.
Now it's time to edit the placeholders.
I'm going to type 'Click to add title'.
And 'Click to add subtitle'.
Once it's done, I align text in this placeholder top, left
and change font size to 54.
As the next step, I select the second placeholder, which will be my subtitle.
This time I align text middle and change the font size to 20 points.
I also want to change the dimension of two placeholders.
I select the first one,
next, I navigate to the 'Shape Format' tab to put the exact values and be more precise.
I want the height of my title to be 5 centimeters and the width 22 centimeters.
For the subtitle, on the other hand, I type 1 centimeter,
and 19 centimeters.
I also want to take care of the text style.
I'm going to use uppercase to emphasize the presentation title and make it even more visible.
Let's use the first standard method.
I select the text, navigate to the 'Home' tab and change the text case into uppercase.
Now, I'm going to check out if the changes were properly applied.
So, I close the Slide Master,
I reset the Title Slide, which I have inserted previously,
and I type something inside the placeholder.
As you can see, it doesn't work.
Please keep in mind that if you want to change the sentence case inside your Slide Master's placeholder,
always do that in the following way:
navigated this Slide Master,
select the text inside the placeholder,
right mouse click,
Choose 'Font'
and check 'All Caps' option.
We can also change the font style into bold.
OK.
Let's check it out.
I close the Slide Master,
and click 'Reset' slide to bring back the changes I've just made.
As you can see, it works fine.
Now let's go back to the Slide Master
by pressing Shift and Normal View icon.
The next thing I am going to do is adding the first design element here on my Title Slide.
I'm going to draw a white rectangle and remove the outline.
Now, I navigate to the 'Shape Format' tab,
and sent this element backward so that it no longer covers my placeholders.
I'm also going to change its dimension into 8 centimeters and 24 centimeters.
Now I'm going to position it in the middle of my slide using the native alignment tools.
Now it's time to position the placeholders.
Like this.
I'm also going to add the second design element, which is a thin yellow rectangle.
I remove an outline,
and drag like this to give it the same height as the white rectangle.
on the right hand side. As you can see, my guidelines help me a lot.
Once I have it, I position it next to the white shape.
Now, I select everything by using the loop selection and position it on my slide area like this.
I also want to have the company's logo over here.
I'm going to copy one from my picture folder.
I press control C to copy.
And Ctrl V to paste.
Now, I'm going to shrink it a little bit by pressing Ctrl Shift and dragging like this.
Once it's done, let's position the image properly.
Perfect!
The last design element I went to place on the slide layout is a small yellow rectangle in the upper
right corner.
I want it to look like this.
OK.
Let's start with creating a square.
I choose the rectangle from the Shape list,
press Shift to make it proportional,
and I drag.
Let's change the line color into yellow.
and line width into 4.5 points.
I also want to get rid of the white fill color.
Now I want to transform that shape a little bit. What I have in mind is opening
the shape's path.
This is how I do it.
I make sure the shape is selected.
I click over here at the Edit Points command.
I place the cursor over the angle
I want to open.
and as you can see, cursor changes into a four directional arrow.
I right click to bring up the contextual menu,
and from this menu, I choose the 'Open Path' option.
Now, I would like to remove these two lines.
To do that, I place the cursor over there first line,
right mouse click,
and choose
'Delete Point'.
Now, I repeat the same action for the second line.
Try to click precisely on the line you would like to modify.
If you click on the slide background, for example, the 'Open Path' options will close automatically.
OK, once it's done, I position this square in the upper right corner of the slide.
And I use Ctrl key and arrows to gently nudge the object.
The very last edit I want to make on this layout is cropping the picture a little bit.
I simply want to place this tunnel on the right hand side, so I zoom out just to see what's going on.
I selected the picture,
click at the 'Crop' command on my Quick Access Toolbar,
Press Shift and drag like this.
OK, now I click at the slide background to save the changes.
Once we finished formatting the Title Slide layout, let's switch to the next one called Title Only.
Actually, this one is going to the same
comparing to the Parent Slide layout. Please keep in mind that Parent Layout should contain the most
useful elements you have in your template.
That's the reason why I formatted title and footers on my Parent Layout in a specific manner, as well
as added little design elements like yellow and grey
lines.
OK.
Now it's time to edit a Section Header layout.
As the first thing, I'm going to hide background graphics by checking this box here.
Next, let's change the text inside the first placeholder into 'Title'.
OK, now I change the font size into 24 points.
Next, I align text middle.
and press Ctrl B to bold.
Now, let's change
the dimension.
I navigate to the Shape Format tab,
and choose 3 centimeters,
and 14 centimeters.
Now, let's take care of the second placeholder.
I change the text into 'Type text here'.
OK.
As the next step, I change the font size into 20 points.
Now, let's change the dimensions.
I navigated the Shape Format tab,
Choose 5 centimeters.
and 14 centimeters.
Now it's time to align two placeholders and position them properly on the slide area.
As the next step, I'm going to insert a background picture on this layout.
I right
mouse click and choose Format
Background.
Inside this window, I select 'Picture or texture fill'.
I hover over the picture source,
click 'Insert',
'From a File',
I navigate to my folder with images. and I'm going to choose this photograph here.
As the last step, I click 'Insert'.
Please keep in mind that if you want to use this picture as a background to all slides in your presentation,
click the 'Apply to All' button, which can be found here.
OK.
Due to the fact that the picture is quite dark, the black text inside the placeholder is no longer visible.
I'm going to change that.
I draw a rectangle and get rid of the default grey outline.
I also sent it to backward,
and type the following dimensions:
9.5,
and 15.
Now, I align the white shape middle, and adjust the position of placeholders,
like this.
As the next step, I'm going to add a placeholder for a Section Number.
I want it to be position on the left hand side, next to my main content.
So I create a rectangle,
and I drag like this to adjust the height to already created white rectangle.
Again, my smart guides help me a lot.
Now, I change the fill color into yellow,
and remove the gray outline.
I group these two rectangles by pressing Ctrl G shortcut,
and position them middle and center.
Let's also adjust the position of placeholders,
like this.
As the next step, I create a placeholder for Section Number.
I navigate to the Slide Master tab, click at 'Insert Placeholder' command,
and choose 'Text' from the dropdown list.
Now, I drag like this,
select the dummy text inside by placing the cursor and pressing
Ctrl A shortcut.
Now I press the 'Delete' button.
Let's type #, so that any potential user of this template knows what needs to be put into this
rectangle.
Next, let's change the font size of this # into 100.
Let's align text middle and center, and press
Ctrl B to bold.
As the last step,
let's align it middle and center with the yellow rectangle.
This time, I will use the Quick Tools add-in.
As the last thing, I'm going to copy the yellow rectangle from the Title slide,
and place it here in the upper right corner.
The Section Header layout is ready!
Now let's switch to the last layout called 'Blank'.
The only thing that needs to be done here is hiding the background graphics by checking this box here.
Perfect!
Our Slide Master is ready.
As you can see, the PowerPoint Slide Master gives you many options for creating layouts, which then
can be used multiple times in your presentations and save you tons of time.
I would highly recommend creating custom layouts for 'Agenda', 'Contact us' or 'Thank you' slides.
However, please do not go overboard because templates which are too packed with layouts might confuse
the user.
It is also good to know that templates full of images and other decorators might substantially slow
your PowerPoint down.
To sum up, if you have frequently occurring slides, I highly recommend making your own custom layout.
if it, of course, does not match one of the existing ones.