In this movie, I will talk about the magic of three keys: Ctrl, Shift and Alt. What is important,
These keys can be used individually or can be combined together to help you work faster and more efficiently.
Let's start with the Alt key.
Use it to activate Ribbon and Quick Access Toolbar's shortcuts.
Let's press and release the Alt key.
As you can see, it activates the little boxes over each command available in the current view.
Press the letters shown in the box over
the command.
I will choose 'N' to go to the insert tab.
Next, I press 'T' to create a table.
I pressed Shift, and Down Arrow, as well as Right Arrow key to select the number of rows and columns.
Next, I press Enter.
And here it comes.
The table is ready!
Please note that Alt key works in the similar way in all Microsoft Office applications.
Alt + right/left arrow keys. Use it to rotate your objects.
To rotate clockwise, select the rectangle, press Alt and right arrow key. To rotate your object counter-clockwise,
press Alt and...
That's right,
left arrow key!
Please keep in mind that this shortcut rotates with 15 degrees increments,
so if you want to rotate your objects 90 degrees, for example, you must do a small calculation.
Ninety divided by fifteen gives us six.
It means that you must press right arrow key six times to repeat the shape 90 degrees.
Shift + arrows. Use it to increase or decrease the size of your objects.
To increase the width of the rectangle, press the Shift and right arrow key.
If you press Shift key and the left arrow key this time, you will decrease the width of your shape. To increase
the height,
press Shift and up arrow key.
And to decrease, the Shift and down arrow key.
Shift + draw a shape.
Use it to get proportional shapes inside PowerPoint.
To create the square,
choose a rectangle from the shape list,
then press Shift and drag. To create a perfect circle, on the other hand,
choose 'oval' from the list, press Shift, and drag like this.
Please keep in mind that Shift key might also be used to create perfect straight lines.
Let's create one!
I choose line from my shape list, press Shift, and drag like this.
Perfect.
It's also a good moment to talk briefly about the crooked lines inside PowerPoint, and how they can
ruin the look of your slide.
Here you can see a very simple concept diagram.
At first glance, everything seems to look fine.
But if you take a closer look, these two lines are actually badly crooked.
How can you fix that quickly?
Actually, you don't need to create lines from the scratch.
Just select the first line, and go to the 'Shape Format' tab.
Do you see this value of 0.2 centimeters?
This is the proof that line is crooked.
Change the value to zero centimeters to make it straight.
Do the same for the second line as well.
Shift + drag: constrain the movement of the selected objects to vertical or horizontal.
Here comes the group of shapes which are perfectly aligned and the spaces between them are equal.
I would like to precisely move this green shape from the first column to the third without using
the alignment tools
How can I do that?
I select the shape, press Shift and drag to the right.
These red dashed lines are my smart guides, which helped me to precisely position the object.
If you follow my steps and you don't see these lines on your screen, right click on the slide area,
choose 'Grid and Guides', and make sure you have these three boxes check-marked.
Control + arrows. Use it to nudge the object.
Let's select the circle,
press Ctrl key and right arrow key.
As you can see, I gently nudge an image
in the direction of the arrow key.
Now, I press Ctrl again, but this time I add the down arrow key to move the object to the bottom.
Ctrl + Shift + drag. Use it to copy and align your object.
I can assure you, this is one of the most powerful shortcuts in PowerPoint.
Let's see how it works!
I want to copy this circle on the top and move it to the bottom.
So I selected it, press Ctrl + Shift and drag. As you can see by doing this,
I copy the object and constrain its movement to vertical.
Now I can release the keys for a moment,
press Shift and drag again.
The smart guides helped me to perfectly positioned the circle.
OK, great.
Now, let's do the same, this time with the left hand side.
I select the circle, press Ctrl Shift and drag to the right.
Now I can release the keys,
press shift and position like this, perfect!
Control + drag the nodes. Use it to increase or decrease the size of your objects and fix the position
at the same time.
Select this image, click on the node in the coroner and drag to the outside like this to make the circle
bigger.
Now, let's drag to the inside to make the circle smaller.
It's quite similar to Shift + drag keyboard shortcut,
the difference is that you don't move central point of the shape.