Now it's time to talk about the top shortcuts helping in the design process.
Shortcut #18, Eye-dropper + left kick.
Eyedropper is a powerful tool which can help you to quickly match colors on your slide.
This is how it works.
First, I select the shape I want to assign a new color to.
I click on the Shape Fill command and select an Eyedropper tool.
As you can see, my mouse pointer changes.
As I move my pointer around,
a life preview of the color I'm pointing at appears.
Now, I'm going to click on this color here, and it's immediately applied to the selected shape.
Now, let's match the fill color of the shape to a specific color in a picture.
I again click on the shape fill command, and select an eye dropper tool. Let's click here, for example.
And this is the trick
not many people know about.
You can match colors from elsewhere on your computer screen just after selecting an object and choosing
an eye dropper tool, click and hold the left mouse button and drag like this.
Now you can move outside the PowerPoint window, but the color will still preview and be matched.
This time I want to get this dark PowerPoint orange.
This trick can be extremely helpful if you work on the client presentation, for example, and you
need to pick up colors from the website.
Now, I'm going to jump to this Skype website.
I select the shape, I choose an eyedropper to.
Left click and drag and...
I want to choose this shade of blue. Perfect!
Shortcut #19, Alt Shift C.
In PowerPoint, you can copy animation from one object to another by using the animation painter.
What is important,
this tool also applies animation settings uniformly to other objects
with just one click. On this slide, I have two animations.
The first one is a spin animation, which turns the five segments circle.
Inside it,
I have a text with the Fade effect.
What I want to do is applying the very same animations onto the second slide.
This is how I can do it quickly with the Alt Shift C shortcut.
I select the circle first, press
Alt Shift C,
and as you can see, my cursor changes into a little brush.
I jump to the second slide, and apply.
Now, let's copy the second animation, which is applied onto the textbox.
I press Alt Shift C. I jump to the second slide, and apply.
I press Shift F5 to see the final effect.
Here comes slide number one,
and slide number two.
Shortcut #20 Alt F10
Once you've inserted shapes, text boxes, pictures or other objects, you can open the Selection Pane
to keep track of them all.
Just press Alt F10.
What is important,
the objects listed in the Pane are in the visual stacking order.
The most recently inserted object is at the top of the list.
You can also easily change the look of the list.
For example, you can hide objects by clicking on an open eye item.
You can make objects visible again.
You can change the order by using these buttons here,
or change the names by double clicking and typing.
For the purpose of this lesson, I created this group of three sites.
They all have a green row header on the left, map and a text box with some geographical data.
Slide number four combines all of them together.
What makes this last slide different is that I used two types of animations here: the entrance animation,
which is 'Fade' and exit animation, which is 'Split'.
Let's press Shift F5 to see how it works.
OK.
So I click,
and Europe appears. I click again,
it disappears.
I click and Asia appears.
I click again, it disappears. And the same goes for Africa.
OK, and the presentation ends, I press Escape to go back.
What if I decide to change the color of my maps?
I have good news.
We don't need to move the objects and we don't need to ungrouped them.
By the way, ungrouping destroys the animations.
Actually, the best and the quickest method is pressing Alt F10 to jump to the Selection Pane.
Now, I select map number one from the list.
Let's change the field color directly from my quick access toolbar.
I will change it into green.
Now, I do the same thing
for the map number two.
And map number three.
Now, let's press Shift F5
to see how it works.
Perfect!
Everything is fine.