Hey guys welcome back.
OK.
On with our first lecture where we cover strategic and tactical advice for making or models correctly
and saving your sanity in the process.
This looks like we're going to talk about visualization and knowing how to tackle the first steps you
take.
Whenever you start creating a new model are you familiar with the term writer's block.
Well it's just the concept that writers or people who write frequently often run into intense periods
of limited productivity for whatever reason.
They just cannot get their thoughts straightened out and uncharacteristically struggled to put words
on a page.
That's why we call it writer's block.
One of the most common times this happens is at the beginning of any project or piece of writing you're
presented with a blank canvas and unlimited direction you can take it and that seeming unlimited This
is what freezes you up.
Ever notice how much easier it is to order from a restaurant that has a menu with five items on it versus
a restaurant with a menu with a hundred item on it.
Well it's a paradox.
More choice means more indecision.
Well there's a similar phenomenon in modeling when you first open your model ready to chart your path
to infinite financial wisdom.
It often takes you hours to get started because you know if you set up the structure of your model wrong
it's going to screw you up considerably going forward and down the line.
So how do we avoid this and how do we avoid that giant ball of anxiety that occurs when you first open
your excel sheet.
Well it's relatively simple and it's the first major tenant you need to follow that of always keeping
the end in mind.
It's not a question of which direction you should turn right now.
It's a question of what series of turns you have to take to get to your specific destination.
It's often the lack of destination that throws everyone off so much.
And specifically with modeling when I say destination or know where you're going what I'm really talking
about is how is your model going to answer fundamental questions about your business.
From a practical standpoint here is what you do to always keep the end in mind.
Any time you ever put something into your model you should be doing it in order to answer a question.
Remember the lemonade stand example.
Every time we put something down on our page we were doing it in order to answer some specific question.
For instance how much do I need to sell my lemonade for to break even with the cost of ingredients.
When you frame it as a question then it's a lot easier to visualize what information we need to establish
and calculate in order to get the answer we need.
In that case we needed to figure out the costs of each ingredient the makeup and the total cost of the
drink.
And then finally what our profit expectations were based off of what we wanted to get paid.
So let's say you're opening up a brand new model and you want to model out your let's say e-commerce
business.
Well the first thing you're going to want to do is to shut down that program of Excel and just get out
a Word doc or a piece of paper ask yourself out loud why am I making this model.
Think about it for a little bit and then write down on a sheet of paper what questions you're trying
to answer by building it in the first place.
There are probably several things about your business you wish you knew in an e-commerce scenario.
We might want to know things like number one how much on average you shipping costs account for in our
overall cost structure.
Number two what's the relationship between profitability and the size weight of your product as in.
Should I focus on lighter smaller objects to save on shipping or shipping.
Not that big of a deal.
Maybe you want to know how much you are paying or manufacturer and what your profit margin looks like
as you order more or less.
Remember the more you order theoretically are not all the time but usually the cheaper your units will
get.
By the way we will cover this when we talk about e-commerce modeling specifically.
Once you have your questions right now order them by priority put the crucial questions at the top and
the nice to know questions kind of at the bottom now why do we do this.
Well because number one you obviously want to get to these crucial questions sooner.
But number two more importantly it's actually more efficient to do it this way because modeling questions
often have dependencies.
Sometimes you can't answer this question before you answer this.
And sometimes if you answer this question you might have already done half the work for this other question.
As you move down the list you might have done a lot of the work and you can minimize your time in it
and the less important questions.
Since we brought up dependencies I need to point out that you should try to be mindful of these.
Now what exactly do I mean by dependencies.
Well let's say I wanted to figure out my overall profitability next quarter if I introduced a new product.
Kind of like lemonade stand.
Would you like strawberry lemonade.
I can't exactly answer that question if I haven't even figured out what my profitability is this quarter
or next quarter.
Even without the addition of the new product you have one foot in front of the other.
Otherwise it will trip.
So when starting your model think about where you're trying to end up that destination is probably the
answer to a question.
The first thing you generally want to do before you model is write out the questions you want to answer
in order by importance and dependency.
You should know what questions are more important to you and what you need right now.
If you're trying to raise capital and certain questions will be more important than if you are just
modeling out to say estimate the viability of a new retail location.
All right guys I'll see you in the next lecture.