Figure it is welcome back.
All right so in the next set of lectures we're going to cover yet another case study this study coming
up is what we call fancy bread because it's based off of an app called croissant.
Yeah I know we're super original so sorry when I were talking.
Well designing a curriculum for this course and this idea stuck out to us as an interesting Casely to
explore.
We've already covered the concept of you works right which is a co-working space but for this case study
we're going to analyze the model of what if we made an app where you could subscribe to like a set plan
and then have unlimited or limited access to many different co-working spaces.
That's essentially what croissant is and it's something I actually use probably four times a week.
As it turns out part of the fun of co-working spaces is the flexibility.
And why not instead of staying at just one every single day turning it into a boring office.
Why not try out all of them if you're familiar with the company.
They might be defunct or just pivoted or something.
It's called class pass.
The idea with them was kind of similar.
You pay something like 60 to $200 a month.
Then you get a set amount of credits that you could spend at any type of exercise class could be spinning
class can be weight lifting the yoga can be Zuba or could be whatever the hottest thing all the moms
are currently doing all CORSAN is kind of like that for coworking spaces.
Monday you might go to this one Tuesday.
You might try out this one Wednesday and Thursday you might try another one and then next week you might
mix it up again and start all over.
So in this model what do you think we'll anticipate running into while we have a subscription system
so a lot of the same dynamics that any other subscription business apply.
Things like churn and things like lifetime value.
We also have on the supply side individual companies that own the coworking spaces that we have to negotiate
rates with.
How do you think we compensate these companies.
Do you think they give us access for free to their spaces because of the exposure kind of doubt it.
Most likely they probably charge us a very low hourly rate for how long the fancy bread user spends
at their place.
Then in order to make the numbers work have to make sure that users on average dont spend enough time
at these places for us to pay out more than what they paid us.
Whether or not that works in the long term who knows.
It's a bit of a tightrope to walk.
But nevertheless it's an interesting model right.
How do you think this would look as it scaled up.
Well let's dive into it next lecture and start working through it.
All right see the.