Hey guys welcome back to the course.
In this case study we are going to look at the SAS business model.
Specifically we're going to do a case study on a company called SAS force may sound like something you
know now if you're new to SAS.
SAS stands for software as a service.
This is where business creates a software that helps clients to do something on an ongoing basis.
Usually their clients or customers pay on a subscription based service and sometimes it's tiered as
well.
So broadly speaking he says companies will fall into three categories of SAS companies.
The first are what we would call the revenue increases.
These are the SEST companies that help their clients grow their top line revenue.
They help with increasing sales they might drive more leads may help with the marketing.
But anything that helps them increase the top line revenue sales force will be one of those companies
or at least some of their products would fall into that category.
Now the opposite of that will be the cost reducers the SEST companies focus on efficiency.
They help their clients become more efficient and save cost.
They may look for cost savings and generally as a whole they try to target claiming somewhere between
10 to 15 percent of the cost savings of their clients.
You know if they're working with clients who are in industries where their clients are spending millions
or billions of dollars every year a percentage of those savings could be super lucrative.
Now the third category of SAS companies will we be what we call the productivity businesses these SAS
solutions help their clients become more effective at what they do.
And its not necessarily tied with cost savings or driving sales but that those could be results as well.
But they tend to focus on things like making them more efficient with meetings or reducing associate
turnover or shortening the time it takes associates to get up to speed and becoming productive.
This category of SAS companies tend to be a little bit easier to sustain just because if your revenue
increase your are a cost reducer there tends to be a limit after a while.
If you're looking at year over year trying to keep improving you're going to reach some sort of limit.
Now for those math nerds out there we're going to be talking about these businesses reaching some sort
of Asymptote.
Anyways enough about that.
What are we going to look at here.
In this case study we're going to do a hypothetical case study on a SAS company called SAS force that
has a business solution that they sell to their clients.
Now like all SAS companies their solutions tend to take quite a bit of money and some time to develop.
And then after it gets develop it requires quite an investment in a sales team and marketing in order
to get and drive sales.
Now usually the sales set up for these companies have the companies offering their sales people a commission
of the sales.
So we're going to look at a common set up and model that out.
We're also going to look at what happens if you hire sales people at different rates.
You're hiring salespeople at a faster rate you tend to see your revenues grow.
But you also need to factor in things like the sales efficiency or effectiveness of the sales person.
It took a little while before they get good at what they do.
So when you hire a new salesperson they don't get to their full efficiency until after a certain amount
of time.
Really fact that in as well and the business model a Starbright right in.