Hey guys welcome back to the chorus.
So for the last section we spent the entire time daydreaming about revenue and how we can chart our
inevitable hockey stick like growth.
But allow me to be the Debbie Downer in the crowd and tell you that we are now going to focus on the
other side of the equation.
I know likes to talk about the expenses.
I'm told I would go so far as to say that understanding your expenses and the relationship they have
with your expansion is probably more important than understanding your revenue model and potential growth
rate.
A lot of modeling revenue is just guesswork.
We assume that we'll get this many customers now in this money later.
But with the expenses we can very easily get real numbers and figure out is this even feasible.
Expenses are expensive and you can quote me on that.
But one distinction we need to understand about our expensive patients is that there are two types of
costs.
Number one is what we call startup cost and number two is what we call operating expenses.
The best way to think about sort of cost is that there are the costs you incur to get up and running
whereas your operating expenses are the expenses you need to keep your business running on a day to
day basis.
In the modeling warm up where we created a lemonade stand empire we didn't incorporate startup costs
because the assumption was that we could scrounge for tables chairs pitchers and the sign that we would
need the things that went into the cost of each cup of lemonade on the other hand the sugar the lemons
the cups and the labor.
We considered those operating expenses you can further divide operating senses down if you want to into
expenses directly related to a sale like the ingredients and into expenses not necessarily related to
the sale directly like overhead.
You know let's say if you had to pay rent for your table spot or you pay liability insurance in case
someone accidentally ODIs on your sweetness.
Those would be examples of overhead.
All right I think we understand the distinction.
If not just ask in the Q&amp;A or the slack group.
Let's dive a little bit into startup costs so we can see how they get visualized on a model.
Okay let's stick with the lemonade example if we were starting up again just like it was yesterday what
would we need to get.
Well we need all of the things associated with first selling some lemonade and we might need the big
ticket items that allow us to even operate in general.
You can think of startup costs as being split between two things.
Thing is you need to get in order to get started and things you need to handle the early parts of your
growth.
Yes I know theres a fuzzy period between operating expenses and startup cost but in general you like
to think of everything you plan for at the very beginning plus a little bit of runway as your startup
costs everything past that once you're flying.
Operating expenses.
Do you need a table to get started.
Yes absolutely you do.
That would fall into the first category and if we were let's say anticipating 100 sales on the first
day well we might need to buy 100 cups up front as well.
Those within count as expenses for the first couple days of growth.
So in the model I'm going to divide the two sets of expenses into what's associated with the station
and those are for getting the stand set up.
If I add in all of the items we covered previously and out of total Well a very rudimentary estimate
of our startup costs.
Okay but what about all of the things you need for your first set of sales you need ingredients and
cups.
Right.
So let's add these things in line at the other cost.
Let's assume we order all of our ingredients and cup slash napkins in small batches just to be safe
in case this business let's say flops day one because we want to make sure this cost falls squarely
into the realm of startup costs.
Let's just add the cost for what we would need for the first two days of sales.
You go past that.
Well good luck explaining to the IRS why that counts as a startup cost.
So it's a based off of our old predictions and Section 1 that will sell some insane amount of lemonade.
In reality when making a model you'll want to loop this back into the unit predictions you previously
made for us we're just going to say these costs are a good buffer for the first days of operations.
We're not really going to take it that much farther.
Okay so now we have a more complete look at what we would need in our bank account to get started on
day one.
If you have the dough then you could probably pull this off.
But of course there's always more to think about and take into consideration.
Do you think planning to float yourself for two days is enough.
Well I'd say that seems a little aggressive right.
Well as it turns out yes it is aggressive but you could get even more aggressive and you could do one
day instead.
And of course there's pros and cons for a large runway versus a short one the prose obviously is that
you need less money upfront and you're more likely to say yes I can afford this.
Whereas the cons are that you might need to take money from a loan shark to cover payroll.
In fact let's try to be realistic with this.
Two days is fine but only if we get these exact expenses.
What happens if we get a fine for where we put our table.
What EVMs of a pitcher breaks and we have to replace it.
Well we need to add the age old concept in of any contingency.
Generally I like to do contingency one of two ways.
One I try to think of all the worst case issues that could happen and then double it or to make it a
percentage of your cost in this case I'm just going to write down $250 but you could base it off like
I don't know 10 percent of your cost base 20 percent 30 percent.
However risky you're feeling these contingency numbers very heavily by not only your risk tolerance
but also your industry.
OK.
One last thing we might want to throw in.
Let's say you hire your sales associates or ministers as they're called and they're just not cutting
it on the first day.
Well let's say they accidentally overheard a Bernie Sanders rally and are now unionizing.
Or maybe sales are just slow.
Let's build on a contingency that takes into account labor.
You the cost estimates we established way back in Section 1.
We can make a contingency plan of say 50 percent of what we project will spend on monthly labor cost
that could cover a whole lot of different labor related issues because remember when you first start
a business you have no idea what you'll need.
It might turn out that you need two times as many employees or just higher caliber salespeople.
These are things that are worth taking into consideration.
All right guys see you in the next lecture.