Hey guys welcome back to the course and the new section where we're going to talk exclusively about
how we tackle modeling user growth.
Presumably you all want your businesses to grow or at least be capable of growth structurally but the
way you model your growth and the way you demonstrate the most likely growth trajectory your business
will take can have a big impact on how you understand your business and what to expect from it going
forward as well as how convincing you will be should you ever need your model for raising investment.
So in each lecture we're going to tackle one aspect at a time and slowly throughout the section you'll
develop a more well-rounded understanding of the many different factors that go into user growth and
business growth in general.
In this lecture where we're going to talk about the concept of user segmentation.
Okay so let's say you just created a premium mobile application and you just started to onboard your
first group of users.
If you were to take the entire bucket of users you gained on each day and use that day to day pattern
to predict your revenue growth in the future.
Do you think that strategy would work effectively for modeling your growth if not how would you display
your users in a more useful way assuming that there is one.
So actually trying to think this one through the question we're trying to answer is how much money are
we going to make in the future and how does that relate to the number of users we have at any given
time.
If you want you can actually pause the video and try to think through it modeling it by users every
single day that we gain and then kind of churning it that way.
Does that help us answer the question that we're trying to solve.
One might be tempted to add this is a common mistake to say yes to the previous question of saying it
is in fact OK to just list out the total users per day.
Then theoretically what you do is you project your revenue for the future and you might just then average
out the amount of revenue per user by taking the total revenue for your period of time divided by the
total number of users that were gained and had during that time.
So let's say theoretically you had you made ten thousand dollars total up until this point and you have
twenty thousand users and your user base well you could probably guess that each user is worth about
50 cents and then you could use that as a revenue compass if you will to guide how much you think future
users will be worth.
We project we will get another half a million users.
Therefore revenues should be something like two hundred fifty thousand dollars but now doing it that
way the way I just described fails at a fundamental level to understand the fact that in this instance
you have users and then you have what are called customers.
Now do any of you guys have any idea what the difference is between a user and a customer.
Well it's actually pretty simple and it's a great insight into understanding other entrepreneurs when
they speak.
Yes that is nice that's your app got 50000 users in its first month but user by definition is someone
who uses your product but does not pay a customer on the other hand is someone who pays.
This is an incredibly important dynamic that any mobile app based business will have to understand inside
and out.
Trust me when we get to the sections on freemium you'll see again how important this distinction is.
Now the distinction between if they pay you money and if they're just a freeloader.
While that has a lot of relevance to this example if 80 percent of your 1 million users don't pay well
that changes the way you think about the ones you do because now the ones that do pay are worth about
five times as much as what you previously thought.
What about other businesses.
What if you only have customers and there's no such thing as a non-paying user.
Well you're most likely going to have to introduce a more relevant way of segmenting your customers.
Now the key to deciding how you're going to split up your customers into visible and predictable groups
it's really got to come down to what makes a difference in answering the questions you're trying to
answer.
If you want to make a sophisticated accurate model you'll need to segment your customers.
And while there are thousands of different ways you could do this it all really depends on what your
end goal is.
Let's say any lemonade stand.
Example How would we have segmented our customers there.
Would we segment by let's say customers that purchase three drinks and more and then customers who order
less than three drinks.
Well ask yourself how relevant is that.
If we were trying to understand say what implementing a bulk purchasing discount you know something
like buy five cops get one free.
What that might do to the total number of three plus cup buyers.
Well then yeah sure.
I guess that's relevant for trying to the average purchase amount per customer but in another situation
not so much if we were trying to figure out let's say which of our locations has the most efficient
person working at it on the other hand.
Well that wouldn't really be as useful in that case we might want instead look at the customer's behavior
and it's segmented that way.
We could split them up by say how many walk bys we had then buy how many stops at our table and then
finally how many ended up actually buying something now.
Sure.
Maybe a good salesman could get a higher ratio of three plus come buyers but if we only segmented it
that way we might end up ignoring that one person has a much higher average overall or just brings in
more customers period which is a more important thing to be aware of.
So with that second version help us answer that question.
Segmenting by walk buys stops and then buys.
Absolutely.
It could be very similar if you were modeling for say a Web site property.
You might want to segment by the number of users that see an ad for your site.
Then the numbers that click through that ad to your Web site then the number that didn't bounce and
immediately leave your page and then finally the number of people that purchased your product.
So when we're thinking about growth it's almost always going to be the case that to do it properly we'll
need to segment our customers in some way.
There is no template for user segmentation and you'll do yourself harm if you just copy and paste a
generic segmentation you saw somebody else using their model.
Now think hard about your business why you're making your model and what you're trying to solve by doing
it.
If you can figure that out then it's just a question of figuring out which way of slicing the pie is
going to be the most relevant.
It could be behavior it could be purchasing amount it could be free versus paid next lecture.
We're going to take this concept and work through the you works model while applying user segmentation
to it and figuring out what's the best way we can do this.
All right see you then.