Hey welcome back to the course when it comes to financial modeling.
You don't want to just sit down and start putting formulas down in a spreadsheet that you like champagne
in your car for a long road trip without having any destinations in mind and just going wherever the
day takes you.
Now I sounds like a lot of fun but not when it comes to building a financial model.
So before you actually start building your model you should have a very good idea of the overall structure
and flow that you're creating.
In order to do that.
You need to have a clear idea of exactly what questions you're trying to answer what sort of decisions
will this model help you with for entrepreneurs and startups.
Those questions might be hey what are the key drivers of revenue for my business.
What business model is better.
What pricing model should we use.
How would revenues look like if we did X versus Y versus Z.
How quickly do we need to grow in order to hit our profit goals.
There are tons of questions that a solid financial model could help you with.
But don't try to answer too many at the same time and definitely not at the very beginning start with
one key question.
What is the one question that you're trying to answer first and what information would you need what
assumptions would you have to make in order to answer that question.
For example if you're deciding on which pricing model might work best for your startup your financial
model might compare different projections that are based on the same growth assumptions but with different
pricing models.
So it doesn't really matter what question it is.
As long as it's clear because having the clear question we'll tell you what you need to build or account
for in your model in our jumpstarted example with the lemonade stand business.
We started off with creating a simple model to select the best location to use and we use the same methodology
to compare three potential locations by looking at the potential profits based on their traffic figures.
We did the same thing as we added more complex questions to models things like what if we added a premium
strawberry add on how would that affect the revenue and gross profits.
Finally we looked at what it would look like if we expand it to multiple locations.
If for example our question was Schweder open a lemonade stand or coke press juice stand.
Well then this kind of model would look very different.
We'd need to build two models one for each type of business and then compare the results.
Co-present uses my have very different economics.
They might require different laborous options different storage spaces different varieties maybe a higher
price point.
So it doesn't matter what question you're trying to answer you just need to be clear on what that is
up front before you start building your model.