Hey guys welcome back to the course in this lecture to explore a new business model called the affiliate
business model.
Have you ever heard of Herbalife.
You know that company that no one can figure out what they do and they're somehow in front of your face
everytime you watch the world's most hated and most loved sports team Manchester United.
Well I know what they do and I will tell you they sell lotion and nonperishable food.
Very strange combination.
There's a whole lot of other things that are not interesting or new.
But the way they make their money is through using an affiliate business model.
Yes.
They are also a pyramid scheme.
But don't let a couple of details get in the way.
And yes there is someone who bet a billion dollars that Herbalife would fail in the next five years.
OK.
Not all the affiliate marketing models are pyramid schemes pyramid schemes are businesses where you
only sell to people inside of your business with very very shady sales techniques and shady promises.
Affiliates are when you sell a product that someone else makes and you're just in charge of getting
people to buy it.
So maybe Herbalife is not a great example.
Let's use another one.
Never use the site app sumo.
They promote deals to subscribers at really low rates.
Another one that might come to mind.
Groupon Groupon is technically an affiliate business model.
Well in the case of Groupon after the other kind of work through this mysterious affiliate model as
well as any blogger that's ever e-mailed you saying oh my god I just found the greatest yoga mat and
it's only available for the next 48 hours through this very specific link.
They're probably using the affiliate business model and while when you pull back the curtain it's actually
not that mysterious.
You see the way it works is that an affiliate operates a business whereby they sell someone else's product
that is it in a nutshell they're in charge of promoting the product.
Dressing it up and getting people to buy it whether someone buys it then the supplier fulfills the order
and gives the affiliate a piece of the revenue for the supplier.
It's a no brainer.
Hey I'd like to sell your stuff.
Just give me a portion of the sales.
You have to do anything.
And it's kind of like free money in the Herbalife example the individual owners what they actually call
them.
They each go out and sell Herbalife solution on their own.
Usually it's to their Facebook friends and then they reap a certain percentage of the return on the
sale.
If we were to draw it the way this model Flo looks like it looks something kind of like this it's a
big circle.
The first step from the perspective of the affiliate is to drive traffic to the product or service they're
trying to sell.
Not necessarily traffic but attention in general.
In the case the affiliate uses a good old fashioned ad then yeah they will see an ad oftentimes an ad
inside of an email then they click through the ad to the page selling the product then the user decides
to buy the affiliate product.
Then the company that creates the product pays you the affiliate based on your sale affiliate commissions
range anywhere from 25 percent all the way up to 75.
I've see 90 percent sometimes the most common methods you see affiliates use is posting ads for products
directly on their site which is actually different from a CPA arrangement than we talked about earlier.
Although it is pretty close.
Usually with an affiliate there is a more close relationship and they're following a bunch of rules
and guidelines set by the publisher It was a CPA and it's a little bit more hands off.
Really it's a distinction that's not really important or worth knowing.
Generally in the case an affiliate.
Well they'll usually do is send out an email to the list that they've spent a lot of time building out
like promoting the product or they might write an entire post that conveniently highlights the product
in the right spots.
OK it sounds pretty simple right.
Well let's take a look at how it looks on an actual model.
Take it from here.
Mr. Simon now the affiliate model isn't going to look all that different from what we did with the ad
model.
In this scenario we're still looking at ads.
Right.
But in this case you're going to be paying for some sort of ads.
Maybe you're paying in terms of the CPC costs and then you're trying to convert those that click on
your ads into purchases of some product that you're trying to promote and you're going to be keeping
some commission of that right.
So if we have these figures as a given maybe we're you know trying to get 5 million impressions.
And you know you can get about a 5 percent click through rate then than then the number of clicks is
going to be the click through rate times the ad impressions you have.
And then if you're paying a dollar of 25 for each click then you're total costs for the clicks is going
to be the cost per click times the total number of clicks.
OK so that's going to be your cost right here.
And if you can convert say 2 percent of those clicks into purchases then the conversion percentage times
the number of clicks that land on your site or that goes through your sales funnel whatever that is.
That's the number of purchases that you have.
Right.
So let's say you're pushing a product that's two ninety and you get to keep 60 percent of any sales
that you make.
Right.
So the gross sales gross revenue is going to be the retail value times the number of purchases.
And your commission is going to be the commission rate times the gross revenue.
So then your profit will be your commission minus what it cost you to drive all of that traffic right.
Is your advertising traffic.
So with this simple model you can quickly get an idea of what your expected profits will be given that
you are confident about these numbers and that you can achieve them.
So how would a revenue model look so let's look at a 12 month model again.
Now we're going to get rid of these columns because we don't want to look at them.
And so we have 12 months here let's say that it's going to take us 12 months to get to this ad spend.
We don't want to spend that much yet.
We're going to slowly work our way up there.
OK.
So we're going to make this the 12th month ad spend equal to that on the front where we're looking at
and it's going to take us 12 months to get there.
So we're going to say the starting point is going to equal to the total that we want to get to.
Divided by 12 months.
OK.
So that's what we're going to start off in the first month and then we're going to slowly build up every
month until we get to that value.
So then the next month is going to be the previous month plus this value.
But now we want to make sure we fix that reference because we're going to keep referring to it.
Divide it by 12.
And then now we're incrementing the ad spend.
Right.
And if we copy this formula through to the eleventh month we'll get this even spread of kind of flat
growth.
OK.
So again now we're going to need to look at the CPC assumption right.
We're going to pull it from the front here whatever we put in here we put in 125 or we're going to make
it refer to 125.
In terms of the leads that we're going to have for the business.
All right your ad spend about how many cost per click then that's how many clicks or how many leads
that you're going to have to your site.
Right.
So we're going to take the ads when we're going to divide it by the CPC and we're going to fix that
reference there.
So then now we have this sort of number of leads based on that ads.
Right.
So then our conversion expectation we're going to pull it from the front.
Again let's call this it was 2 percent.
Now I'll explain why I have the rest of this in gray.
Just when we're done with the rest of this can be a little extra challenge for us.
Right now we're just going to use this 2 percent.
So then the conversions out of all those leads in terms of purchases is just going to be the leads times
the conversion rate right.
Now we can copy and paste the rest.
And this is the monthly purchases.
The convergence we're assuming the same product.
So we're going to reference the retail value of this product.
And we're also going to reference the same commission.
So we have these values here.
So now if we look at it over the 12 months it's pretty straightforward right.
Very similar we have the gross revenues going to be the total number of purchases times the retail value
and then the net commissions is going to be the gross revenue times the commission
and then the profits will be the net commissions minus the actual outspan here.
So once we have all three of these done we can copy you can select the rest and paste it now as a sanity
check.
Remember what we did in the previous one.
Here we can write the if statement or we can just make it equal to what we want to check.
Right here we're just going to see if it's the same Samedi equal to the profit from the front.
And we know in month 12 we have the same ad spend the same amount of leads everything is the same so
the profits should be the same as what we calculated in the front.
And it is so we know we did this model correctly.
Now there you go.
Here is a simple revenue model for an affiliate business.
Right.
Based on ads fan and your that drives a certain amount of leads that you can expect and with the conversion
percentage then you have the purchases.
Now if if you're doing something like this one thing that we could upgrade in terms of the model is
you would hope that you're getting a little bit better with your conversions over time.
Right.
Maybe this is what you're starting out at and your conversion might be better over time maybe you could
get to 4 percent by by the end of the 12 months.
Right.
So what if you had a conversion schedule here and how would you improve on this model if you had all
this.
Okay.
So that's a challenge for you guys if you want to do that challenge make this a conversion schedule
and then update the correct rest of the model to see how that would change your model.