You will come back to the course.
OK so we're going to go over these Ghaleb rule financial projections Excel that we built about five
years ago for raising our second round of capital.
We're going to do this a little bit differently than the with Simon did it.
Simon was taking blank Excel sheets and then building them up to get to a certain destination.
This is too complex to do that they would require way too much time diving into how we came up with
all of the information we did and the dynamics of the industry and pretty much all the nuances of our
sales channels.
So instead we're going to want to look at it backwards and show you what we had and kind of talked through
what we did well what did not work and try to put you kind of in our heads.
Back when we were putting this together so attached to the lecture it's either a lecture this lecture
or you can download this and follow along.
Some people might ask is it OK to be shelling this and yes I mean it was confidential but the company
ended up not making it.
I don't actually know why and I talked to that last lecture because I was not there.
But since it's defunct now this is no longer confidential so we're going to dive right into it.
OK so in the set of lectures Coming up we're going to first just focus on each individual tab and they'll
be kind of grouped together in each lecture.
So at first we'll talk about this one and then we'll talk about this and this will move all the way
down and that's pretty much how we'll cover it.
All right so this is the assumptions and data panel.
Another way that we set up our financial model was such that we had all of the kind of basic things
you would expect to see in a startup financial model such as you're trying to raise money.
We had our we were going to use our funds for this raise what we expected our monthly income to look
like.
We look the expected our yearly income to look like.
There are graphs and charts and those graphs and charts.
Then we got what's called a simple revenue which is just a very quick snapshot view of showing your
revenue because not every single person wants to jump in and look at every single detail of your revenue
every single type of sale and location on sale and then you look at the expenses and everything like
that.
So this is just a very good snapshot.
And then we had scenarios and scenarios are just a way to kind of hedge.
Oftentimes you'll be working with investors and they have a very three set kind of view of what your
industry should look like what your business should look like financially and they just have a lot of
built in assumptions and this is kind of unavoidable and so what we try to do is address at least two
common scenarios that could happen.
We didn't want to make a model that just showed the most rosy possible picture assuming everything went
right.
We just picked kind of two out of a hat really that we thought people might bring up.
And so far I mean it's a pretty effective strategy.
It does really kind of lower how much back and forth you have to have with investors because they'll
think in their head well what happens if you miss a deadline like this one.
And then they find out oh right it's just at the back.
This is actually a good strategy as well for pitch decks.
If you use pitch decks it's great to put in the very end.
Responses are rebuttals to common questions.
OK so we'll get into that a little bit later.
What I want to show you first is our assumptions and data sheet.
So the way that this model works is by using pivot tables now pivot tables you'd probably maybe you
don't know what these are.
Maybe you do.
I personally think they are the best thing ever in financial models.
And I will tell you why.
So with a pivot table works is you essentially set up all of these different types of variables in one
sheet and then you set it up such that they can either manually input in the numbers for each assumption
or they can toggle and pick something that is likely.
See like right here we have this dropdown where they can pick some type of scenario.
And what ends up happening is every single sheet on here pulls their information from this sheet.
OK.
Number one it's really helpful to set aside all of your variables and assumptions right here earlier
than one s.c you can see them all isolated.
So when someone can just read through these and see if they agree a lot of this stuff is subjective
how do I know if paying your CEO $60000 a year is competitive given the competitive landscape right
now.
We don't know.
Someone might have an opinion saying it's too much and some people might think it's too little.
So by doing this by setting up in this way when someone looks at this like an investor they I can put
in whatever they want.
I mean one of the biggest problems of financial modeling early is pitching financial models to investors
is you have to use because you have to just pick one scenario you're going to say yeah we're going to
sign on 10000 users in this amount of time it's going to take us this much money and everything else
is going to look like this.
And then immediately you get someone who is a pessimist or an optimist and they'll say you're selling
yourself short or they really might just go after certain parts of what you're trying to say.
And unfortunately there you are you're stuck with the model that they hate and it's you can't really
mess with it.
So with this we just set it up so that the investor or whoever is looking at it can fill it out the
way that they feel like.
Again financial models.
The whole point of this exercise is to show that we understand our business and understand our industry.
So it doesn't actually really matter if these variables change that much.
We just have to show that we understand the way that they work together and show that no matter how
you screw with this unless you go crazy with it we still have good fundamentals and we still have a
good shot at profitability.
OK.
There's only one thing you remember from this entire financial hot hole course.
Pivot tables they're great.
Let other people pick what they feel comfortable with and then make everything kind of flow from that.
So let's just start from the top left.
If you guys remember Sellar Perot was an application we used it to help people apply for scholarships
there was like a common application for scholarships and we use schools as a primary kind of growth
channel because they liked it.
One of the students they use it said there's some symbiosis there.
And so they would promote it directly their students but the student then would pay.
So what we had up here was revenue assumptions right.
So we still had the business model of the student paying.
So we would put our variable here for the price we were saying twenty five dollars a year this was actually
before we decided to change the system and go with a monthly one which actually makes a lot more sense
than a yearly one because we originally were thinking oh you apply to scholarships once a year.
Therefore we want to lock you into a yearly subscription and you pay for it at the very beginning of
the scholarships season.
And then at the end you still have it and then you want to renew again.
So we were worried that with the monthly people would end up essentially churning or leaving right after
they're done applying and then not picking it up till eight months later.
But in reality we could actually charged a lot more if we did monthly.
So that was our mistake.
The next thing we have is penetration rate and this was just an assumption that some people will think
is too high and some people think is too low.
What it basically means is that when a university emails out are out to their students what do we think
that the actual rate of sign ups will be.
Right.
So they can read the e-mail a hundred people.
How many people do you think will actually sign up.
Now there's multiple ways of getting to this.
This number right here.
You can use baseline judgment.
You can look at other things and base it offer that you can look at basic SAS subscription kind of sign
ups if you wanted to kind of go for a low end and those are sent out an e-mail about any random SAS
tool.
Maybe 5 percent of an email list on average will end up converting if you guys want to learn more about
that going to bear metrics dot com that's actually where you can see a lot of benchmarks of systems
for industries and their Sign-Up metrics.
But for us we actually came at it from a different angle.
So what we did is we ran a simulation over here we have the Miami-Dade test which is the details here.
I don't know why we had that but what happened here is so we really had no idea how many people would
sign up.
We really didn't know how happy the schools would be with the program in general.
So we went to a school and did a small test within a subset of the school so Miami Dade is school network
in Miami.
And I think Miami Dade is like the kind of they have like an honors school and it's just not nearly
as many people in it.
But what we did is we kind of negotiated a deal.
So they would promote it to their students.
And I think we gave them like a reduced rate or something like that in order for us to then use these
statistics to then inform our financial model and to kind of figure out how likely it was that we could
raise money.
And how popular it was in general.
So what happened here was that see we saw roughly 20 percent of people would actually pull out a credit
card and pay us.
And so I think it was out of 500 people.
Yes if 500 people were the test 233 clicked through so presumably the other ones maybe maybe they don't.
We're not looking for scholarships not something that applies to them.
And then these ones were serious enough to do it.
So in order to be kind of reasonable about this and this was a very hand-selected group of people we
looked for honors it was like an honors college.
A lot of people would transfer into larger colleges that costs more kind of just cut that in half.
And I think that's where we got the ten point thirty.
That's generally a good way of doing it.
Take a number you.
You feel confident about are comparable.
And then just make it harder.
Right.
So when someone looks at that they can see that you're hedging right.
And then and if you can still show that this works even in a worst case scenario that's a lot better
situation than showing the same number you got and then apply it to everything and then having someone
kind of call you out on it.
But regardless we set it up here so you could change it right.
So if you wanted to change this to ten point ten point nine we could.
And if you wanted to look through the system you would see all the numbers are changing.
The next thing we wanted to kind of build an assumption around was the number of schools promoting scholar
pro year.
Now this is a bit of a kind of a Genki calculation here.
The idea again we got to find schools and not promote our system.
So we did a lot of tests.
You know we do a lot of cold emails cold calls and we kind of just summarized how easy it was to get
in contact with people at schools who could send these e-mails out.
And we kind of figured out how long it would take and how many hours it would take because we did this
with about a 20 to 30 schools.
We had a pretty decent idea how long it would take someone.
So we kind of just assumed well if it takes this amount of time and we had someone at first it seemed
dedicated to it and then someone eventually dedicated to it.
Then we kind of just extrapolated this number and the way that we got this is down here.
We had sales assumptions so we assumed that.
I think the starting point was in the three salespeople all the time we made this thing we only had
one.
But then it goes yeah.
So our calculation was they could do 33 in a year.
So at 33 and then we kind of assume that over time how many would we be able to add on that.
Regardless this time this equals this.
And that's how we figured it out three people first year probably at 100.
Now the next assumption is OK well if you add a 100 schools how big are they.
Because you can have a college that is like my college was 7300 people Doubs in college but you can
also have colleges that are gigantic.
I mean 13000 actually is not even that large.
There's some public university systems that are over 100000 So that's a really big variation.
Right.
A hundred tiny colleges or 100 mega colleges.
We don't really know.
Well we did know though is that working with big schools took much longer working with smaller ones
did not take nearly as long.
But you know that was a calculation we try to do later to try to figure out per hour you spent on it.
Which one was more valuable actually into being the bigger schools because bureaucracy is bureaucracy
regardless of how large the school is.
So what we did here was we wanted to show different ways of visualizing the revenue growth based on
how you break down that hundred schools.
We don't really know how to show this so we just kind of said like why don't you get a bunch of scenarios
right so one scenario might be more small schools one might be more medium or much more larger schools
and an equal mix.
And so you can kind of see over here we're showing Let me qualify it as a small schools of the 10000
a medium 10 or 30 and anything over 30 is large.
And again we just kind of did this to set up the investors to gas whatever they wanted.
I mean they might think that this appeals more to medium schools or small schools or they might think
it's only larger schools whatever.
What you will see though is that when you pick larger revenue growth or revenue in general it goes up
quite a bit.
And if you go down here it goes down quite a bit.
So really it's going to be up to them.
But the reason why we did it like this and give them scenarios was because generally someone who's looking
at this is not sophisticated enough to know that.
Well guess so schools are different sizes.
And then I would say well I know exactly you're going to get 90 small and 10 medium or whatever.
I mean they can literally change it if they want to.
We just wanted to make it as simple as possible and also kind of guide them in the direction we thought
was reasonable and also made us look good.
They could actually if they wanted to change it or here and if you can look at these these calculations
these are actually really quite simple to set up really all this sad was.
So if J.J. is scenario so the scenario says more small schools then set this at 25.
If it says more medium schools than set this one here at Bhooter is ze six.
So think it's like 35.
And then if it's equal Maxton set at Z A.
Or is it.
OK here we are it's over.
So it's pulling it over here.
Right.
And so these would be the acquisition breakdowns and a quick reference but it just pulling it over here
and that's how we got that number over here.
It's actually relatively simple.
And then what we have right here is an assumption that maybe we lists of whether the big schools or
small schools maybe we just have a flat rate of how many mega schools we can add because there are not
that many big hundred K plus enrollment schools and you ask there's like 20 or 30 but we didn't really
want to bake that into this because this is only kind of like a one time thing.
It's really time intensive for these ones.
And again we really just didn't know how much bandwidth we'd have to add more of these schools.
So we put that one right here so this just gets added to the whole pie right now in here we put subscription
renewal rate if SAS company looked at this and they're like wow only 30 percent of people were read
up after a year they'd say that's terrible.
Like 70 percent churn is terrible.
But in our situation yeah.
I mean it doesn't really make sense that you're going have 90 percent retention if the whole idea is
that you apply for scholarships.
So you either get them and leave the system or you age out of it like you go to college or you go to
grad school and you don't need it anymore.
Or a million other reasons you didn't like it.
So we just had a lot of things working against us in terms of our subscription rate problem.
You could make an argument that we probably should have gone with the subscription rate.
I would not try to argue with that.
I guess we're going to cover just a little bit more and then I'll see you in the next lecture we'll
we'll round out this assumption table.
This is actually where the majority of the explanation is.
This is really where a lot of the work and thinking kind of was put into this.
The last thing I will kind of cover over here is we kind of just put some basic assumptions over here
to let people kind of toggle them as they feel appropriate.
So direct cost assumptions like credit card processing fee 2.1 five.
I don't know who charges 2.1 five anymore.
It's usually over 30 percent.
Even Squire I think is above this but we can just set it so that Gerri whatever you know we run into
investors you are convinced that your processing is going to be 6 percent and then other ones just couldn't
care less.
So we set this up so they can change it for whatever they feel like.
Then we put this which is cost to acquire a school.
So we just assume that we'd have like a direct cost associated with getting schools.
And it really was a catch all a lot of times you just know there's other expenses involved you're going
to want to map it out.
You don't understand it well enough.
So you just kind of gave this blanket it was like we had a budget for collateral design flights kind
of things that are associated with making a sale.
It didn't necessarily I don't think it applied to their salaries the salesman salaries might.
But that's a general kind of a technique you'll see where we don't know it.
We don't really know if it's terribly important if we break this down all the way and every single part
that you pay for every parking ticket you get parking to go talk to their financial aid office or whatever.
So we just got to use a blanket and this is just contingency like you saw Simon do several times but.
Yeah.
And so again you can let anyone change this to their heart's pleasure by saying we've put subscriber
maintenance subscription.
So again if I'm using an application as a SAS tool it doesn't really cost us anything to keep you on
the system how ever it will cost time and money to have customer support and maintenance.
So something breaks and they want to talk to support.
Well you know that's labor.
Right.
So we just figured well we have some direct cost assumptions let's just assume per month per user the
use of something like $2 right because in general maybe 5 percent of people you support and all the
other ones don't.
And so those five pretty much all your costs but then we spread it across you get something like this
again.
People can change it as they see fit.
OK guys soon as we're getting around a little bit long on this lecture I will catch up in the next lecture
and we'll kind of round this out and then start moving on into the individual models and graphs.
Okay.
See that.