Hey All right let's get started.
Now what you were looking at first is just some brainstorm ideas that I had before I started building
any models sometimes just gathering your notes on what you know about how you want to model it.
Business model revenues expenses overhead anything that is just things that you want to make sure you
remember as you build it you can put it in a brainstorm worksheet just to make sure that you remember
them.
OK so once you have that one of the first things that's easier to build that is start up related assumptions.
Now for a start like this where we're going to be converting some space year you got to furnish some
space.
We may want to break out some of the startup costs differently.
So we'll break out.
For instance the buildout for the space and how we're going to furnish all the spaces.
Right.
So this right here is we get the total size of the facility and then how are we to allocate the space
based on these breakdowns.
So then we have the square footage.
Now that means we'll have different number of units for some of them right.
We may have two big rooms and we have multiple number of breakout rooms maybe some other bigger common
space and then some offices and reception area.
OK.
Now the build out for each of these spaces might be different.
Right because a big room that's just filled with chairs you don't really need to put a light in there
but break rooms.
You probably don't need a lot in there either just some tables and chairs and some other things but
offices and common space.
You've got to make it a little bit nicer.
There's going to be more of fixtures that are going to cost a little bit more.
So the build out for that space might be a little bit more.
So that's why we're going to break out the build out costs separately and so we can get a sense of how
each of the space is going to cost in terms of getting it to the point where you can start renovating
it.
Now for this one we're going to assume that they're taking a long term lease on this.
And so they're leasing it and they're they're putting down a secure deposit and then they're doing some
of their own build.
Ok for those costs.
Now in terms of furnishing the spaces one way to do something like this is to create a little grid a
matrix like this.
OK.
So on the vertical axis we have the things that you can fill any of the spaces with.
So I have large table small table chairs desk chairs projector TV and just all sorts of goodies and
left a few other spaces for miscellaneous things.
And then on the horizontal axes we have the different spaces right.
Then what we can do is we can just put in the number of how many of each of these things we want to
put in there.
So a large table we don't need it in the classrooms but we want to in the breakout rooms each breakout
room is going to have one large table and three small tables.
So that's how we do that.
And here this is just the per cost of a per unit cost of all of these.
So then from that once we have all of these puts in there we can calculate the total furnishing costs
for each of the rooms and the way we do that is we basically take a product of these right the product
of each of these and then sum it up.
So we do the same product and then we multiply by how many number of units of those spaces there.
So it's these ones we're classrooms and we only have one.
So we're just going to leave it as is.
But if we change the number of units it would be different.
It would cost a little bit more because we have to furnish more.
So we see this come in a lot more for the breakout rooms right.
It costs a lot less to to furnish one of them but because there's 15 of them the total cost is going
to be more than furnishing the other spaces.
We have something similar for the common and open spaces because we're putting a lot more chairs a more
big tables and such.
Okay.
So based on these assumptions we can have total cost of furnishing.
Okay so this here this worksheet then tells us how much we need for build out and how much we need for
furnishing and just kind of getting the space ready.
Next what we can do is kind of look at the actual startup related costs.
Right.
So I see that the build out and the furniture.
So this is not quite true anymore.
All right.
So the build out and the furniture and equipment or something like that is pulled from our build out
and furniture furnishing worksheet.
But then there are other things that are going to required for doing this kind of business.
You still need to get permits you may need to get some architecture and engineering to help you you
know make sure that you're doing everything to compliance as well as it looks nice and you're going
to need some initial marketing budget.
Once you have the space ready to really launch this thing you may be paying someone to help you build
a nice web site.
You're paying your first month's rent and security deposit you're getting a you know some setting up
some other expenses that you need to pay throughout the launch period and you know you're getting some
funds ready for early hiring and training you've got to hire associates and train them and get them
ready before you actually have the opening.
So you're going to have to pay them for that and maybe you want to set aside some additional construction
contingency.
OK.
So then when we add it all up then we have these totals start up costs there.
Now one thing about the start of kaso is that's not all that you're going to need in order to get things
going.
You're going to need some working capital capital that you're going to need to keep paying for the lights
to stay on and the utilities and the wages before your revenue starts to outpace it and you're able
to break even and start making a profit.
So we're going to revisit this at the very end because we're going to calculate this at the very end.
It requires us to actually model everything else out first before we can calculate what these are.
OK now what's this stuff over here.
Well this stuff over here is just to help us understand the timing of when these startup costs occur.
They don't all happen on day one.
They happen over time and some of them happen first before the other.
You're going to have to make sure you're permitted and you did do all your Any stuff before you can
actually do your construction or rehab.
Right.
So we're looking at these periods in and threw out just means it happens throughout all of this all
the permitting construction and the early launch.
OK.
So what we then do is all right for each of these timings we've got to determine how long they last
and in what order.
Right.
So we're going to have a permitting may take three months and then after it's done then we go into a
construction or rehab period where you're doing all the build out and making sure everything's furnish.
And then after that there's three months of launch that's when you know we're actually spending these
amounts of money.
Right.
So this will allow us to model out when these expenses are going to happen.
And in the next lecture we're going to see how we use the timing for modeling also for some of the revenue
related things.