All right.
Now before I go over the model for this one I want you to download the business plan that's associated
with this model.
The model and this business plan is actually one of my former clients and I have permission to share
this and make it a case study for this course.
Something I did years ago for a client and this is the business plan they helped him put together.
Now you know you have to read everything but definitely browse through it to get an idea of the business
model itself.
Definitely look through some of the photos and the idea is to have these golf simulators.
You see the gentleman at the bottom you're actually using real clubs or real balls and you're hitting
into a high definition screen that has an image that's projected to it kind of like a video game.
You know if you've ever played we in there's the Tiger Woods game where you're using the remote controller
Well instead of the remote controller using real golf balls with real golf clubs and after you hit it
when the ball impacts the screen the real ball drops.
But the virtual ball keeps flying.
So it's a pretty interesting experience actually I went to actually play it just so I can get a better
understanding of this technology.
And it's even better now today than it was years ago.
So this overall business plan if you just skim through it I'll give you a better idea of what the models
are trying to do.
All of the inputs all of the analysis that's in this business plan came from the model that we're going
to go over in just a bit.
You know the model talks about a business case that involves these simulators or the stations that have
these golf simulators some are going to be semi-private and some are going to be like a VIP private
in clothes just give you an idea.
The one on the bottom is more of the semi private Stalley.
It can be made for four people.
There's little barstools there.
So you know a normal foursome can play here and play through the rounds and it would be pretty know
fun there they actually are able to get through an entire round in about two hours since the virtual
game.
You don't have to actually walk to the bar.
Everybody's ready to be able to hit right away.
And then the bar stalls there is meant for food and drinks to be served.
The more private one gets for larger crowds you can fit you know a larger group of people in there.
And for some they may be even planning to have an additional television where some other people can
play other video games or do other things and other activities while also having the golf simulator
there.
So this will give you a pretty good idea of what kind of business model looks like where they're going
to generate their revenues from.
Right.
So there's these simulators in these stations and then there's food and drink as well.
More top of style.
Ok now I'm going to go into the model so you can see what the model looks like.
All right.
So here is the model.
This model looks quite a bit different from the other models we've gone through.
There's a few things here.
It is a bigger more dense model.
There's a lot of moving parts so it takes awhile to digest so I'm just going to kind of walk you through
the parts in this lecture and then we're going to start going into how it's organized and with trying
to do now just like the other case studies.
We're not going to be able to go in and explain every single formula but I think understanding what
we were trying to do with the model in the logic then you could actually go in there and see how it's
implemented because you know what it's actually doing.
First things first.
These yellow highlighted sheets are where the inputs are.
This is where all the mean assumptions all the assumptions around pretty much the whole entire business
structure is put this one in just a separate page that was used to capture furnishing assumptions and
all these blue ones were summerise pages that were meant to publish to the report and were meant for
sharing.
This first one here was just some data that was gathered from a client to get a sense of what the golfing
household market was in the target market.
They were looking at which was Los Angeles at the time.
Now all these green tabs here these are all of the calculations sheets calculating the different things
that are labeled here.
So there's several different sources of revenue there's simulator rental revenue food and drink revenue
and then some other miscellaneous revenue.
And then from there we're looking at some cash flow calculations this is looking at what the cash flow
looks like when we factor in the startup expenses ramp up for revenues to see what the actual capital
maximum cash outlay is right to determine what the need in terms of capital would be.
And then there's one for an income statement just because there's a lot of capital that's going to be
depreciated.
We did this to get a sense of what the taxes might look like and some other calculations these this
worksheet was to find out when the business would break even and which month it would break even.
And if there were investors how long it would take to return the equity to the investors given how much
equity was placed into it.
So based on the assumptions however was drawn out.
She would tell the investors have you invest this much and if you agree with the underlying assumptions
about the operations of this business then this is how long it would take us to return your equity back.
OK.
Now let's go through some of the core assumptions.
This one the furnishing this is pretty straightforward.
Right so we have different spaces in that business and we're just basically itemizing What are the main
items.
How much the cost and what was the total cost for the likely furniture and furnishing that we would
need.
It looks like the budget that we estimate at the time was about 20000.
Now the main assumptions page this one has all of the assumptions.
The reason we did this at the time instead of splitting into multiple sections was it would have so
many sections and it was really difficult to see all the assumptions same place.
So we decided to put it all on the same page and just put them in different sections so it was easier
to kind of go back and forth between the assumptions.
So the top part here is making assumptions around the startup costs and there's an additional distinction.
We decided that there may be two phases of the startup.
Just in case like we the one of the options remember was we're looking at a space for the client that
like a larger space and he would open with fewer with half of the lounge spots first and there would
be some additional space that he could then expand into.
So he was kind of planning for some growth but then he wouldn't need to borrow as much.
And if he was right about the revenues and the utilizations and then he would be able to get the self-finance
the growth into that space.
So that's what this part is all about.
Here is some financing for the simulator's the seller or the manufacturer of the simulators.
They were actually providing seller financing.
They wanted people to buy it.
They were kind of expensive.
So they were providing some financing and they were approaching these terms at the time.
Now here in the middle section These are the operating assumptions and looking at assumptions around
what are the operating hours.
How many days versus a week nights and daytime hours versus nighttime hours.
Because you're going to be charging different rates the time rates versus the nighttime rates the amount
of space in-house to add up the payroll.
So this is the amount of folks that they would need to hire at the time the minimum wage rate was lower
at the time than it is now in California.
So this was years back but the logic still makes sense here.
So the thing here was initially that he was thinking about doing a sauf launch.
So not a huge grand opening but kind of slowly open testing's out with you know kind of private invite
and then start doing some advertising after they kind of get comfortable with things.
So this is the assumptions for the first three months and then these are the assumptions for after that.
All right.
And then some other assumptions around office supplies marketing expenses and other other assumptions
run insurance and worker's comp and some of it may be having a third party account Accounting Service
to do the books for them.
Some other cost related assumptions.
The there is maintenance that was anticipated for The Sims.
So there's going to be small simulators and large simulators large simulators actually cost more than
the small simulators think these were supposed to be like 45000 now now this part right here is the
cell section is about the pricing and the utilization of the simulators.
To think about it in two ways right.
The the some the semi private stations all you need is a smaller simulator so they're going to be smaller
and they're semi private So you're not going to be on charge as much.
And then the large simulator that you're going to put in the private space the VIP room you're going
to be able to charge more.
Now pricing wise can I have to think about weekday versus weekend rates.
And then also night time versus daytime rates.
So that's what all those rates are.
And for some I was thinking about having memberships to encourage some people who are regulars give
them extra discounts to give them an extra deal for the private simulator or the other simulator.
So we're testing different rates.
I think at the time we assume that for the private VIP one there was no discount given for the members
the regular rooms the members would get a discount.
Grand opening assumptions here which is basically assuming that the first three months there's going
to be a discount on the rates you know just to encourage people to try it out more.
I hear the membership assumptions how much it costs in terms of the fees you know how many members are
adding per month.
And then what the stabilize membership count would be.
And then some sort of annual renewal rate then see we have some other assumptions here around the this
is additional income.
So you know some people don't have clubs when they bring it to this facility.
Then they can rent clubs at a certain rate.
This was here for depreciation for tax purposes for the income statement and this one is just looking
at the ratio the number of weekdays versus weekend days in a given month.
So this whole section here now is looking at a totally different part of the business.
This is looking at the Food and Drink part of the business.
It's one of the ways we're looking at it was he wanted one side to be pretty much almost a standalone
restaurant that serves top of style food and beer and wine kind of like a mini sports bar.
That would be geared towards Gough's TVs that would show a lot of golf and things like that Golf Channel
and his thought was there's me some people there is going to hang out.
They're not going to play and so there may be some people that will come in just for the food.
So I wanted to make that distinction and look at the revenue potential from both but those kinds of
potential customers.
This last part is some assumptions around some miscellaneous sales.
So like there's merchandising there maybe like lessons for the unrented hours.
So if a simulator is not being used by somebody could be potentially used by an instructor would use
it to give private lessons because then these kinds of simulators actually gives what's what are called
launch measurements for when people hit and when they hit a ball it measures things like swing speed
the launch angle.
All of those things that are useful for an instructor to help the students who are trying to learn and
improve their swing.
So it's actually a great learning tool as well and they thought maybe there's an opportunity to do some
of these kinds of to take advantage of these open slots by working with local golf instructors giving
them certain dedicated time slots where they could teach and it would then they would just charge the
instructors 25 bucks an hour.
Well you know typically those instructors for private lessons are charging over 100 bucks an hour.
Also the gaming experience playing on the simulators they can actually be programmed to show like a
five or 10 second advertisement in between certain number of holes.
And so he was thinking about that see.
That would be significant or not if there was enough customers that came in you know just enough ads
where it could make some revenue but not so often where it annoys the experience so it can be set like
as in like loading time between when it loads for the next hole.
OK so those are the assumptions.
Now in the next lectures we're going to show you how it was structured and how it is actually modeled
out to reflect all of these assumptions.