OK we are back.
All right let's look back at our user X model and apply the new concept.
We are now masters of customer segmentation.
OK let's refresh your works.
Is our version of We work and we're planning to run our office space on both strict and flexible terms
to all sorts of small businesses and freelancers.
We rent big space we convert it to something you know with like the water tanks with the cucumbers in
it and then we make sure that we have at least eight different types of African coffee.
The idea here with this business is that in order to capture the largest group of paying members we're
going to offer different types of spaces.
So Miguel what you call a hot desk or I think in the Excel we call it a shared desk and some will basically
want a cheap semipermanent office for their company.
OK on your own Think this through how would you segment your customers slash users.
Well first off let's answer a quick question.
Do we have both users and customers.
Well it's possible that we offer something like 30 day free trial and for that first month they're considered
users for our sake and what I think is actually more of the norm and this co-working space is that we're
not going to have a free trial or at least a lengthy one.
We can just pretend that everyone that walks in the door pays some kind of dough.
So how in this scenario would we segment it.
Well Pat yourself on the back and if you didn't just blurt something out like income bracket or the
brand of the car that the customer drives we have to figure out what questions we're trying to answer.
And we don't really care what car they drive.
Well since this isn't a real scenario we can just hypothesize.
Since we're talking about projections for a proposed business right now we can assume our goals with
our model are probably a little bit different than if we were already in the thick of things trying
to figure out what's going on.
Let's go through three possible scenarios to give you some context to play around with let's say in
order to start this business.
We wanted to get a loan from a bank.
Is this something a bank would finance.
Yes actually it probably is something and you probably wouldn't have that hard of a time.
Banks care about having assets they can seize in case you missed your bills.
That's probably their biggest sticking point.
When you ask for money from them but past that what's a bank probably going to care about the most member
banks just give you money and you pay them back a percentage of the amount you loaned them over time.
They don't care if you grow into a billion dollar company or a million dollar company.
What they do care about though is when you're going to break even.
Because that's when you can start paying them back in earnest.
So if I was trying to figure that out trying to break even what might I segment my customers by what
segmentation gets me closer to figuring out that answer.
Now remember coworking spaces are basically miniature leases and like any monthly plan you can pay monthly
or you can pay up front.
Well I would guess that a lot of customers will want to pay each month and a lot of them will want to
pay per year specially if there is a discount.
So if we segment by that we can then see what the proportion of the two is and how if we focus towards
one versus the other which one could potentially get us to break even faster we can do that because
we isolate the two.
Now the best thing about annual buyers is they give you a wad of cash up front.
So we're probably going to be focusing on the upfront buyers that gets us there a lot faster.
Really helpful to segment them that way if you're trying to figure that out.
OK now scenario number two right we're not doing the bank loan thing anymore.
Let's imagine now we're instead talking to venture capital and trying to raise a million dollars to
get this thing started.
VC on the other hand is not a loan.
It's equity.
They basically own a percentage of your company for probably more or the same amount of money you'd
get from a bank.
Now what's a VC going to care about.
Are they gonna care about assets.
No not really.
Actually they rarely care about assets VCs if you're not aware are really the way they work is they're
just designed to look for big payoffs spread out over a portfolio of companies.
So I'm a venture capitalist I invest in 99 companies 99 of my companies all just fail returning nothing
to me that's bad for me.
But if I gave one more investment and that one investment turned into Facebook guess what I'm the best
venture capitalist in the land.
I crushed it.
So maybe you can guess what question might we want to answer for them.
They're primarily going to care about how big you can grow and potentially how fast no sense in them
investing in 100 companies or 50 of them.
Literally cannot grow large enough to pay off the losses from the other ones.
So there are a lot of ways that we could split this.
But what's at least one way of segmenting our customers such that we can show the possibility to replicate
this process again many ways actually to do that.
So don't blame me if you copy this and your your venture capital pitch doesn't go very well but this
is one way we can do it.
So what I would propose is why not segment users by location.
The assumption is you'll do multiple cities.
Right.
So if you list them out by city you can easily see the profit potential of each group and then naturally
you can tell hey there's a lot of other cities that are not on this map.
That's a very easy one to do.
To show look how much money I made in this one spot.
Now multiply that by 5000.
All right now the last scenario let's say we were deciding if we could personally swing this with our
own money bootstrap it.
Well in that case maybe we want to know the breakeven like the bank situation or maybe you want to see
how small we can start this and still make it profitable relatively quickly.
If it were the second option we're thinking hey why do we need a 50000 square foot space when that might
legitimately bankrupt me.
Why not instead get a 5000 square foot space to start off with and then use the cash flow to expand.
Well in that case savvy entrepreneur we might care about how our customers and specifically how much
space our customers take up permanent offices will take dedicated space that you can't use for anything
else whereas the shared desk folk don't need assigned space.
But you know always you can't oversell that type of customer or you won't have enough space in any given
day for them and they get mad.
In this case maybe you can calculate how much square footage each customer type might take and then
you just segment by the regular user type share desk versus private desk versus small office versus
large office.
That way we can focus on how much space we need and how much money we can make per the space by adjusting
the way we focus on private offices versus share desks.
OK so you see there are a million different ways to segment any given scenario.
Usually you would segment these in the most vanilla way you can.
And then if there are specific questions you need to sawle then break out a separate sheet.
You do your separate but more obscure segmentation to answer these separate but not main questions.
It highly depends on the situation you're in.
All right guys I will see you in the next Lochore.