Hey welcome back.
We did the single salesperson economics and you were able to see that there's going to be some more
expenses from the person it's going to outpace their bookings initially.
There's a general trend where you're going to have some losses in terms of investing in a salesperson
first and then over time you can earn that back and then gain a profit.
Right so now we're going to look at how can we take that process and build it into a revenue model for
the company.
So the only difference here is let's say we have the timing here but now we have a sales team.
Okay.
And the sales team are going to grow it kind of like the headcounts that we've done before.
Right I say we're going to start off with three sales people starting in month 11 and then we're going
to add two every two months until we get to a sales team of 25.
Okay.
So if you see this to the right here we're going to see a growing growing and growing until we get to
25.
Okay that's what that's doing right there.
Now why in month 11.
You know we have the start up worksheet here is very similar to what you've done before so I'm not going
to go over it too much but let's say that there's an initial development that took nine months is a
beta maybe you know period.
And then there's an official launch that has a big marketing push that takes over the course of a month.
And that timing is coming here.
So we hired the sales team though right around here during beta right.
So maybe initially just the founding team kind of does their own sales or with the early customers clients
that trying it out but then they start bringing in sales teams when they want to really get ready and
ramp up for the launch or we can change that.
That's just what the assumption here is.
Okay.
So then what we got to do then is we basically need to do the same thing that we did for the per person
economics here where we had we tracked their annual contract values and then adjusted for attrition
converted it to monthly recurring revenue adjusted with churn to get the actual monthly recurring revenues
which is what is actually built and collected right so that's your real revenue.
We did it for one person.
So what would it look like for a whole team.
Now this is where conceptually it's exactly the same as what we did but executing it in the model a
little bit harder.
Okay let me explain why we are going to have to track the sales team by cohort of which month they came
in or were higher.
That's because every cohort has that learning curve that we did right.
This activity curve and they're going to have their own performance straw.
So it's all staggered somebody who's joining in months you know two months later is going to have a
different curve.
They're not going to just suddenly be 100 percent right.
So each cohort has to be tracked separately.
If I'm modeling this out for five years for 60 months Well guess what we're going to track it for 60
cohorts.
You see that.
So what I'm doing here then is I'm tracking the head count by each cohort.
This is the month where they were hired.
OK so you know we didn't start hiring until the 11th month so guess what.
We hired three people in the 11th month.
All right.
So that's why that cohort size stays at three for the love month.
OK.
Now once we have the actual head count by cohort so mean squeeze that down because that's what that
you know here's the total total headcount.
We got to make sure it matches right.
So it does match.
So we didn't do anything wrong here.
Remember that we try to check as often as we can in our in our models to make sure it's accurate.
OK.
Another modeling practice sometimes you know I have the month up here but because when I'm looking at
all these cells sometimes I just want to put it in the middle as well it's easier to access so I can
refer to this line instead of having this row all the way back to the top.
It's choice.
You don't have to do that but if you start building in these building these kinds of models where you're
starting to get too close to a thousand rolls it's going to come in a little handy when you do that.
So what do we do first.
Well let's look at total new bookings right.
The annual contract values first because that's what we did.
We got it.
Hey what was the annual contract value that was booked in that month.
But we got to do it by cohort.
So here we see that each cohort We're tracking the annual contract value of that cohort so that cohort
add more people to first one had three right.
So these could be higher versus the other ones where they're at each of the other cohorts.
Every two months apart.
And they were staggered so every next cohort is a little bit later.
Right.
Two months kind of delayed in terms of their productivity and reaching their full sales schedule.
But after a while they're all going to kind of reach the same level when they're stabilized.
Okay.
So that is what we're win here we have the annual contract value.
And once we have the annual contract value let's look at sales attrition so we can do the sales attrition
again.
We had a attrition schedule too.
Maybe they're more likely to quit in the first month that they join.
And a lot less likely.
You know after 12 months or something.
Right.
So we can't just have a global attrition we have to have attrition schedule that follows each cohort.
You'll see it here.
So basically doing the same thing but I'm tracking it with each row now for each cohort and then for
that after we account for the attrition.
Now we have the actual net bookings right.
So that's just the sum of these two.
OK.
So then we have net bookings but it's now by cohort we tracked it by cohort.
So then when we have that number we can calculate the total new monthly recurring revenue that's coming
in from that month and it's going to be tracked by cohort as well.
So you see that for each of them that is the net bookings the annual contract value divided by 12 because
that's what's actually collected even though that's the contract value that was booked that month.
So now we have that.
But again if we want to track the correct revenues we don't just look at the new monthly recurring revenue
that's coming in from that month.
We also got to then add in the monthly recurring revenue from all the prior bookings right.
And we do the same.
We can track that for each cohort get.
So we have all the prior month bookings for each of the cohorts here.
So we have something like this where you have a lot of cohorts to track.
Generally you're not modeling it for more than five years out.
A lot of you can probably do just two to three years out.
But I did this year to show you that you know it can be done.
You don't really need to go farther than this.
So you know about 60 cohorts which one for each month is going to be more than enough for ninety nine
point nine percent of you guys.
OK so now we have the new bookings from that month plus the prior Billings right for the monthly recurring
revenue.
And then we also factor in churn churn for each of the cohorts.
Then when we hit once we have that we can do the total month of recurring revenues which is what's actually
billed because it is exactly the same rates what I want you to do if you're if you're really looking
into this is to look at the formulas for these.
Okay.
So for all of these big blocks squares here I only put the formulas in the first.
Basically this first left corner here.
And once I have the formula I copy and paste it for you know all of the cohorts all the way to all 16
months.
So just look at this first formula here.
And when you do that you can figure out how it's calculated.
By now you've seen quite a bit rate you see in quite a few formulas if you want me to explain every
single formula here is going to extend the time for this lecture for by a lot.
So I don't want to I don't want to get into the very specifics because you can just dive into them.
The formulas are actually all there for you to look at.
That is the revenue actually you know conceptually is pretty simple right.
You know we took the economics of the single salesperson but we just applied it to an entire hiring
schedule for a whole sales team.
Now next we're going to look at the expense side of things.