Hey welcome back to the course.
Now we're looking at the expenses sheet here for the expenses sheet.
We want to track the main thing is the number of hours that the customers are actually going to be using
at the offices right for each hour they're going to be using at the co-working spaces we're going to
have to pay our partners our co-working space partners some dollar amount that we're going to owe them.
Right.
So in order to do that first thing we're going to do is look at the maximum number of hours that are
available per month for the Explorer it's 10 for the creators 40 for the luminary it's unlimited but
really it's not that unlimited right.
There's still a limited number of hours per month in the given month.
So we're just going to make an assumption around what that is.
And I think right here I'm assuming that there's five days a week times 12 hours per day times four
weeks per hour per month so about 240 total hours in a co-working space.
We can make that and more we can make it 300 hours.
You know if you're trying to include some evenings and weekend hours that are available as well.
So you know if we make it 300 hours that's fine.
And then the average utilization that's going to be more important.
Right.
We're going to have to make an assumption around here of those available hours that somebody could use.
On average how much are they going to be using for the explorers.
They're probably going to be using a pretty high utilization since they only have 10 hours.
Right.
You may even assume that they're going to just use it all up for the creators of 40 hours.
So froggery pretty high.
But for the luminaries you know they're going to be going there on a regular basis even if they are
going you know 40 hours a week.
Like full work week every week they're really looking at 160 hours right.
So maybe forty five percent of 300 hours.
So we don't need to know exactly what it is but we just want to make sure we account for that kind of
information right now.
Now we still need to track the hours that are used by guests as well.
Right.
So zero hours doesn't matter so 100 percent utilization of 0 0.
But if we change that in the future then we have this here so we can the model can account for that.
Now for the creators there's five hours.
So we can assume that maybe they'll use most or all of it.
Right.
And something similar for the luminaries in terms of the guests hours.
Okay.
So we have these assumptions now we're going to be able to factor that in later.
Now in order to do the right kind of timing for the expenses first thing we do is we've got to look
at the startup costs first.
Right.
So we we have the start schedule that we did before with the timing and then we have the categorization
of the start startup expenses by when it was going to happening during the development period during
the beta during the actual launch period or some of the costs that are happening throughout the whole
start up phase.
We have all the startup expenses here that are being spent and then that's our initial cash outflow.
Next we can actually start thinking about these hours and utilization.
So well first you know let's let's do an assumption around the costs maybe we can negotiate.
You know it's two bucks an hour for each customer that uses the co-working space initially but we think
as we get more and more people to use it and grow our user base over time maybe we can get that rate
down.
So this allows us to do that you know how to do that by now from looking at some of the similar things
that we did on the revenue worksheet.
Okay.
So this all this does is it calculates an initial price or costs per hour and then over time it reduces
it to our stabilize rate which was we're setting it at 125 and are now from there.
The next thing we want to do is we want to look at user.
Right.
We've got the cumulative customer count from our revenue side we looked at how many customers we have
in any given category in any given month after factoring in attrition and any movements in between those
kind of the final month figures.
So from there we also can calculate the percentage that we're bringing gas.
Right.
And then the customer hours that are use.
Okay.
So that comes from looking at the utilization we have the utilization times the maximum hours times
how many people were in how many customers are there.
So then we have the hours of that were used in that give them a total.
We also have guest hours that are used right from these free guest hours plus the we're pulling something
from the revenue side here which is plus the overage guests hours that was calculated.
So that still costs us money.
So we've got to factor that in.
So we have both customer hours and the total guest hours both free and overage guests hours then we
have the total hours when you combine the two.
So now that we have these total hours we then can calculate the total cost of office usage.
Right.
So we already have the cost calculated the total hours will just be this costs times the total hours
use which will give us the total cost here.
Okay.
So this is a total off cost of the office usage by tier of customer.
Next thing we can think about was the advertising costs.
So we have a certain amount of ad impressions that are coming in.
So per CPM right.
That was coming from the front.
And then if we have a CPM schedule maybe initially were not that good at it were paying more and over
time we are better at it were getting better rates were more targeted than you know it can go down over
time and you may be able to save money but maybe you already can be the opposite.
You can do either.
Okay.
If it gets more expensive you just put the more expensive rate here and it will update accordingly from
there.
It's just the total ad impressions in the thousands times the cost per CPM that you are experiencing
right.
So then we have the cost per CPM now then we can also look at the acquisition costs full well for the
users we were spending on the ad so the acquisition costs is calculated right because were putting the
advertising costs there then how many customers we require per month divided by the total ad spend we
can have the cost per acquisition.
Now for partnerships its going to look something similar right for partnerships.
Maybe we're going to look at had hey how quickly are we going to be able to grow partnerships initially
we're going to be able to grow faster because your growth rate you're at a lower starting point so your
growth rate is going to be higher.
But over time maybe you have a lot more units you're going to grow much slower on a monthly basis.
Okay.
So we may start something where we're growing 10 percent a month and then we then get all the way down
to just growing 1 percent a month.
You know after three years in let's say we start off with a hundred initial locations partnership location
that's right.
So then starting with 100 that you sign on on day 1 and you can keep growing it right.
We can grow this user or this partnership while you're in development you should be building your partnerships
as you're doing your development and really you know growing the business right.
So you know you could do that or you can start smaller and start a little bit later as well for this
one.
We're assuming it starts early and then you're building over time.
So then by the time you launch your you have have a little bit more than you started with.
Okay.
And then after the launch it starts to slow down again in terms of its growth rate and we would grow
more slowly in terms of the partnerships now the partnerships are more involved you're going to have
to talk a little bit more.
So it may cost you more or you may have to hire someone to make all these calls and have multiple calls
to in order to convince a partner to sign on to be part of your network.
So we're going to just make an assumption around the acquisition costs here.
OK so every time we sign someone up then that's a new costs for the company after that.
Well we didn't have labor rights some other overhead So here we're using that same structure that we
did before we were tackling some of the headcount for different categories.
So maybe initially just two founders we don't have any of that.
We may have a late third founder ad and maybe some of if you have sales and marketing later some more
engineers to help with the coding so that the founders aren't doing as much later.
Whatever you are deciding in terms of your need for your team to build this.
OK.
So then we arrive that the headcount and then from the headcounts we can then also look at the schedule
of the comp..
So maybe the founders are willing to take a haircut at the beginning just to make sure they can extend
the runway over time.
Then they increase their compensation.
Okay.
So maybe the founders will increase the competition a little bit longer before they actually do that.
Okay then with the compensation that's calculated and we can also look at other kinds of overhead.
So we have the per person per month costs.
You know we have this legal retainer if you want to factor that in.
And then any other monthly costs.
So this one is structured in such a way like to start in a certain month.
You know we may not want to have a lot of stuff kicking in yet.
Right.
So this is where you can add these other monthly costs.
Now once we have that we pretty much have all of the expenses and we have the revenues that was done.
So then in the next lecture we can put it together and see what it would look like based on our assumptions.