It Hey welcome back.
All right.
We're going to look at the cost side of things now.
So one of the things that we've got to do on the cost side of things is because it happens before we
actually open the grand opening date.
So we looked at sales.
Everything starts on month 1 August 1st.
Now for the expenses we're looking at the build out before that.
So this one I kind of did it backwards where we have Month 1 when it actually launches but then we start
working backwards that way.
Okay.
Now in terms of revenues we know that this is pulling in from the revenue side.
All those sales that are coming in.
Right.
Doesn't start happening until it opens.
So then we can look at okay so that's the sales and then any other taxes and other things that we need
to pay.
So that's all on the cash flow kind of in the then we started looking at other expenses all the cash
that's going out.
We've got some basic operating expenses payroll and some rent and other things that start to kick in
right like supplies marketing and all these other things we know you're not doing marketing while you're
building it out really you're not doing too much you might be doing some of that you could do a little
bit earlier but you want to do a slow launch right.
The first part so probably not going to do too much and then he would let word of mouth do that here.
Now there's something in this line and when you look at the years this is a revenue shift.
And then here is expense shifter and expense multiplier.
What that is is actually something coming from summary page.
It's one of the things that I just want to let you see is a summary page is a summary of what all the
projected revenues are operating expenses the net operating income for years 1 through 5 debt service
coverage ratio and all over the debt service on the sims.
When it's break even.
All of this is really great here it gives us an idea and here's the breakdown of revenue coming from
CMS versus coming from food and drink rights.
It gives a summary but by building in something called a revenue or expense if you get something like
this what if we increase revenues by 5 percent what would it look like.
So this makes it very easy to adjust changes at the summary level.
This is a global shift in the revenue and this is a global shift in the expenses.
So you can kind of make that adjustment if nothing changes the revenue.
But if expenses suddenly get 5 percent more expensive right thing you see the operating senses change
and the like goes lower.
So that is something that is actually very useful and it's quite easy to do because you can do that
at the very end of all your calculations once you have are able to sum everything up and have these
aggregate calculations for certain things for revenue or expenses into this global Shiff increases or
decreases it.
And so you see how it changes your overall calculations based on that.
So all right going back to this.
So when we have all the expenses here.
These are expenses and then we're looking at really our cash flow we also got to look at our startup
costs right.
When are we spending the startup.
So here here are all the start of base expenses of when they're happening.
And then the startup costs that are happening right now for those of you that are looking at this I
have a preference to primarily work with numbers that are just smaller so don't take up as much room
and some of the models we use just the regular numbers.
So this one is what I do personally is if it's going to be in bigger numbers or on thousands or just
working single digit numbers like this and just I know that these are all in thousands.
It just takes up less space on the screen.
Now you also see that you know I don't really format too much of these calculations sheets because this
is just for me an entrepreneur.
It's not being shared so much for investors.
But you know these are going to be formatted easier for reading and digestion.
Right.
So your calculation sheets it's just got to be clear you gotta know what you're doing.
You don't have to make it super pretty.
All right so once we have that now this this other part here is just looking at hey if it's being if
they're taking the equity investment and keeping track of that for the investors and then we're pain
that investors back what does it look like.
Right.
This part here is about treating the cash where there is a business account and actual checking account
for the business because in reality when the business makes money it doesn't magically gets distributed
to everybody right.
It's got to be held somewhere.
And and it would be distributed at different times and actually designated times.
So the best way to calculate the return of equity to investors is to actually calculate when they get
the cash.
They don't get it instantaneously every month when business cash comes in.
It has to be determined when it actually happens.
So that's what this is for.
This is if there's debt there additional debt that's being borrowed like a business loan.
This is later debt that we talked about in the front end and it's once you put all that together we'll
have net cash flow right net cash flow and then when we take the cumulative cash position then we know
what our max cash need would be.
And then we can see what that funding would be needed.
And then based on those figures there we can look at what the each year's aggregate figures look like
for revenue and splitting it between Sym and food drink revenue.
Operating expenses you know on debt payments what they look like what the is then this one is the income
sheet just to see if we calculated it factored in taxes with the depreciation what it would look like
what the Buddha would look like.
All right so there you go.
That's the cost side of things.
And and the next one will let's look at how it is summarized.