Hey welcome back to the course and this lecture talk about the paper use business model.
This is where a customer will pay for a product or service every time they actually use it.
So think back to your first experience with iTunes when you found a song that you like 99 cents and
you pay for it.
If you didn't want to buy anything then you didn't pay for it.
So there are a lot of business models that are like this where it's on a pay per use basis at least
starting out.
And then they may evolve into something a little bit more complicated.
So in this lecture we're going to look at a pay per use model for a business where there is two types
of paper use class.
One has a lower initial startup fee or setup fee with higher pay per user fee and the other plan has
a much higher set of fee but a much lower pay per user fee and in terms of modeling the revenue.
What if the users within each of these plans also had a distribution in terms of their light usage or
medium usage or heavy usage because how often or how much they use determines the revenue that the business
is going to make.
So how do we model something like that.
Let's take a look.
All right let's look at a business that gets a bunch of their potential customers of first do trials.
It's a product that takes a little bit of a learning curve.
People need to use it to really get comfortable with that.
You know maybe they give a one month free trials and then out of the users that do the trials some of
them become paying customers in some of these users are going to choose Plan A.
Well some of us are going to choose Plan B.
Now the difference between the two is one plan has a low set fee but a high per use fee and the other
one has the exact opposite.
A high set up fee and a low per user fee.
So one thing we can look at when we have these two plans like this is we can sort of see what it would
look like in order for them to break even.
Right.
What kind of usage or how many uses would it take for both of these to break even.
So the way we're going to do that is we're going to do a simple test here here or we're going to calculate
the cost of the plan for a given use.
Right.
So when I say Berty Okay now if is 30 usage under Plan A the customer would pay 5:49 under Plan B they
would pay 6 49.
So there's a difference here of 100 and the way we can solve where there are exactly the same at what
usage they would be break even with each other is use something called Gool seek and what we do is we
go to data go to data and there is a what if scenario.
In excel under analysis and there's a thing called Gool seek when you hit go see you're going to see
a dialogue like this is going to be a set sell part the sell part is the sell the result that you want
to change.
So in our case we want to change just breakeven number here.
That right now has a difference of 100.
I want to set it to zero.
So when it's at zero it means planning and plan B are equal to each other and the so we're going to
change is the uses.
So what it does is it's going to go through several iterations and finds that out like but it does it
instantaneously.
And so we find that at a usage of 40 that's when they're the same.
And this is good to know if you're testing between you know two or three plans because you want to make
sure that you price it in such a way where the brake usage breaks makes sense.
Right.
If almost nobody gets to the for the usage and it doesn't really matter where you set the plan B.
So you've got to set it in a way where it actually makes sense with what you think the users are going
to be doing.
So let's take a look.
So let's assume that plan a customers has this kind of usage distribution you know the vast majority
just uses it about 10 times.
You know there's a few power user that end up using it more than 40 times.
But the vast majority will use less than 40 times.
Makes sense right.
Because if they're using more than 40 times they probably are going to move to the next plan.
Plan B usage is for power users they're going to be primarily most of them are going to be using it
over 40 uses.
And there's a few of them that go to Plan B thinking they're going to use a lot more but end up using
a little bit less than optimal so they end up paying a little bit more than they would have if they
stay with plan A.
So here these are all we need to do for each of these plans is a distribution that adds up to 100 percent.
How we want to distribute.
And what is the average usage in each of these groups and you can create as many as you want here at
5.
I mean you could do too you can do three.
It really doesn't matter.
You can set as many as you want but I probably wouldn't do much more than 5 4 for dividing or segmenting
your users within a particular planner or product line unless you have data that can that are that granular
for you to use.
OK.
So when we have this 10 weeks we can calculate the revenue by plan within each of these groups.
Right.
And then if we suck them up then we have the revenue totals for each of the plants which we did here.
So this one is just all these plans and this one is for the Plan B.
Now the big thing here is we also added calculative set of fees fears.
First set of fees is just going to be the number of customers in that plan times a set of fee.
Okay.
Pretty straightforward right.
And then we add it all up.
So this one what it does when you do something like this in terms of sanity check is it helps you kind
of lay out your structure for your model when you do want to model things out.
Okay so let's see what that would look like if we start to model this out over time.
All right.
So now we have something that is mapped out for say 12 months.
Let's assume that these are the monthly trials that the business is getting in a given month.
Okay.
And we have a certain conversion rate.
So there's a certain number of customers that they're getting right.
And you know what let's make sure these customers are around are rounded to the nearest whole number
because otherwise partial customers don't really make sense right.
I went around these all to something.
Now you may see something happening here that's changing right.
What I'm doing here is I want some numbers here that aren't just straight flat number.
Maybe I think that overall they're going to get on average around 2000 trials.
But I wanted to fluctuate randomly between eighteen hundred and twenty two hundred.
So that's what's happening here.
It's random numbers being generated and then we're taking 15 percent of those as converted customers.
OK so now this set up here is coming from the front right we got our two plans and we've got the breakdown
between the customers so we can start calculating how many users or customers are in each plan in the
plan A.
What we do is we take the percentage there and then we multiply by the total number of customers and
we're again going to round down just so we have whole customers going to make that much of a difference.
But you know it will allow you to feel better.
Okay.
So we have that and then can copy the formula across.
Now we have the total number of uses for each plan.
The next thing we need to know is we need to have the cumulative number of users right now in the first
month.
It's going to equal to that.
So for some of you if you don't like these numbers changing each time what you can do is once you use
it you can just copy this whole thing and then you place value.
So you just keep to that particular set of rendah values.
Now when you do calculation calculations it doesn't keep changing.
Now for the second one is same as what we did before where we take the previous month plus the new month
right.
And we did the same for here for Plan B and then we have these calculations now the cumulative number
of customers in any given month.
So let's start with calculating the activation fees for activation fees are only when new customers
are activated.
Right.
So make sure you don't use the cumulative numbers.
So we're going to take the new users times the activation fee for each of the plans right for Plan B
we have the new users here times a plan B activation fee and then what we can do is we can calculate
it for the rest of the cells here.
All right.
Now remember we had the usage groups by how often they use the app.
So let's first calculate the number of users within each of these user groups and then we calculate
the revenue and then we're going to repeat the same process for Plan B and then we can start looking
at all of the combined revenues.
Okay so the usage groups here is going to be the percentage to the Leffe times the number or the cumulative
number of users in Plan A.
So now we've got to make that reference there and after a while you're going to get pretty comfortable
with all this.
Now this here you can round down again if you feel more comfortable with that.
So now here in these groups the total usage is going to equal to usage times the number of users that
are using that that much times the per use fee.
We've got this here now we have the revenue for Plan A.
Depending on which group of usage they're in you know you could do the same for Plan B and B times the
cumulative time B users get nice like whoops the wrong reference here.
This one I set the row as a solid reference when in fact it should be the column right.
So after a while you can't you can spot check it.
I know they shouldn't be forced.
Right.
Should be different.
So that's why when I copied it and it looked different it didn't look right.
You know you can visually do your error checking as well.
That looks right.
OK.
So let's then do this one times the number of users times the per use fee for plan B.
And now we have the revenues for each of the plants.
And so we take the all of the plan a total revenue.
What would it be then it would be the total activation fees that month plus the sum of all of the per
user fees for that month for planning for plan B.
It would be the equivalent right.
The total activation fees plus the sum of all of the subscription fees under Plan B that should be of
be there.
OK so now that we have those two well we can have it then.
All right what are the total activation fees.
Sometimes it's good to separate your revenue out in different ways.
Just so you can visualize that.
So this one will just be these these two teams and the total usage revenue will be the sum of the both
of the usages right.
So it was some's.
You can do.
You can put a whole array in there and then add another array.
This is called an array or a group of numbers and you could just put both of them in the formula and
what we would do is so some all of the components.
Now it can kind of break it down.
I can see plant a person versus plan B and I can see activation versus usage revenue.
Pretty helpful.
And what we should see is that if we sum them all up any of these two we should get the same as the
sum of these two.
Right.
So we can take that we can use either of those to add the total.
We'll just use the nearest ones.
And so it's easier.
And now we have the total revenue per month.
So there you go.
We have a model here that has two plans where it has a pay per use and there is some activation fees.
Now you may not like the colors that I'm using here but what it does visually is I can know which ones
are related to plan B or Plan A just by looking at this right.
I know that the blue this is plan A plan A you know this is for a plan a total and the same for the
purple's.
So you can choose whatever you want.
I find that using colors can make it easier for you to see even if the colors aren't the prettiest.