Hey guys welcome back to the course.
If I didn't know this by now you know that VCs care a lot about growth.
So how do entrepreneurs and startups model growth in their financial models.
Well there's an easy and lazy way and then there's a better way.
Now the easy and lazy way is to just have growth rate as an assumption in the model like growing 5 percent
a week.
And this assumption can be made to change over time such as accelerating or slowing down or reversing
as the company gets up in size.
Let's look at some examples where we model monthly versus weekly growth rates.
And then we'll look at the better way.
All right let's look at a scenario where the person is using a monthly growth rate as an assumption
right.
So this is an actual input into their model.
And let's say they're starting with a user base of five thousand users and in a 24 month period they
want to reach some sort of a target.
OK.
So right here they want to target $5 million let's say users then they would need to get to about 35
percent monthly growth rate.
So this kind of modeling is very common.
When you look at the user growth rates and you chart it out you see something like this.
The infamous hockey stick that every VC has been barfing over for however long.
That's because the growth rate that is used is put in.
You'll see that you know depending on what that growth rate is the result at the end of just even a
24 month period can be pretty drastic.
Right.
And if we go to a weekly grow for example the difference is even worse here.
We're only doing 1 percent differences right here on the 10 percent range and the difference here is
between under a million users and 9 billion users with a 10 percent range.
Right.
So this growth rate here is I guess it's pulling out of thin air or pulling it somewhere where it's
not very savory but it doesn't really work this way.
You don't just say I want to have this growth rate for my startup.
As you can see besides the fact that the numbers that you use will vary widely and can change the growth
rates like crazy.
Where are you ultimately pulling these growth rates from out of thin air or somewhere less savory that
I'm not going to mention.
See the problem with that approach is that in real life you don't get to just name the growth rate you
want to have growth rate is the outcome.
It's a result.
So what's a better approach better approach is to make growth rate a result rather than input as an
assumption.
So first you decide what is your metric.
The one thing that measure success or failure for your startup.
And then think about what would it take for you to achieve that milestone and win then work backwards
to derive the growth rate that you need in order to achieve those targets.
So let's see how that plays out and the model better way maybe to do something like this.
So in this example we say maybe you find out what your target is it can be a target revenue right.
Or to be target number of users whatever that may be.
Let's use this as an example right now.
Let's say the start of wants to get to a million dollars a month revenue and it will be charging what
it were some average revenue per customer per month.
So in order to reach this amount they're going to need a little over 100000 users are active paying
customers.
OK so if we're still looking at the 24 month period then the growth rate needed in order to achieve
this value say you're starting at with zero users is going to be going from zero to this value and then
taking 24 months to get there.
Okay.
For example if your goal is to have 10000 paying customers in 12 months you can work backwards through
your funnel to see how many leads you need to generate what conversion rates you need to have that you
need to achieve what kind of traffic you need and how much ad spend that you only see once you have
all that figured out.
So you've got to remember that just because someone becomes a customer doesn't mean that they'll stay
that way.
Businesses will lose customers and your business will too.
So in our next lecture we're going to look at how to factor in attrition or turn into our modeling.