Hey guys welcome back.
All right.
So here we are at the end of our roundabout tour of modeling modeling if you haven't figured it out
yet it's really just an exercise in getting to understand your business and your industry better or
in what I call.
Oh that's right.
We have employees we need to include those.
So far everything we've covered are things you would need to see in almost every financial model.
This isn't just limited to startups trying to disrupt their eternal nemesis email not a real problem
by the way or small businesses.
At the end of the day regardless of your aspirations for your business we all share the same components
and the same need to answer specific questions about our situation.
Every business will have both revenue and expenses.
Every business will need to understand the relationship between these two halves.
You will have burned.
You will have labor you'll have contingency and you will have unexpected expenses.
For the most part you'll be operating off of a whole lot of assumptions about a whole lot of things.
So now that we've covered the fundamentals the thing that every business has in common We're now going
to branch out into the things that not every business will necessarily have.
These are the things that vary by the business model and e-commerce store for instance doesn't have
to calculate churn but an online SAS tool does the same SAS startup won't have to deal with estimating
the unit cost and macro facts of hundreds of possible products.
But a food delivery business might so in the next set of sections till the end of the course we're going
to hit on all the popular models will cover things like e-commerce businesses brick and mortar businesses
will cover aggregators when you don't even sell anything you just connect people other businesses cover
businesses that rely heavily on sales to business and sales of very few but high ticket items.
Now you don't have to watch every single one of these but I do suggest you do well because more learning
is better than less learning.
But if you don't have the time then just pick out one or two that you think are the most familiar to
your business or propose business and they just follow that one.
Also worth mentioning is you can download any of the models at the beginning of the case studies so
feel free to build off of them.
Follow along or just modify them as you please.
All right guys.
I will see you in the next section.