Hey welcome back to the course.
In this lecture we're going to talk about the base plus features revenue model.
So think about a car dealership or a car manufacturer.
They have a base model that you've got to pay a base price for and there's a number sometimes dozens
of independent features that you can purchase as a customer you can select to add this or that and any
combination of things.
So if you have a business model where you have something like that where customers want to buy some
sort of a base model of something and they have all these features that they can independently add what
would that model look like.
So in this lecture I'm going to show you how to build that out how to factor in the different combinations
and how to factor that in so that you can build out the revenue model for something like this.
Let's take a look.
All right let's take a look at a quick sanity check for a business model that has some sort of a base
product or based service and then where people can add features right.
And let's look at an example where maybe we have a base product that costs $10000.
And there are some features a B and C that are all independent and have their own prices so the potential
customers could buy any combination of these features from none to or three to any other combination
in between.
And when we look at a business model like this we might start with something where you know there's
going to be some sales pitch right.
These are higher price higher ticket type of products so it's going to be a more involved selling process
usually might involve some sort of one on one sales call or something like that.
So we can assume something that's higher touch.
Okay and maybe out of ten thousand pitches they sell 8 percent you know able to convert 8 percent of
them into purchases of the base product and then out of those some percentage of those are going to
make some purchase of a combination of the features.
So here I'm just structuring this in such a way where we can sort of visualize what that might look
like and if there's 10000 sales pitches and 100 based purchases here then we can see what the revenues
look like.
Now of course when we start modeling out we've got to see you know what that is in terms of the timeline
but gives you an idea you know if if you're making a 100 sales in a given year then your revenues are
going to look something like this where there's that much in base based revenue and then the rest coming
from premium cells.
So if we're going to model this out say over the first 12 months we might structure something like this.
All right let's assume we're able to get a certain number of sales pitches every month and you're able
to consistently convert some percentage of them into base purchases.
Right.
And we have this data here that's the same as what we're assuming in the front.
Some base purchase price the premium feature prices and then what combination what percentage of those
that are customers would end up buying any of these combination of premium features.
So here I'm assuming 75 percent are going to buy some at least one premium feature.
But you know a quarter of them are just going to stick with the base model.
So then when we have that what we can then see is let's look at how many customers fall into any of
these given combinations.
We can take a look here and start doing this.
We are going to take the numbers who are making based purchases and then we're going to multiply by
the percentages that fall into each of the combinations right here.
So base in a will be that 1 5 percent only right because it's only 8.
And then we can kind of go down the line and have it matched this way now.
We do need to fix that again to have the reference correctly.
And so now we have these breakdowns we can see the customers that are going to fall into each of these.
Okay.
So every month we're getting these kinds of purchases.
Now once we have that the next thing we get to do is calculate the revenues.
So because we have these three different features and we're going to be looking at the premium revenue
for all of these combinations.
One technique that makes a little bit easier is to create what are called dummy variables here.
They're kind of like on off you can think of it as on off for these features.
OK.
Now you'll see why this kind of makes more sense when we start to actually do this.
So for example for basename only they want to look at the features.
Then I only turned 8 on and then it turned off other features by putting a zero so a 1 means it's a
feature that's included in a zero means the feature is not included.
Right so we can look at all the combinations here.
We get all zeros or ones and all the combinations of you know having two of them on or only one of them
on.
Then what we're going to do is then the actual revenue for the premium revenue is going to equal to
the number of customers that are in that combination for that month.
Right.
Times the.
And we're going to use something called a some product or some product function basically allows us
to do this multiplication of these two arrays or two sets.
I'm going to take this first array here.
Now I mean a set is so that all the references always stay with this box.
Right.
So I'm fixing the column references but will move down when I move formulas down.
And the other box that I want to reference to that's going to multiply against is the prices.
Now I'm going to fix that completely because everything needs to refer to this one and none of it none
of the references to this box should change right.
So that's why I have the dollar signs in front of the rows and columns.
So when we multiply these two or have a sum product what it's saying is we're going to take the first
elements multiply them together and then take the second elements multiply them together and then the
third element multiply them together and then add it.
So you take the sum of all the products and what the ones and zeroes does is it allows me to easily
then just take the correct price for the combination here by just putting ones and zeros right.
So if I have just the one for feature then I know the sum product is equal to 1 times to ninety nine
and then the rest are going to be zeros so only that two ninety nine is going to come in.
And then this is the correct price times the number of customers we're buying.
That option only.
So then we have that calculation.
And so three times 299 equals to 97.
Now if we take this to the other ones we should have the right kind of combinations here.
Right.
So we see this one it's zero none zero.
There's nothing that we put that there just so we have we're able to look at it.
But the calculation could just easily be zero.
So we copy this out.
Now we have the premium revenues for each of the combinations right.
So then our total base revenue is equal to the total number of customers or 8 times the base purchase
price.
And then our total premium revenue is equal to the sum of the premium revenues here.
And then the total revenue will just be the sum of these two.
So then if we take the wrasse now we have this revenue projections for a business model that has 3 has
a base product and three premium features that are independent.
And if you have the combination of you know how many customers are falling into each.
It's relatively easy to calculate the rest.
The new thing you're learning here is the utilization of what are called these dummy variables.
So this really doesn't mean anything other than the fact that it's useful for our calculation.
Now we've looked at many different revenue models.
And this is by no means an exhaustive list.
It's just to give you an example of the different options that are out there and sometimes just changing
things as simply as the labeling and a few little things can help your model represent an entirely different
business model.
Now there is going to be some of you that are coming up with business models that are even created yet.
But when you look at the examples here and especially when you look at the case that is later you're
going to find bits and pieces that are going to pull from to create your own.
So we hope this gives you an idea of where to start.
Now next up we're going to take a look at the other side of the equation all the costs and the expenses
side.
All right.
SIEV-X.