Welcome to the first video.
Let's take a look at the different types of jobs available in the market.
Knowing what kind of jobs are out there and what excites you is important to your success.
Usually you'll find this information in the job description, and if nothing is posted, you can safely
assume that it's a full time position.
The first time that we're going to talk about the temporary part time or seasonal or temp jobs, as
you may call them, they're meant to fill a role temporarily.
It could be like on a daily basis.
For example, I used to work at a bookstore at the start of the fall season because the bookstore on
campus needed help with restocking all the books and making sure that all the textbooks were available
and easily accessible to students who are going to start their school in the fall season.
Now, once that period was done, the bookstore didn't need us anymore, so we would have to find other
means of employment.
This would be temporary or seasonal employment now temporary full time.
These jobs are designed to meet the company's needs on a temporary basis, perhaps slightly longer than
the temporary seasonal jobs.
For example.
Think of someone who's gone on maternity leave.
You need to fill their position.
Until this person returns to work.
Third kind we're going to talk about, ah, the contract and contract to hire Jones.
Now from a company standpoint.
Contract jobs are attractive because they reduce or eliminate the risk associated with hiring a new
person.
Now, hiring a new person is not without risks.
And depending on your seniority and your job role, it can take up to 12, sometimes even 18 months
for a candidate, a new hire to actually start making money for the company.
This can include expenses like as simple as creating ID cards all the way to software licensing and
training and making sure that this new hire is able to independently execute all the tasks that they
were hired to perform.
The fourth kind is the consulting type now with a consulting gig.
Your let's say you're a consultant, then you accept a job.
As a job order for yourself to solve a specific problem that exists in the company.
Once this problem is solved, you move on to the next task and possibly the next company.
It allows you to explore the job market without being tied down just a contract job.
Consulting will give you the flexibility of being able to work for multiple employers in multiple industries
and see what's the most exciting to you without being tied down to a company.
Now, permanent, full time jobs, which are very common in a lot of specialized and professional fields,
they are said to be in a permanent job, of course, when you're employed with the company on a permanent,
full time basis.
Your salary comes from the company and your pay stub probably has your company's information on it.
Now, in the next video, we will take a look at what your resume could say about you.
And before then I have to mention that every job opportunity, no exceptions, every job opportunity
that is posted is designed to solve a problem.
And you as a job seeker have to project yourself as the one that can solve this problem better than
anyone else.
And that is what will get you your interview.
Thank you for watching.
I hope you found value in this and I look forward to seeing you in the next video.