Welcome to the ninth video of this masterclass, which is about how to gain visibility efficiently.
Now, when you have your resumé and your LinkedIn profile created, the next thing is to gain visibility.
Now you want to do this in the most efficient way possible, which is not just sit and apply for jobs,
but let jobs find you as well.
So to do this, identify all the top job search sites in your area.
For example, if you're in Toronto, Ziprecruiter is a big one.
But if you're out west, CareerBuilder could be a big one.
And in certain other places, like with Corporate Corp, Monster and Dice Dotcom are also big.
So the recommendation here is to upload your resume and fill out all the forms and make sure that everything
is consistent with your resume on every job search site.
Possible.
Don't you do this?
Just keep track of all the websites where your resume is online.
Once a week.
You want to just log in?
Click Update resuming.
This is a trick that I use that I recommend to people that I teach as well is Click Update as May.
You don't have to actually update your resume unless there is something to be updated, but then just
save.
And the reason for that is when a recruiter or a hiring manager performs a search on any of these sites,
then the top search results will be the ones that were active most recently.
And by just clicking on update resume and saving, you want to show that you are active.
The same thing works for LinkedIn.
The more active you are, the more likely you are to appear at the top of the search list.
And the more relevant your keywords are to the job that you're gunning for.
The more likely you are to appear at the top of the list.
So obviously combine the two, you have highly relevant keywords that maximize your chances of getting
found in a search result, as well as updating your your skills or your resume getting recommendations.
This works, especially for LinkedIn, is you should ask either your previous employers or people that
you've collaborated with, or if you're a fresh graduate, then your academic advisors or your teachers,
probably somebody who can recommend you and someone who can endorse your skills, especially on LinkedIn,
because that helps you get found as well.
And when you see recommendations, then it increases the confidence level for the recruiter or the hiring
manager and you are more likely to get invited to an interview sometimes even without even applying
for a job.
You will let Jobs find you.
Another way to do this is to network efficiently with recruiters.
Now, recruiters, just like I told you before, they work on a many to many basis.
So you have one recruiter with many clients on one side and many candidates on the other side.
So the recruiter can tap into a pool of candidates and choose which ones or recommend more than one
candidate to interview at any of their clients when the opportunity arises.
So what you want to do is contact as many recruiters as possible, upload your resume on the staffing
companies websites, try to build relationships.
I'm more about building relationships with people than about just selling.
The best people, the best salespeople are the ones that build good relationships.
Spend more time building a relationship with recruiters, with hiring managers, with your with the
staff at your university or college and so forth.
And when you do that, then you are more likely to get referred.
You're more likely to let Jobs find you.
People will be more pleased to work with you.
So approach it from a standpoint of empathy.
Now, at this point, I want to explain to you the difference between empathy and sympathy.
Empathy is when you understand the other person's standpoint without.
Necessarily agreeing to it.
Sympathy is when you agree.
And when you empathize with someone, you understand where they're coming from and you can act accordingly
to maintain a harmonious relationship.
And when you maintain harmony in relationships, that's when you can really maximize your chances for
success.
Now, Daniel Pink, in his masterclass on Sales and Persuasion, he talks about how you can write the
letter E!
And in front of you in the air.
And if you do this.
Then you're seeing it as a reverse.
So I'm doing this from my perspective, so I'm not thinking about it from the other person's perspective.
But if I were to write an E like this, that's an E to you.
It's reversed.
To me, that means that I'm empathizing and making it more convenient for you.
To see what I'm writing in the air.
So think about it.
Empathy versus empathy and use an empathetic approach to selling your skills.
Always think about what the other person will want and act accordingly.
Talk to hiring managers, talk to recruiting managers, connect on LinkedIn if you can afford a premium
membership.
Then during the peak of your job search, it's also advisable to pay for a premium membership because
it allows you to connect with people.
It allows you to send emails directly to hiring managers, directly to staffing company managers, and
to recruiters without having to connect with them.
And it's probably not advisable to send connection requests unless you've actually built a relationship
with that person.
And Premium helps you send an email without needing to connect first.
And this way you can show off your skills.
You can invite them to view your profile.
In that situation, your cover letter would go something like, This is who you are and this is why
you're interested in working for the company.
And the call to action, which is the last line in a standard cover letter, you would have mentioned
something like I'm available for interviews immediately and may be contacted by via this email or phone
number or whatever.
Right.
You would change it slightly to include, I invite you to view my LinkedIn profile and this is the link.
And once again, if you don't have the LinkedIn.
You know, stash your name.
It's recommended that you get one because it's easier to remember.
Thank you.
And I look forward to seeing you in the next video.