So far, the entire interview process has been from the perspective of the employer.
So I'd like to talk a little bit about what it means from your perspective.
How can you make yourself a more marketable candidate or a superstar interviewee?
It's through creating a unique selling proposition or a USP.
Now, you might be unique, but it doesn't mean anything if you cannot project it to your to your interviewers
the right way.
And this is what I tell my business coaching clients as well.
So how do you create your unique selling proposition?
See, when you graduate from college, then it's very, very likely that you're going to be a generalist,
which means that you have some general idea of how things work, but you don't have any real exposure
to to the industry because academia and industry are two different things, right?
So when you gain experience, as you keep gaining experience, as you keep working with more companies
or in better roles or whatever, then you start building up not just your resume.
You start building up a set of skills that all amount to something, that amount to get you where you
are.
And if you're in college now, or if you've just graduated and you're looking for a job, then this
is your time to think about where you want to be in the next two years, five years, ten years, whatever.
Yeah.
Okay, let's not think about ten years for now.
Let's let's think about short, medium and long term.
By short term, I mean in about three months, medium term, I'm thinking two years and long term,
maybe five years.
So that said, think about all the skills that you need that you think you will need in the next three
months or six months or two years.
And think about what your ideal employer is going to look like.
So if you already have an ideal employer in mind, then take a look at their job postings and see if
there's something that that interests you.
You may or may not be an immediate fit, but it's something to definitely consider and keep in mind
because just having a copy of that, just having it somewhere on your computer or print it out, pasted
on the wall, whatever, will give you an idea of what skills it takes to be part of that company,
and you can work towards that.
Now, as we evolve, our goals evolve as well, and the challenges we face will determine some career
paths that some detours that we take.
So it's never a straight line.
So when you start out from college, you're here and then suddenly you face some kind of challenge and
that that forces you to detour.
And then you start learning a different set of skills and then you continue back on that path.
And then there's another detour.
So more, more likely than not, your graph, instead of a straight line, is going to be up and down
like this.
But as long as you're dedicated to to what you want to do and who you want to be, then it'll definitely
show an upward trajectory.
So that's a.
Creating a unique selling proposition will involve let's let's say, three steps.
First one, what makes you special if you're still lacking experience, if you have less than two years
of experience, then it's likely that there's not too many things that make you special, that make
you stand out from 200 other candidates that are that have sent their resume for the same position.
Right.
So don't worry, there's always time to work on something.
What it means is that you can always project yourself as someone who is willing to learn because you're
making it a part of your career goals.
So it's not just willing to learn so you can do a good job and take home a salary, but it's willing
to learn from a career standpoint.
And this is something that employers find very desirable.
And you will thank yourself in a few years time if you think back to this day and decide to have to
learn a few courses if you're in college or if you've just graduated and you still have your student
credentials, then it's also a good idea to to pick up new courses, such as if you're in India engineering
field, then you can learn computer aided design or analysis or things like statistical software, whatever,
whatever will get your career accelerating.
Think about doing certified courses and then do them, of course.
But if.
A $50 course which has a certificate which comes with a verified certificate of any value.
Right.
If a $50 course will get you a job that pays you $100 more each month, then within a couple of weeks,
you would have already recovered the investment that you made in that course.
So think about that for a moment and keep doing this over and over until you have a lot of knowledge
which will propel your career in the direction you wish to go.
So regardless of challenges, you won't be stuck there needing a job.
You jobs will come to you because you will become a desirable candidate at some point of time.
You could also show those those certificates, and that's the effort that you've put into self development,
personal development.
And you can say, this is me and this is what I'm capable of.
So what more do you need?
I mean.
Think about it.
And the unique selling proposition is what separates you from all your competitors.
When you think about, let's say, Domino's Pizza.
There is nothing great about.
There's nothing really special about them.
They're a pizza company.
And there are so many others.
So why?
Why did Domino's Pizza become a multibillion dollar company?
It's because they had something unique, even with something as generic as pizza.
They cater to to college students who are hungry and who wanted to have pizza within 30 minutes, 30
minutes or free.
And they wanted it cheap because it was college students.
So they had two unique, unique things about them that separated them from all their competitors, and
they use those two things to their advantage and projected themselves as the viable choice for most
college kids, most college students.
So this is the kind of thinking that will help you establish your market leading position or unique
selling proposition.
Thank you.
And in the next video, we will go through the closing and the checklist.
And if you've come this far, then congratulations and thank you very much for being a part of this
course.
I hope that I've added a lot of value to you.
See you in the next video.