What happens when an interviewer asks you if you are ready to work overtime?
Now, if you're like me, then you enjoy work life balance.
I don't even like calling it work life balance because you shouldn't have to balance the two.
One should not come at the cost of the other.
You should be able to enjoy both.
Now be true to yourself and answer the question according to what?
How you see fit.
It's allowed to ask an employer how often you'll be working overtime.
And if you're a workaholic, then that's great.
Then having to work constant overtime might actually fit in with your need to keep busy all the time.
But if it's going to affect your personal life, if it's going to affect your family, then think about
whether that's the right thing for you to do and be upfront and honest about it.
And you can always say, Yes, I'm happy to put in whatever effort is necessary to finish my job and
to go above and beyond.
And it also depends on how often I'll be putting in overtime.
So you can ask questions like instead of just directly responding to the question, you can also ask
what the history is and how often over the last, let's say, six months, how often other colleagues
in the team have been working overtime and what kind of projects are involved?
What kind of challenges are they solving by working overtime?
What are other people doing to go above and beyond?
And you can base your response around that.
You can have some kind of a skeleton, some kind of an idea of what you're going to respond, what you're
going to use as a response when you talk to them, but at the same time, be ready to ask them some
clarifying questions as well.
Think about how that affects you and frame your response accordingly.