Here's another question.
Tell me how you handle criticism.
Now, this is kind of a curve ball question because they want to see how well you handle criticism,
but also whether you're a team player.
It's a lot of questions rolled into one.
What if your manager gave you an unfavorable appraisal at the end of the year?
How would you handle it?
What if someone told you that your work was not up to par and how you handled it?
So a lot of questions rolled into one.
Now, if you cannot think of any experiences or any examples from your previous work history, then
you can talk about things like your school or your personal life, your sports, whatever.
But be ready to come up with an example and this is something you should do well beforehand when you're
rehearsing all your answers and talk about what the criticism was.
But before that, talk about the task again, your your following the state approach, your situation,
what the situation was.
And why you received criticism, which is the task in this case?
It's not a task.
But what who criticized you and what did they say then?
Action what you did.
That would impact this situation positively and what the result was.
So it always helps to to keep a positive attitude and to also maintain lessons learned, if not in a
journal, then you can always do that right here.
But you want to keep a record of lessons learned, so you're continuously growing and improving yourself.
I am not the same person that I was ten years ago or 15 years ago because I've learned so much and my
mind has expanded from what it was before.
And and when someone has criticized me, then I've generally taken that as an opportunity to improve
myself.
So that would be the way you would frame your response to this question is how you took the criticism
and didn't take it personally, but you applied it as as a means to improve yourself.
So from where you were using the criticism to where you are today, and that's what you want to convey
through this.