There's another question.
It's a dated one, but a lot of interviewers still like to ask this question.
It's where do you see yourself in five years?
I'm not a big fan of this question because a lot of things can happen in five years.
And it's important to set goals.
For example, I read close to 50 books in a year.
I pick certain activities that I wish to accomplish, and I do accomplish by the end of the year.
And if I don't, then I'm at least a certain percentage close to completion.
And I talk about or I justify to myself why I was not able to finish them and what I can do.
And these are all related to personal and professional development.
Now, if you are driven, if you are a driven individual and trying to continuously improve, then you
should get into the habit.
If you are not there already, then you should get into the habit of setting goals for yourself.
And these will not just be professional goals, but they should be personal goals as well.
Things that help you improve not just in your career but as a person.
Help involve help get involved in in the community.
Give back to the society by mentoring somebody or by leveraging your skills to see how you can benefit
the society.
Things like that.
Now, the reason I even talked about all of this is because they kind of relate to how you see yourself
in five years and for most people.
That would be relevant to their job interview at hand.
And you would not you should not say the other side of this desk or in your position or something like
that.
That doesn't make sense because.
You do not want to come across as threatening to the interviewer.
And when you don't come across as threatening.
Then your interviewer might like you because they see that you are a goal oriented individual.
You care about your personal development.
You care about growth.
You have a drive.
But at the same time, your drive is not to upstage anybody in the company.
Your drive is just to grow.
And that's what you want to convey through this.
So when someone asks you, where do you see yourself in five years, you can answer that with tact and
say, These are the goals that you've set for yourself and this is where you wish to be professionally
and personally.
Now, for example, you can also think about everything that's involved from start to finish in a typical
project in your field, and you can talk about how many things you've been a part of for.
As an example, let's talk about manufacturing with the when a product comes to market and it's sold
in the market, that's the end.
But the beginning is when the product is identified as a result of a need.
So a need exists in the market and there's nothing to fulfill that need.
And that's where someone comes up with the idea of a product that can fulfill that need.
And then they go about getting specifications and then they translate those specifications into concept.
And then the concept is translated into a detail design, which is then manufactured and tested and
assembled, put together, and then the finishing stages it's sent out to the customer after creating,
let's say, documentation, user manuals, agreements, things like that, and making sure that it not
only meets the needs, it does what it's supposed to do, and it does it in the best way possible.
Now, what I just mentioned to you, I was I walk you through the entire product development lifecycle
there.
And if you're in in the in the product development field, then you can think about or consider every
stage that you have personally been a part of that you have personally contributed to.
And over the next year, two years, five years, whatever, what other stages would you like to be
a part of?
What else can you contribute to to become a more well-rounded individual?
Now, that's from a professional standpoint, and then you can talk about supplementing that with something
that improves your skills.
So did you learn a new software or did you learn a new tool?
Did you attend some kind of leadership courses?
Did you study, let's say, business law or.
It doesn't matter.
I'm just throwing out examples here.
But think about how this would apply to your field.
Think about a project and think about what what your contribution level is and base your answer from
that and start with that and think about what else you can do in the next five years that will help
you grow professionally and personally.