Here's another question that interviewers like to ask.
Sometimes it's What would you change about your life?
And this is an interesting question because they want to see if you are someone who's forward thinking
or someone who lives in regret.
Remember that every decision, every event that has taken place in your life has shaped you in some
way into who you are today.
And any rational person, anyone who's capable of even the least amount of critical thinking, given
a certain set of circumstances, will always make the right decision.
Now, whether it's right for them or not at that moment, it can never be known at that moment.
It can only be known when the results make themselves known later on or in the future.
But your fundamental focus should be on maintaining a positive attitude and maintaining an attitude
of no regrets with when you're in the interview.
So something that you could change in your life has to be said without any regrets.
And don't make it something so big that it will change the course of your life, because then you may
not even put yourself in the situation where you're presenting yourself as a good candidate.
Because then you're you're talking about some decision that went so wrong that you didn't you didn't
foresee it.
You didn't do anything to correct it.
You you weren't a good decision maker, so you want to come across as a strong candidate.
Then you want to show that every single thing that you've done has been done with due thought and consideration.