Have you ever hired or fired people?
When someone asks you this question, they're trying to establish whether or not you're cut out for
a corporate job.
Now, when you hire someone, you do it based on your best judgment and put yourself in your interviewer
shoes.
Would you hire yourself?
That's the fundamental question here.
When you establish your own candidacy for the position, but when you hire someone, then you're taking
into account their personality, their skills, that experience, and how they fit with the company.
Now, if it doesn't work out, then you need to show resolve and fire them and or let them go.
But the company might expect you as a team leader to justify your decision in firing this person.
So that means that if you're fired, if you have hired or fired people, then you can always tap into
your experience and and talk about what.
What qualities you look for when you're hiring.
People don't just say yes or don't try to justify that.
Try to give some kind of reasoning or some data.
Tap into your background and talk about what qualities you've looked for when you've hired people.
And if you're fired, someone then talk about why you had to do that.
So again, start response right there, situation, what happened and then what was the what was the
consequence?
What was the result of that?
And what did you do?
You fired this person and what the result of that was?
Did it improve company morale?
Did it result in you hiring a different person?
Did it result in saving the company some money because this was a totally unproductive employee?
Think about everything.
And you want to show determination.
You want to show results.
And if you've never hired or fired anybody, then just say so.
Say that if your goal is to be a team leader, if if that is your goal, then talk about how it is your
goal to be a team leader and to be able to hire people.
Don't say be ready to be able to fire people, but just say you're looking for the opportunity to build
your own team, which will be productive and which will match the company's core values and things like
that.
Always related back to the company.