When a hiring manager says You're great but you're missing some key skills, it usually means that the
details of the job description and what's relevant to who can solve the problem reveal themselves at
a later time in their own job search process.
So when they started by posting to the job description.
And they may not have considered every skill that's important for you or for anyone to perform the job
effectively.
As they interview more and more candidates, some of these skills reveal themselves.
And usually it's later on.
And if you find yourself in that position, then focus only on your strengths and focus on what you're
willing to learn.
Now there are three things that you can do.
You either you're willing to learn because you see your skills and.
Your career going in that part, you're willing to learn a new skill.
You're willing to learn a new skill, but you don't want to make that the top priority for you because
it helps you perform a job well.
It helps you get results, but that's not something that you wish to invest more time than it's necessary.
And then you have the skills that you're willing to not learn at all because they don't bring any value
to you.
So identify which of these the skills that you're missing will lie under.
And if any of those skills lies under the first two categories, either the ones that you want to actively
invest time and effort in, or the ones that you're willing to learn for the sake of performing the
job, then be open about it and say that you're you're willing to learn whatever it takes and skills
can be taught, but attitude cannot.
So most companies, even if you are missing key skills, will want to hire if you show them the right
attitude, because learning skills is just a matter of time.