Hi.
And welcome back.
This is the 12th video of the master class and it's about dressing for an interview.
Now, before you get invited to an interview, obviously you know what position you've applied for,
which means that, you know, the seniority level, the level of education and experience that they're
looking for, and it's important to dress according to that.
Now, even though you may be dressed in in casuals at work, it's not necessary that you must be dressed
the same way during interviews.
You want to be your best version of yourself.
Now, think about this.
Are you in a customer facing role or are you are you going to be dealing primarily in the back end?
And if you're in the back end, then you may not need to be dressed in formal every day.
But a lot of times sales professionals, marketing professionals, they're usually dressed in formals
because they interact with people and it represents a certain degree of professionalism within the company.
So that said, if you're in an entry level, you could even get away without a tie.
But if you're regardless of your gender, you would be advised to dress up in either formals or business
casuals.
So that could include a blazer.
Now, it's important to remember that when you sit down, you want to have your blazer unbuttoned.
The reason for this is the blazer is a direct descendant of body armour.
And when you have your when you button up, that means you're in a way protecting yourself and you're
not opening yourself up to the conversation.
Now, if you look at a lot of motivational speakers, people who speak on stage, they display open
body language by opening their arms up like this and saying, welcome.
Thank you all for being here.
And the reason for that is they are displaying what is called ventral fronting.
In his book, What Everybody is saying.
But Joe Navarro says that ventral fronting is when you leave your front exposed.
Now, those are where your all your vital organs are.
And if you leave that exposed, you're not protecting any of it, then you're showing the other, the
listeners and the recipients of your information that you are not displaying protected or uncomfortable
behaviour.
In other words, you're you're showing yourself as vulnerable and inviting and that should be the basis
for your communication during an interview.
And one good way to do this is dressing appropriately, but at the same time having your blazer and
obviously not your shirt but your blazer.
And when you when you're interviewing at a senior level, then apart from attire, you could also have
a pocket square.
And that kind of completes the outfit and it helps you present yourself more professionally.
Now, the tip here is even in a phone interview, I would advise you to be dressed the same way you
would for an actual interview.
The reason for that is, although the interviewer cannot see you over the phone, obviously it still
helps you get into that frame of mind where if you're dressed in casuals, wearing your pants or pyjamas
at home and wearing just a hoodie, then you might be inclined to think and approach it from a casual
standpoint.
But if you're dressing in formals, then your brain automatically thinks that it is in a formal setting.
And even though you're on the phone talking to somebody, you will still feel that need to be formal
and that itself will trigger your brain do to craft your responses correctly and to treat the interview
with the consideration that it deserves.
Thank you, and I hope I was able to add value.
I look forward to seeing you in the next video.