So far, you have learned how to create a compelling resume, how to decode a job description, how
to improve your nonverbal communication, your body language.
During interviews and in the last video, we talked about the Fuji method to influence your interviewer.
Now onwards, this last series is about answering some of the most difficult air interview questions.
There are two kinds of questions.
Let's talk about situational questions and the other kinds which are tell me about style questions.
So situational questions.
They when they're still telling me about questions, but then data, your interviewer might ask you
something like, tell me about the time where you resolve the conflict.
Tell me about a time when you made a mistake and what action did you take to correct that mistake?
Tell me about something on your resume.
Tell me about this experience right here.
When when you're confronted with a situational question there.
Then one very effective way to deal with that is the star method.
Star stands for situation the task.
Your action taken and the result.
So you would do well to think of all these negative as well as positive situations.
Situations where you excelled, you exceeded expectations, situation that could have been embarrassing,
but you turned it around.
A situation that shows your strength, situation that shows your weakness.
Think about one example for each of these and write down what the situation was and then what was the
cost of continued inaction.
Which is all in the situation.
So for example.
You could talk about as an as a manufacturing person.
You made a mistake that could have been worth tens of thousands of dollars of of of wasted raw materials
or wasted product.
But that was the situation.
So continued inaction would have cost the company tens of thousands of dollars in terms of wasted material
or product.
What's the next step?
Which is a t tusk.
What did you do?
What was the task?
It was to correct it.
Right.
So what action did you take to correct it?
And that would be the root cause analysis, which would be why would the money have been wasted in the
first place?
Why would the company have incurred the loss of tens of thousands of dollars?
Think about that and then think about how you solved that problem.
Exactly.
Perhaps you stopped the production midway and made sure that the drawings were corrected and then sent
them back so that people could start working on them.
From there on.
And the result was that you saved the day by taking corrective action in a timely manner and saving
the company tens of thousands of dollars.
Now, what I did right there was I turned a position of weakness into a position of strength by being
proactive and by taking the necessary steps to correct the error and making sure that the company didn't
lose money because of that.
Now, think of.
Similar situations that you have been a part of.
If you haven't been a part of such situations professionally, that's fine.
Think of something from your college.
Think of something from your university, your personal life.
Think of anything that can add value to you as a candidate by using a situation to ask action and result
and write down.
Three or four such incidents showing different, different qualities in you that you can use during
your interview, because these will help you prepare your interviews, not just about your resume.
And the more prepared you are in your responses, the less you will have to improvise.
So think of all these and make a list.
Thank you very much.
This was a start method and in the next short video, we will see the Six Sigma method to approaching
situational questions.
And I look forward to seeing you in the next video.
Thank you.