Welcome to the next video in this masterclass, which is about maximizing your chances of success at
job fairs.
Now, when someone has the right attitude, I can usually narrow down the lack of success to two things
either a lack of skills or a lack of guidance.
And with the job fairs, you are not there to get hired.
You might.
But that's not the fundamental goal.
That's not the primary goal of a job fair.
A job fair.
You need to approach it with the intention of building relationships.
And in order to in order to get success at job fairs, you need to detach yourself from the outcome.
You may or may not get a job, but doing the groundwork ahead of time will yield much, much better
results than if you're unprepared.
And if you just walk it in now, ensure that the job fair is at least two or three weeks ahead in time.
And you have to remember that all job fairs have a theme.
Now, if it's not a if the companies are not specific to a region, then they're specific to an industry
or specific to certain skills.
So identify what kind of job fairs you're going to.
Is it a is it a job fair with all the companies in a certain location or is it a construction job fair
or an I.T. job fair?
Or what is it about?
Make sure that you try to upload your resume well ahead of time.
So usually you have to register for a job fair.
And you can do this today.
You can do this online.
And when you do that, you might most likely you will have the opportunity to upload your resume.
And when you do that, also get a list of all the companies that will be presenting or that will have
stalls at this job fair.
Now, take special note of the ones that have triggered your interest, the ones that have jobs specifically
in your areas of strength.
This takes a lot of groundwork, by the way.
Visit the website of each company that you've identified and apply.
Apply already to all the jobs, relevant jobs in the career section of each of those companies.
If they don't have one, try to find what jobs they have available through sources like Google or indeed
or Glassdoor or whatever.
Keep a list of all the positions that you've applied to.
And this is critical because when you're organized, then your thoughts will be organized.
And when you enter the job fair, you will know exactly what what positions you have applied to at that
company.
And.
You need to have a cover letter and a resume prepared for each company and Job wrote.
It helps her not apply to too many varying positions within the company because then the way you will
come across is that you don't know what you want.
You're indecisive or not focused and you don't want that.
Now read up about the company, read up about the core values, draw some inferences about the work
culture, and print out at least one copy of your resume for every position that you've applied to within
the industry.
And it's possible.
In fact, it's it's also a fantastic idea to create business cards if you can afford them on your own.
All you have is your name and contact details and perhaps a list of skills in the back or a couple of
keywords.
Don't make it too busy, keep it clean, and have your your own personalised business cards.
If, of course, if you can afford it and attach one business card to a copy of the cover letter and
the job description.
Now let's assume you're applying for a company, ABC, and you've applied to two positions there.
Then you want to have a copy of the resume that you used for each of those positions.
Now, if you've followed my advice so far, then your resume might and most likely will be slightly
different for each position because you would have tailored that to the job description.
Now, as long as it's not vastly different, you're fine because you've only chosen to retain what is
relevant for that job description.
Everybody works more than they can print on their resume at some point of time, and no one will judge
you for it.
Along with the résumé, you would also include the cover letter and the business card and be ready to
hand it over at the job fair.
Now, when you get to the job fair, spend some time and take note of the map if you can find it.
Or walk around and take note of the companies that are there compared to the list that you've made previously.
There could be some last minute new entrants.
There could be someone who dropped out last minute.
You never know.
So at that point, Mark, the ones that are most interesting to you.
And mark differently the ones that could be of interest to you.
And lastly, Mark off the ones that you find uninteresting or the also rans, as I may call them, when
you do this, you will spend a majority of your time among the companies and jobs that are very interesting
to you, that you would like to be a part of, that you would like to contribute, to walk over.
And when it's your turn to talk, don't ask them about the company.
Show them what research you have done about the company and tie that to how you are a good fit.
Talk about the work culture.
Talk about their values.
Talk about what makes them unique and what makes you unique.
You're showing them that you've done the research and you hand them a copy of your resume.
And don't say that I would like to apply because this is something that you would have done already
when you registered or well ahead.
So most likely when you hand them a copy of the resume, you're just putting a face to the name and
that's it, or you're helping them do that.
And when that happens, most likely people will get impressed by the amount of groundwork that you have
done and your chances of getting a call to an interview will be higher.
Not just because of the impression that you create, but also because you would have applied a couple
of weeks before the job fair, which also means that they would have had a couple of weeks to go through
your resume to identify that you're possibly a good candidate.
And when you present yourself well, then you are just further.
You're likely to improve your chances of getting an interview.
Now dress well, dress.
Always dress appropriately for a job fair, depending on the dress code, depending on the level of
education and the level of seniority that you're looking for.
Always remember that it's better to be overdressed than to be underdressed.
You do not want to go in a polo shirt and jeans when you're looking for a professional job that involves
a high level of responsibilities.
Thank you.
And I look forward to seeing you in the next video.