Hi again.
Let's talk about one of the last questions that you will encounter in the interview.
Why should I hire you?
So.
Remember the Fuji method.
Now, typically, people who are logic oriented, people who think logically and people who are still
fence sitting, they might ask you this question just because they want to hear from you one last time.
They want to convince themselves.
What?
I am not sure why I should hire this candidate.
So what makes them so special?
Let me hear from them one last time.
So why should I hire you?
So here.
I would suggest I would recommend strongly not bringing up any of your any abstract values or words.
I'm hard working.
I'm a team player, things like that.
You don't want to do that.
Everybody can claim that.
What is unique about you?
Now, if you if you go back to the beginning of this class, this Masterclass series, then we talked
about your unique selling proposition and how to create one.
Now, before your interview, you would have created one for yourself as well.
And if not, then this is the time to do it when you're preparing for your interview.
Then specifically write down what makes you special in the field.
The whole reason you're sitting there in the interview is because there's something special about you.
And they have identified that now they want to match what's on your resume on a piece of paper to what's
in front of them.
Your interviewer That is.
So when you talk about why they should hire you, then you want to convince them based on facts and
based on things that they can actually see.
So that also means that you will you will frame your answer of two or three fundamentals here.
The first one would be.
What makes you special?
Why you stand out?
The next one will be what is the problem that the interviewer has?
Which resulted in this job description.
Or this job opening.
So there is a problem or there are some problems that the company has that they've identified.
That a new hire will solve the problem.
Right.
So the cost of inaction versus the return on investment, if they sit on it and do nothing, then that
will cost them more money than to hire somebody and solve the problem for them.
And that's the reason for the job.
So empathize.
Think about it from the employer standpoint, why should I hire you?
Is actually a question on how will you help me solve my problem?
How will you solve my problem?
So frame your answer around that.
So we're looking at three things.
One, what makes you stand out to what is the company's problem?
Three, how will you solve it?
And once you've done that, then you can put the cherry on top saying, I am also.
This, this, this, which is just a summation of the company's core values or their work culture.
So how you fit in, but don't make that the primary objective of your answer.
Your primary objective is to solve that problem.
So before you interview, make a create a paragraph and rehearsed it and be ready to answer it whether
you're asked this question or not.
Thank you and see you in the next video.