Let's talk about questions you can ask the interviewers.
Now, at the end of any interview, because an interview is a two way street.
They want to know how you can solve their problem and you want to know what's in it for you.
Of course, you want to know about the word culture and your future there.
So your interviewer will ask you, do you have any questions for us?
And yes, you should have questions.
So if you're in an in-person interview, then ideally on your copy of the resume, you would write down
facts about the company and a couple of questions that you can ask the interviewers.
Now, if you're in an entry level or lower mid-level position, then it's absolutely okay to ask questions
like, what's my team going to look like?
What's what's the average day in the life of an engineer or what's the or accountant or lawyer or whatever,
right?
A paralegal assistant.
It doesn't matter what's the average day look like in the life of someone in this position?
And you can also ask questions about the company's learning programs or what sort of trainings they
do and things like that.
But as you grow to higher level positions, these questions become very, very basic.
So in addition to these or as a replacement to these, you should be asking questions that are more
geared towards the company's growth and things like that.
So you want to ask questions about the company's growth plan for the next few years.
But what it shows, it doesn't have to be one year or two years, five years, whatever the number is
relevant.
What's important is your.
You're trying to get an interest in the company or trying to know about the company's growth plan for
the next few years, which means you're willing to make a long term commitment to the company.
You can ask questions like, what is the what specifically is the interviewer's problem when it comes
to fulfilling their responsibilities where you can step in and help?
So what is the nature of the problem, apart from the job description itself?
What other traits and experiences or qualities do the interviewers find useful?
When it comes to fulfilling this role and doing it successfully.
And those are the kinds of questions that you should be asking.
You can also ask questions about the companies work culture, what they do in the way of events, show
some interest and be engaged.
Because even if you choose to be a contract employee, whether you choose to be a contract employee
or a permanent employee, you want to show that you're interested in being a part of the organization.
So frame your questions around that and have at least two or three questions.
Write down at least three questions that you can ask the interviewers.
One of them could specific to the role.
One of them could be specific to the company, and one of them could be about how you fit in.
And remember, always follow up their response with something that you say.
For example, if a company says that they find a certain quality, very important and key to being successful
in this position, then always follow it up with one example of how you demonstrated that quality.
And this is impressive because this is one of the last questions that this is probably the absolute
last question that an interviewer will ask a candidate.
And when they do that, then the response is kind of firmly imprint why you are qualified for the role.
So it gives you a better chance at success.
Thank you and see you in the next video.