Welcome to the seventh video of my masterclass.
This video will talk about cover letters and thank you notes.
So far we have covered how to decode a job description, how to create a targeted resumé, and how to
build your LinkedIn profile.
So cover letters and thank you notes are extremely underrated and it's very important to build a strong
cover letter.
And once your interview is done, to follow it up with a thank you note.
So for this, I'm going to share a page from my book that has a sample cover letter and we're going
to talk about it.
Now, when you look at a business letter, any letter, then obviously your name and your certifications
or licenses or designation comes on top.
And as far as a cover letter goes, you want to keep this part consistent with your resume.
So you want to have the same header and then the date.
Now, if you have the companies information, then it's always useful to include it here.
And if you have the name of the person who posted the job, then it's useful to include it there as
well because then you know what the salutation will be.
You know who you're addressing.
And it's, it's, it acts favourably from the company standpoint as well.
If you've gone that little extra mile just to find out who posted it and you're addressing them directly.
Now that said, your salutation will be the name of the poster.
And on LinkedIn it's fairly easy and it's quite common for a lot of hiring managers or staffing company
managers to use their names and their profile as the person who posted it.
So then you know who it is.
Now, with any business letter, three paragraphs are involved.
The first one has the introduction in the salutation, and that's pretty generic.
And most companies, from a psychological standpoint, most companies, most people will focus their
attention immediately on the second paragraph, and that becomes the main body of the letter.
What's your background in a nutshell?
Now, before saying that you want to establish what makes you special and include that that's your market
dominating position, that's what you are offering that no other candidate in the job market is offering
for that same position.
What is it that makes you special?
How many years of experience you have and what relevant fields?
And pick a few words from the job description and the company's core values.
It helps to do research about the company.
Now you can also provide one or two data driven examples of when you've achieved certain things that
are relevant to the job description.
And this data should reflect verifiable information.
And it shouldn't be it shouldn't be hypothetical.
So think about things like how much time you saved at some point what your what the end result was for
the company, how many people you may have trained, the size of the facilities you were working at,
things like that.
And then your conclusion.
What's the goal of the cover letter is to make it compelling enough for them to read your resume.
So then what's the next step forward?
You've included your resume along with with this application and then tell them how they can contact
you and when you are available for an interview.
So the resume is basically your portfolio.
You've created your resume for them to view and gauge for themselves that you're a good fit.
But the cover letter tells them the other details, like when you're available for an interview, what
makes you special and how you can be contacted.
Things like that.
Now, thank you.
Notes work the same way and I find it very useful to have a template thank note as well as a cover letter
and vary them based on the job posting or based on the results of the interview.
Now it's always a nice gesture to include a thank you note in your in your application after you have
been interviewed.
It shows that you've done some due diligence.
Send a thank you note within 24 hours after your interview is over.
Don't delay.
And in your thank you note the main body.
The difference between the thank you note and the cover letter in this case is in the main body.
You're in the thank you note.
You're telling them exactly how the interview went for you with specific instances.
That may have come up during the interview that show them how you are qualified to perform the job.
That's it.
Keep it simple.
Thank you very much.
And I hope I was able to add value.
And I look forward to seeing you in the next video.