Welcome to the third video in this lecture series.
What do recruiting managers and hiring managers look for?
Generally speaking, a job posting is meant to solve a problem within the company or the department.
There's a problem in a company.
You didn't create it.
It's already there.
The company has decided that this problem needs to be solved by a new hire.
In other words, the consequences of letting the problem remain are not acceptable.
And this is when a company posts a job with the list of skills that they think is necessary to solve
their problem.
And that person with those skills could be you.
Now staffing companies operate on a many to many basis.
What that means is they serve many companies.
And usually have many candidates on file that they can tap into.
To help fill these positions for their clients, the companies.
So it follows that a staffing company is looking to fill the needs of their client and will look for
a candidate that closely matches the job description.
You have to remember here that the more general order, the lower the level of experience for a job,
the more competition there could be for this job posting.
Specialized roles have lesser competition.
But it also means that their chances of finding the ideal candidate could be less because this ideal
candidate could be employed at a different company.
Now, when there are two candidates with very similar experiences and attitudes, then companies, including
staffing companies, they try to find the one that's most eager to get the job, the one that's most
motivated, the the proactive one.
Now, a perfect match in terms of attitude and experience, of course, would be the perfect candidate,
100% matching the job description skills and 100% of the attitude.
Now, someone is a reasonable match in terms of experience, but has strong soft skills, strong qualities
such as attention to detail, critical thinking and so on.
Then they would be a good match.
The least desirable match would be someone who has the experience but no other attributes to go with
it.
So.
The questions to think about here are what does it mean to be a team player?
As an example, someone who's invested in the collective success of the group and someone who puts the
needs of the team above their own personal needs, someone who can collaborate with others to solve
problems.
Think of all the instances in your professional and personal life where you've had to show teamwork,
dedication, focus, attributes like this to solve a problem.
List at least three of them down.
Think about six different things for every single incident or example.
What the issue was.
What were the consequences of not acting on the cost of continued inaction?
What you did.
What qualities you displayed, such as teamwork, dedication, motivation, focus.
Quality, critical thinking.
Any number of these things.
What people you interacted with and the end result.
Now once you've done this.
These will serve as examples that you can share during your interview.
In the next video, we will take a look at how to decode a job description.
Thank you for watching.
I hope I'm able to add value.