Let's talk about what you need to do before your interview.
Now, ideally, in an in-person interview, you print out copies of your resume, as many copies as
the number of interviews you're going to be facing.
And if it's your if it's a video interview, then you would have a copy of your resumé open.
So just in case you want to share your screen, then it makes it easy to do.
Now you will make a list of all the keywords from the job description and highlight the ones that match
your resume and your skills.
Now that will be for easy reference, but it will also attract attention.
You should familiarize yourself with company specific information like their core values, their mission,
their vision, facts and figures.
If that makes sense, depending on what role you're going for and the higher the seniority, the more
you want to know about the company.
Otherwise, talk about the work culture, look at the reviews on Glassdoor, and indeed look at what
other employees have to say about working for the company and try to empathize with those values and
see how much commonality you can get.
You should also look at the LinkedIn profiles of your interviewers, if possible, to find out if you
can get some common ground and understand their background and what kind of leaders they are, where
they may have worked, and what you can find in common with your own experience.
Write down at least two or three questions to ask the interviewers now in person.
When you have a copy of your resume, one is your personal copy where you have the list of keywords
and you have the list of questions that you want to ask the interviewers.
Then that automatically shows the interviewers that you've done some homework.
And you know, about the company and the copies that you hand out to these interviewers will be just
plain nothing written on them, and that's just for their reference.
And they can choose to write whatever they want.
Now, another thing to do if you're in a video interview is to have sticky notes with little prompts
similar to teleprompters.
But here you can stick them to the sides of the screen and they might even help you answer some of the
difficult questions.
And you also could get away with typing your elevator pitch and having it in front of you on the screen,
in word or notepad or whatever you feel comfortable using.
The reason for that is, although I'm looking at the screen right now, if I look away and I were reading
from there without actually moving my eyes from left to right like this, then I could do a better job
than having to memorize it.
Of course, I did say in the previous video that it's important to memorize it.
So even if someone wakes you up from sleep, you're able to recite your elevator pitch.
But in case you are not confident enough to do that, it's always a good idea to have that open in front
of you during your interview because the Tell Me About Yourself question is what you will respond with
your elevator pitch, and that will set the tone for the rest of the interview.
Now, next video, we're going to talk about video interviews and phone interviews.
So I hope I was able to add value here and hopefully you have enough information to prepare for your
interview and what kind of homework you need to do before your interview.
Thank you.