Hi.
Welcome to the fourth video in this lecture series.
How to Decode a Job Description.
Now, unfortunately or fortunately and conveniently for us, most job descriptions in most fields are
created the same way.
And like we mentioned before, all job descriptions are designed to solve a problem for the company.
Now, when you look at any job description, you will see a few lines about the company, a few lines
about the job divided into must have skills and nice to have skills.
And then you will find you may find a few benefits of working for said company.
Now what I would like to do is share my screen and we can take a look at three different job postings
from three completely different fields and try to decode them so that we can create a resume that's
targeted to that.
I'm going to.
Share my screen here.
So first thing I wanted to show you was.
I performed a simple search for mechanical engineering jobs in California.
Now, when you look at this, this is a random job posting from a mechanical engineer for this company
in Carlsbad, California.
And when you look at it, job highlights the qualifications.
Here are the must haves.
These are things that the company cannot do without.
They absolutely need someone with a bachelor's or a master's degree with five years of experience in
this and with experience in 3D CAD design software, in this case SolidWorks.
Experience with drawings and rapid prototyping in Microsoft Office and being able to draft work instructions.
Now, those are the must have skills as far as technical the technical area goes.
Now, when it comes to soft skills, they also want someone with strong written verbal communication
skills, analytical organizational skills.
Conceptualising, innovative and creative designs.
They also want someone with sheet metal experience and all these things.
Good troubleshooting skills.
Strong general computer literacy.
Five years of experience.
They already covered that previously, and if they repeated it here, that means it's important to them.
Previous biotech engineering industry experience.
Previous experience with automation, production equipment.
Now those are the must haves.
Now, the responsibilities could also tell you more about what they're looking for.
Cross Functional Engineering Team.
What does that mean?
To be successful, you are expected to be working as part of a group.
So they're looking for teamwork, cutting edge biological and medical research, which means they're
looking for someone with experience in research because industrial research is vastly different from
academic research.
Now you will work with a variety of R&amp;D staff and team members for new product introduction with an
emphasis on customer wants and needs, which means being able to understand customer requirements is
important to this company.
Now understanding and applying technical knowledge theory, best practices.
So they want someone who is strong, not only with applied part of engineering, but also with the theoretical
part.
They're talking about.
The primary engineer being the one to increase capacity on critical automated production line.
That means you'll you'll be involved in critical, out-of-the-box thinking.
You will need to demonstrate that.
You will need to demonstrate that you're able to support people.
You'll be required to analyze, identify improvements.
So.
Let's take a look before.
Before we make any conclusions here, let's take a look at something else.
Sales jobs in Toronto.
This was another surge stemming.
Now.
Again, just like I mentioned, there's a little bit about the company.
And about the road working there.
What does it mean being part of a friendly team in a working environment, in a welcoming environment,
open to new ideas?
That means that they're looking for someone who is friendly, who can be welcoming to others as as welcoming
as they are to this new person.
It means being able to communicate with senior management and being dynamic.
Now growing and open to continuous training of employees means that they're looking for someone who
is proactive, who wants to keep learning and improving.
Now look at the roles and responsibilities generate sales.
Of course, that's a sales consultant's job.
Maintain a high level of customer service.
So they're looking for someone who's cheerful, who wants to who who wants to put the interests of the
customer above their own interests.
High level of knowledge of products and services, product merchandising, cleanliness of the store.
That means they want someone who is organized.
Now demonstrating curiosity and empathy, being a team player, working with little supervision, which
means that they want a team player who is capable of working independently.
And doesn't wait around for directions to be given to them.
And then there's a little bit about the benefits.
I want you to focus on this rigorous and structured training program.
When you look at that.
And you compare that to this growing and open to continuous training of its employees.
That means that they're looking for someone who is committed to working for the company.
Join an innovative company in business for more than 50 years and benefit from a rewarding work climate
in the interior design industry.
Now let's take a look at another one.
Lot of jobs in New York.
This was another search that I mean, this is for a paralegal in New York.
New York.
Self-Starting highly.
The kind self-starting, highly organized, detail oriented individual with excellent written and verbal
professional communication skills and follow through.
Paralegal experience is required.
But they're still open to various levels and types of experience.
Interest in working as a member of a team.
What does that mean?
Team player once again.
Disciplines of theater publishing related entertainment fields.
So why is that?
They're looking for someone who is a true team player as well as has experience in.
In the theater.
But what could it mean?
It could mean someone who's self-starting, who's who's a detail oriented, because theater involves
a lot of these skills.
They will be liaising with attorneys and fines.
And I'm looking at the responsibilities now handled state and federal compliance.
So this is a little bit of a high stakes job.
Assist with attorneys and clients in connection with the creation and dissolution of entities.
Now.
They're busy.
They are a boutique entertainment law firm.
Now, that's that explains the experience that they're looking for in theater is because they're in
entertainment law firms.
And.
They are looking for someone who has good analytical skills, who is organized, who has experience
in all the fields earlier, and who can support and work as a team member.
Once again, that's exactly what this says self-starting, highly organized, detail oriented, with
excellent communication skills and follow through.
Now.
We have seen three different job postings in three different fields.
Mechanical engineering, sales consulting and a paralegal.
Three completely different ones.
But the job postings are built the same way.
And out of every job posting, we have managed to extract a set of keywords that can be put into one
of two categories either skills required to perform the job or soft skills.
Now, things like teamwork, self-starting or highly organized detail oriented.
These are all.
Soft skills.
They're related to communication.
We're not quantifiable.
Things like five years of experience, bachelors degree in engineering, experience with sales or experience
in the theater.
Things like this.
These can be quantified.
How many years of experience do you have?
So when you look at a job description, make sure you break it down and.
What did down as a set of keywords.
Instead of focusing on the entire job description, focus on the keyword.
Every required skill, every job responsibility will have at least one keyword now.
Jot that keyword down and put it into one of these categories.
Is that a skill that's required, like a hard skill or a soft skill?
And this is how you break it down.
Now, at the end of the analysis, you should have broken down the job description in its entirety into
a set of whatever keywords five, ten, 15.
I'm not sure depending on how big the job descriptions.
And once this is done, you are going to integrate all these keywords to build a targeted resume.
Thank you very much for watching and I look forward to the next video.
I hope I was able to add value.