Tell me about your greatest strength or your greatest weakness.
Now, the strategy for both of these questions is the same.
First of all, you do not want to appear either overconfident or depressing.
You do not want to absolutely open yourself up and and project yourself as a weak candidate instead.
As far as strengths go.
Think of specific examples.
The same goes for weaknesses.
Well, don't just jump in with a random adjective or something like that.
Oh, I'm a workaholic or I care too much.
No, that's that's not a good way.
That's not a good approach to doing this, although a lot of people say that it's okay.
The best way to approach it is actually through specific examples.
So any of these questions, you can always give a specific example and then demonstrate to the interviewer
how that made you feel, what made you feel like that and what you did.
So greatest strength, for example, you want to show using a specific example what your greatest strength
is.
And if you've gone through the job description or if you've gone through the core values of the company
or the word culture, then you will have an idea of what quality to display as your greatest strength.
For example, if a company values.
Integrity or honesty, then you can always say, for example, a hypothetical situation.
I could say I was in in one of my previous companies, I saw someone trying to do this, trying to disregard
existing products and and try to buy new, new, for example, camera lenses, try to buy new camera
lenses, each one costing upwards of $10,000.
Then what I did was I identified that there were still some lenses available that we had never used,
and instead of throwing them away and ordering new ones, I said, we can just use them.
And through this simple gesture, I saved the company $20,000 because we needed two lenses.
What I did was I stood up for the company.
Even though I was talking to a colleague, I was I stood up for the company.
I tried proactively to save the company money by by identifying products that had been that would have
otherwise been neglected or just trashed.
So what did I do there?
I displayed integrity and I displayed value for the companies time and money.
And these are valuable qualities to have.
So that would be an example of a strength.
You don't want to say.
My greatest strength is this.
And then stop.
That's not a good approach for weakness.
There's a couple of schools of thought.
One way to do it is to disguise a strength as a weakness.
For example, you had to work.
Being a workaholic might be considered a weakness, but at the same time, if you're a person of the
company, then you're you go above and beyond to ensure that your work is done.
And even if that means having to work overtime, then you're disguising a strength as a weakness.
That's one approach.
And another approach would be to choose a weakness that has nothing to do with the job at hand.
It doesn't have anything to do with any qualities that that you might need to fulfill your roles and
responsibilities properly.
Right.
For example, you might want to do you might be interviewing for once again a marketing job.
And if you are, then things like being being a good salesperson, having good people skills, being
empathetic in your communication, these might be important to your success in the role.
But what's not important, probably being bad at math, I'm not sure.
So then you want to pick something that's that's completely unrelated to your job roles and the responsibilities
that you will be fulfilling in your job role and using that so it doesn't affect you negatively in any
way.
There are two different schools of thought and it's difficult to ascertain which one is better because
they both work in different situations.
As for my personal preference, I would I would keep it relevant to the job description itself and perhaps
disguise a strength as a weakness.
Or I would say what started out as a weakness.
For example, a couple of videos prior we saw about manufacturing and how someone saved tens of thousands
of dollars by correcting the manufacturing drawings instead of allowing them to to be manufactured and
costing the company tens of thousands of dollars.
So in that situation, what started off as a weakness ended up as a strength.
So in that situation, you're not disguising anything.
You're starting off with some mistakes that you made and you're showing what you did to proactively
correct yourself and ending with what you have learned, the lessons learned and what why exactly.
You have not repeated that mistake ever again.
And that's what people want to hear.
And that would be my favorite approach there is be honest, but at the same time show what you've done
to correct yourself.