Hi and welcome back to this masterclass on job search and interviewing.
Now, we already talked about what you need to do before the interview.
And here is a quick list description.
Keywords match them to your resume.
Highlight them so they're easy to see not just for you, but also for your interviewer.
So they know that you've done some kind of work and then familiarize yourself with the company work,
culture and values and mission and vision and things like that.
Write down questions and try to do as much research as possible about the interviewer so you can find
some common ground and build a relationship during the interview.
Moving on, let's talk about video and phone interviews.
Now, I did mention earlier that 93% of your communication is all nonverbal.
That means your tone of voice, which makes up 38% and your body language, which makes up 55% of nonverbal
communication.
However, in a phone, they cannot see you, obviously.
So the 55% of body language goes away, but you still have to work with your 45%, out of which 38 is
your tone of voice.
Only 7% is what you say.
So that's it.
Be enthusiastic, be upbeat, and try to emphasize all the keywords.
And trying to emphasize what makes you stand out.
Now, it always helps to actually dress up even for a phone interview because your brain automatically
switches modes.
If you're dressed in a hoodie and pajamas, then it's likely that you will think in a more relaxed way
as well.
And that will come across in your interview as being very lax and not eager to get the job.
So if you want to avoid that, then even though it's a phone interview, dress up in formals.
Now, we already talked about how to dress up for interviews, so my recommendation here would be to
dress up the exact same way that you would for an in-person interview, even if it is a phone interview.
It's just a question of half an hour or one hour, but it'll change your mindset.
Now, video interviewing is almost exactly like in-person interviewing, except there are a few things
to remember here.
Now, as you see the screen in front of you, you see that this person is in front of the computer.
But there are nine other people, three in each row in that video call.
And if you observe the top row, the middle person here and the middle row, the person on the left,
these two are probably positioned the best for success in this video interview, and that's because
their head all the way to their chest is visible in front of the camera.
Also, they have neutral backgrounds.
Everyone over there has neutral backgrounds, but they don't have anything that distracts them from
the conversation.
It's okay to have a conversation piece in the back provided it doesn't provoke debate.
So if there's something interesting, like a picture of your dog, for instance, then that could be
a conversation piece that might help build a relationship with your interviewer.
But you don't want political pictures there because that might spark debate.
You don't know which way it's going to go and you're not there to have a political debate.
You're there for an interview.
So that's it.
Make sure that no more than 30 or 40% of the screen is actually you.
So if your face is too close to the camera, then it will overpower everything else.
And you do not want that smile, of course, and keep a positive attitude.
It's always good to have your hands visible so that you can gesture whenever necessary and it doesn't
appear like you're hiding anything.
Another thing to remember is do not swivel in your chair.
Don't do what I'm doing right now.
Because it looks unprofessional and distracting.
It also gives the appearance that you're not invested in the interview, you're not invested in the
interviewer's time.
And even though it's just 30 minutes, one hour, whatever it may be, the duration of the interview,
you want to be completely invested.
You want your torso facing the camera.
Don't slouch your shoulders.
Don't do this because it indicates a lack of confidence.
So how do you prevent yourself from swiveling?
Simple.
Just place your feet firmly on the ground.
And when you do that, you're achieving two things.
You're making sure that you're completely invested and focused on this interview.
But secondly, you're also telling your mind that this is not a situation where you want to trigger
a freeze flight or flight response.
So there's no place to hide.
There's no need to hide or run.
And there is no need to freeze.
The worst thing that can happen if you're uncomfortable is that you'll spend a few more seconds thinking
about what the correct response is.
And that's it.
Now, other than that.
Everything else is similar to in-person interviews, and I'll talk to you about gesturing in the next
video.
But as far as video interviews themselves go make sure you don't you don't hide your neck either like
this because that automatically triggers some kind of victim response.
So when you look at children when when they're caught doing something that they shouldn't be doing,
then their neck goes up like this and they want to turn them in and they don't want that happening.
You want your toes to point towards the screen and make sure that your feet are comfortably placed in
front not too far back, because then it gives it triggers a reserved set of emotions in you.
So you tend to withdraw a little bit and don't put your feet too far out because then you can get overly
comfortable and you want to.
There's a difference between being comfortable and being too comfortable.
Being lazy is, is that you're you're comfortable and yet you are alert, you're paying attention,
you're actively invested in the conversation.
Let's talk about hand gesturing in videos and in-person interviews in the next next lesson.
Thank you for joining me and I look forward to seeing you in the next video.