Now the next question is, why are you looking for a new job?
It's never going to work in your favor if you speak ill of your present employer.
So you want to avoid gossip.
Avoid creating a toxic environment because you want to leave your interviewer with a happy memory associated
with you.
So what?
Before your interview?
You should make a list of some solid reasons.
Maybe two or three solid reasons on why you want this new job.
Now, if you're unemployed or if you're just starting off, then it's much easier because you can just
talk about what the company offers and and relate that to what you can offer and try to create a bridge
there.
If you're currently employed and looking for a new job state, what drives you?
If you know why you're looking for a new job.
Now, perhaps the work environment right now is toxic for you, but you cannot say that to a new employer.
What you would say?
Is how this new employer's values and the new employer's culture matches better is a better match for
you than where you are now.
Perhaps you want to make progress and feel.
If you're shifting from a small company to a large company, then you can talk about how in a small
company it's very fast paced and you wear many hats, but in a larger company your job would be more
focused and that allows you to perform better and at a more optimal level.
If you're moving from a large company to a small company, then you can say the opposite.
You enjoy more dynamism.
You enjoy being more creative in your problem solving.
You enjoy having complex challenges and a fast paced environment, and that's why you're shifting to
a smaller company, things like that.
So think about what drives you.
Think about why you would want to leave where you are and and move into this new company where you're
being interviewed.
What values do they have that match up with yours?
And you would have taken note of the company's core values, of course, when you were doing the research
prior to the interview.
You can always use that to leverage your answer.
So there are two stages.
Why are you looking for a new job and why are you looking for a new job in this particular company?
So then you can you can target both issues with the same question.
Thank you very much and I look forward to seeing you in the next video.