Let's talk about employment gaps as we move out of COVID.
It's not uncommon for people to have employment gaps.
You could have had an employment gap for any number of reasons.
You could have been laid off due to reorganisation.
You could have taken an extended vacation.
It stopped working to go back to school, started a family.
You could be you could probably be looking for your ideal employment, and that's why you're there.
Now, the most important thing is to not display shame or embarrassment in this.
Everybody goes through an employment gap.
A lot of people do at least, and it's nothing to be embarrassed about.
Talk about briefly state how long your employment gap was and why and what you have done in the meantime
to make yourself a better candidate.
And I strongly advocate going through coursework online or trying to improve a certain skill, make
yourself a better candidate, and position yourself better in the market.
And when you do that, then that's something that you can really leverage.
During an interview when talking about employment gaps.
Thank you.