Hello welcome to my ultimate recommendation on which is to me the best platform you can use to build
and run and train your own miles.
So if it's going to be Amazon Web Services is it going to be Google Cloud platform.
Is it going to be Microsoft Azur cloud platform or is it going to be IBM cloud or eventually is it going
to be paper space.
So here we go.
My final recommendation is Amazon Web Services.
There we go.
So some of you might not be surprised because indeed this is the most popular one the most used one.
And that's not only because it's Amazon that's also because they have great advantages which I'm going
to explain and highlight in the next tutorial but first before we do this I just would like to remind
you where and how you can set up a virtual machine on a W-S.
I remind that I rather recommend the Linux virtual machine than a Windows virtual machine.
You just need to go here to product and then Amazon to Amazon.
Easy to is exactly the virtual server on which you can be connected to a powerful computer far from
you.
But it's as if you had it in front of you because you can basically get into it and train your models
inside.
All right.
So it's very simple to get started with Amazon.
Easy to.
You can actually click this thing here get started with Amazon easy to but before this I like to highlight
the fact that in order to be connected to a server you need to have an Amazon easy to account.
And of course ultimately when you use it permanently it will be a paid account.
And I'll talk about the prices soon but the good news is that you can actually try amazon easy 2 for
free.
It's AWOS free tire that includes 750 hours of Linux and Windows instances each month for one year.
So you see you can really experiment and see if you like it but when you start you can either click
this link.
If you don't have any account on Amazon to make sure you get one free AWOS account first and then you
can click this link get started with Amazon easy too and you will see they have an amazing guide that
walk you through step by step through the process of connecting to a virtual server or a virtual machine.
So here I already have an account.
There we go.
I think that's the one.
All right.
So here we are on AWOS.
The first thing you need to understand is that in order to connect to a virtual server or a virtual
machine which has got an Amazon easy to instance you need to create an instance first and that's why
here you have this option launch instance so you can just click it and you will have many virtual machines
you can select and you see that for each of them it is specified if it is free.
So you're eligible.
And that's the one you must choose if you're still in the experimenting phase retire legible.
So that's an example of one.
But no worries if you see many of them you might be wondering right now which one I should choose.
Well no worries because the quick start guide which is actually right here getting started guide will
explain step by step which one you must choose to start.
So they will tell you exactly the one.
And then inside this one they will guide you step by step and you can see actually the steps here.
Step one launch an instance step to connect your instance which is exactly what I was talking about
you know connecting to a virtual machine virtual server and then step three you need to clean up your
instance and then you have some next steps.
But let me show you here the main steps the steps on how to get started with Amazon easy to Linux instances.
Perfect.
So here you have an overview of how all this works.
You have the prerequisite of course which is just setting up with Amazon easy to remember.
On one of the prettiest pages you know right after I clicked Amazon is to.
Well we had two links.
First getting started and second get to retire in order to set up with Amazon easy.
Well that's just a prerequisite.
Make sure you set up with Amazon.
Easy to write and then you have the different steps.
Step one is to launch an instance and here's you can see it is explained in great details on how you
should do it for us.
Open the Amazon easy to con..
Then from the console dashboard you will see launch instance that's exactly what we did before.
Remember this launch instance but near.
That's what you must do.
And then you need to choose an Amazon machine image.
Am I.
So I'll show you this.
If we click on launch instance here.
Well these are Amazon machine images and they tell you as I said the one you must click to get started
with.
Which is this one's the HD m edition of the Amazon.
Am I.
And indeed it is marked as Freet eligible.
So let's do this AGM this one.
So that's the first one.
HVM and it is indeed Freespire eligible.
So we click on select.
I guess that's what they say.
And then on this next page choose an instance type you need to select the T-2 that micro type.
So let's do this.
You see I'm just following step by step what they explain and really won't encounter any issue.
Everything is well-made on AWOS.
That's one of the reasons why it is my highest recommendation.
There is no issue.
It's very easy.
And so there we go here that's what ask to select T-2 that micro free are eligible.
That's the reason.
So make sure it's like this but I think it's selected by default and then they ask to click review and
lunch.
If I'm not mistaken Yes that's right.
Step up step five.
Review and lunch.
So let's do this review and lunch.
All right.
So we are connected to the right instance tied to that micro we're using one virtual C.P. use with one
gigabyte of memory.
Nor is the virtual machines you'll use for your machine or will be much more powerful but here that
of course because it is the free are eligible.
Am I to get started.
All right.
So then you need to click on lunch.
Let's check that.
It's the next step.
Yes indeed.
And they give us more details on the review instance launch page that hit this page here review instance
launch.
Well what we need to do is under security groups security groups here the wizard created and selected
a security group for us we can use the security group or alternatively we can select the security group
which we created when getting up using the following steps.
The steps are here but we're going to use this selected security group here that will do it.
No need to get in too much advanced details now and then we just need to click on launch right here
on this review instance launch page let's do this launch and now we have this window opening.
And again they tell us in great detail what we have to do.
No room for any issue.
We just need to choose or create a keep there.
So you will get your key pair of public key and private key when setting up your insitu instance.
Make sure you keep that somewhere.
And here it will automatically select your key pair and then you can just click launch instances and
there we go.
We are connecting to our instances are instances are now launching and then you can just follow the
next steps and then we can move on to step to connect to your instance.
All right so I just wanted to guide you a little bit do a little bit with you the steps on how to connect
to an instance then you just need to follow the next steps.
And remember as a bonus of course I'll give you a nice and well made practical PDAF handbook on how
to connect your instance and get familiar with it.
All right.
And now we're going to move onto the next toile where I'll explain the main reasons and the main benefits
that make this Amazon Web services cloud platform the first choice.
I'll explain that in great detail in the next tutorial.
And until then and data science on the cloud.