Come back to the into is hands course and today is going to be a bit of an advance tutorial because
we're going to work with a different type of variable.
We want to work with one of these variables.
So so far we've been working with dimensions and dimensions are actually categorical variables.
These are type of variables are a yes no variables or they say a day of the week the you know the type
of education a person has the marital status like.
So it's basically words or categories you know day of week can be considered a category these old categories
months.
These are all different types of care.
So what category does a person fall into.
Whereas here we've got numerical variables which are different in the sense that you cannot consider
them categorical.
There's a continuous numerical summary of a continuous numerical variables.
So for instance you've got H.
Right so a person you cannot just categorize MHG because they could be like three and a half years.
Or it could be 3.1 2 years old or a thing or three is probably a 30 and a half or 29 years and two months
in one day and things like that so it's not easy to bucket people among these.
And so let's see what happens if we give it a go.
Right.
So if we duplicate the sheet we take like age then we're going to be working.
So we can just rename this.
So we take age for instance and try to do the same thing you know first of all doesn't replace and even
if we try this something else comes up write something completely different and we can probably build
some interesting charts around this but we can apply the same exact approach right.
We cannot just say you know like just replace edge there simply because it's not a categorical variable.
So what we're going to do is we're going to create a categorical variable out of it through bins.
We're going to create like we're going to been age into groups.
And so you'll see how we do that.
Or if you just right click and you clearly click Create and you play create bins and then you say don't
worry about anything else we're going to go into detail you just say size of being five or so years.
The bins are going to be five years each.
Been there and now you can see a categorical variable here age being.
And so by the way before we do this I want to show you that if you take your age bean and you put it
into columns and then you put number of records in two rows you'll see distribution you'll see how people
are distributed across that those across those bills.
And this is what I mean by bin's instead of having to if I go back to age of set of having If I just
take age like this into calls right can't really do much with it because even if I take a number of
records now you can't really do much here because it's just doing by the here it's building them up
because it's sure you've got now category's right you've got 15 years so that's 15 to 20 20 to 25 or
25 to 30 to 35 and so on and so each bin is represented by the lowest age in 35 to 40 45 40 45 and so
on and this shows you how many people are in each one and so you can presume control and copy it into
color it looks even nicer or you can add that to a label.
You know that puts a label on top looks really nice right.
You can create a really nice chair like this.
So you now know how you people distribute it or as we know you could add a great Tibo calculation and
you could do a percent of total.
So you know how many people fall into which group so 22 percent of your customers are between 30 and
35 as you can see by the way.
That's one of the powerful things about tabel.
How quickly did we create that because all Zeshan very quickly.
But that's not the goal here.
Right.
So our goal is analytics we tried to we can create distillations that's another thing we can be doing
in.
But for now we've set ourselves a challenge to explore age right.
And so now we have just been very confused into the outcome and bam all of a sudden you see how this
you know the whole thing works out with age which people are more likely to take up the offer which
as always remember the statistical significance thing you know this is not really this is not really
as well.
None of these are really significant.
But here at the bottom you can see that kind of like something interesting happening.
Right.
So you can see that the Middle Ages you know between 35 and 50.
They are low or maybe 35 to 60 even though they have quite a low percentage of subscription.
But the younger people between 20 and 30 they have like a higher percentage rate.
So that's that's something interesting to observe.
Again these are data looks like statistically significant species one of two or three variables but
that could be something going on here like it's not to say that it definitely isn't.
They might be but we just cannot.
We don't have enough evidence to say that it is.
But already you can pull some information on from here I guess.
So yeah.
So that's kind of like one of the drawbacks of this visual method that unless it's statistically significant
you can really say much and that's where a machine learning comes to the rescue.
What I wanted to say Alice here is that you can also practice one have these bins if you like for other
variables for instance pede days could work.
Previous could work and you can find descriptions of it here but we're not going to delve into that
further.
We're going to stop here so you can continue exploring but I think this this illustrates the power of
visualization for data mining for driving insights.
There are other ways you can apply viz. you can apply those elections to create beautiful charts and
beautiful graphs and so on them and present things in a very coherent manner.
And that's also very important in design.
But here at least we explored this first component I think it's very powerful.
Like it's not only just about creating charts and graphs but it's also about the data mining aspect
and it shows you that you do have a lot of power in your hands already.
Even not knowing complex that this takes mathematics that this Dickel learning machine learning or even
if all were all those things you really have quite a lot of power in your hands with simple tools like
tabel.
And on that note I hope you enjoy today's Statoil and I look forward to seeing them.
Until then enjoy Dennison's.