Now that we have learned about the task concept and Gradle, we can take a closer look at how to customize
tasks set up.
The first thing is to configure tasks.
We already have tasks at above plugins.
So when we go to our Java based convention plug in where we apply to Java plugin, we can go and configure
tasks that have been added by the Java plugin.
Because that's a plugin we applied here in the top to x tasks directly use the tasks container.
For tasks that are already registered.
There is an excess of when you use to call in dstl so you can write tasks, compile Java for example,
to configure the compile Java task.
The same name that we saw earlier when we looked into the console which tasks have been executed?
So ideally details of tasks are already configured through extensions.
So for example, when we set the Java version up here, the Java plugin will take care that this information
is forwarded to all tasks that care about the Java version, which are the compiled tasks.
The test task and also the Java Top task.
But we can also configure all of these tasks directly and in some cases we need to because the extension
just didn't offer us the possibility to configure certain detail.
One example is the encoding which is expected from the Java source code.
So this value might differ on different operating systems by default.
So it's good to set it to a fixed value.
This is done through the options encoding setting.
A good choice is to set it to UTF eight.
Note that all these options are typically inputs to the task.
So if you set an option, it's a task where we execute, even if the source files have not changed.
So not only files but also configuration details are inputs to tasks.
If we take a look at which tasks are available in our projects, we can see that there is also a compile
test java task which compile test code.
We haven't added this yet.
We'll do it a bit later.
But this task also compiles code so it probably makes sense to set the encoding option here as well.
In such cases, we have similar tasks.
It makes sense to set the options for all tasks of a certain type.
With the Toth type.
I mean, the implementation of a task behind each task there is some Java class or Kotlin or Ruby class
that implements the task action.
So the actual code that is executed when the task runs and does something, for example, calling the
Java compiler.
So if you want to find out what the type of certain task is, you can use the code navigation feature
of the IDE to navigate into the SSA and you will eventually find the task implementation, which in
this case is part of greater core.
In other cases, you might end up in the job of another plugin if the task was added by a community
plugin.
In this case, we can see that the implementation type is Java compile.
To configure all tasks of a certain type, we can use the tasks dot with type notation we add to type
here in Kotlin.
This type notation can be used for that and then do configure each.
Now we have a configuration block that is applied to all tasks of this type and we can set the encoding
here.
I would be very careful with using the with type way to configure things because it will configure all
the tasks of this type, no matter at which point they are added over just to the project.
In this case, it makes total sense to use it, but just be careful in general and if possible, prefer
using the direct source.
If an excess or is not available for some reason you can also use the notation dot named for accessing
the task, which is exactly the same thing as using accessible in the DSL.
You should use this way to access tasks, but I'll get back to that later as well.
Another task you typically have to configure is the test task, which will also talk about.
That's it.
Using the task container, you can configure details of any task that has already been registered by
plugins you applied or using the tag notation, you can configure all tasks of a certain type.
However, if possible, try to configure things through an extension if that is available so you don't
even need to touch the task directly.