Let's get a bit more into the topic of dependency management.
At first, a few remarks.
Dependency management is a large topic and cradle of a very powerful dependency resolution engine to
find dependencies and to resolve conflicts.
While some notations for dependencies are inspired by the Java ecosystem, the engine itself is not
specific to Java and therefore it has a lot of features that you probably won't need in a standard Java,
but also not in a standard Kotlin or Scala or Ruby project in this fundamental course.
I will only give you an idea of what concepts are available so that if you encounter them in some documentation,
you are not too surprised.
Explaining all the concepts that are available and the inner workings in detail would take a lot of
time and would shift away the focus of this course from the fundamentals.
So the things I'll talk about are just to give you a certain idea of how things are connected.
Don't worry if you don't understand everything.
I will always go back to what you can use in Java or other JVM based projects, which is probably enough
for most.
But let's look at a concrete example.
We go back to the build file of our business logic component where we define some dependencies before.
As mentioned, a dependency definition always has a scope or also called configuration and then some
coordinates possibly with version two point.
It's a component you want to depend on.
Now let's take a short look at the scope slash configuration thing.
So configuration, which is a bit unlucky and very generic name, is another concept in Gradle on a
similar level as tasks.
It's the fundamental concept of greatest dependency management.
What I'll do now is nothing you need to do in your build.
I just want to show you a few things.
Similar as the tasks container.
There is also a configuration container where you can define, manage or modify configurations.
But this is something that ideally the plugins you apply already do for you.
So the Java plugin does a sophisticated setup here for Java, but also other JVM languages which in
the end all compile down to Java classes and Java files.
So the dependency management in Java, Groovy Scala or Kotlin project is basically the same everywhere
and already set up by the Java plugin on which all these other language plug ins depend on.
So you can think of a configuration as a kind of container that summarizes dependencies and artifacts,
so files that belong together when looking at a project from a certain perspective.
So for Java project, there are two of these perspectives.
The one is that you use the project when you compile code.
So for example, when I compile my EP project, I need a certain view of the business logic project
to compile against classes that come from that project.
And the other view is the runtime view.
So when I run the application, I also need things from this other project which possibly include more
transitive dependency, like the Apache Commons Library, which we defined here as the dependency.
These views of the project are also called variants and gradle.
So configurations are used to set this up in a way.
The configuration we already accessed when we configure tasks is the runtime class path.
So this is like the runtime view I mentioned.
Then equivalent is also compiler class path, which gives you everything you want to see at compile
time.
And these configurations again are compositions of other configurations that you can use to declare
dependencies.
So the implementation scope down here is also a configuration that is included in both the runtime class
path and the compiler class path.
For instance, there are other scopes or other configurations like Compile only that is only included
in the compiler class path and runtime only.
So that's only included in the runtime class path.
So that's a very flexible system.
So the Creator can be used for dependency management and completely other contexts like this Java world.
It's good to know that it's possible, but if you care about developing Java or Kotlin or your Scala
projects, you don't have to worry about this.
So this was just to show you that this concept is there and that it could be extended or modified if
needed.
So let's get back of what to use exactly in the Java project.
So we use the implementation scope so far, and that's what you should always start with.
I mentioned the compile only scope.
This means that something is only available at compile time, but when the application run it's gone.
So this is something you really need.
Usually all your software, everything you develop and everything that you pull in needs to be there
at runtime.
Otherwise it can't do anything when the application runs.
There are certain edge cases like when environments already provide something in a kind of container
that just might be interesting.
But usually they're very little practical examples where you really need this.
Then something a bit more interesting.
It's a runtime only scope, so runtime only means it's not there at compile time.
So you never use any classes to compile code, but you just plug it into the class pass at runtime,
and then it's somehow found on the class path, probably by reflection of some other mechanism.
Example was useful is when there's a separation between an API and an implementation of something,
for example, a logging framework like self.
So as an example, we could add the SLA for API as an implementation dependency to the business logic
component.
And then in our print service, we can use it to do some logging.
If you run the application now, we'll get an error printed to the console that we try to lock, but
there is no implementation available, but we won't get any error at compile time because the compile
time the logging is not running, it's just compiling against the API.
And then we can go to our application project because that's the only place at the moment where the
code actually runs and at runtime only dependency to one of the SLA logger implementations.
So this is a useful use of runtime only.
This also makes the implementation exchangeable.
So if you use the business logic component in some other context, for example, we use it in another
application.
Then in that application you can add runtime only dependency to some other logging implementation.
Now the final scope I want to mention which you might encounter is API.
This is the scope you only have on Java libraries and not on applications for example.
API means that a dependency you add gets visible transit during compilation.
Concretely, it would mean if we would change the dependency to common slang here to API in the Business
Logic Project.
Common slang will also be seen in the project, which depends on the business logic project because
it gets visible.
Transitivity.
You can see this here.
At the moment we can't access any class from comments land in the implementation.
But if we doing the project again after we change to API, we can suddenly access classes from there.
Now if we really want to use classes here from Apache comments learn I would always suggest to also
add the dependency to the project so that you see in each project or each component what it's depending
on.
Otherwise, you quickly end up in a messy situation.
So I would be very careful with API because if use implementation you have components neatly isolated
and there's less risk that something is used by accident because it's just visible transitive like a
compilation during compilation, Java doesn't need to see everything, it just needs to see the things
it compiles directly against the things that is used in the internals of any of the dependencies.
Now.
Sometimes something needs to be visible, even if you don't use it directly.
For example, if you extend the class.
So the general rule of thumb would be if something is on the public API, it should be also an API dependency
in the example of our business logic project with the Commerce Lang dependency.
This would mean that somewhere in our service implementation we would put some type from common slang
on the public API, for example, as a return type of a public method doesn't really make sense here,
but that's how things become public API of the library and thus possibly consumers.
So other components that use a library like a project might need to see them.
However, in large projects, if you want to do the separation between API and implementation, it can
become very tedious.
One thing is just to stick with implementation, which is, from my perspective, a viable approach.
If you're going to use API, I would suggest to use some additional tooling that can tell you if something
is supposed to be an API dependency or not where the core doesn't offer any tooling here.
But as a plugin, the dependency analysis plugin which you can apply and which can analyze your source
code to tell you which dependencies should be API because they're used on public java, Kotlin Scala
or groovy API.
As I said, this was meant to give you an idea of what Gradle has with the Scopes configuration concept.
But as I said, for the fundamentals, for standard project setups, it's probably enough to use implementation
everywhere, possibly combined with runtime only if you have situations like with the local implementation
as shown in the examples.
And if you consider using API, it's most likely the best to use the dependency analysis plugin in combination
to tell you what should be API and not implementation.
Now that we have talked about scopes or configurations, the next thing we need to talk about are versions.