Hey.
Welcome to this course about Cradle.
Cradle.
It's one of the most advanced build tools for Java and other JVM based languages like Kotlin, Groovy
or Scala.
I'm Hendrik, and I worked on Gradle from version three to version seven.
I not only know most cradle features by heart, but also helped to develop best practices to structure
great builds such that they build efficiently and are maintainable.
In this course, I share my knowledge with you so that you can structure your software project with
Gradle and get the most out of it.
This course is hands on.
Together we will build up a project from scratch.
Learning greater features one by one.
We will do all this on the example of a Java project, but all the knowledge can be transferred to any
kind of software project built with Gradle.
So whatever automation task you would like to tackle this course is for you to learn how to unlock the
full power of Gradle.
No prior great knowledge is required and we will use the latest features and best practices of Gradle
seven.