In our example application.
So far we have written production code in several components and composed all of these together into
an application.
ESQUEDA We compiled the code and we ran the application.
Another typical development task is to write tests for your code.
Next to compile and code testing is the thing a great bird typically spends most of the time with.
So for typical Java or Groovy or Scala or Kotlin project testing is the last missing piece.
To get started.
There's another great concept you should know about, which is the concept of a source set.
The source said.
Gradle is a central place to configure where related sources are placed like Java source code and resources
like text files.
You also want to ship with your code and how these sources are processed by Gradle, for example, by
the compiler Java task.
So the central point of the source set is a folder where sources are located.
We already used one source set, which is the main source set.
So if we look into our Business Logic project, all our Java sources are in source main java and main
is the root folder of the main source set.
And because that is an explicit concept in Gradle, this is also how IntelliJ was able to detect that.
We have Java sources here because it gets the information from Gradle that there is a source set with
sources in it.
If we create a new folder in this project now an intelligent and look at the suggestions, we can also
see the term source set mentioned here.
So Gradle tells intelligence which source sets are potentially available and intelligent suggests us
to create the corresponding photos we see here that we could add a resources folder if next to our Java
code.
We want to have other resources available at runtime that we then read in our code.
And we also see that we can create folders for Java code or sources in the source set called test.
This faucet is also set up by default by the Java plugins.
And can be used for test code.
Let's create a folder for test classes.
Note that if you apply additional plugins for other JVM languages like the Groovy Plugin or the Kotlin
plugin, you will get a separate folder called Groovy or Kotlin inside the source set and then can place
implementations in the corresponding languages here.
And this works for every source.
So you can write code in Java or in groovy also for tests.
In some projects, for example, it's common to implement everything in Java but use groovy for testing.
In our convention plugin we could access the source sets through the source sets container.
You see that there's a source at the main and the source said, Stop test.
Here we can configure where all assets are located, for example.
So if for some reason you don't want to follow the standard layout of a project, you could change the
source directory here.
Usually, though, if you stick to the standard conventions, there is no need to reconfigure the pre-configured
source sets by the Java plugin.
What you might want to do, though, is create additional assets.
For example, if you need to write different types of tests, which, for example, use different testing
libraries.
In this case, you can use source sets that create to create a new source set, for example, one called
integration test.
We'll get back to this in a bit.
For now, let's start adding a test class as an example to our Business Logic Project.
In Java or other JVM languages.
Tests are written as classes that have test methods in them which cause the code under tests and then
do some assertions.
To do this, you always need a test framework.
The most popular ones are unit four or unit five.
We'll use J Unit five in this example.
To tell you at five that this is a test you need to use the test annotation on the method.
What we see, however, is that the test does not compile yet because unit five is not available.
This is because children at five needs to be declared as a dependency, just as any other Java library
we use in our code.
Let's go to the book file and look at our dependencies block.
So there's another important aspect about source sets.
Each source set inside a project can be looked at in isolation.
So in greater terms they are different variants or different features inside one project.
In theory, you could also put tests in a separate project.
With a similar setup.
It's just the common approach to the tests, together with a code that is tested by them.
Because of that, each toolset has its own dependency scopes and with that its own dependencies.
So next to implementation, we also have test implementation and in parallel we also have test runtime
only and so on.
So to have the G Unit five API available, which is also called Jupyter, we can add a dependency to
it using the test implementation scope or test implementation configuration.
We also need a version of Jaguar files that we want to use.
In this case, I'm sticking with the platform set up for centralized version.
So in our platform build gradle, we add a dependency to such a unit five bom.
Going back to the file.
Such a unit five unit only needs the API.
You also need an engine to execute the tests.
They are different engines because the unit five cannot only execute standard unit five tests, but
for example, also a unit for tests with a different engine.
As we write the unit five tests, we add the standard engine, and the engine is something you can add
to test runtime only.
Because we depend on the G Unit five bomb through our platform.
All J Unit five dependencies get a version if we think our project now.
And go back to our test class.
We see that everything compiles now.
And if we create additional source sets like the integration tests or asset.
We also get corresponding dependency scopes.
To define different dependencies for that source set.
And also intelligence will suggest us to add folders for this additional source set.
So that's an important aspect of the greater project model to understand, especially if you work with
tests, because then you're not only have your main sources in a project, but also have other source
code for testing in lots projects.
You may want to have different kind of tests and then having several tests or sets might be a good setup
because each source set may have its own dependencies.
But before we can run the tests, we still need to do some configuration of the test task, which is
the task executing the tests.
Let's look at this in the next lecture.