Going back to the dependencies blocks of our built files, we see that we have started to set up versions
in several files, even similar versions.
So we have the logger API and the logger implementation.
But one is the dependency in the business logic component, the other in the app component in a good
project setup.
These versions should all go from the book Gradle Files because the versions should be aligned everywhere
independent of where dependencies are.
Because in the end, when we have the runtime class path of the complete application, there can always
only be one version of a certain dependency because that's how Java is working.
It can't load different versions of the same class, for example.
At least not without combining it with other runtime environments.
Like for most Java or Java related setups, you don't want any duplication of classes.
So what Grail is doing?
If there are different versions of a thing, it will do a conflict resolution deciding to pick only
one of these versions and to avoid unnecessary conflicts and clean versions set up.
It's good to centralize the versions in one place.
There are two different solutions provided by Gradle, which are both valid for use.
The one is a so called platform project, the other is a so called dependency versions catalog.
Both have advantages and disadvantages, so I'm going to show you both of them.
And then if you have a related project, you can see which one fits best in your case.
It also doesn't really matter which one you choose as long as you do the centralization, that's a really
important step.
So let's start with a platform concept, a related concept you should understand first is the concept
of dependency constraints.
This allows us to separate the dependency to a component like the group and the name coordinates from
the version.
We can do this directly in the file here so we can remove the version from the common slang dependency,
only keeping the group in the name.
And then instead we add a dependency constraint in the dependency constraints block.
Dependency constraints are just notated like dependencies.
But they don't add a dependency.
They don't lead to common slang available be available in this project.
They just say, if you want common lung, here's some information about which version to pick.
That's why these constraints here can be added to all of our projects without changing anything on the
dependencies.
But if we take these constraints and put them into a central place, then we can re-use that everywhere.
Such a central place is a platform project.
A platform project is a separate Gradle project.
You could add it just as another sub project, but for good structuring because this is more gradle
related thing.
I prefer to put it also into the gradle directory.
So I do it as a separate included built called Gradle platform.
So what I will do now I'll go back to our settings file and add another small included build which I
put into the cradle slash platform directory.
Now because this is also a great build.
It can get a build greater CTS file.
And then because this is a Java platform, we apply the Java platform plugin.
And into the dependency constraint.
BLOCK We put the dependency constraints we had before.
Note that in a Java platform project, the only scope or configuration you need is API.
The others are also not available.
This means that the constraints are always visible to the outside transitivity, which makes sense.
Remember that defining the constraints doesn't add any dependencies.
A constraint for certain dependency is only used if that dependency turns up through a dependency declaration
one of our components.
Otherwise, the constraints are just not put into action.
Now what is the Java platform compared to, let's say, a Java library?
It's quite similar.
Only that a platform only defines dependency constraints and possibly also dependencies.
So it doesn't have any code or any jar or anything like that attached to it.
It's basically like a library minus the actual code.
So concept of a Java platform on Gradle is inspired from the concept of builds of materials which you
might know from Maven.
Build of material in that context is just a file XML file that basically contains dependency constraints
information.
So many libraries on Maven Central that are composed of several components that have the same version.
Also publish a bomb, which is in greater terms, a platform or a Java platform.
So if you find the term bomb in some dependency, you can think of this as the same as the Java platform
and Gradle.
In addition to defining dependency constraints here, we can also define dependencies to another platform
which will pull in all the dependency constraints defined in that platform.
As an example, we could add the bottom of the JSON processing libraries checksum.
For libraries that don't have a bomb, we add directly a constraint here.
So this platform we have created is now just a collection of version constraints.
So tells us something about the versions we want to use if needed.
If you make this platform available in all of our components, the resolution engine of Gradle will
pick versions from here.
If we have dependencies that need a version.
So how do we make the platform available?
We can do it by adding a dependency to our platform similar to how we add dependencies to other platforms
here.
We need to make sure that we set a group for the platform so that we can address it as something to
depend on.
And now we add a dependency to the platform in our Business Logic Project.
Make sure for platform dependency to always use the platform keyword.
This is needed because there may be components that provide both a platform and an actual implementation.
So this makes sure that Gradle chooses the platform in this case.
This is again related to configurations or variants in dependency management.
So since we want to use the same dependency versions everywhere, we should add the platform dependency
to all of our components and all our build files, and then we can remove the versions everywhere.
Note that you could also add this dependency in our base convention plugin.
Then you don't need to copy paste it into all the build files.
In such cases, I think both solutions are fine because copying it here still shows us very clearly
what our components depend on.
So a little bit of duplication in this case isn't too bad in my mind.
We learned about the concept of dependency constraints, which allow you to separate the dependency
definition from the version.
And we have looked at platforms as a concept to collect constraints so that you have some in central
place which you can then reuse in all your components.
An alternative to separating version from the dependencies is to centralize the complete dependency
with the version in the dependency version catalog.
We look at this alternative now.