To test our code.
We have written a test using unit five and edit the corresponding dependencies in the build gradle file
of the Business Logic Project.
But before we can run the test, we still need a bit of configuration to do.
Tests are running gradle by a task.
The test task, which is a quite powerful task that not only supports several test frameworks but also
allows you to run tests in parallel.
We configure the task in our base convention plugin so that it's the same for all our projects.
We configure it as we have learned by accessing it through the tasks container.
So the task is called tasks dot test.
The first thing to configure is which test framework to use by default.
The task is for historic reasons configured to use.
Table four.
We say that we want to use Unit five by the used unit platform statement.
Another important property is Mac's Parallel Forks option.
If you set this option, Gradle will run tests in parallel.
It's good to set this option in almost all cases because then creator can make better use of the resources
of the machine it is running on and the test run will finish faster.
Technically created for separate processes to run the tests.
That's why the option is called parallel forks on the separate processes created and gives control to
unit five or whichever framework you selected, which is then executing the tests and sending reports
back to Gradle.
There are many other details you may configure here.
One thing that could be interesting is that you can define the memory of the four processes.
So if you have tests that are very memory hungry, you can modify the max memory.
While we talk about parallel execution, there's also another flag you should set in your properties,
which is the parallel flag.
If you do that, you allow Gradle to execute tasks from different projects in parallel.
So if you do that and if, for example, have tests and our data model and or business logic project,
then well would be able to also execute these tests in parallel because it's also like there can always
be one task running.
This is an opt in right now because in theory, tasks from different projects could have dependencies
between each others that are not integrated.
This is because you can do so many things using the Kotlin or groovy language when you configure your
tests.
However, if you follow a clean project setup with convention plugins, as we learned about in this
course, you won't have these issues and you can safely turn on parallel, which will in some way become
a default in future gradle versions.
If we know this configuration intelligence and go back to our test.
Intelligence offers us to run the test directly here.
If we do that, intelligence will launch the greater test task, execute the tests and pick up the results
from Gradle again.
We can see that our test was successful.
You can also find the test results in an HTML report written into the build folder of the project.
For many projects, though, set up might be enough.
But as mentioned already, sometimes it makes sense to split tests into several groups.
There are two ways to do that.
One is to have several test tasks that just execute a certain selection of tests from the test source,
said one other source.
The other option is to add an additional source set with another test task on top of it.
The difference is that the second source said physically separate the tests.
So you put them into a separate folder and you also can define different kind of dependencies or even
use the different test frameworks for that.
Let's first look at option one, which is registering an additional test task for the test.
So set.
As we've learned, we use tasks to register to register a new task.
Let's call it test slow.
This task is of type test, which is again a task implementation provided by greater core force.
It's the same type that the test task that the Java plugin already does has.
Now to make this task work for the source said, we need to do a bit of manual setup because this is
a newly registered task.
Basically the task needs to know about two things where the tests are located and what the class path
of the tests is.
These things are configured by the test classes, the property and the class plus property.
And we can get the information from the source set.
So there's nothing individual we need to do.
We just need to do this wiring up.
And everything else is test toss configuration as we did before.
So let's also use unit five here by saying use the platform.
Then we would also like to have our additional test task run.
Always when someone calls, build or check.
So we wired into the check lifecycle task.
As we have learned by using the depends on keyword.
If we would run check now it will execute both our test tasks and both will execute all the tests in
the test source set.
So all our tests would run twice.
That does not yet make much sense.
Instead, we would like to filter tests.
Which is a feature that is provided by the Unit five directly.
So the Unit five allows us to define so-called tests on the tests to categorize them.
In our example, we would like to separate slower tests to make them run by the tests load task.
And we could introduce a tech called SLO for that and annotate the corresponding test for set.
And then in the task configuration, we say that the default test task should exclude all tests annotated
with slow and the new test slow task should include all tests with Zetec Annotated slow, and by that
automatically exclude all other tests.
With this setup, we split the execution of tests from the test set into two groups.
This could be used, for example, to make it clear that certain tests are quite slow and probably only
should run on the AI, so that if you run tests locally, they would be excluded.
But they won't be excluded if you do a complete check run.
So the other options to split up tests is to use additional source sets.
We already created a source set called Integration Test just to show that you can do that if we now
actually want to use the source set to define tests in them.
We can do the same as we did before for the test set, which is registering a test task.
So we would just start test task.
In this case, we can call it like the source set.
So it's called integration test.
And then again, we set the test last year and the class pass.
In this case, we get the information from the integration test source set.
Also here, we say that we want to use unit five.
And now we could do the same as we did for the test set up.
We can create a folder for integration tests.
We could add test classes to this.
And in the boot file we add dependencies to the G Unit five API and the runtime for the integration
tests.
And now we could, for example, add additional dependencies to some testing libraries we won't like
to use for integration testing which we don't want to have for the other tests.
Testing software is an important topic, and Gradle offers a lot of options to set up testing.
In this lecture, we saw the most important things to configure, which is the test framework dependencies
for tests, parallel test execution and different options to add additional test tasks to split up tests
in a project in to multiple sets.
With this.
You now know the fundamentals for structuring a modern gradle build and compiling and testing coordinate.
In the example, we always use Java as a language, but it works similar for other JVM language like
Kotlin Scala or Groovy.
And even if you do other things, just cradle all automation with cradle uses the same concepts and
follow similar patterns as the ones we have explored on this example.
For everything I showed, I used the Kotlin DSL.
So before the course comes to an end, I want to show you alternatives to this.