Let's start this course with a quick overview of what Gradle is and what is useful.
Gradle is called a build tool, but you can also look at it as a tool to describe or model your software.
So it is gradle over the language, domain specific language or DSL to describe how your software project
is structured.
For example, an application written in Java composed of multiple Java libraries or components.
Once you have done the description in Gradle, see ASL.
This model can be interpreted by tools to help you develop the software and to build the software to
get the final application.
These tools are great in itself, which can build the application or run test for it and other automation
tasks in your development and deployment pipeline.
But also other tools like an ID can read this model.
For example, IntelliJ idea, which we'll use in this course, can use Gradle to read the model that
describes your project, and then it can show you the project in a structured way in the IDE and give
you additional tool support like navigating between classes of different projects and things like that.
So it's helpful to look at Gradle primarily as a tool that describes the structure of your software
project and learn how to do that with the DSL cradle of us.
That's the perspective we'll take in this course.
How was this done concretely?
Technically great.
Dstl is a java API, so any job based language like Kotlin, Groovy or Java itself can potentially be
used to describe a software project in greater terms.
To make this convenient cradle of the Scotland version of its DSL and a groovy version of its DSL.
This basically means that next to the greater specific constructs, you can use any means of the Kotlin
or groovy language to extend or customize Gradle.
While this is a powerful feature in certain places, it can be harmful because by having the full power
of a programming language available, you can do things that lead to a hard to understand project structure
or even break rails caching or environmental building functionality.
So in this course, we'll mostly stick to the specific notations and I'll show you best practices you
can follow that won't require you to step out of this greater world.
If you follow this, it almost doesn't matter if you use the Kotlin or the groovy DSL as a notations
in most cases can be identical.
So in this course we use the Kotlin Dstl because it offers the best integration with the intelligent
idea IDE, which we are also going to use.
By the end of the course.
I'll also get a bit into the Groovy Dstl so that if you look for more documentation on a certain feature
online and find solutions in the groovy dstl, it's easier for you to map them to the corresponding
content annotation at the end of the course.
I will also talk about how you can use Java to configure your variables.
So if you are not familiar with neither Kotlin nor Groovy and don't want to learn it in detail just
because of Gradle, you can do a lot of things directly in Java and then only need to know about some
greater specific constructs where it almost doesn't matter that you use Kotlin or Groovy.
So when we start now to build up a project with the Dstl don't think that it is Kotlin code when we
write a greater configuration file, but think that this is greater configuration in the greater dstl
that we use to describe the structure of our software project.