What do we do if the task that we want to use is not available as an implementation yet?
Then we can implement it ourselves as we've seen earlier.
The task implementation is a Java class.
More concretely, it's a Java class that extends a certain grader type default task and uses some gradle
annotations in our plugins build where we have all convention plugins.
We can also add other source code and so implement the task here directly.
Let's do an example of such a task.
Assume we want to count the job files that make up our application and write the result to a file which
we then can potentially ship with the application.
Let's look what the task should offer if we register it.
So in our application convention plug in, we do a task register again and say we assume that we have
an implementation for Jar Count task, which we call a conscious.
In the task.
We'd like to have an input.
Let's call it all jobs to which we can add the jobs we want to count.
Similar to what we did in the zip task before.
We now add the job from the project and the runtime class path which will provide all the jobs of the
dependencies.
Then we would like to have an output.
Let's call it count file, which contains the number of jars in the end.
We set it to a file in the directory.
No, because the tax limitation doesn't exist yet.
We get this across here.
So now let's do the implementation.
A task can be implemented in any JVM language as long as the greater project you implement it in is
configured to support that language.
Because we are already in the Cotton Project here, we can use it and either implement the task in Scotland
or in Java because I assume that most of you are more familiar with Java.
I'll do the implementation in Java now.
For that.
We also add the Java source folder.
And then we create a new Java class in it.
We put it in the sample greater package and call it as we would expect when we just ring the task.
Which is now a task implementation can be abstract because then Gradle will fill some of the implementation
for us.
Then we need to extend the default task of Gradle itself.
The next thing is to define the input and output properties.
Gradle by now offers its own types for these.
This is important because if you use the greater specific types, the input and output wiring works
so that if you set an output of another task to the input of another one creating the relationship.
We can also work with simple Java types like string or file.
But if you use these, you will lose this connection and create a rule no about the task dependencies
because if you set the input to a simpler file, they have no relationship back to the task where this
file is produced from.
So if you create a value task nowadays, please use the greater specific types.
Even if some older tutorials still might suggest otherwise.
Let's start with the input property which we call all just.
In Java, properties are represented by getters.
So we add an abstract method which we call get all the get will automatically be stripped in the code
landslide.
So it will just be called or just the.
Together, get the type configurable file collection, which is a greater type to use.
When you want to express that, you can add arbitrary many files or folders to an input.
And the Tegretol.
That is an input of multiple files.
You also need to add the add input files annotation.
Alternatively, there are also types for single file, which is called regular file property and for
single directory called directory property.
For these you need slightly different annotations called input file or input directory.
If you use these, you also need to use the corresponding annotation, which is input file or input
directory.
Now the scatter is abstract, and this type here is an interface.
But that's enough for Gradle.
By the annotation, Gradle will discover this and will automatically create a concrete subclass at one
time with which creates an instance of an object that implements the interface.
So we don't have to keep care of that.
That's great.
Internal injection and firing mechanism.
Now we can do the same for the output here.
We want to have a single file as output, so we use regular file property as type.
We call it get count file because count file is the name of the property we want to use and we annotate
it with at output file because now we have the type with the inputs and outputs.
You can already go back to our convention plugin and we can import the char count task.
And then this clip doesn't have any errors anymore.
Taking a closer look, though, from is a notation from the configurable file collection type that we
used for the old jars property.
So this is something the greater standard types provide for us.
For the count file, which is the regular file property, you get a set method which is also provided
by GRAIL'S property concept to set the value.
Now, what we didn't do yet is implement the actual task action.
So the actual thing the task should do to provide a task action implementation.
You create a Java method in the task implementation class.
You can choose an arbitrary name.
Important is that you add the task action annotation to the method.
Then where the will find this method when the task needs to be executed and run the code inside this
method.
So in the method you typically first access inputs, you can then use a get or get files method to map
the specific type to Java standard types, which you know about.
In this moment.
Well will also access get the files if they are not yet received.
So one reason for this property system in Gradle, in addition to figuring out past dependencies is
that things are done as lazy as possible.
So what we have here is inputs are references to jobs and not necessarily actual job files that already
exist in a certain location.
So Gradle only builds or downloads the charts when it's needed.
But he has a task.
We definitely need the input files so we can safely call the get or get files method.
In this case, we call get files and then just call size because we just care about the amount of files.
For output.
The count file.
We do the same and map it down to a java file.
Then we use standard Java functionality to write the size of the old jobs list to the count file.
If we want cradle to catch the results of the task.
We also need to annotate the task with that task, which often makes sense.
Sometimes there are cases where writing and retrieving from the cache is considered more expensive than
the actual task.
In this case, task explicitly not made catchable.
This, for example, the case for the task.
With this, we have finished implementing and registering our very own task.
Let's go back to where we were just as a task and also add a group and a description.
If we do our project intelligent now we can see that our new task also turns up in the task list.
Let's Tegretol to execute the task.
Again, we can see how the dependencies.
So the other tasks, for example, are all executed before.
If we rerun the build, we can see that incremental compensation.
So up to date checking also works for our very own task implementation.
And we can find the result.
The text file with the number in it inside the build folder.
We could now, for example, extend our bundle task to also take the output of our task as input to
bundle this file as well.
We have seen how Gradle allows you to implement custom build logic and plug it into Gradle seamlessly.
If you already use convention plugins and already have a plugin build, it's a small step to add a task
implementation as part of this plugins.
You can add it to the source folders that are already available.
If you use inputs and outputs with the greater specific types, this task can be wired into the task
setup you already have and will be executed as part of your build if necessary.
Up to date, checking and even caching works for custom inputs and outputs.