First off, if you're working in an XA environment,
then you don't really need to worry too much about
transactions and acknowledgement modes.
The Transaction Manager will commit anything that has occurred on
the session when the transaction completes.
If some form of unhandled exception occurs, then the transaction is rolled back.
Known XA sessions need a bit more thought though.
We have seen when creating a JMS session that there are two
parameters that are passed to the CreateSession method.
Now if you pass transacted true,
then the acknowledgement mode parameter is ignored.
Any operations on the session will take place within a local transaction,
not a JTA transaction.
If you leave transacted false,
then the acknowledgement mode parameter will be used.
There are three possible options,
which primarily deals with messages which are received
during this session and acknowledged.
We have already used AUTO_ACKNOWLEDGED.
In this mode,
the session will automatically acknowledge the client's receipt of the message.
This will therefore mean the message has been marked as
delivered and is not eligible to be delivered again.
Another option is DUPS_OK_ACKNOWLEDGE.
In this mode, the session may lazily acknowledge the receipt of the message.
This could be read that it will acknowledge it at some later point.
If there is a failure in the client or the server before
that acknowledgement actually takes place,
then it is possible that the message may be delivered again.
Therefore,
your system must be able to deal with duplicates of the same
message in order to use this acknowledgment mode.
There is also a third option called CLIENT_ACKNOWLEDGEMENT.
In this case,
it is the developer's responsibly to ensure that the acknowledge method is
called on the received message at the correct point.
However, beware, although the acknowledgement method is on the message object,
it actually applies at the session level,
so all messages that have been consumed in this session will be acknowledged, so watch out for that.