In the previous section, I showed you how to consume messages from a queue.
In this section, I'll show you the equivalent for a topic.
But I'm only going to show the consumption using a messageListener approach.
There are only a small number of changes,
so if you do require the polling method that we saw in the previous section,
then I think you will be able to work it out pretty easily.
First off,
I'm going to rename the consumeFromDestination method that I created
earlier to something a little bit more suitable,
which is consumeFromQueue, which more correctly reflects what it does.
Then I'll create a new copy of that method, and rename it consumeFromTopic.
The only real implementation detail change is that I'm
consuming from a topic rather than a queue,
but as I already mentioned earlier,
if you pass the destination object into an equivalent method,
then it could be used to consume from either or a queue or a topic.
Back to our main method,
and I'll make a few small changes here to show that we are
calling the consumeFromTopic method,
and that the name of our topic should change, but other than that, it's pretty much identical.