The problem with non-durable topic subscriptions is that if
you are not actively consuming messages,
then typically you do not receive any messages that were published
to the topic while the client was disconnected.
We get around this by using a durable subscription.
If I go back to the consumeFromTopic method,
than rather than calling createConsumer,
I can change it to createDurableSubscriber,
which returns a TopicSubscriber object,
which we will also return from our method.
Now, we also need to provide the name of our subscription.
It's entirely up to you what you want to call it,
but in my case, I'm going to use test-subscription.
Back in my main method,
I'm changing the message consumer to a TopicSubscriber
and changing all the references to it.
Now you can see here I'm still closing the TopicSubscriber, that's important.
When you close a durable subscription,
we are basically saying to the message broker,
keep any messages for me until I connect or start again.
We actually need to do one other thing,
which is define a client ID on our connection.
Again, this is pretty much what you want it to be,
depending on your application.
I've just added something arbitrary here.
When you no longer want to keep messages on the
broker while you're disconnected, then you need to close TopicSubscriber,
but you also need to call unsubscribe on the session using
the same subscription ID we used earlier, which in my case is test-subscription.