Hi, this is Grant Little from Pluralsight,
and welcome to this Practical Enterprise JMS Playbook.
Let's quickly go over some of the content in this course.
To start with, we'll look at should you consider using JMS at all,
some of the pros and cons of using JMS,
we'll be using Apache's ActiveMQ in our examples and demonstrations,
so we will look at getting enough information to get it up and running.
We will then cover off some basic JMS use cases.
This course does assume you already have some JMS knowledge,
as it's not a beginner's JMS course,
but I have included this as a place you can go back to
and refer to for some basic use cases.
We then look at some more advanced use cases and some of the JMS
features that can typically be useful in an enterprise
environment or for more advanced scenarios.
We then look at some of the frameworks available that
make working with JMS a breeze.
We will look at using JMS with both the Spring Framework and
also within a Java Enterprise Edition, OR JEE environment.
Once you have your code developed,
then you will also need to think about administering and
monitoring your application when it's in the wild, so we will touch on some techniques that can help with that.