To get message listening to work using annotations,
for basic use case, there isn't actually much more we need to do.
We already have most of the wiring in place,
including the MessageConverter we want to use,
the ConnectionFactory, and the EnableJMS annotation on our configuration.
Creating a JMS consumer with Spring annotations is really quite simple.
I've got a component here named EMailMessageListener.
Inside that, I've got a method called onMessage,
which takes an email object as a parameter.
This will be the email that we receive from the queue.
In this case, we simply output the email to the console.
The method is annotated with a JmsListener annotation.
This is a marker for the Spring Framework to create a new
instance of a default messageListener container.
When it starts, it will deliver email messages to this method.
Most of the attributes on this annotation are used to create the container,
for example, the destination name, in this case the Emails queue,
and the number of consumers we want.
In our example,
we want dynamic scaling with a minimum of 3 consumers and a maximum of 10.
There is also an option to declare a messageSelector
attribute here if you require one.
So that's it, pretty simple, eh?
Let's just actually prove it works though.
In an earlier section, we created an email producer,
so we should have messages on our emails queue.
Let's start the application up, and see if they get consumed.
In the output, I can see that the messages are now consumed.
If I jump quickly into the ActiveMQ Admin console,
then I can see on the Emails queue that we have a number of consumers,
which will scale up or down depending on load.
Now if you've noticed, I've explicitly said the destination was the Emails queue.
What if we wanted to use a topic?
Well under the hood, a bit like the JmsTemplate,
the DefaultMessageListenerContainer assumes the destination is a queue.
Therefore, we need to define some configuration for connecting to topics.
However, rather than creating a DefaultMessageListenerContainer directly,
we instead define a factory class that is responsible for creating them.
In this piece of code,
I'm creating a new instance of a DefaultJmsListenercontainerFactory,
giving it a Bean name of TopicListenerContainerFactory,
and setting some default properties.
As this factory is for topics, I call the setPubSubDomain method,
and set the value to true.
I'm going to use the JacksonMessageConverter for message conversion.
I'm also going to assume it's a durable subscription,
therefore I need to define a clientId that is injected as a property.
I'm also setting concurrency to a minimum and maximum of 1.
For topics, it doesn't make sense to set it to anything other than 1; otherwise,
the consumers will all receive exactly the same message.
I have then created another service called OrderMessageListener.
I have another onMessage method,
which is decorated with the JmSListener annotation.
This time I've declared the ConnectionFactory attribute,
and set it to the name of the Factory Bean we've just created,
which is the TopicListenerContainerFactory.
I've also defined the name of the subscription, which is orders.
So you can see this is fairly simple,
and it will in fact receive any order messages that
are sent to the orders queue.
If you do want to receive the raw JMS message,
rather than the order object,
you can do this by simply changing the parameter from an order to a JMS message, and that is what you'll receive.