Sometimes messages need to be consumed based on some priority,
although you can't guarantee this,
you can give hints to the message broker to at least try.
Jumping back to the sendMessageToTopic method,
and by the way, you can do this for queues as well,
on the messageProducer, I'm calling the setPriority method,
passing in a value of 9, which is the highest priority,
0 is the lowest, and 4 is the default if it's not set.
Generally priority 0 to 4 are considered normal priority,
while 5 to 9 are expedited.
Doing it this way will mean all messages sent by the
messageProducer will have a priority of 9.
If you do want to do it on a message-by-message basis,
then you need to do it a different way.
In this case, you need to use a different variant of the send method.
You still pass the message as the first parameter,
second is the delivery mode, which I've set to be NON_PERSISTENT,
and the third is the message priority.
So to be realistic,
this would probably become a parameter of the sendTextMessageToTopic method,
and then set here.
The fourth parameter is the set time to live, which we'll come to in a second.
Doing it on the send method allows you to control
the priority for every message.
Sometimes a message might have a finite lifespan,
for example, you might expect a message to be processed within 10 seconds.
If it hasn't,
then some other part of the system will notice that
message hasn't been processed and try again.
You don't want lots of these messages building up in your queues or topics.
In this situation, you want them to expire.
Again, we can do this for all the messages sent by a messageProducer,
by setting the time to live on that producer.
The value is in milliseconds with a default of 0,
meaning the messages don't expire.
Similar to the message priority, we can also set it on a per-message basis.
Again, to be relevant in this situation,
it would probably be more likely to be passed in as a parameter to the sendTextMessageToTopic method.