Generally I prefer to have a reusable Bean that I use for sending messages.
This takes care of most of the required boilerplate code,
leaving the bare requirements up to the calling client.
So here I've got a local Bean interface defined.
It currently has a single method called sendMessage, which takes two parameters.
The destination message is to be sent to,
and a Java 8 function that takes a session object as the input parameter,
and returns a JMS message object.
Now if you aren't yet using Java 8,
then you probably have to replace this with a custom callback
interface of some description that can be invoked.
So to the implementation of this interface,
I'm declaring a stateless session Bean,
in that I'm using the resource annotation to inject the
ConnectionFactory using its JNDI name.
In the SendMessage method,
I'm creating a new connection session and messageProducer objects.
Well hopefully this will have raised some alarm bells with you.
If you've watched the earlier modules in this course,
then you'll recall that I said it was good practice
to cache or pool the connections, sessions,
and message producers.
So why have I broken this rule?
Well I haven't really.
The difference is we are in a Java Enterprise Edition container,
and that container has taken on the responsibility of
doing that caching and pooling for you.
So you don't need to be worried about it.
When you close a connection, for example,
it's not really closing it,
it's simply putting the connection back into a pool of
available connections for reuse by other processes.
Once I've created all the objects I need,
then I invoke the messageCreator function passed in,
passing in a reference to the session object.
This function returns the JMS message object,
which we then send to the required destination.
If I scroll down a bit,
you will notice this massive final section of the tricatch block,
in which I'm closing all the available resources.
This is why I like to create this style of reusable session Bean.
I can take care of all this nonsense in one place, rather than littering my code base with tricatch blocks.