I've got another example to demonstrate something,
it's similar to the previous example where we use the default messageListener
container to consume messages using multiple cached consumers.
When using multiple consumers,
the JMS API doesn't stipulate that the messages are delivered in order.
The consumers are basically competing with each other
to take a message from the queue.
But then we get into race conditions within the various
threads to process those messages.
From the output you can see on the screen,
it's clear that the messages we're processed in order.
This is because of the competing consumers within the default
messageListener container implementation.
So what if your system requires your messages to be
delivered in a specific order?
For example,
you don't want a message on a queue representing an
update operation for a customer order,
if the customer order hasn't already been created yet.
This is a real-world problem.
Now it's best if you can architect your application to deal with these events.
If you receive an update event for an order that hasn't been created yet,
then maybe you can place that message back at the end of the queue
or on to another queue for processing later on.
Maybe use message priorities with creates having a higher priority.
There are various techniques for dealing with this.
Another option that is part of the JMS API is to
guarantee the ordering of messages.
Now this approach does have a downside.
It means that only one consumer can ever process the messages,
so it affects throughput.
That's a tradeoff you'll have to think about and deal with.
So on to the code.
I've restructured the example to try and make it a little
bit more clear as to what's going on.
I'm still creating five consumers; however,
this time I'm using the index of the for loop to identify the
messageListener being assigned to each consumer.
This just makes it a bit clearer in the console output.
If the for loop index is an even number,
then it uses a fast operation, and if it is odd,
a slow operation.
The important bit is on the sender's side.
So I've overwritten the method that sends my 100 messages onto the queue.
In this case though,
I'm using the index of the for loop to determine if it's odd or even.
I then use a specific string property on the message,
which is the JMSXGroupID, and set it to one of two values,
odd or even.
This tells the message broker that all messages with the
even value should go to a single consumer,
and all messages with the odd value should go to another consumer.
Now the message broker effectively makes the decision
of which consumer to send it to,
but if for some reason the consumer goes offline,
then the message broker will start sending the messages to another consumer,
so there is still a level of failover, which is important.
Generally I recommend setting the JMSXGroupID to the lowest common denominator,
for example, an order number, an account number,
or a customer identifier.
This will help ensure the maximum amount of throughput possible.
If you set the properties to something like order,
then all order messages are going to go to one consumer,
which may not be able to process them quickly enough to avoid backlogs.
So let's run this example.
In the output, even though I have five consumers available,
I can see only two are being used.
Notice that overall the messages are out of order,
but all even-ordered messages are being processed in order, and all all-number messages are also being processed in order.