So here I've got a Singleton session Bean that has the MessageSender
implementation injected into it using the EJB annotation.
I'm also looking up the Emails queue destination and
injected it via the resource annotation.
I then have a method called sendEmail that takes three pieces
of required information to send an email,
the email address, the subject, and the message body or content.
I call sendMessage method on the message sender with the
emails queue as the first parameter.
The second parameter is a lambda that gives me access to the session object,
which I then use to create a text message.
To send the email, I'm storing the email address and subject,
a string properties,
and the body of the email is the main text within the message.
Hopefully there is nothing really new here if
you've been following this playbook.
So what invokes this sendEmail method?
Well, in the real world,
you would have some client that would invoke this
whenever an email needs to be sent.
For simplicity of demonstration,
I have a simple scheduled job that executes the sendEmail method
every 5 seconds with the same information.
So, we will effectively get many copies of the same email on the queue, but the example serves the purpose of showing how the JMS interaction works.