Hello and welcome back to the course of machine learning.
Today we're talking about the intuition behind the a priori algorithm.
So let's get started.
And we're going to get started by talking about a story.
It's a somewhat legend of data science or religion that is quite well known and in a sense you may have
heard of this alleged It's not a myth.
It actually happened.
But as you know the things that happened a long time ago and then time passes and the facts get the
story.
But I'll tell you my story of this legend and it might not be exactly correct but this is how I know
about and how I've heard about it.
So what do you think the commonality is between these two products Pampers or diapers and beer.
What do you think they have in common and why are they part of this urban legend.
Why are they part of the state of science.
Well as the story goes.
A company we are not going to name the company but a company that is actually actually like a convenience
store and did some analytics around the products that people are purchasing.
And so they were looking at you know what people are checking out with.
What are the commonalities and they analyzed thousands and thousands and thousands of transactions so
thousands of people who actually checked out if not tens of thousands and they found a very interesting
thing that very often during certain times of the day when people shop in the afternoon between 6 and
9 p.m..
People who buy diapers also buy beer and it was like out of the blue completely out of the blue like
how why these two prices completely not connected right.
Why would somebody buy beer when they're buying diapers or why buy diapers when they're buying beer.
Right.
So that was the fact that they came across in the data and the explanations as fact.
One of the plausible explanations is that in the afternoons or in the evenings when the husband gets
home and they're look like him though her husband and the wife are taking care of their baby.
They sometimes find that they run out of diapers and who has to go pick up the diapers of all the husband
has to go pick up the diapers.
Right.
Or the wife sends a husband to go pick up the diapers and while he's picking up the diapers because
it's really after hours after work.
He also he's already in the convenience store.
He also picks up some beer.
Right.
And so that is a plausible explanation might be case might not be the case but sounds reasonable and
based on that so that's something that you can really think of it just by yourself.
But that comes from the data.
Right.
And based on that you can decide how to arrange products in your store right.
So some stores might decide to put these two closer to entice people to buy a beer when they're buying
diapers.
But actually a lot of stores do the opposite.
There are a lot of stores separate beer and diapers right just like they try to separate and you probably
noticed this from your convenience store that they try to separate bread and milk as far as possible.
Why.
Because that way they really know that these two products are bought together.
And so you actually have to walk through the whole store to pick up.
You know you've picked up your bread and then to get to the milk you have to get all the way through
the whole store to the completely opposite corner of the store.
So as you're walking through the store you see more other products and you're more likely to pick up
an additional item that you weren't actually planning on buying when you got to the store in the first
place.
So there's a lot of interesting marketing tactics that are used based on this data.
But the question is how do you get to this data.
And one of the ways to get to it is that a priori algorithm.
So let's talk about a priori and a bit more detail now.
All right.
So it really is about people who bought something also bought something else or watched something also
or something else who did something also did something else so it analyzes and this whole association
rule learning part of course is all about analyzing when things come in pairs or in triplicates or in
in C not in sequence but they are combined together for some reason looking for those rules and those
ways that this happens.
All right so let's have a look for instance.
Movie recommendation right.
So you've got your user IDs you've got two movies that the people liked.
Movie 1 2 3 4 movie 1 and 2 for the second person and so on.
And from here just by looking at it even if out not knowing anything about Association rule learning
or a priori the a priori algorithm you can really tell that there are some potential rules that can
come out of this that for instance everybody who watches movie one.
Everybody but it is likely that people who watch movie one will or who like movie one will also like
movie number two.
And people who like movie Number two are quite likely to also like moving on before.
And people who look like in a movie a one are also quite likely to be like movie number three.
So you can you can come up with lots of different potential rules but some are going to be stronger
some are going to be weaker and we want to find the very strong ones in order to build our business
decisions or other decisions on those rules.
We can see in the data right we don't have to go and ask people hey do you like movie number one and
would you like movie number two because of that.
Do you like movie number two or what does it taste and preference we can see this thing from the data
and we want to extract this information and as long as our you know we have a large enough sample size
it's not just like five people if it's 50000 or 500000 people that we're analyzing we can come up with
quite some quite solid rules.
All right so here's another example where we've got a market basket so example of people who buy grocer
not just groceries but more kind of like a restaurant or a takeaway place.
And here you can see there's a link obviously in burgers and french fries.
Interesting.
Vegetables and fruits.
People trying to be healthy burgers French fries and ketchup.
Again these are potential rules not necessarily the ones that we're going to take away from there.
This is just an example of something that you might observe visually just by looking at the deficit.
All right.
So how does the a priori algorithm work.
Well the apriori algorithm has three parts to it.
It's got the support the confidence and the lift.
So we're going to start up with the support and you will see that it's very similar to something we've
already discussed.
It's very similar to the way we talked about intuition for the Beijing for the Navy base classifiers.
So let's have a look here.
We were movie recommendations support for movie M is the number is defined as the number of users who
watched movie divided by the total number of users.
Right.
And market Buskin optimization same thing.
Number of transactions containing an item I divided by the total number of transactions.
Let's have a look at an illustration here we've got 100 people so we've got five rows and 20 columns
of human beings.
And let's see how many of them let's say we're talking about a movie.
And I'm going to give an example of one of my favorite movies ex machina.
And if you haven't seen it definitely check it out.
It's all about AI and machine learning.
So let's say let's see how many of these people have actually seen ex machina.
So there we go.
There's 10 people who have seen ex machina right out of 100.
So what does that mean.
That means our support here is 10 percent good.
OK.
Now let's move on to Step Two.
Step two is we need to find the confidence.
What is the confidence.
Well confidence is defined as the number.
Let's go for a movie.
So the number of people who have seen movies and wanted them to divide with them.
People have seen a movie.
So here we are going to assume that we were testing a rule we're testing a rule that let's say people
who have seen interstellar right where we have a hypothesis that says that people have seen interstellar.
They are also or have liked interstellar are also likely to like MSXML in all this.
Let's even go if some people have seen interstellar are also likely to have seen ex machina.
So basically here movie number one and one is going to be
the interstellar movie the one that we're saying.
So going to take everybody who's in interstellar and we're going to check how many of them have seen
ex machina.
And that's exactly what we're doing here.
And Marquis Buskin optimization same thing you can think of an example of French fries and burgers for
instance.
People have had burgers we've ordered burgers also likely to order French fries so at the top you'd
have people have ordered burgers and French fries and appear at the bottom.
You have people who have ordered burgers on them who have ordered burgers regardless of whether they've
ordered French fries not.
Much easier to talk about this with an illustration.
Let's say those great people colored in green are the ones who have seen interstellar riot who have
watched this movie.
Now we want to know not out of a whole population but out of just those people who have seen or to sell
or how many of them have seen ex machina.
So out of them we have seven people who have also seen X machines so there's only seven people who have
seen both movies that's what we we're after.
And so our confidence is going to be seven divided by 40 just by definition.
This is how I was calculated.
Forty people have seen it yourself and seven people out of those 40 have actually also seen ex machina.
So the conference here is seventeen point five percent good.
And the next part or the third and last step is the lift and what is the lift.
Lift is very simple again.
It's going to be very similar to what we had in the Navy bays and they've been classifiers in that algorithm
when we were discussing it.
So conver the lift is basically the confidence divided by the support.
So what we calculate in step 2 do but what we calculated in step 1 and let's just talk about it in the
illustration because it's going to make way more sense that way.
So here's our population.
Those people in green are the ones who have seen interstellar and all of these people in red are the
ones who have seen X machine.
So basically our lift is all right so if we just randomly right randomly suggest to a person to watch
ex machina.
Right.
What is the likelihood that they will you know that it's a movie for them it's a movie that's not in
this population like out of this population we know that out of 100 people only 10 actually walks six
machine and we're going to assume that watched and like are interchangeable terms here.
So we're going to assume that if they if they didn't watch it they're not going to like it anyway.
So if we take another random population and then what is the likelihood that if we recommend to a random
person in that population that brand new population will recommend that they Ex Machina movie what is
the likelihood that they will like it.
Well the likelihood is 10 percent right because we only are out of 100 people only 10 of them actually
liked that movie.
But now the question is can we prove that result by using some prior knowledge.
That's why the algorithm is called a priori Ken in that new population let's only recommend ex machina
to people who have already seen interstellar.
So people who are marked as green in this population so we will only find out.
We only ask have you seen interstellar if they have then will recommend next machine what is the likelihood
that a person will actually like ex machina if we recommend them that way.
Well in that case the likelihood as we've calculated out of the green people only not only of the people
at 17 and a half percent actually liked ex machina.
So the lift is the improvement in your prediction.
So your original prediction European politicians 10 percent right if you just randomly take a person
out of your new population and recommend the next mission that they like for a likelihood of 10 percent
if you first ask the question Have you seen and liked interstellar.
If they say yes and then you recommend ex machina the likelihood of a successful recommendation there
is seventeen point five percent.
So the lift is by definition one point seventy five.
There we go.
That is what the lift is defined as.
And that's pretty much the whole a priori algorithm that's the steps that it involves.
And now we're just going to put it all together in this one kind of step by step process so step 1 you
need to set up a minimum support and confidence right.
So you to want to only because there's so many different recommendations.
We only looked at one example one specific example to simplify things we talked about ex machina and
interstellar.
But as you could see in the examples before that you could have like 100 different movies and the different
combinations a priori is actually quite a slow algorithm because it just goes through all of these different
algorithms all of these different combinations so it says what if movie one is a good recommendation
from movie to movie one means that person will like me to make one means a personal like movie three
and one movie four and then it actually combines more and says movie you and movie to might mean that
personal like movie 3 and so on.
So it actually combines lots and lots and lots of nudges.
Not triplets.
Like it combines four five six seven items in one in one set and so on.
And so it gets quite big and therefore you need to set some kind of limitations so you need to set a
minimum support.
For instance you might not want to look at products that are that have a support of less than 20 percent
you might not even want to consider them because you don't want to waste time building a model for something
that is only has a success rate of 20 percent on its own right.
So or you might limit at 5 percent then you might want to also limit it confidence so in our example
the conference was seventeen point five percent right.
That's somebody who somebody who liked one movie will like the other one maybe you might want to limit
it at anything less than 12 percent.
You don't want to look at it because it's not a strong enough facts for you is not a strong enough rule
for you because there is going to be so many different rules on the output of this algorithm.
You already know that you'll have much stronger ones so you don't want to consider anything that's less
than 12 percent or 20 percent or whatever percentage you decide to set for in that specific scenario.
Then once you've set those and you take all the subsets in transactions having higher support than minimum
then the minimum Sopore take all the rules of the subset.
Having high confidence and mean in-conference basically apply those to minimums that you've set.
And then at the end of course is sort the rules by the decreasing lift.
So that's where the lift comes in.
The rule of the highest lift given these criteria is going to be the strongest rule and that's the one
you might want to look into first right.
Something like I don't know if a person buys a burger and French fries then they're likely to buy tomato
sauce or ketchup as well.
And because you know and that some of that sometimes it makes sense right because you need ketchup to
a lot of people like to eat catch up with their burgers and french fries so busy you find the ones with
the highest lift and those are the ones in the top 10 or top five and those are the ones that you consider
for actually implementing a business decision and basing it on them.
So that's pretty much how the a priori algorithm works.
It was quite a long story but I thought we had some some good fun here.
This is another example that I wanted to share with you.
OK.
So I just wanted to mention that recommender systems like things like companies like Amazon News and
others and Netflix and so on they're like a good there would be or they would be a good example for
using a priori.
A priori would be good there but of course they are much more sophisticated than not just a priori.
They actually use combinations are very specific or specifically designed algorithms so I just don't
want you to be confused that a priori.
That means that everything uses a prayer.
Prayer is just a basic kind of straightforward approach to solving this problem.
And it's a good example of you know how it can be done but of course there are other ways of doing it.
And for instance we'll look at the look at some other methods and in fact some of the methods that we
already use can be used to build recommender systems as well.
All right.
So on that note.
Thank you for attention and off we go to lunch to look at how we can code a priori in our and Python
and all see here next time.
Until then happy analyzing.