Great to see you back here.
And today we're going to look at the handy trick that will help your models become a more robust.
Before we continue though I wanted to quickly recap on what we did last night and what we did is we
use the backward elimination method to construct a multiple linear regression using our data and through
that method we constructed four separate models you can see them on the in the background here so Model
1 2 3 and then 4.
And when we get to model 4 we were only left with one independent variable spent on research and development
because all of the other ones were eliminated and basically we completed the backward elimination process
.
However we were left with kind of a feeling that maybe we shouldn't have excluded the last variable
and why is that.
Well first of all we saw that this P-value is not that much bigger than the significance level that
we selected we select a significant level of 0.05 the P-value 0.06 So just a bit greater than the threshold
.
So that kind of leaves us with a feeling maybe we shouldn't have excluded that variable.
The problem here is that this these methods this step was a regression methods they are very arbitrary
.
So once you select your significance level threshold you got to stick to it right you use which is 0.05
This one Serpens 0 6 so there's greater and we've just got to cut it off and not look not look back
anymore and just proceed with the method.
So how can we improve our method of building models to assess situations like that and give you like
an extra opinion or have another criteria to tell us whether or not we should have actually kept this
variable.
And there is a way and we're going to talk about it right now.
So let's look at the top part over here.
The top part is responsible for the variable so you have the coefficients and you've got the p values
and so on.
So we've talked about it quite quite extensively.
But let's look at the bottom part.
The second part of our report and here as we discussed before we've got the stats there are for the
model as a whole.
So how well has been fitted how well it's working and so on.
So the stats that we'll be looking at today are are squared and adjusted r squared and they will help
us come up with a cool approach integrated approach to improve our backward elimination method.
So we already talked about both R-squared and adjusted R-squared in that section of course.
However if you chose to skip that section because you're not interested in the formulas and so on then
I'll quickly recap for you now.
So R-squared we're here is basically a characteristic or a parameter of your model which tells you about
the goodness of fit.
So how will your model has been fitted and R-squared squared can never be greater than one and you wanted
to be as close to one as possible.
The closer to one it is the better your model is deemed to be fitted.
However R-Squared is biased and it's biased in a way that the way is constructed and the way these models
are run.
So the ordinary least squares method it doesn't allow R-squared to ever decrease so the more variables
you add to your model the greater R-squared will be.
So basically what we're what this means is that as long as you keep adding variables R-squared will
always grow and we can observe that here so if we start from the end where we have only one variable
you can see that R-Squared is zero point ninety four.
Then R-squared became.
Well if you go this way it's 0.35.
There is zero point ninety five 0 7.
So as you can see the more variables we have the greater R-squared gets and that's that's always going
to be the case just because of the way R-Squared is derived.
And moreover you can even include completely around a variable so if I throw into this model I throw
another variable which is basically the temperature outside like air temperature outside right now then
.
And I throw that in as an independent variable.
Of course it's not a predictor it can predict a profit of a company in our works in New York or California
.
But R-Squared is still going to grow and is going to imply that our model is now even better fitted
So that way our square is biased and that's where adjusted R-squared comes into play adjusted R-squared
is very similar to our square has got a very simple formula but it actually has a penalization factor
.
So basically just like R-squared would grow if you add more variables that are square would also grow
but there is a factor which makes it small which reduces the adjusted R-squared as you add more variables
.
So there's kind of these two effects battling each other on one hand it's growing because of the way
it's constructed on the other hand the penalization factor is penalizing you or penalizing that just
in R-squared and reducing it every time you add a variable.
So basically if the variable that you added doesn't make adjusted or doesn't make R-squared grow that
much like for instance here you can see 0.9 5 0 5 2 0 9 5 0 7.
So it only grew by a fraction.
Very very small amount.
Well if that happens then the penalization factor is going to overwhelm this growth and therefore the
adjusted R-squared is actually going to decrease in that scenario.
And that way we can use and we will use the adjusted R-squared to watch the goodness of fit all of our
models and how it changes.
So let's let's go ahead and do that.
Let's observe that just at R-squared in our method.
What was the adjusted R-squared here it was sir.
Point 9 4.
Then once we excluded administration expenses adjusted R-squared went from 0.9 foot 5 to 0.9 4 7 5.
So as you can see here adjusted R-squared went up where it just basically what that means is that the
model is now better.
It's been it's fitted better it works.
These variables in this combination fit the profit variable fit this model to explain the profit variable
better than these variables in this combination to explain the profit variable which is good.
It's a good step.
Okay.
So that means we improved Amahl here adjusted R-squared is 0.9 475.
Let's see what happens when we move to the next step and the next step adjusted R-squared is zero point
nine for a 3.
So it went up again meaning that once again we improved our model so altogether these variables are
doing a better job explaining profit then these variables together are doing a job explaining profit
.
That's great.
We improved our model again.
And now let's see what happens when we take out the last variable marketing spend.
So we went from adjusted R-squared 0.9 8 3 to adjusted R-squared 0.9 for 5 4.
And what does that tell us.
Our risk adjusted R-squared went down and went down by from by zero point zero 03 approximately.
So that means that this model this new model is actually worse than this model so this model was better
fitted to predict or explain the variance in profit than this model is doing so.
So there you go.
So even though we excluded a variable according to our Bacary elimination method this may this variable
shouldn't have been excluded because it was Improve it was with this measure of variable.
This model is actually working better and that is your takeaway handy trick how to observe your models
and how to create them.
You don't only just follow the backwards elimination or whatever method that you are using and arbitrarily
follow the rules just instead follow the rules but also watch the adjusted R-squared and see if it's
actually improving.
So if it's growing then you're doing the right thing.
As soon as you see are adjusted our square drop then you have to stop and question.
I just do the right thing or not.
And you know what.
What is the trade off of excluding a certain variable or opposite of including this variable.
So I just it R-Squared is the kind of your indicator how you're going along the way.
But that's it for today.
Hope you find this just one hope you can apply you'll find ways to apply this in your actual work.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then I'd be analyzing