Hello and welcome back to the course on machine learning.
Today we're continuing exploring Association rule learning and we're talking about the intuition behind
the Ekla model.
So the cloud model is very very simple.
After we have already studied the a priori model it's kind of like a simplified version.
All right so let's have a look.
It also talks about the and also talks about people who are bored also bored.
So it's kind of like a recommender system and similar to what we had in the a priori algorithm.
Here we've got for instance movies and we've got some potential rules so basically exactly the same
things.
If you've got your movie lists people the movies that people liked people who like movie 1 or just generally
looks like if somebody likes movie one they are very like it's like movie too if they like the movie
too.
They're likely to like me before if they're like movie one they might like movie three.
Again these rules have will have different strengths.
But here we are are actually going to be talking about rules per se because the cloud model is different
to the a priori model.
In the current model we came up with rules towards and that's output and we based on the lift we could
judge the strength of a tool.
Whereas here we are going to be talking about sets and you'll see why just now.
So here we've got the market basket as optimization.
Same thing that people who buy burgers are likely to buy French fries as well.
People who buy vegetables are likely to buy fruits and these are just some potential rules.
I'm not saying they're strong some potential outcomes that we're looking at we're not saying that they're
strong when we're not selecting and we're just saying what could potentially be and then the cloud model
is responsible for actually going through all of these combinations and telling us what we should focus
on.
All right.
So in the cloud model just like in the a priori model we have the support factor.
So they're pressing them every model we have or the algorithm we had support we had confidence and we
had Lyft in their Clamato we only have support.
So we only are looking at OK.
So people who are watching a certain certain combinations of movies.
How often does this happen.
And here just bear in mind that doesn't mean that just one move and this was the same for a priori it
was just easier for us to understand intuition based on one movie or one product but actually M and
I what they stand for is a set of items or a set of.
So as specifically in the cloud model it's doesn't really make sense to look at you know an item by
itself because we don't have the confidence and the lift factors we're only looking at support so we're
just looking at how frequently does this set of items occur.
So if we're just going to look at a set of item of items which contains only one item then we just looking
at the frequency at how what does the popularity of movies and that is very trivial so we're not going
to be looking at.
We're going to be aiming for at least two items in a set and therefore m here stands for a set of two
movies or more.
And what we're calculating for support we're calculating.
Okay what it is.
How often does this set off to movies that say interstellar and ex machina.
How often does it occur in all of the watch lists or what percentage of watch lists or what percentage
of
lists of movies that people liked contain.
Those two together not just one of them but those two together.
And let's say if if hypothetically if 100 percent of the lists that you had in a large dataset contain
both movies together then that would imply that you know anybody who likes interstellar or ex machina
in real life ex machina Lex and Stella and pretty much so if anybody has seen even one of those movies
that you need to recommend that movie.
The other one to them if you or if you had like 80 percent of the list of your lists had those two movies
together that basically mean there's a high likelihood that they come in pairs right.
That if somebody liked one of them then they'll like the same thing.
Fortunes action like if you have chips and burgers in you know 75 percent of all of your orders right
then if somebody is just buying burgers then they're likely to.
Then when you recommend chips to them there's a 75 percent chance that they will also be interested
or will like to buy chips with their burgers.
And that's it's a very very trivial approach.
And that's my shit that's all there is to their Klugh model.
It's much faster and the steps involved are set a minimum support so you want to set up a support level
at which you want to only offer below which you want to disregard anything.
Then you take all the subsets in transactions having higher support and support.
And then you saw the subset in decreasing support.
And basically at the top you will have the most the strongest combinations of items which you should
look at.
Maybe you know you'll look at the top 10 or top five or something like that.
So that's pretty much it.
That's all the cloud model is.
And as you can see it's much easier to understand after you're you know a bit about the a priori.
All right.
Hope you enjoyed this tutorial and off we go to had lunch to implement this in practice and I'll see
you here next time.
And so then happy analyzing.