Hello and welcome back to the course on machine learning.
Today we've got a very interesting topic today we're talking about Thompson sampling and the algorithms
intuition.
And again we're going to be using this algorithm to solve the multi armed bandit problem.
All right.
So let's get started.
A quick refresher on that multi armed bandit problem.
We have several slot machines each one of them has a distribution behind it.
Do you want to G-5.
We don't know what these distributions are and we need to start playing these machines and at the same
time figure out which one has the best distribution so that we then exploit that best distribution.
And what it'll take us some time to figure it out so we need to maximize our return during the process
of figuring.
So we have to find that ideal balance or tradeoff between exploration and exploitation.
We had a few tutorials previously on these things so we talked about the multi armed bandit problem
you know a lot of detail.
If you haven't watched the tutorial highly recommend jumping into the previous section and watching
it there they're also understanding of the upper confidence bound algorithm will really help you grasp
the concepts of Thompson sampling so if you haven't seen the upper confidence bound tutorial then I
highly recommend checking that out before proceeding with today's lecture.
All right.
So let's get started.
A quick summary of the mulcher armband problem is as follows We have d arms for example arms are ads
that we just play to users.
Each time they connect to a web page so by the way.
Yes indeed.
A modern application of the more or modern representation of a multi armed bandit problem is advertising
so when you display ads that is very similar or the algorithms are going to be applying can learning
can be applied to solving a problem where you are displaying ads.
If you go back here instead of having these slot machines each one of these is a different add and you
want to figure out which one of these ads is the best performing ad but you don't have time to do an
AB test.
You don't have the funds or the resources to do an AB test.
You want to figure it out on the fly.
That's when you apply one of these algorithms are we talking about in this part of the course and of
courses of or other lots of other modern problems that are very similar.
There must have been a problem there for these algorithms are valid for them too.
All right so moving back here so we've got DRM.
For example arms are ads that we just place uses a shell that connects to a web page each time a user
connects to this page that is considered as a round at each round and we choose which ad is displayed
to the user at restrung and the ad gives us a reward either 0 or 1 1 if the ad is clogs or if the ad
is not clicked.
In the case of the actual bandits it will be a monetary war or will be just to one it will be of some
value.
Our goal is to Maxxis maximize the total reward we get over many runs.
All right so that's a quick overview of the problem though is solving.
Then here we've got some very complex looking mathematics and Bayesian inference and all these distributions
and Syria operability and other prior distributions and bebetter dispositions and so on.
We're not going to delve deeper into this right now so headline will take some time to walk through
this slide with you in the practical tutorials because we're going to be coding this from scratch.
This in our.
And therefore he will actually walk you through this slide.
Our goal for today is to understand the intuition behind all of these things so we're going to skip
skip the slide and get to the intuition part.
And this is the actual steps that you're going to be using in the practical tutorial.
So again had had will walk you through this slide as well.
And today we're talking about intuition.
So this is going to be fun this is some interesting slides coming up.
And get ready for a fun ride.
So grab a cup of coffee or a cup of tea and some popcorn and let's get started.
All right.
So here we've got a scale.
Why.
Or the horizontal axis is the return the return that we expected to get from a band.
So we're going to look at a simplified problem we're going to look at another five or even 10 we're
going to get three bandits because they're going to a lot of stuff going on on this chart.
And I don't want to clutter it up and we want to keep it as simple as possible just so that we can understand
the concept and then something applies for five or 10 or however many machines you'd be looking at.
So here we've got the return and these vertical lines just like in the case of the upper confidence
bounds.
We had the horizontal lines these vertical lines represent the expected return for each of the machines
so each of the machines out of the three machines that we have each of the machines has a distribution
behind it so that the result the amount of money that you win per game is picked as a random value from
that distribution.
And when you get a job description but basically just imagine distribution behind each one of these
expected values.
So this is this is just the center of central distribution or the actual expected return from that machine.
And we're just visualizing it here but this is as kind of like looking into it into the actual machine
itself like pulling it apart and knowing how it works.
Being the designer of the machine in reality when you're playing these machines of course you don't
know.
So this is some additional information that will guide us.
That'll help us understand how the algorithm actually works the algorithm itself doesn't know this information
right.
So this is hidden but it's just there for us so that we can better understand what's going on.
So these are the expected returns the actual expected returns of each of the machines.
And obviously if you knew this right away you would say that machine of the three or the yellow machine
is the best one because it has the highest return right.
It has the highest return you'd always just bet on this one.
But again you don't know this yet.
All right so what happens with this algorithm.
Well at the start just like with upper confidence band algorithm you don't know anything right.
You have no prior knowledge of the current situation or status of things and therefore all the machines
are identical.
And you have to have at least one or even a couple of trial rounds just to get some data to analyze.
So let's see.
Let's say that has happened and there's some trial runs for some machine.
One or the blue machine.
And based on those trial runs the algorithm the Tompson something get them this is where it starts getting
different to the upper conditions but we'll construct a distribution right.
So we'll get to the distribution.
Second what means.
But for now let's do the same thing for machine the green machine.
And so we're just pulling the arm several times like four times for instance and we're getting some
values and that are going to be somewhere around.
Obviously the actual expected return.
And based on this and those values of course is probably going to be a bit more than four.
We're constructing some sort of distribution or some sort of perception of the current state of things.
And this is the part where it gets interesting.
So the actual meaning of this these distributions is not what you might think at first so these distributions
are actually showing us or they're representing not to the degree we're not trying to guess the distributions
behind the machine.
So the first thing that might come to mind is that.
All right so we've constructed distribution and so the blue distribution is our attempt at guessing
the actual distribution behind the blue machine right.
The distribution that this is expected to turn for and the green is for the green machine the elephant.
Well actually not that's not the case.
We are constructing something completely different something completely out of this world.
We're constructing distributions of where we think the actual expected value might lie.
It's very important to understand that so we are creating kind of a if you want think of it that way
we're creating an auxiliary mechanism for us to solve the problem.
So we're not we're not trying to recreate these machines we're recreating the possible way these machines
could have been created kind of in that sense so let's let's just solidify that this is where we think
that expected the actual expected values will be so let's look at the blue one for instance.
We've got four values and based on those four values we've constructed this distribution which will
show up which is showing us where is that value star.
So this is mystar the actual mystar but we don't know it.
So the algorithm doesn't know it so it's constructed the distribution trying to guess where this value
is.
And of course Kansas say it's here or is there it's over there.
It's saying OK there's a is a very high likelihood here but it also could be here and could be here
could be here.
And as you move away the likelihood drops but it still could be anywhere in this space.
Same thing for the green distribution.
So based on the values that we've seen there and valleys that have been selected in the four four rounds
that algorithm has created this distribution which is saying that this actual actual expected return
from machine from the green machine is somewhere in this area and it's most likely to be here.
But it could be here it could be here could be here it could be anywhere it could be.
So is it most more likely to be here than could be here could be here and as you move away the likelihood
of it actually been there drops off something for the oil.
So it's very important on the stand so just to reiterate we are not trying to guess the distributions
behind machines right.
We are doing like kind of a little magic trick or a little hat trick.
I don't know Patrick but we're trying to do this create this perception of the world we're trying to
mathematically explain what we think is actually going on or what could be going on and that is that
is important also important thing because this demonstrates that the Tomsen sampling is a probabilistic
algorithm.
The upper confidence Bond was a deterministic algorithm where everything was strict you know everything
was OK so whichever one has a pie some pre-conference bound us on we're going to choose and so on.
But here we are creating a probabilistic perception of the world we're saying.
So it's likely to be here but it could be anywhere in the blue area and this one could be new in history
and so on and you'll see exactly why we've done this in the next slide will understand how this works.
And let's jump straight into that.
Let's understand now that this is probably the hardest part to kind of get your head around what we've
created.
And now that we've created it let's see how the algorithm is going to utilize this auxilary mechanism
that we have.
Chris Lawrence.
So there are our distributions that's where we think.
So these are the actual expected returns for each of the machines.
But the algorithm doesn't know them the old algorithm has created is.
Are these distributions where we allow it to kind of guess where the actual distribution might lie for
each for each of these machines.
So what is going to do is it's actually going to trigger each of these distributions.
So like we're in the we're in in year round we have to choose a machine to use.
So what the algorithm will do is it will go and call this distribution and it will pull out of value
out of the suspicion and let's say it pulled that value then will pull a value out of the grid distribution.
So pulled that values out of the grinch vision and let's say and then pulls a value of Yeldon.
And this is that decision or that value.
And again it's pulling them so according to the distribution right.
So this is a distribution of values so basically it's most likely to pull a value somewhere in this
area then less likely in the way you go.
It's more or less less and less likely but still it can happen that you can see this yellow values actually
quite far from the center but it still can happen that it pulled this Valier distribution and it can
happen and pick this Greenan value out of the green distribution totally can happen in the long term
of course going to be picking somewhere close to the center like over the long run.
But on a one off basis this can totally happen.
And so now let's pick these values and guess what that means will what this actually means is that we
have.
By doing that we have generated our own branded configuration.
So we have created a this hypothetical or imaginary
batch of mush or not batch imaginary set of machines in our own virtual world where we are saying Okay
so the expected the actual expected return for the blue machine.
Is this value the actual expected return for the green machine is this value and the actual expected
return for the yellow machine is this value.
So we've created this Sub-Zero sayto world or hypothetical virtual reality in which we have all our
own three bandits and how we're going to solve this problem.
And is this a problem is very easy to solve.
It's obvious how to solve this problem.
You just pick this machine right because this machine has the highest expected return out of the street.
And I was just going to go with this machine in the virtual world in the search.
So the new reality and what that means is that now we translate this result into the actual world in
the virtual hypothetical world.
We've selected the green machine so in the actual world that the algorithm will also select the green
machine and what that will do so basically pull the lever for this machine.
Right.
And what that will do is actually it will give us a values to the machine spit it out or spit out a
value but that value is going to be based on the distribution behind this machine where this is the
actual expected value of that distribution.
So the value is going to be somewhere here probably close to the actual expected value doesn't have
to be.
Again there's a distribution behind all this.
Far you could because but let's say in this case is this.
All right.
So now this information this is new information to the algorithm.
What is it going to do is it's going to say Aha OK so the I pull the green lever.
The lever for the green machine I got this value.
So now I have to adjust my perception of the world.
Right so I have a prior probability So these are all for the Green Machine This is my prior distribution.
This is where the vision in France comes into play or is it's already been in play and this is where
adding to the Bajun inference.
So that's our prior product.
Now we've got some new information.
This is our new information we're going to added in and see where see how that changes our perception
of the world our perception of the role has changed.
The tradition has shifted a bit and it's become narrower because we have more information we are sample
sizes and creeds of course.
Excuse me of course it's not going to increase that that much.
This is just an example to demonstrate what we're talking about to get the point across.
But that's that's the point that every time we add new information our distribution becomes more and
more refined.
All right so now we have a new perception in the world now what happens next is a new round.
Right.
Same thing we're going to do the same thing again for a neuron.
Again we generate or we pick some values out of our distributions that they are now we've constructed
a or we generate our own branded configuration in our virtual virtual reality or in our a hypothetical
world out of these three we have to pick the best bandit which is of course the one here the yellow
bandit and we're going to now puled actually pool in the real world pull that lever of the yellow bandit
all algorithms can do that.
That's going to trigger the distribution behind the yellow bandit.
And that will give us some sort of value.
So this is the actual value that we received in the real world.
Now we're going to incorporate that value into our perception of the world and our perception of the
world is going to change.
It's just that we go now we're into debt again.
All right.
So let's do this one more time just so we practice the logic behind all of this.
So neuron's generates the generous banded configuration right.
So this is what we think that our expected actual expected returns are going to be Alban's confession.
This is obviously the best one we're going to use pool the yellow machines are a lever that's going
to trigger the distribution behind the old machine is going to spit out a value in the real world.
There is a value and then we're going to have to adjust our perception of the world again to match or
to incorporate the new information and so on we're going to keep doing that until we get to a point
where we've refined the distributions substantially and picture looks like that so they might be to
provide even more.
This one might be more fun this one might be more refined but as you could see from there we slowly
will start generating more and more rounds based on the yellow machine will be treating the machine
So these ones might not even get that refined in the long run which is totally fine because our point
is to get to the best machine to find it and exploit it as much as we can.
So there we go.
That is pretty much how the Tomsen sampling algorithm works.
And as you can see it is a stick algorithm and every time we're generating these values they are kind
of creating this hypothetical set up of the bandits and then we're solving that and then we're applying
the results to the real world.
We're adjusting our perception of reality based on the new information that generates and then we're
doing that again.
So hopefully this was a interesting tutorial.
I find this algorithm very very cool.
And in the next tutorial we're going to compare a little bit of a confidence bond and the Thompson sampling
algorithm and I can't wait to see there until next time happy analyzing.