All right.
So perfect.
Now that everything is essentially said let us tackle this data repressing faith.
So we're going to do this very efficiently.
I'm going to go to my data depressing template and I'm going to copy paste each of these code cells.
You know the first ones so I'm creating a new code cell here.
Pasting them here that's for empowering the libraries.
Then we're gonna take care of the second step of pressing which is empowering the data set creating
therefore a new code cell here.
And let us first take care of this.
You know the last one the easy one.
Splitting the data set into the training set and the test set and pasting that in a new code cell right
here.
All right.
Perfect.
And now before we encode a categorical data let's just make sure to replace what's necessary here in
this template.
And then once again that's the beauty of the template.
We only need to replace one little thing which is of course the name of the data set here.
Right.
And the name is of course 50 on the score.
Capital S startups.
That's yes.
There we go.
Let's do this.
50 on the score start ups.
Great.
And as a reminder we don't have to change anything here because this automatically selects all the columns
except the last one and therefore all the four features here.
So that's perfect.
And this line of code automatically selects the last column which means the dependent variable profit.
Okay.
So once again we've tackled data pricing and a flashlight and now we just have this one less tool to
add in our data repricing phase which is to encode that state variable here.
So to do this we're going to get our data repricing tools which you have in your part one data progressing
further.
And now we're going to scroll down to find that tool that you know encodes the Caracol data.
So remember we actually have two such tools here.
If I may say that first tool that applies one hot encoding which is exactly what we want.
And that tool that just encodes a binary variable into 0 and 1.
And of course what we need is this one so I'm just gonna copy paste that piece of code and then I'm
going to face that right here in a new code cell to encode categorical data.
And now your turn your turn to think and figure out what we need to do next please press pause on this
video and figure out what you have to change here in order to indeed apply one hut encoding on our dataset.
I'll give you a hint.
You only have one little thing to change and then you'll be good to go.
So please press pause.
Okay.
And now I'm gonna give you the solution.
So the only thing that you had to change here is that index here.
Remember this corresponds to the index of the column you want to apply one hot encoding.
And in our previous dataset you know data that says we well remember the categorical variable was the
first column.
That's why we put index 0 here.
But for new data set the categorical variable is actually the fourth column.
But be careful.
Remember that indexes in Python start from zero.
Therefore this gone hasn't it zero.
This one is the next one this one as is x2 and this one has indexed three.
And therefore the index you need to change here is of course three.
Right.
So this will apply one hut including to the column of index three in your data set.
Therefore exactly this date column.
Perfect.
So we're done with the data repricing phase.
So now we are going to observe the results of what we just built.
You know just in terms of data pricing and therefore we're going to do several things here.
First we're going to upload the data set into our notebook right and to do this we click this little
folder here and then upload.
All right.
So as usual my machinery is that folder is on my desktop.
So we're gonna go inside make sure to find it on your machine.
Then we're going to go to part of regression then Section 5 multiple in our regression in Python.
And there we go.
That's the data set which we need to open and upload into our notebook.
All right.
It is uploaded.
And now what we're gonna do is we're gonna run each of these cells that we just made.
But I'm gonna add a few prints you know so that you can really see what we did.
You know how the different metrics of features and have been in viral vector are created and modified
along the data repricing phase.
All right.
So first let's start by imploring the libraries.
That's easy done.
Next step we import the data set and we can now because we have the dataset uploaded in our notebook.
So make sure to have it as well.
Okay.
Now data set is imported.
We have a matrix of features and the dependent variable vector Y.
Good.
And now I'm gonna do a print to show you the state of X you know what is x exactly.
At this stage so I'm going to print x and I'm going to run the cell.
All right and let's see what we get.
All right.
So indeed we get exactly the same columns as in this dataset with first aren't you spend then administration
spend then marketing spend and state right we can clearly see that we get the same columns here in the
same order.
All right.
That's the matrix of features all good.
Now I'm not going to show you the dependent variable vector because that's abuse we're going to get
the same profits.
But what I want to show you is what becomes X after we encode the categorical data you know and you
can actually guess what it will become but you will see that the three comes resulting here from one
how the encoding will actually be placed at the beginning.
All right so let's check it out.
Let's run the cell to indeed apply encoding categorical data.
And now let's create a new code cell in which we're going to print x again and let's run this cell to
see what X becomes.
And there you go.
Exactly as I told you.
We have the same three first columns here.
So that corresponds to Orange spend that corresponds to the administration spend.
And that corresponds to marketing spend.
But now instead of having this state column here we indeed have these three new columns at the beginning
encoding that state variable and we can actually see what corresponds to what you know if we have a
look at our dataset.
Well the first row has new york as a state and therefore New York was encoded as 0 0 and 1.
Then let's see as a second State of the second row you know corresponding to the second start.
We have California and therefore California was encoded as 1 0 and 0.
And finally.
Well Florida was encoded as 0 1 and 0.
All right.
So that's the one how encoding that happens and now all good.
We have a fully pre processed dataset.
And as I told you in part 1.
But I'm gonna say it again here because this is important.
We don't have to apply feature scaling.
Why.
Because you know in the equation of the multiple in our regression you know you have this coefficient
that is multiplied to each independent viable of each feature and therefore it doesn't matter that some
features have higher values than others because the coefficients will compensate to put everything on
the same scale and therefore remember this in multiple linear regression there is absolutely no need
to apply feature scaling.
And one last thing I would like to add as well because I know a lot of you asked this question Do we
need to check the assumptions of linear regression.
The answer is absolutely not.
Because I will explain at the end of this part you know part two regression that whenever you have a
new dataset and you want to experiment with some machinery models to figure out which one leads to the
highest accuracy.
Well even if your dataset doesn't have linear relationships you can still try a multiple in our regression
on it.
And if you know your dataset doesn't have linear relationships well you're multiple in our regression
model we'll just perform poorly and therefore it will get an accuracy lower than the accuracy of your
other models so you will just not select the multiple in our regression model.
But you don't have to check the multiple in our regression assumptions it will just be a waste of time
really I will show you at the end how you can so fast and so efficiently try each of the models on your
dataset and select very quickly the one that has the highest accuracy.
All right.
So I just wanted to be clear on that point don't worry about the multiple in our regression assumptions.
If your dataset has linear relationships then good you're multiple in our regression will check the
assumptions indeed and we'll bring to you a high accuracy and if your dataset doesn't have linear relationships
well fine your multiple in our regression just will perform poorly and you will just take another model
and that's it.
That's as simple as that.
All right.
So now good we're done with data processing.
We can therefore move on to the next step which is to train the multiple in our regression model on
the training set.
So take a little break here.
And as soon as you're ready to build your next machinery model well join me in the next material to
tackle this.
And until then enjoy machine learning.