Our friends were almost at the end of this implementation, congratulations again for implementing,
you know, part one that was quite big technical and then, of course, part two and part three to build
and train our new artificial neural network, CNN.
And now we're going to tackle together Part four to make a single prediction, which I remind will consist
of predicting what's inside these two images.
So this one and that one.
So basically, we will deploy our CNN on each of these single images and we'll hope that our CNN predicts
a dog here.
And, of course, a cat here.
All right, let's do this.
So you'll know how to basically deploy CNN in production on a single observation.
All right.
So let's create a new coat cell, and we're going to start by importing none.
I should have actually left it as our essential library is.
You know, that's what I mean.
We always need non-pay, you know, most of the time.
So there we go.
No, I.
As NPR.
Yes, please.
Please.
At this work at NPR.
Then we will import a new module, which is actually something we almost imported before.
You know, at the beginning we imported the image data generated from the image submodular of the pre
pricing module of the Keres Library.
And in fact, what we would like to import now is that image module.
But because we specifically imported something specific from that module, well, we need to import
it again.
So let's just do it quickly.
So we're going to start from karez, from which we're gonna get access to the pre processing module.
Perfect.
From which we're going to import that image module.
Great.
All right.
And now we have everything we need to make that single prediction.
And now the next step will be, of course, to load that single image on which we want to deploy our
moral to predict if there is a cat or dog inside.
And therefore, I'm going to create here a new variable that will be exactly that image in which will
be actually the input of the brick method.
And we're gonna call it variable test, underscore image as the image you want to test our model on
in production.
And the first thing we'll do with that variable, you know, the way we're gonna initialize it is by
simply lowering it from our folder or same single prediction folder that we have here.
OK.
So the way we're gonna do this is with a specific function of the image submodular module, which is
the load I M.G. function in which we can actually find right here by scrolling down a bit, you know,
or scrolling up actually.
Whereas it exactly.
It is exactly here.
Load image function.
So we're going to use that function to simply load an image into the P.
L format.
All right.
That's the first format we'll get.
But you're gonna see that we will need to adapt it a bit more to make it accepted by the predict method.
OK.
So let's go back to our implementation.
And there we go.
Let's go first that image.
So module from which we're gonna call that lo underscore I m g function.
And inside this function will very simply, we have to enter two arguments.
The first one is the path in quotes.
That starts from the root, which is, you know, are data set folder and then going to that single
operation for there and then specifying which image we want to select.
So we'll start with this one.
And therefore, here we need to specify the path data set, slash single prediction slash GARRALDA one.
All right.
And that's exactly what is expected as the first argument of this load underscore HMG function.
So let's do this.
We have to enter it in quotes.
So we start with the data set, then slash.
Then we go into our single underscore prediction folder.
And then we specify which image we want to select as this test image.
OK.
And that let's just do a copy paste.
Make sure we don't make any mistake.
So pressing.
Enter.
Copy that.
And then let's based that back inside our implementation right here.
All right.
And this will lead us to that image, which will be that test image variable.
And then let's not forget the extension that J.
G.
OK.
So that will lead us to that image.
So that this test image will become exactly that image elected.
OK.
So that's the first argument.
And then let's add the second argument.
A very, very important one.
And actually compulsory that image, which, you know, will become the input of the predict method,
has to have the same size as the one that was used during the training.
And remember, we actually resized our.
Images into, you know, this size target size of 64 by 64.
You know, whether it was for the training set or the test set.
And we specified this again when building the CNN right here with the input shape.
So the size of any image we're going to work with, whether it is to train or CNN or to call the predict
method has to be 64 by 64.
Okay.
And in order to specify this here, we need to enter as this new argument, the compulsory one target
underscore size equals and in some parenthesis, 64, 64, 64 by 64.
OK.
Perfect.
So now we have a first test image.
But in order to be accepted by the predict method, which, you know, expect a certain format, we
have to do some extra work here on that test image.
And that first extra work is to convert that bill.
You know, P I.
L format, which is a format of images into an array.
Remember that the Pyhrric method expect as its input to the array.
You know, you remember these double pair of square brackets which we used to input in the predict methods
of our previous Murrells, you know, when predicting the outcome of a single observation.
Well, here we're about to do exactly the same by converting this test image into an array.
And the way we're going to do this is with another function of this image date of preprocessing module,
which is exactly this one image to array, which converts indeed a P.
L image instance into a number by array, which is exactly the format of array expected by the print
method.
So we're going to use that function right away to convert our test image, which so far has the P.
L format into this number by array format.
All right.
So we're going to update our test image again.
So I'm calling it again and then updating it by sending it equal to a new value.
And, well, as you understood it, we're going to use our image, some module again, from which we're
going to call this time that I, M.G., underscore to underscore array function.
And guess what?
It has to take as input.
Well, very simply, it just needs to take that image in the P.
L format, which we want to convert into the non-pay array format.
And therefore, well, the input will simply be that test image and nothing else.
You know, we only need that image of which we want to convert the format.
OK.
So that the next step.
But then we still have some extra work to do, which is still related to the fact that, you know,
the British method has to be called on the exact same format that was used during the training.
And well, remember that, you know, when preprocessing are training set in our test set right here
in part one, they will be pressing.
We actually created batches of images.
Therefore, you know, our CNN was not trained on single images, you know, entering the network one
after the other.
But it was trained with batches of images.
And therefore, we have this extra dimension corresponding to the batch.
Now we have batch number one containing 32 images.
Then batch number two, containing other 32 images, batch number three, et cetera.
So we had this extra dimension of the batch.
And even if now we're about to deploy our model on a single imit, well, that single image still has
to be into a batch, even if we're gonna have one image in the bet.
It needs to be into this batch so that the C and moral and more specifically the predict method of the
CNN model can recognize the bat as that extra dimension.
And so, you guessed it.
What we're about to do now is just to add an extra dimension which will correspond to the batch and
which will contain that image into a batch.
And the way to do this is, once again, by you know, I just computed before so I can just based it
once again, update our test image by adding to it.
This extra dimension corresponding to the bat.
And a way to do this is with non-pay.
You know, that's how we can always easily manipulate and then by array now that, you know, test images.
Indeed.
And then by Ray.
And so I'm gonna call nonpaid first, which has a Shoket M.P. from which I'm gonna call this function,
which allows exactly you to add a fake dimension or, you know, a dimension corresponding to the back
end, which is called the X-band underscore dims function.
And now you guessed once again what we have to input inside this function.
Well, we have to input the image to which we want to add this extra dimension corresponding to the
batch.
So first, I have to paste once again our test image.
But we have to add one extra argument here, which is where we want to add that extra dimension and
that dimension of the batch is actually always the first.
I mention, you know, that makes sense, you give first the batch of images and then inside each batch
you get the different images.
So it seems natural to have the batch as the first dimension and to specify this.
That's exactly what we need to enter here as this extra argument and that parameter to specify this
is access, which we have to set equal to zero.
OK, so that the dimension of the batch, which we're adding to our image will be the first dimension.
OK.
And now we're getting very close to the final result because now is the time we can call the predict
method, because indeed that test image, which is not only in the right number by array, but also
which has that extra dimension gurus point to the batch has exactly the right format expected by the
predict method.
And therefore, here we can create a new variable, which we're gonna call result, because it will
actually be the prediction of our CNN called with our test image.
But I'm not calling it prediction yet because it will only return zero or one.
And then we'll have to do some encoding work to say what is zero and what is one.
You know, zero will actually be kept.
And one will actually be Doug.
I'll explain why later.
But there we go.
We're just gonna call this first result variable, which will be, of course, the output of the British
method.
Call from our CNN.
And so there we go.
We need to take our CNN first, from which we're going to call, of course, to predict method, which
will take as input, of course.
Well, our test image, which now has the right format expected by that predict method.
So nothing else.
We simply need to input test image here and then.
Now is the time to do that encoding work.
So the way to figure out what is zero and what is one, you know, if zero is get a dog and one is Caradog.
Well, the trick is to call the class in.
This is attribute from our training set object.
But since now, we can't run this code.
I'm just going to write the code that allows us to know which in this is correspond to which classes.
And then you can see that on Juber, a notebook.
But I will just tell you that by using this, we actually know that one corresponds to Doug and zero
corresponds to cut.
So to get that information, we need to call our training set or actually the test set as you want.
And then from which we call this attribute called class underscore in this is just like that.
And by printing this, you will get the right class indices.
And with this wind, you'd get that Durka response to one and get your response to zero.
And therefore, our final step here, you know, to have a nice result displayed in the output in the
end when we make that single prediction on these two single images.
Well, we're gonna finish this with, you know, and if condition where we're gonna specify that if
the result.
All right.
Now, remember, that result contains also actually the result into a batch because it was called on
a test image that was into a batch.
So results.
Also has this batch dimension and therefore, we're gonna first get access to the batch.
And there are only one.
And it has, of course, index zero because index isn't Biton start from zero.
So here we get access to the batch.
And then inside the batch, we're gonna get access to, well, the first and only element of the bat,
which corresponds to the prediction of that same cat or dog.
One image.
Right.
We're dealing with a single image and therefore a single prediction.
And to get that single prediction where we need to get inside this batch of index zero.
Well, the first and only elements know the first and only prediction, which has once again, index
zero.
All right.
That's how we get exactly the prediction we want by first accessing the batch and then accessing the
single element of the batch.
And that's exactly our prediction.
And so if that prediction is equal.
Notice w go here to one.
Then since we know that one corresponds to Doug, then we'll create a new variable, which we're gonna
call prediction and we'll set that prediction variable equal to Doug.
And then I'm gonna copy this because then in an els condition.
No meaning if the result you the prediction is equal to zero then.
Well, prediction will be equal to cut.
And then we simply finish this with a less code cell containing a simple print of the prediction.
And that's it, my friends.
This is how you make a single prediction with a convolutional neural network.
So now now it is the show time.
It is time for the exciting step, because we're all gonna sit comfortably in our chair and we're gonna
shoot this code on Jubera notebook.