Hello and welcome to this art Tauriel I'm super excited to be in the deep learning part.
This is one of the most fascinating and exciting brand of machine learning and besides it's one of the
most powerful and the following tutorials who are going to solve the business problem described by curial
at the beginning of this section and you will see that we're going to get strong results thanks to this
artificial neural network that we are about to build with our.
So as usual we are going to make this artificial neural network model very efficiently and we're going
to use the best package for that which I will let you find out about in the next two titles.
So let's start.
And the first step of our journey is the boring step data processing but we will do it very efficiently
because we have our template our classification template that I've prepared here.
And why can we use this classification template.
Well it's by nature of the business problem you saw in the business problem description that you have
some independent variables and with these independent variables you have to predict a dependent variable
that has a binary outcome.
And since the outcome of the dependent variable is binary that means it's a categorical variable.
That means we have to predict classes 0 and 1 and therefore that makes our problem a classification
problem.
And so OK we're going to build a deep learning model but this deep learning model is going to be nothing
else than a classification model.
And that's why we are going to use our classification some places we have here and that will save us
a lot of time to build our typical neural network.
And besides we want to focus on the deep learning model itself.
So we will get there very quickly thanks to this template.
All right so let's take everything from this template from the top down to here because we cannot use
this section here because you know this is the section to visualize the trainings that results and the
test results as well.
But only when we have two independent variables because one independent variable corresponds to one
dimension.
And since.
Now in the data set of the business problem we have I think 10 or 11 independent variables.
Well then it's a little bit hard to represent something in 11 dimensions.
So we won't take this but we will definitely take everything that's above.
So I'm going to copy that.
And let's go back to our aid and moral and paste this classification template right here.
All right.
And now in this template we're going to change a very few things.
And of course we are going to build our artificial neural network right here in this section create
your classify here.
We can already replace class 5 here by and then to then build them model.
All right.
But of course we need to make sure everything is OK and all the data pre-processing step.
And that's what we're going to do right now.
All right so let's start let's start with the basic step.
Setting the right there as a working directory.
So right now I'm on my desktop and going into my machine in a folder.
Then we are in port eight deep learning and now Section 40 artificial neural networks.
Here we go.
Make sure that you have the turn modeling Dotsie as you file.
And if that's the case you can click on this more about near and then set as working directory.
Great.
And now let's change a few things.
So first of all let's start with this section importing the dataset.
Well the name of the data set is not social network adds.
It's now churn modeling.
All right.
We are now ready to import the data set.
So let's do it right now.
I'm going to select this line and executes all right dataset one important.
Well we have actually 14 variables but let's see if we include all these variables in the real data
set.
You know the one on which we want to build our differently model.
So let's see I'm going to click on this dataset here to see which independent variables we include in
the mall.
All right so just a quick reminder this dataset contains 10000 observations containing some informations
of customers in a bank like the surname the credit score geography gender age and all the other information
here.
And during six months the bank looked for each customer.
If the customer stayed or left the bank within the six month period and this result whether the customer
stayed or left is given.
In this last column here exited.
So one means that the customer left the bank during the six months and 0 means that the customer stayed
in the bank during the six months.
So what's important to understand now is that all these variables here from row number to estimated
salary are the independent variables.
And the last column here exited is the dependent variable.
So right now our goal is to make MRO where we can predict this result exited here whether the customer
left or stayed in the bank.
From the information contained in all these independent variables here but the thing is that in these
independent variables some definitely don't have an impact on this dip in or it will exit it.
And so now what we have to do is only take the independent variables that could have an impact and correlations
with the decision of the customer to leave or stay in the bank.
And so that's what we're going to do right now.
So let's look at each of these in the bin and Vogels one by one and let's see which one we keep in our
model.
All right.
So let's start with the first one.
Row number.
Well row number has definitely no impact on the dependable exit.
So of course we will not include it then Customer ID.
Well Customer ID does the same.
That's just an identification number.
This definitely doesn't have any impact on the decision of the customer to stay or leave in the bank.
So we will not include that either.
Then the surname.
Well that's the same system because your name is Andrewes that you have more chance to leave the bank
than if your name is Romeo.
All right.
So we don't include her name either but then we have credit score and credit score might have an impact
on the decision of the customer to stay or leave in the bank.
Indeed we can assume that customers with a low credit score are more likely to leave the bank than customers
with a high credit score.
So definitely we're willing to credit score in our model.
All right then we have geography.
Well maybe some customers are more likely to leave the bank in one specific country and that can be
due to external factors like the economy of the country or any other factors.
But yes definitely there might be some girlishness between the countries and the decision to stay or
leave the bank.
So we're willing to do that as well than gender.
Well that's the same maybe men or women are more likely to stay in the bank than the other.
So we need to check it out then age.
Well that's the same and that's even quite intuitive.
We might expect that younger people are more likely to leave the bank than older people because all
the people who have more balance and have more stability when to age as well and tenure.
So tenure as for how long the customer has been in the bank.
And so that's the same we might expect that customers that have been in the bank for a long time are
more likely to stay in the bank than recent customers.
So yes we'll take that then balance well balance of course we might expect that this customer with this
high balance has a lot more chance to stay in the bank than this customer with a zero balance.
All right.
And the number of products so that's the number of banking products the customers have in the bank.
And so of course maybe that the customers with many products in the bank are more likely to stay than
customers with for example one product in the bank.
So we wanted to check it out.
That's just assumptions that's the model that we'll find out about these correlations more thoroughly.
But you know definitely from our intuition we need to include number of products as well then has credit
card.
Well that's a little bit of the same as this variable customers that have a credit card might be more
likely to stay in the bank than customers that don't have a credit card.
So yes is active member.
That's the same if a customer is active then this customer is more likely to stay in the bank than a
customer that is not active.
So yes that might be a significant and viable than estimated salary.
Well that's the salary of the customer estimated by the bank and it would make sense that customers
with a high estimated salary have more chance to leave the bank and customers with a low estimated salary.
All right.
So that was the last independent viable of this data set.
So now we know which independent variables we include in our data set.
And that's what we're going to specify right now by updating our data set taking only the indexes of
the independent variables we want to include in the model.
So let's see what these indexes are.
OK so indexes are start at 1.
And so basically we're taking all the independent variables from credit score up to estimated salary.
So let's see.
Index one index to index 3 index 4.
So we are taking the indexes 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 and 13.
All right.
So we are taking the indexes from 4 to 14 because you know in our it's not like in Python when we separate
a matrix of features and the inevitable vector we includes all the variables in one frame.
And so we include the dependent variable.
Great.
So let's input these indexes.
So we just said that we want to take the indexes from 4.
So that's the index of the first independent viable up to the index 14 which is the index of the dependent
variable and that's great.
Now we can update our data set by selecting this line and execute.
Great.
And now as you can see if I will go back to the dataset here we have all are potentially statistically
significant independent variables that might have an impact on the dependent Voivode exited.
And so now the first step of data processing is completed.
We imported correctly the data set by choosing all the relevant independent variables.
Okay.
Now let's move on to the second step the second step is and coding the target feature as vector Well
we don't really need to do that because the dependent variable of our data set is a categorical variable
with a binary outcome one or zero.
And the thing to understand is that the package we are going to use is going to recognize it as a categorical
variable with a binary outcome.
So we actually don't need to encode this target feature exited as Efexor so I'm going to remove this
line.
We don't need it.
However we do need to do something regarding some categorical variables.
Of course I'm talking about the two categorical independent variables we have in our dataset and these
two variables are of course geography and gender.
So we have two problems here.
So we need to do two things here for these variables.
The first thing we need to do is to convert them as factors and then we wanted to do something more
than we used to do when encoding our categorical variables to set them as numeric.
And to do this we'll use the as the numeric function.
And why do we need to do this especially here.
Well that is just because the deep learning package that we're going to use is requiring it.
And that's the only reason it expects factors but set as numeric numeric factors.
So let's do this.
I'm going back to my end in model and so first we're going to change this to say that we're encoding
the categorical foibles as factors.
All right.
And now we're going to take this categorical data file that we made in part one day to pre-processing
because you know there is the code ready to encode any categorical data.
So I'm going to select all this and paste it here in this second step of data pre-processing to encode
the categorical variables as factors.
All right so let's do this.
We just need to replace the names of the variables and then add this as the numeric function to set
the factors as numeric.
So let's start by replacing all the names here.
Well the first categorical variable gives to countries but it is not called country.
It is called geography.
So we will replace here country by geography.
Same here.
And the good news is that now we don't need to change the names of the categories here.
France Spain and Germany because that's the same names.
So that's great.
And we will keep the labels.
One two three.
All right that's good.
And now we add this as that numeric function to set the factors as numeric.
So I'm putting all these facts to function here inside the parenthesis of the as numeric function.
And now I just need to align everything well.
Here we go.
And same for here.
All right great.
And now let's do the same for the second category go viral.
So we need to replace purchase here by gender.
So let's do it.
Purchased replaced by gender.
All right.
Same here.
Gender and now we replace the two categories.
No and yes by female and male.
And here we can give the labels we want.
So let's for example take labels one for female and two female.
All right.
And let's not forget to add the as that numeric function which I remind we just do for the future deep
learning package that we're going to use.
So parenthesis here parenthesis here and now that's the line everything.
Here we go.
All right.
Great.
So now everything is ready this section is ready that encodes as required by the deeper and package
are categorical independent variables.
All right so I'm going to select the section here and let's execute.
All right executed properly.
Now let's have a look at the data set to see what the variables became.
Perfect.
Geography was encoded into one two and three categories that are numeric categories and the gender one
for female and two female greats.
And again as numeric factors perfect.
So this section is now completed.
And let's move on to the next one.
We can see how we're getting very efficient at this.
The next one is about splitting the data sets into the training set and a test that we need to do that
because we will train our artificial neural network on the training set and we will test its performance
on the test set.
So we'll do that.
But let's not execute too fast.
We need to replace purchased here by the name of the dependent variable which is exited and maybe we
can change the aspect ratio as well you know put 80 percent for the training set so that we have 8000
observations to train artificial neural network and 2000 observations to test its performance on new
observations.
That is the new observations of the test.
So now that's ready.
We don't have to do anything more here.
The most important thing is not to forget to replace purchased by exited.
And so now I'm going to select all the section and exit routes.
Perfect.
Now we have our training set and our tests at Great.
So that is the whole dataset that is our training set with 8000 observations and that is our test set
with 2000 observations perfect.
Now let's go back to our CNN and we are finally getting to the last step of data pre-processing and
that is feature scaling.
So now the question is do we need to apply future scaling to train an artificial neural network.
And the answer is yes absolutely.
That's 100 percent compulsory.
And that is because training an artificial neural network is highly compute intensive.
So there is going to be a lot of computer actions and besides parallel considerations.
So definitely we need to like future Skilling and besides it is required by the package.
So we will execute this.
But before let's not forget to change the indexes these indexes three here where the index of the dependent
variable in part one data preprocessing.
So right now we just need to replace this index three here by our new index of the depende inviolable.
And so where is this index that is the index of the exited column.
Well we can see that directly here.
This dataset has 11 variables.
So that means that the exited column here has indexed 11.
So let's replace three here by 11 then here as well 11 11 and 11.
Great.
And now the features getting section is ready.
So let's select the whole section and executes great.
And now if we have a look at our training set.
Well well yes definitely.
Everything is scaled.
And our test set same everything is definitely scaled.
We are happy we are ready to build our artificial neural network and that's what we're going to do in
the next toile.
So I'm super excited to start.
I look forward to seeing you there and until then enjoy machine learning