Hello and welcome to this art to Tauriel.
So we have a very exciting to toil ahead of us because in just a toil we are going to build the N-N
and fit it to the training set.
So right now it's time for action and let's build our first artificial neural network.
All right.
And as I told you in the previous tutorial we are going to use the best package for that.
That is the most efficient one that offers the most options and also one package that can run your models
very efficiently.
That's indeed very important because the models that we're going to build are complex and you know they
can run over many epochs.
So we need a package that will be efficient for these highly compute intensive tasks that are inevitable
when we build a deep learning model in this section in this Statoil we're not going to build a very
deep learning model.
We are going to have in the two hidden layers but still.
And if you need to work with a deeper artificial neural network.
Well of course it's better if you have the best package.
So there are several deep learning packages in our So we have neural net to build deep learning models
that are regressors and not classifiers so we cannot use this one.
Then we have an net that allows to build a deep learning classifying model but with only one hidden
layer and then we have deep net.
Another very good deep learning package that can build deep learning models with many hidden layers.
But that's still not the one we're going to use.
And so now I'm going to tell you the one that we're going to use it is called the H2 o package.
So why is it in my opinion the best package to build deep learning models.
Well it's for three reasons.
The first reason and that's the most important reason is that age 2 0 is no open source software platform
that allows you to connect to an instance of a computer system that therefore allows you to run your
model very efficiently.
So thanks to this connection to this computer system we will be able to train a deep running model very
efficiently like in a few seconds.
For those of you who follow the Python tutorials It's like connecting to a GP you know that allows you
to run highly compute intensive parallel computation.
So that's the first reason efficiency.
Now the second reason is that this package offers a lot of options to build your deeply moral.
So you know it will be very easy for us to choose different numbers of hidden layers and choose different
numbers of neurons and the hidden layers as well as other options to develop your model.
And speaking of options that leads me to the third reason why to me it is the best deep learning package.
Well the third reason is that one option of this age to a package is that it contains a parameter tuning
argument that allows you to choose some optimal numbers to build your deep learning model.
So we will see that by building the model and so let's start creating it.
So the first thing we have to do is of course to install the H-2 package.
So let's do this.
We're going to use the install packages command.
Here we go.
And remember this install the packages function when to input the name of the package in quotes that
is age 2.
So that's all h to o written the simple way.
And so you just need to select this line and execute it to install the package.
I already have it installed on my our studio here it is.
And it's also already imported.
But of course this will install this package without any issue.
And of course if you have an issue you can ask me some questions in the Q&amp;A.
I'll help you fix that.
So I'm going to put that in comment.
And now let's move onto the next line which is to import this package in case we have to automate the
scripts so to import it as you know we use a library and in parenthesis not in quotes the name of the
package age too.
All right.
Great.
And now we need to do something special.
It's not the usual package that we've been using throughout this course.
It's a new kind of package because it's a package that we're taking from an open source platform and
therefore that requires a connection to an H-2 instance and therefore what we'll do right now before
starting to create the model is to establish this connection and don't worry that's very easy.
We need to take our package age.
Oh then dot and then as you can see here it contains many functions and the function we're interested
in to make this connection and in fact initialize and H-2 instance well we need to take the in its function.
All right.
And as you can see in this function we have several parameters that allows you to connect to a specific
server.
For example this first argument here is IP which you can use to specify the IP address of the server
you want to connect to in which are H-2 instance will be running but that's only if you have an idea
of which server you want to connect to.
But in our case we will connect to some sort of a default available server and therefore we want to
use these parameters here.
However there is one that we'll use and that is the end threads Ravenor here and what does this argument
while this argument is the number of course in the system that you're connecting to that will be used
to build deep learning model.
Because you know building a deep learning model requires a lot of confutation highly compute intensive
ones.
And therefore we need many cores to run this computation.
And again that's the reason why we prefer Gippi use or VCP use because simply G-B use have many more
cores so he will take this argument and threats.
And now the trick is to input the value minus one because specifying this minus one value will take
all the available course of the system you're connecting to.
So don't even think about it.
I strongly recommend to use Manasquan here because this will optimize the number of course to use and
therefore the future computations.
Great.
And that's actually the only argument we need to import here in this and it function.
So we are ready to execute that to connect to the system.
All right so let's execute starting H2O JVM and connecting.
And here we go all the connections are established and now we're working on another system much more
powerful because we have an optimized number of course.
And so we were ready to build any kind of complex deep learning models.
Great.
Now we have everything we need.
We have a powerful tool with us.
So we are definitely ready to start building the deep learning more.
All right.
That's what we're going to do starting from the next to Tauriel and then learning