All right so this is the fun part adjusted r squared.
So here we've got a simple inner.
We've talked about how the R-Squared is derived so what the formula for our secret is it's equal to
one minus sum of squares of residuals divided by total sum of squares where sum of squares of residuals
is the sum of squares of the distances from the observations to your fitted line so we don't see it
here that's your linear symbol in your regression line that we fit onto our data and the sum of the
whole sums whereas we can see it here so that's the total sum of those squares of those red lines we
can see here so the difference between your observations and the average Sobieski R-Squared is telling
us how well is your model fitted to the daughter.
In fact how much better is it fitted than the average line that she can just draw through her daughter
very easily.
So let's get rid of all of that and put all our secret formula no left for a second.
Now we talked about R-squared for a simple linear regression while the same concepts apply for a multiple
in your regression.
So for instance we have two variables R-squared would be calculated in the same way.
We're just not going to go through all these derivations right now because it's just easier to visualize
the way we've done it and that's exactly the same concepts apply to a multiple linear regression and
still.
So what that means is that all ordinary least squares method is used.
And the best fitting is a multiple linear regression is the one that has the least sum of squares of
residuals So you're trying to minimize the sum of squares of residual.
And when I bring that up well we'll need that in a second.
So we want to use R-squared as we discussed as a goodness of fit parameters so the bigger it is the
better the current closer it is to one the better model.
And that's awesome.
We can totally try doing that but there is one problem and the problem is or starts to occur when you
add more variables to your model.
So here you can see we've got two variables in our multiple integration.
What will happen if we add a third variable to our model.
We think of it as an example let's look at that example with a salary.
So your salary equals to a constant 30000 plus 10000 times the years of experience plus for instance
B2 could be a constant hour coefficient times the number of qualifications you have.
And I don't know B-3 could be how much how much money you brought the company in the previous year so
if you're a salesman for instance so a coefficient times the amount of dollars that you brought the
company in the previous year something like that.
So you can keep adding on variables that you think are actually impacting the outcome so are impacting
the dependent variable and you want to fit in model and see if it's better or not.
So in this case we're adding a third variable.
We already have a model with two variables and it works okay.
And now we want to add a third variable and see if maybe using a third variable we can fit our model
even better so we can create an even better model with three variables.
So how can we judge that.
So we've added all bearable and we've run the model.
We can look at the R-squared did the R-squared get better or worse.
So in fact did the R-squared increase or did it decrease or stay the same.
So the problem here is that R-squared because of these two things are spread will never decrease.
And let's go through that in a in a bit more detail.
I'm going to use my mouse here because this is quite an important part.
So R-squared over here is equal to one minus somewhat squared of residual divide by some square of the
total.
So once you add a new variable to your model.
Right it's going to somehow affect what the model looks like.
And the fact that we're trying to minimize the sum of squares of residual what that means is that either
this new variable will help minimize the somewhat square of residual somehow the regression process
will find a way to give it a coefficient that will help minimize the sum of square residuals.
And then and in that case R-squared will happen to us squared.
It'll be one minus something that is less than it used to be.
Right.
Divided by the same value because we by adding a new variable we're not affecting the observations we're
not affecting the averages of observations right.
This does not change.
So by adding new variable the regression process through this condition we'll definitely try to minimize
this value make it even smaller than it is currently.
And that way this whole part will decrease and this whole part will increase.
So you are going to increase if it so happens that the new variable that's added whatever coefficient
you give it a new coefficient you give it if you cannot decrease SS residual.
Right.
What will happen.
Well this coefficient will just become zero.
It very rarely happens I don't think I've ever seen a coefficient like B exactly zero.
And I'll tell you just now why.
But in the worst case scenario the regression process will say this variable is you know completely
just making the world model definitely worse so I'll just put a 0 instead of this coefficient.
And forget about it.
And that way as this residual won't change and R-squared won't change.
So you only have two options either R-squared will increase or it won't change at all.
So R-squared will never decrease.
If you add variables and why say that B-3 is never equal to exactly zero because they can always be
or there will always be at least a slight random correlation between the independent label and the dependent
variable.
Doesn't matter what you put in here.
So even in the example when we're looking at salary so salary equals years of experience plus how many
how much I mean qualifications a person has.
And then we can add in what is the last digit of the law of the person's mobile number.
Right.
Of course that is not going to.
It doesn't have any correlation with the independent variable.
What sort of that will there is no causative factor there's no association between the two.
The lossage of your mobile number has no effect on your salary.
But if we added in and they'll we'll randomly be a slight correlation you know.
It'll just be a random correlation and the regression process will pick it up and I'll give it a go
efficient and R-squared will probably decrease by that tiny little or increase by that tiny little bit
.
And so that is why there's a problem with R-squared.
You can add variables and you will not know if those variables are helping your model or if they're
not helping because you're R-Squared is going to is biased is basically always increasing regardless
of the actual improvement or non-proven fit.
So we've got to come up with different parameter to measure goodness of fit and that is where adjusted
R-squared comes in.
And this is the former for just that R-squared.
Here is the number of regressors.
So the number of independent variables and is the sample size so it's over here.
Now they say that adjusted R-squared has a penalization factor.
It penalizes you for adding independent variables that don't help your model.
And let's talk about that.
That's the important bit about just R-squared so p is a number of endpin verbals.
Let's look at the piece here is in the bottom in the denominator.
That means that when PPI increases when you increase the number of independent variables.
This whole part decreases.
And when this whole part decreases the denominator decreases the ratio increases and as the ratio increases
this whole bid increases as well.
And as this whole increases one minuses hold decreases.
So as you can see as you're adding more regressors the adjusted R-squared is decreasing is going further
away from 1.
And that is the important part.
Also you can see here what happens when R-squared increases when just normal R-squared increases R-squared
increases.
So this part decreases right.
One might R-squared decreases and that means that this whole part increases.
So you've got a battle here on one hand R-squared by adding a new variable you're increasing R-squared
So you're increasing a justed R-squared.
But on the other hand by adding numerable you increase P So you're decreasing adjusted R-squared.
And in that sense it's a fair like it's a fair battle here.
If your variable is not good is not helping the model then adjusted R-squared this will be an insignificant
increase.
And this penalization factor will actually drive R-squared down adjusted R-squared down.
If on the other hand your new variable that you added is helping to model a lot then the increase in
R-squared will be substantial and it will overwhelm this penalization factor so even though you'll still
get penalized for adding a variable that increase the benefit to the model will be so great that even
the justed R-squared will go up.
And so that's how the adjusted R-squared basically works.
It's it's a very good metric it helps you understand whether you're adding good variables to model or
not and we'll be using adjusted R-squared throughout this course to make sure our models are robust
when we're building them