Hello and welcome to parts 1 data processing.
So I had to start with this part because this is a crucial step in the journey of making a machine learning
model.
If there is no data repossessing your machine learning model won't work properly.
So it's you know it's like preparing a journey.
Imagine you are about to go for a long journey while you have to prepare.
It's in every book your flights book your hotels and the pack your luggage.
That's definitely the boring part.
Before the trip but then when everything is well-prepared and you're ready to go your trip might be
amazing.
Well it's the same for our machine learning journey.
We have to prepare some stuff in order to make sure that we build our machine learning models without
any issues.
And this stuff that we need to prepare for a machine learning trip happens to be data processing.
So I have to be honest with you this is the boring part but we are only doing this so that we get the
maximum fun later in this course when we make all the machine learning models.
So trust me we have to do it because if we don't do it we will miss out on all the fun of machine learning.
So I did the best I could to gather in this part all the essentials of data processing and even if I
made sure to make it as simple as possible.
There is all you need to know about data processing there is all you need to know how to do to prepare
any data set for any machine learning model.
So excluding this one there are going to be eight tutorials in this part.
So hold onto them and I promise you that we will get a lot of fun once we start our machine learning
journey.