Hello welcome back to the course of machine learning.
Today we're going to talk about specific aspects of the Kamins algorithm which is the random insulation
trap.
So let's have a look at this phenomenon and see what it's all about.
So random insulation traps.
Here we've got a scatterplot.
Again we have two Berbel So we've got the x and y coordinates.
And in this case let's say we're going to choose three clusters.
So right away you kind of can't tell which is the final result what is the Father's are going to look
like if we choose three clusters.
It does look like you can pretty easily spot them here.
But let's them with less form this operation this algorithm.
And if we initialize our centroid like this then what we will get is because we already kind of can
tell that probably that's a classic asset class and that's closer.
So just to make the algorithm a bit faster so we don't have to do too many easy steps and directions
we're going to select all the centroid like this.
And the right of way if we perform the algorithm We'll get to these clusters.
And next is even if we move around the centroid So we find the centroid of each of these classers nothing's
going to change.
So you can in your own time you can perform the steps that we learned about in the mirror tutorial and
see that nothing will indeed change because of the way we selected the centroid.
This is already the final result.
So those are the going to be the clusters that we're going to end up with.
So that's kind of the end result of the Kamins our own because we selected the clusters of the centroid
is in the places where we did.
Now the question is What if we select a centroid in different locations will we be able to change the
result will all be different.
And of course an algorithm has to be what we want from this algorithm is for it to use a deterministic
result because we can select the centroid at random and therefore we don't want that selection of centroid
to affect how the clustering is going to happen.
But let's have a look and see what happens.
So what will happen if we had a bad random initializations so bad is like a term we're going to use
loosely for now but you will see why we're using bad random insulation just now.
So again we're going to go through the steps that we discussed in the Bruce tutorial.
We're going to choose a number of clusters which is three all selected random three boys which will
be us and Troys will assign Is there a point to the closest Android that will form K clusters will compute
and place a new centroid for each class of thinking in terms of center of mass or center of gravity
and the survival re-assign Is there a point to the new closer centroid.
If there are any assessment of place we'll return to step four.
Others will go to the end because the model has converged.
So these steps we discussed previously Let's have a look at them in action.
All right.
So three clusters and this time is sort of selecting a centroid here here and here.
What we're going to do is we're going to think differently we're going to select the centroid is like
this.
So we'll put one centroid here on this side once it's right here.
And what's interesting here.
So let's have a look what happens now.
If we draw a line so this and we have 3 cluster two centroid.
But the principle is the kind of the same.
We still have a point which is equidistant from all three of them so this point here is the same distance
from all three.
And then this line is equidistant from these two.
This line is equidistant from these two the size equidistant from these two.
Again this is not part of the algorithm as part of the algorithm you just take each individual point
you look at this point and you see which centroid is closest to the Semmes green coloured green.
This one you check again with colored green this one you check again colored green and so on.
Then this one is the closest to red you'd color are red and so on but just to make things easier for
ourselves we're going to use this little hack.
We're going to use these lines to say anything in this part of the chart is going to be closest to read
.
Just because these are equidistant lines and you think in this part of the charge is going to be green
anything is partial is going to be blue.
It'll just save us time.
So based on this method we can tell right away that this is the red cluster for now this the blue is
the green.
So now we're going to assign each data point to the closest centroid.
That's great.
Now we're going to we want to step four and we're going to remove these clusters.
So we're going to recalculate compute and place and new centroid for each cluster so there we can see
that that is probably the center of mass for the red points.
That's one for Bluepoint That's one for green points.
So we move our centroid to the new locations.
And now we get to perform Step Five We're going to reassign edged out a point to the new close centroid
.
So again we're going to use that quick hack with the lines that see how the lines will look like this
time.
There's our new equidistant point and these are the equidistant lines.
So this time you can see that nothing will change the red points are already in the red corner of blue
points or in the blue corner and green points are in the green corner so nothing's going to change.
There will be no re-assignment.
So we don't go to step forward instead go to finalizing the algorithm because it has converged.
So there we go.
That is our model.
It is ready.
And as a result we have these three clusters Now these clusters are different to what we saw at the
start so let's have a look.
This is what we saw at the start.
We're going to call them the truth 3 clusters because you can tell just from the charge you can tell
that these points would most likely to form a cluster.
These would form a class and these would form close just by looking at it you can intuitively tell that
that is the case.
This is what we got in the first.
At the start of this tutorial and this is what we got now.
So you can see that the three clusters are different and therefore what we have is a situation or phenomenon
where the selection of the Central is at the very start of the algorithm can potentially dictate the
outcome of the algorithm.
And that's not a good thing because the centroid are selected at random.
So how do you combat this.
How do you battle this.
Well the answer is actually not as straightforward.
There is a addition or a modification to the Kamins algorithm that allows you to correctly select the
centroid and the solution here is the Kamins plus plus algorithm.
Now at the same time I wanted to mention that we're not actually going to delve deeply into the K means
plus plus algorithm in how it's structured.
You can definitely read up more about it on Wikipedia or other sources.
It is quite a involves approach in how that selection occurs.
But the good news is that all of this happens in the background so the Kamins plus plus happens either
in our or Python or whatever tool you're using.
You don't need to actually implement it.
So it's just a good idea to be aware of this issue that there is a true cluster result that you're after
.
And there can be some false or some non desirable clustering results clustering outcomes of the Kamin
clustering algorithm.
It's good to be aware of that issue and it's also good to know that the tools that you use will be or
make sure that the tools you're using are going to be implementing that specific selection of the random
centroid.
At the very start so that you get a good result.
So definitely if you are more interested in interesting to learn more about the Kamins plus plus Algren
definitely read up about it but otherwise it's not something that you really have to worry about it
just something that you need to keep in mind and make sure or be confident that the tools you're using
are bypassing this insulation trap.
So enjoy today sartorial and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then in Germany in learning