Hello my friends welcome to this new section on now Decision Tree regression.
So we're about to tackle a new practical activity where we will all learn together how to build the
decision to regression model.
You will see that it will be super easy based on what we did before you know with all the feature scaling
and inverse transformation of the SVR we are now we won't have to apply feature scaling and therefore
we will just smash this.
All right.
Are you ready Are you ready to start.
Before we go into this part two regression further let's just make sure that everyone here is on the
same page.
I give you the link to this folder just before this tutorial so you just have to click the link and
then now we should all be on the same page so we're gonna go into part two regression and then Section
8 decision tree regression.
We're almost at the end of the regression path.
Congratulations for the great progress you've made so far and now we're going to go of course to python
in order to find our files for this section.
So there are two files here.
The Python implementation of the dissident regression model in IP one be format which you can open with
either Google collab or Jupiter notebook and our same positions salaries data set containing that same
data of the previous company showing the different position levels from 1 to 10 corresponding to business
and those 2 SEO and the corresponding salaries from 45000 to 1 million dollars per year.
All right.
So this time we're going to train a decision tree regression model to understand the correlations between
these two features.
However I have to say something important here.
The decision tree regression model is not really well adapted to you know these simple datasets.
You know with only one feature and the dependent variable vector you'll see what I mean by that at the
end.
On the visualization graphs.
But having said that I would like you not to worry because the implementation of the decision tree regression
model we were about to build will still work on any other data sets you know with several features.
Here we have one feature but the code we're about to make will work for data sets.
Having any numbers of features.
All right.
So even if the results won't be beautiful in the end well you will still be able to use this decision
tree regression implementation on your other data sets even if they have hundreds of features but then
make sure to add some data processing tools if needed.
For example if your dataset has some categorical data or missing data but you don't have to apply features
killing for decision tree regression and neither for running false regression which will be our next
model you know in the next section.
All right.
So that's the important thing I wanted to say here and now we're going to start our implementation by
double clicking this file here which you can either open with Google cool AB if you like Google cool
add like me or Jupiter notebook.
All right.
So choose your favorite.
And now let's open Google laboratory.
It is opening a notebook and here we go.
That's the whole implementation.
All right.
So as usual now we're going to create a copy of this notebook because this is an read only mode which
means you can't modify it or recode it.
So we're gonna go to file here and then click here save a copy in drive and this will as you can see
create a copy of this notebook on which you will be able to read code on it.
You know read implement this decision tree regression model.
Perfect.
So now you know the next step we're going to delete the code cells but since it is the third time we
actually work on this position salaries data set and of course each time it's the same two first steps
of the data processing phase importing the libraries and importing the data set.
Well this time we want re implement this.
We will just leave them and not delete them.
So we will just delete all the code cells from here you know from the step training the decision to
regression model on the whole dataset.
All right let's do this.
Let us start by deleting this one because we will re implement it together then this one and now this
one.
All right.
Perfect.
Also you can notice that at the end we will only visualize the decision tree regression results in high
resolution because you will see and I will show this to you that the decision tree regression results
in low resolution you know without applying the grid solution will absolutely not make sense.
And I will explain that at the end of this section.
All right.
So we're almost ready to start now.
We are going just to upload you know the dataset by clicking this little folder here and then right
now it is connecting to runtime to enable foul browsing and in a second we should be able to see the
upload button.
Here we go to upload indeed the data set and now we are on my desktop.
That's where I put my machinery.
It is it for them.
But make sure to go wherever you saved it.
And now inside we're gonna go to parts of regression and then decision tree regression and then python.
And then there you go.
You select your position salaries data set and click open.
And this will upload the data set inside the notebook.
And now we're ready to start.
Let's just run these two cells here.
The first one to import the libraries and then the second one to import the data set.
All right.
Perfect.
So now we have the data set and of course the matrix of features X containing only the position levels
and the dependent variable vector containing the salaries.
All right.
And here a quick reminder this model that we are about to build you will truly be able to implement
it on your data sets and you will only have two things to change which are first of course the name
of the dataset here you will put the name of your data set and then in a matrix of features well maybe
you will want to select all the columns.
And here we just excluded the first column because this contained only the positions and strings which
are exactly the same as the levels in this column.
So of course we didn't want included but check your dataset check if you want to include all the columns
and mostly check if you need to apply some of the tools of your data pricing toolkit which are either
you know taking care of missing data or encoding categorical data.
Right so you would need to check the variables and see if there are some categorical variables in strings
if the order matter is like for example the size of a close while you will apply label encoder and if
the order doesn't matter like some countries or some states well you will apply column transformer with
one HUD encoder.
All right.
And then you don't have to apply feature scaling.
You can totally split your data set into the training set in a test if you want to evaluate your model
on your observations but you don't have to apply feature scaling for Decision Tree regression and neither
for random forest regression Why is that.
That's because you know the predictions from a decision tree regression or random forest regression
model are resulting from successive splits of the data you know through the different notes of your
tree and therefore there are not some equations like with the previous models and that's why of course
no feature scaling is needed to you know split the different values of your feature into these different
categories leading to different predictions we can still do this with the original scale of your features
even if your features take different ranges of values.
All right.
So remember this no feature scaling and then check for the other tools but just for your future datasets
where you would like to apply decision tree regression.
Okay.
Perfect.
So we have everything we have the dataset and now we are ready to build the decision tree regression
model on the whole dataset.
Right.
This time we don't want to split it.
We want to leverage the maximum data to understand the correlations in this small amount of information.
So we will turn it on the whole data set.
Then we will predict our final result in the salary of the position that will number six point five.
And then at the end we will visualize what the regression curve of the decision tree regression model
looks like.
All right.
So let's do all this in the next three tutorials.
Starting with this step training the decision tree regression model on the whole dataset.
And until then enjoy machine learning.