Hello my friends.
Welcome to this new practical activity on our second classification model which is of course the K nearest
neighbors.
We just tackle the logistic regression model and we actually made a classification template which will
allow us to finish this Cairn and implementation in a flashlight because we will only have one cell
to change.
So it's really important to understand that the previous work we did on logistic regression will actually
serve as a template you know a classification template for the other classification models here.
So I'm going to show you this in actually one single tutorial.
We will be extremely efficient and before we start let's of course make sure we're all on the same page.
So right before this tutorial I gave you the link to this folder which contains all the codes and data
sets.
So make sure to connect to that link.
And now we should all be on the same page.
And therefore my friends we're gonna go into Part 3 classification and then K nearest neighbors K and
N.
All right.
And as usual we're gonna start with Python and inside this folder you will indeed find two files.
Of course the K nearest neighbors implementation in IPA in the format which you can open with either
Juba notebook or Google collab.
And the same dataset social network ads containing 400 observations where each observations you know
each row corresponds to customers and for each of these customers we get the H.
That's the first feature The estimated salary.
That's the second feature and their purchase decision whether or not they but yes or no.
The SUV and that's of course the dependent variable and our exercise here is to learn some correlations
between these features The Age and the estimated salary to predict this dependent variable per taste.
And the goal of all this is to of course predict which customers are going to buy the new SUV so that
we can optimize our targeting.
All right.
So exactly the same.
And now we're going to open this implementation.
Kenya is neighbor with either Google collaboratively or Egyptian notebook.
Choose your favorite.
And now it is opening the notebook laying it out in a second.
So learning it.
Laying it out.
There we go.
And that's the notebook.
And as you noticed as you probably noticed I actually kept the logistic regression implementation to
show you indeed that all the code cells inside these two implementations are the same you know all the
code cells are the same except the one where we indeed build and train the model on the training set
right.
So up to here you know all this is the same.
All this is the same.
And once we reached that step where we train the classification model in the train set.
Well that's where we have this single change and then all the rest is the same.
Then we predict a new result you know with the same name for the classifier which we called classifier
then we pretty test results here.
Once again we have nothing to change.
It's all the same right all the same.
So if by any chance you are starting with K and and you know before logistic regression I really encourage
you to do logistic regression for us because all these cells are explained in detail.
And for this key in an implementation we will just re implement you know that cell to train the key
in and oral on the training set right.
So that's why it is a classification template which you can use to build any other classification models.
And together we will of course use this classification template to build all our other classification
models including K and N support vector machine kernel as VM navy base decision tree test vacation and
random forest classification.
And we will all build them in maximum efficiency.
All right.
So let us start with Kiernan.
As you understood the only cell that we have to change here is this one.
So actually since we can not do it here you know re-employment here because this is an read only mode.
Well we'll have to create a new file you know a copy of this file by clicking here this button.
Save a copy and drive.
This will create a copy and inside which we will be able to read implement that cell to build and train
the cane and model.
All right so let's do this.
We just need to scroll down here all the rest of the same.
And there we go.
So what we're gonna do is just remove that cell and there we go.
Now we can re implement that cell.
So let's create a new code cell.
And now I would like you to please press bus on this video to indeed try to do it yourself first because
once again I not only want to train you on machine learning but also I want to train you on how to be
independent and create things on your own you know create Europe machinery models on your own.
I already guided you on how to navigate the psychic learn API to find some information in tools.
And now I would like you to do this same exercise again.
Please press buzz on the video and navigate the circuit here and API to find the class that allows indeed
to build the key and model and then you know how to train it on the training set.
All right.
So in two seconds now we're going to start a solution together.
Here we go.
All right.
So let us suppose you know I'm just like you.
I'm not an expert in machine learning and I would like to build and train a cane and model on the training
set.
So since I actually have no idea of what is the name of the class that does it well I'm gonna go off
course to search it online and inside.
Well we will do it this way.
Suck it learn.
Then we're gonna go to the first link.
All right we will end up in the cycle learn welcoming page then we're gonna go remember to API which
contains all the modules and functions and classes of cycled learn and now.
There we go.
We are looking for the class that allows to build the K and moral.
Let's scroll down a bit and if we have you know too much difficulty to find it.
Well we will do a controller command F to find it.
You know there are many tricks actually.
You can also directly type in your search bar K nearest neighbor class cycle turn or cycle learn K nearest
neighbor class something like that.
But I like to navigate the secondary API because it is really well-made.
And so here by scrolling down do we find it.
Yes.
Here it is.
Nearest neighbors.
So it was actually hard to miss but indeed we had to scroll down a bit but that's OK because it's really
good to get familiar with the cycling library.
All right so that was the name of the module you had to find.
And now the next question is which of these classes because you see these are all the classes of this
neighbors module.
That's actually the name of the module by I learn neighbors.
And these are all the classes that allow you to build machinery tools you know in this nearest neighbors
branch of machine learning.
All right.
So of course the one we're interested in is this one K Nabors classifier.
There you go.
Congratulations.
If you found it.
So let's click it and let's see the whole documentation.
So feel free to read it if you want you can see what are all the parameters and also attributes.
But what we actually simply need is this you know the whole name of the class and the module and the
library cycle.
Because the only thing that we need really to build and train this cane and model is the name of this
class to you know create the object and also the parameters here.
We need to know which parameters we have to enter here in order to build a relevant K and a..
All right.
So first let's take this and let's go back to our implementation to here faced it and then adapted by
you know doing this from from site learn and then from the neighbors module of psychic learn we will
import this class to K Nabors classifier that's the class and then in the next natural step it is to
create an object of this class which will represent exactly the K and then model itself the classifier
and that's why we call it class set fire and then to create an object of this class well we just need
to call the class again.
So I'm copying this basing it here and then adding some parentheses.
All right so that's the first information we need to get from the cyclone API but then the second thing
we need to check also are the parameters here and you have all the descriptions here.
So for example the first one and neighbors equals five AND neighbours is of course the number of neighbours
of your cane and model you remember the intuition lecturers you have the neighbours that you use to
make your predictions and we have to choose a number of neighbours and well you know we can just try
this value five.
I actually know that we will get good results with this but you know in your future missionary projects
if you're using a cane and moral Well I recommend to tune it with several values but five is usually
used.
So let's do this first parameter and nay verse equals five good.
Then next parameter let's see weights equals uniforms.
Uniform is the default value of weight and weight is the weight function used in prediction and well
here we will actually keep the default value uniform which means that all the points in each neighborhood
are weighted equally.
OK.
So they have the same importance.
So we will keep that.
That's fine then algorithm equals zero.
What does that mean.
Well that's basically the algorithm used to compute the nearest neighbors and auto is the best value
to choose because it will decide automatically the most appropriate algorithm based on the values path
to the fit method.
You know the method that trains your model on the training set.
So definitely here it will be simple if which was auto and then you have some other parameters leaf
size of which will keep the default value and P which is the power parameter for the min Koski metric.
So there we go.
That's important that the other parameters we will enter the last two parameters that actually want
to enter are this one metric equals Murkowski and P because indeed metric is actually the distance you
want to use to compute you know the distance between your observation points and the neighbors.
And we actually want to choose the Euclidean distance which is you know the classic distance equal to
the square root of the sum of the squared differences between the coordinates.
And in order to take that classic Euclidean distance Well we had to choose a min Koski metric with p
equals 2.
So basically we're keeping all the default values of this K neighbors classifier class but in order
to make sure that we are using them.
And just to highlight them.
Well let's just write these parameters with their default values anyway because it's important to see
what we're dealing with.
You know what version of K and then we are dealing with.
Okay so let's do this quickly.
Metric equals Min count ski.
And then P equals two.
Perfect.
And so now we have basically a classic K nearest neighbors model with five neighbors.
And the classic Euclidean distance.
Okay.
And now you perfectly know how to finish this.
The last step here is of course to train our classifier which indeed we built so far but is not trained
yet on the training set.
So that's exactly what we need to do as a final step.
And so there you go we call our classifier from which we're going to call our fit method which as usual
takes as input.
First the matrix of features X train.
And second the dependent variable vector Y train of the training set of course.
All right.
Perfect.
And that's it.
You know we're done with this implementation all the rest is the same.
We don't have to change anything else here because indeed since we called our canine model classifier.
Well here to make the predictions we already have the right name of the variable classifier and then
same here to predict the test results classifier and then same for the computer matrix.
Why test why bread.
Which result from our same classifier and then same for the visualisation of the results.
Sorry I just showed them to you.
I hope you didn't see but we're gonna get to that in a second.
There you go.
That's the same.
Same names of the variable classifier X strain y transfer all the rest of the same and that's why I
like to call it a good code template.
All right so now my friends we are going to rerun all this right because we're basically done.
And so to run all this again we're going to first upload the data set because it is not yet uploaded
in the notebook.
So right now the notebook is connecting to a runtime to enable file browsing and in a second we should
see the upload button.
Perfect.
So upload and then make sure to find your whole machinery.
That folder containing all the codes and data sets.
Mine is on my desktop so then we're going to go inside and we're going to go to part 3 classification
and then K nearest neighbors Keenan and in Python and then we select our social network at dataset click
open.
Now it's going to be applauded on the notebook.
Perfect.
There we go.
Now we can run everything and to do this well we're gonna click runtime here and then simply run.
Oh and let's just start from here.
OK great.
R K nearest neighbours classifier was created and trained properly and at the end so all the predictions
are generated again we can actually have a look at them and while we seem to have some great predictions
that remember on the test.
So all this is correct here we have an incorrect prediction meaning that the key and then predicted
this particular customer to buy the SUV whereas in reality that customer didn't buy the SUV then all
this is correct or correct.
All correct.
It seems really good it seems to be some great predictions here.
Here we have another incorrect prediction.
This time the opposite one our model predicted that this particular customer didn't buy the SUV whereas
in reality that customer bought the SUV.
Right.
Correct.
All correct all correct.
So pretty good.
Wow.
I think we actually have very very few incorrect positions.
Let's actually check it out right now.
Okay.
So I didn't see it properly but we actually haven't heard all four plus three incorrect predictions.
That's real really good that's better than the logistic regression model.
Remember we had actually an accuracy of the test set of 89 percent.
So here clearly the Kenya's neighbours did better than the logistic regression model.
And you will perfectly understand why when I show you the visualization so it's actually here.
All right so four plus three equals seven incorrect predictions then 64 correct predictions of the class
0 meaning 64 correct predictions that the customer doesn't buy the SUV and twenty nine correct predictions
of the class one meaning twenty nine incorrect predictions that the customer buys the SUV and then we
have indeed four incorrect predictions of the class one meaning four incorrect predictions that the
customer buys the SUV and three incorrect predictions of the class zero meaning three incorrect predictions
that the customer doesn't buy the SUV.
So very very good.
And now as you can see it is still executing the sell that plots that to the array you know showing
all the prediction regions and prediction boundary of the key and in model first on the training set
and then on the test.
And the reason why it is taking some time here to execute Oh there you go we're about to have it in
a second.
Yes.
So perfect timing but I was going to say the reason why it takes sometimes to execute is simply because
you know the K and model is actually very compute intensive.
You know there are a lot of computations when running the cane and model and that's where it took some
time.
And so now let's interpret the results.
So remember with the logistic regression classifier the prediction boundary was a straight line.
And that's because the logistic regression model is a linear classifier will actually see another type
of linear classifier in this part.
But remember for Linear classifiers the prediction boundary or prediction curve for classification is
a straight line and in three dimensions it's a straight plan and an end dimension.
It's a straight hyper plane.
And so here we had a straight line which therefore resulted in having a lot of incorrect predictions
because as we can see there are a lot of green points here you know green customers who bought the SUV
in reality that fall in the red region where we predict indeed that the customers don't buy the SUV.
And same for these ones here you know here we have a lot of customers who in reality but the SUV but
we're predicted not to because they fall in the red region.
And so what we were hoping for is to build a new classifier for which the decision boundary you know
separating the two prediction regions does something like this.
You know would not be a straight line but some kind of a curve catching all the red points here without
catching those great points here and here.
OK.
That's what we were hoping for and well that's exactly what we got here.
Thanks to our ken and moral we don't get a smooth curve but we get actually some kind of a curve that
indeed catches all the red points here without catching the green points and leaving those grid points
and these ones inside the green region where they should end up right.
And of course here we have some green points that were super hard to catch because they are stuck in
the middle of all those red points here.
So that's fine in any way in machinery we want to avoid overfishing.
You know when we have some to perfect predictions on the training set and therefore probably resulting
in having bad performance bad predictions on the tacit and well speaking of the test let's see how arcane
and did it should be fine.
Yes it is.
Execute it.
And once again we get excellent results right because same the Kiernan prediction curve or prediction
boundary or even decision boundary catches all the right customers.
You know the red customers who didn't buy in reality the SUV therefore leaving the Green customers who.
But in reality the SUV in the right prediction region the green region.
OK.
And of course we still have some wrong predictions incorrect predictions but that's because the training
was properly run without overheating.
And that's why here we can clearly see are incorrect predictions.
These two customers here and this one and this one who are indeed incorrect predictions that the customers
bought the SUV whereas in reality they didn't because these are red points falling in the green region
and the other incorrect predictions here which are incorrect because these are green customers therefore
who in reality but the SUV but we're predicting that two because they fall in the red region.
All right.
So that's already much better.
We get much better results for indeed this particular data set for which.
Well nonlinear classifiers that can have that kind of curve is a benefit.
And indeed we increased the accuracy of the test by 4 percent and now the question is can we do even
better than this you know with our future classification models.
Well that's exactly what we're going to find out in the next sections when building our future classification
models which include as VM kernel SVM Bayh's decision tree classification and random for its classification.
Take a bet on what is going to bring in the end the best accuracy.
And while my friends follow me in the next practical activities to discover the big winner.
And until then enjoy machine learning.