Hello my friends.
Welcome to this new practical activity on polynomial regression.
This time we're going to learn how to build together a nonlinear regression model which will allow us
to tackle a problem with a nonlinear dataset meaning a dataset with non-linear relationships on which
therefore a multiple in our regression model would not be relevant.
All right so as usual I just want to make sure here that everyone is on the same page.
So right before this tutorial I gave you the link of this for this.
Make sure to connect to that link and you'll be inside this page just like me.
Ready to start this new Polynomial regression model.
And now we're all gonna go into part two regression.
We're still learning on how to predict a continuous numerical value.
And this time we're gonna go to Section Six polynomial regression.
To learn how to build.
Indeed this nonlinear regression model.
All right.
And as usual we're gonna start with Python inside which you will find two files pulling them all regression
that IP y and B which is of course your Python implementation which you can open either in Google cool
app or Jupiter notebook and the dataset called position salaries.
All right so as usual we're gonna start by describing the dataset.
Once again I'd like to remind that this is a simple data set and that's only you know because we are
starting with our journey of machine learning so right now I want to work on simple data set so that
you can focus on how to build the models themselves without being too overwhelmed by a complex dataset
but no worries.
The further we progressed in this course the more we will work with real world and complex data.
You will see at the end we will work with datasets with many more observations and more complexities.
All right so no worries about this.
We will get there a little by little.
So what is this dataset about.
Well let's imagine the following scenario.
Let us imagine that we are actually an H R department and that we want to hire someone and we actually
found someone that seems to be a great fit for the job.
So we would like to offer this person a position in our company.
And so this person says yes but at the end of the interview process comes the inevitable question What
is your salary expectation and let's say that this person is you know very well advanced in its career
and therefore that person is asking for one hundred and sixty thousand dollars per year and then also
as H.R. negotiators we ask this person why are you expecting such a high salary and this person replies
Well that's because that's what I earned in my previous company.
That was my salary in my previous company I earned one hundred and sixty thousand dollars per year so
I am expecting at least one hundred and sixty thousand dollars per year in your company.
Is that the truth or is that a bluff.
Well that's exactly what we're gonna figure out thanks to our polynomial regression model.
We're going to build a polynomial regression model to predict the previous salary of this candidate.
So how are we going to do this.
Well of course in order to make such a prediction we need data and that's exactly the data we collected
here.
So what is this data and how did we collect it.
This data is actually the different salaries of the previous company for the different positions from
business analyst to CEO and now how did we collect such data.
Well you know there are many websites online which actually display different salaries of different
positions in companies.
I can give you an example like Glassdoor.
Well let's say that we did this and that's how we collected all this data containing all the salaries
for the different positions of this previous company for which this person worked.
OK so we have this data and now we need to know obviously which position this person had within this
previous company.
Well that's easy.
Let's say we went to LinkedIn and we checked out the profile of this person and we actually saw that
this person was actually a region manager.
OK.
However on the LinkedIn we also see something else it turns out that this person actually has been a
region manager for quite a while.
Like let's say two years.
And therefore you know the salary of this person should not exactly be one hundred and fifty thousand
dollars as we can see on this dataset but instead it should be somewhere between one hundred and fifty
thousand dollars the salary of Position Number Six and two hundred thousand dollars to salary of position
number seven.
So in order to extrapolate we're going to suppose that this person has a position in between six and
seven and we'll consider this position to be six point five.
So that then we can actually deploy our moral you know after training it of course on the position level
six point five so that we can get the predicted salary of such a position level and we will compare
this predicted salary to the salary expected by this person to see if indeed there is truth or bluff.
All right.
So that's the strategy.
It's basically going to be in four steps first step.
Data processing.
Second Step.
We will build the polynomial regression model.
Third step.
We will train it to understand the correlations between the position levels and the salaries.
And fourth step we will make that prediction.
Now time to brainstorm together on what are going to be the first steps you know within that data repricing
phase.
Well of course we'll start by importing the libraries.
Then we will import this data set but then do you think we actually need to split this data set into
the training set and the test will here.
Exceptionally because we have very few observations we actually won't split the data set into a training
set and a test set because what we want to get directly is actually that prediction of the position
level between 6 and 7.
We will say six point five.
So we actually need to get the maximum data we can.
And that's why we're going to take everything to train our polynomial regression model so exceptionally.
We want to apply that third subset of the data repricing phase and then obviously we won't have to use
any other tools of the data pricing toolkit like taking care of missing data or anchoring categorical
data simply because here we will just train our polynomial regression model on these two columns level
and salary because indeed this column is just redundant with this one right.
It's as if the encoding was done simply on a spreadsheet so we will actually not include this column.
We will train our polynomial regression model with this column as the column of features the matrix
of features even if there is only one feature and this column as a dependent variable vector all right
Are you ready.
Let us do this.
Let us build our polling on your regression model.
So we're going to open our IP way and be Fowler python file.
You have the choice to open it with either Google collaboratively or and notebook.
And for Google collaborators lovers let's open this right now and let us see what we have in our notebook
laying out notebook.
And there we go.
So I remind that this notebook is an read only mode and since we as usual want to re implement this
from scratch we're gonna go to file here to create a copy by saving a copy in drive.
And as you see it is creating a copy in which we will be able to re implement the whole model from scratch.
And there we go.
All right.
So now as usual we're going to delete all the code cells so that we can re implement this from scratch.
Make sure to only delete the code cells and not the text cells so we can see the structure you starting
to know the story now.
And lastly this one.
Perfect.
All right.
So this is the whole structure of this implementation.
Let's have a look.
I already brainstorm with you on what would be the first steps.
But I really want you to clearly see the whole structure.
Okay so we're gonna start by empowering the libraries then empowering the data set.
Then as I told you we're gonna skip the step where we split the data set into the training set in the
test set simply because we want to leverage the maximum data in order to make our future prediction
of the salary for the position level between 6 and 7.
So we skip this step and then we move on directly to first actually the training of the linear regression
model on the whole dataset and that's for the simple reason that we want to compare the two models linear
regression and polynomial regression because I want to show you that indeed a polynomial regression
model will be much more adapted to this dataset and you know the reason that's because the dataset has
nonlinear relationships.
So in the end we will actually as you can see predict the salary of the position level between six and
five with linear regression and polynomial regression and you will see that we will get a much better
result with polynomial regression.
Okay.
So after training the linear regression model on the whole dataset we will train the polynomial regression
model on the whole dataset as well then we will visualize the linear regression results on the whole
dataset again and then pulling them a regression result.
And once again you will see that indeed the polynomial regression model is much more adapted to this
nonlinear dataset than the linear regression model.
And finally we will make our last two predictions predicting a new result with linear regression and
predicting a new result with polynomial regression and at the same time you will learn how to make a
single prediction.
You know because what we've done so far you know when making predictions W to input the whole test set
features you know we input x dest in our predict method and that returns indeed some predictions of
the test set but you actually still don't know exactly how to predict the result of a single observation.
And that's exactly in this practical activity that you will learn it.
Okay.
So that will a good new skill to know and I will of course ask you to try to do it on your own.
Before we do it together.
And so there you go.
That's the whole structure.
And now we're ready to start.
And we're going to tackle this semi data processing phase and flashlight starting by importing the libraries.
And thanks to our data processing templates I'm copying this here pasting that right here in the new
code cell.
Then we're going to import the data set using still our data depressing template because indeed we will
have only one thing to change which is of course the name of our data set.
No actually my mistake we will have two things to change and I will explain why right away.
So first let's change that abuse thing which is the name of the dataset.
So let's see the name of the dataset again position salaries.
All right.
So let's do this.
I'm going to replace data here by position salaries.
Great.
And now the second thing I wanted to change is of course the matrix of features X because remember that
this automatically takes all the cons except the last one.
But actually here you know these two columns are redundant.
It's like we already did the label including you know to encode each of these positions into numerical
integers going from one to 10.
But I wanted to leave that column because it's pretty nice to see the names of the different positions
you know from business analyst to CEO.
So we actually don't want to include this column and therefore we will start to get the column from
the second index which is index 1 right because index isn't both and start from zero.
So there you go.
We're only going to take that column and to do so well we're going to replace that empty lower bound
which means the first index by index 1 so that it will indeed take all the columns from the second one
you know the next one up to the last one except the last one and therefore it will take all the columns
from this one except this one and therefore just this one.
See just a simple trick.
All right.
So now we're all good.
This will still take the last column the dependent viral vector containing all the salaries.
So we are all good and we can move on now to the next step which will be to train the linear regression
model on the whole dataset.
Great.
So would you like to execute this now.
Yes maybe let's do it now so that it's done.
So let's click this folder here to be able to upload the file right now it is connecting to a runtime
to enable file browsing and in a second yes.
There we go we should be able to upload the dataset.
All right so we're gonna go to our missionary.
It is it folder I always put it on my desktop.
Then part two regression then Section Six polynomial regression then python.
And there you go.
Let's get an upload our position salaries data set that's all good.
Now we have it and now we can run these first two sales first important the libraries.
Okay.
Done and now importing the data sets and done as well.
And now we can move on to the next step.
Training the linear regression model on the whole dataset to try to do it on your own because you now
know how to implement the linear regression model.
So I trust you will smash this.
There is no trap and this will be a good way to practice again.
So as soon as you're ready well let's move on together to the next tutorial to build that first linear
regression all together and then the polynomial regression model.
And until then enjoy machine learning.