All right my friends.
Are you ready for the demo.
I remind that this demo works for any data set you know regardless of the number of features.
And as long as they have you know the features in the first columns and then the dependent variable
in the last column and also assuming that any missing data or categorical data was already taken care
of thanks to your data pricing tool kit.
All right.
So this is gonna be very exciting because it's really now that I'm going to show you the power of code
templates and how you can quickly and efficiently select the best regression model.
All right.
So let's do this.
Enough talking.
I'm going to proceed to the demo now.
Just resetting everything because we're gonna do something fun.
We will actually use this run all option of the runtime which will run all our sales at once so that
you know we can really optimize the efficiency but let's not forget to upload the data set in each of
the implementations.
Otherwise this sale won't be able to execute.
So we're going to upload it now.
It is connecting to runtime in a second we should be able to see the button there we go.
So let's click this upload button and now on your machine you're gonna find the folder you know the
model selection of all the.
That's the whole machinery.
It is it for them.
And that this new model selection for the container.
You know that regression folder with all the good templates for regression and the classification with
all the good templates for classification.
If you missed that folder somehow don't worry it was given right before this tutorial you know in the
article at the bottom you had a zip file attached which you could download on your machine and which
contains exactly the same as what I have here.
All right.
So now we're going to go to the regression folder which contains all the implementations meaning all
the code templates for each of your regression models both in IP y and B format which you can open with
either Google cool app or Jupiter notebook and in P Y format which you can open with a classic Python
terminal or spider in Anaconda.
So you have everything and you also have the data set you know containing these four features the energy
temperature the vacuum the engine pressure and the humidity and we predict the energy output.
All right so that's a very classic data set.
Once again very generic trying to represent the other future data set you'll be working on and well
speaking of this data set that's exactly what we have to select here.
So we're going to click open to upload the data set in our notebook and there it is.
And now as I told you here in the implementation you only have to answer the name of your dataset.
And as far as we're concerned here for a demo Well this they say is called data data.
Yes.
All right.
So now we're going to quickly do exactly the same for other implementations upload then data that says
we then open and loading it's uploading it and we'll have it in a second and then we'll just replace
the name data set here by data.
That's easy that's for polynomial regression now for support vector regression will same upload data
that says we open and loading it uploading it in a second we should have it.
There we go.
Now we only replace this by data that's years V then for decision tree regression.
Upload then data that says we open and we will have it in a second uploaded in the notebook and now
replacing this by data that's easy.
And finally for random forest regression upload data see as we open and now replacing this byte data
that is.
And now my friends we are finally ready to test each of our regression models and figure out in a flashlight
which one is the best.
Remember the closer the r squared coefficient is to 1 the better is your regression more.
So in order to figure out which is going to be the best model we'll just take the one with the highest
r squared you know with our square that is the closest to one.
All right.
Are you ready.
Let's do this.
Starting with multiple in our regression.
So now we're simply going to go to runtime and then run 0 and all the sales are now executing.
And there you go.
We end up with an art squared coefficient of 0 point ninety three.
Very good.
Very good one as we can clearly see you know the predictions are amazing they're very close to the real
results.
So remember this first column is the vector of predictions and this second one is the vector of real
results and that's why here we have an amazing are squared coefficients.
But according to you is it going to be the best model.
Well that's what we're going to figure out very quickly because then we're going to run all the cells
here for the pulling them a regression.
There we go.
As you can see it's growing very fast and well for the polynomial regression model with remember a degree
of four.
We get a final r squared coefficient of 0 point ninety four 258.
So we've already beat our multiple in our regression model and therefore so far the best one is polynomial
regression.
Feel free to actually test some other degrees if you want.
But now we're going to move on to support vector regression and see if it's going to beat that pulling
them a regression.
I actually really liked this model and usually I get the best results with this but let's see.
Let's run all the cells and in flashlight we'll get the final performance.
No not yet not yet actually.
And by very very short it beats indeed as a polynomial regression mode you know 0 point ninety four
eighty.
And here we had actually 0 point ninety 458 so so far the best model is the support vector regression.
Can you see how we're going super fast here.
Right.
We only had to change the name of the dataset here and all the rest is automatic and that's the beauty
of code templates.
Now let's move onto the next one decision tree regression and let's see if it can beat the support vector
regression which remember has opened 94 8.
So let's see.
Let's run you know all the cells and the final result is 0 point ninety two two.
Okay.
So that's actually the worst.
I think it is indeed worse than the multiple in our regression.
Yes.
So the decision tree regression rule did not perform well here but maybe that's because it didn't have
enough team spirit to tackle these predictions and that's what we're going to figure out with random
forest regression because indeed a random forest regression model is a bunch of trees teaming up to
return an ultimate prediction.
So now the ultimate question is do you think that the final winner of this competition is going to be
the support vector regression mall or the random forest regression model.
Take your bet and let's see if you're right.
There we go.
We're about to find out in a second because we're going to click Run or now and we're going to get the
final final result with a final r squared coefficient of actually 0 point ninety six which therefore
makes the random forest regression the big winner of this data competition.
So congratulations in a very few seconds you were able to quickly identify and select the best regression
model and mostly you know the most important thing in all this is to finally know how to answer this
very often asked question how do I select the best model.
And well the answer is you simply try all of them and using the r squared coefficient you compare them
and conclude on which one is the best.
And in our situation here you know for this data set.
Well the best is the random for its regression.
All right.
So congratulations.
Now you know a lot.
You know you have an expertise in regression models.
You not only know how to build them but also you have all these code templates which you can use very
efficiently to select the best machinery model for your regression problem.
And that's for any dataset.
And remember if your dataset has missing data or categorical data well you only have to grab your tools
in the data pricing toolkit to handle these situations.
And then you can deploy your code templates.
All right.
So I'm super excited and super happy now that we completed 100 percent.
This part 2 on regression and now my friends we're going to move on to a brand new branch of machine
learning which is classification and which we're gonna do exactly the same but this time to predict
a category and same as what we did for this regression branch.
Well we will build several classification models and at the end I'll show you again how to select the
best one.
So I can't wait to see you in this part 3.
And until then enjoy machine learning.