Bearable trap last time we learn how to create dummy variables to replace our categorical predictors
state in the model.
We also discussed that you can never include both dummy variables at the same time.
In our example we admitted the California dummy.
Now why is that.
What will happen if we include the second dummy variable in the model as well.
Let's see then tension here is that you're basically duplicating a variable.
This is because D2 always equals to one minus D1 the phenomenon where one or several independent variables
in a linear regression predict another is called multicollinearity as a result of this effect the model
cannot distinguish between the effects of D-1 from the effects from of D2.
And therefore it won't work properly.
And this is called the dummy variable trap.
If you do the math behind this scenario you will see that the real problem is that you cannot have these
three elements in your model at the same time the constant and both the dummy variables.
I will leave it up to you to figure this one out on your own and let me know if you have any trouble
.
I'll definitely help here.
So to sum up whenever you're building a model always admit to one dummy variable and this applies irrespective
of the number of dummy variables they are in that specific dummy set.
If you have nine then you should only include eight if you have 100.
Then you should only include 99 of them.
Also note that if you have two sets of dummy variables then you need to apply the same rule to each
set.
For instance we could have had a column which specifies the industry in which the companies operate
to build the model in that case we would have had to perform exactly the same steps and create another
set of dummy variables specifically for that column.
And then we would include all but one of those dummy variables in our actual model.
I hope this explanation was useful and you will never fall victim of the dummy variable trapped in your
modeling.
Next time we're going to cover the different ways you can build a model.
We will learn all about backward elimination of forward selection stepwise regression and much more
.
Going to be an exciting tutorial and I look forward to seeing you then.