Hello my friends.
Welcome back to this implementation of tonnes and sampling.
So at the end of the previous editorial I asked you to implement by yourself.
Well Step three Now that step one and step two are well implemented.
And so you exercise in is Step three was to indeed figure out the trick to select the ad that has the
highest random drop among all these random draws taken from the different better distributions for each
of the ads.
So I hope that you tried.
Congratulations that you succeeded and even Congratulations if you only tried.
What matters is that you know you practice and no worries.
Now we're going to implement a solution together.
So let's do this.
So the first question I have for you is do we have to stay in this second for loop.
Well yes of course.
Because that trick to keep in memory the maximum of the run draws has to be done through all this.
Second full loop you know iterating through the ads and it's only until we get the final random draw
that we can know which one is the maximum.
So of course we stay inside as full loop and Well very simply since you know we have this random beta
here which is indeed the random draw from the beta distribution of the ad ie we are dealing with right
now.
Well what we have to do now is naturally to compare this random draw to Max random the maximum the run
draw which OK so far is initialized to 0 you know at the beginning of the for loop but then of course
you get that we will update that value of Max random to the new random beta if the new random beta is
higher than the maximum and therefore you know over the iterations of this second loop iterating through
the ad well Max random will be updated each time we get a random beta that is higher than the previous
random beta meaning that is higher than this Max random parameter.
So that's exactly the same trick as before you know with the UCB algorithm when we were updating that
maximum of the upper confidence bound at each iteration of that second for loop.
So here it's exactly the same.
And therefore you know what is the next step.
Now next step I'm going to scroll down a bit.
The next step now is to start of course with an if condition and if condition which will check if well
that random draw.
You know this random beta variable here is higher than this maximum random draw.
And if it is the case then inside this if condition we will say that this maximum random draw has to
be updated to become the new random beta.
That was just higher.
OK.
And at the same time we will select the add of index I inside the same if condition.
Because anyway if we get a new higher random beta Well this ad will be updated as well.
OK so I'll show you.
Let's first write this.
If condition.
So if random underscore beta is larger than Max random.
All right then Collin and inside.
Well what do we do we of course update the value of Max random you know the maximum of the random draws
to become that new random beta which is indeed higher than the maximum random draw collected so far.
And then as we said well if that's the case you know if the ad I return with right now has a random
beta that is higher than the max random draw.
Well we can select this ad to become this index.
All right.
So let's simulate you know the first iterations of this loop.
First Max random is equal to zero.
Then I begins at zero.
So first we're dealing indeed with the first ad of index zero.
We compute the random draw from the beta distribution of this first at zero.
Then of course random beta will be larger than Max random.
So Max random will be updated to become the value of that random drug the first ad and we will select
that first ad then I will be equal to one.
You know the index one meaning the index of the second ad then we will take the random draw from the
beta distribution of this second ad of index 1.
If this random draw is higher than Max random which is equal to the random draw of the previous ad then
we will update Max random to become this new random draw of this new ad and we will select this new
ad to become the ad selected and otherwise if you know this new random draw from this new ad is not
larger than Max random then we will do nothing and we will just keep the previous ad and the produce
Max random and we repeat this you know through the iterations of this second for loop up to the last
ad you know the ad of index 9 and successively will Max random will be updated if needed you know if
the random draw is larger than the maximum random draw and we will select the right ad accordingly.
OK.
So very easy trick.
And you know that's a classic in Python to get the maximum of a list through a for loop so it's really
good that you know this trick and it's really good that you did it twice once with UCB to compute the
maximum of the upper confidence bounds and with Dunson something to compute the maximum of the random
draws.
So now you're all set with getting maximum techniques and therefore time to move on to the next step.
Now by the way congratulations if you got this right.
I know it's not that easy the first time but you know by just repeating this over time it will become
so good at this.
And now what according to you will be the next step here.
Well I imagine some of you are wondering if we need to do one else here.
And the answer to that is no we don't need to do an else because if this condition is not true.
Well we'll just keep the last ad that had this maximum random draw so no need to do an else here.
And in fact.
Well the second for loop is done because it gives us exactly what we want.
It gives us the ad that has the maximum random draw among all the ads from zero to 9.
And therefore that's why I got out of this second full loop and I got back into this first for loop
you know right here I am at this level now.
Right.
OK.
So there we go.
Now we just need to finish this implementation because basically you know step one step two and step
three are done.
I know it's a little bit easier than the UCB algorithm but you're going to see that Indian end the result
might be even better.
I won't tell you exactly if it's gonna be the case but you're going to see we're going to have a good
surprise for the end.
Okay.
So now let's finish this implementation.
Basically we just need to you know update the different variables we have here.
You know we need to update exactly these four variables at selected numbers of rewards one numbers of
rewards zero and total reward.
So I suggest we start by updating at selected.
So I'm going to copy this actually will be simpler.
And then right here you know make sure to be at the right level at the level of this first for loop
you know for and in range zeros.
And now I'm gonna place that at selected variable and so now over to you according to what do we need
to do here.
How do we need to update that at selected variable.
Well exactly the same as in UCB of course since this variable corresponds to the full list of the ads
that are selected over time.
You know it contains all the ads are selected over time up to the ten is round and well each time we
select a new ad we need of course to append this new ad that was just selected which has an index ad
of course into this at selected list and therefore in the append function we of course need to input
at.
All right.
Perfect.
So that appends the ad to this full list of the ad selected which will be remember the input of the
histogram.
Then as we said we need to update these two variables numbers of rewards of 1 and numbers of rewards
zero.
But let's think this through.
How do we need to update these two variables.
Well that actually depends on something.
Something specific.
It is whether when you know we selected that ad at this particular round for a particular customer it
depends on whether the ad was selected got a reward 1 or a reward zero because indeed if it got a reward
one well this needs to be incremented by 1 and if it got a reward zero.
Well this needs to be incremented by zero.
Right.
We can actually see that clearly in step 1.
And I want n is a number of times that I got we were won up to round.
And so if at a new round we get we want one.
Well this has to be incremented by 1 and simple this one.
This is a number of times that I got rewards zero up to round n.
So if I go round and we go to reward zero Well this needs to be incremented by 1.
And therefore what we need to do here since we have you know two different conditions.
Well we need to of course naturally.
And if condition once again.
But a simple one that is if condition that we'll just check if Well the reward is equal to one.
So so far I'm just going to write this reward and then be careful.
Double equal one instead of just one equal.
Because otherwise this would be an affectation than Colin.
But now you're gonna say wait we don't have any reward variable.
Well that's because same as in the UCB implementation I just want to highlight what is this reward remember.
And therefore just above.
I'm gonna specifically say what is this reward.
And that's you know that's exactly the same as in the UCB implementation.
It is the value in the data set corresponding to the row we're dealing with right now in this first
full loop you know with this particular customer and the column of the ad that was just selected right
because the reward is the value we get after selecting this add here to show to the specific user we
are dealing with right now in this first for loop and therefore the reward here is the value in our
data set right.
So I'm taking my data set and then the values attribute and then in square brackets I enter the row
of the user we're dealing with right now which is n so n and then the column of the ad that was just
selected which is at right.
That's exactly the same as in the UCB but I clearly wanted to highlight what is the reward here.
So that then we can check in an if condition if the reward is equal to 1.
And if that's the case well what are we going to do.
Well as we said we are going to increment this by 1 because if the reward is one that means that the
number of times this particular ad got We weren't one just got incremented by 1.
Then of course I'm taking the right index of this list of the different numbers of times each ad got.
We want one but the ad we're dealing with right now has of course the index ad because that's the ad
that was just elected and therefore I just need to copy this and then at equal pace that again and then
add plus 1.
All right.
So all good.
This particular value is updated the right way.
And now back in the else condition meaning the other condition where the reward we got by selecting
this ad at this particular round is equal to zero which can be specified through an else because we
can neither be equal to 1 or zero so l is fine here and then.
Well what we need to do is of course take that.
You know I can just copy all this and paste that and replace of course numbers of rewards one by zero
here and same one by zero here as well.
Because in this alpha condition we are in the condition that the reward we collected is zero and therefore
that variable of the index at here which represents the number of times this ad here got reward zero
needs to be incremented by 1.
All right.
Perfect.
And now we just have one final thing to do.
You know exactly what it is.
Let's not forget about this.
It is to update that particular variable which gives the total reward you know the total accumulated
reward over the round.
And since now we are you know in a new round you know with this first full loop here.
Well of course as soon as we get this new reward we need to update this total reward by incrementing
it by the reward we just got.
Whether it is zero in which case there is no implementation or one in which case we incremented by 1.
So let's do this efficiently.
Total Reward is equal to total reward plus reward.
All right.
And that way we update our total reward variable.
And that's my friends.
Now the implementation of Thompson sampling is over.
So congratulations you just implemented your second reinforcement learning model.
And by the way now the full implementation is done because indeed here we don't have anything to change
we can just plot the histogram because we have the same variable names.
So now it's time for the show time in the next tutorial I will show you the demo of Thompson sampling.
We will of course run all our sales.
And mostly we will compare the two performances between UCB and Thompson sampling.
I remind that UCB was perfectly able to find that best ad you know with the highest click through rate
in 1000 rounds but was not able to do it in 500 rounds.
And so now I'm super excited to check if Thompson sampling will do better than this.
Meaning if it will not only be able to figure out the best ad in 1000 rounds but also if it will be
able to find it in 500 rounds which UCB couldn't do.
All right.
So let's find out about this in a next material.
I can't wait to show you all this.
And until then enjoy machine learning.