(gentle acoustic guitar music)
Hi. I'm Chris Haroun,
and this MBA degree program is not what you think it is.
It's better.
(gentle acoustic guitar music)
(pencil scratches)
This program is more than 25 years of business experience,
all rolled into one easy to access online program.
I've sold over one million courses,
in every single country.
I worked at Goldman Sachs,
I have an MBA from Columbia University,
and I've work in the venture capital,
hedge fund, and consulting industries.
I've also started many companies,
and my courses have been featured in Forbes,
Business Insider, CNN, and NBC.
If you're ready to nail your next interview,
get a better job,
get a raise,
start that business you've always dreamt of,
improve the one you currently run,
or better manage your personal finances,
then, this MBA degree program is for you.
I can't begin to tell you
how comprehensive this program is.
It's got everything,
including more than 300 hours of on-demand video.
I would have to do
one of those dramatic opening title crawls,
from a certain space movie,
just to show you.
(thrilling orchestral music)
And check out all the amazing reviews,
from students who have already enrolled
in this MBA degree program.
(thrilling orchestral music)
This on-demand version of the program
is only $499,
and it's more up-to-date
than many of these old-fashioned MBA programs,
which cost you well over $100,000.
Not to mention,
they don't even teach you the practical concepts
included in my program.
Last but not least, there is a 30-day
100% money-back guarantee.
And because you can access this program from any device,
meaning a desktop computer,
or a laptop computer,
or a tablet, or even your smartphone,
it means you can comfortably fit it into your schedule.
Even if you work full-time, it's no problem.
So, if you're ready to unlock the key to your potential,
then, I'll see you in class.
(pencil scratches)