Welcome to Step Six of the course in terms of the what why and how of.
Step Six I'll kick off the what what are we going to learn.
We will discuss who the customer is and what the total addressable market is in much more detail as
we're going to build upon what we answered in step three which was the executive summary part of our
business plan and if applicable as always will answer questions about our customer and the market including
what our market and customer research process is including using using survey tools like Survey Monkey
what our customer concentration is how we plan on collecting information about our customers as well
as how we plan on getting customers.
We'll also talk about social media how to get immediate e-mail alerts when our company or product or
service is mentioned on web pages meaning using Google Alerts.
In addition we'll talk about the customer service process that we use.
We'll talk about our customer response time.
You know what our customer loyalty program is etc..
And as always if a placable will talk about what percent of the market we want to capture now we're
also going to talk about what the problems are with the industry and what the solutions are to the problems.
Meaning why our product or service is it is a bargain or really good to use for our customers.
And you'll see that everything is always feeds into the next tab here.
Okay.
And also everything that we do here a lot of what we do in a step is going to feed into the presentation
part.
Here at the end of the course and that's optional now step 6 We're also going to discuss industry risks
as well as barriers to entry seasonality and much more.
Okay let's move on to why why are we documenting topics like customer research market sizing etc..
Because the customer is always right and the customer is the lifeline and the alpha and omega of our
business model.
And if we don't thoroughly understand who we're selling to then our success rate will of course not
be as high as we want it to be.
Okay lastly how how are we going to complete Step 6.
As with all steps we're going to answer questions in our inputs and analysis tab which then feeds in
other tabs including our Step 6 customers and markets put tap and you'll see that you'll see in the
Step 6 outputs tab here that I provides you with checkboxes.
So you can turn off certain items that just aren't applicable or of any interest to you to include in
your business plan including customer survey research customer response time customer loyalty programs
warranty policy and industry search trends as well as what percent of the total addressable market that
you want to own in five years.
And we can also turn on and off seasonality.
Thanks.