Welcome to step 10 of the course in terms of the what why and how of Sept. 10.
I'll kick off the what.
What are we going to learn.
We will discuss our past if applicable and our future milestones including a product or service that
we create and when we want to be created by.
We also talk about revenue milestones our break even milestone are optional unit sales milestones our
total addressable market percent capture milestones as well as our geographic and industry vertical
milestones.
We also talk about our exit strategy milestones like an IPO and much much more.
Let's move on to why.
Why are we talking about milestones and why are we doing this so late in the business planning process.
Because we not only want to show the reader of the business plan what our product or service vision
and road map is but we really want to do this close to Step 12 meaning the financial part of our business
plan has a lot of what we're going to document here in Step 10 being the milestone section can be used
to create our financial model in Step 12.
Lastly how how are we going to complete part 10.
Well we will answer the questions in the inputs and analysis tab and you're to notice here that I included
several of these optional questions here because many of us haven't achieved past milestones in our
business models especially if we're writing a business plan for a company that hasn't even launched
yet.
So all we'd care about his future milestones in that case.
And so if you click on the output button here you'll see that I provided checkboxes for you in case
you want to omit the past milestone and additional future milestone options here.
Thanks.