Welcome to step one of the course in terms of the what why and how of step one I'll kick it off of the
what.
What are we going to learn.
We will learn about general business inputs to our business plan and other crucial topics that we need
to cover before writing a business plan including who is the reader of the business plan what type of
legal structure the company has or will have as well as intellectual property topics like copyrights
patents and trademarks and if applicable.
And if you already have several employees we will talk about which employee will write each part of
this business plan and what the deadline dates are.
We will also discuss the strengths and weaknesses of your company and other legal topics and much much
more.
Moving on to why why are we answering all of the questions in step 1.
Because I want to make sure that we understand from a high level perspective what the legal structure
is of our company as well as the pros and cons of this business model and who the reader is so we can
customize our entire business plan based on the aforementioned topics.
Lastly how how are we going to learn about these concepts together.
In the next lecture and as with all 13 parts of this course we will click on the blue inputs and analysis
button and answer many questions together.
Thanks.