Welcome to Step 11 of course in terms of the what why and how of Step 11.
I'll kick it off for the one.
What are we going to learn.
This part of the business plan creation process allows us to talk about any material risks that we have
not discussed yet in steps 1 through 10 including future macroeconomic risks the emergence of future
competitors risk future changes in technology that could impact our product or service even if we're
not starting a tech company.
I also included a question on what is your disaster recovery strategy just in case your Web site gets
hacked or there's a fire at your headquarters etc..
And I also included a question that I love asking CEOs and entrepreneurs which is optional.
But is this what is the most mis understood aspect of your business model by potential investors or
customers or employees or partners.
In addition I included a question on other potential risks in case we have not yet disclosed other material
potential risks in our business plan so far.
Now as a quick side note if there are other documents or items that you want to include like resumes
for exhibits etc. We'll talk about this.
In step 13 which is the appendix step.
OK let's go back to Step 11 now let's move on to why.
Why are we discussing so many risks and other topics like disaster recovery because the reader of the
business plan will really appreciate this as it shows how thoughtful and thorough your business plan
is and this will give your reader and you as well more confidence in the success potential of your company.
Lastly how how are we going to complete Step 11.
Well after we answer the questions in this inputs and analysis tab then you will see in the output section
that I have also included the option to turn off the topic of the most undershoot the most misunderstood
aspect of your business model.
Although I do recommend that you include this in your business plan.
But I understand also that you know.
If you want to exclude it that's cool because we're all different stylistically when it comes to documenting
our business plans.
Thanks.