Please click on the button called inputs and analysis for Step 10 milestones.
And there's a couple of different sections here there's future milestones and past milestones.
And most people taking this course in reading your business plan are not going to talk about past milestones
because I'm anticipating that a lot of you are creating brand new business models but I included in
case you have a more established company and you're using this course as kind of a checkup so to speak.
And so here I outline what the purpose is of milestones.
And it kind of helps you understand qualitative goals that you have and quantitative goals as well.
And I put this part of the business plan milestones closer to the end because I want to put it ahead
of and close to Step 12 where we have our financials because if you had a break even target date that
you want to quantify and showing your financial model.
But if you mention the milestones section or if you have a target revenue by a certain number of years
or a certain number of units you want to sell etc..
It makes sense to have it close to where the financials portion is here.
Okay.
And again we'll talk about how to build out financial models using units or or services based billing
per hour etc. when we get here and in this part of the cost step 12 I'll talk about how to model a product
based company and service based company or both at the same time.
So the first one here is what is your future revenue milestone targets.
And if you want you can set up your targets for revenue goals in 1 3 5 and 10 years.
And if you can't answer this now.
Don't worry because we'll cover more detail in Step 12 but it is a milestone worth mentioning.
If you come up with.
If you come up with these goals just take note of them remember what they are.
So later on in the financial section we can tie it in nicely to what you wrote here completely optional
at you at home.
And then here what are your future units sales milestones like how many units of the product if you
have a product are you planning on selling them 1 3 5 and 10 years and you can write that down here
if you want.
It's optional.
And then we'll tied into your revenue income statement later if you don't know much about financial
statements don't worry I'll start from scratch to Haaretz.
And then here I've got a future total addressable market percent milestones.
You know what percent of the market you want to own a 1 3 5 and 10 years.
Again this is this is optional here.
And then what's your future break even milestone if you can mention when you think you'll reach profitability
if you can't answer this yet.
That's OK.
And you might want to flag it here by selecting a flag and a red flag and then come back to it later.
Right.
So you can do that with all these questions as you know.
So a lot of these you might actually want to win a flag and come back to after you complete the financial
statements portion of your course in Step 12.
It's fine to flag it and not completed.
All right.
Now because there really is a lot to do in this course so I just had a two flags there just sample flags
whatever.
And then here.
What are your future product or service milestones.
You know what.
When is the product going to come out in the future for you if you have a platform solution.
Are you going to build upon that platform longer term with with different products or services etc..
Or if you run a strategy consulting company are you to branch out into technology consulting as well
that sort of thing.
Okay.
And here this is optional but do you have future Geographic milestones like are you going to open an
office in other markets.
And do you think that you'll get a significant revenue with certain markets over time that sort of thing.
Again this is all optional and I made another category here future.
Other milestones in case I don't cover other milestones get it's all optional.
And then here we've got what your future exit strategy if you plan on doing an IPO cetera.
You can comment on it optional of course and I'm going to talk now about past milestones achieved and
you can skip.
Yes you can skip the rest this lecture.
If you're if you don't have any past milestones but if you're a little bit more established or your
company was founded on a number of months ago or a number of years ago whatever you can answer in your
past revenue milestones achieved here your past unit sales milestones achieved maybe when you sold your
100 product or whatever it is or build your 1000 hour if you have a services business you know what
what's past a total addressable market percent so achieved if applicable.
It probably won't be for most people what your past breakeven milestone achieve if you've already had
revenue and expenses which of course means break even again optional.
And then you're past profit margin milestones etc. and we're going to talk a lot of boat about margins
profit margins and there's different types of margins as well.
We'll talk about gross margins net profit margins that sort of thing and we'll cover that in a lot of
detail here and there's financial ratios that are automatically to be created for you here and you'll
you'll love it.
He's close that down and if you go back to the homescreen and you scroll down you'll see that there
are some margin percent financial ratios that will appear there as you complete the rest of this course.
Okay.
And then here have you.
What are your past products or services milestones achieved if you released a product already you probably
want to talk about that in a it really gives investors or readers of the business plan comfort in knowing
that you've reached milestones in the past.
If not don't worry about it.
And then previous Geographic milestones like maybe you expanded to the east coast last year or West
Coast or whatever country or region you're in that sort of thing.
And then just other past milestones are here as well and so as you complete this the that the non-optional
questions again this will automatically update for you or you can just click here to override and then
it will mark has 100 percent which shows that we are well and making good progress.
Really it's a two thirds done 71 percent done.
I will see you in the output portion of step 10.
Thanks.