All right let's mix it up a bit.
And I want to talk about doing the financials and I'm mixing up because I want to use my own is my old
Think Pad laptop.
I just love the keyboard here on the fly came through on this one.
OK so I'm using this on Windows.
It should be the same thing.
I've also test this on the Mac obviously.
All right cool.
So there's going to be a lot to this part.
OK.
And there's a bunch of different tabs I've set up for you.
And basically I say is the one that you should be on now so please click that if you're not already
there in a stands for inputs and analysis and everything for all your financial statements.
I set this up by architecting this so that everything we enter on this one tab here called the inputs
analysis tab will automatically feed through and populate all these financial statements.
And then this here is called all and it has a combination of all of the statements.
So let me just show you from a high level perspective what I'm going to do and then I'll explain it
in a lot of detail.
And if you're already very knowledgeable about finance and county you might want to skip some of this
but let me run through it anyway.
So this here is the revenue tab.
Okay.
And this all this statement has here are this this this tab is just details on revenue and what drives
financial statements is usually revenue.
Okay revenues the top line and most items on a financial state when your forecast and the future are
based on a percent of revenue that's revenue.
Okay.
Next up we've got I guess which is the income statement and revenue feeds into that and I'll explain
all this in lot more detail and then I've got the balance sheet then the cash flow statement and then
I've got something called all day and you can always navigate this way in that way if you want.
I like cooking these things.
The same thing.
So all is going to be an output.
And when we make this a bit smaller
now I miss my Mac.
OK so all is going to be an output of everything that we create together and kept in these pages here
are going to feed into our final output as well.
But we're right now we're we're talking about all of these financial statements on this little tab here
hopes.
Sorry about that.
OK.
A quick click the watch a video of this section.
All right.
So if I scroll down a bit you're going to see that financial statements are being created for you and
the revenue net income highlights are at the top there.
And c c right right here it is.
And then below that is a chart and you'll see the chart has nothing in it because we haven't created
any data yet.
And I while all this is really important.
Please make sure that you don't minimize or close any of the data in the columns.
If you want to look at what's in the charts.
Otherwise you won't be able to see it on the chart because it will be hidden.
So if I went like this then Year 2 you wouldn't see that information in the chart.
Just leave these open you can close in if you want just when you look at the data but if you want to
look at the charts and especially for when we export all the stuff for our fight or file a business
model document you want to make sure those are all open decks.
Okay.
And again this stuff will populate automatically.
So this year is going to be the first page and this will make a lot more sense to sync as with the first
page is just a little snapshot of of our financial section revenue net income and then a chart of revenue
and net income.
Okay scrolling down here is where your financial ratios are and create if you automatically and I added
this here from actually one of my other courses my introduction of finance and then of course this year
we'll just remind you what each one of these ratios mean.
And I'll talk about them all at length as we go through this as well.
And then I have as you can see here a chart of gross margins.
Again I'll explain everything from scratch.
And then below that you just stop scrolling so it can populate helps to stop operating margins.
I'll just use the arrow keys.
And then I've got.
Net profit margins and all this stuff will automatically populate and then I've got return on assets
return equity which most people won't look at initially anyway.
Okay.
And then here I've got the monthly and this is automatically to be creative for us you'll see this is
awesome.
The monthly revenue for year 1.
And then I've got the quarterly revenue for year 2 for year 1 every every single quarter for them for
the first three years.
And this will look a lot better too don't worry.
That's how we put it into our our final output it just looks a little bit jagged here but it'll look
good.
And then here we've got the annual revenue and these will both go on a page together which is why I've
got them here right there.
Garrett is there their get away.
Okay so page 5 will have these two statements here the Coralee an annual revenue.
It's a lot.
I'm showing you but don't we as well make a lot of sense soon you're going to love it.
Okay.
And I've got operating expenses here for every month for for year one and don't worry if these here
are or are cut off a little bit they'll look really good by the time we're down to this I promise you
rights and I put in a bunch of other categories in case you want to add other items or we could just
remove that.
Okay.
And then I've got annual operating expenses than I've got here.
Your quarterly income statement from your once your 3 and then strolling down here I've got the annual
income statement from your 1 to your 10.
And then I've got and don't feel overwhelmed please this is all going to be fed from one tab.
It's so simple you're in a lot of it then I've got the balance sheet here.
And this is quarterly.
You can see here from your once a year three and then I have got the annual balance sheet from your
once year 10.
And they're all zero because I don't put any data in.
And then I've got the cash flow statement for I've got it for the first three years here quarterly.
And then after that I've got the annual cash will stay in for 10 years and then that's it.
It's a lot.
That's it.
So let's go together to I.A. and everything is going to be fed into here that we're sure everything
we enter is only to be here has all we fed into all of these awesome little tabs here.
I know I'm a finance nerd.
OK great.
So we're now on the inputs tab here inputs and analysis case should be green.
Make sure it's green and what you want to do is I'm going to go through this in a lot of detail and
again if you're really good at finance and count you might want to skip this.
But every single line item that's going to feed directly into all financial statements will be done
below on this one tab and the naming convention.
I've got the set up here as a member in this course we only answer stuff in white cells to but I also
made the items that you can change that are in the white cells blue just so you can see a little bit
better because that's like gray there.
So only change blue white cells.
Ok cool.
And one more thing I want to show you is is this whenever items are linked from a previous tab or another
tab.
They're green.
See here if I go to the revenue and if I get the balance sheet green and then cash flow statement is
basically almost all green.
So again you scantier stuff in this one tab here which should be Greenall inputs and analysis.
All right let's do this.
So I don't know if you're running a services company or a product based company but I set this up so
that you can answer data for both.
So if I were to go here and click one you'll see that all these tabs are shown or all of this information
is annual and I can open up each year if I want to that's monthly.
OK.
So I go monthly for the first couple of years and then after a couple of years I just went to quarterly
because what happens is you tend to model monthly for the first couple of years and then you do have
most big companies do which is you just do quarterly.
So the first four years or five years we see here looks like it at five years look gets like five years.
Oh yeah.
And then by year 6 I just did quarterly.
Can all of this data works.
And then I did annually after that because it's so hard to forecast what's going to happen in the future
between Year 6 and year 10.
I mean this year is hard enough as it is.
And if you've never done financial modeling before one thing I want to tell you and I've done a ton
of financial modeling on Wall Street when I worked has finished venture capital center.
But you have to be comfortable with uncertainty and explain that when we make a lot of assumptions and
where we forecast in the future and it's never going to be perfect.
But just be comfortable with the fact that it won't be perfect.
If everybody could forecast the future perfectly then stocks would always be priced perfectly and stock
markets wouldn't exist.
So I hate to show you a methodology I developed over the years having worked on Wall Street work the
hedge ministry work in much of the street.
I've done a lot of modeling I love it.
It's a lot of fun and I love doing.
I think pagen pure outswim business but this work on Mac as well.
OK.
So what I want you to do now is before we get started entering all the data down below are we to close
all of these capped and what do you do as I want you to name the years it's blue with white tech so
you can name it and see how my recording is going.
OK.
I'm still recording I'm using Powerpoint by the way record books like this.
I insert a PowerPoint screen.
You can only do the screen recording on Windows.
All right.
Otherwise quick time in Mac.
So your name all of these and this will filter through everywhere and this will be awesome you'll love
it.
So I'm going to name these just based on the years today.
So 2018 and you might start this course in January 2019 so it all depends.
Or you might want to throw on some historical data as well.
Tally up to 19.
And then I can do 2020 and I'll go into high speed mode.
This is software
OK so I have all 10 years entered in and you never after 20 years again will automatically be done for
you.
So if I open this up we've got January of of 2008 teens it's automatically fed in directly.
Okay great.
And let's open them all up now.
And then if I were to scroll over here you see January 19 all the months and then all automatically
done quarterly after year 5 meaning you're six.
OK.
And then I'll be done annually for the last 5 years on this model four years as a model.
So there's the Coralee one that's year six and then year seven eight nine 10 11 or the.
That's right yeah.
This year is quarterly based on these numbers tell us 23 and these are the last four years.
OK good.
Now that everything is open I want to scroll over here and show you a couple more things.
These down here what's automatically be creative for you is something called Spark lines and this is
a really cool feature can and I've added these everywhere on this.
This tab here and this is great.
So you've got the top line is going to be the currency change like the actual dollar or currency amount
changed.
OK.
And then the bottom line is going to be the percent change and this will allow us to look for trends.
And once the data gets popped.
So make a lot more sense to you.
And so if you were to scroll down you'll see that I've got spark lines all the way down that will be
created for you.
OK great.
And this here is optional but you can enter in comments here notes if you want us on why you assume
certain numbers will be the way they are or whatever just just little comments here and there.
And then here is where you can flag stuff as well so say I want to come back to revenue line.
One I would click here.
And then what happens is that flag appears there.
And then if we go to any other part in the spreadsheet outside of this you'll see that right there I've
got one flex yet there.
Okay got to let me go back here to I.
Okay great.
Now if scroller me here again you can enter in comments and you ignore what you see over here by the
way.
These are just inputs for me to make some charts for you.
Okay.
And you can look if you want to but I'm not going to talk about the course.
All right.
So now let's go all the way back here and let's start insert in putting the data together and I don't
know what business model you have signed to keep this very generic but what I'm going to say is going
to apply to any type of business model services based or product based.
So a lot of you will only have one revenue line at it because there's one type of product you're selling
but some you have to.
So let me start off with one.
OK so if you want you can just hard code on topis it's blue and white so you can type on top of it.
So say revenue in January 2013 is $10 and you go up to $20 or whatever it is.
I'm going to hit Control Z to undo that.
Now I also made a formula to do what I'm about to show you.
And if you don't track things on a unit basis you can ignore when about to do and just entering your
revenue here.
Okay.
Here yes.
So now let's say that you sell units like virtual reality goggles and let's say you think that you can
sell 100 in this period or you have sold in that period and make this the future if you want or use
whatever data you want and then say we sell 120 units here and then business gets cooking we're selling
140 this month 150 this month.
And I'm going in a bunch of dummy data and you'll see why in a second.
And the reason why there is a decimal here you might think yourself Chris hucking sell half a unit.
We included that because a lot of people won't be using this for a product based business model.
They'll use this financial model for services so if you have a firm where you build by the hour if you're
a lawyer or a doctor or consultant and you build by the hour you might have a half hour.
OK so here you're an answer in either the number of units or the product that you sold or the number
of hours that you've built for service.
A lot of consulting firms work that way.
So let me go ahead and then just change this around a bit and you can even assume that you're going
to grow by 10 units month over month.
And let me just say this and all of that plus 10 cases that were growing by 10 per per month over month.
And way I can do is I love Excel.
You can highlight this stuff here go all the way here.
You can't change out it's not blue and I can right click and I can pay special as a formula.
OK.
So I pace and special that as if formula some of you might want to use the other way of doing it which
is you go up here and then you go paste and then you select Paste Special and then you select formulas.
I know the Mac version looks a little different but this is how you do it there formulas it can get.
Okay great.
So we've now got the units or number of hours done for the first year and I'm going to do the second
year now and let's just say that things spike and we got 20 20 units or hours increase month over month
I had to skip remember that's an annual one.
Right.
So if you double click on anything the beautiful thing about Excel is it highlights all these numbers.
OK.
And also I've set this up so that certain items are tagged as well like here if I highlight that says
financials input revenue line item 1.
And so I can even go here as that was limit him to take me down.
It's pretty powerful.
I named all stuff.
OK.
So now let me go back here.
Go back up to revenue line item one.
OK.
And this is so much easier to do find his accounts easier to do if you look at it in a modularized perspective
meaning one thing at a time and we build on this logic as well so that longer term we have this eureka
moment where we're like oh my gosh this is amazing we're actually modeling from scratch.
We understand it all but a lot of people get intimidated because they look at all the data the same
time.
We're not going to do that.
We're going to break it down.
OK.
So now we're in increase.
That was 20 units and let me double click here.
Good that's 20.
And those can do the same thing here with that plus 20.
And then I got a copy
and then I'm going to pay special here.
And then I just know that's formula.
And you can use other methodology up here I showed you before if you want.
OK.
And then I'm going to assume just for fun I'm going to grow this by another 20 units every single month
for the next couple of years so I'm going to copy this
and then I can actually get the pace that in there I know I should pay special but it's fine.
That was OK.
See there you go.
And then going to do it again for 2021 for our units or the number of hours that we're building if it's
service and where we do this slowly and build upon it.
And then you're like oh my god I get it so makes sense to me.
OK.
Get.
It's a wonder when that was an update.
Somebody said it takes time.
OK now read it one more time for this year here.
OK.
Paste and that's going to update I'll take a second or two.
That data will work don't it give it a second to think.
Come on.
Think it's coming.
It'll work during
that update.
I don't know why it's taken a while.
I'll come back to you at work.
OK.
And then now it's on a quarterly basis.
And if you want you can model quarterly here completely or call.
This should be updated.
Come on.
There we go.
Finally add up that took a second there all right.
And then here you can do quarterly as well.
And I'll just leave this out for now.
You can do annually as well which is which is pretty self-explanatory.
Now I want to show you something cool that got created here.
Whoops sorry about that.
OK.
So we have the number of units has been created here on an annual basis.
So that's Year One two three.
It increases like that.
Okay.
And this would be the other end all year so we didn't do.
And this is the percent increase year over year change which is still growing but the growth rate is
declining.
Okay.
Because we're only growing 20 month over month on a larger number.
So it's still positive growth but the rate of change is slowing.
I ignore what's over here because I mentioned information there.
OK.
Now let me go all the way back here before Answer other stuff.
One more cool thing
there you go.
All right.
Now you see what happened here was this spark line was created in this SPARC line shows that you've
had growth of 20 units or so or 10 years or so month or month if I delete these you'll see that there
will be a change here in this chart.
Ill update and everything will be impacted see here that the growth rate dropped were a lot lower now
so me do controls the controls that if you're in Canada or England or anywhere else in the world that
really goes back.
Okay.
So that SPARC line was created there now as well.
And the sparkling chart was automatically created here as well.
See here pretty cool.
Okay great.
So now we're done with with units but before we move on I want to show you what happens here with these
numbers and so we always look in finance at the mix we're still recording.
Good.
Okay.
We always look in finance at the rate of change.
And so in year one there's no year over year which changes this year once there's no formulas here.
And then here we look at the month over month right.
We grew here by 20 percent Mohon 220 and then we grew twentieths which is 17 percent.
And then a smaller growth than we look here at quarter over quarter growth and create a formula for
it here.
So this amount here is 480 this amount here is 364 and 80 is growth over 3 or 60 33 percent.
So you get quarterly growth there.
Okay.
And I've got sorry less space here.
Let me just scroll back up here quarterly and then what happens is here we got yearly.
So this year we've got and this is smart enough to skip that annual thing again.
So here I've got 150 percent growth year over year.
So you're going from 100 units there and now we're at we're at 250 that's one of percent growth.
And then growth here you can see yada yada all the way over here.
Okay.
So we're now done with with with units and because this is taking a lot of time I have to break this
lecture up because you know you're allowed to have much more in 20 minutes in lectures and in the next
lecture we'll do is we'll then talk about the average selling price per unit her hourly rate charge
backs.