Please click on inputs and analysis for Step 8 free or go to market strategy which means how you distribute
your products.
And I provided this helpful green shaded row here just to kind of explain.
Go to market strategy and a little bit more detail.
And it basically means how you're going to reach your customers how good your products or just your
services to customers.
And so a direct delivery or distribution and direct model means you're selling directly to your customers.
I mean there's no middleman like Dell computer would sell computers over their web site only and not
in stores.
In the past and then there's indirect which basically means if you're selling your products to a retailer
like Best Buy or or or Wal-Mart or even Amazon if they're if you're having somebody sell your products
for you through another distribution channel and just try to think about as you complete this part of
a business plan how do you ensure that no customer is more than 10 percent of your total revenue in
the very long run because that could be a red flag for some investors.
Some don't care when it right.
It all depends and every business Miles little bit difference.
And then we're going to talk about your sales and your sales force team's strategy in the next part
which is which is part 9 here we're just talking about distribution of your product or service.
I mean here we just you know you're entering here.
What is your online distribution strategy if you have one.
What is your off line strategy.
And then here what is your direct distribution strategy and I thought about not having an online distribution
strategy or at least have that is optional but I'm keeping it in there because longer term everything
is going to be sold online or sourced online or you'll be able to get leads online.
So I'm I'm leaving that in because I think that whoever reads the business plans can be thinking longer
term like that as well.
But it's not relevant you can always to leave it.
And then here this is direct to your customers meaning if there is no middleman.
And then here you got indirect meaning if you sell to somebody that you know is going to is going to
sell for you like selling it to wholesale.
And then here is just the cost of distribution.
Don't spend too much time on this answer though please because we're in talk about the cost of everything.
In a lot of detail in Step 12 when we talk about financials but I included it here because we're talking
about distribution meaning our go to market strategy and whoever's reading your report might be curious
about the cost of distribution even though we'll go in a much more detail on this later on.
So we are now done with with Step 8 inputs.
So if you answer all the questions here and I think they're all mandatory there's no optional ones here.
Then you'll see 100 percent show up or you can override here by selecting that and now shows 100 percent
done and we're officially 57 percent done look at that needles movement pretty cool.
Pretty cool.
Ok I will see you in the outputs part of step 8.
Thanks.