Please click on the inputs and analysis button for Step 3 which is the executive summary.
Now these questions are very high level and we can keep mostly answers pretty short for now and will
go into much more detail on some of the questions in the future steps here later on the course so the
reason we have an executive summary and just go here to what your final look like depending on which
template you chose.
But the reason we have the executive summary is a lot of times executives or potential investors or
the readers of these these reports only have time to read this section here.
And if it's really good they'll read the rest of it.
Sometimes they won't even bother and so I keep it very high level so in this section we talk about a
company and the overview of the market the target customer the national team the board if applicable
the problem and the solution with with your company.
Meaning what the industry problem and how does your product or service solve that problem.
And then if applicable We'll talk about a significant company milestone it will give a picture of the
product or markup of the product design if applicable and so you'll see that later on when we discuss
how to make these these final or business plans here.
You just click anywhere here in your table contents and it jumps directly there.
So this is going to be a relatively short section maybe a couple of pages and that's it.
And so it will end right here again I'll explain how to put this together later on in the course.
Okay so let's go through these questions now.
I mean keep them pretty short please because this is just a summary section.
OK so what is the ideal customer.
I kept mine short here in the answer for Tony shark movie and video game fans.
And you'll see which ones are optional which ones are not so obviously that's optional because it says
optional.
And then in the first two years where do you want your customers to be based in the United States.
This is just a fictional example that's all.
And then the ideal customer in five years will be in other countries.
And then here you can put other demographic information like the age and other details if you want.
And then here I've got the total addressable market in the s.a.m stands for total addressable market.
And you usually want to start companies in markets that are massive in what you can do to find out the
size the total addressable market is you can do a search online and see if there is a reputable source
like a great consulting firm like McKinsey or the Boston Consulting Group or Accenture etc. or Gartner
in the tech sector for example in Forrester just to tell you the size of the market lot of times you
get these reports of the headlines with the ports for free.
Every sector is different so I'll keep this answer quite generic but a lot of venture capital firms
only want to invest in companies that have a market size of over $20 billion.
And if you're having problems getting the size of the total addressable market then what you can do
is get the top 20 or 25 companies in your sector.
And if they're publicly traded just add up the annual revenue for all those companies and that's a decent
proxy for the size of the total addressable market.
Okay.
And the total adjustable market is how much revenue the entire industry makes each year and so in this
hypothetical example since my Tam is the video game industry and also the movie industry I've got the
TAM for both of them listed here.
Okay.
And then you want to find the growth rate of the industry is well if you can have two industries here
I'm targeting So I've got different growth rates.
And then moving down here we've got the source and it's always great from a credibility perspective
to show the sources that you have and put them in your report.
And there's a place in the first section here the executive summary section I to say where there's going
to be a footnote that's going to be fed and you see this oil field here this field here is is what's
going to be pulled from from here.
OK.
And I'll explain how later on when we look at the final business plan.
Okay.
So you want to name your sources or source.
For me it's IBIS World but the movie industry data and this artist for the video game industry and every
industry is different.
And then here I just put in the hyperlinks to those two sources which we will put in our report.
Alschuler OK now the next question here is optional.
What percent of the market do you want to capture in five years.
It's optional.
But I asked this because when we're doing our financial model later in the course if you wanted to kind
of figure out in five years what your revenue is going to be and if you're at 1 percent here then this
would be 1 percent of the market that sort of thing for revenue in five years.
And don't worry we'll discuss that and a lot more detail later now.
A lot of what we're doing in this entire business plan process is qualitative.
Okay.
And here is where we do the quantitative side.
And a lot of the stuff that we do in steps 1 through 11 will really help us to create the financials
part of the model and this will make a lot more sense to later on.
OK.
So I wrote here who my largest competitor is my second largest my third largest.
And these are three companies that make virtual reality equipment and software.
Again my company Tony Sharq virtual reality is just pretend company.
And then I put optional here you can list the fourth and fifth largest competitors here again only entrance
stuff in the at the white cells.
Please and then here write down what your competitive advantage is.
I wrote were the lowest cost producer and we have an exclusive contract with Disney which is pretend
of course.
Why now.
Why are you starting your company now.
Why is now the right time.
And I wrote here that theater sales are weak and studios need a new higher margin platform to sell their
content too.
And then how are you planning on selling the products.
So this is all about what's called go to market strategy and we have an entire section on that step.
This is just a high level answer right now.
How so.
Hypothetically I wrote the heart always will be sold on Amazon Wal-Mart Target and Best Buy big retailers
in the U.S. and then the media will be sold on that pretend Web site there.
Why you why are you the right person to do this.
And I wrote here because Tony has previous work experience just pretend of course in the Oculus virtual
reality division of Facebook where he created the content platform software distribution business model
certainly makes him credible.
And don't worry if you don't have great skills because your investors or readers of the business plan
will be impressed by because once we get to Step 4 of the course what we'll do is I'll tell you how
to put together an incredible board of advisers it costs you nothing that makes you look really really
good.
And just for a quick overview here let me go here to the presentation slides part of the course which
is completely optional.
So if I were to scroll down here to the management team and this will be filled in all the non picture
stuff for you as you complete each section in the course this is all just pretend data.
But you see here that I have three people that work in my company some logos that make them look good.
It's all pretend.
And then here's my board of advisers some guy named Gates William I don't know if you know him and then
some guy named Goeden Seth.
Anyway so I'm going to teach you how to get really good advisors have something in common with you.
Maybe they went to the same high schools you are university or maybe they're from the same hometown.
I teach how to network to get advisors.
Ken it's a lot of fun and it's free to do.
And actually if you go to my Web site Harroun ventures dot com that's all lowercase Harroun or un venture's
dot com you can download a networking book for free which is 200 pages which will teach exactly how
to network and get board advisors or get a meeting or get a customer or or an interview whatever that
sort of thing.
OK now let's go back to executive summary so I'm clicking here and again like I mentioned before when
I click these buttons it takes me to the top so if you don't want to go to the top but where you were
you can just click on the tabs down here.
All right next up scroll down here we've got the why you isn't here.
This is where you write down skills that your employees have.
OK if you have more than one person and I wrote here and this automatically pulls the data from your
step one in step one for you just for fun what I did.
Let me click here is I entered in the names of your employees has superheroes you have superhero employees
right.
So they're right here.
You might recognize these from certain certain movies like Scarlet and Jozen.
I changed that name just so that I can't get sued by the person whose name is not exactly Skaro Hinduism.
Just kidding.
I've got a bunch of others as well but but I put that there directly in this step for you.
When I pulled the information over from this cell for you so it's easier for you to think about how
to answer this next question here.
OK.
So it's just a field that you really need to know especially anyway quickly.
So all I did in this field was I pulled all of your employees names directly in here.
If you answered that men in the White cells back here in in step one you can just ignore that.
OK thanks.
So I wrote here.
If you have more than one person your company list the impressive skills that they have that will help
your business succeed.
I pulled in all their names and I made this up to pretend company.
But I wrote experience at Marvel studio the former CFO of high profile Soffer company an engineering
experience at Google etc..
And then here and this is optional because I don't know if we're going to have a board or not but I
wrote here write down some of the skills that your board has and we'll put your board together later
and if you while you can always come back to this question by just flagging this.
OK so let's just flag this for fun and during step for all.
I'll come back to that flat.
So you can see there's a little flag that's been created down there and then it appears here.
We know it to come back to this park.
OK.
So let's scroll down here another optional question is how much do you intend to raise.
If you plan to raise money enter it here as well.
Where did you use the proceeds.
And we want to raise that money.
It says to hire two software engineers and to open an overseas office in Bollywood.
OK and this here these two questions here are important.
And I kept it simple.
What is the problem that your company addresses and what's the solution meaning how does your product
or service address that problem.
This is important and I will try this new a couple of answers in this course.
And I also put it directly here on the presentation slides.
If you plan on making a presentation down here is the problem is the solution on this page here.
You can always click here to go back it's all hyperlinked and I'll take us back to exactly where we
are right now.
Here it is.
OK.
So the problem here and you write in one sentence so I wrote here.
The problem with mood Mark is that it is that the growth of the market is anemic and large media companies
are looking to reignite revenue and profitability growth.
And the industry solution which is based on our product our pretend product we believe that our company
solves the problems that large media companies are having with slow growth as our company has high margin
and scalable revenue model.
Yada yada yada.
That sort of thing OK so enter your answer there.
Next up we've got industry risks and we're seeing a list this from a high level perspective.
And later on during the other part of the Course here Cisco there I'll show you.
We're going to talk about other potential risks with this industry and your industry in general like
future competition macroeconomic future tech development.
It doesn't matter if you're Korean tech products or not technology will impact your industry later on.
OK.
So let's now go back to where we were.
The executive summary and now I have to scroll that's where it was.
Again you can click just on the bottom links here if you don't want to have it jumped to the top when
you push one of these buttons up here.
And these are just images.
By the way not real buttons will teach you how to create all this stuff.
At this point in the course in this lower third here OK if you're interested that's optional obviously.
And so if you want and this is completely optional of course you can put your image here of your product
towards the high level no data flow diagram of your service if it's applicable.
And if you don't have a product and a lot of people talk about MVP which stands for most stands for
minimum viable product you can always put the minimum viable product image here or you can go to five
or dot com and get somebody to create a wireframe sample of what your product will look like completely
optional.
To understand how to use 5 or dot com to get images done for you or mockups in general like I did with
my logo just.
You can go there directly by.
If you go back here to cover page you can you can actually just click on this link here and it will
take you to a video I made on that topic.
All right back to executive summary I'm going to click down here this time.
So I remember exactly where I was there.
All right.
And then here this is optional.
But what's your exit strategy if you have one.
OK so you're going to put everything here in the White cells.
So it might be an initial public offering or selling the company or something else that's similar to
an IPO or not a placable at all.
And as I write this down because a lot of times when you create these business plans you're trying to
raise money in a lot of the investors that might invest in your company are thinking OK if I give you
this money what's the exit strategy going to be.
Again it's optional and it's all based on whoever your customer is.
And if you can't remember what you wrote down for customer.
You just go here.
Who's the target reader of your plan and that sort of thing.
If you answer those questions earlier on the course.
If not don't worry but just ignore that.
And then here if you have a milestone meaning if your company is already existed for a while write down
a big milestone that's really really impressive.
In this cell here again it is optional.
And after you answer all of these questions especially the non optional ones then this will automatically
update as 100 percent done.
Or you can override that as always by clicking this button here which will not only update here but
also your total progress in the course and so assuming that we're done all three of these steps that
shows that we are now 21 percent done with the course I will see you in the next lecture where we will
talk about the outputs for the executive summary.
Thanks.