You know it looks a little bit off to me there is just a shadow.
That's fine.
OK.
All right.
I think we're done now with this.
You know we're done.
We're done.
OK good.
Great.
All right.
Let's go back home and see what is next.
OK.
We talked about all of this oh this was a pain the next to line me up on the outside.
All this is here.
These here these are lines.
So I grouped everything together and I create these little lines here individually which was disastrous.
So if I were to go group and then ungroup and then I drew them on there.
And the reason I drew them on there is because I wouldn't have.
These are all formulas here and I wanted that to be shown in the background.
And there is a way to put formulas on text but it's not perfect.
It's kind of buggy.
All right.
So what it did was this I just drew this.
And once you create one the rest are pretty easy so you learn little tricks hit shift control commands.
And then when I drag it down it's going to make a copy.
Take your finger off you there and over and over and over again create multiple ones.
And then when you move things it's shift.
So it'll only go left right or up or down but not in between diagonal and they were off there.
And that's how you line things and you want to zoom way way in as well.
When you do that just get it perfect.
Come talking like an artist.
Now it's just software it's all I like.
I always have.
All right.
And then here just all these these here are the things the first video of each one of the different
sections in the course.
And so I just read up on my website which I got over Squarespace you Squarespace beacon can it's it
makes it really easy to create web sites from scratch.
And that is it.
And this here by the way that's just text.
And I put that there because if it takes a while for for a page to load an Excel tab to load them what
you do is Yep I threw this text here just to.
So I want to say hey you're still with me right.
That sort of thing.
And I made it.
I started with 2.1.
This is some Mike's site.
So we see they start with higher numbers like you never start with one point out people like oh my god
it could be buggy.
And you start with 2.0 like oh 2.1 is good enough.
It's a minor upgrade as well.
All right.
At least I'm honest about being on the call.
And that is that.
And this year what I did was I disabled this.
I just made it a little bit transparent because when you're in the first tab you can't go back anywhere
right.
And so you can do is just get rid of the text there so we can actually do something with the box.
So when you click there signs that are box appear there are picture formats you kick it and then what
I did was I went to transparency here and I made it less transparent.
Instead of being like that I didn't want I want to press it and say hey it was going to go back man.
And then the very last happens while I did that so you can't you can't go forward.
And so I click presentations has to live here right there see.
And go back home.
And we are now done with the with the men is great.
OK good.
And one thing I'm going to show you and I know you're probably really curious about this.
Is this going to show you this.
And after I show you this what I'll do is over and give you your story on how I do this data here.
This one is tricky.
And so this here basically you've got it.
And don't try to recreate this just use what I have for you here.
Can I just copy and paste it right for me.
The way you do is it's all pattern recognition with this stuff.
So you go to HIDDINS speedometer or Odama.
I don't know what it is.
And then you're going to have I removed certain labels just you can ignore that there.
But this is where the needle is set up.
And then I've got different different dial labels right.
So if I wanted to actually Control-C and if I were to pace labels over here then the labels would appear
here I think let we see actually home here paste here Kenmare came here.
Hold on a second here.
Yeah I must've deleted it.
But they all show up but showed up on here all of the labels.
Anyway it's fun.
And then basically it used to go 10:23 for all the way up.
And then what I did was I found that there was a formatting issue so I just created and pasted special
numbers up.
OK.
And then here just play around with this and then just copy what I have because what happens is the
needle goes up based on different numbers.
It's too hard for me to explain but I went to total progress here.
So watch this Master-Maid he told us it commands and you can always just command and then the open square
brackets are called Square back and said jump right there.
OK.
So here I am here so I can hard code here 50 percent point five over.
I can't remember and will go back there and I'll show you what happened this could run off of that.
So a hidden speedometer.
I guess I was point five percent.
Chris 50 percent want to go here.
There you go.
All right good.
So it's just basically all this did was it drives off of total progress which is over here and it controls
a couple of times.
And what I did was I named this cell here.
And that's how it knows to refer to that I could have said go to G 11 and whatever but then I'll never
remember what Jila means.
But I call it total progress so I got to create another one hearing and say in when you do this.
It has actually you got to first of all click here and it can't be a reserved word you can use the words
already been done and you can have spaces the way computer code works is all Pramer always have to be
attached kind of so hi.
Hi there like this got here and sometimes it doesn't work.
And if it's being a pain in the neck and this happens sometimes you go up instead of being all the name
here.
What you do is Excel treats it like a formula c Go here to define name and get to work so I guess I'll
go Hi there.
OK.
And watch this.
It'll work it'll show there.
OK anon.
For those you using Windows.
This probably won't be an issue for you.
OK.
So hi there shows up.
So if I were right equals.
Hi there.
Good.
Then it knows that.
And this is really powerful when you're looking at financial statements.
We look at financial statements in this course and we had the red and green different colors.
So basically turn's formulas in English is kind of like COBOL which is computer oriented business logic
language.
But for myself to program this stuff.
All right.
So whenever I change this to what will be shown over here.
Great.
All right good.
So now you kind of understand this put on yourself just play around these numbers here if you want and
then I think if you were to add numbers here or one of these columns Ill add the labels back here if
you want look again.
All right.
So we are now done with that.
And what do we show you next is just to keep it consistent.
Do these and then I'll do these here OK and then we'll be done with them.
But the many completely and part me you want to make sure your menu is perfect though because the worst
thing can happen I've learned by failing and I made a course last year I had to go on every single tab
and change one little thing and a million times so make sure the last thing you do is you put this on.
It's like yeah OK.
Right.
So these here refer to different step status so basically member step 1 all this stuff.
If I drive up here and grouped it up or whatever.
Step One two three four Yeah.
All the way in here.
So this is step 13 status.
And that's all it is and I formatted it in such a way that it's on two different lines and I'll teach
you that in a second.
So if I go to command or control or whatever and then openings and close brackets here.
Then it jumps back to here.
OK.
So we're on step 1 tab.
And then what I did was I grabbed it from down here.
So ignore everything else just look at Wilderness and this here is named step 1 status.
That's the name and that's how every single page here all of these pages know to go right here.
They all know that step 1 status is the content Cerci here.
OK good.
Now I'm going to hits back and work that way or probably not.
Yeah.
Well I.
So I went back there so again the use on my screen is getting done here.
Sort of that knows whatever.
All right so.
And basically what happens is this here is a formula and I get the form.
And so when you're working with formulas I know it might seem a bit intimidating but I promise you gets
a lot easier.
Caja what you do is you always start with one bracket and you ignore everything else so I'm not going
to I'm going to escape to cancel this out here.
We always start like really basic like that.
Oh I start with some.
And then you build on the outside of his escape.
So a with that is OK.
All right.
So what I did here is this is counting what percent I'm done of that step in the flags as well.
And so what I did was remember here when I said you can override me over by clicking here.
So if you click here this will change override to true can overrides on other tab but basically make
nullify all this crap here.
So this is just if then logic is really cool.
So if this manual override button is pushed meaning it's true then just make it 100 percent we're not.
But if it doesn't then do something else.
And if it doesn't it's basically their main option.
But if it if it's not at 100 percent then execute this formal here and ignore this if everything I throw
if err on the outside of a lot of things just in case you change something and then you're like hey
what's going on.
And this is just doesn't work.
I just have it kind of going blank like it.
So always throw if error on after you've done everything.
And so what's going on is inside here it's basically just calculating what percent you're done.
This step and so if I get rid of that manual overdrive override which is 100 percent it'll disappear.
And then the calculation will occur at 0 percent.
And by the way it's basically saying well if there's no cells filled in right.
If you haven't answered all of the required questions remember some require some optional.
If you haven't done that then it's going to calculate it to be less than a hundred percent.
And before I show you the formula there because I know I probably confused people because I'm not that
good at explaining this.
I want to just match one more thing.
You know I had it on two different lines.
Zero percent and zero flags.
Well this here if you use a character called 10 char 10 it basically it's like a paragraph mark.
When you're hitting enter in Microsoft Word it's pretty cool.
OK.
Now what you do is going to build in the slope.
Here I am telling you I am not doing that.
OK.
So I'm going to go here and I usually hide stuff that's formula based because I don't want the student
to erase it or get confused or just you know in a day with too much stuff.
OK.
So what I did was here I created a bunch of things here and a lot of really smart much smarter developers
and I do like to use these big arrays which is kind of like databases within fields where to keep it
simple.
So did he was here member here if it's optional I said you don't have to fill it out.
So I did this.
That's pretty cool feature I just learned it.
It's called is number and is number is basically saying within this box here Deayton search for the
word optional.
If there is the word optional then return the word true.
That's it.
That's all it is.
And if it's true then make this zero if it's false.
Make it one.
So that means because you haven't answered anything yet here I just know for a fact because this is
a blank template.
This is what is personal from of course.
So if I did all this stuff here then that's 18 K there's 18 once.
That means there's 18 of these that have to be answered that are not optional.
So it'll go to 70 and if I put the word optional in somewhere here.
So I just sneak it in here see how that works.
Optional
see if it picks up that no.
Optional it has to be a word or at the beginning.
Let's see here option.
Oh that's why.
Oh I was smart.
See that there dude.
OK.
I threw the open square bracket because I got messed up before I threw the word optional somewhere else.
Me try to fool myself.
All right.
So if I had a little wash this little square bracket here to the beginning that should go to true.
So watch this.
I wonder if it's going to be caps sensitive or not.
There you go.
Yeah.
See you.
OK.
That's how you do it.
Now it says 17 buckets.
So all it does it counts up.
And then what I did here was these here are just formulas you know if if that what you saw over there
was zero that make it no otherwise.
Yes it is required.
And then we just did a count of the yeses here and them.
That's how we did the math to figure out what percent we have finished of this section or not.
And then for the flags all I did here was I basically said well if over here they select come back to
this question then put it in the number one over here.
So watch this
the number one will go there and when the number one is there then I put conditional formatting in.
That's just number one there otherwise is blank conditional formatting is here a conditional format
I don't jump around a bit but it's easy to explain a conditional formatting basically will it'll make
you ill make it a different color that box or put it in like a character or a cool thing like like a
flag.
So here are they.
That's right.
It was a new feature and they wanted to show off to it's on the Home tab.
It's actually true it's a marketing thing.
OK.
So basically what you do is you can insert a new rule.
I'm going to go to manage rules here and show you what the flag looks like.
So here is icon set.
OK.
And then what you do is you just grab that.
You the rule here but so if it's greater than zero which means it's one that make a flag.
If I want to I can change this to that and then it would show that instead and I used to use this a
lot there is this a lot when I was amental portfolio and I have my own phone whatever and I kind of
created my you know my my own portfolio manager system which is in another course my whatever.
OK good.
So I think I explained the red flag thing just counting the number instances of one.
And I explained the menu at the bottom there and if it's complicated what I said there and I know I
threw a lot at you there.
Then all you got to do is just build upon it slowly.
OK.
Apparently I've done native 6 percent so I was messed up.
Yeah.
Anyway so it just kind of go through here.
And I encourage you to just delete things and see what happens.
And the reason I had flag and then asked is because I said well if it's that one flag is not grammatically
correct say that one flag.
So anyway that's why I did there that's that.
OK.
I want to make this course perfect for you.
So do I care.
All right.
And that is that and then I added a bunch of filters here.
But let me let me go back here to the to the Home tab because I think you've talked about.
OK good.
We're done with all this except for one more thing I want to show you this and I got this.
I used my complete crypto course is well.
And so what's thrown here is text.
And so before I show you how to cheat how to change what's here.
I want to first of all you how to change what's in this box.
Because you'll see it just looks like text is confusing.
So what we do is we go to
data data validation and then we pick it from a box you see here.
So it's on another tab called Master-Maid which I had I just had it for you here.
It's basically saying get a list and you got a choose list.
That's the only way to choose the dropdown now to get a list from this part here and show it in the
drop down box.
That's it.
And I could change I have alerts as well and put messages and errors but I don't want do that.
It's become a tech support nightmare.
OK.
And that's it.
And so what happens is you click here and then drop down here and you could have done this here if you
are a developer you can add this just to search online how to add this tab.
You don't see it.
But I could have also done the dropdown list as well.
Combo Box but it's a pain in the neck because a lot of times you have to use to use macros in.
I don't want to you know I don't want anybody to have security issues or viruses.
So.
So what you do is you just choose them here and then based on what's in here then this changes.
And this here is a hyperlink.
So right there it's basically saying get a hyperlink of whatever is in this menu here and whatever's
in that menu actually comes from here.
So what we'll do is we'll go to the master menu here and then I will you can you can trace back where
the words coming from.
OK so Master menu here and you just use the command.
Open square box called square brackets.
So what we're doing is we're grabbing the data from here.
So it's basically looking up the view look up basically does this.
It looks a bunch of that and finds a match in a different column.
So we look up is basically coming over here and it's looking at all this stuff here at age 3 to our
two one for cash.
Massive amount at age 3.
And this is how we did the flags as well on the show later and all those custom links based on what
country you're from in hyperlinks.
So all I did was I got all this stuff here.
Kids look up and all that stuff it is saying go to the third column and find a match for B-6.
OK.
And so click here.
And then what I do is the first one always I make it just dummy data.
So I always say Click here for whatever.
And then what happens is click here will automatically throw in there just the default nothing.
Police like the resource and that looks like this over here.
Please like the resources.
And that if it's how to raise money for start startup it goes here.
That's it.
And that's just a youtube link.
It's just hyperlink.
And then you can click through here to understand where I got the information from.
I put all my links here just play around with this and it can play around with that's probably the best
way to explain.
All right.
So I'm going to stop and continue in the next lecture but this is a two part crescendo fishing up.
We've finished all of this here and then I'll talk about the stuff below here in the next lecture.
Thanks.