Please click on the button called outputs for Step 5.
I don't know if you have a product company or a service company.
So I gave you this option here.
So if you click this service only that title will change there.
And if you click this one here at the de-select that it will say product and if you click both then
I'm sorry if you unclick both Ill say product and service description there.
OK.
And so this is pretty self-explanatory.
Everything you wrote in the previous input tab will be pulled over here and you can always look at my
example here.
And then quality control if you wrote in the book quality control appear here.
Same thing with packaging and then the same thing with production in your current price strategy and
your future price strategy if applicable and then whether or not you want to bundle etc..
And so there's a lot of great information here on your pricing strategy when it comes to distribution
which means your go to market strategy.
We will discuss this in more detail when we get to Step 8.
There's just some people that when they look at the description of your product and service they might
ask questions about distribution early on but we'll go into more detail later on there.
And then here's a return policy.
If you have it's customer service is very important always because a company is only as good as its
customer services.
And that wraps it up for this part of the Course Step 5 is done.
If you have any question as always please let me know and I will see you in step 6.
Thanks.