Well please make sure you're on the aid tab.
Now we're going to talk about the balance sheet.
We're done with the income statement and you can go back to the first lecture in the section to learn
more about what a balance sheet is.
If you want.
OK.
And so it doesn't really make as much sense to forecast a balance sheet when you're first starting a
company but some investor might ask you for it but I wouldn't spend too much time on it.
And you'd have to it's so hard.
Like one of our short term investments like do we really have a lot of cash in T-Bills sitting on our
balance sheet or Capital.
Probably not.
But if you want you could answer them in here.
I'm not going to do it but you can do it if you want.
And then you've got accounts receivable and you can make this a formula actually if you wanted to so
accounts receivable means let's say that you sell something you sell when you're goggles and you have
not collected that money yet.
OK.
But it's so it's an account receivable it's an asset you're still owed it but you don't have that money
yet.
And if accounts receivable are too high it's a bit worrisome from a cash collection perspective and
so you would see that in here in some people what they do is they make accounts receivable a percent
of the costs of goods sold.
So let's say that 5 percent of people that buy your goggles or whatever product it was they'd bite on
credit.
And so you would basically if you wanted to you could go in here zero point nine five times that amount
above.
OK but it's a little bit more loose and leave it like that for now.
So to keep this simplistic.
Same thing with inventory.
You can calculate how much inventory you have and how much you haven't sold.
If you want to as well and that would feed into here and that's an asset.
But it's important to document this if you want to in every company's never leave it blank as is.
But basically what happens is if if you have too much in inventory then you could face a cash crunch.
And so I showed you what happened with the returns just for those four months just for you know for
fun whatever is little example.
But that's how you do it here.
And as always having is tracked year over year month or month and percentage of revenue every company
is different.
But I provide it for the tools for you in case you want to do it.
Then you have cap packs which is how much you spend on machinery if you want to.
I'm outsourcing everything with this fictional company and just like a company like Cisco Cisco a big
telecommunications company here in the Bay Area they don't really seeing themselves they outsource everything
to CMAC which stands for contract manufacturing services company.
Apple does that too with Flextronics and other companies.
And then you've got your other I've got the seasonality SPARC line appears as well.
Accounts Payable.
You can make this a percent of revenue if you wants or stuff that you owe.
And just think of yourself like you're a bank always you always want to pay your bills as late as you
can without incurring fees.
And if you do that in the long run you'll save a lot of money.
A lot of my retail companies do this because retail margins are really thin.
A lot of times retail companies only make you know one or two pennies for every dollar and stuff they
sell.
And so if they pay everything back as late as possible then they pay less fees and they can remain relevant
longer term.
So everybody thinks of themselves as a bank in business.
And I challenge you to think that way as well because people are going to try and pay you back in lead
as they can without incurring a penalty fee.
And sometimes what happens is you encourage people to pay back by using 0 30 and in certain terms a
little outside the scope of this course.
But I want to throw that on your radar screen as well.
And here is I don't use any debt.
But if you did get a loan that's less than a year that would be short term debt you put it in here.
I want you to raise equity just because you can use the networking book on my web site to get these
meeting set up with high net worth investors who will invest in your company.
And don't don't speak with VC firms right away.
I would do high net worth initially because the sales cycle is shorter and there's only one sausage
maker which is the rich dude.
And again go to Harroun venturous dot com.
And then just download my book there you'll see it's free.
It'll help you lots.
Couple hundred pages.
Two hundred and ten pages just think and a couple of hours of links to youtube videos and I promise
you will help you raise money from equity investors from people from banks.
But if you want to raise money from banks you can always go to the savings type and in the Settings
tab.
It doesn't matter what country you're in.
Go to settings just for fun I'll throw it to another country random one here and I'm going to show you.
You can access where that is.
Or Serbia is.
I went there for a wedding actually meant my best friend Corey Paula Netrunner got married there.
Great guy.
But if you're in Serbia for examples around the country I picked your kid to go to your ministry of
finance website.
Here's some taxes are do in Serbia and then you're here the largest banks in Serbia.
Second I did the top five in every country Sofia.
If you went and click here you can go to our RIF and I saw him on how to pronounce everything.
But you clicked that Windass computer slow slow sorry.
But but it should open up a browser.
Here it is here.
So it goes directly to that I guess RSS Serbia so it's right there.
Cute puppy.
And if you want credit ratings information whenever you do that and don't get loans if you can.
And if you do just make sure you pay back your debt quickly so it doesn't mess up your credit rating.
Here's more details on the credit rating industry in in Serbia for example.
And so what I'll do I'll just leave it at Serbia and then it's it's in Gibraltar pensar I guess it must
change as well.
This matter is still pretending it's in dollars doesn't matter.
So if you were to click here you'll see that whatever currency you selected is automatically placed
right here.
See here.
OK great.
So let's go back now.
We're going to click here.
I don't want to click on that but it will take me to the top and I'll be put in place.
All right.
So we got short term that were done in short term that is basically debt you owed in less than a year.
So on a balance sheet you've got current assets and current liabilities current assets are stuff you
can convert to cash in less than a year by cash itself or bonds and long term assets are things that
you can convert to cash more in the year like say you own a factory.
And factories usually take a lot of time to sell.
Same thing with with about you it comes to short current liabilities and long term goals current liabilities
are things that you have to pay back in less than a year like credit card debt or accounts payable and
then long term liabilities are stuff like long term limits.
And when I click on the Boushey button in Minot which I will I'll show you that more detail in here
you know there's long term debt.
If you have long term debt in here every company is completely different though.
OK.
And then common shares if events you want to go public.
I left this year as well for the share count which is a little bit outside the scope of what we're talking
about here because we're talking with start us by left to their you.
And if you put in and you might want to read this too if you will.
This is completely optional.
But if you put in money to your company or somebody else does.
And you know were to account for it.
I call that a pick additional paid in capital and you just put it here and it will filter through to
complete your policy for you and help you out with the actual Same as well.
So we're done with the balance sheet.
You can go look at the spark lines if you want.
So we already talk about revenue feeds in the income statement where we type things income statement
next thing is Balochi wish we did.
And this is going to feed over here and I put in a lot of cells as well.
Me just get a little more realistic here so about.
They're all green because they link somewhere else.
Okay and then accounts receivable I mean as a percent of revenue here and this just filters off of the
cancer SuBo which is this line divided by the revenue back on the competing.
And so this year is cash and cash equivalents and this comes from the cash flow statement which I'll
talk about in person again.
We didn't enter anything for short term investments or accounts receivable and we didn't enter a thing
here for cap ex although we do have depreciation because if you buy equipment you can appreciate like
a dichotomy for that there's a total assets.
Again people are not going to look at this that closely when you first started the company because they're
not going to be much data in here.
They're going to focus a little bit more so on the income statement which is why if you you know in
the executive summary I spend more time on income statement related stuff and on that one pager which
is completely optional by clicking the home button I show mainly income saving stuff there.
And the same thing if you give a presentation if you're a click on the presentation tab.
Let me actually go there.
We'll come back about the second one show.
So I click here on presentation slides.
It's can here.
This is going to pull for it automatically for you when you complete all the information.
Sort of like zoom out a bit here so I can.
So it limited financial stuff here just a one pager.
I'll show you here.
It's mostly incom same stuff got there in the second so.
Yeah.
So I just made an income statement stuff and you'll recognize this data.
It just pulls over from stuff we completed.
I've got revenue net income and then I put gross margins up her part in it and then here I put her to
rebut.
Spell financials right.
We're happy to provide you with detail financials upon request.
And then you know these are all the numbers that we talk about reading we haven't forecasted here.
That's why I bank this is the first year like near fifth year 10th year.
And usually it's just when you present to investors or you know early on people who might be in your
business model the 10 slide deck as you see here and then you just list a couple of income statement
stuff usually never Balanchine's stuff.
This is a little bit too early for that but I want to include there nevertheless.
OK let's go back to the balance sheet.
You get.
So we're still here.
And again the reason I clicked down here is that going up to the menu is because if I click here it
goes right to the top.
All right.
So green means from another tab and then you've got other white cells or grey cells I should say that
are not blue shaded not blue font wear shoes calculations.
OK.
And that pulls everything directly over.
And that is that.
And so we are now done with a balance sheet.
What I'll do is I'll talk about the cash flow statement now as well.
So the cash flow statement pulls everything automatically from the income statement and the balance
sheet.
Okay.
And the great thing is just it's a little bigger she read it is if you have a capital statement if you
ever think of the same and a balance sheet then the capital gains automatically always created for you.
Most people realize that but it's just math.
And if I went back to the balance sheet here you'll see that I've got I've got these little comments
here and if you want you can mouse over it just read what those comments are.
But let's go back now to the outputs for the cash flow statement and the Cashell Satan will just tell
you that change in cash every single quarter in this example here in your pocket.
OK.
And so I'm going to be very negative at first because we're losing a lot of money and you'll see here
the way the capital saving works is as follows.
You're reconciling the income saves the income statement a lie.
And so the income.
And you can also or you want to see all this stuff here.
I give you lots of comments on what all of these are and why they're here.
And so with the cash flow statement does is it basically says Hey Mr. or Mrs..
Income Statement I'm going to take the bottom line of your of the income state which is net income and
I'm going to make you tell the truth by saying what the real change is in cash because net income does
not mean that change in cash in your pocket.
OK it's an accounting thing.
And so we're going to add back stuff that's not real.
So for example depreciation is a non tax or non-cash expense.
How we say on tax non-cash expense so we can add that back and then this is always the change you can.
You can.
You don't have any information since the first quarter but this year is just the change.
See this period.
Missed the previous period.
So the Cashell say it does looks at the change and so let's say that if accounts receivable went up
a lot and you sold the products but they still on page.
That's unfair you can't account for it that way.
You have to back it out and that's what the cash flow statement does.
It says accounts he will for one period minus the previous one.
So if it goes up it's about the if inventory goes up a lot as well.
That's a bad thing from a cash perspective especially if you don't sell it.
But if and if accounts payable goes up a lot.
That's a that's actually it's a good thing as long as you're not paying it back too late because it's
more cash in your pocket temporarily.
Same thing here with Cap backs.
If you if you're buying more machines and stuff that will hurt your investing perspective.
So this is from we're correcting the income saving here in the operating side.
And here we're looking at stuff we invest in like cap x can make the change here and then financing.
If we got a loan or an increase in common shares like somebody invest in our company equity wise you'd
make this an increase in cash because somebody gave you money so necessarily great thing.
It's just a cash changer at the bottom.
What happens is it will pull it directly over and reconcile whatever and tell you how much changes in
cash.
So first couple of years we're bleeding cash obviously.
And then here cash increases and then we're off to the races here.
That's when the investment bank bankers will be pounding on your door saying please go public.
OK.
So we are now done with that and the next step in the next session to talk about the final outputs for
all financials.
Thanks.