Imagine that you have a Git repository on your computer
somewhere. It's this orange repository here, and you also want
the same repository somewhere else, probably on a different
machine. Here, I made it purple.
Now, the machine that hosts the purple repository must be able to
connect to the machine that hosts the orange repository, so you
might have some technical setup to do here.
You have to run a Git daemon process on the orange repo so that the
purple repo can connect to it, and so on and so forth.
But in this training, we don't care about these technical details.
So, let's make it easier.
I just moved the whole cookbook project to GitHub
and removed it from my computer.
So now the orange repo is in the cloud,
right? A service hosted on the GitHub servers, and the
purple repo will be on my own computer.
So I want to get a copy of the project on this computer inside this empty
directory. You probably know which command to use here.
It's the git clone command.
It takes the address of a Git repository,
which I can copy‑paste from GitHub. There, and now I have the project.
All the files are here, but I didn't just get the files,
I got the entire .git directory as well and all the files it
contains. Here is what git clone did. It created an empty
directory for the cookbook, and it copied the .git directory from
the GitHub project to this directory.
I'm simplifying here.
It didn't literally copy each and every file. For example,
unless you're using a very old version of Git, git clone
only copies one branch, the main branch.
If I want to work with the other branches on the remote repo
I need to give specific commands to do so, but that's a
detail, an optimization if you wish.
The important part is Git did copy over the objects in the object database.
They are in here. After copying this stuff, Git checked out the main
branch to rebuild these files in the working area.
Remember, the working area in Git is not very important.
You can always rebuild it on the fly from the content of the .git directory.
And since the .git directory contains the entire repository, now we have a copy
of the project and its history on this computer.
This is an important point, so it's worth repeating it.
Now that we have two clones of the repo,
one on GitHub and one on this computer, both clones are equally good.
Git is not like Subversion or other traditional revision control
systems that need a centralized server and everyone else is just
talking to that one server. Instead,
both computers now contain the whole project and its
history. We could have as many of these clones as we want
synchronizing with each other.
Of course, you can still decide that one clone is the most important one.
For example,
if you have multiple developers working on the same software project,
then you will probably decide that the repo on GitHub is the
reference repo, the one that you build the releases from, and
everybody must synchronize with that one.
That's why I drew the GitHub repo on top. You can still synchronize the
developers' repos directly with each other, but even then you probably
want to appoint a well‑known reference copy that is visible to everybody,
and everybody synchronizes with it.
However, in Git that's not really a technical issue, it's more of a social issue. It's a convention. From a technical standpoint, all of these clones are peers.