Now, what happens when there are other repos pushing towards you?
So the state of origin might change at any time.
Now, we cannot just write changes to the remote,
we also must read changes from the remote.
Things get a bit more complicated here,
so I will use a diagram here instead of a demo.
Imagine that we have a remote repo that looks like this, it's a single commit.
I will use different colors for the commits, and I will not draw
trees and blobs. I will skip them because they would make this
diagram too busy. When we clone this repo,
we get the same objects in our local repo, and here are the branches. I'm
assuming that the remote has the default name origin, so so the remote
main branch is called origin/main. Now, let's say that we add one commit,
and we push. If the remote's main branch hasn't changed in the meantime,
then things are easy for Git. It copies our new commit and the associated
object to the remote and then updates the remote's main branch to point to
the new commit, and it also reflects the change locally by updating the
remote branch origin/main, and everything is aligned again.
This is what happened when we pushed our changes a few minutes ago.
Now, let's do it again.
This is the initial situation again.
We add a commit, and we prepare to push, but this time imagine
that something has changed on the remote as well.
Someone pushed another commit to the remote.
This green commit.
Now we can't just push, we have a conflict here.
We have two different histories that need to be reconciled.
In this case, we have two options, basically.
One option, which I would not recommend, except in very special cases,
is to force a push.
We can do that with git push ‑f, that stands for force.
That's like saying, I don't care what changes are on the remote,
forget about them and just match my local history.
That's the real one.
So when we force a push, this happens, and we're probably losing that on origin.
Here, we are losing the green commit. No branch is pointing out that commit
anymore, so it will be garbage collected eventually.
We're also creating a very confusing situation for all other people
synchronizing to the same remote because now their local history will
be conflicting with the history and origin.
This is our teammate, Annie, working on the same cookbook
repository, and she still has the old green commit in her
repository. But after our force‑push, if Annie tries to interact
with the remote, she'll have a conflict.
Her history doesn't match the history of the remote, even though she
didn't cause the conflict in the first place, and so she'll probably be
left wondering what happened and how to solve it.
So forcing a push is not a good idea in general.
It doesn't really solve conflicts.
It just puts the burden on other users to solve the conflict,
so it's not going to win us many friends in the team. But we
have a second better option.
Let's say that we didn't do that force‑push.
Let's go back to the situation we had in the beginning. We added
the light blue commit, and we had a conflict because somebody else
added the green commit on the remote.
What we want to do in general is we want to fix the conflict on
our own machine before we push. To do that,
we need first to fetch the data from the remote.
There is a command to do that called git fetch.
We get the new objects from the remote, and we also update the current
position of the remote branches, origin/main in this case. Now that we
have the new commit and the related objects,
we can merge our local changes with the remote changes.
So we did the fetch.
Now we do a merge. Of course, during the merge,we might have to
fix merging conflicts and like, but the important point here is
that we're not rewriting history. Merges never do that, they
just add the new objects.
So once we do the merge,
our history is the same history as the remote, plus our local stuff, the
light blue commit in this case, and we can push that new stuff to the
remote without rewriting the remote's history.
This is what you do most of the time. You fetch the changes from the
remote, you merge them into your own repo, and then you push the result.
This sequence of a git fetch followed by a git merge is so common that
there is one single command that does both. It's called, you guessed it, git pull, a fetch followed by merge.