Okay, now give me just a few minutes for a short aside.
From the first module of this training,
you might remember diagrams such as this one.
It's about trees and blobs.
To make things easier,
I avoided talking about trees and blobs in the second module.
I mostly talk about commits.
I'll just mention trees and blobs again quickly to show you in more
detail how Git manages your working directory.
You know that the objects in the database are commits,
trees, and blobs, and also notated tags,
although there are none of them in this example.
You also know that all these objects are arranged in a graph.
They reference each other.
There are references from a commit to its parents,
references from a commit to its tree,
and references from trees to blobs and other trees.
These references all look alike, but they're used in two different ways.
References between commits are used to track history.
All the other references are used to track content.
We've also seen that Git is good that we're using content,
so you can have objects that are reachable from more
than one commit like these ones here.
The point I want to make is that when you move to another commit,
for example, you switch to another branch,
Git doesn't care about history.
It doesn't look at the ways that commits connect to each other.
It just cares about trees and blobs.
So if you look at the world from this commit here,
then Git forgets about the link to the parent of the commit,
and it looks at the tree in the commit and all the
objects that can be reached from there.
That is the entire state of the project at the time of the commit,
a complete snapshot of every file, every folder.
Git uses this information to replace the content of your working directory.
That's how you travel back and forth in time with Git.
It is the whole point of versioning.
And if you look at this commit here, same thing,
it counts with an entire representation of the entire project.
You might think that merge commits must be more complicated than that,
but actually they're not.
Okay, they have multiple parents, that's the definition of a merge,
but Git doesn't care about that when you move to a commit.
It just goes into the commit, and our tree is the tree in the commit, as
usual. A merge commit will, in general, have its own trees and blobs because
the objects in the merge might not be present in any of the parents. Think
of a file that has lines from both parents, for example. On the other hand,
from the merge commit's tree,
you can probably reach objects that are also reachable from other
commits. And once again, Git doesn't care about which blob or
tree was introduced by which commit.
When it stores the commit,
it just reuses objects that are already there, and it creates the objects that
are not already there. A way it checks out the commit, it just looks at the tree
and rebuilds the state of the project from there.
I told you this story because I want to make a couple of points.
First point, don't get confused with trees and blobs. Retrieving a
past state in GIt is a pretty straightforward thing.
It's just a stupid content tracker.
It goes into a commit and retrieves the trees and blobs from there.
Nothing more complicated than that.
When you use Git, focus on the history,
how commits connect to each other, and trust Git to do
the right thing with trees and blobs.
The second point I want to make is that Git doesn't
really care much about your working area.
Remember, when you move to another commit, Git adjusts or replaces the
working area with the stuff from the object database.
Git mostly cares about the objects in the database, not your working directory.
The objects in the database are immutable and persistent while the
files in your working directory are as transient as they get. They can
change as quickly as you can do a Git switch or checkout. Git is not
reckless with your working area.
It will give you a warning before overriding your files.
For example,
if you try to switch to another branch, but you have uncommitted changes,
Git will tell you that.
But other than that, as far as Git is concerned,
your working area is the least important part of your project.
All the good stuff is indeed not Git directory.
And now that I made this aside,
you can forget about trees and blobs for the rest of this training. From now on, we will mostly be concerned with commits and history.