Now we have a better picture of the nature of Git, let's recap.
A Git repository is a bunch of objects linked to each other in a graph.
They can be commits, blobs, trees,
or annotated tags that we'll talk about a bit more later.
Then there are branches that are references to a commit.
And finally, there is HEAD.
That's also a reference, but there is only one of it,
and it marks our current position in the graph.
It's usually pointing to a branch,
but it could also be detached and pointing directly to a commit.
Then there are a few rules.
First, the current branch tracks new commits.
So if you create a new commit by saying git commit or git merge,
for example, then the current branch moves to the new commit.
If you are in detached HEAD state, then HEAD itself moves to the new commit.
Second rule, your working directory is updated automatically.
When you move to another commit, typically with git switch or git checkout,
Git replaces the content of your working directory with the
content that can be reached from that commit.
Three, any commit, blob, or tree that cannot be reached from either branch,
HEAD, or a tag is considered dead and can be garbage collected.
And essentially, this is the whole thing.
Branches, merges, moving back and forth in time,
it all boils down to these simple rules.
Okay, I know what you're thinking now.
What about rebases?
Yeah, rebases. We'll talk about them in the next module.