So let's recap. In the Git object database, you have blobs, arbitrary
content, trees, the equivalent of directories, and commits.
There is also a fourth kind of object in the database.
It's something called annotated tags.
Maybe you know what a tag is. It's like a label that you put on a commit.
For example, you might tag a commit to mark a release.
That's a typical reason to use a tag.
And there is also a special kind of tag called an annotated tag that
carries additional data like a message, and the name of the person who
created the tag, and the date of the tag.
Now we won't go into details about tags for now.
We'll do it later in this training because by then it will be easier to
understand how tags work. For now, just know that an annotated tag like this one
is a small object in the database that contains the data, the message, author,
and so on, and it points to a commit. So, it's another type of database object,
very similar to a commit in a way.
Again, the details will come later,
but I wanted to at least mention annotated tags for completeness
because there is nothing else in the database,
just these four types of objects.
So, if you know about blobs, trees, commits, and annotated tags, then congratulations! Now you know the entire Git object model.