[Autogenerated] in this module.
We're going to start looking at using Cloudfront and Route 33 advanced concepts.
Let's discuss some of learning objectives that we want to cover in this module.
Now,
the first main one is we wanna learn how we can place cloudfront in
front of distributions within our AWS account.
We're gonna look at generating signed You are l's for access.
And then we're going to discuss de dos attack
mitigation strategies with cloudfront.
The next major focus point is understanding how we can use advance
Route 53 configurations within our architectures.
This will touch on routing policies.
It's gonna touch on health checks,
and then it's also gonna look at creating some records.
So just an overview on how we could create different
records in our account now well, in here and on the next clip will begin diving into cloudfront