[Autogenerated] cool.
Okay, we just created our first cloud friend distribution.
Now, just a caveat that took probably about, I would say, 15 to 20 minutes.
So be aware that any changes to your distribution
could take that long or longer, depending on what's going on.
Any time you make a change to your distribution,
it essentially redeploys that distribution toe all the
edge locations that you selected.
So now what I can do is I can go to this cloudfront domain.
And if I go to index dot html,
we'll get our bucket page and you can see it's from s three.
So this is serving that static site in our bucket,
and we're actually pointing at the cloudfront your L Now
you'll recall we said we want to restrict access to our
bucket objects from cloudfront.
But if I go ahead and go to s three and get that bucket in point again,
you'll notice that Hey, we can still access the objects.
What's going on here?
Well, we still have to edit our bucket policy.
If we had one in place,
you'll see that cloudfront added this second statement here,
and it allows our origin access identity to get objects within our bucket,
but the 1st 1 allows everyone.
So what I want to do is I want to kill this.
We'll save our bucket policy.
It's Mark does not public now.
If I go back to my tab and I refresh there you go,
we get a forbidden, so that's perfect.
But if I go to my cloudfront,
I can still access these files because now we're restricting
access to our cloudfront distribution.
Now.
One last thing before we wrap up.
We want to give this a domain name.
If you remember, we gave it an alternate name of Andrew ss dot me.
So to do that, we'll go to Route 53.
I'll load my hosted zone for my Andrew ss dot me,
and what I'll do is I'll create a record set.
I'll leave it at the domain or apex of the domain.
It'll be in a record.
It's an alias, and I wanna point it at our cloudfront distribution.
We'll leave the routing policy and target health
evaluation at the default I'll click on create,
and what we'll do here is I'll give it a few minutes for
this to propagate around the globe.
And what I'll do is I'll go to Andrew Estes that me once it's
loaded to make sure that we can get there.
All right, there we go.
So now, after a few minutes are d.
N s record has propagated,
and I'm now accessing our static site from s3 via
cloudfront on a secure listener.
Now that's gonna do it for this first part covering
cloudfront distributions in the next one.
What will do here is will set up an origin that is actually pointing to an
application load balancer delivering the same content. So let's end here and then in the next one will continue on where we left off.