[Autogenerated] Okay, let's pick back up where we left off.
We just finished up creating an s three bucket as our origin for a
static site that gets delivered by cloudfront.
And we also looked at restricting access to S three via cloudfront.
Now, in this demo,
what I did in between clips as I went into our distribution
settings because it takes so long to push out updates.
And I changed our origin on the back end and you'll see now the origin here
is pointing at an application load balancer in us east to and it can show
you that here we have one instance running.
And I'm just listening on the default http in https ports and
what I'm doing is I'm setting that as my origin,
as opposed to my bucket.
So now we're using a load balancer as the back in,
and then we can specify some settings.
We can have our minimum SSL protocol, which we looked at,
and we can also specify a protocol policy.
So since this is different, we can force Http,
we can force https or we can match the viewer.
And what this is doing is saying Hey,
how do we want cloudfront to connect to our back end origin.
So the connection to cloudfront from a client might be secure.
But maybe we just want a route Basic, non secure http.
Traffic to our origin and then pull it out that way.
So I'm gonna match the viewer.
So whatever I do, it should match.
I'll leave the time outs the same you can see we specify our ports
and then we have a custom header section again.
I'll go and click on Yes, at it.
I'll go back to general, go to distributions.
And now it's editing again.
Now, this one should be quick cause I didn't make any changes.
But if I go back in here,
one thing that I did have to do to speed this up since stuff was getting cashed,
which is how cloudfront should be working.
I had to go into in validations here.
And you can see I created in a validation for certain objects.
So if I go to details, you can see that.
Hey, I wanted to invalidate all index dot html and all C.
S s files as well.
Now what this did is starting at that time when I created this invalidation.
It goes through and removes the objects from the edge.
Location caches.
There are less expensive ways Like A W s mentions here in the description.
But this is a quick way to go ahead and force an
update of those cache files now,
because I did this whenever I hit my edge location
again similar to this diagram here.
What happens is our distribution has to go back and fetch our
source data and files from our origin and then cash them again
at the edge location for our users.
So it runs an origin fetch and then cashes that.
So I'll go ahead.
I'm gonna go to distributions here.
And if I go to that cloudfront domain name,
you can see that we're pulling now from E C to an A L B.
So this is no longer pulling from our s three bucket like we had before.
And to prove it,
let me go ahead and navigate to R s three file that we had
and you'll see here that obviously the C s s doesn't work
because I'm looking at my html file,
but we get the From s three header that I put into the HTML for this demo,
and I changed this header on R E.
C two instance so that it shows from E.
C two in a lb.
So that's how we can show that we're passing different origin traffic.
Now let's go ahead.
And in this clip here and in the next short clip will just have
a quick overview of some tidbit information that I wanted to cover that gets covered on the exam.