[Autogenerated] cool.
Welcome back.
Let's go ahead and dive into Route 53.
Now I'm at the dashboard in Route 53 and you'll see we
have several different options now.
The 1st 1 I want to talk about is registering a domain,
so Route 53 can actually register our new domains forests.
So if I just make up a new domain here and I check the domain availability,
it checks worldwide if that's able to be purchased.
And it is.
So if I wanted to, I could add this to the cart.
I would go through and edit my contact information for this domain,
and then I would say, Hey,
I want to automatically renew or I don't want to automatically renew.
I agreed to the terms, and I want to complete my order,
and this sub total would just get billed to my Amazon Web service bill.
So I'll cancel out, and this brings me to my next point.
We have are registered domains that we have via Route 53 so you
can see these are all my domains that I own.
We have our expiration dates if they're set to auto
renew as well as a transfer lock.
So what's cool about Rue 53 is if you purchase a domain in a another D.
N s registrar, maybe like go, Daddy,
you can transfer your domain to route 53 from that original register.
So what you do is you basically point your domain toe 0.2 Amazons name servers.
So then you can host that here and edit the records.
Now with that, let's go ahead.
I want to jump in tow, hosted zones.
So ah, hosted zone is the logical grouping of our records for a specific domain.
Now there's public zones which are for Internet traffic,
their public and there's private zones in a private zone is for vpc use on Lee.
So this will be used for an internal application that you don't want to
host publicly or have someone result from the outside.
So let me go to my Andrew estes dot me and you'll see we
have our name servers and then I have ah,
authoritative server value as well.
So for this demo, I want to create a new record set.
But for this one, you probably know how to create a record already.
I want to discuss the routing policies in the fail overs.
So I'll create in a record I'll do W W w I'll make it an alias and I
want my primary to be our load balancer that we had.
So this is pointing at that static site on R L B.
And you see we have routing policy.
Now the default is simple and simple is good.
But the problem in this aspect is if I create this record,
I can't go back and create a secondary record with same thing.
So I go here and I just 0.2 s three just for a demo sake will get an error.
And there you go.
So I'll click on close.
Let me go ahead and go here.
I want to edit this and what I want to do is I want to
select out of this list I want to select.
Fail over now Wait.
It is going to wait.
Requests and load balance them in a way Leighton see is based on the
best Leighton see available to the client request.
So whichever path provides the lowest Leighton see, that's what they get.
And then Geo location is based on what it sounds like geo location.
So where are they located?
So whichever path is closest to the client that gets selected.
And it's important to know in the exam that just because
someone's Geo location is closer to a point does not mean that
the Leighton see will necessarily be lower.
Usually it is, but not always.
So for this I'll choose fail over.
And that's because I wanna have a primary and secondary record.
So we set our record type.
This is going to be our primary, so I'll leave primary in here.
We give it an I D, which is just a human name for us to quickly identify it.
And then we evaluate target health.
So I want to say yes because I want to make sure that our
health on the back end is good to go.
And if we had a health check, I can associate it with it right here.
We don't have any, so I can't select one.
But I want to go ahead and let's save this.
And there we go.
So we added that to our load balancer here and then what I
want to do is go back in W W W It's an alias,
and I want to point to our cloudfront distribution as a backup.
So I'll go to fail over.
This is our secondary.
We're not going to evaluate health target because we can't
do it being an alias of a CLOUDFRONT.
So this is why you wouldn't want to make it your primary record on a
health check because you cannot evaluate the health.
So when I click on create here,
you can see we have to a records for the W W W sub domain,
and they're pointing at our alias records.
Now, whenever I go to this domain,
you'll see that it pulls it from the E C two and load balancer,
so that's perfect.
But let's make sure that this actually works.
So if I go through here and you remember,
we set our load balancer as our primary target,
What I want to do is I want to go and I want to kill that instance.
Let me go ahead and go too easy, too.
I'm gonna find my running instance for our Web
server and I want to shut this off.
Let me go ahead and stop it.
And what this is going to do is cause route 53 to evaluate our target health.
It's going to see hey, this targets not resolving.
So let's go and swap over to secondary.
And then that should push us to our cloudfront,
which is pulling from our S three bucket as a backup.
Now, this is a pretty common scenario once again on the exam.
So be sure to understand how you can implement these fail over
technologies via Route 53 cloudfront if needed.
So what I'll do is I'll go ahead and give this some time to start failing.
And then once it starts showing that it's swapping over all resume and
you can see we have a 503 So here in a little bit,
I should start getting redirected to our cloudfront.
Okay, so I went ahead and gave it some time.
And now when I go to my Andrew s to stop me page with
that w w w prefix for the sub domain,
we get our cloudfront distribution because our load balancer is now failing.
So rue 53 automatically failed over to our cloudfront
distribution so our users can have seamless interaction or
near seamless interaction for recovery.
Now, before we wrap up,
I want to go back in here and I want to show you some health checks.
So when you create a health check, you give it a name.
You can choose what you want to monitor so you can do other health checks.
You can do a cloud watch alarm, or you can do an end point.
You can do I ___ or domain name.
You can specify your protocol, so let's just go ahead and give this.
Andrew estes dot me will do Port 443 and we'll switch
this to https will do a path of index that HTML We can
view our advanced configuration.
So a standard is gonna check every 30 seconds, and fast is every 10.
Now It's important to know here, depending on what you choose,
your back and compute can be getting hit very hard with these health checks.
A standard one, as you can see,
is sending an in point a health check every two or three seconds.
But a fast selection is sending multiple per second,
so that can add up quickly on networking bandwith,
depending on your back in architectures we specify the
failure threshold that we want across.
We can look for strings if we wanted to.
So if we had in health check in point that returns a string
in the request body or response body, I should say,
Then you can look for that here.
Now I'll do know we can show our Leighton see graphs.
So if we wanted to, we can see what requests are taking longer.
We can enable S and I which we do want because we
have that on our load balancer.
You can invert it.
So if you want to go ahead and say hey,
when this is unhealthy it should actually be considered healthy and vice versa.
You can disable it by default and you can customize your health check regions.
So the recommended is most of the region's offered But you
can customize and select what you want.
So depending on where your user base is,
you can select some of these and remove others.
I'll click on next.
We can create an alarm if we wanted to To push to a topic or create a new one.
I'll click No click on create And there we go.
We now have our health check.
So this is going to start checking.
Our end point www dot Andrew s is dot me, which is what we see right here.
And what it's gonna do is it's gonna send http calls to
our domain name that we specified,
and you can see the health checks that is here.
And as I give it more time, there's more checks.
You can see the region, the I ___ when it was last checked,
and then our status code.
So it's saying, Hey, status co 200 then that means that's okay.
So after a while,
this should swap two healthy once we get enough thresholds cross.
And that will be about a minute and 1/2 of waiting so we can get this.
So I'll go ahead and wait for this to go well,
fast forward and then we'll check it when it says healthy.
Okay, there we go.
So that's awesome.
So we now have a healthy because it's been reported healthy by all of these
instances in our threshold and specified amount of time.
So now what we can do with this health check if we wanted to weaken,
go into our records here.
I can select my A L B primary record and we can
associate this with a health check.
So we can say, Hey,
we wanna look for this particular health check and that's how
we're going to evaluate our target health as well.
So this can speed up the process, depending on your configuration.
Now, I'm not going to select this just because that wouldn't make sense.
I'm pointing to my static site for a L B.
And that kind of defeats the purpose.
We would just point to a dead end.
So I want to click on No,
but that's how you can create a health check and associate it with a record.
So we'll go ahead,
will wrap up this Route 53 overview and in the next clip will
start looking at traffic flow and our resolve, our options that we have