[Autogenerated] Hello.
My name is Andrew Estes and welcome to my course designing,
scalable in fault tolerant systems within a W s.
I am an enterprise cloud architect at CSG International as well as founder of
quick to cloud reliability and performance efficiency or two of the five
pillars that make up the well-architected framework.
This course is going to cover a range of topics that help
you meet the guidelines for both pillars.
In this course,
we're going to look at implementing resilient systems
by using auto scaling technologies,
multi ese implementations and A W s content delivery network service is
some of the major topics that we're going to cover include designing
stateless architectures within A W s understanding auto Skilling groups
and multi ese implementations with load balancers using cloudfront to
serve as a CD en for applications.
And then we'll leverage Route 53 for advanced
routing policies and health checks.
By the end of this course,
you're going to know how to design and implement a resilient
architecture for any system within AWS.
Now, before beginning, you should be familiar with the solutions architect,
associate exam materials,
and it will be helpful to understand what is tested on for the
solutions Architect Professional exam as well.
You need to know the core A W s service is for architecture
design and you should have a general understanding of
networking designs and protocols.
From here,
they're going to feel comfortable diving into other solutions architect,
professional related prep materials.
And this includes courses on gaining operational excellence,
managing A W S operations and any of the other relevant solutions.
Architect Professional Learning path courses provided by plural site.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn how to implement
a resilient architecture with the designing, scalable in fault tolerant systems within a W s course here in plural site.