[Autogenerated] welcome to the designing,
scalable and fault tolerant systems within a W S course.
My name is Andrew Estes and I'm an enterprise cloud architect for CSG
International and founder of Quick to Cloud This first module.
We're going to discuss designing stateless architectures four resilience
within our AWS accounts before we dive into this module.
Let's just do a quick course overview so we can learn what to
expect as we progress through this course.
Firstly, we want to learn about designing resilient,
stateless architectures within a W s,
which is what we're going to do in this module here.
Next,
we wanna learn how we can implement auto scaling solutions
within our accounts in an optimal fashion.
And then finally,
we're going to use cloudfront in Route 53 for advanced scenarios.
So will demo.
How we could Kim figure a CD en as well as advanced Route
53 routing policies based on our needs.
Now that we have a good overview of the course itself,
let's dive into our first module in this module.
We're going to design stateless architectures within a W s.
And we're going to identify optimal times when we should
use spot reserved or on demand instances.
So with that, let's wrap up this intro and overview clip,
and we'll pick up in the next one where we're going to dive into stateless versus state ful architectures.