[Autogenerated] Okay, so last video in this course.
And this is just a simple review on what we learned early on in the course,
we discuss the different use cases for the different E.
C to life cycle types that are offered to us.
So we looked at spot instances and how those could be
interrupted at any point in time.
We looked at reserved instances for long running instances in place,
such as domain controllers or even data bases on Easy to.
And then we talked about on demand, which is the normal,
easy to instance type that gets spun up in the console.
We then looked at designing resilient, stateless architectures within a W.
S.
And to demo this we used a W s Lambda with an a p I
gateway front end in a dynamodb back end.
So we looked at how a p a gateway in Lambda were stateless.
They simply passed the workloads through and performed actions.
And then any state full data was stored on dynamodb building.
Off of that,
we looked at implementing resilient auto scaling groups
for our workloads and to do this,
we used multi availabilities own load balancers secured
with T L s certificates provided by a CM.
So we were able to spin up an auto scaling group across multiple A Z's.
So if a particular ese failed,
we would still be able to pick up the load in the other ese.
Now, we also looked at using cloudfront for cashing and security purposes,
and we discuss the different use cases and
configuration options that were available.
And then we just finished up,
creating Route 53 routing policies and health checks with fail overs.
So we looked at how weaken set up global D.
N s resolution with advanced health checking and fail overs
as well as advance policies based upon Leighton see and even
geographically based request.
Now, with that,
I'd like to thank you once again for taking the time to watch this portal
site course on designing scalable systems within AWS.
Now,
some suggested next steps would be to continue on the
solutions architect professional Learning path.
There are several courses in there, and then once you're done with that,
look for some deep dives into different topics like cloudfront and Route 53.
So you can get a better understanding those architecture considerations
based around those technologies are heavily tested on. So with that, we'll go ahead and wrap up, and once again, thank you.