[Autogenerated] All right, let's dive in tow.
Auto Skilling groups Now this slide is going to pertain to the priest
scaling that happens in an auto Skilling group.
You can see we have a simple two tiered architecture er
spanned across to availability zones.
And in the middle here we have on Auto Skilling Group.
Now what this auto scaling group allows us to do is automate Skilling out and
back in on demand when certain metric thresholds are crossed.
So in this instance,
we have a group of users making a request to our load balancer.
That's fording those requests to our auto scaling group Instances.
But let's say we start getting more traffic so that user base
doubles now and so does our internal traffic.
Going to our instances while using auto Skilling groups
within a W S allows us to automatically scale are groups of
instances specific to this workload.
And the beauty of this is that we can scale both out like I mentioned
and back in once thresholds are back to normal.
So it really builds on the paper use model that a W s loves the push you
only pay for compute that you use And with that auto,
Skilling itself, as a service is free to use.
You only pay for the compute that you're scaling out and in.
So now that we have a general understanding of how it works,
let's dive in a little bit deeper.
Now, in the upcoming demos, we're going to walk through a few different tasks.
We're going to explore launch configurations and launch templates in the
differences between them and then using our launch template,
we're going to demo automating via user data.
So will automate some actions via Cem user data to show
how easy it is to repeat deployments.
The next thing we'll do is we're going to deploy an auto scaling
group based on the launch template that we created.
And when we do,
this will specify some metrics that air measured that
determine the scaling behavior of our group.
And then, lastly,
we're going to attach an auto scaling group to a load balancer within our V p.
C.
And by doing this,
we're going to explore how routing between public and private sub nets
work for this multiple availability zone architecture.
So with that,
let's go ahead in here and we'll pick back up in the next clip within the AWS consul and start exploring auto scaling groups