[Autogenerated] we just got done talking about application load balancers.
So let's look at the network load balancing offer.
Now.
The network load balancer is a high performance load
balancer offered to us by a W S.
It allows us to focus on the networking layer of the
traffic as opposed to the application layer.
And due to this,
it means there's less overhead for routing the traffic in
that results in a much higher performance than a typical a
LB or classic load balancer.
So let me go ahead.
I want to create and then we give it a name, so I'll just call it Web server.
LB.
We can choose internal or Internet.
I'll do Internet and then we have our listeners.
So it shares a similar component to an application load balancer.
Except for this time,
we choose the protocol that resides on the network
clear so we can specify T c p t l s.
There's UDP in t c p u T P.
Now, even though it's on the same port as http,
it's inspecting for a TCP traffic as opposed to an application layer.
Http application routing protocol.
So I'll choose t l s it shows 443 which is the default.
And then we choose our availability zones.
So we want to spread this across multiple availability zones for
highly available infrastructure deployment.
I'll click on next, and this is where we can configure our security settings.
So this is what we would have seen on R A l.
B.
Had I configured a secure listener upon creation of the load balancer,
I'll use the same cert in the same policy and I'll move to configure routing.
And now we can create a new target group for this network.
Load balancer Sokol is nlb A.
We can choose instances or I p ease.
We can do our protocol.
So T l s or TCP in the port that were routing to And
then we have our health check protocol.
Now this allows some flexibility.
We can look at application layer health checks or we
can do networking health checks.
And the advanced settings are similar to an ale.
Be just with a fewer options.
So I'll go to register targets and in here I'll go
ahead and post an I P address.
Now, this is one of our instances in our auto.
Skilling group and you can see we register based on I P Not instance.
So it's registering the I P address on Port 80 in US
East to a So I click on review.
I'll click on Create I'll click on Clothes and then another thing
we have to do is I have to edit our Route 53 record for that W W
W record that we created earlier.
So a copy the network low balance her D N s.
I'll go to Route 53 Let me go to my zone and edit this W W W
record and I just swap it to the Web server.
LB.
It's the same thing a C name for W W W.
I'll save it and then let me close.
Now if I open a new tab, I should be able to get to my website.
Right?
Well, wrong.
So one key critical difference here is that with the network load balancer,
you may have noticed we don't specify a security group like we do with an a l.
B.
By all intensive purposes, a network load balancer is invisible to the Internet.
Compared to a application load balancer,
it's strictly quickly routes traffic and balances it across back in Compute.
Now, a new,
important key factor here is you can assign a static
i p to a network load balancer, and that's a newer addition.
But you could be tested over it by a W s.
So what I want to do is I want to go to security groups,
locate my application servers.
I want to edit my rules,
and I want to allow http and https from anywhere I'll click on Save.
I'll go back to load balancers.
For now,
we see our listener configured with our certain So let
me go back to my tab and there we go.
So after a little bit of time, for instance,
is registered, and now we get that same Apache Web server screen.
Let me go to PHP info.
And there you go.
We've now compared and network load balancer with a secure
listener fording traffic to a target group which hosts an
auto Skilling group on the back end.
Now,
one key difference here to keep in mind is that with a network load balancer,
you can maintain a consistent single encrypted connection from client to server,
an application load balancer breaks apart that encryption at the
load balancer level and does SSL offloading?
Now that's a common scenario to get tested over.
So be sure to research and read about the differences
on configuration for SSL traffic.
And another common scenario is you might have an application
load balancer at your Web server level.
So the public is hitting that.
And then on the back end,
you may have some back in servers or application servers servicing
requests that are attached to a network load balancer.
So you have a layer of low balancers with servers in between,
similar to this diagram here.
That's gonna go ahead and do it for this demo on network load balancers.
Let's go ahead and move on to the module,
wrap up and review where we'll review what we learned throughout this module. Quickly before we move on to the last module