[Autogenerated] all right, way to go.
You've made it through the second module of this
plural site course Before we end.
Let's just have a quick review and wrap up of what we learned Now.
We had in depth exploration of auto Skilling groups and the components that
make them up like launch can figs and launch templates.
We passed in user data toe automate some simple
installs four auto Skilling groups.
And then we placed an auto scaling group behind an application
load balancer to demo how routing that external traffic works in
a multi ese auto scaling system.
So all of this built on the previous module of a stateless architecture
by showing how it quick and easy it is to scale in and out when we have a
stateless design that we architect it now,
we'll go ahead and wrap up here and then in the next module,
will begin looking at using Cloudfront and Route 53 within different advance scenarios.