Hi everyone. My name is Bryan Hansen, and welcome to my
course, Building Applications Using Spring JDBC.
I'm the Director of Development at Software Technology Group
and now a seasoned author on Pluralsight.
Interacting with the database has always been harder than it should be in Java.
Spring and the Spring JDBC framework give us a great alternative
and make it quite easy to access our data.
In this course, we're going to set up a database in a framework to
fully utilize Spring JDBC for accessing our data tier.
Some of the major topics we will cover are all of the CRUD
functions of data access and retrieval,
as well as batch operations and exception handling and transactions.
By the end of this course, we will know how to
effectively use Spring JDBC in our application.
Before beginning this course, you should be familiar with Java
and an IDE such as Spring STS or Eclipse.
I hope you'll join me on this journey of learning how to Build Applications Using Spring JDBC, at Pluralsight.