To show you the SimpleJdbcInsert,
I am actually going to comment out the tdbcTemplate example
that we had done earlier because I'm going to revert our code
back to that after we're done.
If you are using GitHub,
maybe you want to branch this example and do it in a separate branch and you
can save it and look at it later or revert back to it,
whatever you choose, just for this example I'm going to comment it out.
Now there are a few reasons that I want to show you the SimpleJdbcInsert.
It's an alternative, and it acts like an ORM more than a straight database call.
So we're going to start off by creating a new instance of the new
SimpleJdbcInsert, and this takes a jdbcTemplate in here.
So it's built upon the JdbcTemplate.
Now there's a lot more set up with this, but if you're
going to use this in multiple places,
you can create one SimpleJdbcInsert and set some of
these values up per repository.
You don't have to do this in every method.
I'm going to go ahead and now create our list of columns.
So you have to tell this what to work with as far
as the columns in your database.
So it's a little more verbose upfront with some of the configuration.
So we'll say columns and then we're going to make a new ArrayList, and then we
want to go ahead and add what our column names are in here.
So we'll say columns.add, and we're just going to pass a string
in here of name, and then we want to do columns.add, pass
another string in here for duration.
So these are the columns in our database. Just like we had
created in our simple select statement up above, we're going to
now map this object to that database.
The next thing that we need to do is we need to set our table name.
So we'll say insert.setTableName, and our table name
is ride, and insert.setColumns.
So we'll set our column names in there and we just called our columns.
Now, we're finally down to where we can start putting the data in here.
We want to create a map, and this is going to go through a simple map
instance with a string and an object for the key and value pair. We'll
call this data = new HashMap, and inside of here we can start putting
our data in there. So we'll say data.put, and for the key it's going to
be our column name.
So for the name we're going to put in the value of ride.getName, and for the
duration we'll say data.put and we'll give it a name of duration and the
parameter we're going to pass in is ride.getDuration.
And we're almost ready to run this.
We've got to do one more thing.
One of the benefits of using the SimpleJdbcInsert is that we can return the
key that was created automatically from the database.
So if you'll remember when we created that table we had an id column and it was
an autoincrementing field. In one call we can get back that ID. So we can say
insert.setGeneratedKeyName and we can pass in that it was the column name id.
Now we're ready to say Number key = insert.executeAndReturnKey and pass in that
data that we had just created. Just to show that the key is getting a return,
I'm going to go ahead and throw a System.out.println for a test value here
until we replace that return null and pass in the key value to it and see what
happens. Now if your server is still running, it should automatically redeploy,
but if it doesn't, you may want to restart your server. Once that's up and
running, we can go ahead and open up our unit test and go back to our
CreateRide unit test, and I'm going to change this to another trail ride name
that I like called Round Valley, one of my favorite rides here locally, and
change it to 38 minutes and save that just so we have another data point
getting added to our database.
Right‑click and say Run As, JUnit Test.
Once this completes, we should see that our
testCreateRide completed successfully.
If we switch back to our console, you'll see that ID number 5 was
printed out on that System.out.println, and we can verify that by going
to our workbench and running that execute statement again for the select
*, and ID number 5 was in fact created with the Round Valley Ride with a
duration of 38 minutes.
So we've looked at that alternative way of using that
SimpleJdbcInsert, which isn't bad,
it's just not my favorite because of the amount of prep work that
you have to do to get it ready to use. We have to define the
SimpleJdbcInsert, we have to list the columns,
set the table, we have to bind all of our data to a hash map and pass
it in, but I do like the option of getting that key back in one call
using the executeAndReturnKey approach.
So there's a few tradeoffs, and as I mentioned also you can create one
SimpleJdbcInsert and utilize that throughout your repository.
So maybe you only do this in the setup of the object one time
and use it throughout all of your methods.
I am going to uncomment our SimpleJdbcTemplate update from before and
comment out the code that we just did using the SimpleJdbcInsert so
that my method is just using the JdbcTemplate and not the
SimpleJdbcInsert because the other methods we're going to use just use the JdbcTemplate approach.