If you didn't like using that KeyHolder to obtain the
ID of our newly inserted record,
there is one other option, and that is to use the
SimpleJdbcInsert that we had earlier.
I'll let you decide which one you like better. I'm comfortable with
anonymous inner classes, but a lot of people aren't. First, let's start off
by stopping our server so it's not trying to redeploy as we make these
changes. And when we go into our RideRepository,
that keyHolder that we just created down to the number
ID, let's just comment that out.
You can compare on your own as to which one you like better.
I'm going to go into the notes.txt that I had mentioned earlier that we
pasted in and grab that code now. We'll come back over and paste that in
below and uncomment it, and you can see here that we have a
SimpleJdbcInsert, it's exactly what we had written before, and we had to set
up our GeneratedKeyName and map our columns,
map our data, call set on it, but it does have that one helper function
of executeAndReturnKey that we can see down here.
Now we can save that,
go back to our RestController and change this to another name,
we'll say the Yellow Fork Trail, and save it.
We'll start our server back up.
Now we can right‑click on our testCreateRide,
Run As, JUnit Test, and see that it was successful.
Run our testGetRides again and see that it now has our
Yellow Fork Trail down there as well.
So, not a lot of code changes saved as far as one over the other,
but you do eliminate that anonymous inner class inside of your code and
you're just dealing with these maps to swap data in and out.
You don't have any SQL, it acts more like an ORM, so it's really which is more
beneficial to you for what you would like to do. If your inserts are always
going to return this and you like the ORM syntax,
maybe you'll go with this approach. If you don't
mind that anonymous inner class, you have this approach as well.
Both work well,
it's all a matter of which is easier for you. In terms of
efficiency, they're both prepared statements so they get both compiled and ran with the same efficiency.