So the solution we're looking to get out of Spring JDBC is that
we can remove configuration code or lookup code and developers
can focus on the business needs.
Like I said,
that's a big one for me is that the business doesn't care that I have
a try catch block or how I handle this exception,
they care that when we ask for a CAR we get that CAR back.
Our code can also focus on testing.
So on that previous slide,
it really wasn't that testable as far as I have things hard coded in there,
I have a driver manager that I'm getting a connection,
where's that connection coming from and that type of information.
Spring JDBC is built on top of Spring so we also indirectly have
the power of Spring using dependency injection.
If we want to annotate our code rather than having so
much configuration code in there, Spring can help us with this as well.
So make things easier to test, make things focused on what the business needs,
and remove the configuration lookup code through doing
annotations or XML based development. Let's look at that JDBC code again and compare it with what it could be.