Let's look at that business focus slide again. That JDBC code that we
looked at earlier has all of this getConnection and DriverManager,
prepareStatement information, that huge finally block that essentially does
nothing but close connections for us, and now here's what our code could
look like using Spring JdbcTemplate.
Notice that nowhere in here is it mentioned that we have a connection or
a result set or a prepared statement, DriverManager,
it doesn't talk about closing stuff or how we handle any of that extra
code surrounding us doing that select statement.
We have our basic find method and return statement, and that's it.
This is a great example of the template method pattern and how Spring
JdbcTemplate utilizes that template method pattern to interact with our code
This may scare some of you that there is a black box with Spring and Spring
JdbcTemplate, and I hope to alleviate some of those concerns, but look at how
much smaller and more concise this code is,
and it really is just doing what we want to do.
There's no reason we should have to rewrite what's on the left for every query we need to make on the right.