We previously left off with the ability to sign up users.
But what we're going to right now is a function to sign in or log in users.
And that process involves finding a user checking if the password matches what was sent to the server.
And then if it all matches logged them in.
And what do we mean by lock them in.
That could mean setting a cookie in the browser sending some information in the session or in our case
that's going to mean signing or creating a Jaisalmer what token and sending it back in the response.
So we're going to find the user using D-B that user does find one when we want to make sure that we
all wait for that promise to resolve.
So we're gonna use the await word.
We're going to find users by their e-mail.
So users are going to log in with their e-mail and that comes in from racked up Oddy e-mail email were
then going to restructure some properties from the user like we did before Id username profile image
you are.
Let's make sure that user name so we're just going to get some properties from the users to that it's
easy to send that back in the token.
And in the response we're also going to make a variable called Match which is the result of our user
compare password function.
We're going to get that second compare password is going to accept recked up Adi Da password the past
where that's coming in the request.
So in our user model we made a method that should actually be methods so that folks compare password
is a function which accepts some kind of plaintext password and compares it against a password in the
database.
So when we talk about this password hashing the idea is that no one can actually reverse the hash password
that's in the database.
What we do is we rehash another password and we compare it with what's in the database.
And if they're the same is match returns true.
Otherwise it returns false so add a little bit logic that says it is match which means if this is successfully
a match with the password in the database we'll make a token.
And here we'll use the JOAT time function again and we'll pass it what we want in the payload is going
to be the id call it id username calling username.
And once again since these keys and values are the same we're going to organism as 2015 object shorthand
notation and we'll pass in the image you know as well profile as you are to be specific.
And that's it.
Now instead of our token we're also going to make sure that we sign it using process that envy that
secret key.
We want to make sure that we're using that same secret key design and leader to verify our tokens.
If that all goes well or return a status of 200 with adjacent response that includes our ID username
profile image euro and the token if the match is not successful we'll return next pass to the air handler.
A status of 400 will pass and a message of invalid e-mail or password.
Once again if there are any errors that go on here make sure we put that inside of our home.
Looks like we don't even have a try catch.
Let's go make sure that we put that.
Anytime you're ready an easing function you always want to make sure you wrap everything in a try catch.
So we'll put all that code inside of our try.
And then in our catch we'll add a little bit of code to send this once again to the air handler with
a status of 400 and a message once again of invalid e-mail or password.
So what we're going to do with this sign that function.
Well let's go to our Roths Let's go to off Jeff's and make sure that we import that new sign in function
that we will also make sure that we add posts for Slash sign.
It's going to look just like above.
We're going to change.
You are all to the slash sign in command d to highlight the next occurrence.
It's also make sure that that's router depost create.
What's this is.
So back in the terminal Let's first make sure that the server starting.
And that looks good.
Great.
Let's go back and make our first HDTV poster request to localhost 81 slash API slash off slash sign
up and let's sign up a new user so username of new password of new and an email of new and new dotcom
when we make this request we should see the token it means that our sign up is working correctly.
Let's go see if our sign in works.
But first let's try to break it a little bit.
Was put in a different password.
And make sure that our End Point is signed.
And this looks good.
We're getting that error of invalid email or password.
Let's try putting in incorrect you know and the correct password.
And once again we get the same error.
Which is great.
Now let's try to post successfully with the correct password and the correct e-mail.
And we should get back the correct response which includes the Tokin and the ID and the user name.
We're not getting the profile image or El because we haven't included it in the next section.
We'll start including messages which is our second resource in the application.