Hey welcome back.
So the next big animation topic will cover has to do with keyframe animations.
Now keyframes are another tool in the animation arsenal but unlike transition's they allow us to build
much more complex multi component multi-state animations and on top of that they also allow us a lot
more control over the details of how the animation works.
Things like the timing when it starts.
How many times it repeats and so on.
So we'll see how they work in just a moment but first let's compare them to what we know transitions
so transitions allow us to animate a single state change.
We have a red circle and it changes to a yellow circle and we can tell it how long that transition should
take or we have a square and it's actually animating to a circle because a border radius and so on.
Or we can have multiple things that are changing at once right.
We could have a square that's changing to a circle and at the same time the background color changes.
But it's one state to another state a start and an end.
Keyframes allow for much more complex multi state animations so that we don't just have a beginning
and end point but we can define as many in-between points as we want.
So that's really really important to making complex awesome animations.
So here's a little diagram I made for transitions.
We can go from state A to state B.
Here we have an orange circle going to a red circle and we have control over how long it takes the timing
function.
If there's a delay but that's pretty much it.
But with keyframes we can do things like this.
Let's say we have that same orange circle and we want it to end up as a red circle.
We could do that with the transition but what about if we want other things to happen along the way.
Well suppose this is mimicking a sun.
So we have sunrise and sunset.
What we want to happen in between is the sun is going to rise up using transformed translate and it's
going to change color.
It's going to become yellow in the middle of the day.
So we could move the sun up and over to the right.
We could make it a little bit lighter orange.
And then we could continue that make it yellow at the middle of the day and move it upwards into the
right and then maybe this is noon towards the afternoon.
It moves back down stays yellow and then finally it ends up as red at the end.
So rather than going directly from A to E in this case or 8 A B we're actually going A to B to C to
D E.
So we have a lot more control we can define these these points along the way that we want things to
happen at.
So I can say exactly halfway through if this is the beginning and this is the end exactly halfway through.
It should be let's say 300 pixels up and 300 pixels over and it should be yellow and then I could say
well actually in between that at 25 percent of the way through or 75 percent we can define these key
frames and to turn keyframe.
So later on we'll actually have an exercise where we build a rising sun like this rising slashed setting.
And we also will have a sky in the background that's changing to the appropriate color if it's sunrise
or sunset noon night time and so on.
So that's coming up.
But let's start off with something a little bit tackier a little flashier.
We're going to make some animated text that flashes the colors of a rainbow while also growing and shrinking.
Maybe a sort of a throwback to the early 90s Internet ads.
And the reason we're going to do this is that I think will help explain how keyframes work and the basic
structure of them.
So here I have a timeline.
It goes from zero to the end of the animation in the very beginning to the end 0 and 100.
And the way that keyframes work is that along that interval we can define at any point that we want
a keyframe I can say that halfway through something should happen or 1 percent of the way through or
79 percent of the way through something else should happen.
Now I'm only going to do very basic ones here.
As you can see we've got a 25 percent 50 75 percent and 100 percent.
So I'd broken it into quarters but we could continue to break this or break it into an even intervals
which we'll see you later on.
So what we're going to do again is have some texts.
Let's say it's a paragraph and at the beginning I can say OK.
0 percent.
It should be red color of red and the font size should be 20 pixels.
And then at 25 percent color should be orange then at 50 percent.
The color should change to yellow and the font size should be 40 pixels.
So what will happen is that from 0 to 25 it'll go from red to orange 25 to 50 Ogo from orange to yellow.
But then we have font size and we only specify it at 0 and 50.
So that font size will change from 20 to 40 evenly across this interval here.
So we don't have to specify we want it to be 30 pixels here.
So then at 75 percent will change color to green and then 100 percent will change color to blue and
font size.
We'll go back to 20.
So what will happen let's just focus on the color that all change fade between red orange yellow green
and blue.
So it won't be these instantaneous flashes.
Rather there will be a fade between them and then we have font size that will start at 20 pixels.
But then in the middle of the animation it will have enlarged to 40 and then it will shrink back down
to 20.
So here we could sort of visualize what it would look like if we have the text Hello as read that grows
a little bit and change it to orange at 25 percent then it grows to its peak hello as it turns yellow
and then it shrinks back down and changes green and then it goes all the way back to the initial size
and is blue.
But now imagine that rather than being displayed as a timeline this is happening in real time and you
would see something like this very cheesy.
Like I said not the prettiest thing you've ever seen but I think it illustrates in a very very simple
way how keyframes work and this is something that you could not do with transitions.
You could have a single transition from here to here or from here to here but we can't specify all the
steps along the way.
The last thing I want to do is showcase a couple of fun cool animations I found on coed Penn that are
built using She says keyframes.
So here's a walking cat.
And as you can see there's a couple of animated components.
We've got this background scrolling by and then we've also got this cat that's moving.
So this is definitely tricky to make to make it look good.
Obviously to have these assets and to know how to animate something to make it lifelike very very difficult.
But underlying it is some pretty simple core concepts the same keyframes.
Here's another example.
Little picks a large tree with a flashing star on top and falling snow.
So this is all dictated with keyframes although there's a lot of things that are being animated.
This is definitely a lot of CSSA behind this.
But if we looked at a single thing let's say this star here there's a couple of keyframes at the beginning
it's small perhaps and then it grows and then it shrinks back down to sort of like we did at that rainbow
text Here's a fun one.
Mr. Jelly fish jelly fish pierce the s s animation.
So I've got a bunch of bubbles rising up.
Then we also have the jelly fish who has moving tentacles.
It has eyes that blink and it also has this little I don't know fin up top that moving and a shadow
that's moving along with it.
So there's a lot of things going on here but underlying it see is as keyframes.
And then finally this one is maybe the least exciting but it's actually very difficult and impressive
in my opinion this clock here.
There's a lot of things happening.
So we've got it actually works the time itself isn't accurate but it works in the sense that the hour
hand and minute hand the second hand are moving at the correct speeds and we have an updating readout
down here as well.
So the animation here is not that difficult just involves using rotate.
But there's a lot of things that are happening at the same time and a lot of time keeping underlying
it.
OK.
So I'll leave it here.
And this video sort of had a conceptual overview of keyframes saw roughly how they work but we actually
haven't implemented them we haven't seen the syntax.
So in the next video we're going to make this very simple rainbow animation but actually write the code
and see the keyframe syntax.