Welcome back congratulations on making it this far in this section.
There's just one thing to do.
Use what you've learned about D-3 to create a David dashboard visualizing some data that you're interested
in.
This is easier said than done.
However you've learned a lot about D-3 in putting it all into one set of visualizations is no easy task.
I don't want to prescribe too much of what you should do for this final project but here are some general
guidelines.
First your dashboard should consist of at least two visualizations.
Second at least one of the visualizations should be an advanced graph type that we studied either a
map or a force directed graph third.
Your visualization should involve some dynamic component rather than just being rendered once on the
page load.
They should be able to update based on some user interaction.
And finally your visualizations should use tool tips to highlight important features of the data.
Other than that there are no restrictions.
You can visualise any dataset you want using whatever types of graphs you want.
You can choose from the types of graphs who have studied together or you can choose an entirely different
type of chart.
We didn't cover all of the graph Alpert's D-3 provides.
So there were definitely many more types of charts the D-3 can help you build and there are also other
helpers that we haven't touched on.
So as you're working on this project make sure to consult the D-3 docs regularly.
I've added some links to example datasets and the resources for this video.
I've also built a sample dashboard in case you need inspiration.
We looked at this dashboard in the very first D-3 section.
You may remember that I've got three graphs here a map chart a pie chart and a bar chart.
The map chart visualizes CO2 emissions by country and by year I can adjust the year and adjust the coloring
to represent emissions or emissions per capita.
The pie chart visualizes the same data though the tooltip is a bit different.
When I mouseover an arc in the circle I see what percentage of total emissions for that year are represented
by that arc.
For example in 2011 the United States was responsible for just over 16 percent of all CO2 emissions
worldwide China was responsible for nearly 28 percent.
Lastly you can click on a country to see a breakdown of its emissions by year and the bar chart on the
right.
This is helpful in identifying trends in emissions.
Unfortunately the trends through 2011 aren't great over the two decades in the data set.
Very few countries significantly reduce their carbon footprint.
I hope that the sample dashboard gives you some ideas.
Feel free to build your own dashboard for this data set or to visualize something entirely different.
In the next two videos I'll walk through my code for this dashboard.