All right.
Welcome back.
So next up we're going to focus on building a complete application using react on the front end with
a node slash express slash Mungo Back-End.
So a full stack app or starting simple just our classic to do list.
I know it's not the most exciting thing ever.
However earlier in the course we already built a To Do List API.
So the first thing I want to say is that if you don't know how to build an API with Express and Mongo
and Noad are ready then go check out sections 13 and 14 of course if you want to build the full stack
reactor application.
Now if you don't care about the API and you just want to focus on the re-act side of things that's fine.
I have a repository that you can clone get it on your computer and just get it up and running.
And that's what we're going to do in this video.
But before we get there let's just talk about conceptually how are Apple work.
So our app is actually going to be two different applications.
We're going to have a re-act application.
We're going to run create re-act up they'll make us a new server new app for our front end then we're
going to have the node API the back end which if you haven't built it yet.
And Section 13:14 you're just going to clone it and we'll have that running its own servers.
So two separate servers talking to another as well as the Mago DP server which we don't really have
to do much with because their API takes care of that at this point.
But it's good to know that our re-act front end is in communication with the node API which is in communication
with the Monga database.
OK.
So the first thing we'll do is hop over to cloud 9 I'm in our workspace here.
I'm going to make a new directory where I'm just going to put everything.
So let's make a new directory.
I'm just going to call it full stack to do app CD and into that and now I'm going to clone my existing
to do list API.
I already have it here this is where I built it.
But I also want to leave this here so that students who are in Section 13 and 14 aren't super confused.
So I'm going to keep that there and just clone it into this full stack to do app.
All right so here's the API.
On get home.
So we're just going to copy this you Arel and go over back to cloud 9.
And I'm just going to run get clone and clone my API.
I should mention that if you built the API in Section 14 and you don't want to clone it again you want
to use your own version.
That's totally fine.
Just don't do what I'm doing right now.
And then in the next video once we run create re-act app you're connected to your existing API.
Otherwise go ahead and run clone.
It will take a moment and we end up with this two API folder.
So this contains your API server and in the next video we're going to run create re-act up and we'll
have a second folder inside of this full stack to do app and that will be our front end server that's
going to communicate with our back and server.
OK.
So let's make sure we can get it running.
This will likely be review but just in case we're going to run NPM install in that directory might take
a moment to go grab all the dependencies things like mongoose and express and all of their various dependencies.
OK there we go.
Now if we try and run it right away depending on what you've been doing in your workspace or on your
computer we might get an error.
And that's because we depend on having the Mongo database running.
And we may not have that running at the moment so I'm going to deliberately encounter that error.
So if I try and start it with node indexed Yes that's the name the name of the main file in our app.
You'll see we get a problem here.
It tries to start it up but then it says in this mongoose file there's an error unhandled error it says
first connection.
Connection refused to Mungo's server.
And that happens when our Mungo's server isn't running.
So I'm going to go ahead and open up a new terminal just says either review.
If you already have Mongo installed or if you don't have it installed I recommend that you check out
Section 13 where I talk about how to install it so that video already exists in Section 13.
You'll see how to install mongoose and once it's installed we just need to start it up.
So I have this Man-God.
I'm going to run mangu.
D whatever.
There you go.
And it starts up a server.
This is our database.
It's listening now waiting for requests to come in.
So now we won't get a connection refused error so this time if I try.
Nope.
Not NPM install again.
If I try Knode indexed.
Yes we don't get that connection refused error anymore.
Everything is looking good and if I actually visit my application right now I'll close these down and
just reopen it show preview preview running application.
I don't like it over here.
Personally I'll open a new tab and I have some existing things in the database.
You may not if you just clone this.
So go ahead and we can add a couple of things in.
Just to end this video so let's do walk the dogs OK.
So as long as we have some data in there that's all that really matters in case we're totally lost.
I definitely recommend you check out Section 13 14 where we build the API.
If you don't want to do that you need to clone it.
But then you also need to make sure you have Mongo deeply installed.
And so for that you're going to at least need to check out part of Section 4 or Section 13 where I discuss
it anyway.
We get Mongols running.
We get this back and server running and now we're just going to leave it going.
And we're basically not going to touch it.
There's one small change we do need to make to get it to play nicely with 3.x but otherwise we're not
changing anything.
We're going to leave it running and we're going to focus on the front end server or re-act app that's
going to talk to this.
And before I let you go the last thing I'll cover are the API endpoints.
So if you didn't go through Section 13 14 and now I'm saying that a lot.
This is how our API works.
So there are four main endpoints.
They all start with the slash API slash to do's and there's the four main crud functionality.
So things like retrieving all to do.
So that's what we're going to start with we're going to retrieve all Tutu's in the database when our
react app loads.
Then we have a create app or create route.
So if we send a post request to slash API slash to deuse along with some to data it will be inserted
into the database.
We can also delete and update particular to use using an ID in that path.
So we'll get to those.
We're going to have all four features implemented in our re-act up.
But I recommend that you explore this a bit play around with the API.
If you didn't go through second and 14 you could do things like this.
Let's go look at our API slash API slash to use.
Here we go.
And I should point out there's an existing front end.
You can see it here.
This part is not the API.
This is what we built in Section 14 a single page but it doesn't use react.
So again our endpoints all start with Flash API slushed to do it.
So we'll be making requests to this you are all to this point and we're basically going to ignore this
part of the app and we're going to build our own new front it using react.
Okay that's enough.
We've got our app running at our back and running at least.
Now let's focus on creating the re-act.