Now that we've covered the stack will go over two very important functions that facilitate asynchronous
code set time out and set interval.
And we just have two objectives.
First to write asynchronous code using said time out and second to write asynchronous code using say
iterable first upset time out time out is a function that asynchronously invokes a callback after a
delay in milliseconds.
So in this simple example here we've got a callback named callback.
We've got a variable that's a delay.
So one thousand milliseconds or one second and then set time out will invoke this callback one second
in the future.
One Second After a set time is invoked let's look at a set time out example.
So in this example it's similar to our last one except that we're providing now an anonymous function
right in line as a parameter to set timeout.
So our first parameter here is an anonymous function.
And our second parameter is our delay in milliseconds.
So two seconds from a time set timeout is invoked this function will be invoked and we'll see runs in
approximately 2000 milliseconds in the console.
And that's what we get.
At times you also may want to cancel a set time out.
So every time you invoke set timeout you get back an ID for that time out.
In this example here we first have a set time out that will console log this function runs in 30 seconds
and we're saving that ID to this variable timer ID.
Now we invoke another set time out.
That will be run in two seconds.
That clears that timer.
So this first time out the callback inside the set timeout will never actually run because this set
timeout will be invoked first and it will clear the first time out when this runs we'll see something
like this in the console.
So you'll see that we're canceling the first set time out.
So this callback runs but the other one does not.
Now this number here I just made up.
But it will be some integer number that references that set timeout.
Let's see this running in the console.
So we've got our code here with the first set time out and the timer ID and the second set timeout which
will clear that timer when this runs we're only going to see this second message console log.
We won't see this one because it will be canceled
and two seconds later we've got the console log that we're expecting.
Canceling the first set time.
Now let's see how set interval works.
It's very similar to set time out.
The parameters are a callback and a number for a delay.
Just like before but the differences set interval will continuously invoke the callback every x milliseconds
where X's that repeat value.
So in this example every three seconds three thousand milliseconds this callback is going to be invoked
and it will continue to run as long as your program is running.
Here's a set interval example that console logs a number every second.
So you see here in our callback function we're incrementing our number and then cancel logging that
number after we've incremented it.
So the way this will run First we'll see one in the console then we'll see two then we'll see three
and we'll see four one every second.
As long as our program runs this will keep going of course but I'm going to run out of space pretty
soon so you can imagine the next number after that.
So just like I said time out we can also cancel or set an interval.
So in this example we're starting out with a number that's equal to zero.
And just like before we're incrementing the number on every invocation of our callback function.
So this is going to run every second or every 1000 milliseconds and then we're going to cancel log the
value of number after we've incremented it.
But once the number becomes three will invoke this clear interval method and will cancel or interval.
So this will stop our set interval callback from running again.
And in the con. we'll see one and then two and then three and then after that no more because we've
clear the saturable here let's see that in the real con..
So I've got the code here just like the example number is going to start at zero.
It's going to be incremented up until 3 and then once it hits 3 our interval will be cleared.
So as you can see we've got one two three and then no more because clear interval has cleared the interval
and stopped it from running.
We've seen examples of said time out and set interval.
Up next is your turn.
You're going to be working on an assignment that involves that interval.
Good luck.