In the last video we got our form working.
So now let's figure out how to hook it up to the rest of our app.
Let's start with just saving the data in the form.
And this gets into an area that we haven't touched yet.
So I've got this data inside my form and I want it to be saved in a different component.
So if I open up the recipe app over here this is the component that has the state which needs to be
updated.
Now remember that state can only live in one place.
So the recipe app is the component that needs to change the state but the recipe input is the one that
knows when the event happens.
It controls the form so it knows when the Submit happens.
So the solution to this problem is for the recipe app to pass in a callback function to the recipe input
as a prop and the callback function will do the State Update.
So recipe input itself won't know anything about what happens when the user clicks save.
It just knows it needs to call a callback function.
So let's set that up.
First of all I'll just give the recipe and put a default Propp and I'll call it on save.
Now how should this recipe input use on Save well down here in our form.
We need to have a method for an submit that calls the unsafe callback.
I'll call this function handle Samit
handle Smit's only job is to first prevent the default behavior so that prevent default and then to
invoke the unsaved callback.
And one last thing it should do.
It should clear out our form so that there's no more data inside the form.
So let's let's see that first.
I'll put the handle submit method in the constructor and bind it
next I'll implement the method
and the first thing I want to do is prevent default.
Next we want to use our own Save method and we want to invoke on Save With all the values that the form
currently has.
So I'm invoking on save and I'm passing into it a copy of all the values in St.
Now the last thing I want to do is clear out our form after submit so that there's no more data in the
form for the next time you want to create a new recipe.
All right.
That should be our handle Samit method.
Now the next step would be to hook it up into the recipe app.
So when the recipe app mounts the recipe input it should pass in an unsafe callback.
My first step is to implement a handle save inside this recipe.
And remember Handels save gets an object which represents a single recipe.
Now what should handle save in the recipe app do.
Well it should update its state.
One quick thing I have noticed so I started these ideas out at 1 2 and 3 were computer scientists here
so it started out at zero.
In that way our next recipe idea is correct.
It should be 3 after the ID 2.
Ok I mentioned that little fix because now we're going to call that state and add a new recipe into
our recipe array.
And we're also going to update this recipe next recipe ID after we use it to create the new recipe.
So let's see all that in this function.
I'll use set state with an updated method because my next version of state will depend on my previous
version.
It'll depend on the value of this next recipe ID.
So there we have our new recipe.
It will consist of all the values that were passed in from that on save invocation and then the ID that
I am getting from this state up next recipe ID.
Now let's return our new version of state and we want to update the next recipe to be incremented by
1 and then also modify the recipe array to include our new recipe.
Now the last thing we need to do is pass this method in.
Well there's actually two things we need do we need to put this method inside of our constructor and
bind it to this.
And now we need to pass this into a recipe and put component as a prop.
Now let's check out the app and see if we can save a recipe.
OK I'm just putting in dummy data
and we got a new recipe.
So it looks like it worked.
That's great.
Let's send the video there.
Next work on hiding and showing the recipe input form.