Welcome back.
In this video we're going to go over solutions to the 2015 inheritance exercises.
The first thing we need to do is make a class for a vehicle inside of this class will create a constructor
method and will pass in a make model and year inside of this function.
Let's attach some properties onto the keyword.
This will specify the stop make equals make the stop model equals model and the this year equals here.
We then need to create an instance method called Start which just returns the string vroom.
We're also going to create an instance method called two string which will return the make model and
year are this dot make this dot model and this year we're using template strings here to help us out
quite a bit.
Next we need to create a class called car which will inherit all of the methods from vehicle.
So let's use the extension keyword to do that.
Inside of the car class will make a constructor method which will also accept a make model and year
and invoke super and pass and make model and year if we'd like we can also use the arguments array like
object and spread out all of the values.
We'll also need a property called Number wheels which will set to for.
We're going to use very similar logic for our motorcycle class.
So let's create a class for a motorcycle which will extend from vehicle and inside here Meeka constructor
method that's almost identical to the car except this time the number of wheels is to instead of spreading
out the arguments.
We could once again pass each arguments separated by a comma but that would be very challenging when
we have lots of parameters and that's all for the inheritance exercises.
See you in the next video.