All right.
So the next topic that we'll tackle here is Seah says transforms so transform is actually a property
that she has comes with.
It's really really powerful.
It's a little bit complicated potentially intimidating.
So we're going to break it down.
And the first thing we should discuss is what does it actually do.
So the official definition or the explanation is that transform but to manipulate the coordinate space
of the SS visual formatting model.
So I translated this a bit into something a bit more understandable.
Hopefully this is what I got.
Transform lets you move warp rotate and scale elements.
So it allows us to take elements let's say a div and it's at a certain place on our page.
I can spin it around.
I can move it X pixels to the right or down.
I can do things like scaling it up shrinking it down warping it according to 3-D perspective all different
things that I can do.
And when we use this in conjunction with what we're going to learn about CSSA transitions and keyframes
we can then animate them.
So what I'm going to show you now isn't really animating I'm going to show you how to move things that
are warp them how to skew them and rotate.
But it's not going to be graceful.
I can be animated.
So if we rotate something it's going to rotate immediately.
Our next step will then be learning how to slow it down how to set the timing function of it all that.
So for now we're going to start by taking a look at the documentation which is actually a bit overwhelming.
If we look at the official transform syntax I copied it over here.
There are so many possible variations for this.
It's a bit different than other properties.
You know background color.
You pass it a color maybe it's an R.G. B color maybe it's RBA might be hexadecimal.
It might be a named color and it's kind of a lot of variation for most CSSA properties but transform
has.
I don't know what two dozen or more possible functions that we pass in.
If we go to the docks here I'm an M.D. and I scroll down to syntax can see that the syntax looks like
this transform colon just like any other property followed by a function.
So in this case translating scale rotate skew skew X skew y matrix translate 3D.
You know there's tons of them I don't go for all of them and we're not going to talk about all of them
in this section either.
I'm just going to point out a few of them basically because they're commonly used in animations.
And those three that we're going to talk about up front are translating turns to X translate Y and then
we'll talk about scaling and scale x and scale Y and then rotation.
And those three functions put together cover most of the bases for animations.
Maybe you need to do something with a 3-D animation or a false 3-D or skew something at some point but
usually least in my experience most UI animations are done by rotating by translating moving something
essentially and scaling it.
So without further ado let's end this video.
I'll see you in the next video where we start typing some code.
We talked about our first transform.