Welcome back.
Hope that wasn't too challenging but I think it's great exercise.
So let's go for the solution.
Remember we're at this point with our recipe component and we want to build this.
So I suggest starting first with the nav bar mainly because it's all stacked against him.
So it should be an easy place to start.
So first thing I want to do is I'll just create a copy of this.
So we have the starter code and the solution.
So I've gotten that directory copied over and I have started the server so we're all set up to start
development in the new recipe proper solution folder.
Now let's talk about that now.
I'll start by making the two files for the component the nav bar J.S. and the Gnab RC ss.
Now it's fill in the nav bar component like always we need the standard imports and the class definition
so let's do that
OK.
Now we've got the skeleton of our bar component.
The next thing that I'm going to do is just return our ECMO here and I've already got that set up.
So this is going to be very similar for the nav bar we have the recipe app which will be off to the
left and then the nav off to the right which has new recipe home about and contact us and all these
things won't do anything for right now.
So that's our now Barch component.
Let's add it into our recipe app.
All right now we've added to the recipe app.
Let's see it in the browser.
There we go it's rendering.
Now let's add some CSSA.
All right let's talk over this CSSA quickly.
So in the top level of that component I made a header tag.
So I'm just adding some styles that are the main thing here is that it's display flex.
We're adding some space between and adding some color for the text we're taking up the list style for
all the allies in the header and we're taking out the text decoration for anchors reading some opacity
when we hover some pretty standard stuff so I'll include this in the notes but I won't go over it line
by line.
In this last part here where we're changing the now slightly when the size of the the window changes.
All right.
Let's see that.
And as you can see now we've got a header that looks a lot more like our solution.
So pretty good progress.
Let's now work on a list of these recipe components.
Now make recipe list.
Jasin CSSA so I had that.
And the purpose of this component is just to take in a list of recipes and then display them using the
recipe component.
So it's not going to do too much we'll see.
I'll start by adding the normal boiler plate that we're always going to have we're going to import re-acting
component and we're going to create the class.
Now this recipe list is going to render a list of recipe components so let's import that as well.
And we also want to import the CSSA that we just created.
So now I've got everything set up.
The next step would be to accept a prop that describes all the recipes that I want to display.
And since we don't have any any data coming in from the user let's create some default props here so
we can display something.
So at the top of my class I'll add some default props
and I've already got an array of different props that I'll copy over.
So these are the props that I use for my my solution.
We've got spaghetti milkshake and avocado toast for my my solutions.
I remember so far we've only got spaghetti as an image.
I'll copy over the milkshake and the avocado toast as well.
So all three of these files should exist in the public folder.
Next let's specify some prop types.
So and my prop types here
and the only problem taking an adverse component is an array of recipes.
And like I said that's going to be an array
and this is an array of objects this time.
Now with prop types you can get more specific and say prop types that shape and describe the shape of
every object that you expect.
But in this case we're going to describe that inside the recipe component so no need to do it twice.
Also you'll notice that this is underlined because I don't have prop types importer yet so I have to
go up to the top and do that.
Now in my render method I just want to iterate over the recipes array.
I want to map over each element and return some GSX.
So let's do that.
Now all I have to do in this component is return the list of GSX elements inside of a div.
I've added a class name here so we can style this container.
Now we need to use this component inside of our recipe map.
Let's go to recipe objects.
And rather than render one recipe here let's run into the whole recipe list.
So first I'll import the list
and then I'll render the list.
And remember since we have different props here.
I'm not passing in recipe recipes array but in practice we should pass that in when we have real data.
Now let's check that out in the browser.
It looks like we've got a bug here and it says it can't resolve recipe list that's VSS and that looks
like it's in the recipe list jazz file so check that out.
And the issue here is that I didn't do a relative path so I need to add relative to this current directory
and now it works.
All right so we've got all of our recipe lists.
I just need to do a few things so I'll add some styling to the recipe list so that it doesn't show up
in a column like this.
And then I'll also add those two images first the styling so recipe list that's the SS I'm going to
add the recipe list has display flex direction flex direction row and then this flex wrap so that wrap
to the next line and then when the screen gets small it will it will change the display.
Let's see that
great.
Now they look much better.
Now off camera I'll just add in those other images by dragging and dropping into this public folder
my avocado image of my milkshake image.
And then check it out.
And they added those images.
So let's go check out the website.
And there we go.
Looks good looks just like our solution.
Great.
So the last step I want to do before I call it quits is to add prop types to that recipe component.
I'm just going to paste in the prop types and explain.
So just like the other example we're just adding prop types this component so that the user of the component
is clear what things are required.
So in this case we've got prop types for the title the ingredients the instructions in the image and
come to think of it we should probably also make this recipe less required.
So anyway all of these are required because they're needed for display and in the recipe lists.
I'm also going to add required to this and that's all that's are completed up.
So next up we'll talk about one more props concept props that children.