All right.
So this is the solution video to the Random User Profile generator.
So I go into the code pen starter code and the first thing we'll do like I always like to do is just
get the button click event setup so I select it using query selector and the id be T.N. and then I save
it to a variable add event listener.
And I'd like to just check that it works with an alert and it looks good.
So next we can move on to making the fetch.
So I'm going to make a variable just call it you know and just set it equal to the API you are all that
we've been working with.
Just make sure it's valid perfect.
So we're going to do a fetch you RL And we'll add then and catch in there and we'll just do some really
basic.
Let's do a function rez and we'll just print out rez and we'll do the same thing except we'll call it
error rate there just like that.
Cool.
So let's make sure that works click our button to open the cancel clear some of this out.
OK.
Looking good.
We're getting our response object.
So the next thing to do is to parse our data on.
So we'll just add in a dot then before that that also has a response and we're just going to return
Raz dot Jaison pass it into here and let's rename this from res to data doesn't actually matter but
this makes more sense because by the time we hit this this will be the face on data coming back from
here appear it's a response object we can print both if we want it to cost a lot like Grez first then
parse it.
So it costs about log
parsing.
And then when it finishes down here we'll print the data.
Okay let's try that out.
Click the button.
Looks good.
So it prints out the response object then we get parsing and then we get our data down here.
So we have a couple of directions we can go with this.
The first thing that I would do is identify what pieces of data we want out and let's start with the
most obvious thing on the page.
This full name right here Dave Id equals full name John Snow.
How do we get the full name out of this.
If we look okay results is the key we need to work with.
So that's the first thing we care about.
And I like to just whittle it down so we have our data daat results that gives us an array you can see
here.
It only has one item.
So we need to do data results bracket zero and then to get into name it's under name here but there
is no fullname So it's first and last we need to combine together.
So let's try that.
We'll just do this mka variable here.
Just call it full name equals and we want data dot response or excuse me results.
Bracket zero because this is an array it only has one thing in here.
I believe this API allows you to specify that you want ten or five or however many random users.
So it returns an array but by default it's just one item which is what we want.
So data results is zero.
And let's just start there and print out full name even though it's not actually full name.
We do that.
There you are getting a single user.
So then we want dot name as we saw here and let's do dot first and know this is like going on the screen
we minimize some of this here.
OK.
There we go.
We get Nathan or storm like that name and Byron.
So that's looking good.
So we'll start with that.
And now let's focus on updating the dom because the process for the rest of the other properties is
pretty much the same.
And what we're going to do is select the div right here.
With ID full name and replace this in our text so let's select that and we can do it.
Uptalk for now.
So var and the hardest part for me here is coming up with good names for this.
Let's just call it full name display equals document that queery selector.
We have an ID for name and save.
Then we'll come down here and set for name.
Does the ISP dot in inner text equals.
And let's just do the first name to start well I'll just use a variable created to have it.
So even though it's only the first name for now.
So let's see what happens.
Clears some of this out next user and scroll up here and we get Nicholas or Niccol or however you say
it.
So to get the full name there we want to do plus.
Well we want a space plus data.
Results zero dot name dot last.
And now if we try it you know we're getting that form name updating there so we can refactor this.
You know there's some repetition here this data results zero results zero.
I'm going to come back to that in just a moment.
But let's now focus on the image so to get this image we are going to need to use inside of here.
If we look at our data if we print our full data again Cazotte log data
inside of the results.
Zero.
What we want to pull out of here is under picture and I used medium.
So let's start off by selecting the actual avatar image which is right here.
So did appear Avatar equals document that queery selector with their ID Avatar.
And that needs to be the ID Octa Thorpey.
And down here makes more space.
This is an obnoxiously long line that we will be refactoring in a bit but down here the next thing we
can do is do Avatar dot SIRC equals data that results zero that picture dot medium and lets see if it
works.
There you go.
So we're updating the name and the picture.
OK.
So let's do a bit of refactoring this is getting kind of annoying right here.
So to refactor this but I'm actually going to do is first pull this parsing we can get rid of the constable
logs but pull the parsing code the rest of Jason into its own function.
So I'll start by doing that and I'll explain why in just a moment so down here I'm going to create a
function and I'll just call it let's do parse J song just like that.
And there's a couple of reasons I want to do this.
One is that I just like having the ability just to say parse.
JS on here.
Clean it up like I showed you here.
It's a potential way of organizing our code.
But more importantly what I'm going to do is do a return restart Jason with the dot then here.
And what I'm going to return out of here is data dot results zero.
So what this will do is rather than just having to reference data results zero everywhere in here.
I can actually just replace it with data because what's happening is I'm returning.
So once the Jason is parsed and we get all of that it's in a variable called data and I'm returning
data.
Results zero.
So here it's passed in and when we refer to data now as you can see I refresh the page open up the Consul
and I click we just have the actual person data.
We no longer have what was it results in an array and accessing the first item.
We don't have to do that.
So we've narrowed it down and basically passed in the data we care about so that we can clean up our
code here.
Now we only have to say data not name and I do think it might be kind of confusing to have this data
here and call this data so I might change that just for clarity sake.
Mainly just for educational purposes.
I'm going to change this instead of data.
I'm going to call this parsed data just to make it clear that they're different but everything should
still work the same as you see here.
OK.
So now we have this parsed Jaison the next thing that we could do is extract this.
All of this to its own function.
So if I could do something like instead of just saying parse Jaison I could do it then and I could call
this you know update profile and that would be the code that actually manipulates the dog.
So I'll do that now.
Function update profile and rather than calling this data I kind of like calling it
and that's all we need to do.
And it should still work just fine.
So we're parsing the Jaison then updating the profile.
Everything still works.
And so now we have our named functions.
It's clear first this happens then that happens and we can come in and do the same thing so that we're
updating not only the full name and the profile picture but also the user name.
So we'll do that next.
OK.
So I started off by selecting the div that has the idea of user name.
Right now it has king of the north in there and I use query selector like you did for everything else
and then down here I'm setting the inner text to be equal to data dot log in Dot username which is inside
the response data.
It's under log in username.
And while we're here let's take a look at where city is inside.
Location dot city.
So before I do city that's just make sure it works.
There we go.
So we're now getting the username to change as well.
Perfect.
OK.
So lastly City
OK so what did it appear.
City equals document that query selector city with the ID and then set the inner text to data location
that city make sure it works.
And there we go.
The city is changing.
So we have all the data updating.
Oh actually we're missing one thing the e-mail.
So same process.
So e-mail is just its own field here and the top level.
So that makes it easy.
So I'm just going to set e-mail and her text equals data.
E-mail this e-mail here is referring to appear where I selected the e-mail.
All right.
So let's take a look.
Everything's updating how it should.
Perfect.
So the last thing that we could do if we wanted to handle errors which we're not doing right now.
I would start off with a dot then handle errors and now would be the first thing I do.
So I need to define that function handle errors and that takes a response and this is where we do our
logic.
If it's not if read is not OK we can throw an error and in here we'll just do the red dot status.
We've seen that before and we still need to return response so that we're passing it in two parts Jason.
So we're handling the errors like we've done before.
If we're requesting a bad you R-OH 404 or some other status code that's not 200 throw an error or otherwise
return the response and from here goes into parse Jaison then we update the profile and then we also
have this catch which we could extract into you know a separate thing as well.
Maybe we'll call this display errors and then down here we can just define maybe just paste it in actually
function display errors
very simple and or just cancel out like liking the error.
Maybe I'll just do a copy of that log inside display errors just so you can see where that's coming
from.
OK.
So that should be good here.
We've got first fetch then handle errors then parse Jaison then update profile and then our catch display
errors.
Let's make sure everything works still.
Open the console up.
Make sure we don't see anything there looks good.
And if I turn off my internet and try it now we're getting inside display errors.
Perfect.
And then the error itself is printing.
So everything's working how it should.
So hopefully you see how cleaning this up a bit it's just a preference but it makes the listener code
much simpler because we're already nesting inside a callback here.
So adding a bunch of more a bunch more nested code with you know defining functions appear is kind of
ugly in my opinion and it gets out of control.
This is very easy to understand what's happening.
And then we just have a nice little neat named function is down here.
Some people would argue it is less succinct it is more code but I think it's worth it.
Just an opinion though.
So that's it.
We are successfully parsing or making the request we're handling any errors that have to do with the
status code then we're parsing the response we're passing in to the update profile function that is
going to do the hard work of changing the DOM manipulating all these properties and then finally if
there's a problem we have our display errors.
Perfect.
So we're done.
That's it.
Hopefully you hung in there through that.
Moving on now to learn about some other tools that help us make requests.