Let's take a look at a solution to this countdown problem.
So I'm going to start off with the name of my function countdown and it's going to take in the number
of seconds I want to count down until now remember the goal of this function is to console log.
Let's say if I passen for here it will console log for.
Wait a second.
Three.
Wait one more second to one.
And then finally cancel log ring ring ring and stop counting down after that.
So I know I'm going to need a set interval.
And I also know that that set is going to need to stop.
So we'll save the interval ID
I'll pass in my non-MS function here.
And because this countdown is going to print something every second I want this to run every 1000 milliseconds
or every second.
All right.
Next up we will subtract the number of seconds that we've got.
So since this runs after a second we will start off by subtracting and then if my seconds are greater
than zero
so that's when I want to just print the number that I have right now.
And otherwise
I want to cancel log.
Ring ring ring.
And at this point we know that we counted down to zero and we don't want to count down any more.
So I also want to clear my interval and I'll pass in the interval ID that we saved up here.
All right.
So that should do it.
Let's test it out.
I'm going to count down.
Let's use for
three to one.
Ring ring ring.
And now we're done.
There's nothing left to do.
So the interval is stopped.