Welcome back.
In this video we're going to introduce a new kind of loop for easily iterating over arrays and newer
data structures.
In 2015 in the form of Lupe the syntax of a for loop is very similar to a for loop a for loop is traditionally
used to loop over keys in an object but it isn't the most helpful for iterating over values in an array.
That's where four of can help us out.
Let's create a variable called R and assign it to the array with 1 2 3 4 and 5.
We can now use a form of a loop to iterate over all the values in this array.
We will say four letters all of our and inside of that loop cancelled out log each of al.
So how does a for loop work.
Yes 2015 gives us a new primitive data type called a symbol which you will not be working with frequently
but there is a method on symbols called iterator which specifies how a data type is iterated over some
built in data types like strings and special kinds of objects like arrays as well as to new data structures
which we'll examine later maps and sets and the built in symbol that iterator function however objects
do not.
This means that we cannot use a for loop to iterate over an object.
Let's examine what we mean by that.
In the chrome console I'll use the console that Diyar command to look at an array and if we examine
it's donder proto we will see that on the array dot prototype there exists a method called symbol iterator.
This means we can use a for loop.
How about an object.
If we go up to the Dunder Prato and look at the object prototype we will see there is no symbol that
iterator implemented.
And if we try to use a for loop we will get a type error.
Since we're trying to invoke a function called iterator that does not exist in the next video we're
going to introduce a new operator which might look a bit strange at first but will quite a bit with
writing cleaner and more maintainable code.
See if there.