Now that we've seen Paul let's take a look at apply.
Remember that the only difference between these two is when we have arguments to the function that we're
using call or apply on in the previous example with the say hi method.
It did not matter if we used call or apply We only start to see a difference with call and apply.
When we start adding arguments.
So if we take a look at the example below it seems like call and apply are identical but things get
different on the add parameters.
Let's take a look at the add numbers function to illustrate this point.
Here we are concatenating the value of the first name property with the string just calculated and the
sum of four numbers which are parameters to the Add numbers function.
If we want to use the Add numbers function and set the keyword this to refer to the only object we can
use call or block in order to pass arguments to the function using call we separate them with a comma.
So you can see here that when we use call the arguments you pass are one two three and four separated
by a comma.
In the case of apply we passed all of the arguments as values in one array.
So it looks very similar to call.
But instead of comma separated values as arguments we put them all inside of one array.
So one might apply be useful when a function does not accept an array as a parameter.
We can use apply and spread out all the values in an array.
Let's imagine that we have an array of numbers and we want to figure out the highest number in that
array.
Mathematics is a friendly function that does that for us but it does not except an array it accepts
a list of comma separated values.
So if we pass an array to math Max we get back.
Not a number.
However if we use apply we can pass an array of values and they will be spread out.
In the case below we don't care about explicitly setting the value of the keyword this we just care
about spreading an array of values out.
Let's take a look at another function some values which adds three numbers.
If we pass in an array we don't get the output we want but if we use apply to spread out all the values
we get the correct output in the next video we're going to talk a little more about byde and see how
helpful it can be when working with asynchronous code.
See even.