Are right it's time to deploy our backend.
So what we're going to do first is make sure that we have Heroku installed.
So if you don't have that installed yet make sure you head over to look for Heroku C-L I want to head
over to this link right here.
All attach to this and the section notes if you have this installed already on Mac wonderful if you're
on Windows or on any other OS.
Here's how you would go about doing that.
And once you've installed that successfully you should be able to type in Heroku in the command line.
So what I'm going to do right now is first get rid of the Get Ribault that I have because this is going
to make sure that when I start again I'm dealing with the correct remote.
So if you haven't made this a good reboot yet that's totally fine.
If you have just removed that because we were dealing with a nested folder structure.
So what I'm going to do now is get in it once again.
I'm also going to add the node modules into my damn good ignore file.
So it's going to make sure that when I push my Nord modules don't go with them when I add the same thing.
So what I want to do now is create a Heroku application so I then use the Heroku create command and
we're going to call this warbler server and I'll call this asked for my initials so let's see if that
name exists already and it doesn't great.
I've just created my Heroku application.
I take a look at my remotes and get an now have this remote called Roku and that looks great.
We're also going to add on the Mongo lab edition and this is going to allow us to have a production
database.
And once we create that we should see that we have an environment variable pointing to that production
Type in Heroku config we can see what that you are.
Looks like we're going to be accessing this you are all using process that EMV dot Mongo D-B you are.
We're going to do that inside of our code.
Another thing we want to do is make sure that we have a file called a proc file and this is going to
be the file that Heroku sees to run a command to start our server.
So let's go write some code what we need to do are just a couple of small configurations inside of our
indexed.
Us.
What I'm going to do is instead of this port variable we are going to use process that EMV Dopp port
or 80 81.
And this means we are assigned a port by Heroku.
We're going to use that one instead of 80 81 which we were using previously in development.
We're also going to make sure in our index not just in models we use process that EMV Mangu D-B underscore
you are high or mango D-B local host warbler.
So this basically will state that if that environment variable exists use that which we will in production
otherwise go use our local database in our proc file.
We want to make sure we simply type in a web of colon node index dot J us and this is going to tell
Heroku when the server starts to run node index j us to get the party started.
So we'll make sure that we get ad dot will then get commit always need that dash and flag and we'll
say ready to deploy once we finished this.
Let's get push Heroku master and this will simply take that commit that we've made and send that to
our Heroku server and take a little bit of time.
Let's give that a second.
Now there there's actually one thing that we forgot to do and that is we already have an environment
variable right here inside of our envy.
And what we need to do is we need to tell Heroku about this environment variable as well.
So what we're going to do is add a config variable and we're going to call that secret key and we're
going to give this some value of some kind of random string of characters.
Now ideally you wouldn't see me set the secret key but I'm going to take this application down quite
quickly but this is not something that you would want to share with others.
So let's go and take a look at what our application looks like.
We're going to type in Heroku open and this is going to open us up in the browser and it looks like
we're getting back to this 404.
This is actually a good thing here we're not getting some kind of internal server error we're simply
getting a 404 from our server.
So let's try to sign up a user.
We're going to type in each EDP post to each colon slash slash warbler dash server dash Yes Dot Heroku
app dot com slash API slash off.
Slash Sign-Up And let's see what happens now.
And this looks good.
We're getting that same error message that we saw before.
User name is required password is required and so is e-mail.
So let's sign up with the username you should pick a password of secret and an e-mail of Ali and Ali
dot com.
Let's see if we can successfully sign up a user and that looks good.
So it looks like our API is working right now in production.
What we're going to do in the next screencast is configure our front end application.
That's going to be a little trickier because we're gonna have to point back to a different proxy.
We're going to change some things in a different file.
We're going to add what are called Build packs on Heroku.
But this right here should be enough to get our production application running on the back end and then
next screencast will deploy the front in.