We just finished up our recipe app and there's one more thing about prop's I wanted to get into before
we move on from this section and that's Propst children.
So our objectives will be to first describe what prop's that children does and secondly to read more
about Propst that children helper methods.
So what are Propst our children.
It's a collection that you have access to inside your component and we'll see an example to help clarify
what I'm talking about.
So imagine this let's say I want to make a row component like this where I can just put the row tag
around some other content.
It doesn't matter what content is whether it's a paragraph a div or an H-1 and then everything inside
that row component will be displayed in a row.
So how do we get that to work.
Well use props start children.
So as you can see here I'm defining some styles to make anything inside of this row component displayed
in a row.
So the styles here are going to be we're going to display flex.
We're going to do flex direction row and then we'll justify contact with space around.
And now this props to our children is a collection of all those elements that are inside and it could
be all different types of things.
So no matter what gets passed in those will be displayed in a row and we'll get something that looks
like this.
Now that's just one example of using children.
There's a lot more that we can do.
So at this point I suggest checking out this blog post by Max Stoiber.
He's a very active re-act developer who contributes to open source a lot and he's got a very very good
writeup about all the things you can do with props that children.
So at this point I'd say read that check it out and then move on to the next section.