Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be introducing a new data structure.
Yes 2015.
Call the map.
In other programming languages this is also called a hash map or sometimes a hash you can think of a
map as an object that the keys can be any type.
Remember that the data type for javascript objects is always a string for keys.
Objects are similar to maps in that both let you set keys to values retrieve those values delete keys
and detect whether something is stored at a key to create a map.
We use the new keyword.
Let's see what that looks like.
Here we're creating a map and setting the keys of one false and the string.
Nice.
Notice that our keys here are of any data type including Bullen's and numbers.
We can even set keys to be array as an objects to retrieve values from a map.
We simply get them and if we do not want that for each item we can iterate over a map as it comes with
a for each method.
We can also iterate over the keys and values if we like using a for loop.
Since maps implement a simple iterator so why would we use a map compared to an object finding the size
is easy.
Knapp's have a Size property like we mentioned before.
Bickies can be any data type which is handy.
Maps also do not have their own prototype object so you're never going to accidentally overwrite keys
in the Object prototype which is an issue that you'll encounter with objects finally iterating over
keys and values is quite simple and more friendly than an object.
Now that you've seen some benefits to using maps.
Let's see when a good time to use them would be.
If you find yourself working with keys that need to be looked up dynamically.
Think of this like using bracket notation with objects.
It's a good time for a map.
If you need keys that are not strings and find yourself frequently adding or removing keys maps are
a better option.
Finally if you're operating on multiple keys at a time.
Maps are easier to work with than objects along with maps.
There is another data structure called a weak wrap which is similar to a map except all the keys must
be objects and not primitives.
This makes a weak map more performant than a map but we cannot iterate over a weak map since values
can be cleared from memory.
If there is not a reference to them you will not find yourself creating too many weak maps.
But if you come across them in libraries and frameworks just know they are like maps but all the keys
must be objects in the next video will introduce another data structure that he has 20:15 gives us other.