This exercise you'll build a memory game.
So the game includes 16 cards you can click on a card to see its color and then you're trying to find
the matching color.
That's not it.
If you don't find a match the cards go away.
But if you do find a match they stay visible.
So there you go.
Those two don't match and they go away.
So you'll keep playing until all the matches are visible.
Or you can click this new game button here and the board will reset and you'll get a new new random
game.
So now there you go.
There's no other match.
So building this one might be a little tricky.
There are a lot of different conditions you have to keep in mind when you're planning out these state
transitions.
So what you could try to do is get started now.
See how it goes.
And if you feel like you're stuck.
Come back to the video at this point in a few seconds.
I'm going to give some hints but if you're excited to get started.
Hit pause now and try to do it on your own try to get as far as you can on your own and then come back
here and see some hints
OK welcome back.
I'm guessing you're stuck.
So I'm hoping these hints will be helpful.
First of all one thing that I did which I think was very helpful was I made a an an object called Card
state and the card can be in one of three states.
It could be hidden which means you just see the gray or it could be showing.
Which means that it's up but not yet matching anything.
Or it could be matching.
So I use the state object inside of my state for the app and my app state looks like this.
It's 16 objects.
Each one has an ID card state and a background color.
I start the state out all of them hiding because the game starts with all the cards face down.
And then I shuffle the cards and make that mistake.
So my state is equal to an object which has the property cards and inside of it you get a shuffling
of this array.
The next step would be to figure out what happens when a card gets clicked.
Well you need to figure out how many cards are currently hidden or showing and make the appropriate
transition.
So I hope that is a good starting point.
Good luck and if you're still stuck Don't worry the solutions up next.
But I really encourage you to try to get through as much of this as possible before checking out the
solution.