OK.
So I don't want to just bombard you with all these different properties.
I want you to feel like you're making something learning stuff and then applying it blah blah blah.
So let's go ahead and make a little Neph bar.
So here's what it will look like.
Don't expect anything too crazy.
I'm not you know a designer but it's functionally very calm and very important to a typical web layout.
So in our case we have these four links that are aligned to the right up top but it's responsive.
And as you can see as you scroll Well first of all everything kind of shifts over stays the same.
Then they kind of split up that space take up the same amount of space like a traditional kind of nap
or an iPad maybe or a tablet lay out and then they go to the standard column layout on a mobile size.
So you know the actual styling behind the spacing the colors the font size all that's very very easy
to change.
But what we're going to focus on is really the flex box part of it.
So that will be kind of how we structure this.
I'll start off with very ugly styled code or on style elements and just position them using flex blocks
how I want it to work.
And then if you care about watching me style it I'll do that yet.
But you also have the source code the solution code included along with this video starter and solution
are resources.
So if you'd like to just skip ahead and look at that.
Feel free to do so.
OK.
So here's our beautiful starter code.
Basically all it is is a Nav. with four links and each link has some text in it as well as an icon.
Not mandatory but I'm using font awesome again.
We've got home with a home icon about with a question mark contact to the phone.
And it's very very tiny.
And then dogs of course every NASCAR needs dogs and a little preprint.
All right.
And then over here I've got fun.
Awesome.
And then a font from Google fonts that is not mandatory but I just didn't want to have to you know have
you import that yourself if you're trying to follow along if you're doing this as a code along.
So the first thing we should do is establish how it's going to work.
As far as flex box we know it's a flex box section so you need to use it.
The rough idea is that we're going to make this Nav. a flexible container.
These items inside of it will be able to align them to this side using just the right content.
But then what we'll need to do is change how they are justified or what the value is just if the content
as the screen size shrinks.
And then finally at this break point we'll want to change it from a row to a column layout.
But let's start making it work just on this maximum size.
So we want things over on the right side.
So we're going to start by selecting the nav which is not a class don't need that period.
We make this a bit bigger.
OK.
So we'll do now and we'll start with display flex.
Not very big change but what we want to do is now shift those things over to the right.
In this case remember by default it's a row we could be explicit no problem with that flex direction
is Roe and that means our main axis goes from left to right.
So to move things to the right side we want to preserve the order so we don't want to do like Roe reverse
for example which technically moves them to the right but now Douggs is the first item which is fine
by me but our customer does not like that.
So if we go back to Roe Instead we need to change his justify content.
That's the point to justify content.
It allows us to distribute all this space over here on that main axis and if we add that border that's
due to pixel's solid pink Not really.
Nope.
There you go.
We've got a ton of space.
So by pushing it over but just the right content we don't want it to center instead.
What we want is going to be flex and all the way on that right side.
Okay.
So yeah we'll worry about the spacing and a little bit at the end.
We're going to want to add some padding to make things look nicer but for now that's the right just
what we want.
So then the next step would be to get this to work at this middle break point.
Let me go to the solution right there as we go.
I'm always zoomed in by the way so that's why that's happening.
It's really closer.
There we go where they spread out evenly and that's really some people would prefer if they were just
centered rather than spreading out like that totally up to whoever's designing this which in this case
was me.
And I'm not a good designer.
So what we want to do is have a break point.
So just to go over what we would do or we're going to do is change just if I content to space and we
could either do space around which is most likely what we'll do.
Or you could also play around a space between.
But we don't want that just to happen by default.
We want that to happen at a break point.
And the one that I defined it was actually kind of nice if you use code pen you get this.
Well I can't point to it with the mouse but if you look in the middle of the screen there's a screen
size readout that tells you how large and so I had it right about here.
I believe it.
Nine hundred twenty pixel or so and that's fully zoomed out.
So that means actually right here it changes over.
So to do that we define at media always a good habit to have that screen and you don't have to have
that and will do max with.
We do need this part.
Play around with what number you prefer but I'm doing 920 pixels.
OK.
And then all that will do in here is tell our NAV to justify content space around.
So nothing changes yet.
But as I shrink it down every go that's happening much earlier than probably happened to you because
you've been.
So this is more what it looks like happens right there.
So you could also change that if you prefer to center if you'd like that more you know play around with
these.
Figure out what works best for you.
Because personally if I'm being blunt I don't know if I like that space around but that's what I went
with.
All right.
So then we have this other thing to take care of which is I go to the original changing them to a column
this is a really classic use for fluxbox and just naff bars in general having things switch over to
a column when you get to Mobile size.
And that's really simple.
If we ignore the media query aspect for now and we just want to make it into a column right away all
we have to do is flex direction.
Gerrity have changed that too.
Column and there we go.
So it's as simple as switching that over but using a media query.
So this time and again at media and we'll do screen and Max with I think it's 400 or maybe 600 pixels
will work and all we want to do is Nav..
We're going to make that flex direction column.
So nothing happens.
But as I resize we get that column but there's one key difference that we're missing.
If you look at how this was working everything is centered.
So what's the property to align them centered on that cross access.
Because remember our main access goes from top to bottom Cross access left to right.
It's not just about content this time it bigger instead it's line items center so as you can see as
we go.
And just to hit that home you know we could change that to flex and
there you go or flex start which is the default but we want center.
So that's actually it for the Flex box portion.
We have this responsive nav bar just looks really really bad.
So what I'll do if you care is I'll style it.
You can also just look at the solution to see how like I'll point out some of the key things to make
it work a little better.
Aside from I go to 100 percent here.
Aside from the color and there's a slight hover effect with the transition throwback to our last couple
of sections.
There's also a change in the font size that happens.
So as I scroll here could see the font shrinks.
I just added that to the break point.
So if you want to add some of those styles.
Here we go.
First thing that we can take care of is style these links so I'll do that now.
Anchor tag first thing that we can do is just make them bigger.
Let's try 40 pixels.
Pretty big.
Let's get rid of all that.
GROSS default styling so that's text decoration.
None.
And let's also change the color.
I was using a gray Hex that I found.
I think it's nine five a five a six.
And when I say I think I'm actually just reading.
I definitely know that the next thing will do let's change the font.
So that's font family and we'll use the font that I included up here which is called railway but it's
spelled oddly on purpose of course.
OK.
So we're getting closer.
The next thing we could do would be nice is to add that underline the bottom.
So that's actually just a border bottom border bottom one pixel solid and to have another color that's
not memorized five to see Nine AA
goal.
Now they look like.
First let me get rid of this awful pink border.
It looks like just one giant line which maybe some people like actually but there would be an easier
way just to get a giant line.
What we could do is just assign it to the neph.
But what we want is some space between them.
They're running together.
So that calls for maybe a margin.
So on these days these lengths will just add margin.
And let's just do a margin everywhere to start it seems to work well.
I like the space appear as well.
So now we have some space and this is looking pretty good.
What we can also do is come in here and add our little hover effect.
So we do a hover and all I'm doing I don't even know if you could pick up on that in the video.
Just changing the color so just color.
And then another lovely hex 3 4 9 8 D-B And I'm also changing the border bottom color.
And that's the exact same color.
I'll just copy that.
OK.
So we hover.
You can see that happens.
But we could add a transition.
So let's do transition and let's make it maybe half a second
and let's ease out OK it's a little better.
If we wanted you can also apply it to the border.
You could do all instead of color.
But that will apply to other things.
If we ended up changing those later.
OK.
So another thing you might notice is this spacing here the icons are very close.
There's a little more space there.
So if we select the icons we can just add a margin.
Right.
And let's do maybe 10 pixels.
Yep looks good.
Have a little space there.
So now as we shrink this down we have a problem which is that they end up going on separate lines.
I am zoomed in.
So that could be contributing to it.
Let me see still happens though.
So what we can do is just change the font size when we get to this first breakpoint when we do space
around.
We just select anchor tags and just change font size to something like I don't know 25 26 pixels.
See how that works.
Not that we go perfect so that it's working just how we want it.
As you can see looks pretty good.
The only other thing that we could really do if we wanted to is play around with what it would look
like if we centered this.
That break point rather than space around.
Looks pretty similar.
But if we change it to space between or space around there is more space there.
I kind of prefer it centered to be honest and not totally up to you.
You could also just to be clear you could move it to the left.
No reason why not have it over there.
Starts on the right.
It was left in the middle.
Let's keep it Center.
I like that.
And that wraps it up.
So let me just change the view to full page zoom out to 100 percent.
Here's a lovely little Nav. beautiful hover effect.
Brilliant artistry.
Shrink it down.
OK.
Here's our tablet.
Old now FUBAR and then our mobile and Ackbar.
And you know we could adjust this slightly if make these bigger on mobile or sometimes what you'll see
is on mobile.
You get this background added.
If we really wanted to you know you could do something like this.
On the mobile size just gives the NAF a background.
I don't know what color would look good.
Maybe Gray.
No not gray but you can see what I'm talking about.
You get this board.
Well we can get rid of that border pretty easily by the way.
We need to do is come up here and say body
zero and it goes away.
But hopefully you can see what I'm talking about where we could make this look like a more legitimate
mobile lay out where you have a Nashbar up top that's a contrast in color just that's not the color
that we want it to do.
But maybe we could change the items to that item or let's just you anchor tag color white can be kind
of a stark change but there we go.
You know I don't really like that color scheme but it works.
We get this nice mobile lay up and I actually went and found a slightly nicer color darker blue that
I think looks much better.
OK.
So here we go shrink it down.
There we go.
Looks pretty good.
I change the font color to white as well.
You can see that here color white and then background that is next perfect.
So that's the end finally made.
So we're going to keep moving on a couple of other properties.
We'll see some properties that apply specifically to the items inside of a container or flex container.
And then we'll build another project.
All right.