Welcome back I hope that was a good exercise.
So let's take a look at the solution.
This is indexed Yes.
So this is where I'm using react on Brender and I've got my main component memory games so let's look
at that.
Now if you check out the hints you probably already have seen this but just go over it one more time
in case you didn't.
I've got a card state object which is the three states that my card can currently be in.
It can be hiding meaning that it's greyed out right now you can't see the color.
It can be showing meaning you can see the color but it's not currently matched or it could be matching.
Meaning that the card should stay up.
Now down here in the constructor making an array of 16 card objects.
So each card has an ID card state mentioned above and then a color.
So there are eight pairs of colors here red Navy green yellow black purple pink and light blue.
And then I use this shuffle method here to shuffle up that array.
Now shuffle I got from importing shuffle from shuffle array and that I've installed using NPM.
So shuffle register pensee for apage just an easy way to shuffle that array for us
and then so far my render method doesn't do much.
I render nav bar which we'll talk about in a second and then I iterate over those cards and I render
a card component and I card component right now doesn't do anything.
So let's take a look at that.
So a rendering 16 of these.
But right now it's just an empty div it doesn't have anything.
Let's check out the nav bar.
So here's my nav bar so far it just says memory game and then on the right side it says new game.
Now we're going to have to hook this new game link up to the state.
So when it's clicked it can reset the game for us.
OK so that's what we've got so far.
Let's get started in the car.
Let's make the cards visible.
The first thing we'll do is add a class to this div so that.
So if we take a look at card that CSSA which we're importing here we have this card container class
and it essentially just gives our div some size and makes it display inline block.
And the important thing here is the background color is gray.
So by default our card is gray it's it's hiding right now.
The next thing we want to do is add some props.
The first prop we want is whether or not the card should be showing.
So let's add a prop type for that.
So this would be a boolean that just says is this card showing or not.
Secondly we'll need a background color
and this will be a CSSA background color that we'll use to overwrite the gray.
OK so now what should we do with these two.
Well let's add a style object that will conditionally add a background color to
OK.
Now we've created the the style object and if the card is showing we've given a background color which
is equal to the prop that we're passing in.
Now we want to render our component with that style.
All right let's see if we have something visible now.
All right.
These are apps so far.
We've got our 16 cards and we've got our now.
I can't click on any of the cards though.
So let's start working on that.
So inside this card I want to respond to a click event and the state won't be owned by this card.
All I want to do is expose a click event as a prop so that a prop type for one click
and then add that prop to our div
and I'll make multiple lines.
There we go.
Now our card component is either showing or not showing.
And it will also invoke a click callback.
Let's test out to make sure the showing and not showing is working just by hard coding some values in
the memory game
so Ideally this should show us the background color for each card.
We also have to put a function in there just to make sure it all works.
And we'll fill this in later
okay.
Now I see all 16 colors and they're shuffled so that looks good.
Let's try hiding them.
All right so it looks like the showing and hiding is working.
And it looks like our shuffling is working.
Next up we need to make them clickable.
Now let's start hooking this up to the state.
A little bit more.
So rather than making showing true or false let's only show the card.
If it's not equal to hiding
that way we can see all the cards being clicked and turned over and we can also implement the new game
function.
Now let's add an unclick function into the constructor that will place here and we'll build on this
It'll start out as just a function that changes the cards state from hiding to showing and vice versa.
And this function will take the idea of the card that was clicked.
So you know which one to modify in the state array.
So I've implemented said stay here and we won't keep this function.
But essentially what it does is it goes through each card using a map.
And if the card were matches the ID that we're looking for we'll change that card to either change a
state from hiding the matching or matching the hiding depending on what the state currently is.
If the card that we're looking for is not equal to the card.
Excuse me if the card that we're on is not equal to the current ID then we'll just return the card as
is.
So essentially this will make the card clickable.
And when you click on it it will show it.
And when you click on it again it will hide it.
Let's put that up inside of the unclick
and see if it works.
OK looks good so far.
When the video here on the next video will implement the new game functionality in the nav and then
also make our game playable so that cards are hiding and showing appropriately depending on how many
you're matching or non-matching.