Now let's see what happens when we bring the key word this back into the mix.
Here's where things get fun in the first code block.
We have a method called Say hi which is a function that calls a set time out and counseled out logs
the string high concatenated with the value of the first name property on the keyword.
This before we see what the code returns.
Pause the video and think about what the key word this refers to.
Go back to the first two rules is the key word.
This in the global context is the key word this inside of a declared object.
You might be thinking it's clearly inside of a declared object and you are right.
However since the set time out is called at a later point in time.
The keyword.
This does not refer to the parent object.
It actually refers to the global object.
This is very tricky and trips up lots of beginners.
So let's walk through it again since the set time out is called.
At a later point in time.
The object that it is attached to is actually the window just like we said before.
So Time Out is a method on the window object.
Remember that time out accepts a callback function and every function gets its own value of the key
word.
This even though it's defined inside of the cold object which it is declared the context in which the
callback function does set time out is executed is actually a global context.
So how can we solve this problem since we're losing the correct context of the key word.
This we should explicitly set what we want the key word this to refer to.
We can do that using call and apply.
But since we want to invoke the function at a later point in time we don't want to use either of those.
Remember the call and apply invoke a function right away and doing that would defeat the purpose of
a set time out which is for executing a function at a later point in time.
So that leaves us with bind in the second code block we can solve our problem by passing in as the first
parameter to the bind method.
The value that we want.
The key word this to refer to you may be totally confused as to why we pass in the keyword this as the
first parameter.
Let's take a step back and see inside of the code object in the say high method.
The value of the keyword this refers to the cold object instead of the keyword.
This you can ask in the variable called to the bind method and you will get the same result.
But if we were to change the name of our variable to Ellie our entire function would break.
So you're more commonly see code that uses the keyword this.
To recap we saw that the bind method returns a function definition unlike call and apply and it's useful
for setting the value of the keyword this when we do not know what all the values of the arguments will
be or when we are working with asynchronous code.
One final note.
The material we're covering here is quite advanced.
But if you're looking to become a professional javascript developer these are the kinds of questions
that you get asked about in interviews and this is the kind of code you see when working in production
code bases as well as with larger and more complex frameworks like angular and react.
If you're still quite tripped up with this example that's OK.
Try to walk through each line of code and make sure you take the examples to see what's going on.
As always feel free to ask us questions.
We're here to help you learn.
See you in the next video.