Welcome back.
In this video I'll walk you through my solution to the pie chart exercise.
In the last video you may remember that I recommended you build this chart in three stages.
First build the chart for a single year.
Next get the range input working so that you can change the year and finally add the inner chart that
shows data by quarter rather than by month.
Let's walk through the solution in these stages.
First I'll build the pie chart for the first year in the data set.
Just like in the earlier videos on pie charts I'll begin by setting an SPG width and height and by calculating
the minimum year my dataset Eventually I'd like to color code each one of my arcs to prepare for this.
I'll build an ordinal scale to convert months to colors to do this.
Let me first create an array of months.
This array will be important later on because the months are arranged in chronological order.
Next I'll create an array of colors these colors are based on D-3 scheme category 20 but include colors
that are not part of that scheme.
Cool once I have these two arrays I can create a color scale using scale ordinal.
My months will be their domain and my colors will be the range.
Let's hop into the console and test the scale out as you can see the first month is mapped to the first
color the second month is mapped to the second color and so on.
Next let's take care of some basic setup for the chart.
First I'll select the SPG set it to what height and store it in a variable.
Then I'll append the group to the SVGA that will be the basis for my chart.
Just like we've seen before.
I'll center this group and give it a class so that I can easily target it later.
I'll also append a text element to the top of the SPG.
I'll add a class to it.
Center it and style little bit.
In order to reduce code duplication I'd like to try a function that's responsible for drawing the graph.
This may seem like overkill now but it will be a lifesaver when we want to get the range and coworking
so I'll write a function called Drog wrath which takes in a year based on the year of my data set.
I also set up my pie chart.
I'll create a variable called Arkes and assign the value based on the 3 pi.
I'll use the value method to specify I want to graph births and I'll use the sort method to sort my
Ark's here I want to sort things chronologically so I'll use the index of the month in my ordered month's
array to determine the sort order.
After that I'll create a path function using D-3 that arc.
Since I know I'll add an inverter later.
For now I'll set the inner radius to be positive.
Now I also left my chart group create an empty selection and join the data I get back when I pass my
year data into the Ark's function.
I'll store this in a variable called outer.
Since it's the outer chart one thing that's nice about this chart is that the number of arms is always
the same.
So I never have to hop into the exit selection instead for any you arx out a class of Arc and set the
fill for the merged selection I just need to update the attribute.
Note that this Enter selection only matters the first time I draw the graph.
After that the update selection is the only one that will have anything in it.
Finally I'll update the text in the title.
I do it here rather than when I originally appended the text element so that I can avoid some duplication
when I need to update the text.
Now all I need to do is call this function and pass in many
next stage too.
Here's where having the drug graph function really pays off.
First I'll put the input into the DML and set it step to one.
I'll also Center it in the ss.
After that I'll use the readout Max to grab the largest year and then all I need to do is select this
input set it's min max and its value and inside of the event handler for input events call the draw
graph function and Hassen the event target value looking good stage to complete for the final stage.
I've just got to do a few more things.
First I'll create an array of four colors for the forequarters I'll also need to append a new chart
group.
I'll give this one a class of inner chart.
I'll also need to tabulate Earth counts by quarter in order to do that.
Write a helper method called Get data by quarter which does exactly that.
Given some yearly data I'll first create an array which keeps track of births for each quarter then
a loop through my data and store the current element in a variable called row.
I can determine the quarter for row based on its month's position in the ordered month.
For example if its index is 0 1 or 2 it must be in the first quarter this expression will give me the
quarter for any of my objects.
Once I have the right quarter I can update the appropriate object in my order Talley's array.
Finally once I'm done looping I can return my tallies by quarter
next.
I'll need different pine arc helpers for the second chart to generate the arc objects.
I'll use D-3 PI and passen the same callback to the value method.
But now I can just sort by the value of the porter key my inner path will also be similar though the
Radie I will be different.
Once I have these I can join my data to Ark's inside of the inner chart by taking my year data call
and get data by quarter on it and calling in a Arc's on that.
Then I can go through the same patternist before I didn't set up a color scale so I'll just keep things
simple and use the index to find the right color in my quarter colors array.
Also I need to use my inner path function to set the attribute instead of my path function.
That's it.
Let's save and refresh great now.
Stage 3 is complete.
I hope this video was helpful.
This completes the section on intermediate D-3 in the next section will cover some miscellaneous topics
that we haven't been able to get around to yet.
I'll see you there.