OK.
So we have a working API.
All we have left to do now is clean things up a bit and we're going to refactor our routes file by moving
all the logic inside the route handlers into a separate helper so that our routes themselves will be
really really simple.
We'll have just routed out get and then that will be mapped to a function to call.
Will be a single line.
Nice Inkley.
So we'll start by making a helper's function or excuse me helper's folder and inside of that we'll just
make a new file and we'll just call it to Dewes that.
Yes.
So in here.
Let's start with the first one.
Let's do it here.
So our index route that retrieves all tattoos I'm going to copy the entire function call back there.
And this won't work just yet but we'll get there when open up to do.
Yes and I'm going to say exports dot and then give this a name.
So let's just call this get to do as equals this whole function just like that.
And there's a problem because I don't have DB defined so I need to first require DBI and to do that
from this directory.
If you look where we are to get to the models I need to do dot dot slash models.
OK.
So now we should be good to go here.
Or we have experts that get to do.
And the last thing we need to do is actually add that to our experts a model that experts equals experts.
OK.
So basically we're just adding them to an object.
So will have all of them available instead of our routes appear.
So I'm going to move over the first two so I'm going to take the second one as well.
This is our create.
So I'm going to go and just call it exports.
Create to do that.
Perfect.
And I'm going to go back here.
Now I have these two that have the exact same route.
You are at at least the different request verb.
And I can combine them in a pretty cool way.
So I'm going to delete this and change it to router.
Route slash.
And then I'm going to chain on the get and the post and I'm going to require helpers so I'm going to
make a new variable and it is going to call it helper's equals required and path is dot dot slash helper's
slash to do this.
So this helper's variable will have create to do as a function and get to do.
And so I want to map those.
So don't get too slash.
All I want to do is call helper's get to deuce and post.
I just want to do helpers that create to do it spell it correctly and notice how much cleaner this is.
So we still have the same logic.
It just moved to a helper so that our routes are very explicit and very simple when you request slash
which in actuality remember is slash API slash to use as a get.
We're just going to get to these as opposed.
We're going to create it to do.
OK.
So we can do the same thing here.
I'll fast forward through some of this.
I'll call this one.
Get to Cingular and the next one I'll go and do our update so a copy that no call this exports update
to do.
Perfect.
And then we have one more which is do we do
so I'll come back here.
Exports dot delete to do equals that.
OK.
So we move them all to a helper and now I have these three that I can combine in the same way.
So I'm going to do a router route.
The path they all have in common to do ID.
And then we have our get and when we get request this path we're going to want to call get to do it
instead of her helpers.
Don't forget that helpers don't get to do make sure.
Perfect then we'll come down and do adopt put it just helpers that update to do and then delete which
is helper's that they call it removed to do now delete to do perfect.
And we can get rid of this and look at how clean this is now.
So all we've done is move our logic into a helper's file.
And now our routes are really explicit that we're there grouped together first of all so all the routes
to slash API slash to do's are here.
All the app all the routes to slash API slash to use slash to do id or group tier.
It's very easy to see how things are working and to debug if there's problems.
So let's actually do that now let's make sure there aren't any problems.
It looks good.
Let's test it out.
So we can get all of our traduce I can get a single to do as well.
And then in postman Let's try creating a new to do so post and underbody include a name.
And this one is going to be Joash pet hippo that looks good.
Let's take this I.D. and let's try updating this one.
So that's going to be a put request and we'll update the completed to be true.
Right now TNT it's false get changed to true.
Finally we have our delete.
So if I just rerun or get requests you can see at the bottom we have washpot hippo let's delete it.
We did it.
So delete request says we they did it.
Let's go back to our Get request to view all of them.
And poor thing is gone.
We watched her hippo.
OK.
So we have a completed API now.
It's kind of a lot to set up the logic itself isn't terribly complex but it is a lot of files to make
things nice and clean and modular.
And this is I've said this a couple times but this is just for a single model to do.
So as we incorporate other models other functionality things grow pretty quickly but we have a nice
structure that allows that to happen.
We have our models directory so if we add users we just need a user's model.
If we want helpers for users we just add a user's helper file.
Same thing for routes.
So things are kind of set up for success as we grow.
So that's it for this section.
We have a working JS on API.
Now what we're going to do is build an app using this API.
So we're going to build a single page app using AJAX using Jey query to send requests from the front
end to this API to retrieve all the tatoos to create a new one to delete one to update one and so on.
So we're going to do that actually inside our own application which is kind of weird but that's how
single page apps work these days.
You have a back end API and then you're back and also serves up a nice page that has javascript on the
front end that requests your own API and consumes it.
So that's what we're going to do next.
OK.
Hopefully you made it through that unscathed.
I know it's a little bit difficult and tedious and we didn't really have exercises but it's really just
about making sure we have what we need to get to the Riak section and build a full stack re-act app.