Welcome back.
In this video we'll be talking about the fourth rule for determining the value of the key word this
and will recap all four rules to help you wrap your mind around the tricky topic.
The fourth rule for determining the value of the key word this is when you see the new keyword.
The new keyword is a reserve key word which does quite a few things we'll be covering the New keyword
in more depth in the object oriented section.
For now just know that when the new key word is used a new object is created.
The new keyword is used with the function and inside of the function definition.
The keyword this will refer to the new object that is created.
Finally when the new keyword is used an implicit return this is added to the function which uses it.
That sounds like a lot but will cover it in great detail in the object oriented programming section.
For now let's take a look at this code example.
We have a function called person which takes in two parameters.
First name and last name inside of the function we are attaching properties on the keyword.
This equal to the values passed to the function.
You may be thinking hold on a second.
The value of the keyword.
This is the global object.
We saw that in a previous video and in fact you would be absolutely right.
However the value of the keyword this changes when we use the new keyword.
Like we said before the keyword this now refers to an object that is created when the new keyword is
used.
We are storing that object in a variable called L-E and can then access the first name and last name
properties on it.
To recap we covered quite a lot in the section we examined the keyword this which is a reserve key word
in javascript whose value is determined at execution.
We saw the four rules for determining the value of the keyword.
This global implicit or object binding explicit and the new keyword when set in the global context in
a function.
The keyword this is either the Global Object window in the browser or undefined.
If we're using strict mode when the keyword this is inside of a declared object its value will be the
closest parent object.
When we lose the context of the keyword this we want we can explicitly set the value of the keyword.
This Using call apply or bind.
Finally when the new keyword is used the value of the keyword this is set to be an empty object and
returned from the function that is invoked with the new keyword.
Once again we'll covered this quite a bit more in the object oriented section.
Congratulations you made it through the series on a keyword this yourself on the back.
This is some tough material.
If you're still confused try to walk through some of the code examples.
Be sure to ask us any questions.
We're always happy to help out.
Thanks for watching and I'll see you in the next section.