All right last property here around the flex trifecta is flex shrink so shrink is similar to grow.
Obviously it's different.
It dictates how items should shrink when there isn't enough space in the container.
I will mention the math is actually different for flex shrink.
I'm not going to go into it but there are some articles explaining it.
It's very confusing to be honest.
You don't really need to go into it but if you want to work out the equation it is possible but it uses
a different formula than the one used to figure out how to distribute the space in Flex grow.
But all that we really need to know is that it allows us to roughly proportionately dictate how space
should shrink or how items should shrink when the space shrinks.
So there's not enough space which right now there's plenty of space so let's make a condition when there
isn't enough let's say let's give them a flex basis of 500 pixels was enough.
Yes.
So they are combined 2000 pixels which is greater than the width of this.
So how should they shrink.
Right now they're shrinking evenly which leads us to believe that flex shrink by default is 1.
So nothing changes.
They all shrink at the same rate and you know I can continue to shrink like that and you'll see they
all shrink at the same rate.
That's the default.
But let's say that I actually want box.
Let's go with I don't know three I want Box 3 to shrink faster so I can manually set it to be two.
And you'll see that it already has shrunk.
Or how about for and so I can see that flex shrink to zero for the other ones.
And what that does is it says these should never shrink and you can see they actually go outside the
edge of the container.
And they don't shrink at all.
So maybe not that useful.
Sometimes you do want to set flex shrink to zero.
But in this case we don't.
And that's also because we don't have like a rap enabled so they go outside of the container.
But the key thing I'm trying to show is by setting flex shrink to zero on all of the others and then
any number on poor little three here Mr. or Mrs. three has to shrink to make up as much space as possible
it shrinks completely and it's still not enough.
If you'll notice three and four.
Like I said is out of bounds.
So we could also give flex strength to another one of them.
How about we'll go with four.
So what happens is that flex basis is set to 500.
They each have that.
And so ideally they take up five hundred but that's not an option.
There's not enough space.
So they have to shrink down to fit inside this container.
Well where's that space come from.
It comes evenly from three and four is split between them.
So that's the basics.
But here's a more common scenario.
If you had maybe three boxes let's say keep going back to a column accidentally.
We want to know we have three boxes let's set foot flex bases to be two hundred and fifty maybe OK.
And let's give them a flex grow to start actually let's do a little bigger Let's do 350 perfect.
OK.
So they're even.
And let's get rid of that Flextronics zero.
Let's give them all flex grow of one.
So they grow to take that space up.
So right now of course they shrink at the same rate because flex shrink by default is one.
OK but let's say I actually want one in three to shrink faster.
So that's easy to do I just will do a flex shrink and we can just do two to start on one.
And then on three and you'll see that it doesn't kick in right away because flex basis is set to be
350 pixels.
So if we inspect this sorry if there's a lot going on in screen right now re-inspect one of them.
OK.
We're at 447 pixels there.
And they keep going to inspect again for 12 for 12 for 12.
So they're evenly sized but as soon as I go below 350
did that happen yet here we go to 82.
But this one in the middle is 316 and this one on the left is 282.
So this one in the middle is not shrinking quite as fast as the two on the left and right.
It does shrink because remember flex shrink is set to be one by default.
So if I keep going to turn this off
you'll see they shrink a lot faster twice as fast.
But this one still does shrink.
If I didn't want it to shrink at all I could set flex shrink
to zero and I'm doing that on all boxes.
I mean we only have three of them so I'm already assigning flex shrink on these two.
So why not just assign it here to be more explicit.
OK.
So this middle one will not shrink at all.
And now remember this number doesn't matter because it's just a ratio it's a proportion.
So these are equivalent.
They'll shrink at the same rate.
Here we go.
And if we inspect this one you'll see it's still 350 pixels even though we shrank it way down.
And in fact if we shrink it too far down it still will stay 350 pixels the whole way even if it ruins
everything at all costs.
It's not budging.
All right.
So that's like shrink I guess I could show you.
You know we could do the same thing but instead of doing let's go 0 1 and 2.
Now if we shrink these down there you go see what happens.
We end up with this guy not shrinking this one shrinking half as fast as this one or this one shrinks
twice as fast as that one.
So it's very useful.
In particular when you have content that you know you want to emphasize at certain parts like if this
was an add on mobile you don't want your ads to be gigantic or often with nav bars you want things to
shrink in a particular way.
You want your main links to the Home link maybe to stay larger than the little social media buttons
will play around with it and you'll see in the next couple of videos how this all fits together.
Which brings me to the very last thing our syntax here flex where we have flex grow flex strength and
flex basis.
Again the order does matter.
So grow shrink basis and we can replace all of this well not all of it.
In this case because we have three different numbers but all of this right here with a single line.
So let's say I want them to all start off as the same size let's say 300 to 200 pixels smaller.
So nothing will happen yet.
But if I say the flex grow should be zero.
I don't want them to grow and the shrink should be zero.
What do you expect in code Penn. refreshed ahead of me darn them.
But here's what we get.
They stage 200 pixels they're not going to grow to use that space and they're not going to shrink.
Not really that useful.
So I could change like Schiro now to be one.
What do you think will happen already that they all grow evenly to take up that space.
And I could see that flex shrink to be one and they would all grow as well.
Or excuse me I'll shrink evenly and then I could go down to one of these other ones that say box to
like and say OK box two I actually want to grow twice as fast and have it shrink at the same rate but
I want it's flex basis to start as 500 pixels and now it starts larger.
It uses up space.
If there's any and it shrinks at the same rate of one so that's a shorthand flex that's far more common.
We pretty much never see people using flex grow flex basis separately sometimes.
But most of the time you'll see them use them together with the flex prop..
All right.
Next up we're going to build a very simple little widget that I found on a game review Web site.