All right.
Welcome back.
So in this video I'm really talking about how these properties work together alongside rap flex rap.
So Flex meaning flex grow flex shrink and flex basis in combination with flex rap and to do that.
I didn't want to just hit you with some more slides.
Instead we're going to build a very simple widget.
This is a Web site polygon a game site gaming news and reviews.
And there's this little banner they have on every review page and you'll notice there's three evenly
spaced.
Or even the size things boxes shrink they shrink together they grow together.
But there's this cool behavior when you get to a point it wraps and then takes up the entire row and
then they go to culms.
So to make this it's actually pretty simple.
You have to understand how flex grow shrink and bubble bath how that works.
So here's some starter code that I made.
If you want to follow along first thing will do.
Just look at the markup.
So we've got a container div with three boxes.
Each box has an H3 inside with some dummy text.
And then the middle box has a class of middle just so I can change its colors.
There's other ways of doing that of course.
Cleaner ways using emptive type or something but I just wanted to have this video focus purely on flex
blocks.
So let's start off by selecting our container and let's give that the magic display flex as we go.
Super easy to get them in line like that.
OK so now let's do just some basic color.
So the box the top and bottom are the first and third boxes are going to have a color background and
color.
I'm not memorizing this.
It is CCPs 00 zero for two.
And let's do the same thing.
But for middle and that color is be 2 0 0 3 9.
All right.
So now that we have that out of the way let's take a look at their default behavior.
So it's actually pretty close to what we want.
Things are shrinking evenly.
But then this happens.
We don't want that.
So the first thing you know just to be clear the default flex shrink is one but we could play around
with that.
And do you know Frech flex shrink to and that goes of course on the actual items not the container.
There you go.
So they will have a drink of two but the middle one will have a flex shrinker.
One what happens.
Here we go.
There we go.
It shrinks at a much slower rate.
It still does shrink but much slower than the left and the right.
But we don't care about that for now.
So let's talk about the rapping behavior.
So I want it to wrap.
So that's on our container.
So it's Flack's wrap colon wrap but it just starts wrapping right away.
Why is it doing that.
Not what I want.
And this has to do with a couple of things.
One is that we don't have a flex basis set which remember is the initial state that it gets put in there.
And what's happening instead is the initial state of each one of these.
Let's take a look.
447 pixels 516.
453.
So let me get rid of the disp the display flex.
You know you can see these are massive.
They go all the way across of course.
So we don't have a flex basis set.
And so it's using the width of the content inside to determine that.
And because of that this thing is too large to fit over here.
So it goes onto the next line.
We don't want that.
What we want instead is for them to wrap at a specific point and for us I believe they think the number
that I came up with was around 200 pixels.
So once each one of them is 200 pixels wide it should wrap it to D that comes to flex basis.
So Flex bases we could give you something small like 100 pixels and save turn flex wrap like spaces.
So let's add a flex bases to the boxes flex bases.
If I can spell it and let's just do one hundred pixels at the beginning.
There we go.
So they're forced into this 100 pixel sized container I guess.
And there's three of them and we have a bunch of space by default flex grow is what it's 0.
So they don't take up the space.
So if we want them to do flex grow one.
Now they all take up that space.
OK.
So we're getting close.
Right.
That looks good.
But now what happens when we get to the point where they should wrap.
And where is that point.
Well flex basis is set to be 100 pixels right now.
So that's pretty small.
So when they each take up 100 pixels which is going to be where you right there and you see that line
right there.
Yup.
So right when we hit 300 pixels it shifts down and you can see now that they are rapping.
And why is it taking up this entire row.
Well there's a bunch of whitespace and we that flex grow to be one.
So if we get rid of flex grow and let it flex basis to be 200.
So they start there.
And once I shrink down to that size notice it doesn't take up the whole row.
But if I add flex grow it now grows to take up the entire row.
OK.
So that's kind of just that's it that's a little trick using flex basis along with wrap.
So combining them can make some really make for some really nice results.
Also I'll just show as I keep shrinking what happens.
Well flex basis is 200 pixels.
We're running out of space.
Go onto the next line and now they each have a roach themselves.
They take up all that white space because flex goes one I think it's pretty nifty.
Very easy to make a nice layout like that.
And really we have or we've achieved what at least the functionality of this you know the styling stuff
to do but it's exactly the same you know the numbers might be different.
I didn't go through and look at the exact with.
We compare that to ours.
Let's see where does that change.
Looks about the same as far as the widths.
So you could experiment more with that.
So that's really all I wanted to show on this video.
The last thing we could do is simplify this with a single line.
So just change it to flex what's our flex grow zero.
What's the shrink one that's the default and the basis 200 pixels.
Get rid of these two lines and just see we end up with the same exact result right there.
Cool.
So if you want to see the stylus you can do that.
But if you don't care.
Go ahead.
Move on.
So if you do care all we'll do is set a set the color to be white and the font family should be I think
Helvetica we can add some padding.
There we go just all around.
The other thing that we can do is add that hover effect I don't know if you noticed that it just changes
background colors.
So does box colon hover.
Well just do background and that color is f f 0 0 5 2 perfect still a little bra.
So why don't we add a nice transition.
Some review here.
Transition.
Let's go very fast point one seconds and let's do that just on background.
Yeah it's a little nicer.
All right.
And that's pretty much it honestly.
Oh and the last thing I did zoom out here and you can see our font size is not quite right.
So we might want to replace that with something to H-3 maybe will do font size maybe 30 pixels.
That looks good although you may want it to shrink down the window so you could use a media query you
could use calc you could use.
What else could you do a percentage or even do VH or V W in this case could do like two.
VW I'm not really a fan of this because it gets too small at the end.
It's doing 2 percent of the width of the window but just showing you could do that.
But I think 30 pixels or work right or not.