Welcome back in this section we're going to talk about closures to create closures and where closures
are used in the real world.
If you read a bit on closures you might think they're quite confusing but once you can understand what
the definition of a closure is it becomes much much easier to understand them.
So let's define what a closure is a closure is a function that makes use of variables defined in outer
functions that have returned.
That sounds like quite a bit.
So let's see an example.
I'm going to open the chrome developer console and create a function called outer inside of the outer
function.
I'm going to create a variable called Start and assign it to the string.
Closures are.
I'll then return a function from the outer function and call it inner inside of here.
I'll return the string start concatenated with the string.
Awesome.
If I invoke the outer function I'm going to see the definition of the inner function and if I invoke
the inner function right away I'll see the string closures are awesome.
You might not think this is very impressive and that's OK.
Right now we just want to focus on the definition.
If I look again at the outer function being called I can see that inside of its return value there is
a variable called start but how does this inner function have access to that smart variable.
The outer function has returned.
The answer is through closure.
Let's take another look at an example of closure in this function called outer.
We accept a parameter called a and return a function which accepts a parameter called B inside of the
inner function.
We are making use of the parameter a.
Even though the outer function has returned already one more time closure exists when an inner function
makes use of variables defined in an outer function.
It has returned a couple of things to note.
We need to return the inner function and invoke it and we do not need to give the inner function a name.
We can make it anonymous we have named it for learning purposes for debugging as well.
It is recommended that you name your functions now that you know what a closure is.
Let's see if you can identify it the following code contains a closure.
Let's take a look at this first example.
Is there a closure.
How about the second example.
The first one is not and the second one is Why is that.
Remember closure only exists when an inner function makes use of variables defined in an outer function.
It has returned the inner function does not make use of any of the external variables.
All we have is a function inside of another function.
Now you have an idea of what closure is.
Let's see how they actually work.
What's essential to understand about closure is that only the variables that are used in the inner function
are remembered with seek a look at an example using the chrome developer tools.
I'll make a function called outer F and an inside.
Create two variables to which I will assign to the string something from outer effen and fact which
I will assign to the string.
Remember me.
I'll then return a function called Inner FM and inside of there place a debugger keyword and then on
the next line return the fact variable.
When I run this code I'll be placed inside of the sources tab where I can examine all variables in my
inner in a debugger keyword causes execution of my code on that line in which I place it.
If I press escape I can open up a console where I can see what values of some of the variables that
I have are.
So what variables do you think I'll have access to in inner ephah.
Let's see if I have the fact variable and in fact I do.
But how about data.
If I try to access this I'll get back a reference.
What's really important to understand here is that inner functions do not remember everything from outer
functions that have returned only the variables that they need.
What happens here is when a function returns it first checks to see if there are any inner functions
which are use variables defined in the function.
It makes sure to remember those variables if it needs to.
This is how closure works.
Now you might be wondering why do I need to know this.
When will I be using closure.
See if you can brainstorm some ideas of when it might be helpful and the next video will answer those
questions and more.
See there.