Hello again I'm here with Tim Garcia The Greatest Man That Ever Lived to introduce the next chunk of
content and of course moving our focus away from CSX for now and towards writing Asynchronous JavaScript.
The end goal here is to eventually build single page applications using javascript.
So Tim's going to take a lead on this next section and introduce some important concepts around asynchronous
Janus will cover things like how to write Asynchronous JavaScript how to manage asynchronous code using
callbacks and how the javascript event loop works.
The material here is essential.
Understand is fundamental for building single page applications.
After that I'll be back to cover the actual process of making requests to third party API is using AJAX.
Until then you're in Tim's good hands.