Now let's talk about state.
So everything we've done and react so far honestly can really be down with just H.T. amounts.
SS We haven't done anything that requires some some data that changes.
But now that the ADD state will we'll see the difference between props and state and how state can actually
affect change in your application.
Our objectives will be to first define stay in re-act second to create a component with a constructor
and state.
We haven't seen the constructor yet but we'll see it in this one.
And third to describe what happens when set state is called what is state.
Well state is just like it sounds that stateful data it's data in your application that can change.
So when we use props and all the examples before we can never change props and state is different state
can be changed.
But just like prop's we can't modify state directly.
We'll see how we can modify state in just a minute.
In this example we've got a react component called app that has the first constructor that we've seen
so far and in every constructor that you create in your re-act component you always want to take prop's
as a parameter and then invoke super props which essentially calls the the constructor of this component
that you're inheriting from.
So this is just boilerplate you'll do this in every constructor that you write Propst as a parameter
and then super prop's is the next line.
After that we're defining our state in the constructor.
So this state equals some object inside that object.
We have data that we care about in our application that we might want to change.
So favorite color here is a piece of state and then inside of our render method we can access that state
using this state DOT.
In this case favorite color.
But this is just a normal javascript object so any property that's defined in state we can access via
this state DOT name of property.
But this component still doesn't do anything it's just displaying the static state that we've set in
the constructor.
So how do we change the state well the correct way to change state in your application is to use the
set state method set is defined on your component so you have access to it by saying this that set state
and the simplest usage for set state is to provide a new object which defines all the properties that
you want to overwrite in your old version of your state.
I want to point out here that you should never ever modify state directly just like props you never
want to add your own values to state or overwrite values that state has.
You always want to call set state to make any change to your state and we'll see more of that as we
go.
This is an example of changing the state in our application.
So this is the same as what we saw before with a constructor and a render method that shows our state.
But now we have a set time out and after three seconds this callback function gets invoked and inside
the callback.
This starts that state is going to change our favorite color from red to blue.
Now it's important to note that this not set se is not a synchronous function it's asynchronous.
So if I were to put a console log after this line of code this does state that favorite color would
still be red and why is that state not synchronous.
Well that's because how it acts said state will eventually invoke the render method.
So whenever a set state is called the state will eventually be updated.
Do you have thoughts that say that favorite color become blue when that state gets updated render will
be invoked when renderers invoked will render a new view.
So are Domville get updated.
We'll talk more about this later on.
But the main takeaway is whenever set state gets invoked renderer will eventually get invoked and will
change the DOM with whatever the new value of state is.
That's it for this video.
Now before we talk about more state concepts we need to take a step back and talk about a functional
programming concept in order to understand set state better.
So the next section will talk about pure functions and what it means for a function to be pure.