Write so we're about halfway done with our back end.
Our users can be created and log in what we want to start doing now is adding the idea of a message
for each individual user.
So what we're going to do is create a message model and I've already made a message not just inside
of here.
If you don't have that that's totally fine.
Just go make one.
We're going to bring in mongoose.
We've seen this before.
Remember buyer mongoose.
But this time we are also going to bring in our user model.
We may be wondering why are we bringing in our user model.
That is because we want to make every message have a reference to the user who created it.
We're also going to go back in our user model and add a property that refers to all of the messages
for that specific user.
But let's start with a message first.
This scheme is going to be a little bit shorter.
This is a message schema.
And as a new Mangu schema this is an object right here with all of our fields.
We're going to have really simply just some text.
This is going to be a type of string we're going to make sure that it's required though we don't want
any empty messages.
And let's give this a max length of we're going to be fancy will be 160 characters.
We then want to make a reference to every user for that message.
We could call this whatever we'd like but I'm going to be calling it user.
And it is a type of a mongoose schema types object Paty.
This is specifically just an object ID or a unique identifier for some user.
But what's really important here is that it is a reference to the user model.
You may be wondering well what happens if you just put a lowercase you are called something else.
Everything's actually going to break.
This capital user right here is exactly what we named our model.
You have to make sure those match up.
Otherwise you can have a whole bunch of issues.
What else do we want inside of here.
Well we're going to make a message that's going to be a mongoose model call message and will pass in
our message schema and then we'll make sure that we export out
our message.
So if we say that that should work out well let's head over to my server and you may have seen this
already but actually use Mago Klein is no longer necessary in mongoose 5 and up please remove it.
So if you're not using mongoose 5 and up you will actually have to put in that use Mongo client.
This is something that's actually relatively new.
So inside of my index Yes I'm actually going to take this part out.
This is something I've been doing previously but mongoose 5 has now not needed it anymore so I can quickly
restart the server.
And here's what I have right here.
So if you saw that error message if you're using mongoose 4 and under.
Just make sure you have this huge Mongo kind of true.
That's something I've been doing for a while but mongoose has changed.
So we don't need it anymore.
That would just remove a nice little warning in the server.
So what I want to do next.
Back in our message schema is think about the relationship between messages and users.
So in my user model I want to make sure that every user has a reference to all of its messages and instead
of this just being an object this is actually going to be an array.
It's going to be an array of object IDs.
Once again we're going to have that type mongoose schema types object id and a ref to message.
Now you maybe be wondering here well wait a minute how come we don't have to pass an message right here.
And the answer is actually because it is all being exploited for us right here.
We'll bring in our message and pass in message by exporting these out all together the message model
is able to be accessed by the user.
But we have to pass in that user to the message model.
So if we save this we should be able to start creating messages.
But there is something that's pretty important when we create these messages.
What I want to think about is what happens when we delete a message when we delete a message we don't
just want to remove that specific message.
We also have to go to the users messages list or array and remove that specific I.D..
So just to review we've made a list of messages for every user that refers to an individual message
ID and for each message we have a user that it refers to.
But we need to add one more thing inside of our schema.
We're going to add a pre remove hook and this is going to be once again another azing function that
accepts next.
And what is the purpose of this remove hook.
Well we need to find a user.
We need to remove the ID of the message from their messages list and then we need to save that user
and return next.
So this is important because we don't want a situation where we delete a message but a user still has
that idea of the message that could break things in our API.
So we are going to first find a user.
But remember we're dealing with an easing function.
So we have to wrap everything with a try catch call this ear error ever you'd like just keeping it real
simple.
So we need to find a user.
How do we find the user.
What makes some variable for that call that user.
That's the result of user defined by id this user ID.
And this refers to the specific document if you'd like to try to make this an arrow function.
Things are actually going to break because we do need the correct value of the keyword this.
We don't want something outside.
So I'm just giving it simple using the function.
Next thing we want to do is remove that ID from the list and this is done using the Remove method.
This is a mongoose method that is completely synchronous.
This is just like splicing a specific value from a list.
We then want to save that user so we can weight saving of that user and then return next.
And if anything goes wrong at this entire time you've seen this before.
We return next with that.
And this is going to be important because when we create our messages we want to make sure that we populate
the list of messages for that user.
And when we remove a message we want to make sure that is removed from the users list.
We'll see this in action when we start actually creating some messages.
Let's do that in the next week.