High in this section we're going to learn about a very popular front in library called reac react was
created by Facebook.
It started out on the web but it's also been used for many other purposes like mobile applications and
virtual reality.
We'll start out with the fundamentals react including GSX components prop's state and component lifecycle
methods.
Next we'll talk about more advanced concepts like the re-act router redux and authentication.
By the end of the Course you'll be a re-act expert.
You may be wondering why we chose react over other printed frameworks like angular puji Yes.
Well there are a few reasons.
First react has a very strong community of developers who make many useful open source packages.
Secondly I personally really enjoy programming re-act After you master the basics Riak becomes very
easy to use.
I think you're going to enjoy it as well.
So let's get started.