Before we get into events and react let's take a step back and talk a little bit about the virtual Dom.
So the objectives for this section are going to be to describe the virtual Dom define a synthetic event
and describe changes that are happening in the new version of react react 16 so the virtual d'armes
the data structure stored by re-act that tracks changes from one render state to the next render state.
And if something is changed from one renders the next the browsers Dom will be updated.
So essentially what this means is that Riak keeps track of all the changes you make when set state is
called and then it decides how to change the DOM based on what happens to the virtual Dom.
So the process of reconciliation sort of in a visual way looks like this.
Let's say we have an app and inside of that app component we have three instr. components.
Now some said State happens and let's say we remove one of the instructors.
So after that remove all the virtual Dom will get change from the version on the left to the version
on the right.
And because of that change there's a component in the actual Dom the browser's Dom that needs to be
taken out so that re-act component needs to be unmounted that process to figure out what changes happened
and what what needs to be updated and the DOM is called reconciliation and reconciliation is one of
the awesome features of react.
You don't have to worry about the details of updating the dog every time you want change something you
just describe the changes you want to make in a declarative way.
So you go from one state to another state and then react figures out how to make those changes happen
in the DOM re-act also provides the concept of synthetic events and synthetic events are similar to
browser events all the same synthetic events exist as made of browser events.
But the main difference with synthetic events and browser events are that the synthetic event API is
the same across any browser synthetic event essentially smooths out all those API differences and makes
it one uniform API.
Now if you want access to the native event you can still get that.
But I've never had to do that in code so I don't think it will be high on your priority list.
OK so let's talk a little bit about reac 16.
The update is known as fiber because that's the name for the new reconciliation engine that's coming
in re-act 16.
So there's a couple user visible features in re-act 16.
One of them which I think is pretty nice is the ability to return GSX elements as an array or as just
a string from a random method.
So in this example below there's a render method and typically in re-act 15 and before you can do this
you couldn't return an array of multiple elements you always had to return one high level component
and then put all your components inside that and oftentimes what you ended up having to do is create
extra wrappers just to make a certain render work but no longer and re-act 16 you can now return arrays
Another new feature and re-act 16 is this air boundary feature.
Dan AdMob the creator of redux and now an employee at Facebook created a blog post about air boundaries
which is a new feature and we act 16 I would say read that it will do a much better job of explaining
it than I would.
It looks like this so you can isolate components in your application with an air boundary and definitely
read up more on that in this blog post.
Lastly I want to say re-act 16 includes fiber and fiber is the new reconciliation engine in react now.
There won't be many API level changes because of fiber so the majority of re-act is exactly the same
between 15 and 16 as far as the API is concerned.
But there are some really cool new abilities that Riak now has because of the fiber rendering engine.
So I would I would suggest watching this YouTube video to learn more about that than Clark has a great
talk at the last reac come about fiber and I think its a really approachable toxo definitely worth checking
out.
That's it for this one.
Next up we'll talk about events.