All right welcome back.
So before we can dive into code for we can start writing our own requests.
We need to address this Zemo.
What's the deal with that.
So I've mentioned a couple of times that it's a bit of a misnomer Asynchronous JavaScript and SML because
something has replaced SML that something is called Jason.
So this video we're going to talk about X-amount.
And Jason what are they.
What's the difference.
How do we use them.
All right.
So let's get going.
Essentially they're both data formats.
So this is a portion of the diagram a much larger diagram from the previous lecture that really honed
in on the important stuff the requests and responses.
So it's really all about here this little part of the diagram.
When the server and API responds with data in this case Pinterest data to produce the new pins so that
contains information probably like an A you are Alpher images for each pin number of times people have
saved it a caption or whatever they call it a date.
The person who posted that pin probably a bunch of other information that I'm missing.
But those are the big things for each pin.
So all that data maybe 20 pin to the time 10 pins has to be sent back from the server to our javascript
so that it can be added to the page.
And the question is What does that data actually look like.
How is it sent.
That's where data formats come in.
So we're used to things like Tim.
As a developer that's what we work with that is a way of formatting data of representing it.
But the problem with him in this context is that it's T.M. encodes structure.
So for example if I go to read it's outcome Here's the home page.
Hopefully there's nothing wildly inappropriate on here today.
And if I inspect the HMO view source can see this.
Each team is crazy bloated for the amount of information that is actually on the page 90 percent of
this structure metadata all the stuff that we don't actually care about.
If all we want is the pure data for example to look at a list of subsets.
If you're familiar with that take a look at this right here.
So we have funny and random.
We have asked Reddit today and world news and for each one.
There's all this stuff around it spell and a tag with a span the age raft class all the stuff lies that's
cluttering it that's necessary to style it and to structure it on a page.
But if we just want the pure information we don't need that.
So that's where data formats come in.
It does exist to share information between computers or between bits of code rather than humans.
So the structure the style none of that matters.
So instead formats like SML and Jason are used and the API that we use today and we'll use in this course
are almost all son and we'll talk about why.
But I also wanted to add that later in the course we'll be making our own API is using node create our
own backend and we'll actually write Ajax requests to our own API that also responds with Jaison.
And that's a really common thing to make a single page app using things like react or angular.
Having a JS on backend or JS on API on your back end.
But we're getting ahead of ourselves.
So let's start diving into the details of X-amount first.
So X-amount has been around a long time.
It looks very similar to HD mail but rather than encoding a page structure it just encodes information
and relationships between data.
So here's a potential way of representing a little bit of info from Pinterest.
So I'm calling it a pin.
And then inside of that each pin has a title and top of Maine Coon it has an author Cindy S..
And number of saves some saves that I called 8900.
So as you can see we have these opening and closing tags and you can basically put whatever you want
there to HVM L is like a more specific version of Zemo.
That doesn't mean that they work the same way like this won't render anything on a page.
These are meaningless to the browser.
It's just a way for us to represent data.
So again similar in syntax it's very very different no presentation.
So this used to be very popular.
It's still used occasionally but it's been replaced it's been usurped by another format called Jason.
So Jason which stands for javascript object notation looks like this.
So the same exact information represented in a different way.
You can trace on where we have key value pairs and it essentially looks like javascript objects pretty
much exactly like Javascript.
So you can see we have you know pin colon and then a javascript object with curly braces.
And then instead of that we have curly we have key value pairs title string adorable Maine Coon author
is a string Cindy S none numb saves is the number 18:00.
So the same data represented in two different ways.
X-amount the old way Jaison kind of the new ish way.
It's not cutting edge or anything but it is more popular now.
And the reason for that is just that javascript is more popular.
And so as Ajax rose as more people started to make requests from javascript Jaison started to be the
format of choice because if you're working with javascript it's so much easier to parse to process the
data coming back from an API if it's Jaison it's in the name javascript object notation.
So it's very similar as you can see it's javascript doesn't require much work on our end to get that
into actual Javascript code.
VS This is very different than javascript syntax and if we wanted to turn that into something we could
use in javascript it's not impossible there's libraries that do it.
It's not actually that hard but it's harder definitely than this.
This is much simpler much more similar to Javascript.
So the last thing we'll do is take a look at the redit Jaison.
So I'm at Reddit dot com slash dot Jaison so that dot Jay sun changes the format and we get Jason.
That's not a trick you can do to every site.
That's just how it is set up.
So there's still a lot of info here.
But if we look at it first of all it's a wall of massive text.
It's not very easy to digest compared to what we see when we just go to read it does come but that doesn't
matter.
This isn't made for human eyes but if we look at it we have things like where can I find approved by
Noal over 18 false domain giftie cat hidden false key value pairs.
It's javascript object notation.
I should mention if you don't have a Chrome extension or whatever browser you use Chrome or Firefox
idealy there are chrome extensions that will pretty fly and make Jaison much easier to read and to interact
with.
So I'm going to just go and install one.
I uninstalled it just for this video.
I always have this installed.
So add to Chrome extension now it's there and if I just refresh the page you'll see takes a second to
kick in.
But now we have this nice interactive piece on page where I can condense things explore how things are
related.
So I highly recommend that you install that just as we started to work for data even if it's not this
crazy complex.
It still is very very useful to be able to actually see the structure of your code or that Jason.
All right.
So that's a very brief intro to Jason as well as X-amount Asynchronous JavaScript and Jason is really
what's used these days for the most part.
But a judge just doesn't have quite the same ring as Ajax.
So even though people say Ajax typically it's actually a Jag these days.
All right.
On that note let's get to the next video where we'll actually learn how to make our first request.
Our first adj request.