Hey there we'll welcome back.
So we've seen a ton of different properties.
Learned a lot about flex box.
It's time that we put some of it together to make a nice little exercise.
So what you're going to do here is actually solve an age old web developer layout problem.
It's been plaguing developers for a long time.
It's called the Holy Grail layout.
In fact it's such a common problem or it's so commonly problematic to make.
There's an entire Wikipedia page devoted to it which I've included in the resources.
Basically the idea is this you have a header and footer the top and bottom of the page.
The width doesn't really matter.
Let's just say the exact same dimensions.
But then between the two you have three columns of equal height regardless of the content as you can
see the content is of different height.
You know the ADD thing goes about halfway.
The main stuff in the middle goes almost all the way down.
So they take up the same amount of space regardless and that's what causes problems with outflux box.
Traditionally there's been a lot of ways of approximating this or of achieving it but with some drawbacks.
So here's a common solution using floats and a cleared footer down here but this doesn't work well if
your content is not exactly the same height.
We can have them start at the same you know the flush up top but their backgrounds won't line up.
If the content is not exactly the same height and that's a problem.
Same with the footer.
It floats upwards.
So there's ways around it.
There's an entire section down here that talks about known work arounds.
So sometimes people will use tables sort of an older way of doing it using tables for layout or using
photo columns I've never actually seen this but I heard about this by reading the article that I guess
people would take a background image and make the entire body have the same background image where the
columns would be colored into the background and then the content on top is transparent.
So it looks like there's columns and rows behind it that have corresponding colors.
The problem with that of course is making it responsive is basically impossible.
And one other problem with some of the work arounds using a table for example or using a lot of nested
divs and floating things is that your markup becomes very convoluted difficult to understand.
So what we actually have here if you look at the basic content in a perfect world we would just have
a couple of sections maybe inside a header and footer and that's pretty much it in our markup.
But if we're using floats or a table we have to add all these weird table elements in their TVs and
all these different table things that really clutter our markup and have no meaning.
They're just there to help as a work around with the layout.
Same with floats and that makes it very inaccessible to screen readers and also to whatever you know
Google or whatever algorithm is crawling across your site and trying to parse it for meaning.
So that's obviously a big problem as well.
So the workaround is to use fluxbox which is where you come in.
So here's what I'd like you to make.
Let's be clear the colors don't matter.
The rounded corners the padding the margin none of that matters all that we really care about.
So you have a head or a top and a footer.
Then in between we have a row that consists of three columns of equal height regardless of the content
inside.
And along with that you want to make sure that the main container the middle section is larger.
Now I wouldn't worry about getting it to look exactly like this with the exact proportions but if you
are curious this is 60 percent and these two take up 20 percent and yes you can use percentages with
flex bases.
So that's a bit of a hint.
But again that doesn't really matter if it vaguely resembles these proportions.
That's fine.
I'll also point out this should be at least 800 pixels.
So how can you specify that at least eight hundred pixels tall from here to here not the entire body
just this main section this section this section.
OK.
So then how does it respond or how is it responsive.
Here is what it should do.
So as you shrink it things shrink down the main content stays larger.
But then we hit the 640 pixel breakpoint and everything should stack.
But not only that.
Notice the order changes.
So it used to be that the side now was first then the main content and the aside.
Now the main content is first and the side now of a second and the aside is third.
So make sure that that happens so that the main content becomes the first thing after the never top.
And the only other thing I'll point out this top nav I added in another bit of complexity where there's
enough left in nav right.
So basically something should always be on the left something is always on the right.
They come closer together but nothing changes.
They just stay like that.
Let me show you what I mean.
Here's the solution as I shrink it down.
Notice how things respond.
And then I hit a break point right here and we're stuck with a larger thing of main content to smaller
navs and then the footer don't worry so much about the sizes of these.
Just make sure the main content is largest and also that comes first after the nut for the header.
So there's started code for this.
Let me show you what it looks like.
You do not need to touch this.
So all you have is a header with now left and nav right.
So that should be here and here.
Then we have our main which is that middle row.
So this here all three things inside of it.
There's an article a Nav. and an aside and notice that the main content comes first by default.
Here it's second.
So you'll need to reorder that.
And it makes sense to have it come first is the most important thing.
It's kind of annoying if you have your advertizements first in the markup.
So Flex box allows you to put the most important content up top make it easier for screen readers to
access.
OK.
And then at the end there's a footer so a couple of things I'll point out there is no container around
all of this except for the body.
So you'll need to work with the body to make sure that everything is inside a flex container.
All right.
So give that a shot if you have questions you can consult the specs but remember you don't have to make
everything match perfectly.
Colors shapes borders any of that.
That doesn't matter.
Just focus on the rough shapes the rough areas and making sure you get the idea.
And that reminds me of one other thing I want to point out.
I was trying to think of a good example to show you of a holy grail lay out in the wild and I found
a bunch of Web sites but I didn't think any of them were that commonly used.
And then I was going to listen to some music and right in front of me.
This is spotify if you don't use it you're not familiar.
Here is what I use to listen to music.
But here's a perfect textbook Holy Grail layout.
So we have a nav bar up here.
Right there.
Then we have our left kind of side nav in our right side.
We have a footer and then we have our main content.
So the proportions are a bit different but here is a very typical layout involving the holy grail.
So I just wanted to throw that in there prove that this is a real thing I'm not totally making it up.
Go ahead give it a shot in the next video.
We'll have a solution.