All right.
So we saw how to write ts s transitions we saw the syntax.
The four main properties as well as the shorthand version we haven't really discussed performance.
There's actually two things you haven't discussed.
What are the properties that can be transitioned.
Are there things that cannot be transitioned.
Yes.
And then also what should be transitioned and what I mean there is you know what are the things that
are the fastest the most performant to transition and what things are a nuisance can cause performance
issues if you're transitioning them.
So we're going to answer those two questions in this very quick video.
So the first thing what can be transitioned.
Here's the official list pretty long.
So there's a bunch of things on here some of which we've already worked with like background color transform
we've seen things like border radius Forder with all these things that we've seen before.
So as you can see there's quite a large list of properties.
These are the things that can be transitioned but it's not a complete list of all CSSA properties.
So there are things that cannot be transitioned at all.
But then there's this second question which is what are the things that make sense to transition what
will not affect your Web site performance very much to transition.
And that list is much much shorter.
It's actually just four key properties.
Now again this is not a hard rule.
There are certain situations when you'll need to do things like background color or perhaps something
that's you know on this list that doesn't make it into these four properties but these four are kind
of a standard set of properties that are recommended to animate or transition and that you should try
to stick to these.
If you're concerned about performance.
So if you're doing your own personal project a web page for yourself or maybe a demonstration page or
some sort of art project whatever it is you know feel free to use any of these.
But if you work at a company or you're starting a big app and you're concerned about the performance
of your animations perhaps you'll have 10 20 30 100 different things on the page that could be transitioning
at any given time.
Or you're worried about mobile performance how these animations perform on iOS or Android phones and
the web browsers.
Then you should try to stick to these four.
And these four don't just come out of nowhere.
There's actually a reason for them.
One there are a bunch of articles talking about them which I'll show you to.
I've talked to a couple different people who work at different companies.
I want them to get a feel for what their internal rules were about using transitions and what the animator
will properties where and from both companies to reasonably large 100 plus person San Francisco startups.
They said the exact same for properties transform.
So translate scale and rotate as well as opacity.
So where is this coming from.
Well underlying all of this here's a great article that kind of details it including the resources it's
from a Web site called Timofei rocks but it actually talks about why these four properties can be animated
cheaply or easily and why all those other properties for a couple different reasons are slower or less
performant and it has to do with how a browser actually renders a web page.
So this could be a much longer video.
This could be an entire course actually at my previous job.
We created a four or five hour course just about browser rendering and performance.
So this is going to be a real really quick crash course in it.
But basically there's a couple of different stages that go into the rendering of any web page.
So there's things like calculating the styles that apply to elements generating the position for where
certain things should be.
So that includes things like with higher margin left top.
Then we move on and there's this paint set up stage you don't need to worry about that.
But then the paint actually happens this is when pixels are actually filled out or colored in for each
element.
So that's things like background border radius bhakt shadow which makes sense.
And then finally there's what's called composite layers and that's things like transform and opacity.
So these four.
So notice that those come at the very very end.
So for those to change it doesn't require much work.
It doesn't have to go through this entire process again.
But if you are trying to animate something like let's say with or margin then what is going to happen
is what's kind of called a waterfall.
Basically it requires more work.
The entire process starts over here in the lay out changing means that things have to be repainted and
so on.
So it kind of creates this cascade effect.
So what you want to do if at all possible.
And again this is only if you're really concerned about performance is stick to transform and opacity.
And with those properties you can actually achieve a lot.
Most of the animations that you see on popular large web sites they have tons of animations going on
you know small little interactive effects but they're usually done with just transform scale transform
translate transform rotate and opacity.
So you can do a lot with those.
OK.
So that kind of wraps it up I recommend you check out this article if you want to know more about how
the render process works in your browser.
If you want to go into more detail about things like lay out or paint in the different stages.
But for now just keep that in mind.
It's definitely not a hard rule but it's just worth knowing that it's out there and that there's a reason
that these four properties are in general recommended across the web development community for your
animations.
All righty.
I think that's a pretty good place to stop.
To wrap up our discussion on C as.