Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be going over a few useful object and Array methods that yes 2015 gives
us a common problem you may encounter and Javascript is dealing with making copies of objects because
we can't simply assign one to another.
Let's see what happens if we do that.
Or make an object called over and give it a key of name and a value of L.D..
Now make a new variable 0 2 and assign it to the 0 object.
Now let's change the name property on the O2 object and set it to the string.
Tim if we take a look at our original variable we can see the name has changed.
That's because when we assign one object to another we are just assigning a reference and not creating
a brand new object.
Thankfully as 2015 gives us a really easy way to create objects using the object that assign method
object that assign accepts a series of objects and will return a new object with the keys and values
for all the objects passed to it.
It's important to note that if you don't start with an empty object object outside will still keep a
reference to another object included in it.
So if you want to make a copy without a reference Be sure to put in an empty object as the first parameter.
The object assigned another gotcha with object or a sign is that it does not create a deep clone.
So if there are objects inside of the object that you're copying those references will still be there.
You can see here that the instructor's key in our object O can still be changed from the 0 to variable.
If you need a deep clone you can write your own function or use different data structures or popular
libraries like load ASH.
You will see object out assign quite a bit with libraries like react and redux.
So it's a very helpful method to know.
Now let's take a look at another useful method that as 2015 gives us called a radar from which allows
us to easily convert an array like object into an array.
You might be wondering what an array like object is and you've actually seen quite a few of them.
When you use methods like document that get elements by tag name or document that query after all or
when you use J query to select elements from the DOM or use the arguments keyword.
What is returned to you looks like an array but it does not have all of the array methods like.
Push.
Pop slice for each map and so on.
Let's see what we mean by that.
Here we have a variable called divs which is the result of getting all the divs on the page.
If we try to access the reduce method on it we get undefined because the divs variable is not actually
an array.
It's an array like object to convert this object into an array.
We use the slice method along with the call method so that we could set the target of what we want to
slice as the array like object.
Once we do that we can access Array methods on the converted array like object.
Although that code works it's a bit complex and as 2015 gives us an easier way to do that with a radar
from.
Notice that the from method is invoked directly on the array function.
This is another example of a static method array up from accepts of value and converts it into an array.
If possible a tradeoff from works with strings maps sets an array like objects.
Here we can easily convert an array like object and in the second example we can convert a set into
an array.
You'll find yourself doing this if you need to remove duplicates but then want an array return to it
in the next video we're going to discuss a few more useful methods that yes 20:15 gives us the event.