Already.
So this video will be super quick.
I just want to talk about browser support for fluxbox.
So in the past this has been the main problem with fluxbox.
When people don't want to use it it's not because they don't like how it works.
The fact that it works and how it works is the selling point.
The problem in the past has been that it's not well or hasn't been well supported.
However if you look at can I use dot com right now and we look for flex you can see it's fully supported
across all modern browsers currently without any prefixes.
However in Internet Explorer if you can can make that bigger.
It does say partial support only because is a large amount of bugs so it still is supported fully without
prefixes.
But there might be some bugs if I click show all you can see it has a rather lackluster history going
back.
There was a lot of yellows and reds.
So it was not supported in IEEE at all until 10.
Same thing here with mobile.
Safari has been a problem in the past.
So you can see here.
The other thing I should mention is that specification has changed over time.
So if you did want to add backwards compatibility for old versions of Safari that say I'll zoom back
in for Safari 3.1.
It says only supports the old flex box spec and does not support wrapping.
So you'll have to use prefixes like Web Kit.
In this case but on top of that the syntax is actually different.
Here's an example of some old flex box that I found.
There's different property names.
For example instead of display flex its display box instead of wrap you have multiple boxed lines.
We have box dash flex vertical align there's a couple of different things that just box pack.
There's another one.
So those don't exist anymore in the current browsers.
My advice to you would be it depends really on what you're doing.
But in 99 percent of the sites that my students make and their audience most of the time they only need
to worry about modern browsers and maybe a version or two back.
There's no reason that I can't think of a reason that you need a portfolio site or something like that
that supports ideate for example.
But if you do want to do that I've included an article that I like.
There's two of them actually.
One is called mixing old and new.
For the best browser support for using Fluxbox mixing old and new.
So this talks about how if you wanted to support as many old browsers as possible you will have to support
the old flex box and tax that has changed over time.
And there are some strategies for that here.
But another option is this article here that talks about how do you deal with browsers that don't support
it so old ones let's say ideate What do you do.
So you can have no fall back and your site will just look however it looks you know on an old browser
like this one here I hate actually without fluxbox because those styles don't apply but you can also
add in different fallbacks or alternative solutions.
And this article goes into it.
If that's something you care about so you can use C S S or javascript to create a fallback.
Basically you write code that will be using Fluxbox and then backup code when there is no flex box detected.
So again if you want more information check this out.
So to summarize you do not need prefixes for any of the current versions of browsers.
That's a big deal but if you do want to support older browsers and older versions you need prefixes.
And just to be safe you can always use the auto prefix or so we could do something like
let's get rid of this here and we can do display Flack's for example or justify content center and you
can see what we end up with over here.
So you could use that there's no harm in that.
But the good news is if you're only worried about current browsers you don't have to worry about any
of this at all.
OK.
So that wraps it up.
Things have come a long way for fluxbox.
The future is looking bright.
Oh my gosh.