All right.
So before we dive into the code itself let's take a moment to talk about our game plan.
Let's outline what we're going to build and we'll start off by talking about the structure of our data
and our database.
So we're making a simple simple app and there's three things that we really care about.
For each to do we have a name.
So that's the text the whatever walk the dog by milk.
Bake a cake.
We have completed which is going to be a simple true or false.
And then we have a created date which are not really using but it's good to add into their.
It's a common thing you want in an API.
So a created date which is a date itself.
So a string of bullion and a date.
So I have a bunch of to do's in our database then the endpoints that we want for RJC on API that we
could request with Ajax requests.
Are these five.
So the first point is slash API slash to do is actually GET request and that will just list all of our
to do.
So if I come over here and I go to that URL you'll see we get a list of all of our dues as Jason.
So we have the name created date be completed as well as an ID which is generated by Mongo when we insert
into the database.
So we'll get to that then we have the create a new to do route which is a post request sent to slash
API slash to Dewes.
So I won't send one of those just yet.
But when we hit enter here it's sending a post request to that you know where she can view in our network
tab.
One more.
There it is.
If we look at this it is a post sent to slash API slash to deuce.
So I won't go through every single one and actually make the request but then we need a way to view
an individual to do which we're not actually using inside of our application.
But it's a traditional route to have in an API and then we have the update to do route which is API
slash to do and then the idea of the to do that we're going to update and add to put request in the
same you or L as a delete request will delete that particular to do that we're specifying in the row.
So these are the five routes we're going to build.
And remember the three fields we want for each to do so without further ado let's get going.
And first we have the very best part and by very best I mean very absolute worst which is installing
everything so that we can get going with our code.
So next video we're going to install a bunch of stuff.
It's going to be mediocre.