All right I'm excited about this video we're getting in some user interaction so we'll be able to build
much more interesting components at this point.
For our objectives first will demonstrate an unclick event and then we'll use bound functions and inline
functions for callbacks.
We'll explain more when we get to that part.
First up an On Click event.
So this is a component that we've probably seen before or something similar where we've got a constructor
with super props and then substate the only state I'm keeping track of is the name and my name Tim.
And then in my render method that's where something new is going on.
So first of all I'm just displaying the names just like usual this that state name but this button below
response user clicks.
So we've added a property here for an On Click event and on click this callback function will run and
inside of this callback function we're invoking set state.
So this is pretty similar to what you've seen before in vanilla javascript where you're attaching callback
events directly to the HMO element.
And this is the correct way to do it and react if you're coming from.
Quarry or something like that where you used to grabbing the element by id and then adding a click event.
All in javascript.
That's that's not something you'll see and react.
So the way to add any type of event is to add it directly to the component that you want to add interaction
to.
Let's take a look at this in the browser.
So I've got that component loaded up here.
You can see I've got my re-act developer tools open and we've got the classic example.
Now when I click uppercase what happens.
Well this on click event is going to get invoked on click.
Remember inside we'll call this set say and change my state at some point in the future set state will
update that state.
So my name will become uppercase Tim instead of lowercase Tim.
And then whenever such state gets invoked render gets invoked again.
So after that said Say call tim will be all uppercase render will run a second time and then will render
the uppercase Tim.
So let's see that.
And you could see here my state changing as well.
Keep your eye on that.
So my state change here to uppercase Tim and then render was called an uppercase Tim was displayed.
Now let's take a look at a similar example.
Except this time rather than put the callback function inline here.
We're going to use a function as part of our class.
So this is pretty much the same example we've got some state that keeps track of my name and there's
a click event down here that gets invoked whenever you click.
But now the differences we make the click handler at a method here so it's not an inline function anymore
it's now a method as part of my class and
and I've also changed the code slightly.
So now instead of just hard coding the name Tim it uppercase is any name that it's got.
So this will work with any name not just him.
And remember this callback function inside of said State is required whenever your new state depends
on your previous state.
So in this case our new state is going to depend on whatever the previous state's name was.
And we're going to uppercase it.
I want to show this example because the pattern that happens a lot and react inside of your component
you'll make some callback handlers here for events.
You'll put those events inside of your GSX using this dot and then the name of your method.
But then the issue becomes when this function gets invoked.
This no longer refers to your component.
Read the context of this will change and in order to prevent that from happening we want to prevent
that because we want this data set state to be referring to our component.
We have to do this in the constructor function.
So inside the constructor we're saying this doc handle klick equals this dot handle clicked up bind
this.
So now whenever handle click is invoked no matter what the context is it'll always be bound to this
and this inside of the constructor is equal to the quick example component.
So no matter what this will be the right this whenever that is invoked.
So this pattern adding this Hanno click equals the start handle clicked that bind this is a very common
one that you'll see throughout our re-act examples where we have to put a lot of callback functions
in the constructor and bind them.
Now let's look at a common mistake that people make.
It's actually just a javascript error but it happens a lot for whatever reason when people are learning
react in this On Click event.
When you add your callback everything looks normal here except there's one issue and that's that here
at the end you've actually invoke the function.
So this will invoke your function right inside the render method.
It won't wait until the on click event happens so that the note down here just says the function will
be invoked immediately not when the event happens not on the event.
So just be aware of that don't accidentally invoke your functions inside of your callback handlers.
One last point I want to make is that there's a bit of a misconception that inline aero functions lead
to a big performance hit versus using the functions that are bound in the constructor.
Now I've never actually done performance test myself so take this with a grain of salt.
But in the Riak docs it seems to indicate that there's no huge performance difference between doing
one of the other.
So feel free to use aero functions or to use bind whatever makes the most sense to you.
I'll usually use aero functions if it's a quick one liner inside of the click handler itself.
But if it's a longer function that has more than one line I'll typically break it out into a separate
function.
Ok that'll do it for events.
Next up is form's.