Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be going through the I guess the password code and break down what's happening.
This example uses vanilla javascript for dominant relation.
So if you've been working with Jake worry for a bit it's great to go back and see how it all works under
the hood.
To get started.
We're waiting for the dom to load on line 1 and then making a few variables for the number of words
and guesses that the user sees an 9:6.
We're selecting an element with an idea of start from the DOM.
This element is a button and when that button is clicked we run a function called Tondo classes and
then a function called Start game let's see what that toggle classes function does here or looping through
the arguments to this function.
But starting at the second one I noticed that var is initialized to 1.
So we ignore the first argument we then use the class list that Tuggle method which adds the class.
If it does not exist or removes the class if it does exist.
If we look at each TNL we can see Line 9 at the idea of start screen has a class of show which means
the toggle class will remove the class and show at a class of hide online 23.
We see that the idea of getting screen has a class of hide so Tuggle classes will remove the class of
hide an outer class of show.
If we take a look at RC SS We can see that the class of show adds a display of block and a class of
hide removes the height which will hide our element of Achen our HABCHI us.
Let's take a look at the start function here we're selecting an element from the DOM with an ID of wordlist
and assigning it to a variable wordlist up into that here on line 22 or using the get random values
function and passing in a word and a word count.
You might be wondering what words and word count are.
Word count is defined on line too and specifies how many words the user will see words is actually coming
from the words dot file.
So let's take a look at that and we can see it is a very large array of words.
This is a separate file which will just contain a long list of words so that each time we play the game
it will not have the same words every time.
Back in our J.S. we're using to get random values function and passing in the array of words and our
word count variable.
But what is that function doing.
If we look at 9:37 we can see that they get random values function accepts an array and then invokes
the shuffle function and then makes a copy of that array return to us the shuffle function using slice.
So what does the shuffle function doing.
If we take a look at line 41 we can see here that this function shuffles the array online 42.
We make a copy of the array so that we do not mutate or permanently change the input.
This function is actually an implementation of a famous shuffle algorithm called fishier gates.
It involves generating a random index and swapping values based on that random index.
When we're done looping we return the copied and shuffled array.
So are get random values function will shuffle an array and then make a copy of the shuffled array with
a number of elements equal to our word count variable.
I count mine 23.
We have a variable called random words which is a shuffled array of random words will iterate over each
value in the array and create a list item and give it the text of whatever word we are iterating over
in the array.
Finally on line 26 we append that list item to the word list element which in our h t l is a UL or an
ordered list element.
All right.
We're more than halfway through.
You might be a bit confused now but reading other people's code is what professional developers do all
the time.
It's rare that you're the only developer and are writing things from scratch in a professional environment.
So reading and understanding other people's code is just as important if not more important than writing
your own so far we're listening for a click on a button.
And when that happens we hide and show some elements shuffle a random list of words and append those
words to the page as list items on line 30.
We're assigning the value of our password variable which we defined online for.
Its value is the result of the get random values function which we saw before.
Here we're picking one of the random words as the password for the user to guess on line 31.
We're invoking the set guest count function and passing in the guest count variable which we to find
on line three as the number of guesses.
A user gets a what does the set guess count function do.
Let's see on line 55 here.
We're simply changing the text of the element with an ID of guesses remaining to be the number of guesses
that the user has left.
Finally back on 9:34 we add an event listener for a click on the wordlist element and when a user clicks
on the wordlist we run a function called up the game.
Notice that we're adding this event listener to the entire element and not to each allied element to
be more efficient.
So what does the function do.
What's the on line 60 what's going on here.
We're first checking to make sure that the target of the event which is a click is a list item.
And if that list item we clicked does not have a class of disabled on line 63 we store the text of the
list item in a variable and on line 64 we invoke the compare words function for the word and the password
variable which we define online 30.
We can see on line 80 that the compare words function.
First make sure the length of the two words being shared are the same.
We are using the throw keyword since we want an error to occur.
If this is happening we wouldn't want the user trying to change things.
The rest of the function starting on line 82 involves creating a count variable and looping through
the word.
We have guests to see how many letters it has in common with another word.
This function returns the number of letters that are similar for each word and we store that in a very
well on line 64 called similarity score on line 65.
We make sure to add the class of disabled to the list item we just clicked.
Since we don't want that same list item to be clicked again and counted as another guess on the next
line we let the user know how many matching letters there are and then subtract one from the number
of guesses they have.
Hamline 70.
We have some logic to check and see if the game has ended.
If the similarity score which is the result of the compare word's function is the same as the length
of the password variable which is a string.
We remove the class of hide and add the class of show to the element with an ID of winner.
And then we remove the event listener which updates the game since it has ended.
Online 73 we're checking to see if there are no guesses remaining.
And if so we remove the class of hide and add the class of show to the element with an ID of loser and
remove the event listener which updates the game since it has ended.
Notice we're using the keyword this which refers to the entire unordered list where the event listener
is being placed.
That was quite a bit of code to read through but the more practice you get with these kinds of exercises.
The faster you're going to be able to get up to speed in a professional environment which is so important
your assignment now is a factor in this code using what we've learned with.
Yes 2015.
See where you can add let and Konst if all parameters and use the rest and spread operator aero functions
restructuring and more in the next video.
We'll see what we can refactor.
Good luck.