So let's get started building the back end for our warbler application.
And we've had a lot of conversation on the team as to what should we do this on cloud nine.
And you have a lot of feedback from all of you which has really helped us determine that we're just
going to do this locally.
So instead of worrying about a cloud nine set up which has been a bit of a hassle I'm going to be building
this all locally.
So these sections are going to rely on an understanding of using the terminal.
And if you're a bit shaky on that please ask us or check out quite a few other courses are new to me.
We do want to let you know this is an advanced course so we do expect a bit of knowledge around being
comfortable in the terminal.
So let's get started making a new application on a directory and I'll call this warbler and ICD into
that directory and inside of here I'm going to make two separate folders one for the server and one
for the client.
And what we're going to focus on just right now is server side code.
So let's see into warbler server.
If you look inside here there's not much.
So what kind of files do I need.
Well I'm going to start a node application I'm probably going to want to start with a package Jason
so I'm going to NPM it and this is going to give me quite a bit of options.
I can press enter and enter and enter.
Do you ever get tired of pressing enter.
You can always run NPM in it dash Y and that will create a package just on for you with some sensible
defaults.
So inside of here this looks pretty good so far I can go in and edit this if I'd like but what I really
want to start doing is installing some modules that I'm going to need throughout this application.
Now if I take a look at the version of note that I'm using and using version 9 which means that when
I install modules I do not have to add the dash Dessie flag.
If you're using an older version of node you want to make sure you're using this so that your dependencies
are saved to your package Jason.
So what modules are we going to need.
Well this whole thing is going to be powered by express.
What else we're going to need to be Crit. module for password hashing.
We're going to need body parser so that we can make post requests and extract data from them.
So what else are we going to need about mongoose.
We are going to be using Gees on web tokens so we're also going to need the Giese on web token module.
We're also in need to spell that correctly first and then we'll install the cores module and Corps's
the idea of cross origin resource sharing.
There's a really important security policy on the web which states that you can't run javascript from
one domain to another.
And that's really so that we can't inject any kind of malicious javascript from one site to another
in order to bypass this.
One of the most common ways of doing that is by enabling something called Cross origin.
Resource sharing or cores you'll hear developers talk a lot of the time oh I'm having cores issues and
what that really means is that they're struggling overcoming the same origin policy.
It's very very restrictive and I'll actually link to it in the notes if you want to read a little bit
more about it.
But what we're going to tell our server to do is to send headers in the response that notify the browser
that it can actually allow for a cross origin request.
And when we start working on the client side we'll actually see what this code looks like.
So what else do we need.
We have expressed secret body parts or mongoose some token cores that looks good for now.
It's very possible that I'm missing one but that's OK when we need it we'll get it.
And there's actually one that I just thought of the need and we're going to see what that is in a second.
And we start talking about security and secret keys.
But for now I think this is OK.
So once these are installed we need to think a little bit about our folder structure and we're going
to need some pretty important files.
I'm going make a file called indexed objects and this file is going to be responsible for starting my
server.
I'm also going to make a couple folders and then make one for my routes one for my models one for my
middleware and another for my handlers.
Now you've traditionally maybe put all of your code inside of your routes but what we're going to do
is we are going to use a folder called handlers and handlers are going to be all of the functions that
we pass to opt out route or apt get.
We'll see what this looks like in a little bit.
But this is a structure that's going to allow us to skil this application much easier with Express which
is a minimalist framework.
You really have a lot of flexibility about your folder structure.
So just remember this is one pattern of building express applications.
Let's take a look at what I have so far.
This looks pretty good.
Knowing you to actually start writing some code in my index genius and all we're really going to do
is write a little bit of code to start the server and using Visual Studio code.
But you can use whatever text editor you like.
So inside of our index day yes we're going to start by bringing in some important modules.
I'm going to bring in Express.
Let's say that Express is going to be the result of the Express module.
We're also going to invoke that express function and this is what is important this is a very common
pattern that you've seen with a bunch of express apps.
We're also going to bring in the course module.
So we're going to bring in cores and that's once again going to be required cores and a lot of this
we really could just give you the boilerplate code but I really want to build this from scratch and
talk about each part of the application that we're building.
What else do we need.
Well we're going to start with a port and here is just a variable.
We'll put that on 1881.
Why not.
Must be something fun.
What we're going to tell our application to use is the cores model.
We're also going to tell our application to use a body parser but in this case we're not going to do
that.
You are all encoded that you might have seen before or since we're building an API Fergies body parser
Jaison.
And that's very important.
Well I want to build a very simple error handler.
And what does that look like.
I'm going to specify all my routes over here.
They will come later.
But if none of those routes are reached what I'd like to do is tell my application to run a function
with something wreck rez RAZ And next you might have not seen next before but next is a very important
parameter It's the third parameter to these callback functions that we're going to see.
We also call these functions handlers and what next allows us to do is move to the next piece of middleware.
This is very important for error handling so that we can bubble up our error with no there are lots
of functions and asynchronous actions and debugging node issues when you're not handling errors properly
is really not fun.
And since we want to build this to be a bit more of a production application we don't really want to
do things like throw or console that log because we would want our application to continue.
But in this case this is going to be for a 4.
0 4.
So we'll make a variable call there.
It's going to be a new error errors a built in function or constructor function in javascript and this
just says not found.
Make sure that quotes match up and then we will set the status of this error to be 4 or 4.
You've seen these before when you visit the page and you go to some route and that route doesn't exist.
That's all we got when I'm going to do then is call next with that specific error.
So what I'd like to do right now is simply listen on a port and then I'd like to run a function and
all we're going to do here is say that the server is starting on a certain port and I'm going to be
using a lot of years 2015 in this application.
So I'm going to start with some template string's server starting on port and whatever the variable
of our port is treated that correctly.
So what have we done so far.
We brought in some important modules.
We've set the port number and we built a very small error handler.
If we were to go start this application we could do that using node indexed objects.
Now we can see how the parser is not defined.
Don't forget that one.
It looks like it.
Yes let's go make sure everybody parser is the result of requiring the parser.
Maybe you saw that if you did.
I'm glad you've fixed it for me.
Let's go run node index that.
Yes and we see that the server is starting on port 80 81.
Now if we were to make a change we would then have to go stop this server and started again.
So thankfully there is a really wonderful tool called Nordman which you can install that will keep your
server alive after any changes.
You can install that using NPM.
Install dash G gnomon.
So I'm going to start with gnomon and start the server.
But how do we know if anything's working.
Well I'm going to go over here and I'm going to simply make a request to this API.
What we're going to do is simply state Perl local host 80 81 and Kearl is a simple command line tool
that allows me to make requests and if we take a look at this right now we get this whole messy bunch
of HVM out.
We get an error that says not found.
We see all this information about the error.
What we'd really like to do is build a bit of a cleaner way to send back that information.
And since we're building an API we're going to be sending back information with J-Zone.
So in the next video we're going to take this error handler that we built.
And we're really going to clean it up.
I'll see you there.