Welcome back.
In this video we're going to continue our discussion on the class keyboard and see how to add methods
which can be used by every single object created from the class in object oriented programming.
We call these instance methods since the class creates objects or instances before 2015.
These methods and properties were traditionally placed on the prototype object.
Let's see what they used to look like.
Here we have a constructor function for a student and a method called say hello which every student
will have.
This method is placed on the prototype object of the student function which is accessible by every object
created from the student function.
When the new keyword is used if this sounds totally foreign to you make sure to watch the videos on
object oriented programming with javascript.
Now let's see what this looks like with yes 2015.
In 2015 we place our prototype methods inside of the class just like what we did with the special constructor
method.
Remember this code is just an abstraction for what we have used before.
There is nothing new going on here.
It is also far more efficient to create instance methods and to place those methods inside of the constructor.
If we place methods inside of the constructor they are redefining each time we create an object from
that class.
Now that we've seen instance methods or methods that can be accessed by objects created from the constructor
function how can we create class methods or methods directly on the constructor function and S-5 these
methods are placed directly on the constructor function.
Here I'm creating a method called student which returns true if the object passed to it has a constructor
property which is the student constructor.
You may have used a similar method like this to see if something is an array.
Notice that the array that is array method is directly on the array constructor.
This is the idea of a class method.
So how would this work in 2015 we'll see exactly how in the next video Ceara.