This video I'm going to highlight what we're calling learning paths because our curriculum so massive
covers so much we thought we should make some shortcuts to get to specific topics.
So you definitely don't have to go through everything at once.
And the first route I'd suggest is the S.M..
It's the simplest one the shortest one basically just the first three sections.
We talked about the basics of CSSA animations using keyframes as well as transitions.
Then we talked about CSSA lay out with flex fluxbox and then we build that Web site project the entire
company web site for our fictitious mountain guides.
The next suggestion is what we call the modern JSE guru.
They don't all have cute names like this but this one does.
This is basically a would be focused on picking someone who knows the basics of javascript who really
wants to get the language down.
So we talk about Asynchronous JavaScript.
You learn the basics of promises but also what's happening behind the scenes with the stack and heap
and that sort of thing.
Then we talked about object oriented programming closures the keyword this advanced Array methods testing
with jazzmen and then iest 2015 is Tony 15 part 2 is 20 16 and 17 as well as the guest to password refactor.
So this is all focused on the language itself purely on Javascript.
Next is the D-3 and SPG person.
If that's something that you're interested in getting to data visualization all you really need to focus
on are D-3 in the DOM D-3 data joint an update pattern and working with SPG intermediate D-3 advanced
graph types and building a data dashboard.
So these six sections would be where you should focus if you only care about D-3 next complete re-act
path which takes some more time to focus on concepts along the way that will make it easier to learn
react.
So you can just skip to the content.
But if you don't know some of the key concepts from 2015 like Aero functions then writing re-act might
be a little bit trickier.
It's not impossible but it will be much easier if you start with creating your own base on API section
and you go through single page maps.
It's 2015 up to 16 and 17 and then focus on the Riak content.
So that wraps it up.
We have the complete Riak path the D-3 and SPG person path the modern Jesus guru and they see us as
master.
So if none of those appeal to you there's nothing wrong with just going through the course at your own
pace going through all of it.
By all means if you want to do that just cover so much.
We figured we should give people some options.
OK.