Are right and this screencast we're going to build a small redux to do application.
We're going to do this with a query.
And then the next video we're really going to start integrating re-act into the mix.
So what we're going to do right now I'm just going to make a copy of the last application that I had
which was the redux counter.
And then I'm going to copy that into a folder called redux to use.
I'm going to UCD into redux to use and I'm just going to open this up and have one particular look at
the files that I have.
It looks a lot like my counter code.
But what I want to do now is change up this HDMI out.
And I want to change up some of that javascript but I still want to keep these three scripts right here.
So what I'm going to start off with is in an ordered list that will call to use and inside of here we're
going to start appending some list items.
But in order to do that we need a form.
So I'm going to make a form that pretty much goes nowhere and I'll give this a label.
Let me spell that correctly a label for a task a task and I will give this an input with a type of text.
We'll make sure the name is task and the idea is task.
And finally we'll just make one button that says add a to do and when we're done with it we should be
able to focus on our job script.
So let's just quickly open this up in the browser.
We shouldn't really see much here except for a little form to add a to do but we're going to do now
is work on some of the javascript here.
So we need to think about what our initial state looks like and our initial stage should be relatively
similar to what we had before.
It's going to be an object but we're going to have a property called to Dewes which starts off as some
empty array and then we're going to need a way to keep track of each to do that we create.
So I'll make a property called ID and set it to be zero.
We then want our root producer to start with some kind of initial state which looks good but let's do
this again from scratch by default we want to see what the actual type is.
So we are going to switch on the action type we could use false statements if you're more comfortable
with that.
That's totally fine.
In the case that we have had to do we are going to do something here will add to do what other situations
might we have we might want to remove or to do.
And when that happens we'll do something here or move it to do that by default.
If it's none of those let's just return whatever our state is keep it real simple for now.
Let's go back and take out some of this code that we have right here.
We're just going to start with a document ready.
And what do we need to think about with regards to our DOM manipulation.
We need to think about when the form is submitted.
We need to dispatch the ad to do action.
So how do we do that.
Well let's start with an event listener on the form.
And when that form is submitted we're going to run a function with some kind of event object.
The first thing we want to do is prevent the default.
To make sure that the page doesn't refresh so it will prevent the default here.
And then we want to think about actually grabbing what was typed in in that input.
So if you look back at our index that each TNL this has an ID task so we could say something like make
our new task to be whatever the idea of task has which is an input and it's value whatever the user
typed in.
We're then going to dispatch an action call store dispatch and what action do we want.
Well remember all of our actions have to be objects and they always have to have the key of type.
And what do we want to do here.
Well we probably want to to do.
But when we think about adding it to do we're going to want to grab whatever the user typed in.
So we're going to add another key inside of here.
We can call that task and that is going to be some new task.
We're going to send this information to the store.
So why don't we for now just simply put a debugger right here and let's just return state.
We'll keep it real simple but we added to do let's see what we actually dispatch right here.
And to keep it real simple the last thing I'm going to do is just grab that form and we're going to
trigger the reset event.
And this will simply just clear any form values that I have.
So one more time when the form I submitted don't let the page refresh grab whatever the user typed in
and send an action to the reducer who gets to send those actions the store will give it a type because
they always always have to have a type and will give it some property called Task We'll see how we use
that.
So I'll save this right now.
I'll head back and refresh the page and open my chrome dev tools so I can see a debugger happen.
I'll go trying to add something like eat dinner when I add that to do I make it to the root reducer.
Great.
And you can see right here that my action has a property called tape as well as a property called task.
This is the first time that we're seeing passing additional keys in an action.
Aside from type but you can pass in whatever you'd like.
That's really nice because now our reducer can take that task and put it in to our to do's in the there's
going to be a little bit of work to do that.
So let's see how we can do that.
Your first thought might be something like let's go take this state and let's just go push in whatever
the action and the task Propertius member task is what we just got back in our action.
But that wouldn't be good.
Remember we always always want to keep our functions pure.
So what we're going to do is keep it real simple.
Let's start by making some kind of new state.
And this is going to be a direct copy of state.
We're going to spread out whatever state was we can then take whatever the ideas of state and increment
it because this did you should have an idea of one.
And we're starting at zero.
What we're then going to do is return an object because remember our state is always an object.
But inside this object what keys are we going to have.
We're going to have whatever new state has.
That should include any to do's and an ID.
And we're going to pass in another key of to use now what we need to do here is make to use an array.
And what we're going to do is grab all of the previous to views that we had we're going to spread out
all of those to do's as well as a new to do that we're going to make each to do should be an object
that has some kind of task and some corresponding ID.
So we'll say that this task is going to be whatever is passed in in the action and the idea is going
to be whatever we're storing in our state.
Remember we've just incremented this by one.
So let's go try this out and add a couple to do's and let's go see our state change.
There's a lot of it is 2015.
Even more that we're doing right now we're spreading out whatever is in state.
This is the idea of just making a copy.
We're going to increment that ID by one because remember our dues always need a unique ID.
We're then going to take that ID and just put it in a new object.
I'm being very explicit here remember you can always refactor this a little bit but want to go step
by step to Doo's is going to be an array like it always is.
But this time it's going to be whatever was in that state as well as a new to do that we're about to
make that's going to include some kind of task and some kind of ID.
So let's save this and tried out our first page.
Head over to the council and I will go home.
Let's go take a look at Stuart Dockett state.
We can see right now that our two do has a task to go home and an idea of one was try something else.
Let's go eat more dinner.
When I had that to do.
Let's go take a look at our state.
And that looks great.
Our to do's now are go home and eat more dinner.
And we're incrementing the ID so it looks like we are correctly modifying the state and everything that
we're doing is a pure function.
We're not overriding any existing state.
We're always starting by making a copy of that state.
But now we actually have to put that on the page.
So our next step is actually to work with some great Querrey before we bother resetting all of these
foreign values.
Why don't we get whatever the current state is at that time.
Because remember after we dispatch that action we should have our new to do in redux the what we'll
then do is make some kind of new list item.
This is just going to be pretty simple.
Jay Cuore last item and we're going to give it the text says object will give that the text of whatever
our new text is that we got in this case.
That's the task.
What else do we have to do here.
We are going to append that new list item to our ID of to do.
So we're going to append that new data and we can be a little more particular and actually give these
a dollar sign so that we know that these are J.A.G. elements that we're making and working with.
So I'll refresh the page I'll go eat.
ALEX Good of you to sleep and I'll go keep recording more.
That looks good.
Let's go take a step back and see how we made this all work.
We started with some initial state our initial state contains not just a counter now but multiple properties.
An array of to do's each of which will be an object with its own ID and some kind of way of keeping
track of what that ideas over time.
We could try to put the idea here for the first time and change it.
But I'm just keeping it real simple.
Moving it out over here.
Remember that we can't create a store without a reducer.
So we have our producer right here.
When you start working on larger applications your reducers are moved to separate files and folders
and your store is in another file and even some of your action creators those functions that make actions
live in another file.
But I'm putting it all in one so we can work through this line by line what we're going to do in the
reducer.
You see what the action type is.
If it's had to do make a copy of the state like we always do increment the id property and then return
a new object with whatever was in that state before which is going to have a new ID as well as the to
do property which is whatever all those old to do were.
And a new to do with a task property and an ID property.
The task is going to be whatever the user typed in that comes in in the action.
And the idea is going to be whatever we just changed our ID to be.
We're always going to increment that by one.
In the case of a move to do what we haven't got there yet.
But in the case of a action where it's not and to do or a move to do we're just going to return the
state 9:22 we make our store and whenever we make a store we always have to pass in that route reducer.
And here we actually read some J.A.G. when the downloads and a form is submitted.
Stop it from being refreshed.
Grab whatever the user typed in and dispatch an action whereas that dispatch coming from our Reebok
store who gets to dispatch the actions the redux store what our actions objects that always contain
a key of type.
In our case we're dispatching had to do and we're passing in a property of task which will come in as
action that task.
And this new task which is whatever the user typed in in the input when we're done with that we're going
to go see what our redux state looks like we're going to make a new list item with whatever the user
typed in and we're going to append that new list item to the page.
Now you might be wondering why would we want to get the current state at that point.
Now if you wanted to do something like append new information to the page or change anything that we
need in the state we'd want to do that and you might be wondering Well one of my actually going to be
doing that.
We're going to need to know specifically what the state is when we start actually deleting those new
use.
So right now we're going to get that state but we might not be using it just yet.
We're going to see where to use it in the next what I love to do right now is every time that I make
it to do like eat and sleep I'd like to have a button next to it that I can click to delete those tissues.
And each one of these buttons should have an ID that corresponds to whatever ID that to do house.
So how do I do that.
We've got to make about what's going to make a new button and this button right here is going to be
once again a worry button and it's going to have the text of an X and it's going to have an ID property
which is what ever current state DOT ID is.
So what are we doing here.
Current state that Id just refers to whatever the latest ID property is in our redox state.
And what that means is that each time we make a to do we'll make a list item and a button with whatever
the ideas in our state.
That might seem like a lot.
Let's go to the browser and see what's happening in the elements tab will seek a look at what's inside.
To do this I'm going to need to open this up.
We take a look at our list item what where is our button.
Looks like we've got to append our button.
It's the last thing we want to do is grab our new list item and we actually can do this right here and
we're going to append that new button.
Let's put the button inside of here so that way we can see that.
Let's try this one more time.
Let's take a look inside of here.
And notice that there is an ID of one.
Let's go try to sleep.
Notice inside of here there's an ID of two.
Well where's that I.D. coming from.
If we take a look at our store state we can see the ideas too which means if we make another to do we
should expect the state to have an ID of three and we should expect this button to also have an ID of
three.
You could use a data attribute or something.
I'm just using an ID to keep it real simple but what's the purpose of this ID.
Why do we need to uniquely identify every single to do.
Well when we remove it to do we need to know which one to remove.
So what we're going to do is add an event listener on those buttons inside of this form we could make
a new event listener but we're going to use a little bit of event delegation.
We are going to say that for any unordered list when there is a click on any button inside of here that
can be created at any point run a function without event object.
What we'll do right now is dispatch an action.
We are going to dispatch the action with a type of remove to do and we need to pass in some kind of
ID.
We're going to use squirty to get whichever button was clicked and we are going to get whatever ID attribute
is we're going to stop right here and throw a debugger and make sure that we make it to remove to do.
This is a really good way to work dispatch an action.
See if you're getting the data that you want and just return the state and not actually removing anything
here.
But we just want to see whatever our state is at that point.
So I'll refresh the page I'll eat a click on this button and it looks like we're successfully making
it to remove to do.
But what's happening here inside of our action you have a type of removed to do and an idea of one where
is that idea of one coming from well event that target refers to that button that was clicked and the
button that was clicked has an attribute called ID.
Let's take a look at that.
That refers to this attribute ID right over here.
What we've done is send a string to redox because our ID is turned into a string.
So we're going to have to deal with converting that string to a number.
So what do we do with this ID.
Well what we'd like to do is go through all of our to do's and remove the one with an ID of one.
So you might be thinking once again.
Oh that's easy.
Well we can just simply get that specific ID.
We could do something like that to do that splice.
We just want to remove one thing starting from whatever index that we got.
So what's our starting point.
Well that's going to be action that ID and then more remove one thing and we'll be very fancy we'll
convert this to a number to make sure that we get the right index and then we'll return our stay positive
video and see if you can figure out what's wrong here.
Well let's see I'm going to save this or refresh the page or I'll eat a click on this right here and
take a look at my state and it's still there looks like that's still there.
That idea of 0.
Well what I did here is just simply trying to splice from my to do's and return that state not only
is this code incorrect but the function is also impure.
So I don't even want to bother debugging this because I'm directly mutating or changing my state a better
way to do this is to make a copy of our to do this.
And how can we do that.
How can we take our two do's and make a copy of it without that specific one inside of it.
We could write a for loop but there's also a really nice array method that helps us do that.
And that's filter.
We're going to say grab all of the traduce where the id property is not whatever idea we passed in right
now.
And then we can simply return a copy of the state with our two do.
This is the same thing as doing to do is to do this right here.
We're just going to pass in an object and right here are two use.
So what we're doing here is simply filtering out any of those to do that don't have that ID.
Let's see this.
And our first page we're not actually going to see it removed from the page because that's where his
job but let's go take a look at what our redux date is right now.
We have an array where ideas too.
I mean have these two.
When I click on it and take a look at my steed notice that that one is actually gone.
And my Adey still stays the same.
I've used filter to make a copy of this array.
You're going to see very commonly when you do remove operations with redox that filter is a wonderful
operation when you're working on an array because filter is a pure function.
It always returns a new array just like map.
You'll see map as well when you do things like updating which I really encourage you to try to implement
omni's to use to the last part that we need here is to actually have some jay query remove those specific
to do this and that really just requires a little bit of Jey query.
What we're gonna do is get whatever was clicked on the event at Target.
We're going to go up to its parent which is the list item and we're going to remove it.
So I'm going to save that.
We're going to go back here.
Let's try to first take a look at our state an array with zero idea.
Let's go eat.
Let's go to sleep.
Let's go home.
Go take a look at our state and we have three items inside and an ID of three that looks good.
The idea is incrementing it staying at three so that the next time it will go up to 4 let's go remove
these.
Looks like the query is working.
So all those three things are being removed.
Looks like I have nothing left in my to do array but my ID is three so I have had another.
We can see right here we have an idea for and that to do right there.
One thing that you really want to try to make sure is that you're not mutating state.
And sometimes you'll get some UI issues around that but sometimes you may actually find yourself changing
state and realizing that it's still all kind of works.
So what I want to introduce is a wonderful Chrome extension called a redux dev tools and what we're
going to look at is the second one break here.
I have this already installed so feel free to take a look at the documentation and install the redux
dev tools.
It's a Chrome extension so grab it from the Chrome Web store using Firefox grab it from the Firefox
add ons what you want to do right after you do that is simply add this line right here to where we call
create store.
The second thing that you want to do and doing this Ancrum is I'll go over here and I'll click on this
extension right here.
I'll go to manage extensions inside of here.
You want to make sure that you have this checked right there allow access to file you are.
Since we're just running things off the file system we want to make sure that redux dev tool still picks
up what we've done so back over here once you've installed it.
You want to make sure once again that once it's installed you click on this right here.
Manage extensions and make sure that allow access the file you are as is clicked.
You can also just run this on a server and you'll be fine.
We're then going to grab this line right here and we're going to see the reduction of tools in action.
And where does that go.
Take a look again.
When you call create store so when you create store we're going to pass in this line right here.
This is not something you're going to memorize.
This is something you find yourself copying and pasting quite a bit.
So if we have this loaded we should be able to go back and we should have a tab with redox that has
this item right here.
Now it's really cool about this is using this application.
We can actually see changes in our redux.
So I'm going to eat some dinner or not now but hopefully after I record this what I just did is dispatch
an action with the task of eat dinner.
And here's what my state looks like right now.
That's pretty awesome.
Brings out a little bit so we can see in a little bit more detail on this over here.
And I'll go actually hide my crumb chrome tools.
I'll bring this over here.
I'm going to click on this right here.
And what you can see here is that we just dispatched that removed to do what I'll do now is just add
another to do.
So once again I'll eat and I'll remove all sleep and remove and I'll go home and we can see all of these
tasks that have happened.
What I can do here as well is simply act as if I didn't do that I can skip that.
And if you take a look at the idea right now is back to Moscow and skip that and it's back to three.
Now since I'm using Jay Querrey for Dominic violation things are a little different.
But if you want to see changes in your state you can always see what would happen if you didn't run
these actions.
This is the idea of time traveling that we spoke about a little while ago.
You can see that as I is my state actually changes.
What's really cool about this is you can go back in your application and see what changes have been
made.
If you want to look at this right here it's a little bit of a more verbose way of seeing all the things
that have happened.
If I actually reset everything I can go back to my default state.
Now since I'm using Querrey for dominant violation.
It's really hard to keep a query and redux in sync.
This is where we're going to start bringing re-act back into the mix because if we can sync up react
with our redux state we should be able to not only make sure we're writing pure functions but also see
changes in our re-act application when we change our read state.
So don't worry too much if you're not super comfortable with these tools.
I just wanted to introduce them at a very high level because when you start connecting react we'll see
it all come back together.
So one more time let's go over the code that we wrote inside our index that each you know we have a
list of to do's here we're just going to append some list items in our form.
We don't go anywhere.
We see what the user types in with an idea of task and then we have a button to submit the form.
We then have some queries I'm redux.
And our own script file we make some initial state and we have a producer which accepts that initial
state as a default parameter.
When we add it to do we make a copy of the state add one to the ID and return a new object with that
updated ID and whatever else was in state and overwrite the to use property with all the other to use
and a new one that we make every to do has a task property and an id property.
You're not sure where some of these things are coming from.
Throw debuggers and see how data flows through a redux app.
How does it work.
Actions are dispatched they're dispatched by a store.
Once the action is dispatched it goes to the producer and some new state is returned.
How do we even figure out what our initial state is.
We call create store with our producer.
What's this whole thing here doing grabbing our redux dev tools.
Those instructions are right here.
If you google redux dev tools you want to make sure you're using this one specifically
next.
We have a little bit of query handling some damning tabulation.
We're really going to bring reactance to the mix in a little bit because I can think of much more nicely
with redux but you can use redox with Jay query with angular with backbone with whatever you'd like.
It's just a centralized place to manage your city.
What we have here is a little bit of advance delegation when in an ordered list Lewisohn's for a click
and it's on a button.
This way we don't replace an event with on every button and we can save some more space.
We are going to dispatch an action.
It's going to be called remove to do and it's going to have an additional property called ID which is
whatever button was clicked downs.
ID attribute.
We're then going to go to the parent of that element which is a list item and we're going to remove
it.
This is the query and this right here is the redux.
Remember we want to keep our redux state in sync with anything that we're doing in the DOM.
So whenever we remove elements we also want to make sure we remove them from our redux date.
The next thing we're listening for which we started with is that form submission.
Stop the page from refreshing grab with the user typed in dispatch an action of ad to do and send to
redux whatever the user typed in.
We then want to get that current state so we know what that idea is so we can add it to a button.
But before we make the button we make a list item with some text.
We then make a button with a simple text of X and an ID attribute of whatever the redux date ideas.
That's important because we need to know which to do to remove.
We then append that button to the list item and then we append the list item to our traduce.
And finally we reset our foreign values.
So here's what it should look like when we have it working.
We should be able to eat.
We should be able to sleep with a P and we should be able to get rid of these right here.
So that's it for our to do application.
I encourage you to implement functionality for updating so you can use functions like map to make sure
you're still using pure functions and in a little bit we're going to bring back re-act who are going
to connect it with redux.
And that's where things really get funny.
I'll see you next week at.