I want to start introducing our first container right now and the first container is going to be called
nav bar dodginess now part of us is going to be pretty simple.
We're really just going to display a couple of links in an avatar.
This will allow us to log in and sign up as we continue adding authentication.
The text of this nav bar will change if the users logged in or not on their side then they'll be able
to log out and create a message.
Right now we just bottlings for sign up and log in for worry about the number.
Let's make sure that we use bootstrapped Stout's application.
So let's go to bootstrap Let's go grab the latest CDN for bootstrap for software can download scroll
down a little bit and go make sure that we grab this link.
We're not aware of that bootstrap Javascript.
So we're just going to get to yes us and inside of our application are indexed at each DML.
We're just going to paste in that link.
We'll also have a link to this in the notes you can access it faster in the terminal was going start
this application and see if our Hello world looks just a little bit better.
And it looks like we have great if we want to double check this.
We can go to the Network tab.
Click on CSX and the first page and it looks like bootstrap is actually being loaded.
That's great.
Now we have this track.
Let's actually start building this nav bar inside of our nav bar.
Yes.
We're going to place this nav bar inside of containers because this is also going to connect to the
redux store number the number is going to change if the user is authenticate it.
And if the users authenticated will display some information for logging out or creating a message.
But right now we're not going to worry about that.
So what kind of things do we need in order to have our For First we get to import react.
And will the structure component from react.
You're going to see this all over the place.
We're also going to include the link component from re-act router.
And since this is a container we also want to connect it to our redock store.
So import connect from reata redux the glue between those two.
All we want to do is make a class called nav bar that extends a compile and inside of our component.
We also want to make sure that we render and when we render we're going to return some GSX what are
we going to return.
Let's start with an element with a class of NFR nap or extend expand some bootstrap for classes just
to get us started.
We're also going to want a class of container fluid to make sure we get a full width and inside here
we're also going to have a link that takes us to the home page and this link I'm home in is coming from
re-act router Dohm that allows us to build navigation.
We want to make sure we use the link tag and not an anchor tag.
We'll also add a class name of nav bar.
Brant let's also make sure we close that link tag and close those quotes with Barbara and inside of
this link we'll place an image with an RC of what will be the logo.
Right now we don't have the images yet so we'll just add an alt of warbler home will add these images
a little bit later.
Let's just get the setup done first.
So when we click on this we would like to go back to this route.
We don't have any route set up.
We're just building the nav bar to get things started.
So it's at and what else do you want to do was add a little bit more to or for now after the did.
We're going to have a know with a glass of now I've never been out of that bar.
Right.
This is going to push these elements that we placed inside of you to the right of our number one make
a list item with a link inside and this link is going to go to slash south.
Right now we don't actually have these routes.
We're just building a couple of links and so take us to the sign up page and component.
We don't have that yet once again.
We're just building some links to start with our navigation.
Let's make another one that's going to go to sign him.
And that allows me to log in.
So I'm not worried too much about connecting things to the Reebok store but we're going to need here
eventually is the current user because if the current users authenticated we don't want to show them
sign of in logon we want to show them something different.
So let's actually just make a function call it maps to props and then start connecting to our redux
or do we pass in some state from the redux.
We return an object and the current user will be placed on props and the value will be from state.
Everything we get on the current user We're then going to export this de-evolved connect and we're going
to ram with maps the props.
We don't have a map dispatched to props so we can just pasand No this is going to change a little bit
and we'll wrap this again in and out our.
So we're not using the redux story yet but it's going to be important later.
So we're going to come back to this when the user is authenticated and change those links from Sign
up to sign in to create a message and log out.
We'll come back to this in a little bit.
But we're setting up the foundation to heal to come back and easily add that functionality.
So let's see if this and that and our.
Let's go make sure we wondered the nav bar.
So inside of our address we're going to wrap all of this and itive will get this div a class name of
onboarding.
Well style is a little bit later.
This is just a nice wrapper div and a wrapper class for our two components that we placed inside of
here.
We'll have a class with nav bar and we'll add another one later.
We'll have a component of nav bar but we have to make sure that we import that nav bar from that flashed
nav bar which can take a look at what this looks like now in the browser and you look at that beautiful
number I promise we'll style it in a little bit.
I just want to start with the functionality to sign up and log in.
If you could do wrong you would actually see the routes change.
We just don't have any components that are being rendered when we go to those routes.
What we'll do in the next section is make this nav bar a little bit nicer and add another component
to display a homepage.