Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be going over solutions to the for each.
The first function we need to implement is the double values function which accepts an array and returns
a new array with all of the values doubled inside here.
I'll create a variable called New R and assign it to be an empty threat of then iterate over the array
passed to the function and at each iteration push the value multiplied by 2 into the new R variable.
We'll then return the new variable once we're done it read.
The next function we need to implement is only even values which accepts and are already inside of this
function.
I'll declare a variable called New are and assign it to an empty array.
I'll then iterate over the array passed to the function and if the value that we're add is divisible
by 2 we'll push a value into the new R array and finally return the new array.
The next function we need to implement is the show first and last function which accepts an array inside
of this function on a variable called New R and assignment to be an empty array.
I'll then iterate over the array passed to the function and at each of you push into the new array the
first character plus the last character which I can access using the lenth minus one.
Remember strings have a length property so we can access them using lenth minus one to get the last
character and only return the new are variable.
The next function I need to implement is the add key and value function which accepts an array of objects.
Some P and some value and then iterates over the array at each of you.
I'll assign a key in each object to whatever value we pass to the function actually.
I'll return the array passed to this function.
The last function I need to implement is the valid count function which accepts a string and returns
an object with the keys as values and the values as the count of the number of vowels in that string.
The first thing I'll do is make an array called split R which is the result of the string split by character
and then I'll create an empty object and a string which contains all of my Vulpes are then iterate over
every character in the split are variable using for each and then use the index of method to check if
the character that I made is of value.
Remember index of returns negative 1 to us.
If the value which we're looking for is not in the string or array we can use index of on both strings
and arrays are then checked to see if that letter is already a key inside of the object.
We can do this quite a few ways but will use an IF statement to see if the value of that object with
the key of whatever character worked at exists and if it is I will increment its value by 1.
Otherwise I'll set a key in that object to be the letter that I'm currently at and assign it to the
value of 1.
Once I'm done iterating I'll return the object.
Make sure to use bracket notation here because we need javascript to evaluate these variables for us
and not hard code a name of the key for the exercises.
See you in the next video.