All right.
So we've seen a lot of the syntax around keyframes and now it's time for you to put some of that into
practice.
So we have an exercise.
This one is a bit different.
We're not going to make anything particularly beautiful or even useful to be honest.
It's really just focused on making sure you understand how to animate things.
So most of the animations that we do day to day on a typical Web site are small and often they're hard
to notice and you're not supposed to notice them you don't want them to stick out.
There's things like little scales or Wiggles or a loading icon where it's tiny.
You're not doing a full page animation.
So what we're going to do is the opposite we're going to start off with something big.
It's not beautiful but it's big and noticeable.
I think it's a good idea to start off on a big scale when you're animating it's much easier to see what's
happening if you're doing things wrong.
And basically it's a good way to understand keyframes early on.
So we're going to make an animated sun and a sky.
So there'll be a sky that changes color and the sun rises from one corner and then sets in the other
corner and also changes color as it goes.
So the end result.
Like I said very simple.
Not that useful but it's a good exercise to make sure you grasp how keyframes work.
But shortly we will be building a CSSA loading icon really a whole animated loading page.
And that's something that's a lot more likeable to most development work rather than a sun in the sky.
But we're starting here.
So first thing I'll do is show you what my version looks like yours does not have to look like this.
It's very ugly he said.
But notice there's two things.
There's well there's three there's a grass or Earth or whatever this is that's not animated at all.
But then there's a sky back here and a song.
So if we take a look first at the sun you can see that it's rising and falling.
But as it does that it also is changing color so it gets bright yellow at the top here and then as it
goes back down it becomes orangey and red at the very end.
And then it's orange over here as it rises and then it becomes yellow again and then separate from that.
We also have a sky.
So for a split moment it's dark right there.
Then it becomes pink and then it slowly becomes blue in the middle of the day.
And then as the sun sets it becomes pinker as if sunset and then dark as if night and so on.
So that's our animation that's what we're going to make.
You don't have to get this exactly the ark of the actual sun doesn't matter the exact colors don't matter
how wide this is it really just about having two components sun and a sky.
So you'll find the starter code code Penn included as a resource in the video.
It's very bare bones.
There's a grass div which you won't touch.
And then there's a sun div and the sky is just the body it's the background of the body.
So it's the only part that's showing here.
So what you'll need to do is animate the sky first.
That's how I recommend you do it and then attempt the sun.
So all you'll do is for the body you'll add your animation here.
Whatever it is animation name and you'll define your animation down below.
Same thing for the sun.
Ill defined an animation and then assign it to the sun class.
But before you go off and attempt this here's a chart that kind of goes through the steps the frames
that I recommend you do for the sky.
So the sky animation it goes from dark whatever this color is dark blue or you can just do black to
pink at 10 percent then to blue at 30 percent blue again.
They're at 70 percent pink at 90 and then back to dark.
And I did that because really the majority of the sky is blue and there's only a tiny bit where sunrise
and sunset that it's pink yes.
Not.
You know it's not accurate because night would be just as long as the blue but where our sun doesn't
account for nighttime right now.
It's a very quick sunset and then it rises immediately afterwards.
So we start with that.
Here I have it actually running with just the sky animation.
So all you should have is it starts at dark and goes to pink and then spends a long time transitioning
to blue and then a long time going back to pink.
Here he goes and then it goes to the dark colored for a moment and then back to pink and so on.
So get that to work first and then move on to the sun.
So the way the sun should work is that again there's two pieces you're moving it.
I use transform translate.
So you can translate the sun over and up and so on and then down using transform translate and then
the color changes as well.
So the specifics don't matter that much about the path it takes.
All that I really care about is that you're animating the sun in a path and that along the way the color
goes from orange to yellow to red.
But I deliberately wanted this to be different.
The the keyframes the percentages you're using this year are 25 50.
This is broken into quarters.
This guy has broken down into non-regular intervals.
Zero to 10 10 to 30 30 to 70.
So it doesn't match up.
And that's by design.
I want you to have two different things animating at the same time that are happening together.
So they're running together but they're not you know 0 25 50 75 100.
Same thing is happening at the same points in time.
So that's really the key here.
The sky play around with the colors if you'd like use these percentages and use these percentages for
the sun and make it set or make it rise excuse me and then set and change color as it goes.
All right.
So in the next video I'll have my implementation.
You can also just take a look at the solution coding next video as well.