All right let's get down to business.
Let's start animating.
Well actually first we're not going animate.
First we're going to talk about some ways that we can trigger our animations which is equally important
at least in the early stages.
We need a way of starting animations.
We need something to cause them.
We could I could show you how to animate things just as soon as the page loads have something happen
immediately.
But that's a pretty rare thing.
Usually animations are triggered by a scroll or a click or a hover often.
So there are you know there's more than that but those are some of the more common things or submitting
a form hitting the enter key instead of an input.
Those sort of things will start by talking about these triggers these state changes in C Ss and then
soon we'll see how to connect them if you will to animations.
All right.
So the keyword is pseudo classes.
C Ss 3 pseudo classes.
You may have heard them called pseudo selectors as well on the corresponding MDAC page which I have
opened here.
It's also in the resources for this lecture.
There is a pseudo class page essentially pseudo classes are special selectors that you add on actually
to another schlechter that I'll just read that specifies a special State of the selected elements so
they're relatively new in the grand scheme of success.
They haven't been around that long.
They always start with a colon.
You can see here selector colon pseudo class and they allow you to select things based off of particular
States.
So in our case we're going to care about three for now hover focused and active.
So we'll go into each one of those shortly.
But there are a bunch of other ones.
And I just want to be clear not all of these are used to trigger things like animations.
This is not a particularly cohesive group of pseudo classes.
They vary a lot.
They range in what they do what they select not all of them have to do with you know something the user
does like hovering or clicking on a button like the ones will focus on some of them are very very different.
So if you are not familiar with some of these if you took my last course that talks a lot about and
child and of type those didn't have anything to do with animation really although it could but traditionally
they don't.
OK.
So let's kick it off by talking about hover.