Welcome back in the last video we introduce Jasmine which is our testing framework and saw how to include
the necessary CSSA and Javascript links to get up and running.
Now that we have an idea of how to start with Jasmine let's learn a bit about some important keywords
and functions when writing tests when we write our tests.
There are a few functions that we'll be using quite frequently.
Here are three of the most important ones.
First we have describe this function is given to us by jazzmen and it is what we use to organize our
tests.
You can think of the described function like talking to someone and telling them.
Let me describe something to you.
Very often when you're reading unit tests you'll have one described block her function or unit that
you're testing.
The second important function that we will examine is it the IT function is used inside of described
functions and inside of the IT function we write code that explains in more detail what we expect this
piece of functionality to do.
You can think of the IT function like you're talking to someone and telling them now that I describe
something let me tell you about it in more detail.
Each IT function corresponds to a test and is often also called a spec.
The last function we'll be looking at is the expect function expect function lives inside of the IT
function and is where we make expectations or assertions about the functionality we are testing.
If one of our expectations inside of the function isn't met the test or spec fails this might sound
a little strange.
So before we get into a javascript example let's look at an example in English.
Here's how we make unit test.
Earth First will describe earth.
We will then say it is round inside of here.
We will expect that Earth is round we can write another spec that says it is the third planet from the
sun inside of here.
We'll expect that it is the third planet from the sun now that we have seen the pseudo code.
Let's take a look at some actual test code.
Here's an example of test code written in javascript using jazzier.
Let's make a simple object called Gerth and give it some properties.
Is round and number from Sun will then use the described function to wrap all of our tests.
Notice that described in it except a string as their first parameter.
This is what will appear in the browser when we look at these tests.
The second parameter is always the callback function for both describe and think of this as we describe
something and then we run a function and we explain what it can do.
And then we run a function where we make assertions or expectations about our code inside of the callback
to our described function.
We place our functions and inside of the callback to our function we place our expect function the expect
function returns and object to us which we can attach other methods to these methods we attach onto
the result of the expect function are called matchers.
The first matter we are looking at is to be which uses the triple equal comparison operator and compares
the result of the expect function with the value we passed to that to be function.
Remember describe it expect and matchers are all given to us by jazzmen.
Now let's see how this all comes together.
Here we place our code inside of the script tags and loaded all of our jazzmen code.
Let's see what this looks like in the browser.
Here we can see that we have two specs.
Remember spec is another word for test and each function we use is considered a spec.
You can see that inside of the word earth we have our two specs and everything is green which means
that our tests are passing.
I'm going to change one of the tests so you can see what it looks like when our tests fail.
Notice here things are now red.
If you'd like.
Feel free to pause the video and try to write some more tests.
In practice you won't be writing javascript inside of your Each team or files.
Instead you'll typically have a couple of external javascript files one of them is called a spec file
short for specification and will contain all of your tests.
The other will be the code that you're actually testing in later sections on testing with the node and
re-act applications.
You'll see those in more detail.
Now that we've gotten to a point where we understand the basic structure of our tests.
Let's talk a bit more about matchers.
Remember that matters are the functions that we attach to the result of the expect function.
We were previously using a matter called 2B But what if we want to see if a value is defined or greater
than some value.
Or maybe we want to check the type of something thankfully Jasmine has quite a few matchers we can use.
Let's take a look at some the first natural will examine is to be or not to be to be.
We'll use triple equals to compare a value with another.
The next matter is to be close to this we'll compare two values and accepts a second parameter for precision.
This is useful when we only care if something is similar to another and not exactly the same.
The next matter is to be defined.
This is helpful in making sure certain variables have a specific value and not undefined.
Next is to be falsie and to be truthy.
These are handy when we expect a value when converted to a boolean to be true or false.
We also have to be greater then to be less than which are pretty self-explanatory and helpful when working
with numbers.
The next one we have here is very useful when working with arrays.
If we want to see if a value is contained in an array we can use to contain.
Sometimes we don't know all the values in an array but we want to just make sure that something is there
to contain is a great matcher.
The next one to equal might seem a bit strange.
We saw that to be a triple equal comparison.
So what does two equal do.
Remember that when you compare two objects using triple equals you will not always get what you expect.
Even if they look the same if the two objects are different references in memory triple equals will
always be false.
Let's quickly see what I mean by that.
I'll open up the chrome console and create an array called our one and then create another array called
are two.
If I compare our one with two using triple equals I will actually get false.
The reason is because these objects are different references in memory.
If I create a variable called R 3 and make it an empty array and then create another variable called
R for and assign it to are three then these will be the same references in memory.
And when I use triple equals to compare each one it will return true.
Always be mindful of how objects are compared using triple equals.
Now back in Jasmine what happens if we want to compare values in an object or array with another.
They are different references in memory.
This is where two equal helps to equal all except two different objects.
And if there are values inside are the same it will return true even if they are different references
in memory.
Two equal is a great way to compare objects and arrays.
The last thing we'll look at is not exactly a matter but a helpful tool when doing type checking.
If we want to make sure some value is an array or function or constructed from a specific function we
can use Jasmine that any to check the type.
Remember typeof does not work for arrays since arrays are a type of object.
So let's see what these look like inside a describe and it block.
Feel free to pause the video and check out the code on this lot.
Here we are using some of the matters before and making sure that all of our tests pass.
You can look through this code and see in a little more detail about each of these matters that we've
spoken about.
If we open this up in the browser we'll see that all of our tests are passing.
If you'd like to play around with these examples just click on the code Penn link below.
These are also included in the section notes now that you've seen the syntax and matters it's time to
practice a bit with these concepts.
See you in the next video.