All right.
So next up we're going to actually fetch the initial state of our application.
We're going to use this endpoint right here so slash API slash to do so on our API.
And hopefully you have some data in there.
Again if you don't have anything then just go to the root URL and add a couple here.
And our goal is to get react to fetch those and add them to the initial state of our application.
So to do that we're going to go to our to do list which we have open right now and we to start by setting
the initial state of to do.
Just to be an empty array and to do that and add our kind of boilerplate constructor drops.
And then in here just add super props and then this state equals and then will just set to dues to be
an empty array just like that.
So we'll leave it at that.
And the next big thing is to load our data and put it inside of this to use inside of the state.
So we're going to use a fetch API call.
We could use some other tools like Acciona or something.
I mean to use fetch and we're going to fetch this you are all right here but I'm going to warn you now
it's a little more complicated than that because we kind of have to get around some small issues with
the fact that these are basically being hosted on the same server.
But for now let's ignore that and just move on.
At the end of this video we'll address the problem.
So what we're going to do is instead of a component will mount or component did mount but I'm going
to do component will mount.
We're going to fetch the data and it's going to be super simple when you factor this in just a moment
but we're just going to do a fetch slash API slash to do.
And we're not going to worry about error handling yet.
We will though for now ours can do that and we'll call it data.
And should we review if you made it through the API or the fetch and J-curve single page app sections
making requests and we'll do another then after that data.
Jason return's promise and I'll just call that data to do.
And we're going to do this that said state
and dues like that which is going to take dues here and set it equal to this to do so here.
Perfect.
So again this should work ideally but it's not going to because of a small problem.
But if we go into a reactor right now you'll see if I go into our state here I mean you have to get
that far because if you actually look at what we're getting it saying that the request actually worked
and we could know that if we went to network and refresh the page you can see the request is made right
here.
But if we look at the response we're actually getting him back or getting this weird page and that's
not what we want.
So what's happening is we're actually getting our own create re-act app page if you actually look at
the code here but see if I can find an example.
We have things like create re-act you need to enable javascript to run this app.
Basically all that matters is we're actually getting our own create react out because we're actually
requesting slash to do slash API on our own page which is not what we want.
We don't want to be requesting port 80 80 slash to do such API.
You want to request 80 81 slash slash to do this.
I think we're saying it backwards but 80 81 slash API slash reduce.
This is what we want to request and we're not doing that right now are we going to do instead is proxy
all requests that are outgoing here to localhost.
ADHD.
So I'm going actually remove this here.
Keep this as a slash API slash to Duse but we're going to tell our application that all these requests
are supposed to start off of local host 1881 proxy the request there rather than to our own local host
1880.
So I realize it's kind of confusing.
Basically we're just telling our app to request through a different port proxy requests through that
port.
And if you want to read more about it create re-act app.
Actually the documentation has some good explanation of what to do.
But all we need to do is take this line here and go to our package that Jaison and anywhere in here
we just add proxy and this is just for development we'll add 80 81 because there's basically a shared
local host.
Neither of them are deployed.
So we're going to do this as a workaround and I believe we need to restart double check and this should
be going to slash API slash dues and because we added this proxy line it will be going to 1881 slash
API slash to do.
And also just to be clear this is on the front end we are proxying request from react so don't add it
to the package just on of the API itself if you're are fresh now we have a different problem.
So this problem invalid host header will go to the documentation they actually explain what's happening.
This happens because we're using a cloud editor in development mode.
So you can read more about this.
Essentially this is just a fix that we need to do in the short term because we're using Cloud 9.
So what we're going to do is make a dot in vidette development file and in that file or we can also
just do it v file but in redubbed development it's better because create re-act Apple only apply it
to development when we're running the app in development rather than production.
We're going to add this dangerously disable host checked equals true.
As you can see it's not a great idea.
You do not do this in production but because we're using a cloud editor if you are using cloud 9 we
do need to add this in.
It's just sort of a workaround.
But once you deploy the application you remove this it won't matter.
So it's really not a problem as long as you're not deploying apps and keeping this line in there.
So we're going to go back here and instead of our to do front end in the top level of it you know make
a new file that in vidette development.
So this is an environment variable essentially a setting that applies in the development mode.
So it will save and close out and I think we need to restart our server to get those variables to load.
Now if we try once it loads to make this request it works well at least you don't get an error.
And if we look at the news we're getting data back and if we go to react we go into the to do list component
and we look at state.
I have four items in that to do's array.
You may have fewer You may have more depending on what's in your database.
But we want to make sure that we're getting something back.
You can see that's happening here.
OK.
So the last thing I want to do is refactor this a bit.
I'm going to add in error handling because right now let's say if our API server is turned off we're
just not going to handle that error at all.
Or let's say we request an endpoint that doesn't exist.
We're not handling that either.
And I'm also going to move everything out of component amount to make something new here I'm just going
to call it load to deuce.
And here is where I'm actually going to do all the requesting and I wouldn't start by taking this flash
API slash to use and defining a constant up here I'll just call API.
You are real.
We're going to reuse this same you r l slash API slash to do.
When we are posting when we're updating and removing.
I don't want to repeat myself so this will be easiest.
Also if we do end up changing the structure of our API or that you are open say maybe it's just under
slash to do's.
I only need to change it in one place.
OK so I'm going to refactor that and then I'm going to hop down here and I'm going to move.
Well first old update this to say API you are ill and I'm going to move this down into load dues.
I'm going to start by just calling this up load to do inside component amount.
So I've just moved that into a different function and everything should still work the same.
If I refresh the page go to react like it are to do list.
Great state showing up there are close but now I'm going to add an error handling to be kind of annoying
to watch me type this.
But here we go.
It's a bunch of functions.
Ok so here we're going to check first.
I'll change this from data to response.
I'm going to check if the response is not ok.
Then I'm going to do another check to see is the status greater than or equal to 400.
And also
also is a status less than 500.
Now if that's the case I'm going to return whatever the responsa Jaison is so this means that we probably
get some error back from the server itself like a page not found.
Maybe something happening on the server side over can a return response Jason because there's probably
an error message in this response and once that Jason is parsed we're then going to take the data in
there and we're going to build our own error message that we're going to send back.
So we're just going to do let barer and in here I'll call it error message his data message.
So basically we're just making a simplified object that contains an error message and then I'm going
to throw that error just like that.
OK we have a couple of syntax errors I'll take care of those in a moment.
But if it's not between 400 and 500 then we're going to just add an else in here and I'm going to do
let error again and this time an error message is equal to.
I don't know.
Please try again later.
Server is not responding or something like that.
So this would be triggered you know for not getting a response.
If we have a problem or the server just is off
and we'll throw that air.
OK.
So we're getting close.
Let's just make sure my syntax is correct.
We're returning response based on now.
I renamed it her espie that Jason and a missing Apprentice I believe.
And I need to move this then over here.
Told you would be a little annoying to watch me type this.
And then finally we need to close off our function OK.
I think we're getting close now.
Let's just double check.
So fetch is it correct for you for that.
Let's move on then onto the next line.
It's looking a bit better.
Perfect.
It's all formatted nicely.
If you're still here it should be working.
Let's double check
and we're still getting our state to do.
All right so all that I really did was just add in error handling.
I'm not going to I'm going to reuse this for a bunch the other requests are making we reflect things
a bit so we moved it to a separate function.
We use API you know which is the constant just so that we don't have to update it multiple places.
We're checking for two types of errors.
We are creating error message.
We're throwing it in two different places.
Otherwise we're just returning response Jason.
So it was nice and simple and clean without this error handling but it's good to have that there it's
important.
And then we're doing the exact same thing after we check for errors and we return that Jaison the response
then we are updating the state with the new state of loaded data.
So this is a pattern that will follow a lot when we're updating data or posting a new to do or deleting
one where we're going to send a request get something back check if there's an error.
If there's not an error then we're going to update our state.
OK we made it.