Welcome back.
In this video we're going to continue looking at common selection methods and D-3.
This time we'll use callbacks to set values for attributes and style properties.
Here are some links to the code we used last time.
In D-3 we're able to set values a bit more dynamically bypassing callback functions instead of primitive
values.
This is really useful and you've got a selection with multiple elements because the callback function
will be run once for each element in the selection.
For instance we could use a function that randomly changes the font size of each list item in RHC them
out by using a callback involving math that random because the callback is run once for each list item.
We're getting four randomly generated font sizes rather than just one.
Every time we run this code we're getting four new font sizes for the list items.
D-3 imposes a certain structure on the callback passing.
We'll discuss the structure in more detail later but for now it's good to know that the second argument
in the callback will refer to the index of the current element in the selection.
So for example if we want to add a striped background to our list we could write a callback that sets
a background color based on the index.
Let's run this code.
You can see that now an even numbered list items have a light gray background.
Finally it's worth mentioning that you can use method chaining D-3 to add style to multiple D-3 selections
in sequence.
For example we could use one string of commands to modify the divs at the bottom of our page DML page.
First we'll select the outer and update some style on it.
Then selecting div inside of it and modify some of its styles.
Well then do the same thing for the innermost divs.
My indentation here might look a little strange but this is a common D-3 convention and musing for spaces
of indentation for methods that return the current selection into spaces of indentation for methods
that return a new selection.
This helps keep the code readable.
There is nothing we've done here that we couldn't have done using vanilla javascript but as you start
using D-3 It's good to get into the habit of using the methods that D-3 provides.
And once we start using more of the functionality that sets D-3 apart from other libraries being comfortable
with these fundamentals will be essential.
That's all for now.
Next video we'll talk about some more advanced DOM manipulation with D-3.
See you there.