In the previous function we were able to authenticate users and make sure that they had actually logged
in with a valid token but we still want to make sure now that users can't modify other users information
even if they've logged in.
This is a process known as authorisation and it's going to follow pretty similar to what we did before.
We are going to try once again to get the token will also make sure that we catch any potential errors
and we are going to grab from the headers that are called authorization bill split by space and grab
whatever is at index 1.
We're then going to call the verify method just like we did before which excepts as its first parameter
some kind of string some kind of Gees on what token.
And then the secret key just to make sure that we can decode it correctly.
The secret key is important for encoding and decoding it has to be the same for both of those.
And then we're going to run a function to see if everything went well or if we get back in here what
we're going to say here is instead of just if it decoded we want to make sure that if there is a token
and inside of the token the ID in the payload is the same as whatever is coming in the you are then
we let to go.
Then we'll allow the user to move on.
So what does this mean inside of R U R L is probably going to look something like what we saw before.
Slashy API users slash some ID slash messages.
And what we want to think about here is what happens if user ID number two tries to make a message for
user ID number four while they still might be logged in user to be logged in.
But the ID and their payload is going to be to read up harams is going to be for this is going to prevent
users from tampering with other users information.
And this is the idea of authorization it's essential when building more secure applications.
So what happens if you don't have the right ID.
Well we can still return next.
But this time we're going to pass something to it a status once again of 401 unauthorized.
But this time the message will simply just say unauthorized.
And if that happens as well inside of here if we try to decode the token and it fails let's do that
same exact thing.
So where are we actually going to use this middleware.
Well we're going to go back to our index that.
Yes.
And we're going to import it and inside of our X-ray eyes.
We're simply going to grab a log in required
and ensure correct user
and those will both come from requiring that flash middleware flash off.
And where are we going to use this log in required and ensure correct user.
Well before you get to messages routes Let's first make sure that you're logged in.
Let's then make sure that there is actually the correct user.
So what's the idea here.
We're going to make sure that you're logged in before you start creating a message.
We're going to make sure that you are the correct user.
And then we'll let you start actually creating messages.
So let's test this out in the terminal and see if it does what we want it to do.
We saw previously that someone could just simply write a message for someone else.
So we're going to try to do is change to does this work.
And let's see if we can successfully post as someone else and we see right away please log in first.
Well how can we get that please logon first.
That's coming from our in required middleware.
We're not just going to let you start creating a message until you've logged in.
So what I'm going to try to do now is make a new user and I'm going to make a post to a local host E
one slash API slash off or sign up with a user name of hacker a password of hacker and an email of hacker
and haggard Artyom and this should create a valid software token.
But what I'm going to try to do now is try to write a message as L.E. using the hackers token hacker
doesn't have my token they only have theirs but we're going to try to take this token and see if we
can kind of forge a request as we go to host 1881 slash API flash users slash my user ID slash messages.
This is the post that should create a message will pass in an authorization Hetter there and then the
hackers
will then pass on the text of that.
See what happens when I do this.
It tells me an authorized.
Why is this happening.
This part of the token is getting decoded it's getting decoded by the server using the same secret key
that it used to encrypt it and inside of my middle where it simply telling me that the ID of the user
with that token is not the same as the ID in the Perrins and that is the idea of authorization stopping
someone with a certain ID from accessing someone else's information with a different ID.
So even if we made sure you were logged in and you use a totally valid token we still need a little
bit more authorization to make sure you're not allowed to write other messages for people.
It's a really tricky concept so I encourage you to practice H.E. pire postman see what these tokens
look like.
You can also if you'd like go to JWT.
I go and take this token and decode it with the secret key that you've made to see how it's all working
under the hood.