All right welcome back.
So it's time again for a quick and hopefully fun exercise.
We've learned a lot about char's how they work their syntax.
It's time for you to get your hands dirty and build something so that something is this.
It's a very simple little widget that displays the current price of bitcoin.
Yes I'm using euros here but we'll talk about that in a moment.
Doesn't have to be euros.
There's a button down here that you click and it will refresh the price with whatever the most recent
price of bitcoin is according to the API.
That will also show you in just a moment.
So if you're not familiar with Bitcoin I'm not going to try to explain it.
I'll do a terrible job.
Essentially it's what's known as a crypto currency.
And if you've somehow escaped ever hearing about it all that really matters for this exercise is that
it's price changes.
It fluctuates a lot just like a stock or an exchange rate and that's nice for us to use as an example
here because every time we click this button there might or usually is a new price that is reflected
here.
So the API we're going to use start there is put out by coin desk.
The you are Alpher the documentation is coin desk dot com slash API.
I'll include that in the resources.
But as you can see there's a couple of API is there's a historical one.
We don't care about that.
You could build something with it but that's not going to change very often.
But we want the real time data API.
So here's the actual You RL API that coined us our complex view on such BPI sosh current crisis Jaison.
I'll also include that as a resource if you visit the URL in your browser.
Here's the Jason response we get.
So we don't care really about the time or the disclaimer or even the chart name we want this BPI Bitcoin
price index and within that there are three sections for three currencies.
You've got U.S. dollars pounds and euros.
So feel free to pick whichever one you care about.
And I'm sorry if your current or if your home currency is not here.
I have no control over that.
So just pick one of these and what you need to do is go to the starter code use this URL and make requests.
So they started very simple.
There's an H1.
There's no price currently displayed but it goes in a span with the idea of price.
So whatever I put here they'll see is green because we have some simple CCS.
So what you'll need to do is when a user clicks this button right here they need to have javascript
that listens for an event makes a request to this API gets the data back extract the rate whether it's
U.S. dollars pounds or euros and updates this span right here to reflect that rate.
So in the end should be able to click and get a price.
And if I wait and click again I get a new price.
So that's what you're building started code is in the links as well as the API itself to give that a
shot if you want a little bit of a bonus.
You could do a couple of different things you could have it so that a price is displayed when the page
loads.
Currently that doesn't happen when I refresh the page.
There's no price until I click.
So that's a pretty easy change.
You could also include maybe a radio button or radio buttons or a checkbox for a user to specify what
currency they want rather than hard coding US dollars or euros.
So a couple of options if you want to go above and beyond give this a shot and we'll have a solution
video up next.