It's time to start adding the ability to load the messages list.
And it looks like if we refresh a page it's giving us an editing load messages is not defined.
So that's happening inside of our producers for messages and that's just because we imported something
called Load message but we won't load messages.
The first page says Expert default important his message was not found.
What we got to make sure that we export that.
That looks good.
And we're back to it.
Great news.
And I began with something right here.
Pretty simple.
Well just you test that testing want Arcam password and username.
And we're back to you made it looks good but instead of saying it meated I really want to display the
messages in the database so inside of our messages list which is a container we're going to connect
to the store to load all of our messages.
So inside of our message is component where we need to do quite a bit of work.
Let's first import react and restructure component from react.
Let's just make sure we get that curly brace inside of component that looks better.
We're then going to import connect from reac redux.
We're also going to import the fecche messages function from doctor slash store slash actions slash
messages.
I remember inside of actions actions messages.
That's the fetcher master's function which loads the messages.
And if there are any errors returns back some kind of error.
Next we're going to import fecche messages from that flashed store slash actions slash messages were
fecche messages coming from inside of our actions fetch messages is the function that makes the API
call to load all those messages.
So we're going to then create a class called message lists and that extends our component and what we'll
do right way is create our maps to props.
So like a function of maps it's props which accepts and see.
And we're going to turn an object and our key messages will be placed on props and that's going to come
from state of messages.
Then let's export a default of connect and let's read maps to props and then pass for fetch messages
under map dispatched to props and then invoke our message list component
inside of this message what component.
What we really want to do is one of the component loads or when it mounts we're going to run this not
props to fetch messages.
This is not to load all those messages.
So inside of our render we're going to destruction messages from distant prop's and then loop over all
of our messages and we'll create a component for each one we'll call that message item we'll need that
right now.
So we can message lists which is a result of mapping over all of our messages.
Each message and and inside of here we're going to return a message item component.
We don't have that component yet.
That's OK we'll make it in a second.
And inside an insider's message item component we always want to give it a specific prod called key.
We always need that for iterating and it's going to be an underscore ID that's a unique ID coming from
Angus.
One of the problems we want what's the date which is going to be created at one of the problems we want.
Let's add the text of that message.
It's going to be text.
We also want to know who made it so a proper user name which is going to be M that user data user name
on the server we're populating each message with a property called user with a username and profile
image you are ill.
So it's going to be that user profile image you are all and that's all we can pass in a couple of these
props to each message item.
Hold now it's import.
Message item from.
This is a container component.
Well there isn't going to be too much teeth here and that's good.
So let's put it inside of components slash message item and let's give me a file inside of components
called Message item dodginess and inside a message item we're going to simply follow a pattern that
we've seen before.
Import re-act from re-act says in the statelets functional component.
What else do we want here.
You want some nice formatting for our days.
So we're going to import a moment component from re-act mummy and I'll link in the section to the moment
Doxey you can see how that works.
We're going to import link from Korea Rotterdam as well.
And it's going to be a bit more for styling actually.
We're going to import a default profile image from that flash images slash evolved dash profile dash
image that GBG was one of the images that we have which I've included for you.
And if the user doesn't have an image where is going to go with that one.
So let's make a message item and it's going to be a seamless functional component which is in to get
some props and return a bunch of GSX.
So we're going to structure some information from props and let's not do that with a console that actually
directly from props.
We're going to get the date profile image you are.
What else do we pass in the past in a text and a user name as so let's return a bit of GSX here.
We'll start with a div
and inside of this div will make an image as our C attribute is going to be the profile image you are
or the default profile image.
If it doesn't exist with an alt attribute of whatever that user name is.
So if you don't have an image that display the default profile image something goes wrong.
We always have that username as an alt attribute will also give this a height of 100 with a 100 and
give a class name which will sound a little bit we'll call that timeline dash image
and make sure that we close it.
Let's make another div with the class name call message area.
And this is where we display each of the messages and let's make a link to slash.
This is not going to take us anywhere but it'll look like a little hyperlink or will display the user
name.
So the way that Twitter does we'll have that app.
And then the user name and we'll add a little bit of non-breaking whitespace tickly things will then
close that link will then add a spin with a classic text and eat it and it's like we're going to use
our moment component.
And this is a wonderful library handles with times and dates and I'll link again to it in the section
notes to give you a little bit more context.
So give us a class of text you didn't which is from Butcha and we'll give this a proper format for the
way in which we want to show these dates.
So we'll do the date the month and the year.
So is something like 30 Jan 28 in inside of your pass in the date that we're working with must close
that on that component and enclose the spin.
And after the span we'll add a little bit more.
So we really want to do here is just take a paragraph 10 and in this paragraph type We'll use our text
I will have some more styling to this later.
So this should be just the text on the page and that's about it.
And make sure that we fix our syntax and we do structure that looks a lot better and it's good to go
look in the browser.
If your front page.
We still see you meet it and it looks like the set of our message list correctly and the timeline correctly.
Well back in our home page we're never actually rendering that timeline.
So on our homepage component let's put it all together.
So let's compare message time on from the last message.
Tamarin and said if you need it let's go render our message timeline component make sure we self-closing
that.
And here you render another genteelly the return statement.
Inside of our message list.
It doesn't look like we're actually returning anything here.
So let's just make sure that we return that list of messages.
So return that message list.
Now we're getting a expert default imported as message item.
So looks like we forgot to export something out.
So let's go take a look at message item and we have to make sure we export the de-evolved message Atum
make sure you spell that one correctly.
It's good to see that we're getting another export default in message time on walk.
Same exact thing.
Let's go to a default message time line.
You're going to make a lot of mistakes and that's OK as long as you know how to debug them.
A lot of it is really just seeing this pattern over again and figuring out why you did correctly.
Message timeline is not defined.
So inside a message time line looks like I call this message time line with a capital L.
It was made that clergies.
Let's take a look now.
So now we're seeing this actually Steve all day is not a function.
So whatever method I'm passing is not actually a valid accedes function because I'm actually using a
capital get be better to make our API just a little bit smarter.
So let's actually make our method to lowercase that way if we use a capital get it all we're totally
fine.
Now we're getting a different artier dispatch catches is not a function.
Let's see what's going on here.
It looks like my syntax may just be incorrect.
Let's go back to messages G-S and go take a look at our fetch messages and it looks like I just have
a mistake with my syntax.
So a great way to debug functions is to go and write regular functions and then use aero functions.
Once you've gotten the syntax down so let's refactor this just use the regular function cured and we'll
put in that catch with a function and an error if something goes wrong.
Dispatch that our.
So this is what the function looks like.
And afterwards we can come back and use our functions.
So that's OK.
Is all.
Totally fine.
Now let's go see what's going on here.
Rest is not defined.
So where is rest coming from.
Got to make sure we get it in our resolve promise.
So that's what we want to pass to load messages.
So I'm here for a page.
Now we should see all of our messages.
Now there's a little bit styling that we need to do.
It looks like we're actually getting the right message with the date format and the text that we want
we like an redox we've actually seen it our state has two messages.
Each of those has created a user and so on.
In the next section we're going to a little bit of styling.
Are going to make these messages look better and have functionality to delete those messages in a little
bit.