All right.
So let's go over a solution to the Sungai exercise.
This is just my solution my version.
Like I said in the initial video where I introduced the problem there's not just one way of doing this.
What's really more important is that you have two of these animations going at once something that's
relatively like a son and something that's relatively like the sky.
So we'll start off by implementing these sky animation.
Here's a little helper chart that I made.
So we have six different frames that we care about the six percentage values and corresponding background
colors.
So we want to go from dark blue to pink to blue to blue to pink to dark blue.
So the colors themselves aren't that important.
I'll start off with just black pink and blue and then I'll go put the appropriate hexadecimal codes
if you care to see what colors I used.
So let's do that.
Now here I have a starter code.
The first thing I can do is define my animation and let's call this actually what I'll do is make this
bigger.
The only problem with that said it will cut off part of the sky and the grass to the right.
So it makes everything bigger but it also impacts the trajectory of our sun which you will see in a
moment.
But for now we have a bigger font and we'll do keyframes.
We need a name.
I'll just call this cycle sky colors whatever you want to call it and we'll add our values.
So we have our 0 percent will do background color is do black.
And then we have our next one 10 percent background color was pink.
And then I'm just going to copy those but change this to be 90.
We want to go back to pink.
And then at 100 I want to be back to black then in the middle we have 30 and 70 that we want to be blue
and you might be wondering why do we need to say that twice.
Why not just say 50 percent we want it to be blue.
And the answer has to do with how the actual transition from pink to blue occurs.
So if I just if I didn't have these two instances if I only change the color to blue one time halfway
through sunrise or the let's call it golden hour between pink and blue would take a long time until
it gets to halfway and then it would not stay blue at all it would be pure blue for one moment and then
it would start transitioning back to pink.
But in reality the sky is blue for a long time in the day.
There's only a short moment where it goes from pink or yellow or whatever color the sky is at sunrise
until it turns full blue.
So that's why I did it.
But I'll show you if we put in 50 percent and I just make background color blue.
Then of course we now need to get this running but we have it defined.
We'll go up to our body.
This is the sky right here.
This is the thing that we're changing so if I made this pink You can see that's what we want to affect.
So we'll add our animation name which was Cycle sky colors colors or colored colors and then we need
to do a couple of other things.
Animation duration how long should it take let's say five seconds to start.
And as soon as I say we can see it runs but of course only runs one time and then we're done.
So let's change that to animation iteration count infinite.
And let's just add animation to play zero which we don't have to be explicit about but it's better to
do that.
OK.
So what keeps you running.
Now if we pay attention to this you'll see that.
Oh.
Another thing that we could do before I forget is add animation timing function.
Let's make that linear.
So that we have the same transitions between all of them.
So let's start off okay.
And those black very quick to pink and it transitions to blue and then a long transition to pink.
But if I change the order here instead of doing 50 percent it should be blue.
If I instead say at 30 percent and 70 percent we want it to go back to blue.
You'll see now that it stays blue for a long while in the middle and then goes back to pink.
Hopefully you can see the difference on the video.
If not if you care.
Play around with your own values or rewind and you'll definitely notice it.
So now let's focus on the sun.
So the specifics of the exact path you have the sun take the exact shades of color don't matter really
what I want to see is that you have a sun starting roughly in the bottom left and in the bottom right
and it goes up at some point and comes back down.
Now the angles and everything doesn't matter.
Maybe you want to make it a nicer arc.
This is not really that accurate for how the sun actually moves but the keyframes that I defined the
percentages are zero 25 50 75 and 100 percent.
And we'll start getting it to move.
We'll ignore the color until the end.
So to move what we're going to do we could we have a couple options but the one we use is transform
translate.
That's the best the most optimal way to move an item on the page as far as the browser rendering process.
As I explained in a previous video so we'll hop over to Copenhagen and the first thing we'll do is define
that animation.
So keyframes let's call it Sun motion.
Sort of sounds like a startup name or something on motion.
So we have that in there and the next thing that we'll do is let's start with just zero percent and
then 100 percent.
So the start and the Finish we'll have it move across the screen on the x axis.
So at 0 percent we'll do transform translate as to zero pixels comment your pixels We'll have it start
where it is.
But then at 100 percent
we'll have it move over to the right part of the screen and this number will depend on your your screen
and basically the computer you are using so I'm going to do 1920 pixels.
It doesn't really matter what you do do something experiment with a number that works best but don't
spend too much time.
So we have that defined.
Now we need to go and assign that information to the sun selector sun motion and then we'll add in a
duration.
Make it match what we have for the sky which is five seconds.
And if we hit save you'll see it starts moving not only goes once.
Let's be explicit and add an animation iteration count which should be infinite and also add an estimation
timing function which should be linear for us.
OK so we have the sun moving across the screen and it keeps going.
If I zoom out you can actually see how far it goes all the way to the edge of the screen.
And then wraps around it.
There's a couple things that are different though than the solution.
If you look here and let me zoom out to 100 percent you'll see that the sun actually sets below the
grass.
So that's something to consider.
We'll come back to that.
Let's now focus on the 25 50 and 75 percent frames.
So we'll go back and define those zoom back in so you can read this a bit better.
Here we go.
So at our 25 percent are 50 percent and 75 percent and inside of them we'll be doing a transform translates
so I'll copy that but we're going to have different numbers of course.
So the numbers that I have personally for this first one are going to go to 330 pixels at 25 percent
followed by zero pixels Y.
And then we'll go to 860 for our halfway point.
And we're also going to go negative 50 on the y axis which will make it rise up and get cut off a little
bit by the top of the page which is a choice that I made I want it to continue to move upwards.
Then we have 75 percent which will have sort of 1920.
We have 13 ninety pixels 0 pixels on the y axis.
So if I save and I zoom out you'll see that I have a rough arc but it's not quite there based off of
the start.
And it kind of started setting and then it flattened out.
So to fix that I will translate 200 pixels down on the y axis at the beginning.
So it rises from below and you will also end 200 pixels below and define zoom out to 100 percent.
If you take a look it's close but there's still a problem over here where the starting position of the
sun is already on screen on the x coordinate as well.
So you can see it starts about over here.
Not in the corner.
So we can change that by just shifting it minus 200 pixels to the left.
And now you'll see it starts rising from the corner and setting in the corner.
But like I said in the assignment video did not want you to get hung up on the exact coordinates.
It can be frustrating.
What's more important is that you just have it going up and down.
It could be setting or rising here and setting here for all I care.
So the last thing is the color.
So if we go back to our guide it should be orange here and then change to yellow at 25 percent and then
yellow and yellow for 50 and 75 and change to red or orange red at 100 percent.
So we can do that very easily.
All we want to say is that 0 percent background color should be orange.
And then at 25 percent should change to yellow.
And then at 100 percent we want it to go back will not go back.
But we want to make it read is is close but you'll see that it's yellow and then it starts changing
to read the entire way down basically between 25 and 100.
We don't want that.
So we're going to duplicate background color yellow at 75 percent.
So it should stay yellow from 25 to 75.
You can see it now it starts transitioning.
Perfect.
So let me slow everything down so we can just take a closer look.
Ten seconds.
And also this one should be at 10 seconds.
They start at the same time there's no delay.
Now you can see that it goes pink for a bit the sky stays blue for a long time as does the sun with
yellow.
And then they both transition to sunset colors sunsets and it starts over.
So we have two animations going with two different sets of intervals.
We're doing quarters over here even quarters in here we're working with zero 10 30 70 and so on.
Now if you do care about the exact hexadecimal codes that are used you can come over here and look at
them inside of the code pen.
Basically I just use typical flat colors instead of doing the default USS Blue or yellow.
I use these hexadecimal codes.
So if you want look at the solution that I've posted and you can use those exact colors if you care.
All right.
So that wraps up the exercise.
Hopefully you are able to see how easy it is to actually get a keyframe animation working maybe how
frustrating it can be to to deal with animating translations transformations dealing with pixels and
coordinates and all that.
Either way hopefully I had a good experience.
All right.
That wraps it up.