Welcome back in this exercise your goal is to build a new visualization that incorporates a tooltip
and transitions while pulling data from an external file.
There are a number of free data sources online.
You can look at data from the UN the United States Census the World Bank or something else you find
on your own.
I've provided a few links in the resources.
Here's a sample project you could build.
I've pulled a bunch of data from the World Bank so that I can graph methane versus CO2 emissions per
capita for different regions around the world.
I'm also visualizing the percentage of energy consumption that comes from renewables with the fill green
circles represent regions with a higher proportion of renewable energy use.
Lastly the size of the circle corresponds to the fraction of the region's population that is urban larger
circles correspond to regions that are more urban as you can see.
I've got a tool tip that provides details when I mouse over a circle.
I've also got a range and but update the year on page load and when I update the year the circles don't
move automatically.
Instead they transition smoothly between their previous state and their new state this visualization
is a little more advanced because I had to pull data from a few different cxxviii files but even though
the amount of data being graphed is substantial.
The code I used here is all stuff I've seen before.
Good luck working on your own visualization.
Make sure to create your own tool tip.
Add some transitions and pull data from an external file source using one of the methods we learned
about in the last video such as D-3 dots ESV or D-3 digests on.
I'll show you my code for this visualization in the next video.