Either in this exercise I'd like you to use what you've learned so far to build scatterplot your scatterplot
it should include label the axes and the title you can use whatever data you like but if you want to
just get started quickly and the resources you can find a javascript file with a bunch of miscellaneous
statistics from different countries and regions around the world.
All of this data comes from the data sets on data dot UN dot org specific data sets I uphold are under
W.H. 00 data.
Then World Health Statistics then demographic and socio economic statistics I've put together a few
of these datasets into one javascript file.
I was curious about cellular subscriptions per 100 people.
Literacy rates for those aged 15 and up.
Population growth rate fraction of the population that lives in urban areas.
Fraction of the population that lives on less than $1 per day and median age.
So these are the keys that each object has.
Note that not all countries had data for each one of these variables.
If there was no data set the value to null.
Note also that there may be some slight variation in the year of the data.
Most data points come from 2012 though some may be a year or two older.
I've only kept the most recent data point for each one of these regions and each variable I use this
data to throw together a quick scatterplot.
As you can see from my labels I've graphed cellular subscriptions on the y axis and literacy rate on
the x axis I visualize two other parameters by adjusting the fill in radius for each circle.
But if you want to know what exactly those attributes are measuring you'll need to check out the solution.
For now I just start playing around with this data and seeing what kind of visualizations you can come
up with.
Good luck building your scatterplot if you get stuck.
You can see how I approach the problem in the next video.