OK so we're going to start right off by installing Noj.
Yes.
And the way I'm going to do this might be familiar to some view if you've taken online courses before
anything on to me are going to be using Cloud 9.
So Cloud Nine is a web based developer environment.
It's an I.D. It's awesome it's free.
Basically what Amazon owns it now actually.
And when you create a new workspace on there which is what we'll do will create a node workspace.
It installs note on the computer somewhere on Amazon servers and gives it to us for free.
Now it is a paid product if you're trying to scale up a giant company or something you want hundreds
of accounts.
But if you're just using it for your own personal use it's totally free.
So we're going to use it.
You do not have to.
That will be included instructions if you want to brave installing things on your own.
Just know that especially Mongo can be a pain to install on your own environment.
If you have other databases or you've tried to install Monga before or if you happen to be on a PC that's
probably the biggest problem and I have a lot of students who use PCs.
So I highly recommend that you use cloud 9 just for this course.
And again you don't have to.
But I think that you should just to make things smooth so we can get to react.
So the way that it works if you go to C9 IO is also included as a resource.
You just need to create an account using your e-mail address.
They will ask for a credit card but you will not be charged anything.
It's totally free.
There's no surprise payments that pop up no subscription unless you opt into that.
The only reason they want a credit card is to prevent spam prevent people from abusing the system.
If you do not have a credit card as a absolute last resort and there are instructions following this
lecture about getting an invite to our course workspace which will then allow you to create your own
account without a credit card but just be conscientious.
It can take a bit of time for us to respond to that.
But if you do need that if you're in that boat and you're willing to wait a couple hours or a day or
two then follow the instructions that are after this lecture about getting an account for free without
a credit card.
But again they will not charge you.
So create an account here sign up.
And once you finish that you should see something like this although you probably will not have all
these workspaces here.
You definitely want.
These are all different environments that I've created with essentially a single click.
So I have some Python environment.
I have some node environments.
What else do I have my ask.
Well environment.
Basically everything that you could want at your fingertips.
The single click.
I think it's pretty awesome.
So we're going to click on Create a new workspace and we're going to give it a name.
Call it whatever you want to call mine WPB part two and I'm going to make it public.
And I'm also going to select the node j as a template.
So this is all we have to do to actually create our own node environment might take a moment.
I'll fast forward through this and before you know it we're done.
So you should see here is the idea.
So we have a couple of components.
There's really three things I'd break it down into.
We have our file nav bar over here.
Her navigator.
So these are all the folders and files contained in our workspace.
And these are just here by default when you create a new workspace.
We're going to delete them all.
It's just kind of showing you some sample stuff so it's not totally empty.
Then over here we have our command line or we can enter commands you can list all the files we can navigate
directories will start our server here we'll install Mongo down here and then here we have our actual
Ed..
So if you want to look at a file let's say the server does.
Yes.
Which we didn't write.
We can see the code here.
I can edit it I can it save command s or control us or you could also go and delete that appear to file
save.
So the last thing I'll do in this video is just show you how to run this application.
We didn't build it but might as well try running it.
So if we make sure we're in the same directory as our server J S file and we just run node server.
Yes and that means things are working as long as you don't get an error.
So if you can just type node and you get this node Seelye or you can start typing javascript you're
all good.
So as far as the actual server itself.
Boy how do I get out of here.
OK so if we run our server the last thing we need to talk about is how we actually view the application
and to do that you go to preview preview running application it will open it up over here.
What I liked to do is actually copy that close out of it and open a new tab and just keep the app running
here.
So what we see right now is the default chat example they build for us.
I should mention that I'm probably really zoomed in and it looks I assume different for you on your
computer but the main idea is that we have this little application that's running a node server.
We're going to delete it all.
So don't get too attached to it and replace it with our own node app in the next video.