Welcome back.
In this video we're going to talk about how to write more efficient tests.
Let's take a look at an example and see if you can answer the question.
What's not great about this code.
Here we have some code that is testing the push method on arrays.
In each of our blocks we are creating in our variable and then testing different parts of what the push
method does including its return value and what values it accepts.
You are defining the R variable each time.
Since we don't want our tests to share the same variable and produce unexpected output.
If we were to run these tests everything would pass.
But there's something that's not great about this code.
Notice how much repetition is going on here.
We are defining the variable three times.
It would be really nice if we could just define this once and not repeat ourselves.
Thankfully Jasmine has a wonderful way to do this using a built in function called before each before
each picks up a callback that will be run before the callback to each function.
Let's see what that looks like.
Notice here that we are declaring the variable inside of the callback to describe and then assigning
it to an array inside of a callback to before each.
You might be wondering why do we need to do that.
The reason is because of scoping in javascript.
If we place the marquee word inside of the callback to before each then that variable would only be
accessible inside of the callback to before each and nowhere else.
If we declare the variable outside of the before each we can access it inside of inner functions we'll
see what that looks like.
Now notice that we only have to define our once and each callback to the IT function has an R variable
that gets redefined each time the same way that we can run code before each callback.
We can run code after each callback using the after each keyword.
Let's see an example here before each callback to the function we are adding 1 to our count variable
and then after each callback to the function we are resetting the count to zero.
The idea here is that we can use after each to reset variables used between tests.
This is also called a tear down and is useful when ensuring that your data stays the same between tests.
You will very commonly see teardown code and testing databases to ensure that you start and end with
the same sample data.
If you find yourself in a situation where you want to create a variable that persists among all tests
you can use the before all and after all functions.
This is not as common since it can lead to unintended side effects but you may find yourself needing
it.
Here's a short example with using before all.
Notice that the code is similar to before each of the variable we create only gets defined once and
is shared amongst all the tests.
The next thing we're going to look at is how we can structure larger test weeks by nesting describe
blocks.
Remember that we said that describe is how we can express a specific level topic that we will test.
We can also nest describe blocks if we are describing quite a few things here we are describing arrays
and then describing specific methods for arrays inside of each of these inner describe blocks.
We can place it blocks.
The idea here is that we want to test arrays but arrays are a very large topic.
So we'll break it down into smaller describe blocks in each of these describe blocks will cover individual
array methods.
Another thing we can do in writing tests is mark them as pending.
This is commonly done when we don't know exactly what we'll be testing or if we do not want to run a
specific test.
We can market test as pending or either emitting a callback function to the IT function adding the pending
function inside or simply placing an X before the function.
Finally let's discuss one more thing you will see inside of each.
It callback function.
You might be wondering how many expect functions should we use perfit block the rule of thumb here is
if the testing of one unit needs more than one expect use more.
Just make sure you are not testing several aspects of a unit which do not belong together in a single
one test case.
Here we have an example that is not great because we are testing different pieces of functionality.
A better alternative is to use seperate blocks.
But if you're testing the same unit you can have more than one expect block and especially when testing
larger units.
You will most often have multiple expect functions inside of an IT function in the next video.
We'll discuss how to better test our functions using spies zylon.