OK.
So next we want to get the forum to work.
And for that to work type some thing.
So we'll have a listener to check if I hit the enter key.
There's no button.
So we're just going to check if I hit the enter key if I do or the user does.
And we're going to take the data in here send a new post request to our create route which is slash
API I-Slash to do so we're going to send the data from here.
We're going to send that to the server hopefully get something good back and if we do if it was a successful
insert we're going to show it and add it to the page.
And if there's a problem then we won't.
So let's try it.
The first thing we'll do is add an event listener to see what's happening with our input.
If someone's typing into it so we'll do that in our document ready.
Do a dollar sign and we're going to select the input which you look at here.
I gave it an idea of to do input.
So we'll select that with that hash sign pounds on Octa Thorpe and we're going to add a dot key press
function and I'm going to in here check what key was pressed.
So if you're not familiar with this there are key codes and the Enter key has a key code of 13.
So we're going to add an if statement that says if event which and which contains the key code value
which if it equals 13.
What we're going to do is create to do so just to convert that log.
You hit enter.
So we make sure it's only working when I hit the enter key.
So let's try it now refresh my page type nothing happens and I'm going to hit enter in 3 to 1 perfect
and I'm doing it again and other kids still don't affect it only when I hit enter.
OK.
So that's what we want.
So rather than adding all my code in here I'm just going to create a function.
I'll call it create to do just like that doesn't exist yet.
So when you hit enter in the input we're going to call create to do.
So that means down here I need to define create to do so and here we're going to send request to create
new to do.
And the way we do that we need to send a post request.
As we've already discussed to slash API slash to do the same you know.
But we can't use get JS on because we're not doing a get request.
So we need a post request.
And the easiest way to do that is with Dollar Sign up post.
So we're going to pass an R U R L and just remove that.
There we go.
And on its own that's not enough because we also need to provide the data and the data we want to send
is whatever's in the input.
So if we go back to postman we could model this request if we send a post to slash API slash to Duse
remember that we have a name field that removes remove some of these in the body and we want name to
be equal to walk the fish or something.
Or you know wash the fish or something like that.
So basically you want to extract what's in the form and send it through under the key of name.
So back here we're going to create an object and we're going to pass in name but what's the value.
How do we get what's in the form.
Well I'll make a variable here and I'll just call it user input equals and we need to select that input
which is what we did earlier appear right there where you go to do input as an ID dot Vau and that's
going to give us the value in there.
So we could just do a count about log user input.
Make sure it's working.
Let's tested up.
So we're not sending a request yet but whatever I type in here.
Hello.
When I hit enter it should show up.
Perfect.
So that's what we want to send whatever a hit Enter we want to take that value which we've already extracted
and we want to send it on in our post request.
So I'm going to uncomment that remove or cancel that log.
So we're going to set name equal to user input.
So again we're making an object name colon whatever's in the form which we extracted appear send that
as a post request to slash API slash dues and then we'll add in our dot then and if it works we're going
to get something back.
Remember when we used postman we sent a request and if it's successful we get the newly created to do
back.
So I'm going to call this new to do and here we'll start by just consider logging to do and but add
a dumb catch error.
With our callback and constant log error because this is one of the more error prone things that could
happen when we're trying to insert into the database because we have those validations where things
are required like name.
So if you tried to send something somehow with a name not existing we would get an error.
So let's save this and let's see what happens.
Moment of Truth here.
So I'll open up my console and buy cheese veggies cheese by car.
How about change diet.
I hit enter and it looks good.
Looks like a request was sent because we're getting back our data where we have name change diet completed
is false created date and the auto generated ID.
If we go back here you can see our debug mode for mongers is showing the insert.
So that's working.
We're actually getting the data back.
So we're taking it from the form listening for the enter key taking the data sending it in a post request
it's coming back successfully in this case.
Now we want to update our page.
We want to insert it just like we did already when the page loaded so we could copy this code and do
the same thing where we make a new to do we check if it's completed if it is we assign a class and then
we append it but I'm going to use it by turning it into its own function.
So I'm going to make a function I'm going to call it add to do singular just like this.
And there's one argument we'll call it to do.
And so for each one at the beginning of the page when it loads we're calling add to deuce and we're
just going to call add to do for each to do.
So basically we've just moved it out into its own function.
Functionality has not changed though so so far we are fresh the page things still work but now we're
also going to call add to do when our post request comes back.
So we're going to do.
Add to do Cingular and we're going to pass in New to do.
So if that makes sense we're reusing this code that we already wrote.
So when we loop through all of them we're just calling out to do to insert each one one at a time.
As you can see this is our code.
We're doing the same operation just once when we try and create a new one and we get a successful response.
Let's see does it work change diet by cheese.
How about I don't know brew cider.
I don't like cider I don't know why I'm doing that.
I hit enter.
I did it twice.
And now we have two of them.
And the reason I did it twice is that I initially thought it didn't work because our texture was still
here.
Usually it should go away.
But of course we haven't done anything to make that happen.
So it's just my own user expectations.
I'm used to something clearing.
So let's add that in now if our post request comes back successful we'll add the new to do.
But we'll also clear the input.
So I'm actually just going to call this line again.
But I'm going to pass an empty string so instead of retrieving the input value like we're doing here
we are setting it to empty string.
And now I refresh the page.
How about thick sunglasses.
That's a real one.
I need to do.
I broke my sunglasses yesterday.
There you go.
So it inserts it sends the post request first.
And this is actually an important topic.
We don't have to send the request first.
Wait for it to come back successful and then update the page.
Another approach is actually to just assume that it's going to work and added to the page first and
then if the request comes back with a bad response we can remove it from the page.
So that's a more optimistic approach.
And the idea is that it's faster from the user's point of view.
If you look here you know this happened to really really quick.
But if we were trying to send a lot more data or wait for a lot more data to come back somehow the server
the request was really slow then a user could be waiting for a while to see their to do show up.
But then the problem is ok if it doesn't work it's kind of a weird experience where users see it show
up and then have it removed a couple milliseconds or seconds later.
So up to you but this is the more standard way of doing it is sending it to the server making sure it
works and then updating.
Cool.
So that's now working.
We're able to load the page get all the traduce.
Right now only one of them is completed in our database.
So we don't have the functionality to mark them completed yet and we don't have the functionality to
delete them but we can create a new one and I'm not going to because I'm out of ideas and I don't like
doing jibberish but does work.
We saw it.
So next we're going to add the delete functionality and that one actually requires a little more work
because when we click on one of these first we need to add the delete button.
But then once we click on the delete button how do we know where to send the request.
What's the URL so that's kind of the puzzle we have to solve the next video.