Now we'll talk about a really important concept in re-act called prop's So this is what we'll be using
extensively to hold immutable data.
Our objectives for this video will be to define props and to use props inside of a component.
First of all what are props.
Well props are immutable data is passed into your component and it's accessible in your component as
an object called the Stop props.
So imagine we have this show text component and we had a parameter passed in as a prop called text.
We have access to that parameter via Vistar props and the note here says that this refers to the instance
of show text.
So if you're a member of the key word this in this case this will be referring to the instance of this
class.
So this class instance has an object called props.
And one of the keys of that object is text.
Since this is a normal javascript object with a property when we put it in the curly braces here the
string that comes back will be the string was displayed in the view.
So how do we pass a prop in.
Well when we use GSX to render show text we just added as a an attribute basically.
So this is a prop called text and the value that prop is going to be.
This is a proper name text and this is what our code looks like except without the comment.
I mentioned this already but it's really important and worth repeating.
Props are immutable so you cannot change this stuff props in the first example here.
This not props not text equals something Caza type air.
So re-act won't let you do this at all but you can do this in your reactive component and you should
never ever ever do this.
The idea of a prop is that it's immutable.
So when you change the stop process in your render method your you're breaking things and reacts in
this last example.
You might be thinking that you want to create a prop that the user didn't provide for you.
And this again is the wrong way to do it.
So we'll learn something later called default prop's that it's the proper way to set initial props that
the user didn't provide you.
But again this is incorrect.
Never ever create a new property that doesn't exist on this dot probs.
So all of these examples just to make it crystal clear are wrong.
You should not do any of these things.
Never ever ever change the stop prop's in your component.
Next up will write some code and get more practice with prop's.