In this next video we're going to talk about GSX.
Now if you remember last video we made our first Riak component.
But I'd argue it was a little difficult to write especially having to create every dom element using
that big long function name.
So in this video we're going to learn about GSX which would hopefully simplify that.
Our objectives will be to first define Babel transpire.
We'll talk about that more soon and then use GSX in our first Riak component so we'll refactor that
component we create in the last video to now use GSX.
So first of all what is Babel.
Well Babel is a trans piler and trans Pilar's something that converts from one type of source code to
another type babbel started out as a trans piler from E.S. sixty five.
But after a little bit browsers started implementing a lot of the six features and Babel was becoming
less necessary.
So it changed his goal from being a trans pilot just from sixty five into a general purpose transpire.
So now in re-act we use Babel to convert GSX into vanilla javascript.
In other words we no longer have to write the re-act arm factories code because GSX will be a replacement
for that.
But we can still use Babel to trans pile our GSX code into something that is essentially still vanilla
javascript.
Now let's go back to our last example and refactor it to use GSX.
Here's our code from last example.
And if you remember it's a pet component that we're rendering in the DOM and we get a web page that
looks like this.
There is Moxey And that's our image and our age too.
We can do better than this example though by using GSX.
So the first thing that we'll have to do in order to use GSX is to incorporate babbel and other we're
using GSX we no longer need this re-act bomb factories.
So I'm going to replace react on factories with Babbel.
There you go.
Now I'm including the babbel javascript file rather than the factories file and the next thing I'll
have to do is change this script tag from type text javascript to a type text Babbel.
So this tells babbel that this is not normal javascript.
This is a file that it needs to Tran's pile into javascript.
So now that we've done that we can start using GSX And what does jazz X look like.
Well it looks like returning h M-L from within your javascript code so we can react to this whole example
to be a very simple return
div h to Occy and then our image tag.
I'll just grab this your show here
and then we also want to include all texts
and an important thing to note is that all jazz X tags must be closed.
So even though unnormalized see him and get away with this in jazz sax it will give me an error unless
I close it so I can either close it like that with a self-closing tag or I can close it this way.
Either one is fine.
And I tend to use the self-closing way rather than having extra typing.
And lastly we need to close out our death.
All right.
So as you can see this looks much tighter.
Right we don't have to call these functions and create all these variables just to get some summation
Chmela render.
So let's comment this out and see what it looks like in the browser.
So I refresh the page and we got the same result which is what we expect.
If you look in the console though you'll see a warning and make that a bit bigger.
This warning here is what I'm talking about.
It's essentially telling you that babbel is very slow.
Specifically this babbel file is run when the page loads the trans piling from GSX to vanilla.
Javascript is a time consuming process.
And later on we're going to use some tools that will do it for us head of time so that the browser does
not have to do it when it downloads the file.
There's one last thing that we need to clean up so let's get rid of all this commented out code we no
longer need it.
We no longer have to use create element anymore.
We can use GSX here as well.
So I'll just get rid of that.
And remember always to close your tags.
So now this should run just fine in the browser and it's I'd argue much easier to read and simpler.
Next we'll learn about more things that we can do a GSX specifically using javascript inside of our
GSX code.