Welcome back.
We've already built the bulk of this marketing page in this video.
We'll finish things up by adding sections for testimonials.
A contact area and the FOTR first a section for testimonials
as with my other sections.
I'll start with the title and an H.R.
then for each testimonial.
Add to be tag's one for the quote and one for the author of that quote.
I'll include three testimonials so that six p tags are pentagonal
these testimonials will come from cold Ellie in 10 to save time.
I'll quickly paste in what they have to say about their love for mountains
this already listees.
I'll just add a few style rules for the quotes
bump up the font size.
Then out the font weight
decrease the line height from the default for r p tags and include some margin.
I'm satisfied with how this looks.
Let's move on to the next section.
By now the pattern for these sections should be familiar.
After creating a section and giving it a class inside of it.
I'll make an H-3 a p tag and then a char
next below the H R O out of form to grab people's email addresses.
Let's save
this form doesn't look so great but everything else is in the shape so let's hop back into the style
sheet and add some form styles.
I'll use fluxbox for the form Santror things
wrap the content
and set it with
next I'll give the buttons and Patti
I'll give the form put some padding to as well as some margin
then I'll update the font size and color
and lastly use the flex property to ensure that the input takes up the rest of the available space.
Nice.
Our firm doesn't do anything but at least it looks good.
Lastly let's take care of the FOTR how out of FOTR tag and inside of it.
Put three children
a couple of tags and a list for social media icons
inside of this UL o icons for Twitter
Facebook and snap chat.
And inside of my PITA's I'll paste in some text
OK.
Let's tackle this stylin
once again.
I'll rely on flex box pretty heavily.
I'll set my footers use fluxbox and all line items to the center and justify the content so that elements
have space around them.
I'll also set the background color font color and padding.
I also use fluxbox for the UL and give each L-lysine margin on the left
then for the tags.
I'll make the tax all uppercase
decrease the font size reduce the opacity and vertically align the elements in the center using Fluxbox.
There we go.
This completes the silent for our marketing page in the next video.
We'll add some media queries to make their design more responsive.
I'll see you there.