Welcome back.
Let's talk about a solution to this do application.
So remember it looks like this.
We've got our input.
We can save it to do and then we'll see the list of studies here.
So let's think a second about what state we need.
Well we know we're going to keep a list of to do's.
So an array of these strings would probably make sense for one thing in our state.
The other piece of state that we're going to need to keep Is this form input.
So every time I type a letter the input for that form will need to be updated.
Let's take a look at the code.
So here's my solution.
Let's start with the constructor and talk about the state.
So we've got the standard beginning of the constructor here we're going to get the props and then call
super props.
The next thing that we're going to do is create the state and the state like I said it's going to consist
of two things the array of tattoos that we're storing that we've saved so far.
And then this new tree will be the contents of that input.
So any time something is typed in the input that new to do will be updated.
Now let's take a look at the render method.
In render first of all here we're going over each to do list of Zeus and mapping them into GSX elements
and this to do item I have up top.
So let's talk about that 2 item here is just a statelets functional component.
And honestly I probably could have just left it as an ally because there's really not a lot going on
here.
But just to have multiple components going on.
So this to do item just takes in a prop for text and then uses it inside.
Now remember this is destructuring that parameter.
So I could have also just left this as props and said props that text here.
But you'll see the shorthand often so I'll leave it that way.
I should say that destructuring often OK.
So that's how we get our traduce and then also here we're grabbing the new to do out of state.
Now we need this new to do for the value in our input so down here the GSX is a form inside the form
we've got an input for that new to do that we want to type.
The main thing the important piece is that the value is equal to the state new to do.
Remember that's coming from the destructuring up here.
And the onchange we're setting new state now this I haven't talked about yet so I'll talk about now
I could have also written this rather than what I've got now as new to do.
So every time I want to change something I'll just use new to do eat at target value.
But if I've got multiple things multiple inputs in my form.
This gets tedious because you have to write a different function for every one.
So another way to do this is to base the the key in your new state object off of whatever the name of
that input is.
So here I'm saying I want the key to be equal to e dots targets that name and the name here is being
set up here.
So this name new to do has to match the key that's in my state.
If that's the case if the name matches the key then this key will be correct.
The key will be the same as new to do.
And I can update my state this way.
So that's a useful trick that we'll use later on in the course.
Something that's up on change we'll set the stage.
And now every time you type a key the new View will be equal to whatever you typed in at this point.
And we've got to submit button just like I mentioned in the last video it's important not to put your
unclick here in order to capture the summit.
That's not actually a summit event.
If you want to submit you want to put your on submit handler up here in the form.
Now what happens on Submit.
Well that's being handled up here in this Hammill submit method.
And this is basically exactly like the example we saw in the video last time.
We've got all the tattoos that we're spreading out inside this new array and then we're adding one more
to do which is whatever the current value of new to do is.
And then when we update the state we're updating that new to use array and we're also setting that form
back to empty so that we can type in something else.
I have to delete it or to type in a new value.
And also it's important here that I have this dot submit equals this thought handle Samit that bind
this.
Remember we need that because without that inside of this callback function this would not refer to
our component.
And if this doesn't refer to the component set state won't exist.
So we need this bind in order to make this line of code work.
The last piece here is just rendering those to.
So remember we've translated Our Jews into GSX and now down here at the bottom we just got an ordered
list of those two items.
I also added some CSSA for this.
I put display flex around the hole up.
I've centered everything and I've done flex direction comb.
That's why they're stacking on top of each other.
I've also made a few things larger.
Just some small edits.
If you're curious about that go ahead and check it out but I think all this stuff should be pretty intuitive
to you.
All right.
That's it.
That's our application.
And again this gives us this nice feature.
Next up we'll talk a little bit about Raf's.