So in the last section we started adding some information about our user but we said that worst during
this password in plain text which is not very good.
So what we want to do is the second before we save the user in the database we want to go and modify
that password.
We're going to modify it by hashing or turning that password into some string of text that can't be
understood.
And we're going to do that using what's called a hook.
And we add our hooks before the save.
So we're going to be adding a hook on a user schema and the hook is going to be a pre C.
What does that mean.
A pre hook for this document.
Right before we save this document Let's run a function.
But let's just not run a regular function.
Let's run in async function.
And we're going to run an easing function so that we can use that a weak keyword.
You might have not seen this syntax before but this is quite modern and we're going to see a lot more
newer node code bases especially ones that have lots of asynchronous actions so to handle our errors
we're going to use a try catch block and inside of this try block we are going to quickly see if this
user is not modified the password because if you have not modified the password we want to then move
on to the next thing.
But what does this idea of the next thing.
What is that next piece of middleware that we might want to move on to.
That is a parameter that is passed to this function.
You can call it whatever you want but very commonly you'll see that as next and this simply means move
on.
You've saved that document will go ahead and save it now.
So we will return next.
And this is simply meaning if you have not changed the password Well don't go and hash it again if the
password has not been changed at all.
Don't mess with it.
So what we're going to do now is make a variable that we'll call hash password and that is the result
of decrypt dot hash and that accepts some kind of password which in this case is going to be the password
for this specific document.
We get access to that using the keyword this.
And then what is called a salt or work factor.
And I want to get too into this idea of encryption but the idea of salting is taking a bit of additional
information and putting it into the hash so that the hashes are different for the same password.
Remember if we were to just take a piece of text and hash it into something someone else could potentially
build a table that does that same exact algorithm and it figures out what hash corresponds to a password.
So once again I don't want to get too into the cryptography of things but something is an additional
step that is very important to make sure that we're securely storing our passwords.
The problem here is that be creeped out hash is an asynchronous action.
So we are going to wait until that finishes.
And once it has finished we are going to set the password property on this document to be that hashed
password.
But we're going to do after is simply return next the next idea is simply just saving if anything goes
wrong.
We're also going to return next.
But remember when we pass an error to next it is going to go to our error handler.
So you're going to see this pattern of next error very frequently.
So right now we're doing a really good job of hashing that password.
But what I also want to write is a bit of a helper function for our user.
So we are going to add one more thing to our schema.
We're going to add a method.
This is the idea of an instance method or a method that every document that we create from this model
has and it's going to be called compair password.
You may have seen this before but we're going to do it a little bit differently by making this another
easting function and inside of here we're going to get some kind of password.
We'll call this candidate password.
This is simply going to be a password that's coming in the form as well as the next.
Remember these actions are all asynchronous.
So we need to tell express when to move on to the next piece of middleware.
Once again we'll place a try catch block to handle any kind of error.
And we will get the result of the script that compare.
We'll get any variable called match.
And we are going to wait for the crypt compare to resolve the crypt compare excepts some kind of password.
We can see right here any kind of data right here that's going to refer to the data to be encrypted.
Remember the idea of checking if the password is correct is read encrypting the plaintext password that
someone puts in a form and seeing if it is the same thing as whatever our encrypted string is in the
database.
And that refers to destock password.
This is going to refer to the individual document that we're calling this on.
This right here is actually going to return true or false.
So we're simply going to return.
That is match property and in our route's we're going to say well if it matches true you've logged in
successfully.
If not you get to tell you invalid user name or password down here.
Once again we're going to return next with her.
So what have we done here.
We've added a pre-sale hook before each it in Mongoose is saved we're going to run this async function.
It's going to wait for the password to hash is going to set that password to be the hash password.
And then it's going to move on to the next piece of middleware which is actually saving that specific
document.
That way we save documents in the database with a hash password.
The second thing we did is build a simple password comparison function so that every document that we
make from this user model has the ability to compare another hashed password with their password in
the database we're going to be using this to make sure that users have successfully put in the right
password.
So that's really all we need to do for our user Geass.
The next step is to start adding some routes and testing them using HDMI.
So we're going to focus on next is building some routes and some handlers for our users.