Welcome back in this section we'll learn about two of the more advanced types of visualizations that
you can build with the three maps and forced direct and graphs these visualizations can be really cool
to look at.
But before we jump in and start building it's important to understand some of the underlying concepts
first.
Here are our goals for this section.
In this video we'll introduce an encoding standard for geographic data Collegio Jaison and we'll see
how to use DOJ start with the three in the next video we'll learn about an extension of Geogia song
called Toppo Jason and compare and contrast the two.
We'll also see how to convert between typologies sun and patho elements.
After that we'll build off of what we've learned and create a map visualization with the three.
Then we'll switch gears and talk about the basics of force directed graphs.
We'll begin by talking about the building blocks for these visualizations nodes and links will also
describe what a force simulation is and how it works and explore different types of forces you can simulate.
Finally we'll apply what we've learned about force directed graphs to a real data set.
Let's get started by learning about creating maps with E3 to give you an idea of where we're headed.
Let me quickly demo what will be building later on in this section.
Here I have a map of the world with countries filled in based on their population.
As you can see countries with high populations like China and India have a deep purple color.
While countries with smaller populations have a lighter shade.
I've also got a drop down here so that I can adjust the heat map based on other statistics like population
density median age and fertility rate.
If we look into the elements tab we can see that each country is just a patho element in the squeegie
that the attributes can get quite complicated but at least these are SVGA elements we've seen before.
If you're concerned that you'll have to write all of these commands yourself.
Don't worry D-3 takes care of most of this work for us.
The approach will be similar to what we saw with pie charts.
Remember that when we wanted to build a pie chart we used D-3 helper methods to translate our data into
valid strings for the D attribute of our paths.
The same will be true here.
But if our output is a string of commands for the path element what should our input be.
Here's where G.O. Jaison enters the picture.
G.O. Jaison is a standardized way to encode geographic information.
It's based on Jason.
So if you look at the DOJ file the syntax should look pretty familiar.
We won't get into the DOJ suspect here.
You can check out the resources for this video if you want to learn more about it for now.
All you need to know is that a Jason object has a features property whose value is an array of objects
that encode data about shapes Let's take a look and a simple example.
Here's a link to the code we'll be looking at for the rest of this video.
Here I have a DOJ file just three features each feature has co-ordinate information inside of the geometry
and a bit of color information inside of the properties.
The properties key is a helpful place to store information that isn't related to the geometry of the
shape.
Let's use D-3 to convert this DOJ data into valid patho elements.
Since this is adjacent file I can use D-3 that Jason to make a request and get this data into my javascript.
If there's an error I'll throw it.
Otherwise old Oakham method called the 3. jeel pass and store the result in a variable called Pass.
We saw this pattern with pie charts and the idea is similar here.
D-3 got jeel path returns a function that will transform G.O. Jason data into a path command strings
similar to D-3 I got histogram and D-3 dark.
You can change methods on to jail as to enhance the path function it returns.
But for now we'll stick with the defaults.
Once I have my path function let me put a debugger in the code and hop into the console to see what
this function can do.
If I pass this function one of the features from my data set you can see that it converts the coordinates
into a valid path command cool.
Based on this example I can now get all of my shapes from the DOJ files to show up on the page using
the same D-3 enter pattern we've seen so many times before.
First of fixin SVGA width and height then select the SPG set.
It's with an height create some Enter nodes by joining with my features array enter and append paths
as we just saw.
I can pass each object in my features array into the path function to get the proper d attribute.
And lastly I'll Cetaphil based on the color stored in the properties object for each piece of data.
There we go.
Here are all the shapes coded in my GEORGIS on file this covers the basics of how to translate between
G.O. Jaison and patho elements using E-3 in the next video.
We'll talk about another Toppo Jason.
I'll see you there.