Welcome back.
In this video we're going to be going over solutions to the async functions exercise here.
We're going to be reacting some of the solutions to the promises exercises but we'll be using yes 2017
async functions.
Take a look at the get most followers function first will start by making sure that this is an async
function using the async keyword.
We'll then make sure that we create a variable and assign it to the result of a waiting a promise we
can take out any DOT bands and just make sure that we have the same exact output as before for the next
function starwars string.
Let's prefix this function with the async keyword and make sure that we start removing all of the dot
bands for each of our AJAX calls.
We need to make sure that we assign variables to be the result of a weighting each one of these promises.
So let's go through each one of these and make sure that nowhere there are any chance we'll make sure
that all of our AJAX calls are also prefixed with the away keyword.
Let's just make sure we name our variables appropriately and make sure we're still outputting the same
information as above.
That looks great.
And that's all for these exercises.
See you in the next video.