Hooray right we're in the homestretch.
It's time to start thinking about how to create a new message for each of these users.
So when you click on new message right now and then I-bar we're going to the correct I.D. for that user.
But we want to do is now build a form to a user to create a message.
So let's go back and head over to our main dodginess because here we need a new route to render this
form.
So that mean yes we'll make sure that we have a route that goes to slash users slash users some user
id slash messages slash new we can call them whatever we want.
We just want to make sure we get the correct user ID inside.
So I say slash users so some kind of ID slash messages slash new.
And when we go there we're going to render a component called message for
now.
We don't just want to render a message forum for anybody we want to render it only users who have logged
in.
So here's we're going introduce the idea of a higher order component.
We also call these Hock's a higher order component is simply a function that wraps another component.
So let's make a higher order component called with off usually haul are higher rated components with
something.
So with off he's going to handle validation to make sure that a user is locked in before they see that
component.
So if the user has Loddon let them go to see that component.
Otherwise take them somewhere else.
So it's only going to look like it's actually going to be very similar to other components are going
to react and component from re-act.
We're also going to import connect from reata redux and at some point that we have connect from re-act
redux because we need to connect to a redux store to see if that user is authenticated.
So right off the bat we'll export a default function and we can call this function really whatever we
like.
We'll keep an anonymous for now.
Inside will also make a function for mask the props.
And here we'll get some state from redox and we're going to grab onto props something called is authenticated
which is going to be state that current user that is authenticated that's a bullion that we're going
to use to see if the user has logged in or not will then return connect with Napster to prop's in some
kind of component will call this component authenticate.
So what does authenticate what.
Inside of this function we're going to make a class called authenticate and it's going to extend component
this function is going to accept some kind of component that will render.
So we can call that component to be rendered.
So you call it function whatever we like but we can call it with off if we like.
And this is what we're going to export.
And we'll wrap it with some kind of component to be rendered when we use it.
That's how we're going to execute that higher order component.
So instead of your we don't need to do too much.
We just need a couple of lifecycle.
That's the first one we'll use this component will mount.
So when this component mounts we want to make sure if not this not Propst is authenticated.
So basically if this process that is authenticated is false if you want to be more explicit if it's
false We're then going to say this Obstat history of push.
And since we're using Riak rather we'll have access to the history object and we can just redirect will
do the same thing with a different lifecycle method with component well.
So many of the component updates because of any kind of C-Change whether that's real estate or yak's
they will see if any of the next prop's that that component is getting there still authenticated.
So if next promise that is authenticated is also false.
We're still going to redirect the slash seinen.
So on the component first loads the users to log in.
And if the company changes for any reason we want to make sure that users are in.
And here we're just going to render and it's over render we'll just return that component to be rendered
along with any prop's.
So we've written a function that gives us a class and a class simply returns another component.
What we're going to do with this is inside of our Mingy as we're going to import with off from that
I-Slash Hock's slash with off so we can bring in our with all function.
And we're going to use it when we render our message form component.
So will that message form with our function called with off
and make sure that this is returning correctly.
Looks like we just need to make sure that our class wraps everything we'll syntax error there make sure
that Matthysse to promise is inside of the definition of the class and return is inside the definition
as well.
So here we see message form is not defined and that's inside of me and Aggi as well.
We have to make our message for him and we'll do that in the next section.