Welcome back in the last video we finished building our marketing page for mountain travel.
The site looks good on desktop but there are large pieces of the design that don't look great.
When I reduce the screen size in this video we'll finish up this project by using media queries to add
some more responsive design.
Let's do this piece by piece.
First I'll deal with the general style rules here I'll make just one change.
The sections have a lot of padding on small screens so I'll set a media query for screens that have
a max width of 800 pixels
and inside of this query I'll reduce the padding for our sections.
Next let's deal with the header.
I'll set up another media query here for the same with
on small screens.
I'll reduce the padding on the header
and also change the flux direction to column so that the list of links will drop below the mountain
travel text.
I'll also add to the bottom margin on tax so that the links have a little bit of breathing room.
Let's quickly save and refresh.
Here's what our NAV looks like now on a smaller screen.
Now let's move on to the hero area
here.
Reduce the minimum life from 100 B.H. to 600 pixels.
Also reduce the font sizes for the H-1 and H-3
and reduce the size of the button
next.
Let's make the images in our destinations section more response's
here I'll add a couple of break points one at eleven hundred pixels and one in eight hundred pixels
per screen smaller than eleven hundred pixels.
I'll grab the large and small list items.
And set the flex basis to 50 percent
on screen smaller than 800 pixels.
I'll set it to 100 percent so that each image will get its own row.
Let's take a look at this in action on small screens.
I have one image per row
then two images each taking up 50 percent.
And when the screen is wide enough the small and large classes provide different style rules for the
widths OK let's move on to the package's section
here again I'll update the fluxed basis for list items in my grid on screens that are narrower than
800 pixels.
I'll set the flex basis to 100 percent and shrink the padding
just a few more sections remaining for the testimonials.
I once again checked against a max width of 800 pixels
per smaller screens all reduce the font size and the margin for the quotes
and I reduced the font size for the author's.
Now let's move on to the form.
This doesn't look great on screen smaller than around 950 pixels.
So here I'll use a media query with a larger max width
per screens narrower than 1000 pixels.
I'll give the input a flex bases of 100 percent
and I'll remove all margin except the bottom.
Lastly we come to the FOTR
on small screens.
I'll set the fluxed direction to column
I'll also send you the text in our p tags and give them some bottom margin.
Finally I'll need to adjust the margin on the social media icons a bit so that they're centered in the
FOTR.
One more time let's save and refresh
as you can see this site now looks much better on a narrower screen.
I hope you found this project useful as you can see styling Web sites is much less painful when you're
using Fluxbox when you're ready.
Let's change gears and start learning some javascript.
You'll see him and COPEMAN next section.
I'll see you again when you get to D-3.
Have fun and I'll see you soon.