Let's talk about refs now this is a feature I don't use super often so keep that in mind as we talk
about it.
So the objective will be to first define a ref and reacts.
And secondly to use a ref on an uncontrolled input component so a ref is a direct reference to a dom
element.
And if you think about that all the things that we've done so far have not directly referenced the don't
we just provide state to react and then react decides what to do with the Don.
So refs are kind of breaking the model that reactor's created.
And straight from the Facebook docs here some use cases for refs.
You can manage focused text selection or media play that with refs trigger imperative animations.
And integrating with third party Dom libraries that's a good one for something like D-3 if you wanted
to make a re-act component that controls some D-3 visualization then it would make sense to use ref.
And this point I want to say do not use refs when you can do the same thing in re-act without it.
Refs should be considered your last option when you're thinking about how to solve a problem.
Most of the problems that you encounter will probably not need refs.
So keep that in mind.
I would definitely search around if you're trying to solve some problem the only way you can think of
solving it is with a ref.
So here's an example of using a ref on our form rather than having a controlled input like we've seen
before.
We'll leave the input uncontrolled So the browser is the one that manages all the state and re-act is
not aware of what's happening to the input.
But you'll notice inside that input We've also added a ref equals.
And this callback function that you get has access to that Dom element.
And what I'm doing inside of that callback is I'm adding a Vistar input text equals that input.
So I'm saving a reference to that Dom element into my component and then appear in the.
We can then get access to that value inside the input.
This is just a normal Dom element with that value in order to update state or anything else you want
to do with that content.
Again this is a pattern that I wouldn't recommend using.
I'd prefer to use the controlled component pattern but this is just an example of what a ref is and
what you are able to do with it.
That's all I'm going to say about refs.
If you're curious to read more I would suggest reading up in the Facebook docs on rafts.
They have a good example in there that you can follow along with.
Next let's improve our recipe app from the last section to include state.