Well I'm calling this video set state can be tricky for the simple reason that set state can sometimes
be confusing when you first start to learn about it.
So let's look at a couple of examples that will hopefully clarify a few things.
Our objectives will be to use a function as the first parameter to set state and to add a callback to
the set state to determine when the state is up to date.
So first we'll take an example of set state call that depends on a previous version of the state.
In this example we have a state where we just are keeping track of a counter.
So every time something happens we want to increment a counter.
So you might write some code that looks like this.
We're passing in a new value for counter which depends on the old value of the counter.
So inside that said state this dot state DOT counter gets incremented by one.
But the problem comes in when you do this multiple times.
So if I have a couple set states like this the value that you'll get after all these red states have
run will be too.
And that's probably not what you expected you probably wanted it to be three.
Well the reason that's happening is because you can essentially think of said State is doing this.
So when there are multiple set states that are called that are depending on the previous state.
It's kind of like doing an object assigned.
So in this assignment the counter value that we're going to get after all these objects are assigned
or over with is still just going to be too right because this starts state DOT counter never changes
and all these objects are assigned.
It's all going to be the same thing.
So how do we fix this problem.
Well sets they can actually take an update function rather than object.
So this is what you want to use whenever the the the state that you're updating depends on a previous
value for the state.
So as you can see here this function has two parameters.
The previous state and wherever our props are and then our goal is to return an object for the new state
and inside of this object we're assigning the value for the counter to be the previous state that counted
plus 1.
And when we use this function update format we're always guaranteed to get a correct value.
So again to reiterate the rule is whenever a set state depends on the previous state use a function
parameter rather than just passing an object
the other gotcha was said state is that said state is asynchronous.
So I call this Dodd said state and I provide an object with name and Tim if I'm doing some debugging
and I want to check the value of state that name right after that the update will not have happened
yet.
So this is a common error that I see all the time when people are first learning react.
They try to figure out what's going on in their application by putting a console log right after the
said State.
So this will not work.
And that's because again set state is asynchronous.
So the correct way to do this is to provide a callback parameter to set state just like this.
So in the first parameter we're providing our object or perhaps our update function depending on which
one we want to use.
The second parameter is a callback function.
You aren't provided any premises callback function and this will only be invoked after that that state
has completed.
So you know at this time that this does state that name will be the result of whatever update the tried
to run here.
So that's it.
That's our two big gotchas.
You want to use an update function whenever your update depends on a previous state and you want to
be aware that set say it is asynchronous so if you want to know once that state is finished provide
a callback function.
Next up will look at the browser plug in for re-act.