Welcome back in the last video we learned about G.O. Jaison and how to use D-3 to translate between
Geo Jaison and patho elements.
Before we move on to start building RMX though it's worth pointing out that there's sometimes another
step in this process for large sets of geographic data.
It's common to use an encoding called Toppo Jaison which is an extension of geo Jaison.
The biggest difference between these two encodings is that top Ojay sign removes duplication in the
geometry by replacing coordinates with arcs.
For example in are drawing from the last video we encoded the border between the blue and the orange
squares twice once as a side for the blue square and once as a side for the orange square top adjacent
eliminates this duplications.
And for larger data sets can often encode the same data more succinctly resulting in a smaller file
size.
There are other benefits to check out the resources.
If you'd like to learn more let's dig into an example as usual.
Here are some links.
This project is nearly the same as the one in the last video.
The only difference is that now I have a file with top OJs on data as well as the original Geogia is
on file.
Let's take a look at the top OJs file.
As you can see the geometries now have an arx property rather than a coordinates property the values
in each Ark's array are indices.
The point to this Arc's property farther down in the file.
Here we have an array of arrays where each nested array again contains an array of coordinates these
coordinates represent the arc.
The first point in each arc represents the starting point and any subsequent point represents distances
from the previous point.
For example here we see that the blue square consists of arcs at index 0 1 and 2 moving to the collection
of arcs.
We see that the first one starts at 0 100 and then goes to 100 100.
So this is the bottom side of the square the next arc starts at 100 100 and goes to 100 0.
So this is the right side.
Finally the last arc starts at 100 0 goes to 0 0 and then goes to zero 100.
These are the top and left sides.
If you see a negative x in the arcs array This reverses the direction that you travel around the arc.
The value of the negative number is called The ones complement of the index.
So to find the arc referenced by the negative number you can flip the sine and subtract 1.
For example the orange square starts with the market index 3 which consists of the left and bottom sides
next is the Arcand index for which consists of the right side of the square the last are references
minus one.
So to find that are we flip this and plus one and subtract 1 to get zero.
This means we need to use the arc index 0 but reverse direction will start at one hundred one hundred
and go to zero 100.
This is the top side of the square.
That's enough about top of J on for now let's see how we use it.
Unfortunately D-3 can't translate between top of Jaison and paths directly.
So when we use typologies on there's a two step process involved we first need to convert the top of
adjacent to Geogia so on and then we need to convert the DOJ onto that and path commands.
We've seen how to take care of the second step of the process using D-3 for the first step.
Need to use another library called conveniently enough topple Jason.
One of the key developers of typologies on is Mike Bostock who's also a developer on D-3.
So the two tools play very nicely together to translate tablemates on into Geogia.
Let me first include the Tabo adjacent library via a script tag next top into the javascript file that
we worked on in the last video.
I'll change the first argument in D-3 that Jason so that we're using the top OJs on file not the Geogia
on file previously we joined our data to the MT selection.
The data that features but now our data is in the wrong format.
It's Toppo Jaison instead of DOJ on to fix this.
We'll use the top adjacent feature method.
This method takes in an object from a top adjacent file along with a path in that object to where the
geometries are
in our case.
If we refer to our file as data we see that the geometries live in data objects collection.
So if we pass these two objects in the top adjacent that feature you can see that we get valid DOJ some
data back.
All we really need to do here is update our data join rather than joining the Davidoff features we need
to call Toppo adjacent feature pass the correct arguments and then co-features on the return value great.
We've recreated the same small demos before just with Toppo Jason instead of G.O. Jason.
One more thing before we move on now at the top are adjacent files also have scale and transform properties
that allow us to scale the image or move it around in the next video we'll see how you can scale and
translate in javascript but you can also manipulate these values directly in the Jaisalmer file.
For example if we want to stretch our shapes in the x direction and translate them over and down we
can update these properties and then refresh the page as you can see our image has been transformed.
OK.
That's it for top of Jaison now that you know the basics of transforming geographic data into patho
elements in the next video we'll build them map visualization.
I'll see you there.