Welcome back in the section we're going to talk about the filter function filter is a function that
is invoked on a race.
And just like mapping for each It accepts a callback function.
However this callback function is a little different than the one we used in for each map because the
result of the callback function will always be evaluated into a Bulliet.
Let's see how filter works just like Map filter first creates a new array and iterates through that
array and runs a callback function on each value in the array.
Here's where things get different.
If the result of the callback function with the value passed to it returns true that value will be placed
in the new array.
If the result of the callback function returns false that value will be ignored and filter will iterate
to the next value.
Always remember the result of the callback.
The filter will always be a boolean no matter what value you return to the callback filter.
It will always be converted into either true or false.
Since filter needs to know if that value should be added to the new array it creates.
That might seem a bit tricky.
So let's look at an example.
I'm going to create an array with the values 1 2 and 3 and invoke filter on it.
Remember the filter accepts a callback function as its first parameter just like for each end map.
But when using filter we have to make sure that our callback function returns true or false.
If we want to filter out all of the values that are greater than 2 we would return an expression value
greater than 2.
If you find yourself writing IF statements inside of the callback the filter go back and see if you
can refactor it to just return an expression that evaluates to TRUE or FALSE.
When I run this code I'll see an array with just the number three in it.
Great.
Notice here that I've passed three parameters to the callback.
This is just to show you that I have access to each value index and the array just like what we saw
with mapping for each.
You do not need to pass these three parameters every time.
Only the ones that you need.
Just remember the order of the parameters is important.
The first parameter to the callback function is always the value.
The second is whatever index you're at.
And the third parameter is the entire array.
Now let's look at another example.
Here we have an array called instructors and it contains four objects.
Each object has a name property and a value which will be early.
Tim mad and cold.
What I'd like to do is return a new array of objects whose value for the name property is more than
three characters long.
So I'm going to invoke the filter function on this array and pass a callback.
Remember the callback function has to return true or false so we can use an expression that evaluates
to a boolean will return value.
Namedrop length greater than 3.
Notice here we're not using an if statement.
Try not to write IF statements inside of the callback to filter which we don't need to do since we just
have to return true or false.
What we're doing here is checking to see if the name property on each object which we call value has
a length that is greater than 3.
When we run this code we get back an array of three objects.
We filtered out Tim and just like we did with for each n map.
Let's try to implement our own filter function.
Let's remember how it works.
Filter creates a new array it iterates through the array and runs a callback function on each value
in the array.
If the callback function returns true that value will be added to the new array.
If the callback function returns false that value will be ignored from the new order.
If you'd like pause the video now and try this on your own.
All right.
Let's create a function called Filter that accepts an array and a callback function will first create
a variable called New R which is an empty array will then create a for loop and initialize a variable.
A zero will loop as long as it is less than the length of the array and increment by one after each
iteration inside of the loop.
We'll check to see if the result of the callback function with a value index an array passed to it returns
true if it does we'll push into the new R variable.
The value we're iterating at once we're done iterating through the array we need to make sure to return
our new array variable and that's it.
Now let's see how we can use filter in our own functions.
Here I have a function called only four letters which accepts an array and returns the result of filtering
the array passed to it inside of the callback filter.
I'm returning an expression which will evaluate to true if each value in the array has a length of 4.
You can see that when I run this on an array of strings I only get back an array of values with 4 characters
just like map I need to return statements 1 for my function and the other inside the callback to the
filter function.
The second function I have here is divisible by three which accepts an array of numbers and returns
a new filtered array of all the numbers divisible by three.
Oh once again I have to return keywords just like above and in my callback.
I do not have an if statement.
I just have an expression which returns true or false.
So when my filter be useful let's imagine that we get an array of 50 of our most recent tweets from
the Twitter API and we want to see which ones have been favored by more than 10 people.
We would iterate through the Saray tweets and filter out all the ones that have been favored by less
than 10.
This would return to us an array of tweets that have more than 10 favorites.
Any time you need to take an array and remove some values based on a condition filter is an excellent
option.
Remember with map we always get an array returned to us of the same length.
So if you're trying to remove certain values in an array filter is a better option.
Before we move on to the next couple of Array methods let's practice a bit with filter.
Good luck and I'll see you in the next video.