Welcome back.
In this video we'll introduce one more reserve key word that yes Tony 15 gives us super before we see
how to use the super keyword but see how he implemented similar functionality in the S5 in the example
here.
We have two constructor functions person and student.
Now this code will work fine.
But notice the duplication in the student constructor function.
Is there any way to borrow the code from the person function and use it in the student function.
We can't just invoke the person function because the value of the keyword this is important.
So how do we fix that issue.
If you remember from the section on object oriented programming we mentioned that we could use call
or apply to refactor duplication in our constructor functions.
Here's how that would work instead of copying all the code we invoke the person function and specify
the value of the key word this to be the object created from the student function using the new keyword.
We could use call here but since the second parameter to apply has an array we can use the arguments
array like object to capture all of the arguments passed to the function.
This is much easier when we have lots of parameters.
So how does your 20:15 handle that issue.
It uses a reserved keyword called super.
The idea behind super is to find a method by the same name in the parent class or the class which has
passed down methods and properties to a child class.
In our case person is the parent class and student is the child class in our constructor method.
In the Student class we will use super which will invoke a method by the same name in the Person class.
Super can only be used if a method by the same name is implemented in the parent class.
Both of these concepts in S-5 and as 2015 are quite challenging.
So before we move on let's practice a bit with this new information.
Goodluck.