So we've written a lot of code and we're moving quickly on what I want to do is just take a step back
and go through the code that we've written so far.
We started everything in an index dodginess inside of this dot EMV config.
This first line of code is loading any environment variables onto process diet envy.
Remember we're going to use that specific variable called secret key.
That's what we loaded.
This is something that we want to make sure that no one has access to.
And when working with other developers we tell them hey you need to make a dot in the file with that
key of secret key and you even give them a simple one to start with.
Right over here we're bringing in our necessary dependencies Express and invoking it cores for cross
origin resource sharing this is going to be important and we start making requests from another domain
that could be local host 3000 or 4000 different port number violates the same origin policy a really
important concept in security that have link to previous body parser's going to allow us to get data
from a forum via a post and error handler and all routes are coming from handlers error and routes off.
Well what is error handler.
This is our nice generic piece of middleware that simply returns a nicely formatted object.
This object will always have the key of error and a value of message and will always get some kind of
string.
Either the message that is being sent from an error or passed to it or just something that says whoops
something went wrong.
This is really helpful at the very end of our code.
Before we start the server to simply say no matter what error you send.
Let this function handle it.
That could be a 404 that could be a 400 or 500.
We simply just want one standard way to respond with an error.
You may not see the total value of this now it's going to be really nice when we start making AJAX calls.
And if something goes wrong our entire error object always looks the same.
This is something where back end developers can make the lives of front end developers much much easier
by doing these little things.
You want to try to not be in a situation where are you doing lots of work on the front and changing
responses from the server to kind of fit this format that you want.
So we're going to try to make our future selves be happier.
We can make future developers work with us happier.
And if you're a back end developer This will make front end developers much happier.
What we then did is started to work on our user model.
You've seen a lot of this code before bringing in mongoose creating a schema of the fields that we need
some validations like required and unique and then a little bit of mongoose middleware.
Right before we save make sure that we have actually modified the password and if not keep moving has
the password set it to be that password for the user document and then move on.
If anything goes wrong send it to the error handler.
This next function right here is an easy way to compare some kind of password that we'll get from a
form or a JS on request and with whatever is inside of the database.
This is going to be really helpful when we try to see if a user has put in the correct password when
logging in and no matter what.
This returns a boolean right here.
True or false.
We take a look at this later on.
It's going to be true if the user has put in the correct username and password.
Or if that is incorrect it will be false.
But if something goes wrong is there any kind of errors move along to the error handler.
It's very easy to just write code like this but if you're not properly handling errors you're not really
building applications that are ready for production.
We then moved on to our handlers and inside of off we started writing the code that simply signed up
a user.
What does that mean.
Well we created the user restructured some properties from the document that we got back and created
a token using the web token module and our secret key we then responded with some Jaisalmer that included
the id the user name a profile image you are ill if they gave us one and the token.
We also added a little bit of logic to make sure that if there are any kind of errors we'll respond
accordingly.
What does that mean.
Well the mongoose errors are a little bit cryptic but sometimes they'll give you a friendly code.
In this case that is 1 1 000 which specifies that some kind of validation has failed.
What do we mean by validation we mean that when we put something like required and unique those have
passed.
So in this case our handlers specifying if you have not specified something that is unique we're going
to say it's already taken.
Otherwise we'll get a nicer error message that says that you just failed to provide that.
We then moved over to our routes we simply exported the router which is the result of express that router
and attached onto it are Sign-Up handler from handlers off back in our index file.
We then included those routes prefixed with Slash API slash off.
How do we test this will back in the terminal we used HVD pi and you can take a look pretty easily if
you're on Mac quite a few different ways.
If you're on Linux quite a few different ways as well.
So no matter what system you're using it should be relatively easy to get HDD pie up and running if
you want to use postman.
That's totally fine.
So how do we test Mungana use each DGP.
First make sure that my server is running.
I'm going to use HDD post to localhost ADT one slash API slash slash sign up and if I do this on its
own I'm going to get a nice object that says user validation failed password is required usernames required
e-mail are required.
Well let's try to put those and we'll put in a password of a user name of none and a e-mail of secret
at g mail dot com.
We're putting in some dummy data to see if this works.
And it looks like we're getting back the right information.
Notice we didn't get back in error we got back.
Whatever was sent as the response what do we mean by that.
Well inside of our handler inside and off we are sending back this right here resident status of 200
dodgy song.
We take a look at what that looks like.
Back in our terminal.
This right here is the I.D. That is the token that is generated.
This right here is the username and you may be wondering well where is the profile image you are l.
And that's because I didn't pass in one when I created it.
And since that isn't required we didn't get any kind of error.
So it looks like we can successfully create users.
What I want to look at in the next section is how to sign up users and then we'll move on to taking
these tokens and making sure that we can successfully create messages where things are going to get
even more fun.