OK so the last thing to work on is getting the update to work.
So when I click on the ally not on the span but anywhere else now why it should first send a request
that will change the status in the database from completed to or from false to true or from true to
false for a completed.
And it should also apply or remove the class to show that it's completed or that it's not completed
and Tocchet toggle back and forth.
So let's start by adding a quick listener so that these allies when we click on them do something.
So here we go.
Same place in our code in our document ready.
I'm going to listen and just like before rather than doing it on the fly because those aren't there
when the page loads are generated after the fact.
I'm going to add it to the list on quick and we're going to listen for specific clicks on allies in
that list and I'll just do an alert click.
So refresh the page.
I click on an ally and I get that alert which is what we want but there's a small problem which is that
technically this span is still inside the flight.
So if I'm trying to delete this one I'd say I brewed cider.
I want to delete it.
Well what actually happened it still will delete but it also triggers the code on the fly itself.
So that listener on the line is also triggered and you can see it removes it but it also gave us whatever
code we have in here which right now is just an alert.
But if we're toggling the status on and off and sending an update request or put request we don't want
that to happen.
If you click on the span.
So there's an easy fix.
So down here inside of our click on the span pass in and use this event.
E or Eevee whatever you prefer we do stop propagation.
If I can remember how to spell propagation.
There we go.
This method will stop the event from bubbling up so that when we click on the span it's not also going
to trigger the parent ally.
Now it's tested.
I click on the span to make a new one.
We don't get that alert anymore.
I do get the alert everywhere else I click there I click over here.
But if I click is on the spin itself we don't get it which is what we want.
Perfect.
Make sure it still works here.
Looks good.
OK.
So that's one issue handled if you're not clear about what this actually does you can research event
bubbling and propagation what happens here.
But essentially the event triggers first on the span and it runs whatever we have in here.
And the event continues to go up if there's any other events that are triggered.
Which is true this is a lie that is also triggered because when they click on the span it's inside the
light.
So we're clicking on two things.
But the event does eat stop propagation prevents that.
And then we remove it in here rather than alerting when we click.
Let's define a function called update to do and we're going to pass in that to do that was quick on
the fly.
It's a dollar sign this refers to the exact lie.
If you weren't sure about that we can just call us about log at
and you can see here.
Open up my console.
Click on this one.
You can see it to javascript or it's a J carry object but this is now live.
And if you look in here somewhere.
There we go.
You can see change diet.
So that proves that so when I clicked on.
So we're going to call update to do pass in dollars.
And this the lie that was clicked update today was not defined.
So let's do that now.
Function update to do takes in and to do and in here we have two things to do.
We need to send the request to change status on the server using the API.
And then after that's done we're going to update our view here by adding or removing the class.
So the first thing we have to figure out is when you click on it to do.
Is it currently done or not is completed.
True or false.
And we could derive that value based off of if it has the class done or not.
And that is a valid way of doing.
So basically we click on this one and we check OK.
Does this ally have the class done.
And if it does then we're going to send a request to say OK it hasn't now.
So the user clicked on it tried to market and done two cent false.
The problem is that technically someone could change the class somehow.
We could have code that is adding and removing a class someone could add in the class and it actually
won't be changed in our server anywhere.
So there is a there's some scenario where somehow your data gets out of sync where the class is not
applied where it should be.
But in the server it still says that it's completed and we're not showing that here.
So instead of depending on the class itself which I want to be clear that would work 95 99 percent of
the time what we can do is just use another data.
Where's that.
Here we go that data and store a completed true or false Boolean.
So I'll do that now.
Now to do that data complete is what we'll call it.
It's going to be equal to to do it completed.
So it's going to be true or false.
We're taking this value that comes in as completed.
True False false and we hop over here and we're just saving that using the exact same method we used
for the IDs.
They won't show up anywhere.
We won't be able to see it but we'll be able to access it and pull it back out.
So speaking of pulling it back out here let's just do a copy of that log.
To do that data completed.
So this is going to take whatever to do was correct.
Call that data completed and print out the result.
So here we go.
I click on this one tells us it is completed on its own.
It's not it's not it's not.
This one is.
So that's how we want it to work.
We're getting that correct value out.
So next what we want to do is send a request.
So the first step to send a put request there's no shortcut.
So it's a dollar sign that Ajax and then we also need to do our method which is put in our Euro.
We have the same situation that we had for our remove or we need to grab the ID and then construct to
delete your row.
So let's just copy this code.
I don't think it's enough to turn into its own function necessarily.
So I'm just going to copy and paste it here.
But instead of doing var clicks you are just going to say let's take this idea here.
And call this update you Earl is equal to this.
So Sasha API Sasha dues plus.
And then the due date data ID so whatever that long ideas here will just add an update.
You are.
OK.
And then finally we also need to tell it what the data is.
And this is kind of annoying.
Like when we posted it up here with dollar signs up post we were able to give it a javascript object
down here it actually has to take a string.
So the object version of that looks like this.
We want it to have completed is set to True or false depending on how we're updating it.
We want to use that.
So we're going to do it in two steps.
The first is to extract the value whether it's completed right now or not.
So we're going to have value variable called is done equals to do that data completed.
So this is just going to grab if it's currently done or not.
True or false.
And then we're going to make our update data variable equal to.
And we're just going to check completed or add completed this value and is done.
So this should generate if we just print out or update data.
And actually this is important.
We don't want to just send is done.
I'll show you why.
Because this one is currently done.
So we don't want to say that computed is true when we're sending it to the server.
We're trying to update it.
We want to flip that.
So when I click on this one we want to tell the server completed should now be true.
So to do that we're just going to nullify or negate excuse me not notify with an exclamation point.
And now it changes it to False.
Is this true that true.
That true.
So that's looking good.
So let's send that data on.
So I'm going to read or uncomment that code and I'm going to add in data is equal to update data just
like that.
And this should work.
So we'll add and then and if it works remember that our API sends back the newly updated to do.
So we'll just call it updated to do.
And let's just cancel that log updated to do and save.
Let's see what happens.
Refresh our page here and let's take this by car.
So right now it's completed is false.
I click it and it comes back.
There we go it says completed is now true.
If we inspected here you can see we have a find and modify its finding based off the ID and it said
incompleted to now be true.
So that's working.
As far as what we're getting back there there's two problems so we're not updating the view so we can
actually see that.
And Kitty and if I keep clicking it still it's just doing.
True it's not flipping them back and forth.
So let's start right just toggling the class and that's actually really easy.
We can just do a to do so that's the to do ally itself toggle class done.
And so if it has done class are going to remove it if it doesn't have it we're going to add it.
So that gets us part of the way.
And I guess I checked all of them off so let's toggle them back.
Just make sure it still works OK.
So as you can see I click one and it's changing in a database.
But if I keep clicking it I guess it's kind of hard to tell.
So let's say I check my cheese off and then I decide to actually wait.
No I I am not done.
I didn't buy cheese.
I made it up.
Well if I refresh the page it still is crossed off and that's because it's only actually flipping once.
If that makes sense.
So this thing if I refresh again by cheese starts off as completed false or excuse me it completed true.
I click now change it to false.
But if I click again it's just sending the same data as false.
Every time I click as you can see here completed false true false completely false.
And that's because I'm not changing the value of our to do data.
So what I'm going to do is change it.
So when it comes back from the server things worked successfully I'm going to do to do that data completed
is equal to the opposite of what it used to be.
And we actually stored that in a variable called is done I'm going to refactor this slightly longer
to make is done the negated version.
So I don't have to put the exclamation point here and then down here I can reference is done.
OK.
So let's walk through this.
You click on one of these allies and the event fires calls update to do with that to do.
We create that you R-OH then we're going to check.
Currently is it completed.
So let's say it is then we're going to make is done variable the opposite of that.
So this is what we want it to be.
So when you click and it is completed we want this to be false then we're going to send that off to
the server.
Are you saying completed is now false.
Then it comes back.
We're going to update the view so that shows class is done or it toggles and if we're going the other
direction and then we're going to take that value of is done which is again what we want to change to.
And because we're in here that means it's successfully updated.
We're now going to change our data method to say that completed is now whatever the opposite of what
it used to be is to do that data computed is negated.
So let's make sure it works.
That's quick.
The change diet looks good.
Let's try toggling it again and refresh.
It's how it's supposed to be it's working.
Let's try inserting a new one.
Let's call it cook dinner.
Toggle it.
Does it work.
I refresh the page.
OK.
Looking good to me.
I can let's unpack all of them have to do everything.
And now I've done everything I'm so productive and now I've done almost everything except buying that
pesky cheese fresh of the page and all we have left is by cheese.
Awesome.
OK.
So we're done with that.
It's kind of a lot of code involved.
You can see how this could really get out of hand very quickly if let's were working with.
I've said this a couple times sort of working with a couple of different entities so to do's and users
and tags comments there's a lot of code to manage and if one thing changes in one place how do we keep
track of it.
This is a problem for us.
How do we keep our completed status in sync.
And that's just one tiny bit of data.
It's a boolean value.
Literally the simplest thing we could store.
So this is where frameworks like re-act really help you out.
OK.
So that's a wrap.
We created our API.
Good old days on API here that we're now using and requesting untether own app is pretty cool.