Now will work on an assignment to help solidify all of the state concepts that we've learned.
So next up we're going to build this application.
It's 32 square divs on the page and every 300 milliseconds box is randomly chosen and the color is changed
to another random color.
It's a bit mesmerizing.
So let's take a look at the starter code and then we'll come back and think about how to build this.
OK so here's our starting code.
I've used create react to app to create a random box's starter and I've also gone into packets Jaison
and I've updated the react in the re-act versions to 16.
I should probably also update that 16.
But anyway they've been updated.
The latest version of react and I've removed no modules and reinstall everything.
So that should be all set.
And also I've got some default props down here.
These are all the available colors and CSSA that exist so you can use these to set up your state and
also to pick a random color when you're changing the state.
Now of course this component will need a constructor and it needs some state for all 32 boxes and will
also need a set interval that will randomly choose a box and then change it using Set say every 300
milliseconds.
So let's talk about how we might set up this applet to go look at the application again.
So just looking at this app it looks like all these boxes are basically the same component.
Right we're going to have 32 of some component you might want to call it a box or anything else.
And then it's going to have one property which is the color.
Hopefully you can work with that as a starting point to figure out your state.
One other piece of advice you might want to make this box a stateless functional component because it
the box itself won't have any state.
The app above it should control of the state.
All right that's it.
Good luck on implementing this.
And we'll look at a solution right after you're done.