Welcome back in this exercise let's build another histogram.
If you look at the resources for this exercise you'll see that I've given you the same data set for
my scatterplot example what I'd like you to do here is pick one of the variables we studied earlier
and make a histogram to display that variable.
For example here I've created a histogram showing the median age of the population in different regions.
Your goal in this exercise is to implement a similar type of histogram.
You can choose to look at median age or any other variable.
If you're up for a challenge there's a bonus here to notice that as I adjust the range and put on the
bottom I'm altering the number of bins in the histogram in order to get this working with the axes adjusting
appropriately.
You may need to look into an access method we haven't talked about cultic values.
It's similar to the thresholds method we discussed in the previous video.
Good luck with this histogram if you get stuck or want to see how I solved the bonus.
You can take a look at the next video.