Welcome back for the next exercise I'd like you to try to add some features to the Notes app.
We looked at before in this video.
I'll demonstrate the features I'd like to add.
You can find a link to the starter code for this exercise in the list of resources.
First I'd like you to add a button to the bottom of the page that lets you remove all of the current
notes.
This doesn't stop me from adding new notes afterwards.
It just removes all current notes from the page next.
I'd like you to add an I'm Feeling Lucky button which changes the style of the notes how you want this
button to work is up to you.
I have it randomly update the font size of each note or you could have it change the color of the notes
update the text or do something completely different.
Lastly I'd like you to try to implement a preview feature for your notes.
When I start typing in a new note I can see the potential new note appear on the screen it's colored
differently than all of the existing notes because it's a preview but once I add the note my preview
note becomes an actual note in the preview area disappears.
If I try to add a second note the preview area appears once again.
Good luck adding these features I'll show you my solution to this exercise.
Next video.