All right.
Welcome back.
So in this video I want to talk about what happens when things go wrong when things just don't work.
How do we handle the different types of errors we might encounter when we're using fetch to make requests.
So you have a simple code pen set up.
I have a button I trigger that button or I click it and it triggers some code which will just fetch
this API.
So this API I'm using by the way is good API.
Here's what it looks like with the link amusing.
It's a valid you know I'm getting a 200 response we're all good.
OK so I'll start off with fetching that you are.
And I'm going to make this very simple I'm going to have my dad then just print out
everything is fine just like that.
Then I'm going to have my ketch print.
There is a problem just like that.
So if it works things are OK.
We should see everything is fine.
And if there's a problem an error we should get there's a problem.
However I'll warn you this may not work exactly how you expect.
But first let's start off with something that should work this you are well I already tested it.
Everything should be good.
I click the button and we get everything is fine.
So far so good.
Now what if I try and visit a URL that is not good.
Something like this.
Just add some jibberish at the end.
We should get a 404.
And we do.
Let's copy this and try requesting that you are well that has a for a for or that gives us a 404 status.
You probably expect it to cause a problem but actually it says everything is fine even though it's not
a 404 error is not good.
And you want to be able to handle that in your code.
So we do get the default Crome error here but this has nothing to do with our error handling down here.
So there's two things to talk about.
One is how do we actually handle 404 other status code issues and the other is what does this catch
for.
What errors will this handle.
So we'll start off with that second question is catch right here.
When will we actually see there's a problem.
The way that it's set up is that promise will be rejected.
Basically the code in catch will run if there's a problem with the request itself.
So if the users internet is off or there's a problem connecting or there's issues with credentials maybe
but not with the actual response.
So let me show you what I mean.
I'll turn off my internet here.
OK.
I turned it off.
Now if I try and make a request to this bad you are out.
Any you will says there's a problem this time.
So that type of error will cause this code to run.
But again a 404 code won't return my internet back on.
Back to our 404 issue or any request here making a request and I'm getting everything is fine again.
If we want access to the actual status code of the request first and need access to the request itself.
But I could do conses that log everything is fine and then consider log request dot status just like
that and I click you can see it.
Everything is fine.
And then 404.
And if I change it back to valid you RL I get everything is fine and 200.
OK so back to the bad you are.
What we could do is add an if statement you know if request does status is equal to 200 do something.
But what I prefer to use is a property that built in called request.
OK.
So I like to do this if requested.
OK and then I'd like to negate it.
So if the request is not OK then we'll throw an error.
Otherwise this should happen everything is fine.
So we can start with just a constant out log error with response status and save.
And if I request this bad you RL I get error with response status and the code afterwards.
Everything is fine still runs.
Now what I want to talk about is how we can refactor this a common pattern that we can follow with our
promises to streamline things.
So here's an example we can actually put the error checking for the response status.
RAZ OK.
In its own dot then.
So we have our first then the first thing we want to do is check if everything's OK.
If it's not we'll throw an error message or throw an error and that will then trigger the catch.
But if things are ok we return the response and then this dot then runs.
So let's type it up let's do it ourselves.
So I'm going to actually delete a lot of this stuff we have in here.
I'll leave that for now but then I'm going to delete this right there and I'll add a second then afterwards.
And this does.
Then what it will do is just take the request again.
Well just cancel that log.
Everything is fine for now.
We'll just leave it at that.
OK.
So if the request is not OK in this first dot then we're going to throw an error and rather than just
doing a 404 let's just do a custom one that's just passing the string.
Just call it customer error for now.
OK.
So let's take a look at what we have.
Now we fetch the euro first thing that runs as soon as the fetch is complete.
Is this code that checks.
Is the request OK.
If it's not we'll throw the error and we're missing something because if it is ok we still need to return
something from here will be passed on to this next day then.
So we'll return the request if we didn't we wouldn't have data in request which we're not actually using
at the moment so we can print that out as well.
Like that.
OK.
So we're checking after the fetch is done is a request OK.
If it's not throw an error which is then going to skip all of this and go to our catch.
So this is a bad you Arel Let's see what happens we get there's a problem.
So we're no longer running this.
Everything is fine.
We're not printing out the request or anything.
We're going straight to there is a problem.
OK.
But if we make an OK request like this one you'll see we only get everything is fine.
And then the request.
So we're not getting there's a problem.
So what about our custom error we have here.
Well if we want to actually display that well we can do is in our doc catch can add an error or whatever
we want to call this and then we'll just constantly log error.
An error will be equal to whatever we throw up here.
It's now let's try it.
This is a good request still going to clear this and I'm going to go back to a bad request.
Never go so you can see our error.
Custom error is now showing up.
Probably better to do is instead of custom error.
Let's just do request dot status.
So if we get a for a for meeting that request if not OK then this will just be for a 4 but if we get
some other status code that's not equal to 200 OK that error will also throw.
So it's not hard coded in.
So now if we try this we get Error 404.
Now of course you may not know you probably don't want to just print out the error you want to do something
with it.
So you could add budget to figure out how you're going to display that to the user probably manipulate
the dom in some way if you present a pop up present some sort of model that explains you know.
Sorry that you are well can't be reached at something like that but that's the basics.
And the last thing I'll point out is that this is pretty commonly used and fed to requests that we can
actually extract it and just leave it then.
And let's move this to a separate function.
I think actually I have it on my clipboard.
Let's just call it function handle errors.
Or we could call it know check response or something lets you handle error or handle errors and format
this Macer just like this.
OK.
So we didn't change anything just give it a name and then appear I'll just do handle error.
Litheness it's just a cleaner way of doing this in my opinion.
It's a matter of taste definitely but I like to have our hands as short as possible.
So this code handles the error.
Let's make sure it still works.
There we go.
Error four or four.
And if I turn off my internet like I did earlier I try again this time we get type error.
Failed to fetch and that's important to failed to fetch.
That's not coming from me remember.
That's coming from fetches top default behavior when a user is off line.
The Fed tries to send.
Can't.
Well that throws its own error and runs our catch constantly logging that error.
So that wraps up what I want to say about handling errors.
Really it comes down to a couple of things.
One the default behavior is that this catch code will only run if there's a problem with the Internet
or the request itself.
It has nothing to do by default with the status codes with the response coming back.
So typically we do want to handle those.
It's really common that we want to make sure you know the request is good.
We can do that by defining our own function like Hadad here to handle the errors and to throw in error
if needed.
Otherwise return the rest of the request and keep going down the chain.
All righty.