Welcome back.
In this video we'll build the map visualization that I showed you earlier in this section in case you
need a reminder.
Here's a quick refresher here.
I've got a map of the world where countries are shaded by population.
I've also got a select element below my nap so that I can adjust the statistic being visualized.
Let's build this project from scratch.
I've got a folder here with an index DML a style that CSSA an app J S and A CXXVI file with data on
countries around the world.
As you can see I've got the name of the country a unique country ID and statistics on population count
Weyand area median age and fertility rate.
These numbers are estimates for 20:17 in order to generate that map.
I also need some type of Jason.
There are a number of ways you can build your own type of sound files from scratch but to keep things
simple I'll just grab an existing typologies on file.
From this you are l.
If you're looking for some Tombo Jaison data I'd always start by searching around to see if you can
find what you need somewhere online.
Let's take care of the HDMI first inside of the body tag I'll place in as Viji as well as my select
element.
I still have these options for population.
Population density median age and fertility rate.
I'll give each one of these elements of value property as well which will be helpful in the javascript's
later on.
After that I need to make sure I load D-3 top with Jaison and my app J.S. next.
I'll add a few quick styles to my style sheet.
I'll center the SPG and select elements and I'll also give every path in my SVGA a thin gray border.
OK let's hop into the app Jay ass and start building our visualization.
I need data from two different sources.
The CXXVI and the top Jaison.
So I'll create a queue and defer both Ajax requests for the CXXVI request.
I'll also pass in a formatter because I'll need to convert my stats into numbers.
I'll also need to calculate the population density to do this.
I'll divide the country's population by its land area.
Now I can wait for these requests to be processed inside of a callback to my wait function.
I'll have access to my map data into my population data first if there's an error I'll throw it.
Otherwise I'll then convert my map data into a valid OJs on format.
So the D-3 can process it using the jeel path helper to convert.
I'll use top J sound feature and I'll store the result of this function call in a variable called geo
data.
Let me throw a debugger inside of this away callback and hop into the console to look at my data.
Unfortunately the original top adjacent file doesn't have much information on the features.
Each one has an ID but the properties object is empty.
Fortunately these IDs are the same as the ones in the C S V file I've built so I can use them to tie
shapes from my top OJs on file to data from my CXXVI.
You may need to do something similar when building your own map visualisations.
If the dhaba adjacent you're using doesn't have much information on the Shape Data.
When I joined my map data to an empty D-3 selection I like my cxxviii did it come along too.
In order to make this happen for each country in my data array I'd like to find a match in my population
data array and combine my two datasets.
There are several ways I could do this for now already.
For each over my population data for each row of data I'll then go into my G.O. data array and filter
so that I can find every element in this array where the ID matches the rows country code.
In most cases this country's array will only have one element in it but regardless of the length.
I'll then loop over each matching country and assign its properties value equal to the row from my population
data array.
If we refresh the page and hop into the console we can see that this worked.
The first country in a data array didn't have a match in the C as we file but most other countries do
next.
Let's get a simple map showing up on the page.
First I'll create variables for my SVGA with the night.
I'll also create a path function using D-3 dodgiest path.
Just like we saw in the previous two videos.
Then I'll update the SPG and create an empty selection by grabbing all elements with a class of country.
After that I'll join my geo data enter append new path elements give them a class of country and use
my path function to set the D attribute see what we're working with while this map doesn't look very
good it's upside down cropped too small and looks pretty distorted.
The way to fix this is to set a projection on our geocache helper.
A projection is just a way to transform spherical geometry onto a plane.
Since we live on a sphere in order to get this map looking decent on the screen we'll need to use a
projection.
There are many different types of map projections that have been used historically and D-3 has support
for many of them from the dots.
You can take a look at many of the built in projections for now.
We'll stick with the Mercator projection which is one of the most commonly used map projections to get
this projection working.
I'll call the three Diageo Mercator and stored in a variable called projection to update my path generator
only to use the projection method the projection method on a path allows you to get the current projection
or set a new projection.
I'll pass my new projection into the projection method on my path generator and save now and I refresh
things look a little better.
So the map is now a little too big and off center.
Fortunately once you have a projection you can scale and translate it using the scale and translate
methods.
These methods do what you'd expect.
They scale and translate a projection based on the values you pass and scale takes a single parameter
while translate takes an array.
One for the x direction and one for the Y getting the map shifted into the right location can take some
guess and check.
Here are the values Olly's.
Now when I refresh the page things look pretty good.
Next let's get the colors working to do this first or the select element in a variable.
Next on change events from my selection.
I'd like to update colors for the map based on the event target value.
This is why I gave each option a value earlier to update colors or write a function called set color.
It'll take in an argument of how and inside of the body I want to select every country and update the
fill of each country.
I'll transition the update as well and give my transition a few settings.
So how can I update my fill I'll need a color scale but the colors I'll be using depend on the value
from the select.
To implement this at the top of the function I'll create an object that converts all four possible values
into a different color scale as we saw in the demo population goes from white to purple.
Density goes from white to red.
Median age goes from white to black and fertility rate goes from black to orange.
Given this color range object I can now create a scale.
I always use scale linear.
The domain will go from zero to whatever the maximum is for the current value and the range will be
the color range for the value OK.
Now I need to do is figure out what to put inside of the outer callback first only to go into the properties
key for each country and grab the relevant data.
If that data exists I can just pass it into my scale.
If not if that country doesn't have any data for instance I'll just give the country a light gray color
to indicate that there is no data present.
Let's save and refresh the select is working but on initial page load the map is still colored incorrectly.
To fix this I just need to hop into the javascript and initially call set color with the first value
of the select.
Let's try that again.
Great.
We built our first map and in fewer than 100 lines of javascript.
I hope you found this helpful in the next few videos.
We'll change gears a bit and talking about our last graph type force directed graphs.
I'll see you in the next video.