OK.
So all we're going to do in this video is refactor the massive To-Do list file and we're just going
to pull out all the fecche calls and turn them into separate functions or methods inside of an API calls
file or an API helper file.
And so we can close out of the other components are just going to focus on this one first thing I'll
do is just make that new file with the new file and I'll just call it API datcha.
Yes and Wynnum copy this API you are over there because we're going to make use of that.
And the other thing that we'll do is inside to do list we will import that file and I'm going to do
an import star and I'm going to call it as.
Let's go with API calls from dot slash API.
So everything in this file is going to be imported and it wanted to move it up.
It's going to be imported under API calls so I'll be able to do things like API calls don't get to Doo's
or create to do none of those are existing yet but we're getting there.
The other thing I should mention is that we're going to do this using async functions.
So rather than dealing with a bunch of promises and putting promises over here and returning promises
and then using them inside of our component we're going to just use async functions.
It's a nice way to shorten things up and basically do the exact same thing.
OK.
So let's start with our very first little bit which loads to do.
Right here we have to do is I'm going to just copy this entire fetch
everything up and tell what we do after the fetch.
And I'm going to move it over here and I'm going to define something.
Let's go with export.
And I'm going to call I need to write async.
By the way and I'm going to call it get to do just like that.
And no arguments might change the spacing
and all that we do is fetch using this API you are all exactly the same code returned the response.
Jason The only other change it's make is to return the fetch.
So then because this nursing function MBRD we are returning this here I can go to my to do list and
instead of low to use I'm able to first need to declares a sync.
And if you're not familiar with async functions I highly recommend you check out the content that we
have in this course on async functions.
It's a nice addition makes things much cleaner in my opinion.
So what we're going to do and it's going to make a variable to say what to do as equals and I'm going
to write a wait API calls dot and what we call it get to do I believe double check get to do.
And Cloud 9 is complaining about this async you can add that to the Linter options and you can ignore
it for now.
So what's happening here is that I'm making introduce variable and by calling API calls I get to do
this.
But by adding this a weight and by making this nursing function and making this async it will wait before
moving on we don't actually need this data then anymore.
And I can just have to do or this that sets a date to use just like that.
And that's all we need.
So it cleans it up quite a bit.
So when the component mounts we could just move this logic into here as well rather than having a separate
load to do with it's just fine and it's going to call and set or API calls call get to do is wait until
that's done whether it works or not.
And then we're going to use that to set the state.
Let's make sure it works and when to restart.
Because I did make a new file I believe we don't have to do that.
So to be safe I'll get back here.
See what happens.
Refresh the page.
We still have raw data.
Everything looks good but we'll just move the code into a separate file.
Ok so I'm going to do the same thing now for ad to do take this fetch over here and write export function
async function and let's call this one create to do and we're going to need to pass in let's call it
name or something and then and here we're just going to run a fetch.
And we called it Val here.
So let's go with Val.
OK.
And we just return that fetch just like before.
And we've named it create to do so now and it's to do list instead of add to do we just call var and
let's go with new to do let's do let equals and it's going to be API.
Well first we need a wait API calls dot create to do and we pass in Vau.
So we just moved it to a separate file.
We passed that in.
We need to declare this is a sin because well then we can get rid of that then and just do this data
set state to do it using new to do
nice and clean here.
We moved all the API logic all the fecche code that mess to the separate file.
So now we just have this nice little clean two lines.
We just say all right the new to do is equal to whatever comes back when we created to do.
And then when that's done because the wait we're then going to update the state to reflect that.
Let's make sure it works try making a new to do.
Let's go with EAT CHEESE.
There we go.
It looks good.
No problem with the cons..
Everything works.
All right.
Moving on to delete.
So same thing.
We're going to just copy all the fecche logic and go over here.
Let's call this one remove to export.
I should mention the way I'm doing this I'm exporting them individually as we go.
And then importing everything under star or using star under the namespace API calls.
So export a sync function.
Let's call this one remove to do it needs an id pass that fetch we're going to return the fetch or whatever
that returns.
And I think that should be good.
The only thing to mention about removing this issue is not really a response coming back that we need
to use or that we care about because we're not using data coming back to update our state because we're
deleting something we don't care what comes back and we're not going to get some new data.
So we're still going to keep it an AC as an async function but all we're going to do over here under
delete to do is well its first to our API first let's declare this a sink to that to do and then we'll
do and await API calls that removed to do pass them the I.D. and then because of this wait.
This won't happen until afterwards.
So we are then doing the exact same thing where we're filtering out the deleted to do the one we tried
to delete and then updating the state to do lets make sure that works.
Can I delete.
Looks good.
Great.
And finally we move on to toggle so I can get a copy of this.
Keep going.
Oh boy.
There we go.
So this is our fetch export a sync function and we'll call this one update to do and it takes the entire
to do rather than just the ID looking good return that fetch everything else is the same.
Then we go to our to do list and we're just going to call API calls.
Update to do pass in the same to do.
And let's make it updated to do equals.
Wait.
API calls and then we need to put a sync here and we can get rid of this then.
Nonsense all those promises so much cleaner.
So we're just waiting for something to be returned which is going to be the data of the updated to do
saving that variable and then everything else is the same.
We just don't have to have all the data that is everywhere.
Great.
So the last thing I'm getting a complaint here that we're not using API you IRL anymore because all
that logic has been moved to API Dutchie us a change that we could make as well is to make this an environment
variable so that it's not hard coded very easy to do.
It just depends on where you are deploying it where your API actually is located but just know that
all you need to do is change this here.
Do something like envy or process.
Ian V dot API you are.
But I'm just going to keep it at what we had.
And let's just test everything out so I can update make sure I can delete and I can create a new one.
There we go.
They all load correctly.
All right.
So if we now take a look at our To-Do list.
So much cleaner and shorter.
We don't have all of those nested fetches.
We've moved it all into our hippie's file our API file that is doing all the heavy lifting.
OK.
So that's it.
The last thing we could do is just dial it a bit.
But really this is more about functionality and kind of refactoring things.
All right.
Congratulations.
Thanks for hanging in there.
It's I know it's kind of a surprising amount of time and content to make a simple little app using react
but the entire point of it is to impose the structure.
So yes it might require.
It definitely requires more code more syntax but it's also when you're working within these stricter
rules even if it's more verbose it's a lot more organized.
So it's a tradeoff.
All right.