So we've now seen four different ways of sending requests with javascript.
We started out with the essay.
Then we moved down to fetch then we saw Jay Querrey and we finally saw X-post.
Now we have a quick little exercise where you'll be able to compare the syntax by writing a request
for different ways.
So this is a starter code you're going to make a Ron Swanson quote generator.
If you don't know who Ron Swanson is that's not necessary to complete this exercise.
He's a character on a TV show called Parks and Recreation.
Apologize if you are not familiar with it.
Here's his Wikipedia page if you care to read it.
He has a bit of a cult following.
He's crazy hyper masculine he loves meat woodworking hunting whiskey and breakfast foods.
So he has some funny quotes in the show.
That's all that really matters.
And actually that doesn't even matter what really matters is that there's a free API that we can use.
So this the API here include the link in the starter code and as well as as a resource with the video.
But every time we request this we get a different quote OK.
So what you're going to do there are four buttons here.
One for X H.R. one for each one project query and one for X..
I'd like you to just write the same request for different ways.
And if you don't care to do it then just do the actio side of things and compare that to the H.R. if
you feel good about S.J. query Don't worry about making your code efficient refactoring it.
It's not you know this is not a very typical use case where you'd have four different ways of writing
the same request especially including two libraries like Jay queery Natsios.
It doesn't make a lot of sense but it's an exercise so hang in there you'll need to include J Crew yourself
and include Acciona as well and then write those for requests.
There are four different buttons.
Each one has an ID so you can select it easily.
So try it out.
And when you're done it should work like this.
We click one of these and see.
Give a man a fish and feed him for a day.
Don't Teach a man to fish and feed yourself.
He's a grown man and fishing is not that hard.
Very funny Ron.
Very very funny.
So I only have the actually close button hooked up right now as an example.
But all four of these should work by the time you're done with it.
And then I'll have a solution video.