Welcome back.
Let's talk about a solution to this random box problem.
So I think one of the hardest things to do in programming is starting from a blank page.
So let's go step by step and talk about how this works.
First of all I'm going to need my class to create a component and I'll call it random box and our component
always extends re-act out component.
Next thing will always need a render method.
So by that and remember we need to randomly choose a couple of attributes so the first one will be font
size.
Now what my font size to be a random pixel value between let's say 20 and 100 pixels.
So I'll create my font size here and said equal to the floor of a random number
times 80 and then add 20 to it.
So it starts at least 20.
Next thing I want a random background color so I'll create that as well.
They're red green or blue
or black as well.
And I want this to be a randomly chosen index saw do math that floor of math at random
times for
greats all I'm doing there is randomly picking index to access that array.
Next up let's return our Gas-X so I'm going to return a div
and inside of that div I just want random box
but this div has to have some properties related to this font size and background color so do that I'll
use the style attribute and inside of that style attribute I'll pass in an object.
The first thing I need to do here is set my font size So let's say my font size is now equal to font
size x.
Next up I want to set my background color so I'm going to make the background color here equal to background.
And this is kind of a lot of wasted code so let's change this variable name to background color and
then just make it a single expression here.
And after that we just have our normal styling so I'm going to paste in some styles here and talk about
them.
We wanted white text so color white we want to center the text in the div..
So I use display flex and then just to line items center and justify content centers as well.
And then we want the div to be a fixed height so the with 500 pixels and the height here is 200 pixels.
All right so our component looks good but there's one step left.
Remember we've created the component but we haven't actually rendered it in the DOM yet.
So the last step here is to add a react on render.
And I want to pass in as the first parameter of that random box component.
And the second parameter is the element that I want to attach it to and the DOM saw it again this div.
And there you go.
It should be all set.
Let's check it out in the browser
Yep there it is.
And we get random sizes and random colors.