In the last video we learn about the stack.
So now let's look at a more complicated example and try to really understand what it's doing.
My hope here with a more complicated example is that I'll start to really click what the stack is doing
on pretty much every line of code that you run.
So by the end of this I hope that you could sort of think like the computer when you see your code and
think about how it's actually working underneath the covers.
In this example we have two functions and uppercase first function that takes a string and uppercase
is the first letter of the string.
And then also an uppercase words function.
This will take a sentence break it up into separate words and then invoke the uppercase first function
uppercase each word in the sentence.
So our example should return lowercase words here except the L and lowercase and the W in words will
be all capitalized.
So essentially what we're doing is we're uppercase saying each letter each first letter of each word.
OK so how does this interact with the stack.
Well remember the first thing that's always going to happen is that we're going to get a main function.
So first we'll add our main to the stack and there's no code to be run in the main until line number
13.
So we're waiting on line number 13 for something to do.
Now the next step would be to invoke this uppercase words function when this function gets invoked.
We're going to place it on the stack.
So now we're inside of the uppercase words function.
We've passed in the sentence lowercase words and we're on line number six.
Now remember every function invocation adds to the stack.
Here we're invoking the Split function which will add another function in vocation to the stack.
So now splits on the stack of split will take our sense and break it up into an array of words based
on that empty space so wherever there's an empty space we'll break it up into separate elements that
are array so split will do its thing and then return that array.
It will come off the stack.
Words will be assigned that new array and then we'll move on to the next line of code.
So I'm just going to kind of skip over line number 7 and move on line number 8 on line number 8.
We're going to invoke uppercase first with the current element that we're on here.
So words of I right now since I's equal to zero will be lower case.
And we're going to invoke uppercase first with the word lowercase.
So that again adds something to the stack.
Now uppercase first is on the stack we're on line number two and we've got the word lowercase.
First of all the first character of our word is going to be uppercase.
So the L is going to be changed to a capital L that causes a function in vocation so uppercase is going
to be placed on the stack upper case does its thing and returns a capital L and then it gets taken off
the stack.
Next we have to invoke slice.
So slice will return our string minus the first character that's what slice given one will do.
So now slices on the stack it will do what it's supposed to do and return a new string without the first
character.
So now slice will get popped off the stack when it finishes.
And now we've got both the first letter and the rest of that string.
We're going to concatenate them together and uppercase first is now finished.
And we're back on line number eight in our previous stack frame waiting for that result.
So now words of I is going to be set equal to the result of invoking that function which was capital
L and then over a case lowercase with the capital.
Now the same steps are going to happen with the next element in our array words.
The string words but I'm not going to walk through all those steps those centrally be exactly the same.
We're going to get the first letter and capitalize it so we'll get a capital W and we'll concatenate
that with oh yes.
To get words with a capitalized w.
So now we'll do that assignment as well.
And now we're done with our loop.
The next step is to move on to line number 10 where we're going to take our words array of capitalized
words and then join them together with a space.
So this will essentially take our array and convert it back into a string with spaces in between them
so that we'll have our resulting sentence with uppercase letters so join will do its thing and then
it'll get popped off the stack.
And now on line number 10 for uppercase words we have a result and since we have the result will return
it.
So uppercase words is now all done.
Last but not least our main function finishes up.
So we've gotten our results are lowercase and words strings have been uppercase.
The first letter has been uppercase and now we're done with that stack frame and we're done with the
code.
So I hope you found that interesting and hopefully instructive.
Keep all this in mind for the next section.
We talk about how this all interacts with asynchronous code.