Hello and welcome back to the course on Tumblr in today's tutorial.
We'll look at how to connect to PDF documents from within Tablo.
I know the previous lectures were a lot of talking, but today we actually get to doing and I'm super
excited about this topic because now we are able to connect to PDF documents.
And this has been personally one of my challenges in the past where it's provided a PDF document and
also to analyze it.
All right.
But let's jump into Tablo and have a look at how this works.
Now, you'll notice the PDF file connection under the normal connection options.
So we'll click that and we'll use our NYC Wasseypur Crime Stats PDF file.
Not immediately.
You'll notice something different as when we connected to our previous files.
It provides it opens up with a page picture.
Now, this page allows us to specify other which single pages we want to use or a range of pages.
And in our case we'll be using all.
But this is super handy.
If you remember the example we had of when a table was on a specific table, then we can specify that
over there.
It's also very important to note that when we're working with page numbers in PDF and I'll just open
up a paedophile, is that Tablo uses the absolute page, no reference.
And that's what you'll find here in your PDF reader.
Do you be careful when using the page number on the sheet as that might differ from the actual absolute
page?
No reference over there because sometimes in reports you will find that the first few pages are just
an introduction or some images and the actual report only starts on later pages.
So do be careful and only focus on that.
This will save you a lot of time and problems going forward.
Trust me, but back to Tablo.
So we will just be collecting all of the pages because all of our data is located on all pages.
And immediately you'll see that Tableau has interpreted the PDF file and created a whole number of different
tables.
But let's unpack that quickly.
We can see that we've got for each page one or two different tables and we'll have a closer look.
But that's just to indicate that Tableau has interpreted the data on the table or the data on the page,
rather, into different possible format.
Let's take page one, table one and have a look what that looks like.
And as you can see, this looks familiar to what we had with Excel files earlier where some of the data
is not properly written.
It's also erasing some of the header information and therefore quite a bit messy at the moment.
But just like we clean our Excel files, we are able to use the data interpretor to clean the PDF document
or a little tableau, apply some logic to see if it can clean this file for us.
So let's use that.
Let's take the used data interpretor and as magic and as we've seen this for Excel files, Tableau is
able to identify it correctly and put the right names into the right columns with the right correct
data.
Now what we'll see.
We've got all the parks running down.
We've got 49 records and this does look complete.
But let's look at what is in table two then.
So if we go to table, if we have a look at table two and still using the data interpreter, you will
see that we have much less records.
So tablas only identified nine records to be read in.
And we know for a fact when we look at our actual PDF file, there's more than nine lines.
They are actually forty nine.
So you can count them, by the way.
But Tablo has been saying or is then saying that in this method, number two, it's only to find nine
lines.
So that definitely does not look correct.
And we won't be using the second interpretation.
Let's add back the first one and we're always using that interpreter.
It's good to check your data quality or you integrate your data is complete.
So let's click on the review results just to make sure there aren't any funny's that happened when Tablo
was in was interpreting this.
Now, we've worked with this before, so we'll skip that first part.
But what we can see is that Tableau is correct, identified the header in rate and all of the lines
correctly.
And you'll see there's nothing at the bottom.
So it's connected to all the lines.
And as I mentioned to you, there are basically 49 different lines in our data.
Perfect.
So we know that is complete and correct.
But obviously, we don't only want the first page, we want all of the remaining pages as well.
So to do that, we'll just hold down the control button and click on the first table only of each page.
So ignoring page two, because we know that the first method of importing the data is correct.
And what you might want to do in the data interpreter is also just to confirm that I have actually already
checked.
That's on no, that is complete.
But yes, we want to add these different tables from these pages.
So how do we do that?
We don't want to join them.
So if we drag them straight into our area over there, it would join them.
We actually just want to open them or rather union them.
So how you do that is once it's all selected, you just drag it over into this pen and you hold it close
to the page one table one that's already there.
You'll see it opens up a and the drop area for us, an area to basically drag the tables to union.
And make sure that it turns orange so that it is actually dropping it in there and not next to it,
so once you drop it in there, tabla will do a few calculations and it will actually add the number
of records.
You can see we've got 1000 there.
We can just make it a bit more, make the limit a bit more by just adding a few zeros.
And now we end up with one thousand one hundred and fifty five rows.
So we're thinking that this is all of the records.
But we will check that.
What also has happened is that Tablo has added and if one field.
Yeah, and that might seem strange because we know we don't we didn't have that in the first page at
first table.
But if we scroll down and have a look, we can see that this is simply the park name, where in some
cases it didn't incorrectly or it didn't correctly identify that.
So we can fix that.
Quite simply, we just click on talk.
Well, while holding control down, click on EF1 and from the dropdown select merge mismatched fields
so it would throw the nulls away and populate them with the correct value that was actually used.
So you can see if we scroll through now, all of the parks have names and if one has disappeared and
was merged in there, I am actually just going to change this.
I just want to call it pork and then clean up the file a little bit because we don't want some of these
fields.
So, for instance, size we can hide.
We don't want any of these fields because we only work with the total so we can just hide them as well.
And I don't care about the table name.
And let's give this a proper name.
Let's call this incidence.
That's where the number of incidents reported so end up with three fields nicely cleaned file.
However, we did see that we've got 1155 records and as we don't have a record count, let me just get
to the PDF once again.
If the fact that we don't have the number of records in our file, but we do know we've got a total
loss, so we can it back to the total line.
So back to to our Tablo, we could just open up a sheet and simply drag in the incidents into our area
over there.
And we can see that now to at least two hundred and eighteen, which does not seem correct at all.
So if you go back to our data source, we know that Tablo might interpret this total, but actually
also as a record.
So let's see if it has done that right at the bottom.
You can see Tablo has seen that as a normal record.
And we know that is not a bug.
That's just a total.
So we can add a data source filter to remove that so we can just click add by the filters, add another
one and go to pork's.
So we want to basically filter the total line of the line with the total input.
So we will just basically say we will look up for the word total, we will select that and say exclude.
This is just if we do refresh our data with new information that we add, new box are being added that
we don't include total or we don't specify specific box, but we just exclude any totals from there.
So we can it's OK.
It's OK.
Once again, we can see our number of rows obviously changed one list.
And now if we go into our sheet, we'll see that we've got one hundred and nine records, which is or
rather 109 incidents, which is correct, as we know from our PDF.
So as you can see, a bit of cleanup is required and a bit of quality checks also in working with paedophiles,
but actually quite an easy way to connect to paedophiles.
And this is for me, excellent.
Then to patches some up, it's important to note that each PDF document that you'll work with will have
different clean up procedures.
So they might be additional steps required or even less taped.
It's all about how that the data is interpreted by Tablo.
Also important to note that the blow will have issues, important hierarchies and headers.
Subtitles multiple rows of content that should be interpreted as one or any colour and shading on your
PDF document can affect how Tablo interprets the data.
So do be careful with that.
In the next material will be looking at another fault up which we are able to connect to in Tablo now
with a new Tablo Connector.
Also a very exciting one in my opinion, in any case.
But we will have a look at the file type and how we can best make use of them in Tableau.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then, happy analysing.