Hello and welcome back to the course on tableau.
And today we're looking at filters important lecture today.
But before we get to it I wanted to ask you for a favor.
So we're no we're not finished of the course yet but I would really appreciate if you could leave a
review for this course.
We're we've done a few modules so far.
And if you like the materials please go ahead and click the button at the top.
The course which looks like this and just choose the number of stars that you think the course deserves
and leave a review if you like if you if you don't want to write anything just choose a number of stars
and click submit.
The reason I'm asking now is because a lot of students don't finish the course to the end for whatever
reason.
And I definitely hope it hurts.
You're not going to be that student.
I hope you get to the end.
But at the same time I would really appreciate a review because it helps me understand whether you like
the course or not.
And also it helps other students who are considering taking this course understand whether it's worth
their while.
So I would be very happy if you could do that for me today.
And now let's get back to the show.
So we're talking about filters today.
We've got this area chart that we created last time which if you ask me looks pretty amazing already.
We're just going to add a bit of formatting to it.
At the end of this lecture.
But how can we add a filter.
So what information is missing currently on this chart.
The information that's missing is gender.
We've got the age groups and we've got unemployment rates split by months but we can't see gender here.
So one way to add gender is by putting gender into a filter.
And that's exactly it.
We're going to do.
So to do that you have to take gender or the variable that you want to add as a filter and put it into
the filter shelf and it's as simple as that.
There we go.
So now you've got this filter made you pop up and you can specify the kind of settings or set up your
filter.
So here we're going to select few.
We we're allowing this filter to work by selecting from a list and there's only two values men and women
custom value lists.
I don't normally use that you could add like your own types of values use all.
So normally you stick with this select from list and this is for like dimensions.
We'll see.
We'll look at a filter for measures in a in a second.
So wildcard usually I don't use any of these is a more advanced kind of things that you use in very
specific cases.
So we won't stop on them right now because if you really need them you can understand them.
But to be honest with you I very rarely I don't think I've ever used the wildcards in my filters.
That's when you have like huge lists that you're filtering from.
So we'll just stick with general and for now we'll just select all and the other thing that you need
to know here is you can select exclude and what that will do is it will allow you to filter what you
don't want to see.
So if you had like 10 values then you could click exclude and that will allow you to cancel out a few
values.
But right now we're just going to select what we do want to see.
So we'll click all will click OK and now you can see the chart and change because we select both genders.
But now we have gender as a filter.
And so if I want to change the filter I click filter and say I want to see the chart only for men.
Then I click OK.
Then you can see the chart did change because now it's only unemployment for men and the access is much
the top value or the maximum value next is much more because there is less unemployed people because
men only look at a subset now for it to change it for women you uncheck that and check that you click
apply to the charts changing in the back there.
So that's all great but that is quite tedious don't you find that you have to click the filter every
time and then change it and then close it again.
So that's why in tableau there is a solution as a quick filter and we're going to learn that right now
as well.
So in order to bring up a quick filter you need to right click on the filter and select show quick filter
and just click that and you will see this quick filter pop up over here so it's quite far away.
How about I just put it there.
So I'll put it there for now but usually you keep him on the left.
I'll put it there just for our convenience so I can zoom in a bit and so here if I uncheck men you can
see the char is changing right away and check women charts changing so I can take all of them out the
chart disappears very handy thing to have this quick filter because it helps you quickly analyze your
data you can change it to type of quick filter you want to see and you can look at you can see these
different types so can be a dropdown single slide or so what we're going to do is we're going to actually
put this one back here and now I'll bring up a quick filter so actually what I'll do is I'll make my
tableau workbook smaller so we can zoom in like that there we go.
So now what we're going to do is we're going to add a filter for H because there's a lot more values
we have an edge and that'll be a bit handy.
So let's just do that.
We'll put age into filter we'll select all four now apply and we'll also create a quick filter for age.
There we go so that's our quick filter for age.
And now you can see how we can customize this filter.
So first of all we can uncheck certain values and as you can see they all disappear from the chart.
So this is not the best thing to have for this chart because we do want all groups of ages in unemployment
in this chart but we're just looking at it like this for now because it's a good example.
So you see we can uncheck the values we don't want to see and the chart changes right away dynamically
right in front of us.
So then we can just select separate ones.
But once again there's that option to highlight.
So you wouldn't need to do that ever if you have this highlighting option and then next.
What we're going to do is we're going to look at the types of filters you can have.
So say you can have a single valueless if you only want to see one at a time then you can just do these
radio boxes and also have this all option.
Also it filters you have the option to remove this all value.
So I can uncheck and then there's no old value so you have to select an option from the list.
But in our case we actually need the old value.
So how about we.
We can also have like a single value dropdown.
So it's like a radio box but it's a dropdown it's a bit more convenient.
What else you can do like multiple values drop down so you can check them.
So it just kind of makes compact you can do a wildcard match where you type in 20 to 24.
Let's see that and I'll pick up the value that you're looking for.
So there's a lot of different options for filters and a more for convenience.
So that's that's pretty much that's I'm just gonna get rid of this one because we don't need age as
a filter.
The other one I want to show you is we'll probably have a look more at measures as filters in the next
section because it'll be more relevant there.
So we'll definitely have we'll definitely look at that and a bit more detail but just so that you know
you can add filters and they're very easy to use.
So in this case if somebody wants to analyze only men or women he can select from here so actually I
was going to change this to single value from list and that makes more sense so you either looking at
everybody looking at just men or just women.
And the chart adjusts dynamically and you can just look at exactly what you want to see.
So as promised we're just gonna quickly fix up the formatting here so we'll just go format and make
it like a twelve and a B an employed and then we'll change format here as well.
Make it a 12:00 and a B and make this a bit bigger.
So there you go.
There's a chart it's ready for export.
If you really want you can add some text over here just to replace this label that's missing.
But otherwise I think it looks quite good.
And yeah.
So that's all for the section.
Hope you enjoyed creating this chart.
We learned quite a lot of new things and make sure to do the quiz because that will help you solidify
your knowledge and to finish off.
I just wanted to remind you I would really appreciate if you could leave a review.
That would mean so much to me.
Thanks a lot for watching and I look forward to seeing you in the next section.
Until next time happy analyzing.