Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo.
In the previous tutorial, we finished off with this beautiful distribution of our customers by age,
and today we're going to create an identical distribution, but it will be of our customers by balance.
So if you would like to perform an additional exercise and test your skills, then you can pause this
tutorial right now and create a distribution for the customers by balance and then play the tutorial
and compare and see how I did it and how you did it and see what the differences were and if you got
the same result.
So now we're going to proceed to creating this distribution.
And the process is exactly the same as we did with this distribution by age.
So let's go ahead and do that.
I'm going to create a new tab.
I'm going to call it distribution by balance.
By balance.
OK, and now, as last time for us, we're going to create a bean balance, create beans.
We'll make them 10000 units of currency beans.
And now we will take the balance.
Been a variable, drag it into columns.
We will take number of records and tarots.
There's our distribution now.
We will take some number of records, control, hold control and drag it into color.
There it is.
So maybe we can record a bit smaller.
That's good.
Now we will change, we will get rid of this header.
We will change our first of all, we will change, of course, rule change, uh, correctible calculation
will change us two percent of total.
And here we will also change it to percent or basically we'll just take this one and we'll drag it into
color.
Doesn't change the color.
But just for consistency, one rule here, what that means is that there is no values in the one hundred
and fifty.
So I'm just going to rotate these labels in the one hundred and fifty thousand.
There's no values and you can filter data and exclude that.
No, but I prefer to keep it.
So I'm just going to press control that and to remove this indicator from here which is right.
Click it and click hide indicator.
OK, so that's our chart and now we're going to quickly format it.
So I'll change the axis here.
Total percent of customers
and now we will format.
Here, the whole chart boult.
OK, so that's our chart, maybe make some more space so that the, uh, columns or the names of the
columns fit in.
And now what we want to do is we want to learn how to work with parameters.
So at this stage, we haven't touched on parameters yet.
But it is time for us to learn how to leverage the true power of this tool in Tableau and use it to
our advantage in this dashboard.
So well, how can we use parameters here and what are they?
Well, imagine that you want to dynamically adjust this visualisation.
Let's say, for instance, you want to be able to change the size of the bins.
Like right now you're not happy with 10000 units of currency per bin and you want to change it.
Well, you need to go to balance beam, right?
Click it, click, edit.
And you have to change this to five thousand if you want five thousand or twenty thousand or whatever
you want.
And every time doing that can be a bit tedious, and especially in data exploration and data discovery.
You need to be agile.
You need to be able to quickly adjust these things because, um, that can help you find anomalies.
So for instance, here, it's a gradual drop off, but when you change it to five thousand orbits,
you can see this spike and it's quite anomalous.
And you might want to understand what exactly is going on there.
So whereas you couldn't have known, you wouldn't have seen it from this chart and how quickly you can
adjust the size of the bins determines how many how much insights you can produce.
So we will create a parameter which will allow us to adjust these the size of these bins.
Very quickly, I'm going to right click and measures and here I will see create a parameter, the parameter
we'll call it.
Let's call it balance balance groups because we're working off balance and it'll be an integer parameter
and we will start off with uh ten thousand and we'll be working for a range.
So the minimum value of the parameter, let's say there's no not much point going below five thousand
dollar buckets or five thousand dollar bins.
The maximum.
Well twenty five thousand.
Sounds like a lot already.
And the step size can be five thousand as well.
So we've created a parameter.
Now we're right.
Click the parameter and we click show parameter control and it appears over here.
So now you can just change the parameter and.
Well right now nothing's happening, of course, of the chart and that's because we haven't linked the
parameter to our, uh, balance bins.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We're going to click edit and here the size of bins, it conveniently prompts you to select a parameter
when you click the dropdown.
And we really have a parameters balanced group.
So it's like that click OK.
And now if we change the perimeter around, you can see that the size of the bins is changing and therefore
the number of the columns is changing.
So you can see here that now I can very quickly dynamically adjust this chart and get to the insights
that I want.
And that is a lot of power.
That's not the only usage of parameters.
And now that you know that you have this option to create parameters which you can quickly adjust and
use to have more control over your worksheet, you will naturally come up with other ways to use them
as you create more visualizations.
But this is one of the good use cases.
So let's now go to distribution by age and do the same thing.
We'll create a parameter here and we will call it age groups.
These parameters, it's going to be an integer.
So a whole number.
This time we want a list of values rather than a range we want to list.
Let's say we want the only three types of values one, five and ten click.
OK, and now we have a parameter age groups.
We will, uh, show parameter control here.
Also, we want it to be a slider and of course, we want to connect it to our chart.
So let's go right click edit HPN.
And instead of this fixed value or for the size of bins, we to create each select age groups once we've
selected that.
Um, well here you can see it's a bit, it's extended outside quite a lot, but that doesn't really
matter because in the dashboard that won't be the case.
But we can always um if we want to reduce the size of this, uh, this is a worksheet even here if we
wanted to.
But let's have a look at what happens when we change the size of the bin.
So if we click to the right now, the size of the bin is five years and the size of the business ten
years.
And you can see that the chart is adjusting as we do that.
So that is the power of parameters.
Have a play around with that and.
See how they think of other cases where you might be able to use parameters in your work with Tablo,
and I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then, happy idolising.