Hello and welcome to this complete Node.js, Express
and MongoDB bootcamp.
I'm really happy to welcome you to this huge course today.
And I promise you came to the right place
if you want to start building your own modern
and powerful backend applications
with Node.js and all the related modern technologies.
Now before we really start this course,
let's take five quick minutes or so
to talk about what's included in the course,
how the course is gonna work
and also how to ask questions
and let me start by giving you a quick overview
of how the course is organized,
the projects that we're gonna code together
and also what exactly you are going to learn.
So, the course is basically divided into four big parts,
the absolute Node.js basics,
how backend development
and Node.js actually work
and then part three and four
are for the complete real-world Natours project
which really is the main part of this course.
And this project has two parts
because the same application contains both a RESTful API
and a server-side rendered website based on the same data.
So, let's now look at each part in more detail.
And we're gonna kick off the course in part one
which is section two
by building this small fun project
with will teach you the fundamentals of Node.js development
so that you get a solid foundation
for the rest of the course.
Then in part two, you're gonna learn the fundamentals
of backend development
and also how Node.js actually works behind the scenes
and this is gonna be a mix of theory
and coding lectures designed
to give you the knowledge that many other Node developers
out there simply don't have.
And this content is in sections three and four.
Section five then is just a quick optional section
to bring you up to speed
with JavaScript promises and async await.
So, just in case you're not familiar
with these modern tools yet.
In the third part,
we finally start building the Natours project.
So, in this part three,
from section six, all the way to section 11,
we design and build the API
and for that we take a deep dive into the Express framework,
MongoDB and Mongoose.
You will also learn all about real network applications,
routing, CRUD operations, data modeling,
geospatial data using the MVC architecture,
modern authentication with JSON web tokens,
authorization, security, error handling
and so much more.
Then in part four of the course
after the finished API,
we are ready to build the rendered website
using PUG templates
to really bring the project to life
with a beautiful user interface
and by the way, I decided to do the API first
and the website later
because this way we already have all the work related
to data out of the way.
And can then focus exclusively on building the website.
So, section 12 and 13 are for exactly that
plus you will learn how to accept credit card payments
with Stripe, how to upload files
and how to send emails using multiple tools
and finally, to finish,
we will also deploy our application to production
with Heroku, so you see,
there is so much content coming up
and this is really just an overview.
Now anyway, this is probably not the first online course
that you're taking
but I still want to say a few words
about how I think that this course should be taken.
So, first and this is pretty obvious,
in all the coding videos,
you should always code along with me
so that we really build all the projects together.
However, in some videos,
I also included some challenges
that you should really try to solve by yourself.
Now in all videos, coding or non-coding,
I really advise you to take as many notes as possible
because there is so much content in here
and so writing your own notes
can really help you retain the knowledge
as you move through the course.
Finally, I also believe that it's a good idea
to take the entire course from start to finish
so that you don't miss any topics
and so that in the end,
your project is exactly the same as mine.
However, I do also understand
that this course runs pretty long
and so, you might not really be interested
in all the topics
and so you can of course just skip videos
or entire sections that you don't need
but again, I do advise you to watch all the videos.
And now let's talk about questions.
So, in all the videos,
I always explain every single detail
of the technology that we're using
or the techniques that I'm showing you
but of course at some point
you might still have some questions
or even worse,
you might actually get stuck
because of some problem in your code
or some error message
that you do not really understand
and nothing is worse than investing all this time
and then not be able to move on in the course
and so, that's why you can always get help here
in the Udemy Q and A area.
So, at the bottom of the video that you're watching,
you will find the question section
for that specific video
and whenever you do have a question or a problem,
you can first check if another student
has already asked the same thing
and if not, well, then just post your own question
and of course with as much detail as possible.
And you will then get friendly support
from me or from my team
so that you're back to writing code as fast as possible.
So, I hope you're gonna have a ton of fun
with the course now
that you become a real advanced Node developer
and that you're gonna be able
to build your own amazing backend applications.
And with that being said,
let's now finally get started.
(upbeat music)