(light playful music)
So now that you know all about back-end development,
it's time to dive really deep into how Node.js
actually works behind the scenes.
So you're gonna learn all about the Node.js architecture,
events and the event loop,
streams, modules, and more.
And the kind of knowledge that you will gain
from these videos will really set you apart
from other Node developers out there.
And that is the whole reason
why I always include these kind of more theory lectures
into my courses.
Now, most people absolutely love them.
But some students just want to write code
as fast as possible, which also kind of makes sense.
But no matter how you feel about theory lectures,
I invite you to at least try out some of them.
And this is actually more of a mix
of theory and code lectures,
so that you can immediately apply what you learned.
Anyway, I'm actually really happy
with the quality of this content,
and also really excited about sharing this with you now.
So again, I'm sure that this kind of content
can absolutely give you a competitive edge
over some other junior Node developers.
(light playful music)