As promised, we will now use
event emitters and listeners in practice,
and we start by creating a new file here.
So events.js and close up this one.
So to use the built in node events,
we need to require the events module,
and from that we're going
to require an EventEmitter class.
So, EventEmitter, this is kind of the standard name
for the result of requiring this events module.
So again this is a built in node module, okay?
And now to create a new emitter,
we simply create an instance basically
of the class that we just imported.
So very simple myEmitter
is a new EventEmitter.
So EventEmitter just like this.
So remember from the last video
that EventEmitters can emit named events,
and we can then subscribe to these events,
so basically listen to them,
and then react accordingly, okay?
So it's a bit like setting up
an EventListener on a dumb element,
for example, for clicking on a button,
and I'm sure you've done it before,
when working with JavaScript on the client side, right?
So our emitter will eventually
emit a named event, okay?
So let's set that up,
and let's simply pretend that we're
building an online store or something, okay?
So we can say myEmitter.emit(),
and then we can make up any event name that we want, okay?
So we want to emit an event called newSale, okay?
And using the example of clicking
on a button that I used before,
this emitting here is as if we were clicking on the button,
and so now we have to set up these listeners, okay?
And let me actually do that before here,
and so again we use our myEmitter object.
Enter that we use the on method, okay?
So on newSale and then the callback function ,
which is gonna get executed as soon as the event is emitted.
So as usually, let's simply to the console.
"There was a new sale!"
Okay, and let's add another one.
So remember that I said earlier
that one of the nice things about these event emitters
is that we can actually set up
multiple listeners for the same event.
So let's do that here,
and so again, of course, we're listening
for the newSale event,
(typing)
and then log just something else.
Doesn't really matter here.
So '"Customer name:', for example 'Jonas"'.
So, let's test this out,
clear the one from before,
and we use node,
and then events.js.
So, There was a sale and Customer name: Jonas,
and so you see already that it's working.
So, great, so this is the observer pattern, remember?
Where this one here is the object that emits the events,
and then these two here,
so this on and this on,
these are the observers.
They observe the emitter
and wait until it emits the newSale event.
And, of course, our emitter could also emit other events.
Like new customer or new order or something like that,
and we could then add listeners for that one as well, okay?
Now another thing that I wanted to show you
is that we can even pass arguments to the EventListener
by passing them as an additional
argument in the emitter, here.
So let's say that pass nine,
so in this case just a number,
and we then have a listener that wants to use that.
(typing)
So myEmitter,
newSale,
and so now this callback function can take an argument,
and so let's call it stock.
So basically the amount of items that are left
from the product that we're selling here.
Let's use a template string.
There are now
stock items
left in stock.
So, if we run this now,
we should see There are now nine items left in stock
because we emitted this event
basically with a nine,
and the listener can then pick up this value here
as an argument of their callback functions.
So this stock variable here in this case.
So if you run this again,
then here There are nine items left in stock.
So, perfect, and you see that
these three logs here appear in the exact same order
that they are declared in the code, okay?
And so that's the normal behavior.
If we have multiple listeners for the same event,
then they will run synchronously.
So one after the other in the order
that they were in the code.
So this small example works perfectly already,
but if you were to use this pattern in real life,
then it's a best practice to create a new class
that will actually inherit from the node EventEmitter.
So, something like this.
(typing)
So let's say class Sales extends EventEmitter,
and that is ES6 or ES2015 syntax for class inheritance.
And again, I hope that you're familiar
with ES6 at the time you're taking this course, okay?
So in rote terms, the EventEmitter is a class,
so the one that we imported from events
into our sales class,
is the new class that we're creating,
and that inherits everything
from the EventEmitter class, okay?
Then in ES6 each class gets a constructor
which is a function that is run
as soon as we create a new object from a class, okay?
And what we need to do here is to call super,
and that's something that we always have to do
when we extend another superclass, okay?
So this is the parent class,
and this is the superclass,
and by running super,
we then get access to all the methods of the parent class.
So, again, EventEmitter in this case, okay?
And so now what we have to do is to
actually move this one down,
(clicking)
and so now my emitter is a new Sales, okay?
And so now it will work exactly the same,
and indeed, here we go,
and actually this mechanism that I just showed you here.
So basically extending the EventEmitter class
is exactly how the different node modules,
like HTTP, file system, and many other node core modules
implements events internally, okay?
So all of them actually inherit
from the EventEmitter class.
Okay, and with this small example working,
let's actually now try another thing.
So, since I was just now talking about the HTTP module,
let me actually demonstrate to you that
it is completely based on events, okay?
So we have this part working.
Let's create a couple of comments here, something,
and then create another example down here, all right?
And what we're gonna do is to basically
create a small web server,
and then actually listen to the event that it emits, okay?
So, up here we need to import the HTTP module,
(typing)
And then down here we can use it.
So we're creating a server,
and now I'm gonna do it a little bit different
than we did it in the first intersection okay?
But it actually works the exact same way.
So all I'm gonna do here is now http.createserver
and just like this,
and now what I'm gonna do is
to basically listen to different events
that the server will emit.
So for that, again, I'm using on,
and so if you see .on anywhere in a node project,
well, then you already know that you are listening,
or that the code is listening for an event, okay?
And so the one that we are listening here
is the request event, okay?
And so now it works just the same as before
we have a callback function
which gets access to the request and the response.
So nothing you at this point we did exactly that
in the node farm project, okay?
So, console.log
(typing)
"request received" and then let's also send something back.
Just the same text actually, okay?
And, of course, we can listen multiple times
to the same event.
(clicking)
So let's just say here "Another request"
using some emoji here just to make it pop a little bit more,
and it's not appearing.
What's going on here?
Ah, here we go.
So, listening to a request,
and we can also listen to the close event.
So, server on close,
and that is the event that is fired
when the server, as you can imagine, closes down.
(typing)
Okay, so that is listening to the events,
and now, remember, we also have
to actually start the server.
So, and we start the server up
by using server.listen,
pass in the port, the address which is
localhost again for us in this case,
point one, and then, our callback function
which is optional but let's include it here again.
(typing)
"Waiting for requests..."
So, let's actually start this,
and we see Waiting for request...,
and the application is not shutting down,
and now you know why it doesn't shut down, right?
It is so because the event loop is
still waiting for incoming I/O, right?
So that's what we learned in the event loop lectures, okay?
Now let's actually do a request on port 8,000 on this URL.
(clicking)
(typing)
And here we go.
So, we see Request received.
So this works because as soon as there is a new request,
the server automatically emits the request object, okay?
And we can see that here of course,
and here in the console,
we see our Request received string.
I actually wanted to get another one here.
So, we can, of course, only send one response.
So here I should have another console.log instead.
So let, exit this, start it up again,
reload,
and, yeah, so now we get Request received,
which is from this first EventListener,
and another request from this second EventListener.
One thing that you're probably noticing
is that each of these here actually is logged twice.
So that means that the server is actually
emitting the request event twice as well.
So let's see why that is.
(typing)
So console.log, request.url.
So with that, we can now get access
to the URL of the request.
(clicking)
Let's quit it here.
Run it again,
reload,
and so we have one for the root URL,
and then one for the favicon.ico
So browsers automatically try to request
a favicon for each website, okay?
So that is why each of these appeared twice actually, okay?
So, you see that not always we have
to actually also emit events.
That is more when we try to use the EventEmitter on our own.
So basically, when we're trying to use
our custom events in our applications.
In this case, of course,
we have to emit the events ourself,
but if we're using a built in node module,
then these functions in there will many times
emit their own events,
and all we have to do is to listen to them.
So that's exactly what we did here,
and with that, I think,
you now know all you need to know about events,
and are ready to come with me to the next video.