So let's now talk about the problems
that can arise when we use too many call back functions.
And to do that,
we're gonna do a small example
to illustrate this effect.
Now remember that if you're already familiar with
Promises and Async/Await and in general,
Asynchronous Java Script,
please feel free to just skip this section
and mark all the videos as completed
so that you can still get to 100 percent completion
of the course.
But if you want to learn all about
Asynchronous Java Script
and how to use it in OJS then let's move on.
So go ahead
and get the starter files for this project
from the course files.
I already have it here on my desktop,
so this folder here.
And it's only this file in there,
so that's all we're gonna need to get started.
And I have it here in VS Code already opened
and what we're gonna do to start
is to just create an NX.JS file.
Just like before.
Now what we're gonna do is this,
we're going to use this,
this dog file here, this text file.
And from here we will read the dog breed.
And then we are gonna do an HTTP request
to get a random image of a dog with this breed.
And then save that random image
to another text file.
So it's a three step process
and all of this will involve call back functions.
And by the end we will see the problem that we have
when we use all these call back functions
inside of one another.
Okay?
So for that we're gonna use a
quite a popular API.
Which is more like a fun API.
But for this kind of stuff
it's a good idea to use it.
So it's the DOG.CEO, API.
So just hit Dog API here.
Then over here,
the documentation.
And what we want is to get a random dog,
or a certain breed.
So click by breed here.
And down here,
down here is the API endpoint that we're gonna hit.
So it's this URL here.
So when you click on fetch here,
each time you get a new image, okay?
And so in this section
we're actually gonna do HTTP request
just like we learned about before
in the previous section.
Okay.
So all we will have to do
is to create an HTTP request to this URL
and then it will get us back an image.
Okay?
But for now, let's actually start with a part
where we read the file and get the content
of that file.
So in our index.js, again we need the file system package
or module.
So FS
and require the FS module here.
And just like before we do fs.readfile
and we do the asynchronous version.
Okay.
Remember that in here we pass the location of the file
and then a call back function
which will be called as soon as we're done reading the file.
So we have our template string here.
And then we use a dirname just like we did before.
So the name of the current directory.
/dog.txt.
Okay and then our call back function
which the first argument as always is error.
And then the data that actually is in the file.
And just to make sure, let's log it
to the console of course.
So another template string
so that we can nicely output our data here.
Okay.
Start up the terminal here
and
bring it up a little bit.
And so I'm using nodemon just like I did before
and then index.js.
Okay so breed is retriever.
And that is exactly what we have here in this file.
Okay so retriever is the breed that we will be looking for.
Now inside this call back function,
we want to do that HTTP request
that we just talked about before.
And there's actually ways of doing it
with native
no JS modules.
But it's easier to just use an NPM package for that.
And there are many again,
but the one we're gonna use is called Super Agent.
Later on we're gonna use another one
but for now Super Agent is just fine for that, okay.
And in order to actually download this module using NPM,
we're gonna start by creating our packet Jason file.
Remember that?
So let me just finish this
and do NPM in it.
And just hit enter on all of these.
This doesn't really matter.
Okay.
We just want this package .jason file
so that it actually holds the name of the package
that we're using.
So we always do that whenever we start a new project.
And now NPM install,
or we can just use the I, which is the same and then
the name of the package.
So nothing new there right?
Now to use this package,
we create a new variable
which will then contain the Super Agent function
that this module exposes to us.
Let's now go ahead and actually use that Super Agent
function.
So for doing a get request,
we simply used to get method on it.
So get and then we need that URL.
Okay so this one that I showed you before.
So just copy it
and paste it here
into a template string.
Because now we are actually going to replace
this breed here.
Okay, so we don't want that
but instead we want to use it,
the one that we get from our file.
So in this case it's data.
Right?
And so like this,
we can actually do an HTTP get request.
Now to then get the data,
we actually will also have to use the end method on this.
And this is then where we're gonna pass in
the call back function.
So again it's an error first call back
and then
we pass in the result as well.
And so in this function,
let's first of all
log the result to the console.
So the data that we get is in the response variable.
So this one here.
And then on that is the body.
So that's where the actual response is.
Okay, now let's actually go ahead and test that.
And now with this save here it actually moved down.
So again that's because
of the previous extension that we set up earlier.
And maybe you also noticed
how it replaced the normal quotes that I had here
with these double quotes
and also it inserted the semi colon up here.
And actually in the last section,
or in one of the last sections,
we set it up so that we always have
the single quotes okay.
And so in order to keep our code consistent here,
let's actually go ahead and
very quickly create the prettier config file.
So remember that's prettierrc.
Then in there we have single quote.
Set it to true.
And also remember the print width.
And set it to 80.
Okay, give it a save.
Save this one again.
And so you see we have our single quotes now back.
So that looks a lot nicer in my opinion.
Again if you don't like it this way,
you can of course use your own settings.
All right.
Anyway,
this piece of code here should now already
be doing the HTTP request.
So let's actually just
test it out.
And indeed,
we actually have this image here.
So actually what we want
is inside of this buddy
in the message property.
So dot
message.
So just like this.
And so here we have our retriever image.
Let's go ahead and actually change the breed here.
And I'm not really good with dogs.
Let's just use this breed here that I know,
Labrador.
I don't even know how to say it.
But I think it is it,
it exists.
Let's give it a save here again.
And so now we have another image.
We can actually click this here
and it will open that image for us.
Okay.
So for doing this HTTP request here,
we needed the data that we got before.
So this piece of data.
And so we needed to do this request here
inside of this call back function
of the read file function, right?
And so you already have a call back function here.
So this one inside a call back.
But now we will actually add another one.
Because now we want to save this string here
into a new text file.
And so we will do that here.
And then that again will have yet another
call back function.
Okay, make sense?
So fs
writefile
and then the name of the file.
Let's call that one dog image.text.
Then the data we want to save to that file
which is rest.body.message.
And then the call back function.
And this one won't have any data of course,
but we have the error again.
Let's log something to the console
like random
dog image saved to file.
Give it a save, it will then rerun
and here is our image file.
And actually you can see that VS code
displays that image here for us.
Give it another save here,
it will then rerun our code
and now we have,
indeed we have a different image.
All right.
So our code is actually working.
Let's just add a small error handle here
in case something goes wrong.
For example, let's say we add some weird name in here.
Run this again.
And so right now it's not gonna be able to find an image
for that.
And that will actually result in an error here.
So,
we should always do this kind of error handling
in the beginning and say
so if there was an error,
and we can just log error
.message.
And actually we should also say that we want to return
right away from this function if there's an error.
So it will return and
log to the console, this error.
And nothing else will happen then.
Okay.
So it says again, not found here.
And it didn't save anything to the file
because we already returned from the function up here.
Okay?
And the same actually down here
in case there is an error saving the file to disk.
Let's go back here,
give it another save.
And so now it's working just fine again.
Okay.
So this is just
a small example to show you how easy it is
to end up with call backs inside of call backs
inside of call backs.
And that's of course because,
we already know that in Note JS,
we should always use asynchronous code, right?
We did end up using call backs inside of call backs
inside of call backs.
And sometimes it can go even deeper of course
than what we have here.
You could of course have like 10 levels
inside of each other.
Now all these call backs,
they make our code look a bit messy.
It makes it difficult to understand
and also in general, hard to maintain.
Again maybe not at this level
with just three call backs inside of each other.
But if we had it even deeper nested,
it could quickly become a nightmare
to maintain code like this.
And that's why this pattern has been called
call back hell.
It's easy to identify this triangular shape
in our code.
It's what we have here.
Like this sort of triangular shape.
Whenever you see this,
it's a sign that you're
basically in call back hell.
Okay?
And you will maybe see or hear this term
when you do some Note JS research
or something like this.
But right now, this is actually the only way
that we know of,
of how to write asynchronous code at this point.
But we're gonna save that throughout
the rest of this small section.
So we're gonna learn how to use
something called Promises.
And that will then in the end
solve our problem and make our code easier to read
and to maintain.
So let's go do that in the rest of the section.