Let's now actually start to learn
how to solve callback hell by using promises.
And we're gonna start off by using a promise
for the agent appear request
instead of the callback.
And this is gonna work because the super agent library
actually has support for promises out of the box,
and so we can simply use them here.
For node functions, coming from internal node packages
like Read File, we will actually have to build the promise
ourselves, and we will do that later in the next lecture,
or so.
But for now,
I want you to learn how to consume promises
and only later how to build them.
Okay, so again we're going to start
with the super agent library
and more specifically with the get method here.
Because this method here actually returns a promise.
So without going into too much detail, for now,
a promise basically implements
the concept of a future value.
So basically, a value that we are expecting to receive
some time in the future,
so it's a bit like us saying, "Hey, server,"
or "Hey, API, please get me a random dog image
"in the background and let me know when you're ready
"and then give me that data back."
Okay?
So that random image is the value that we expect
sometime in the future.
And that is exactly the kind of request
that we're doing using a super agent library
in this example.
Right.
And the get method that we use again will automatically
and immediately return a promise as soon as we start
the request.
So the promise doesn't have a value yet,
because the server is actually still getting the data
from the server asynchronously in the background
but the promise is immediately available
and basically promising us that it will get some data back
in the future.
Okay, does that make sense?
And that state of the promise in that case,
so right in the beginning, is a pending promise.
So it's still pending, it still hasn't gotten back
with any data, okay?
So here at this point, we already have a promise
that we can work with.
Now all we need to do is consume it,
which basically means that we wait for it to come back
with the data.
And to do that, we use the then method on it.
So, all we do is to use then
and then in here, we pass a callback function.
This callback function will then be called as soon
as the promise is done doing its work and has come back
with the data.
And that data is then available as an argument
to that callback.
Now I like to call that the result.
And so, again in that callback function that we have here
we then have that data available.
So let's take all of this here and put it into
this then callback function
and actually get rid of this.
So we no longer need that,
and give it a save.
Now you might be thinking, well, we're still using
callbacks here, and yeah, that's actually true.
So this does not look like a big change for now,
but after we transform the whole example here to
promises, you will see
the big impact that promises will have on our code.
So that's basically if we have multiple promises,
we will be able to chain these callbacks onto one other
instead of nesting them.
Which is already a huge improvement.
Now one thing that I forgot to mention earlier
is that a promise as soon as it comes back with the data
is called a resolved promise.
So in the beginning it's a pending promise and
when it successfully gets the data,
it is then a resolved promise.
However, a resolved promise might not always be
successful because there might have been an error.
So we say that a resolved promise can either be fulfilled
or rejected.
The fulfilled promise actually has a result that we want
to use.
While a rejected promise is when there was an error.
So remember the situation that we had before
where we had a wrong dog breed.
So in that case, we had an error,
and we handled that error using this piece of code here.
Okay.
Now the thing with this then method here is that it
actually only handles fulfilled promises but it doesn't do
anything if there was an error,
because for that, we actually have another method.
So another mechanism of handling that.
And that is the catch method.
So right after the then method, we can chain
another method which is called catch.
Okay.
And so this one will get called if there was an error.
So in here, we actually have access to that error object.
And so let's now go ahead,
take this piece of code,
and put it here,
and now we can get rid of this.
Because actually in this then method,
we have no information if there was an error
or not because it only ever gets called
in case the promise was successful.
So if it's a fulfilled promise.
Okay, so this is kind of nice to actually separate
these two cases automatically for us.
So instead of having that weird handling
that we had before,
we can simply write all the logic for the successful case
which is the most usual one
because we usually expect everything to work all right,
but in case there was an error, we can input
some other logic down here into this error handler here.
So we keep that nicely separated.
Let's change it here again.
Give this one another save to run it again.
And so here we have Not Found,
and so you see that actually it did enter this catch
method here and didn't do any of the things
that's in this then method.
Now go ahead and fix this here,
close it,
give this one a save,
and here we go.
So that is how we consume promises.
So we started with this method here which
returned a promise and so on that,
we can chain the then method
which handles basically the successful case,
and then in the end, we also chain the catch method
which handles the unsuccessful, so the rejected, promise.
But as I said before, this kind of still looks like
it did before.
Right?
So we still have this callback function up here
so all of this callback function
and also here inside our then method, we have this callback
function of the writeFile.
So let's go ahead and fix that right in the next video.