So you already learned
how to use a Async/Await
but there's actually a bit more to learn
about how Async functions actually work.
So let's do that now.
In order to understand a bit better what happens here,
let's just try to add some console.logs
after and before calling Async functions here.
Okay, so console.log
So step one
will get dog pics,
okay.
And then number two.
Here let's just say,
done getting dog pics.
Okay. So let's give it a save.
And whoa, what happened here.
We have these two console.logs
before all the logs coming from the Async function.
So we have the one, two
for this one and this one
and only after that we have the logs coming
from the get dog pic.
Is that what you were expecting?
So if not, let's analyze what happened here.
Well, as I told you before, this Async function
actually runs in the background.
Because well that's how Async functions
are simply supposed to behave.
Right, that makes total sense?
So we cannot just stop the code here.
So as soon as we hit this function
we cannot simply stop execution of our main thread here.
Right?
And that's the whole philosophy of don't block
the event log.
So we need to get some dog pictures from the API,
but that's not an excuse to stop execution over code.
So to block the event log.
So as a result when the java script engine ceased,
this line of code here, it will just offload
the get dog pic function to the background
and go straight to the next line.
So this second console.log here.
So it makes sense that first this string here gets logged,
then it will start running this function,
then right away it will log this line of code
and in the mean time, we read this file in the background,
and as soon as that is ready,
it will start printing this log, this log,
and also this log.
So that's exactly what's happening here.
One two, and then then remaining three ones.
Make sense? Okay.
Then let's take it a step further, and actually
return something from our Async function.
So I'm changing this here to three, so that from
this function, we can return a string
which says two, well let's say ready
and then let's add here again an emoji here
to make it pop a little bit more in our console.
So ready here.
And then let's save that.
Simply some variable, doesn't matter what it is.
And then log x to the console.
So let's see what happens.
And then now here we get this weird promise pending
instead of the string here that we were maybe expecting.
So why is x here and not this string,
but this promise here?
Well, remember how I said in the beginning
of the last video that an Async function
actually returns a promise automatically?
Well, so this here is the proof for that.
So instead of logging ready to the console at this point,
it just tells us that x is a promise
which at this point is still running,
and so it's still pending.
So that's why it says pending here.
So java script can of course not know that x
will be this ready string here at some point.
And so it simply moves on to the next console.log
just as we had discussed before.
And at the time that JavaScript actually knows
that this x here should be the strain that we returned
well at that point, this code here has
long finished executing.
But what should we do if we actually wanted
to get that return value here?
So what if we really wanted to return this string
and log it through the console?
Well, we would have to treat this Async function
as a promise.
And so we would use the DEN method on it
or again, use Async/Await.
Let me show you how to do that.
So instead of trying to save the returned value
to a variable, we can use the DEN method on it.
And so here is where we can then call it x.
So console.log x so just like what we had here
and then we would also do this one inside
of the DEN handle, okay?
So let's review what we did here.
So get dog pic returns a promise, remember that?
And so each that we have a promise, we use the DEN method
in order to get access to its future value.
So the value that will eventually return.
In that case, this will be the two ready string.
Okay?
And so if you want to get x to that,
we need to use the DEN method like we just did here.
And only after that we then can log the third
string right here.
So if we give it a save now like this
it should then work as expected.
And yeah it does.
So we have our first log, then all the logs coming
from our Async function, then the ready
coming from line 42 here.
And finally, the number 3. Perfect.
And I hope it makes complete sense to you.
Now what happens if there actually was an error?
Well that's a bit more difficult to handle.
So let's again, cause an error like we did before.
But you see that actually we still enter
the DEN method here.
So this block here, okay.
So even if there was an error here in this promise
it basically still resolves as a successful promise.
So it still returns this value here.
And even if we add our catch handler down here
that will not change that fact.
Okay, so let's use catch here
and then use console.log and log the error here
so you can see that it still didn't log any error.
And that's again because this promise here
coming from this Async function will still be
marked as successful.
But if you really wanted to mark it as rejected
we will have to do something called throwing an error.
So let's do that here in this catch block.
So if there was an error, we not only want to log it
to the console, we also want to throw it.
So we use a built in JavaScript function called throw.
And with that we can throw an error.
So this will now mark this entire function of this promise
as rejected.
Okay.
Actually let's not just log this error,
let's simply do error to make it a bit more visible,
and something like an explosion maybe.
Yeah, something like this.
Okay, and so let's give it a save an see what happens.
And bam, so now we have our error here actually.
So it says I could not find that file,
so this log is coming from this catch log here
but then also at the same time it will throw an error.
And if it throws an error, that will then mark
this entire promise as rejected.
And so that's why we then enter the catch log down here.
Which will then, of course in turn
trigger this console.log of this error.
Okay?
And this of course is a whole new layer of complexity.
Okay.
But it's still very important to understand how this works
because it happens in real life all the time.
So we need to return values from Async functions
all the time and so it's important how you know
how to actually handle these returned values.
In this case, using DEN and catch.
Now, the problem with this is that it mixes
promises with Async/Await.
So we have Async/Await up here,
then all of a sudden we're being back to using
DEN and catch down here.
So let me actually show you another pattern of doing it.
Okay, so let's come in our this part here
not this way around, more like this.
And so let's use Async/Await for implementing this logic.
Now we don't want to create a whole new name function
for this, and so we're going to use a well known pattern
which I hope you know, which is an IIFE,
so an immediately invoked function expression.
Okay, so in parentheses, we define our function.
Like this, and then we call it right away.
Remember that?
Then, in this case, since we want to use Async/Await,
we also say that it's an Async function.
Okay, and so this looks a bit weird here,
but if you took for example my JavaScript course
this will look familiar to you actually.
Okay, so again, you declare a function
inside of parentheses and then call it function right away.
And so this way, you don't have to declare a
whole name function again that you will to then call
at some point later.
Okay.
Now since we're using Async/Await, we're using the
try it catch pattern again, like before.
So catch, have access to the error here,
and we actually cannot omit this here.
So even if we don't want to use this error,
we still have to write it out here.
Okay.
In future versions of JavaScript this will be gone,
but for now we need to do it like this.
So this is where this error will be.
And up here, we will have all these console.logs.
This one,
and this one.
And now I hope you know how to actually get
the value from the Async function.
So you know how to do that.
Actually I will pause the video and allow you to
figure out how to do it on your own, okay?
So take that small challenge and I'll be back
in a second.
So did you manage to get this string here,
so this two ready into the x variable
just like we had before?
So just like this here?
So it's just like we did before.
You declare a variable and then you await the promise.
And the promise, in this case, is get dog pic.
Okay?
So this function here is an Async function
and so it returns a promise.
And the result value of that promise
is this value here, which is returned,
and so by waiting for that value,
the result will be this string.
So we store that into x and then we can of course
log it to console.
So console.log x.
Then in case there's an error, it will catch it
and log it to the console here as well.
If we give it a save now,
then bam we get the error still because
we had it here, so that part still works.
Fixing it, saving it, and here we go.
So it's working now as intended.
But, again, with Async/Await it's a lot cleaner,
looks a lot better and it's also easier to understand.
And so we're not mixing Async/Await in one place here
and then using DEN and catch down here
like we had before with this piece of code.
Okay?
So in real life, this sort of stuff happens all the time.
So we have an Async function and we called it
from another Async function, and maybe we even
called another Async function from that first
Async function, and so we have a bunch of these
Async functions interacting with each other.
And so it's very important that you know
how all of this works.
And again to recap, the most important thing
to remember is that an Async function automatically
returns a promise, and that the value that we return
from an Async function will be the result value
of that promise.
And so from there, we can simply handle it as yet
another promise.
And that's exactly what we did here by awaiting
that first promise that we created.
Okay?
So please try to wrap your head around this
and make sure that you really understand it.
Because throughout the rest of the course I'm going
to assume that you know how to work with this stuff.
And that is exactly why I created this section,
to kind of get it out of the way before we really start
to work with no JS and express, and all this good stuff.
Okay?
So we're almost done with this section,
there's just one small thing that I want to show you
in the next video.