(gentle electronic music)
Welcome back to the next section.
In this one, we will finally start to build
our big course project,
and the first step in this project
is to build our own API
using the most popular Node.js framework
which is called Express.
So, in the real world,
everyone uses something like Express
to actually build Node applications
because it makes development a lot easier and also faster.
Now we're still using Node.js, of course,
and everything that we learned before still applies.
We simply have an easier way of writing Node code,
and so that's obviously a big win.
So this section is a really exciting one,
and so let's get started.