So now that we know what Express is,
we're almost ready to start building our API.
But before we do that,
I need to quickly talk about APIs on a higher level,
and more importantly,
introduce you to the REST Architecture
which is the most used API architecture today.
This way, we will actually know what we're building.
So it's extremely important to understand the stuff
in this video before moving on,
so that we actually know what we're building
throughout the rest of the course.
First of all,
API stands for Application Programming Interface
and on a very high level,
it's basically a piece of software that can be used
by another piece of software
in order to allow applications to talk to each other.
We have actually talked about APIs before,
more specifically, web APIs,
where we simply built an app that sends data
to a client whenever a request comes in.
Imagine we have our app running on a server
and we have a client.
So in fact, we effectively have two pieces of software
talking to each other, right?
And this is the kind of API we will build in this course.
And I guess it's the most widely used type of API out there.
But in fact, APIs aren't only used to send data,
and aren't always related to web development or JavaScript.
The application in API can actually mean
many different things as long as the piece of software
is relatively stand alone.
Take for example,
the Node File System, or the HTTP Modules.
We can say that they are small pieces of software
and we can use them,
we can interact with them by using their API.
For example,
when we use the readfile function from the FS Module,
we are actually using the FS API.
And that's why you will sometimes hear the term node APIs.
And that usually simply refers to the core node modules
that we can interact with.
Or when we do DOM manipulation in the browser,
we are not really using the JavaScript language itself,
but rather, the DOM API that the browser exposes to us,
so it gives us access to it.
Or even another example,
let's say we create a class in any programming language
like Java and then add some public methods
or properties to it.
These methods will then be the API of each object
created from that class because we're giving
other pieces of software the possibility
of interacting with our initial piece of software,
the objects, in this case.
You see, API has actually a broader meaning
than just building web APIs.
Alright? Anyway, a web API is what's most important
for us in the context of note.
Let's now take a look at the REST Architecture
to build APIs.
REST, which stands for Representational States Transfer,
is basically a way of building web APIs in a logical way,
making them easy to consume
because remember, we build an API for ourselves
or for others to consume, okay?
We want to make the process of actually using the API
as smooth as possible for the user.
Now, to build RESTful APIs,
which means APIs following the REST Architecture,
we just need to follow a couple of principles.
First, we need to separate our API into logical resources.
These resources should then be exposed,
which means to be made available
using structured, resource-based URLs.
To perform different actions on data
like reading or creating or deleting data,
the API should use the right HTP methods and not the URL.
Now, the data that we actually send back to the client
or that we received from the client
should usually use the JSON data format,
where some formatting standard applied to it.
Finally, another important principle of REST APIs
is that they must be stateless.
So this is a very broad overview.
Let's now start talking about these principles
one-by-one starting with resources
and using the Nators API that we're gonna build
in this course as an example here.
The key abstraction of information in REST is a resource,
and therefore all the data that we wanna share
in the API should be divided into logical resources.
Now, what actually is a resource?
Well, in the context of REST,
it is an object or a representation of something
which has some data associated to it.
For example,
tours, or users, or reviews in the case
of the example that we are following.
So basically, any information that can be named
can be a resource, alright?
It just has to be a name, though, not a verb.
Now, we need to expose,
which means to make available,
the data using some structured URLs
that the client can send a request to.
For example, something like this.
This entire address is called the URL
and this /addNewTour is called an API Endpoint.
Our API will have many different endpoints
just like this fictional endpoints that I have here,
each of which will send different data back to the client
or also perform different actions.
Now, there's actually something very wrong
with these endpoints here because they really don't follow
the third rule which says that we should only use
the HTTP methods in order to perform actions on data.
So, endpoints should only contain our resources
and not the actions that can be performed on them
because they will quickly become a nightmare to maintain.
How should we use these HTTP methods in practice?
Well, let's see how these endpoints
should actually look like starting with /getTour.
So this /getTour endpoint is to get data about a tour.
And so we should simply name the endpoint /tours
and send the data whenever a get request
is made to this endpoint.
So in other words,
when a client uses a GET HTTP method
to access the endpoint.
And just like this,
we only have resources in the endpoint
or in the URL and no verbs because the verb
is now in the HTTP method, right?
And by the way,
it's a common practice to always use the resource name
in plural which is why I have /tours here and not /tour.
Now, the convention is that when calling that endpoint,
we get back all the tours that are in a database, okay?
But if we only want the tour with one I.D.,
let's say seven, we add that seven after another slash
or in a search query.
Or it could also be the name of a tour instead of the I.D.,
or some other unique identifier.
The detail doesn't really matter at this point, alright?
Later, I will show you how easy it is to actually implement
this kind of logic with Express
because this is actually where Express really shines.
The first HTTP method or verb
that we can respond to is GET
and it's used to perform the Read operation on data.
Next stop, if the client wants
to create a new resource in our database,
in this example, a new tour,
the POST method should be used.
So we learned earlier that a POST request can be used
to send data to the server,
and so it makes sense to use POST
in order to create new resources, right?
Now in this case, usually no I.D. will be sent
because the server should automatically figure out
the I.D. for the new resource.
Anyway, what's really important to note here
is how the endpoint name is the exact same name as before.
The only difference is really the HTP method
that is used for the request.
If the /tours endpoint is accessed with GET,
we send data to the client.
But if the same endpoint is accessed with POST,
we expect data to come in with a request,
so that we can then create a new resource
on the server side.
So that is really the beauty of only using HTTP methods
rather than messing with verbs in endpoint names.
Again, it would really become unmanageable very quick.
Alright, next, there should also be
the ability to update resources.
And for that,
either a PUT or a PATCH request
should be made to the endpoint.
The difference between them is that with PUT,
the client is supposed to send the entire updated object,
while with PATCH,
it is supposed to send only the part of the object
that has been changed.
But both of them have the ability
to send data to the server.
A bit like POST, actually, but with a different intent.
So POST is to create a new resource,
while PUT or PATCH are used
to update an existing resource
and so it then makes all the difference.
And finally, to the litter resource,
there is the DELETE HTTP method.
Again, the I.D. or some other unique identifier
of the resource to be deleted
should be part of the URL.
Now, usually, in order to actually be able
to perform this kind of request,
the client must be authenticated.
So basically, log into your app, okay?
But that is, of course, a topic for much later.
So these are the five HTTP methods
that we can and should respond to
when building our RESTful APIs
so that the client can perform
the four basic CRUD operations.
So CRUD stands for Create, Read, Update and Delete.
And you will see this term all the time
related to APIs and database stuff.
And you see that these HTTP methods
map quite nicely to the basic CRUD operations.
Now, there might be actions that are not CRUD,
and in that case,
we just need to get creative with our inputs.
For example,
a log in or a search operation,
these are not really related to a particular resource
and they're not CRUD operations either,
but we still can create endpoints for them.
For example, like /login or /search.
But we'll talk more about these cases later in practice.
And just to finish this part now,
remember that we had two other crazy endpoint names
in the last slide which kind of involved
two resources at the same time, right?
And that's also no problem at all with REST.
So, /getToursByUser can simply be translated
to /users/tours,
in this case, user number three.
So this particular endpoint here
could send data about all the tours
that user number three has booked.
Makes sense?
Or in the case of deleting,
there could be a delete request to the same
or a very similar endpoint,
requesting tour number nine to be deleted
from user number three, okay?
So there really are a tons of possibilities
of combining resources like this.
But of course, we don't have to implement
all these combinations in our API.
We only implement what makes sense
in the case of our application
and the client that wants to consume our API.
So, this is how we make use of HTTP methods
to build user-friendly and nicely structured URLs
that are easy and logical to consume for the client.
Now, about the data that the client actually receives,
or that the server receives from the client,
usually, we use the JSON Data Format.
And so let's briefly learn what JSON actually is
and how to format our API responses.
JSON is a very lightweight data interchange format
which is heavily used by web APIs
coded in any programming language.
So it's just not related to a JavaScript.
And it's so widely used today
because it's really easy for both humans and computers
to understand and write JSON.
So you're probably already noticing that JSON
looks a bit like a regular JavaScript object, right?
With all these key-value pairs.
There are, however, some differences,
and the most important one is that all the keys
have to be strings.
It's also very typical for the values
to be strings as well but they can be other things
like numbers, true or false values, other object,
or even arrays of other values.
It's quite straighforward, actually.
And from this example,
you can kind of see how some typical JSON might look like.
Let's say that this is a data that we have in our database
for a GET request to this URL
so the tour with I.D. of five.
Now, we could send it back like this to the client,
but we usually do some simple response formatting
before sending.
There are a couple of standards for this
and we're gonna use a very simple one called Jsend.
We simply create a new object,
then add a status message to it
in order to inform the client whether the request
was a success, fail or error,
and then we put our original data
into a new object called Data, okay?
And we can develop this even a bit further
but this is really the simplest way
of formatting with Jsend.
And just, by the way,
wrapping the data into an additional object
like we did here is called Enveloping,
and it's a common practice
to mitigate some security issues and other problems.
Also, there are other standards
for response-formatting that you can look into,
like Jsend:API or the Odata JSON Protocol.
Alright, and finally,
a RESTful API should always be stateless.
So, what does stateless actually mean?
Well, in a stateless RESTful API,
all state is handled on the client
and not on the server.
And state simply refers to a piece of data
in the application that might change over time.
For example,
whether a certain user is logged in
or on a page with a list with several pages,
what the current page is.
Now the fact that the state should be handled
on the client means that each request must contain
all the information that is necessary to process
a certain request on the server, alright?
Does that make sense?
So, the server should never ever have to remember
the previous request in order to process
the current request.
Let's take the list with several pages as an example.
And let's say that recurrently on page five
and want to move forward to page six.
So we could have a simple endpoint called /tours/nextPage
and submit a request to it, right?
But the server would then have to figure out
what the current page is and based on that
send the next page to the client.
In other words,
the server would have to remember the previous request.
It would have to handle the state server side
and that is exactly what we want to avoid
in RESTful APIs, okay?
Instead, in this case,
we should create a /tours/page endpoint
and paste the number six to it
in order to request page number six.
This way, we would then state on the client
because on a client,
we would already know that we're on page five
and so all we had to do is to just add one
and then request page number six.
So the server doesn't have
to remember anything in this case.
All it has to do is to send back data
for page number six as we requested.
And by the way, statelessness and statefulness,
which is the opposite,
are very important concepts in computer science
and application design in general.
So, it's a good idea to actually have some understanding
what a stateless API is and how it works.
Anyway, this was a huge lecture,
but also one of the most important ones.
I cannot stress that enough and I actually think
that you can see that, right?
Anyway, let's now finally get back to our code.