So in this lecture,
you're gonna learn an easy way
of defining parameters right in the URL,
how to then read these parameters,
and also, how to respond to them.
Now, what we want to actually implement in this lecture
is a way of getting only one tour.
So right now, we have this endpoint here,
which gives us all the tours,
and we want to have something like this.
So let's copy it into a new request for now,
and then, we want slash, and then the ID of the tour.
So for example, let's say five, okay?
So, this is just like we talked about
in the REST API lecture,
where I said that if we hit this endpoint without any ID,
so just like this here,
well, then we would get all the tours.
But if we would specify an ID after that,
so, just like this,
and of course it doesn't have to be an ID,
it can be any unique identifier,
but in this case, the easiest way of implementing it
is to just use IDs, okay?
So, this here is of course a variable,
because it can be five, but it can also be anything else.
And so this piece of the URL here,
so this here, this is a variable, okay?
And so what we need to do
is to define a route which can accept a variable.
All right, and so let's do that here,
and actually right after this one.
And I'm just gonna go ahead and copy it,
because you already know how to write it at this point.
And so, yeah.
So here we have the route,
and so now all we need to do is to add that variable.
And that's very easy.
So we have our slash again, and then the variable,
we define it using a colon, like this.
And so like this, we created a variable called ID.
It could of course be anything else,
like var, or X.
Doesn't really matter.
But this one is called ID, all right?
Now we don't want to send back anything like this,
so let's just comment it out.
And what I want you to take a look at
is at console dot log,
req dot params.
Okay, so request dot params is where all the parameters
of all the variables that we define here are stored, okay?
So these variables here in the URL are called parameters,
and again, they are in req dot params,
available for us to use now.
So let's take a look now
and actually do this request.
And for now, it's not gonna do anything,
so it will not give us tour number five
automatically, of course.
But what I want to do for now
is to just take a look at req dot params.
And so indeed, here we have, ID is five.
So, request dot params is a very nice object
which automatically assigns the value
to our variable, so our parameter that we defined.
And we could actually define multiple.
So we could say ID,
and then we could say X, and we could say Y,
and then we, of course, would have to define all of them.
So 23
and 45, let's say.
Send this guy.
And then, indeed, we have an object
with all these three variables in them.
Okay, now if we define them like this in the URL,
we actually have to then specify.
So if we didn't have the Y parameter,
we would run into an error,
because we are now not hitting this exact route, okay?
So our route is now no longer exactly this,
but it's only this.
And so, there is an error, okay?
Make sense?
Now there is actually one thing that we can do,
and that is optional parameters.
So if you want to make this parameter optional,
we just add a question mark to it,
and now, it is optional, so we no longer have to specify it.
So just like this.
And so now we only have five, 23,
and then Y is still here, but it's undefined,
because it's now optional.
All right.
But let's get rid of all of this,
because we only really need the ID, okay?
And so now all we need to do
is to actually get the tour with this ID
from our data.json, from our JSON file, right?
So basically, from the tours array.
And so that shouldn't be all too hard.
And so let's say,
const tour is equals
to tours
dot find.
And I'm not sure if you are familiar
with this find method here.
So once, more this has nothing to do Node or Express,
it's just a regular JavaScript function
which you can use on arrays.
And the way it works is this.
So in here, we pass a callback function,
and so let me actually start by writing that one out.
So element ID
equals the req
dot params, okay?
So it'll basically loop through the array,
and in each of the iterations,
we will have access to the current element,
and we will return either true or false
in each of the iterations, okay?
Now what the find method will then do
is that basically, it will create an array
which only contains the element
where this comparison here turns out to be true, all right?
And in this situation, we want to find the element
where the ID is equal to the one
that we get from the parameters.
And so by specifying this callback function here
with this comparison, we will ensure
that only the element where the ID is actually equal
to the specified ID in the parameters
will get returned from the find method
and stored into tour, all right?
Now actually, this is not going to work like this,
because as you see down here,
these values here, they are actually strings, okay?
So we need to convert that to a number,
but that's very easy.
All we have to do is to say,
the ID is equal to req dot params
dot ID times one.
So this is a nice trick where JavaScript,
when we multiply a string that looks like a number,
when we multiply that with another number,
it will then automatically convert that string to a number.
So that's a very small, nice trick that we can use here.
And so, now, we already have our tour ready to send.
And so the data that we want to send
is tours equal
to tour.
Or actually, it's just tour,
so tour should be equal to tour, all right?
Make sense?
So maybe the most complicated part here is just this one,
but, yeah, that is again just a normal JavaScript.
And so I believe, or at least I hope,
that you're already familiar with using
this kind of array methods, all right?
So, we only want tour number five.
And so let's take a look if it actually works.
And well, it didn't, so let's take a look at that.
Oh yeah, indeed, here we need to use the ID, of course.
So not req.params.
ID.
Okay, so, try that again.
And now, indeed, we have the tour with ID of five,
okay, and only that single tour.
Let's try number two, for example,
and indeed, ID two.
But now, let's try another situation.
Let's do, ID 23,
and so now, we get nothing back, right?
And that's because there is no tour with the ID of 23,
but we still return the 200 OK status code,
and so, that doesn't make much sense, okay?
And so let's actually go ahead and change that.
And what should we do here?
Well, as a very simplistic solution,
what we can do is to check if the ID
is larger than the length of the tours array,
and if it is longer, well,
then we can send back a 404 error
saying that we could not find any tour for the given ID.
So let's do that very simple solution,
because, well, this is not the real API
that we're building at this point,
and in this case, it's not a problem
to use an overly simplistic solution like that,
because this is not the real thing that we're building here.
We are really just trying to get familiar
with the was that Express works.
And the same thing can actually be said here, for example,
when we...
So down here, where we post a new tour,
in the real world, we would always, always have to check
if the user input is valid,
so if it doesn't contain any malicious code,
or really, anything that we don't want in our wrap.
And again, we're gonna do that, of course, later,
but in this small example here,
I really just want to focus on the fundamentals, okay?
So let's quickly implement what we were just saying,
which is that if the ID is greater than tours dot length,
so for example, let's say we have 12 tours in our array,
well, if the ID is then 13, or 15, or whatever,
well, in that case, the ID is not valid.
So, we say return, and that's because
we want to exit the function right at this point, okay?
And so that's why we say return.
Then we send a status of 404,
because we couldn't find any tour for that ID,
and then a simple JSON response
with a status of fail.
So fail is what we send whenever we have a 400 code.
And then just a message property,
invalid ID.
All right.
And so let's test that now.
So we have our 23.
And, indeed, 404 not found, invalid ID.
So that's exactly what we just did, and,
it looks like it's working, okay?
Another solution that we could
of course implement here as well
would be to just do this test
after we do the tour here.
So we would get the ID,
then we would try to find a tour,
and if there was no tour,
well then we would say that the ID is invalid.
So let's comment out this one, duplicate,
just so that we actually keep both solutions here.
And so we can say, if there is no tour, okay?
So basically, the result here,
if there is no tour found,
well then this variable is basically undefined,
and we can then test for that here, like this.
So if there is no tour, so if tour is basically undefined,
well, then we send back this error message.
So let's test that as well.
And so indeed, it gives us the same result.
Okay, and just like that,
you learned how to specify parameters
in a URL, like this, okay?
Then you learned how to read these parameters
from the URL, by using req dot params.
Well, and then we used that ID, so that parameter,
in order to find a tour with that exact ID.
So that's what we did here, in this line, okay?
So that was the goal for this video,
and so let's now move on to the next one.