After get and post, let's all learn
how to handle patch requests
to actually update data.
And I'm pretty sure that at this point,
you already have a good idea
of how we're going to do that.
So let's do that after post,
so down here,
and remember that we actually have two http methods
to update data.
We have put and we have patch.
And with put, we expect that our application
receives the entire new updated object,
and with patch, we only expect the properties
that should actually be updated on the object, all right?
So usually, I like to use patch,
because I find it easier to simply update the properties
that were updated.
At least, when we start using MongoDB and Mongoose,
it will be much easier to just do it like that, all right?
And it's alsp easier for the user
to simply send the data that is changing,
instead of having to send the entire new object.
So again, we are going to make our app work
for patch and not for put.
So we expect a patch request to come in on the URL
just like before, "api/v1/tours,"
and now we actually also need the ID
of the tour that should be updated.
And so that is slash and then "id."
Okay, so that's what we learned in the last lecture.
So, what do we want to do when there is a patch request,
so when we want to update the data?
Well, actually, I'm not really gonna implement
this operation here, because that's just a matter
of writing some more JavaScript
that is not really important,
because, again, this is just testing API-using files.
In the real world, we're never gonna use files for that
anyway, okay.
So, I'm really just implementing all of these verbs here
so that you get a good idea of the different verbs
that we use with http,
the kind of status codes that we send back,
for example, here we sent 201,
while here we sent 200 and 400,
and also for example, here,
when we had multiple tours, we sent the results,
and when we created a new tour, we sent that data back
immediately, with this newTour that was created,
and so that's the kind of stuff that I want you to learn
for now, in this section.
So the basics of working with the Express, of course,
and also, the correct way of sending back API responses,
okay, and so, again, I'm not going to implement the updating
of tour here, because that would be a lot of work,
you would have to get tour from the JSON file,
than change that tour and then save it again to the file.
And that's a bit too much work here,
and so let's simply go out
and send back a standard response.
So "response.status,"
and we will still use 200 here,
so when we update an object or a resource,
we send back 200, okay,
and then the usual JSON
with the status of success.
And then we send back the data, and in this case,
the updated tour.
So we say "tour," and then here, in this position,
we would send back the updated tour, okay.
Right now, I'm going to send back a string which says like,
"updated tour here...," something like this.
So basically, just a placeholder here.
And we can also kind of implement this code here,
so in order to only send this when the ID is actually valid,
so let's get that from here,
and so this way, we can also actually use this ID here.
Right.
So we're not gonna do this one
because we don't have any tour, but we will use this one.
So this will be "req.params.id,"
and I'm converting it to a number here as well, times 1,
and if it is greater than the tour's length,
well then just like before, it is an invalid ID,
and we send a 404, for not found.
And so like this, we should now be ready to test it.
So, let's first of all save the request
that we did in the previous lecture.
So, just "Get Tour."
And I'm just going to go ahead and copy this one here.
And let's specify the patch method.
So this one's patch, and I will save it here right away as
"Update Tour."
Okay, and you see this one here gets this gray text,
so they're very easy to distinguish here
in this side column.
So we actually should specify some body here,
so let's just go ahead and copy it from here,
so remember, body, raw, and then JSON,
just like this,
and so, let's say that all that I want to do
is to change the tour number three, let's say,
so let's take a look at that one, so, one, two, three,
and I want to change the duration to fifteen.
Okay. Saving it again.
I'm going to save this one as well,
because then it will actually save this text here in a body,
and if I close it and open it up again later,
then all this text here is back,
and that will make my life a lot easier then.
Okay, but anyway, back to this one.
We set the duration to fifteen.
Now, keep in mind, that this will of course
not change anything in the data
because we did not implement that.
Okay, so I'm sending the response now.
And so, here we see "updated_tour_here...,"
just in the place where in the real world
we would then get the updated data back.
Right, just to test it with a wrong ID,
we get this "fail," and this "Invalid ID."
Okay, so give it a save and close it up,
and I'm going to close up this one as well.
Okay, so almost done with the CRUD operations,
so create, read, update, and delete, and as you can hear,
the last one that's missing is delete,
and so let's take care of that in the next video.