Finally, let's now handle the lead requests,
as well.
And just like in the previous lecture,
I will not actually implement the deleting
of a resource in our route handle.
Okay?
So, that is not necessary because, again,
we are only dealing with files,
which is not a real world scenario, okay?
So I simply went ahead and copied the handler
that we created in the last lecture.
And so let's just do some quick changes here
to handle the delete request, as well.
So, the first thing is of course,
this method here which is now not patch, but delete.
Okay?
Then we still need to pass in an ID
for the tour that we actually want to delete.
And then let's also change our response.
So when we have a delete request,
the response is usually a 204.
And 204 means no content.
And so that's because, as a result,
we usually don't sent any data back.
Instead, we just sent null, okay?
So the status is still a success, but the data is null,
simply to show that the resource that we deleted
now no longer exists.
So that is what null means.
Okay?
So pretty similar to patch,
the difference here, in this case here,
is that we change the delete method,
we change the status code to no content, which is 204,
and the data that we send back is null.
Okay, and so even in the real world,
that is exactly the response that we're gonna send back.
Okay, so now all we have to do go, ahead and test it out.
And using of course, delete.
Let me also save it here as delete tour.
And so let's pretend that we want to delete
tour number seven.
Again, that's not gonna do anything.
And so here we have our tool for no content.
And actually, Postman then indeed shows us here
no content at all.
So it doesn't even show us the adjacent that we sent back.
It simply gives us 204 no content.
Okay?
So let's just save it here.
We have it here on the left side now, as well.
And you'll see that our collection here is steadily growing,
so that's really cool.
Now, in the next video
we will actually make our code look a bit nicer.
So organize it and follow some best practices
to make our code a bit less messy.