In this video you are gonna learn how
to install MongoDB on a Windows computer,
so if you're using a Mac
please just mark this video as completed.
Now since I personally don't own any Windows computer and
this installation involves a couple of
Windows specific steps,
I asked my teaching assistant Aleksander,
to take you through the process.
So everyone say hi to Aleksander.
Hello guys my name is Aleksander and
in this lecture I will show you how
to install MongoDB on your Windows machine.
First you need to open your browser and
go to the MongoDB.com website,
you can see the address right here.
Then you need to click on products and
choose MongoDB server, okay?
Now click on this green download button.
And once again choose server from here.
Okay, now we want to install this
MongoDB Community Server and
we have a couple of options here,
so please choose the current release,
which at this point of time is the 4.0.9, okay?
As the operating system please choose Windows,
and I would just stick with this default MSI package, okay?
So after setting this up you can just hit
this download button, or
in case it doesn't work for you,
just copy the link below and
paste it in the address bar, okay?
So now we should see this pop-up that will ask you if
you want to save this file,
just click save file and
it should start downloading okay?
So I will just stop this because
I already have this file.
Okay? But after downloading it you can just
close the browser,
open your File Manager,
go to Downloads.
And you can see the installer is already there, all right?
So double click on that,
and now you should see the Setup Wizard okay?
Click next,
accept the license,
and click to install this complete version, okay?
And now it will ask you if
you want to install MongoDB as a service,
which basically means that
Mongo's server will run in the background,
so you can check this, click next.
It will also ask you to install MongoDB Compass,
which is the graphical user interface,
so we can also check this and click next.
And now just click install,
and you may see some windows pop-up that
will ask you if you want to allow this App to
be installed on your device, okay?
So in that case just click yes.
And now it should start the installation process,
it will take about five to ten minutes,
So I'll be right back to you after the installation.
All right, now just let this compass install,
okay you can see the shortcut right here,
and this is basically the compass community window,
so you can close this,
click this finish button,
and now we have two more things to do.
First we need to create a directory in
which MongoDB will store our data.
For this please open your file manager once again,
and go to the disk where MongoDB was installed,
so in my case it's Local Disk C.
Here create a directory called data,
so right click here,
new
folder
and call this folder Data, okay?
Now inside this data folder,
create another one called DB.
All right, so this is the place where
MongoDB will store our databases.
Now let me quickly show you that
MongoDB actually works,
so I'm going to Local Disk C,
Program Files,
find MongoDB here,
go to server,
4.0, and we are interested in this bin directory, okay?
So we can see there is a lot of files here,
but basically we are interested in this MongoD file,
which is Mongo's server and
in this Mongo.exe file which is Mongo Shell, okay?
So let me just copy the path from here and
open my console,
and by the way I'm using PowerShell but
you can also use the Command Prompt, okay?
It doesn't matter in this case.
So I'm using the CD commands to
go to this directory,
you can also write this DIR command to
list all the files,
and if you compare them you can see that
all these files are the same, okay?
So we are in the same bin directory.
And now let me just run this MongoD server,
so Mongod.exe, you can hit tab to auto complete this,
and I'm just hitting Enter and you can see that
the server is starting, okay?
So if you take a look at this line you can see that
it's waiting for connections on port 27017,
so we've basically started a server and
now we need a shell to connect to the server to
be able to manipulate our databases, okay?
So we'll be able to create databases,
delete databases,
to records, etc.
All right,
I will just open another PowerShell window to
demonstrate it to you.
And just CD to the same bin directory,
but now run this Mongo.exe, okay?
So this is the Mongo Shell,
and you can see that we've automatically connected to
the same port okay?
And now I would just run the DB command
and I should get the test database in return, okay?
And that's right.
So now you see that everything works, okay?
In this PowerShell we are running the server,
in this PowerShell window we've connected to the server,
okay?
And now we can just close this process using Control + C.
I will also close the server, okay.
And there is actually one more thing to do,
so what if I would like to run this Mongo server from
another directory, okay?
Let me just show it to you.
I will open another PowerShell window,
and now we can see that I'm currently in my user directory,
so I'm in C:\Users\Aleksander and
I want to open MongoDB server from here,
let me just write this command,
so Mongod.exe
and there is an error, okay?
So it says "The term mongod.exe is not recognized as
the name of cmdLet, function,
script file, or operable program."
So basically Windows don't know where to look for
this MongoD.exe file, okay?
So it thinks this file should be in
my user directory,
but of course this file doesn't exist here,
because it comes from MongoDB bin directory.
So we need to find a way to tell Windows to
look for this file in that
bin directory, okay?
And we can actually do this using system variables.
So let's close these windows for now,
and I will open settings,
And here in the search bar just write Env, okay?
And click on this "Edit the system environment variables"
so now you should see this small window,
it's called System Properties,
we are in the Advanced tab,
and here just click on this
Environment Variables button, okay?
And we are interested in the system variables,
Path variable, okay?
Click edit, and you can see that
there is a couple of Paths added here,
for example, I have added NodeJS and Git,
so I'm able to run Node from anywhere,
and we will add MongoDB here as well.
So let me just copy the Path from here,
so this is this bin directory okay.
And I will just create another variable here and
paste this Path here.
Now we can just click Okay,
once again click Okay,
you can close this window,
and let's test it in PowerShell, okay?
So you can see that I'm currently in my user directory,
and I will run MongoD.exe once again.
And you can see that everything works just fine, okay?
So the server is running on the same port as before
and it's ready to use, all right?
So you can close this,
and this is all.
So we've installed MongoDB and MongoDB Compass on
our Windows computer,
we've created a directory called Data to
store our databases,
and we've also added MongoDB to the Path,
so we are able to run MongoDB commands from
anywhere in our system.