Welcome back.
I hope you're having fun so far in this section.
I know that I am and so let's now keep it moving
and learning how to update documents with Mongodb.
So back in our mongoshell let's now
use db.tours.updateOne.
Okay?
So that's similar to .insertone that we used
to create a new document.
And remember how we also had .insertmany
and so we also have .updatemany.
Now how does .updatemany work?
Well, first we need to select which documents
we actually want to update and, second, we need
to pass in the data that should be updated.
So the first argument is basically a filter object
just like we learned in the last lecture.
So we basically need to query for the documents
that we want to update and let's start with that
starting in a very simple way.
So I'm just going to select based
on the name
The Snow Adventure.
Okay?
So that is my very simple filter object
so specifying the tour that I want to update
And now the second object that I need
to specify is what I actually want to update.
So another object here and then we close the function.
And so in here we need to use the set operator.
So, again, this works using operators just like
in these complex queries that we saw in the last video.
So set and then we need to create yet another object
and finally in this one we can specify the property
that we want to update and the value we want to set it to.
So, in this case, what we want to do
is to set the price to 597.
All right?
So this one was 497 and so we're now, basically,
increasing it to 597.
All right?
So let's hit return and it's then updated, our tour.
Now if this query here would have matched
multiple documents.
I can't select it for some reason,
but you can see it.
So if this query that we did here
would have selected multiple documents then only
the first one would have been updated because
we were using .updatemain.
And so if we already know beforehand that our query
is going to match multiple documents,
then we should use .updatemany
and not .updateone.
Okay?
Now just to show you that it actually worked,
let's take a look at all the documents.
So db.tours.find and, indeed,
we have The Snow Adventure here
with the new price.
Great.
So we updated a property that already existed.
So the price was already there and we simply set it
to a new value but we can also create new properties
and set these to new values, of course.
And it actually works in the same way but
let me show it to you anyway.
And what I want to do here is to find premium tours
and give them a premium field set to true.
So what are our premium tours?
Well, let's first do a find.
So just to specify that query.
And actually we already did that before.
So the tours that I want should have a price greater
than 500 and a rating greater or equal to 4.8.
So these are the really our premium tours, basically,
so really the ones that are most expensive
and most well rated.
So to create this query its actually quite simple.
And again because we actually already did it before.
Now what I want you to do here is to pause the video
and even if you remember it,
type out this query on your own.
And if you don't remember it, well that's even better
then you can practice what you just learned
in the last video.
All right?
So please pause the video here and try to come up
with this query on your own.
So again we want the price to be greater than
500 and the rating greater or equal to 4.8.
Okay, hope you did it.
And this is the solution.
So price should be greater or equal than 500
and the rating should be greater or equal to 4.8.
Okay?
And here we set just greater than which
is actually the same.
It's gonna give us the same result.
But never mind, let's do it exactly as I said.
And so just to make sure let's see if we get the
perfect result and indeed this is the tour
that has this premium price and at the same time
this premium rating.
Okay?
And in this case, we have only one result but,
of course, we might have multiple results.
And so let's now use .updatemany.
So db.tours.updatemany.
And so our filter object that we want is this one.
So I'm just copying it from here.
So that is the first argument and then second
is actually what we want to update.
Remember that?
So again we use the set operator and then
we say that we want premium to be true.
Okay?
And so this time we actually create a new field here
and we set it to true.
Okay?
Give that one a save and actually we were missing
some closing brace and so we cannot really go back
so let me try to add it here.
But, that doesn't really work, but anyway it doesn't
matter we can just go back to the last command
and then correct it.
So this is the brace that we were missing then
close it and here we go.
So db.tours.find just to check it now.
And here we have the last one which now
has premium set to true.
And again this was the only document that matched
our query and so it's the only one that got this new
premium property here,
but if there were multiple documents matching
that query, then all of them would have gotten
this premium true.
Okay?
So that's why we used .updatemany and remember
if we used .updateone then only the first document
matching the query gets updated.
Okay?
So that's how we update documents at least partially
so with this .updatemany or .updateone we usually only
update parts of the document, but we can also
completely replace the content of the document.
And for that we use .replaceone.
I'm not going to do that, but for the sake
of completeness I wanted to show it to you as well.
So db.tours.replaceone or .replacemany, okay?
And so in here, just like before, you would
pass the search query and then new data that you
want to put in this document.
All right, not going to do that here.
But now you know that it also exists.
And like this we have three of our correct operations
already completed.
So creating, reading, and updating and so
as you can guess in the next video we will talk
about deleting documents.