All right, as a final step in this section,
let's now connect our remote hosted database
with our Compass app and also with the Mongo shell.
So back here in the Atlas app,
let's open up the Connect assistant
by clicking this button here,
and so now before we can actually connect,
we need to do a couple of things.
First up, we need to add our current IP address,
just like this, so that our computer is actually able
to connect to this cluster, okay?
Next up, let's create a username.
And I'm calling mine simply Jonas,
and then a password, which I'm gonna autogenerate here.
And I'm actually showing it to you now
because I need to copy it, but don't try to connect
to my database using this password,
because of course I'm gonna change it
by the end of the course.
Now where am I gonna save it?
Well, let's go to our application
and open up our config file.
And so this is what we created
this file for in the first place.
Right, so remember how we said that each configuration,
we were gonna save into this file,
and so the database password
is actually a perfect example for that.
So database,
password and I'm setting it
to the password that we just created.
And later, when we will then connect our application
to the database, we will then of course use
this environment variable to create that connection, okay.
So, let's now create the user actually.
And now next up, all we have to do is to choose
a connection method and we're gonna start
with the MongoDB Compass application.
Okay, so we already have Compass,
and I'm sure we have a 1.12 or later
and so let's now go ahead and copy this connection string.
Okay, and now open up Compass.
Then up here, in the menu, hit connect here.
Then it will take some time to open up this new window.
But by the time it does, it will then have automatically
detected that we have a MongoDB connection string
in our clipboard, and so all we have to do
is to hit yes here and it will then automatically
fill all of these settings for us.
So our hostname our username and all this other stuff.
And so all we need is our password here.
So I'm going back to that file, grab it from there,
paste it here, and connect.
And indeed, it did successfully connect,
now it's loading our databases.
And here we actually see the three database that
already come pre-configured in this cluster.
So let's create a new one called natours.
And we also have to create a collection name right away,
and I'm calling it, of course, tours.
So create database and here we go.
So open that up, and now open the tours collection.
And now let's then finally insert our first document.
Okay, so again, name,
The Forest Hiker.
The price, should be 297
and I'm giving it a double number here,
and I also want to create
the rating,
4.7, and also as a double.
So insert, and so just like this we have our first tour
created on our remote database.
Great, that's awesome.
Let's now go back actually to Chrome
and take a look at our cluster here,
so when I open up this cluster by clicking here,
then it's gonna load our collections up here
and so give it a second.
And so now, we actually have our database name,
our collection name, and the tour that we just created
in Compass, and that's awesome.
So it means that our connection is really working.
Now another thing that we can and should do,
is to allow access from everywhere to this cluster.
So remember how right in the beginning of this video
we whitelisted our IP in order to grant access
to our current computer to this cluster.
But if you happen to switch computers during development,
you might need to whitelist the IP of that computer as well,
because otherwise you might not be able to connect.
But since we're not really dealing with sensitive data here
anyway, we can simply whitelist every single IP
in the world and allow access from everywhere.
Now of course, we will always still need our username
and our password, but this way we don't need
to keep adding our computers to whitelist.
We will simply whitelist all IPs that exist.
Okay, so click over here on access,
or actually it's not here, so let's open up
this cluster again, and here I think it's on security
and IP whitelist, and now here
on the right side click on add IP address,
and now I wanna allow access from anywhere.
Confirm, and that's it.
Okay, and now just as a last step,
let's also connect our Mongo shell to this cluster.
So let's go back to clusters here,
open up again the connect assistant
and then connect with Mongo shell.
Now we already have it installed here, and so now
all we need to do is to copy this connection string.
So copied it, open up the terminal,
and here we actually still have the Mongo shell running.
So let's quit that very quick,
because remember this is still connected
to our locally running Mongo server.
But now, we no longer want that,
we want to connect to our hosted database.
And so let's copy our string here,
hit return, and it will now probably ask us for our password
and indeed it does and that is in vs code
which I have just here, so copy it,
back to the terminal, paste it, hit return,
and I think it's doing something here.
And it looks like it worked.
So, dbs remember, just to show all the database,
and indeed here we have, natours.
So great, we are connected.
So let's say, use natours,
and so we switched to db natours
and now db.tours.find
and here we have the documents
that we just created before using Compass.
Perfect, so now everything is really interconnected.
We have the Mongo shell, and we have also Compass both
connected to our remote database hosted on Atlas.
And so like this, we are actually ready to move on
to the next section, connect our database
with our express application and then finally
start working with the database in our application.
So great job making it until this point,
and I hope to see you soon.