(light playful music)
Welcome back to yet another really exciting section,
where we will finally connect a MongoDB database
with our application.
And to do so, we're gonna use the very popular
Mongoose library, which makes working with MongoDB
in Node.js, really, really easy.
So in this section, we're gonna take a deep dive
into the Mongoose library,
and really make our application
and API come to life with real data
coming from a real database.
So we're gonna talk about data models,
implement important API features,
add some data validation,
and also use the advanced MongoDB aggregation pipeline.
So, get ready now for a ton of great content coming up.
(light playful music)