(light playful music)
Welcome back to one of the most important,
and also most advanced sections of the entire course.
And in this one, you're gonna learn how to implement
authentication, authorization, and security.
So, authentication and authorization
is all about users signing up
and logging into or applications
and allowing them to access certain protected parts
of the app that are not accessible to non-logged in users.
So that's really cool,
and it makes the app seem even more real world, right?
So to implement authentication,
we're gonna use a very modern technique
called JSON Web Tokens,
which are actually perfect for the API that we're building.
And now I can't wait to show you how it all works.
(light playful music)