So in this lecture,
we're gonna manage our users passwords in the database.
And by that I mean to first validate
if the inputted password is equal to the confirmed password
and then also to encrypt the password in the database
in order to secure it against attacks.
And so the first thing that we're gonna do
is to validate if the two inputted passwords are the same.
And the best place to do that is here
in the confirm password, okay?
And so let's write our custom validator for that, all right?
So remember, we use the validate property
and then since we want to create a function
and also an error message, let's open a new object here
and then in there create validator,
which is gonna be the function
and let's actually start with this one.
So, remember, all we need here is to specify
a simple callback function which is then gonna be called
when the new document is created.
So, function,
and here again, we cannot use an arrow function
because we actually need to use the disk keyword.
Okay?
So, remember that from the validator function
we return either true or false
and if the return value is false,
then it means that we're gonna get a validation error, okay?
And, of course, if it's true, then not.
And so what we want here is to say that the current element
so, password confirm, is equal to this dot password,
and that's actually it!
So, for example, if password confirm is A-B-C,
and password is also A-B-C,
then this will of course return true, all right?
And so then the validation is passed
and no error will occur.
But, if the initial password is, let's say, X-Y-Z,
well then of course this is gonna return false
and we're gonna have a validation error, okay?
So, very simple, but we need to keep in mind
that this is only gonna work on save, okay?
So I talked about that before
when we used the custom validator on the tour model, right?
But I'm reminding you of that here again
because this is absolutely crucial here in this point, okay?
So let me actually write it down here for you.
(keyboard clicking)
On
save.
Okay?
And for this reason, whenever we want to update a user,
we will always have to use save as well
and not, for example, find one and update
like we did with our tours, okay?
So let's keep this in mind when we write
the rest of the code throughout the rest of the section
and especially for updating, okay?
Because let's say that we updated the user's password
simply with a regular update.
Then in that case, this password confirm validation
that we have here would no longer work, okay?
And of course that cannot happen, okay?
And so, again, keep in mind that this will only work
when we create a new object, so on dot create, or on save.
Okay?
So, on create and save,
All right?
So we create new object using create, right?
So, right here, used a dot create
but remember how I also showed you
that we can use a user dot save,
like this, right?
And in fact, we can also use a user dot save
in order to update the user, all right?
But again, more about it a bit later.
Okay?
So let's now actually try out this validation here, okay?
So first of all, let's actually
just try to create a new user
with this data here which should not work
because we already have a user with this email address
and we said that this one should be unique
and so it should not work.
Okay, and so of course our duplicate key error, right?
Now if you were in production, then of course
we already would get our nicely formatted error
that we created in the last section, right?
But right now we are in development and so that's the error
that we defined we want to see.
Okay?
So let's simply use another email here
and since we're working on the email here,
let's also see how the email address validation works.
So let's say that we specified this as our email.
And so, we see the error, "please provide a valid email."
Okay?
So let's test it just like this because I think that this
should also not be valid.
Maybe it is, but let's see.
And yeah, actually it's not because
there are no domain names with only one letter, okay?
And so this validator is pretty specific
so it's really good.
Now if we do it like this, then of course it should work.
But anyway, what we wanted to test here
is these different passwords, okay?
And I remember now that we actually
didn't create an error message, I believe.
And yeah, we didn't.
And so, let's add that here as well.
So message,
are not
the same.
Okay.
So let's add something here, doesn't matter.
And so now, passwords are not the same, okay?
So perfect.
And now of course our validation should be passed.
And indeed, it is and we created our new user.
Let's head over to Compass here,
take a look, and then actually delete it
so that I can later create more users with the same email.
All right?
And we don't want all this junk here anyway
so all these test users, okay?
But now, the next step is to actually encrypt
these plain passwords that we are storing
in our database right now.
So, as I mentioned in the last video,
when we are working with authentication,
one of the most fundamental principles
is to never ever store plain passwords in a database, okay?
So that is something that's absolutely not acceptable, okay?
So we should really always encrypt user's passwords
because imagine that for some reason,
a hacker gets access to the database.
If then the passwords are stored in plain text in there,
then he can simply login as any user
and then do whatever he really wants
and cause a lot of damage in some cases, okay?
And so we need to absolutely prevent that.
And so let's now go ahead and implement this.
Now, where is the best place to actually do that?
Well, I would argue that the model is always the best place
to do this kind of functionality.
So in this case, the encryption
because it really has to do with the data itself
and so it should be on the model
and not in the controller, okay?
So again, keep the fat models, thin controllers
philosophy in mind here.
All right?
So how are we gonna now implement this encryption?
Well, this is another perfect use case
for using Mongoose middleware.
And the one that we're gonna use
is a pre-save middleware.
So basically document middleware, okay?
So, remember that we defined that on the schema, okay?
And in this case, we want to set a pre-hook,
so a pre-middleware on save, all right?
And the reason why we're doing it like this
is that the middleware function
that we're gonna specify here, so the encryption,
is then gonna be happened between the moment
that we receive that data and the moment
where it's actually persisted to the database, okay?
So that's where the pre-save middleware runs.
Between getting the data and saving it to the database.
And so that's the perfect time to manipulate the data.
All right?
So,
a function, and then remember we have access
to the next function in order to call the next middleware.
Okay, now we actually only want to encrypt the password
if the password field has actually been updated, okay?
So basically only when really the password is changed
or also when it's created new, all right?
Because imagine the user is only updating the email.
Then in that case, of course,
we do not want to encrypt the password again, right?
And so we can do that with Mongoose.
And so we're gonna say, if and then this,
which refers to the current document, right?
And so in this case, to the current user
and then is modified.
Okay?
So we have a method on all documents which we can use
if a certain field has been modified.
And so here, we need to pass in the name of the field,
so "password."
Okay?
And so basically, what we want to do here
is to say that if the password has not been modified,
so not, then in that case, let's simply
return from this function and not run
any of the other code that's in here
and then call the next middleware.
Okay?
So again, if the password has not been modified,
then let's just exit this function
and call the next middleware.
Otherwise we will then run the code
that I'm gonna put in here.
And so now it's finally time to actually encrypt,
or as we can also say, to hash the password, okay?
So you will see the term "hash" or "hashing" all the time
and so that basically means encryption as well, okay?
Now we are gonna do this encryption, or hashing,
using a very well-known and well-studied
and very popular hashing algorithm called bcrypt.
Okay?
So this algorithm will first salt then hash our password
in order to make it really strong to protect it
against bruteforce attacks, all right?
And so that's the whole reason
why encryption needs to be really strong.
Because bruteforce attacks could try to guess
a certain passwords if it's not really strong encrypted.
And remember how I said that bcrypt will salt our password
and that just means that it's gonna add a random string
to the password so that two equal passwords
do not generate the same hash, okay?
Make sense?
Now I'm not gonna go into all the cryptographic details
on how this really works behind the scenes
and why we need such a complex system, okay?
But of course you can read all you want about bcrypt online.
There's really a ton of interesting stuff
to discover there, all right?
Anyway, let's now go ahead and use the bcrypt js package
in order to use this algorithm.
So,
so npm install
bcryptjs.
Okay?
And so this basically is a bcrypt implementation
for Javascript.
Okay?
Let's go back to our main terminal
and then go ahead and import it here.
And this one is by default only called bcrypt, okay?
And not bcryptjs.
(keyboard clicking)
All right.
And now, let's actually use it.
So, we want to say that this dot password,
so the current password in this document
should be equal to bcrypt dot hash
and then our current password.
Okay?
And then in here we need to specify a cost parameter, okay?
And we could actually do this in two ways.
So the first way will to be manually generating the salt,
so that random string basically,
that is gonna be added to our password
and then use that salt here in this hash function.
All right?
But instead, to make it a bit easier,
we can also simply pass a cost parameter
into this function here.
And so that is basically a measure
of how CPU intensive this operation will be, all right?
And the default value here I believe is 10,
but right now it's a bit better actually to use 12
because computers have become more and more powerful.
So like 20 years ago, you could have used eight here
and then a bit later than 10,
but right now at this point in time, it's best to use 12.
And so the higher this cost here,
basically the more CPU intensive the process will be
and the better the password will be encrypted, okay?
And of course we could go even higher,
but then it would take way too long, all right?
And I will show that to you in a second.
Okay?
But for now, let's actually finish this
because there is one thing left here.
So this hash here is actually the asynchronous version,
but there also is a synchronous version.
But as you already know, we do not want to use
the synchronous version because
that will block the event loop and then prevent other users
from using the application.
So just like we learned in the beginning.
And so of course we want to use
the asynchronous version which is this one.
And this will then return a promise
and that promise, of course, we need to await.
And so, we need to use await and then say that this function
is an async function, just like this.
So, let's recap that here.
So, we want to set our current password
basically to encrypt this version of the original password
with a cost of 12, not to make it too easy
to break the password, but also not to make the application
take too long for encrypting the password, all right?
So with this, we encrypted our password
and now in the end, what we need to do
is to basically delete the confirm password, all right?
Because at this point in time,
we only have the real password hashed, right?
So, this dot password confirm,
and how we basically delete the field,
so not to be persisted in the database
is to set it to undefined.
All right?
So, we really only need this password confirm here
for the validation that we implemented before.
So just to make sure that the user
actually inputted two equal passwords
so that he doesn't make any mistakes with his password.
Right?
And so after this validation was successful,
we actually no longer need this field
so we really do not want to persist it to the database.
And so that's why we simply set it here to undefined.
All right?
Now you might wonder why this works
because we actually set password confirm
to a required, right?
But that simply means that it's a required input,
not that it's required to actually be persisted
to the database, okay?
Now, just to finish, we of course need to also call next.
Okay?
Let's give it a save.
And actually I'm gonna add some comments here
to make it really clear for you.
So basically what this does, is to only run
this function
if password
was actually modified.
Then here,
hash the password with cost of 12.
And then,
delete the password confirm field.
Okay.
And now, let's go ahead and test this.
And I will now create a new user with exactly this data
and let's now take a look at the result.
And indeed, we now get this very weird looking password
which indeed is the encrypted version of pass1234.
And also, as you see, password confirm is no longer here.
Okay?
And so just like this, we now stored users
in a secure way in our database.
Let me now just show you how it will work
if we, for example, set it to 16 here.
And I need to change the email here.
And so that should now take a lot of time
and I'm not sure if I can even wait.
Oh, actually it took like four and a half seconds.
But that's still a bit too much I believe, okay?
So,
let's set it back to 12
and so that should be better, okay?
And now let's just, again, delete
these users here that we just created.
And actually I need to get rid of this first one
because this one still has the password in plain text.
And so this user is not gonna work
when we start to actually login users
based on their password.
Okay?
So let's get rid of this.
And also what I wanted to show you here
is that we put in the exact same password
for these two users that we created, right?
But you see that the encrypted password
is actually very different, right?
And so that's the power of salting the password
before hashing it.
All right?
So just like this, we, again, implemented a very secure
and good password management.