Let's now continue writing
our protect middleware function.
So in the last lecture, we read the token
from the authorization header
and then checked if the token actually exists.
So right here.
And next up, we have the verification step for the token.
And I hope you remember that in this step,
we verify if someone manipulated the data
or also if the token has already expired.
So we already used, from the JSON web token package,
the assign function function,
and now we're gonna use the verify function.
So just like before, jwt.verify,
and then in there, as you can imagine, we pass the token
so that the algorithm can read the payload
and then remember that this step also needs the secret.
So basically, in order to create the test signature.
So that secret is process.env.JWT_SECRET.
Remember that?
Now, as a third argument,
this function actually requires a callback function.
So this callback is then gonna run
as soon as the verification has been completed.
So you see that this verify here
is actually an asynchronous function.
So it will verify a token, and then after that,
when it's done,
it will then call the callback function that we can specify.
Now, we've been working with promises all the time,
and I don't really want to break that pattern here.
And so, we are actually going to promisifying this function.
So basically, to make it return a promise.
And so that way, we can then use async await
just like any other async function that we've been using.
So in order to do that,
Node actually has a built-in promisify function.
All we need to do in order to use it
is to require the built-in util module.
So let's do that right at the top, actually.
So that will create an object called util, require...
All right, so that stands for utility.
That's not what I wanted.
So that stands for utility.
And then on there, we are going to use the promisify method.
But since we're only going to use that one method,
we can actually do it easier.
So instead of doing this,
we can simply destructure that object
and take promisify directly from there.
So again, this is just using ES6 destructuring.
Okay, so and now it's very easy to use.
All we have to do is to actually call promisify.
So promisify, and then pass the function in there.
And so now, all this here is a function
that we need to call,
which will then return a promise.
So then here, we actually call the function.
And this will then return a promise,
and so we can await it and store the result into a variable.
So that result value of the promise
will actually be the decoded data,
so the decoded payload from this JSON web token.
So let me call it decoded here.
All right.
And we can do await because we actually already said
that it's an asynchronous function.
And now, just to see that it actually works,
let's log this decoded data to the console as well.
And actually, we can remove this console.log off the token.
That one we no longer need.
So let's try to send this request again, and yeah,
but this time actually turning on this authorization header
so that we send a JSON web token along with the request.
So that sent it.
And now, indeed, we get access to the data,
and so therefore, we now have access to the protected route.
Okay?
But what I wanted to see is this decoded object here.
And so this here should be the user ID.
So let's take a look at that in Postman again.
So 62a42.
And so, indeed, well, where do we have that?
Let's take a look at Compass.
And indeed, the ID of this user is this 62a42.
And so that means that we actually have
our correct payload here.
So basically, the correct user ID.
We then also have the timestamp of the creation date
and of the expiration date of the token, as well.
So this is working.
But now let's actually try to manipulate the payload
of this token.
So let's copy it here again.
But then I'm going to the JWT debugger.
So again, at jwt.io.
So let's take this away.
And now what I'm going to do is to change some data here
and that will then change the encoded token here,
which I can then go ahead and copy.
So let's simply replace,
actually, I will just replace these two numbers here
with something different.
And so, as you see, this changed the token over here.
And so now, I will actually try to get access
to that protected route
using this manipulated JSON web token.
Okay, make sense?
So just to see if it's working correctly.
So I'm copying this one here now
and pasting this other different one.
And so, if I now send this request, then we get an error.
So, great.
So, we see the error name is JsonWebTokenError,
and we have an invalid signature.
So, great.
That's exactly what we were looking for.
So that is one of the two errors that can occur.
The other one is that the token has already expired.
So this one is called JsonWebTokenError,
and so actually, let's go ahead and handle this error now.
And the way we could do it
is to add a try-catch block right here.
Right?
So right after doing this code,
we could introduce a try block,
and then in the catch, we would then create errors
that would be sent to the client.
Now, instead of doing it that way,
I actually want to use our global error-handling middleware
in order to do that for us.
So we don't like to do error handling right here
in our middleware function.
Instead, we usually delegate it to the error controller.
And so, let's do that exact same thing here.
So error controller.
And then it's actually the exact same thing
as we have with our other errors here.
So for example, the validation error coming from Mongoose,
so from another library.
And now, this error is actually coming from another library
and it also has its own name.
So let's get that.
And it's JsonWebTokenError.
All right.
And so, let's do very similar here.
So if
.name is this,
then error should be equal to handle error.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and create this function, actually,
somewhere up here.
And this one is actually extremely simple.
All it does is to take an error
and then return a new AppError.
Okay?
So in this ES6 arrow function, as I hope you know,
we can write these one-liners
where we don't even have to specify the curly braces
and neither the return keyword.
So this will automatically and implicitly return
whatever we put here.
Right?
And so, what we want to say here is simply,
invalid token,
please log in again.
And then, the error code, just like before,
is a 401 for Unauthorized.
Now, this only works, remember, in production.
And so, if we did this now again,
then we would get the exact same thing.
And so, let's actually go back here
and run this in production.
So npm run start:production.
Yeah, just like that.
So if we try this now again,
let's see if we get our error.
And indeed, we do.
So if, right now, a user in production
tries to access our app with an invalid token,
well, then they get just this error message.
All right?
So that's the first error that we can get.
But another one is that the user
tries to access the application
with an already expired token.
And so, let's now try to create that error.
And in order to do that, I will change the time it takes
for the token to expire.
So right now, we have 90 days.
Let's put it to, like, five seconds.
Okay.
Give it a save.
And now try to log in again.
So let's actually save this one here, as well.
So, in users, and then log in.
So we can log in, and it will then give us a new token,
but this token is only valid for five seconds.
And so, these five seconds should have passed at this point.
So I will now copy this token
and try to access our protected route using that token.
So paste it here.
And now, let's see what we get.
And actually, for some reason, it did work.
So let's take a look at our JWT debugger again.
And it says, created May 2nd,
but expires only on July 31.
So something went wrong in that token creation, I guess.
And so, let's change this here again.
And I'm just gonna put five here.
And so, that five should then stand for five milliseconds,
or I can even, like, put 5000,
which should then be five seconds.
Okay.
So let me save it now again in order to restart the server.
Try it again.
So logging in again here.
All right.
So now all we need to do is to basically wait five seconds,
and that time should already have passed at this point.
Paste it here again.
And let's go.
And indeed, we get an error.
Now remember how this is basically the standard error
that we get in case we do not correctly handle that error
in our error handling.
Right?
So let's just take a look at the error.
And actually, we have it here in the console.
So let's see where that comes from.
And yeah, it comes from this place.
So this is the case in where we have an unknown error.
Remember, so an error that is not marked
as an operational error,
and so therefore we want to log it.
So we log it here
and then we send this generic error message
down to the client,
so the one we just saw in Postman.
But here we actually the details from this error.
And so, this one has the name of TokenExpiredError.
All right.
And so, let's now handle this one as well.
So I'm copying it now,
and then create just another if here.
So if the error.name equals this one,
well then, let's say,
handleJWTExpiredError
with the arrow.
Let's copy it and put it right here.
And so this, of course, is very similar to the one before.
Your token has expired.
Please log in again.
And again, with a 401 error code.
Okay, let's try that again.
And so, that's exactly the error message
that we should now see here.
All right.
And indeed, it is.
Great.
Let's finish the process here
and start it in dev mode, of course.
So npm start,
and all right.
So this one, we don't need any more, so let's close it.
Or actually, let's fix this small error here,
because indeed, we do not use this error here at all.
So let's get rid of it.
And then down here, we don't need to pass it in there.
Cool.
We, of course, also need to change this back to 90 days.
All right.
And so, just to be really sure,
let's log in here again,
copy the token,
and put it here.
Now, this process here of copying the token
and then pasting it here in this header
may seem a bit weird,
and actually we're going to fix that
in one of the future videos
so that basically, this process happens automatically.
But now, what's important is that
it's actually back to working now.
So we can actually get rid of this console.log here
and move on to the next step.
And we could actually stop here now if we wanted.
And again, most tutorials that you're gonna find out there
would, in fact, just stop here.
But this is not really secure enough just yet.
So for example, what if the user
has been deleted in the meantime?
So the token will still exist,
but if the user is no longer existent,
well then we actually don't want to log him in, right?
Or even worse, what if the user
has actually changed his password
after the token has been issued?
Well, that should also not work, right?
For example, imagine that someone stole the JSON web token
from a user.
But then, in order to protect against that,
the user changes his password.
And so, of course, that old token that was issued
before the password change should no longer be valid.
So it should not be accepted to access protected routes.
And so, that's the kind of stuff that we're gonna implement
here in step three and step four.
So the first thing to do
is to check if the user actually still exists.
And so, that one should be the easiest one.
So let's just say, User.findById.
And so, this is now why we actually have
the ID in the payload,
because we can now use that ID
and query the user using just that ID.
So decoded.id.
All right?
So that should then find the new user.
And of course, we need to await that
and then store it into a variable.
I'm calling it the freshUser.
All right?
Because it's not really a new user.
That's only when we create one.
But this is not really a new one,
it's really just the user based on the decoded ID.
Okay?
And we can do this so we can be 100% sure
that the ID is actually correct,
because if we made it until this point of the code here
then that means that the verification process
that we have previously, here, was successful.
Otherwise, this would have caused an error
which would then have prevented
the function from continuing.
And so, again, this verification process here
is in charge of verification
if no one altered the ID
that's in the payload of this token.
And so, because of that, we can be 100% sure
that the user for which we have issued the JWT
is exactly the one whose ID
is now inside of the decoded payload, so this one.
Okay?
So the verification process is really key.
It's really what makes all of this work.
Anyway, now what we need to do
is to check if there actually is a freshUser.
And if not, well then, of course,
we're going to return a new error.
So if there is no freshUser,
then return from this middleware
and call the next one with an error.
So this is a pattern that we've been seeing
over and over again at this point, right?
So the token
does no longer exist.
And actually, it's the other way around.
So actually, the user belonging to the token
no longer exists.
Right?
And then, the 401.
Okay.
So let's test this once again.
And let's actually create a new user for that.
So just test with the same password
so we're always using the same one here
just to make our testing a bit easier.
And I know that all of this testing here
makes the video take really quite a long time,
but of course, it's really important
that we do test everything that we do,
especially in such an important topic as authentication.
So I'm now using this JWT here, so I'm pasting it here,
but of course, before sending the request,
I will go ahead and delete that user right away.
Okay?
So again, let's pretend someone
created a user then logged in,
and let's say, then, after some time, the user was deleted.
But in the meantime,
someone could've gotten access to that JWT,
and could now try to log in as that user
that was, in fact, already deleted.
And so, again, we should not let that happen.
So let me delete this user here now.
And there we go.
And so, let's test it now.
And again, keep in mind that the user belonging to the ID
which is in this payload is now no longer there.
So let's see.
And indeed, we get this error message that we just created.
So that one is working as well.
And let's go to the last one.
So step number four,
check if user has recently changed their password.
So basically, after the token was issued.
And to implement this test,
we will actually create another instance method.
So basically, a method that is going to be available
on all the documents.
So documents are instances of a model.
All right?
And we do this because it's quite a lot of code
that we need for this verification.
And so, actually, this code belongs to the User model
and not really to the controller.
Okay?
And so, let's do that just like we did before
for checking the password.
So in User model, we already implemented
this correctPassword static instance method, remember?
And so, let's now create another one.
So userSchema.methods.changedPasswordAfter.
So function, and into this function,
we will pass the JWT timestamp.
So basically, that timestamp which says
when the token was issued.
So let's call that JWTTimestamp.
All right.
And by default, we will return false from this method.
And that will then mean
that the user has not changed his password
after the token was issued.
Okay?
So let's put that here, return false, basically by default.
Okay.
But then, we also have if this,
and remember that in an instance method,
the this keyword always points to the current document.
And so therefore, here we have access to the properties.
Now, we actually need to create a field now in our schema
for the date where the password has been changed.
So we don't have that yet.
So let's quickly add it here.
So passwordChangedAt,
and the type of it will be a Date.
Now, this passwordChangedAt property here
will always be changed, of course,
when someone change the password.
So right now, we don't have that logic anywhere,
and so nowhere we are actually defining this property.
And so, most of the documents, so most of the users,
they will simply not have this property in their data,
so in their object, right?
And so, of course, we need to test for that.
Okay?
So if the passwordChangedAt property exists,
only then we want to actually do the comparison.
Okay?
But if not, so if passwordChanged does not exist,
well then that means that the user
has never actually changed the password,
and so therefore we can simply return false.
So again, that's our default,
meaning that the user has not changed the password
after this timestamp.
Okay.
And now, just to start, let's actually log to the console
this.passwordChangedAt,
and of course, the JWTTimestamp as well,
just so we can see how we could compare them.
All right.
And now we need to actually create a user
which has this property on it, okay?
And again, later in the section
when we will implement the logic for changing the password
is when we will then set this property.
Okay?
But now we will artificially, basically, set it here
when we create a new user.
Okay?
So let's put that here.
And here, any date, actually, will serve.
So let's say 30 April 2019 here.
And so that should then be parsed into MongoDB just fine.
Let's try that, see if it works.
And that didn't work.
So it couldn't really parse the date, let's say.
And actually, I need to start with the year
and then the day at the end.
So 2019 and then 30 of April.
Try that again.
And so you see that now it's actually working.
So we have this parsed date here.
Okay?
Now, in order to actually see the result of this,
we, of course, need to call this method.
Okay?
So that's what we're gonna do here in step four.
And so, remember that we can call this instance method
on a user document.
So freshUser.changedPasswordAfter,
and then that timestamp.
So that's at decoded.iat, so issued at, basically.
All right.
So let's simply see the result of doing that.
And so, of course, this should now, not here,
so this should now log to the console these two values.
Okay.
Now, of course I need to log in with exactly this user,
so with test,
so here we go.
Log in.
Copy this token here again.
And again, we're gonna basically automate that
in the next video, actually.
Okay.
Paste it here.
And now, we actually get this bug here.
So I just misspelled this function name here.
Well, let's just copy it.
Try it again.
Oh man.
What's going wrong now?
And I see I simply forgot this log here.
So another stupid mistake.
Probably saw that one coming.
But now here we go.
So everything worked fine,
and all we really wanted to see for now
is these two results.
So we basically have this one here this date format,
and then the other one
in this millisecond or second timestamp here.
And so, we now need to convert this passwordChangedAt
also to a timestamp like that.
All right?
And so, for that, let's create a new variable.
So changedTimestamp.
And we can use this.passwordChangedAt.getTime.
Okay?
And so, that's one of the many, many date functions
that JavaScript gives us.
All right.
And now, let's quickly compare these two
because we're not quite ready yet, actually.
So sending it just to see the results here.
And so what we see here basically
is that this one here is now, basically, in seconds,
and this one in milliseconds.
So it's 1000 times more.
And so, we know we need to divide this by 1000
and then parse this entire thing as an integer.
And for that, we use parseInt.
So another JavaScript function that's available for numbers.
And then we actually also need to specify the base.
So this is a base 10 number.
All right?
And so now, let's actually, again, see the result.
And now, that looks a lot friendlier.
Okay.
And so, now let's actually return our result.
And again, keep in mind that false means not changed.
Okay?
And not changed basically means that the day or the time
at which the token was issued
is less than the changed timestamp.
Okay?
So just as an example here,
let's say that the token was issued at time 100.
But then, we changed the password, let's say, at time 200.
Okay?
And so, we changed
the password after the token was issued,
and so therefore, this is now true.
All right?
And that's exactly what we want to return here,
because false means not changed,
and so true, of course, means changed.
And so, that's exactly what we have here.
But now, let's say that the password
was last changed at 200,
but then only after that, we issued the token,
so let's say, at time 300.
And so, 300, less than 200?
No, that's false.
And so, we return false, which again means not changed.
And so, that's why we use this less sign here.
Okay?
Let's go back to our controller and actually use this.
So if the password was actually changed,
well, in this case, we actually want an error.
So return next, again, a new AppError.
Recently...
Please log in again.
Okay.
And once more, code 401.
All right.
So again, this will return true
if the user actually changed their password.
And so, if all of this here is true,
well, then exactly in that case
is when we want this error to happen.
All right?
So that was actually the last step.
Okay.
So basically, if the code can make it all to the end
of this code here, only then, next will be executed.
And then, with next, we go to the next route handler,
which effectively means to grant access
to that protected route.
Let's actually put that here.
Grant access to protected route.
Okay?
Because that's really all this next does.
Next leads us to the next middleware,
which is usually, then, the route handler itself,
so the one which sends back the data that was protected.
Okay.
Just one last thing that we want to do here
is to actually then put the entire user data on the request.
So we can simply say, req, so request, .user
will be equal to the freshUser.
Okay.
And again, of course,
the code only ever reaches this point here
in case everything is correct.
Okay?
And so, this here might then be useful
at some point in the future.
Great.
Let's just test this one more time.
And basically, this change is in the past now.
And so, this token that we have here,
or actually, I could have reused just this one
instead of logging it again.
But anyway, this token was issued
after the password changed.
And so, this token should now work.
So let's actually log in again
and try it with this token.
And indeed, we get access.
Now, moving to Compass in order to change that date.
Okay.
Let's put it one month later.
And so, that will actually be in the future,
so at least, in my future when I'm recording this video.
Of course, you will be doing this at a later point.
And so, to test this, please put this in your future.
So in the future of the date
where you're watching this video.
So if I go now back to Postman and log in again,
okay, so if I log in again now
and try to access that route,
well, then this token will be issued, basically,
after the password has been changed.
Or actually before the password has been changed.
So, sorry for that confusion.
So the password was changed at May 30,
but this token was issued at May the 2nd, and so, before.
So basically, it's now as if the user
had changed their password after the token was issued.
And so, that's exactly the situation
where we don't want to give access to the protected route.
And so, this should now then reflect that.
And indeed, user recently changed password,
please log in again.
Great.
So that now works.
So our protect middleware is now completely implemented.
Let's just get rid of this console.log here.
Don't need that one any more.
And okay.
So let's quickly recap,
and this video is running very long,
bit longer than I expected.
But it's really important to understand
and to explain how all of this works
and why it's important.
And so, I prefer that than doing this video's much shorter.
Of course, I could just write the code,
but then you wouldn't really understand what's going on.
So this part we already understood.
Then this part, I believe as well,
so this is where the verification happens,
so basically seeing if the token payload
has not been manipulated by some malicious third party.
Okay?
And since we then reach this code here,
it means that no one changed the JSON web token,
and so therefore, we can get a fresh user.
So basically, we can get the current user,
let's actually call it currentUser.
Why not?
So here, here, and also here.
Okay?
So we can get the currentUser from that ID
that was just decoded from the payload.
Now, if the currentUser does not exist,
so this is what we're testing for here,
well, then in that case
we do not want to give access to the route,
and instead create this new error.
But if the user does exist,
well, then we make it to point number four,
where we then check if a password change has happened
after the token was issued, right?
And if it did, then again, we create a new error.
And if it did not, well,
then we make it to all the way
to the end of the middleware function,
where we then assign the currentUser to request.user
so that we can then use it in a next middleware function.
Okay?
Because remember, this request object,
this is the one that travels, basically,
from middleware to middleware.
And so, if we want to pass data
from one middleware to the next one,
then we can simply put some stuff on the request object,
and then that data will be available at a later point.
All right.
So, that's it.
This is a very sophisticated
and very complete route-protecting algorithm, basically,
but I think it's really important
to do it as well as we can.
Anyway, glad to see that you made it
to the end of this big video,
and I'll see you in the next one.