So, over the last few videos,
we allowed a user to reset his password
and then create a new one,
but now we also want to allow
a logged-in user to simply update his password
without having to forget it,
and so without that whole reset process.
So, let's build that now.
And, just like before,
let's do that in our authentication controller.
So, export.updatePassword.
All right, and so, just like always,
our three Middleware parameters here, and okay.
Now remember that this password updating functionality is
only for logged-in users,
but still we need the user to pass in his current password,
so in order to confirm
that user actually is who he says he is.
So, just as a security measure
because imagine that someone would find your computer open
and then be able to change passwords on the sites
that you have currently open
without being prompted for a password again.
And so that would basically log you out
of all your existing applications,
which would, of course, be a terrible experience.
And so, as a security measure, we always need to ask
for the current password before updating it, all right.
And, with that in mind, let's lay out all the steps
that we need to take in order to implement
this functionality just like before.
So, first up, we need to get the user
from the collection, basically.
Then second, we need to check
if the posted password is correct.
Right.
Then, third, so if the password is correct,
then update the password.
And finally, we need to again log the user in,
so basically to send the jsonwebtoken back to the user,
now logged in with the new password that was just updated.
Okay, and this is actually all very similar to
what we did already before,
and so I'm leaving this one for you
as a challenge, okay?
So, please try to go ahead and implement this on your own,
and if you need, you can of course take a look at the code
that we wrote before,
but really try to write the code on your own
without copying too much, okay?
So, you can take a look at the rest of the code to see
how it works, but then don't really just copy it, okay?
Because then you're not really gonna learn, all right.
So, pause the video here, and I'll see you in a second
with my solution.
Okay, so I hoped you managed to implement this
and to get it working, this is how I did it.
So, as always, we create a new user variable,
and in there we await the result of doing User.findById,
and now where is this ID actually coming from?
Well, remember again that this update password is only
for authenticated, so for logged in users,
and so therefore, at this point, we will already have
the current user on our request object.
Okay, so that's coming from the protect Middleware.
So, req.user.id, and then remember
that we need to explicitly ask for the password, okay?
Because it is, by default, not included in the output.
So, we defined that on the schema, remember?
And, we actually need that password
because now we want to compare it with the one
that's stored in the database,
and for that, just like before,
we're gonna use this instance object
that we have somewhere here.
Yeah, so correctPassword, which is available
on all the user documents,
so it takes in the candidate password first,
and then the actual user password, all right.
Oh, and now it's giving me this error
because, of course, I didn't declare this
as an async function just yet.
So, async, and before we forget it,
let's wrap it into the catchAsync function here as well.
Anyway, just like before,
we basically want to create an error here
if the current password is not correct,
and so, let's write that in code.
So, if not user.correctPassword,
and then the candidate password remember,
and so that one is gonna be in a body,
in a property that we're gonna call the passwordConfirm.
Okay, and then as a second argument the actual password,
so that's a user.password.
And then, remember that this is an asynchronous function,
and so we need to also await it here.
Good, so in case that the password is not correct,
just like always, we create a new error here.
So, new AppError, and this time we're saying
your current password is wrong,
and then status code 401 for unauthorized.
All right, great.
Now, if we make it to this point in code,
so basically if the password is also correct,
well then we can actually update the password,
and how do we do that?
Well, very simple, we did that before.
All we say is user.password is equal to req.body.password,
and then the same, of course, for the password confirm.
Okay, and the validation will be done automatically
by the validator that we specified on the schema,
and that will be done once we actually save it.
So, we await user.save,
and so this time we do not turn off the validation
because, of course, we want the validation to happen,
so just as I said before, we want to check
that the password confirm is actually the same
as the password, right?
Good.
And, now just to really make sure that you understand
why we didn't do something like user.findByIdAndUpdate.
So, why didn't we do it like this?
And, I know that I talked about this many times before,
but I want you to understand one hundred percent
why we cannot use this update,
and it is for two reasons,
so let me go back again to our model.
So, the first one is
that this validation here is not going to work, okay?
And that's basically because this.password is not defined
when we update, so when we use find by ID and update,
because internally, behind the scenes,
Mongoose does not really keep the current object in memory,
and so therefore, this here is not going to work.
And, as I said, I already talked about that before,
so it's actually written out here as well, okay?
But, it's really important to keep in mind not to use update
for anything related to passwords, all right?
So, this one is not going to work,
and also, these two pre-saved
Middlewares are also not going to work.
So, if we used simply update for updating the password,
then that password would not be encrypted,
which is this first Middleware,
and then also, the passwordChangedAt
timestamp would also not be set, okay?
So, none of this would work,
and so again, we really need to do it like this.
Let's just put that here again.
And so now, (mumbles), we logged the user in,
and sent the token back to the client.
Now, that would actually be the fourth time
that we did the same code,
so basically this piece of code,
and so, that's now very quickly refactor this
into its own function.
Now, this code actually is not the same everywhere.
So, here we sent the status code 400,
and we do not send the user,
but then up here in the signup handler,
we actually have a different status code,
and we also sent the user to the client, okay?
And so, let's make our function actually keep that in mind.
So, let's create a function here,
create and send token,
and then the arguments that we need in here are the user
because that's where the ID is stored.
Then, we also want the status code,
and of course, we need to have access to the response object
in order to actually be able to send a response
back to the client, okay?
And so, basically now what we need is this code.
So, let's copy it, put it here,
and then replace irrelevant variables.
So, the user is simply called user,
so just like this, and here, the same.
So, not new user,
and then here we replace that with the status code,
so the one that's coming in into our function,
and so I guess that's actually it.
So, let's now go ahead and replace it,
so createSendToken, and here the user is called the newUser,
the status code is 201,
and then of course the response object.
Okay, now we can get rid of this code,
and let's just copy it.
All right, so in the log in we of course also sent a token,
but this time the user is actually called user
and the status code is 200.
And now, let's copy this one.
So, the next one should be here, and reset password,
and here it's actually the same,
so the name is user and code 200,
and now, finally, here it's also the same.
And so, that finishes our update password function.
Now, to make this work,
we of course need to implement the route here as well
in our user router.
So, router.patch, and we will do a patch
because we're actually changing, so we're manipulating
the user document, and so that's what patch is for.
And the route is called updateMyPassword.
So, my password because it's
for the currently logged in user, and then remember, again,
this only works for logged in users,
and so we need to use authController.protect,
which will then also put the user object
on a request object, okay?
So, protect, and then authController update password
that we just created, all right.
And so, let's now actually go ahead and test this, okay?
So, let's copy this route here,
so UpdateMyPassword,
and now what we need to send in the body is
these three passwords actually,
so it's basically the passwordCurrent,
and for now I'm leaving them empty,
I simply want to put the field names here for now.
So, passwordCurrent then just password,
which is basically the new one,
and then, of course, passwordConfirm.
Okay, and now we actually need to log in as a user
because remember, this only works
if the user is already logged in, all right.
And so, let's actually do it with the administrator here.
And this here is, should be still the current password,
and indeed, we are now logged in.
And remember that this token now gets stored
into the JWT environment variable,
and so, here, in order to authenticate,
let's then actually use that just like we did before.
So, in this authorization tab, we select Bearer Token,
and then it will actually automatically pre-fill
this JWT variable.
All right, and so that's then where actually
the user ID is gonna come from, remember?
Anyway, let's now specify the current password, so pass1234,
and then let's say newpassword, okay?
Copy it and paste it here,
but actually again, I want to start by testing it
with a wrong password confirm,
just to see if our validation is still working,
and now the route is not defined,
but that's simply because we're using the wrong verb here.
Of course, it needs to be patch.
Let's try that again,
but now we get your current password is wrong,
but actually it's not, so it's actually correct.
So, something must be wrong with our code,
so let's try to take a look here.
And yeah, so here is actually the problem
because we do not want to compare or confirm password,
of course, but with the current password.
Okay, so that's just a stupid bug, all right,
and so now it should be working.
So, of course, we want to compare the current password
with the one that is currently stored
in the database, all right.
So, let's try that again,
and so that's the validation error that we were looking for,
so the passwords are not the same
because, indeed, they are not.
And now, before actually updating the password,
let's just take a look at Compass here.
Let's just update it here quickly,
and so, right now, this is the password.
So, ending here is pW1i, okay?
And so, let's update the password now
and see what it's gonna look like afterwards, okay?
So, now everything should be correct.
And, indeed, we get our success and our token, all right.
So, let's confirm that here quickly,
and, indeed, you see that the password changed
and also the current timestamp,
so the time at which basically I'm recording this video.
All right, and now, just like before,
let's actually get this test here.
So, basically storing the token as an environment variable.
So, just so that everything really works here in Postman.
Okay, let's save that actually,
update current user password to make it really explicit,
and yeah, I think that's it.
I think this is all we need to do
in order to update a user's password .
Next up, we will then implement updating of other user data,
so stuff like email or passwords.