In this lecture, we will allow the currently logged in
user to manipulate his user data.
And so now, by implementing user updates,
we're really leaving the domain of authentication
and are moving more into real user related stuff, okay?
And so instead of using the authentication controller now,
let's implement this updating functionality
right in their userController.
Okay,
so we have a bunch of handlers, so of routes,
that are not really implemented here, okay?
But let's leave them aside for now
and create our new handler function down here.
And this one is gonna be called updateMe.
And so again, it's updateMe because it's for updating
the currently authenticated user.
Later on, we will then also implement
this updateUser function here, but that is then
for like an administrator to update all of the user data,
while the user itself can only update, for now at least,
the name and the email address.
So, request, response, and next.
(keyboard clacking)
And we are actually doing this, so updating the user data,
in a different route than updating the user password,
well because usually in a typical web application
that's always how it's done.
So you have usually one place
where you can update your password
and then another place where you can update data
about the user or the account itself.
And so here, we're just basically following that pattern.
So again, let's start by laying out our steps.
And the first thing that we want to do here
is to basically create an error
if the user tries to update the password.
So create error if user
posts basically password data.
But then if not, we simply need to update the user document.
So simple enough, and let's of course start
with the first one.
Of course there will be a body
where we're gonna pass in the data,
and so if on that body there is data on password,
or a password confirm...
(keys clacking)
Confirm.
Well in that case, we want to return immediately
and create a new Apperror.
Oh and I guess we didn't yet implement it here,
or actually require,
so let's just grab it from here.
So AppError...
It's not here,
so the userController...
So AppError, here we go.
So 'This route is not for password updates.
'Please use /updateMYPassword.'
So basically the route that we specified before.
So updateMYPassword.
And then also, a code 400 for a bad request.
And let's actually try this one out right away.
And for that just two things,
first we need to send back a response,
so let's say res.status(200) for okay,
and then json,
add the status as success.
And later we will then also send the updated user,
but let's leave that for later.
So that's the response, and now we of course
also need to add this route to our user Router.
So that's of course similar to update my password,
so router, and of course a patch,
/updateMe,
then again, it is a protected route
so only the currently authenticated user can update
the data of the current user.
And so all of this is of course really secure,
again because the ID of the user that is gonna be updated
come from request.user,
which was set by this protect middleware here,
which in turn got the idea from the json web token,
and since no one can change the ID in that json web token
without knowing the secret, well we know
that the ID is then safe because of that.
And so because of this, everything here is safe.
So, userController.updateME.
Now okay...
So let's test this now.
Go ahead and copy this again.
And first of all, let's set the authorization.
Again from the Bearer Token
and of course with this environment variable.
Also it needs to be a patch request,
and we need to specify a body.
And I want to start by testing it,
causing this error of course,
and so let's specify a password,
and then a name.
So let's say that this is the name that we want to update,
so let's save this here.
And actually it is of course in the Users folder.
User Data.
And actually let's create a new folder here,
and put the stuff that is related to authentication
into its own folder.
So up here, we create a new folder
and call it Authentication.
That's not correct.
AH-THEN-TICATION.
(chuckles) So that's it.
And so the password is related to authentication,
also resetting the password, forgetting the password,
logging in, and signing out.
So, let's close these two,
and now log in as,
or actually let's create a new user.
So let's sign up here,
as a normal user so we can get rid of these two here.
And now I'm simply calling it, well, test again, all right?
And let's take a look at what users we currently have
in our database.
So we have hello and admin,
and so let's now use test.
And I'm always again, using the same password
to make it really easy.
All right, we need to give the name as well,
let's just call it J here.
And now indeed we get our token,
and we're already logged in,
and so now when we update the user,
that should be for this user that was just logged in.
So I'm not trying to update and of course,
no updating is yet implemented and so that's not gonna work.
All I want to see is the error that should happen
because I specified this password property here on the body.
So let's try it out.
And here we get this kind weird looking error,
but I guess it is simply because we didn't
actually update the route here,
so remember I just copied a route, so the URL,
and just pasted it here.
But of course, it needs to be updateME.
So let's try that again.
And so now we actually get that error that we specified.
"This route is not for password updates.
"Please use /updateMyPassowrd."
So great, that part is working,
and it's also working that we need to be authenticated.
Because let's say that we have no authentication,
and so let's say that: No Auth.
And so let's try that again now.
And so indeed, "You are not logged in!
"Please log in to get access."
So just to prove you that our authentication
is actually also doing its job here.
But of course, we want our Bearer Token,
and so now we get that other error.
Great, so let's now go ahead implement
the rest of the functionality for the updateMe handler.
So updating the user document,
and we could try to do it with user.safe.
So just like before, basically getting the user
then updating the properties, and then by the end,
saving the document.
But the problem with that is that there are some fields
that are required which we're not updating,
and then because of that,
we will some error.
And so just to quickly demonstrate to you,
let me actually do that.
Okay, so very quickly, getting the user here.
So findbyId, so request.user as we already know, .id.
And then let's say, user.name = 'Jonas'
and then await user.save.
But again you see that this will give us an error then.
But for now let's also of course declare it
as an async function.
And all right.
So let's test it now,
but we should expect to see an error now.
So let's of course get rid of this one,
and indeed we get: "Please confirm your password".
And so that's because passwordConfirm is a required field
but we did of course not specify it.
And so the safe method is not really the correct option
in this case.
So instead what we can do now is
to actually use findById and update.
So we could not use that before for all the reasons
that I explained to you multiple times by now.
But now since we're not dealing with passwords,
but only with this non-sensitive data like name or email,
we can now use findById and update.
So, let's get rid of this.
Let's also call it here updatedUser.
And then in here, we need to pass not only the ID,
but also the data that should be updated,
and then some options.
So the data, let's for now call it x here,
and I'm telling you why in a second,
and then the options that we want to pass in.
And so that's just like before,
the new option set to true,
so that it returns the new object,
so basically the updated object instead of the old one.
And the also runValidators set to true.
Because indeed we want the models to validate our document.
So for example, if we put in an invalid email address,
that should be catched by the Validator and return an error.
Now why am I putting x here, and not simply request.body?
Well that's because we actually do not want
to update everything that's in the body,
because let's say the user puts, in the body,
the role for example.
We could have body.role set to admin for example,
and so this would then allow any user
to change the role, for example, to administrator.
And of course that can not be allowed.
Or the user could also change their reset token,
or when that reset token expires,
and all of that should not be allowed of course.
So doing something like this would
of course be a huge mistake.
And so we need to make sure that the object
that we pass here,
so again that object that will contain the data
that's gonna be updated,
only contains name and email,
because for now these are the only fields
that we want to allow to update.
And so basically we want to filter the body
so that in the end, it only contains name and email
and nothing else.
So if then the user tries to change the role,
that will then be filtered out
so that it never finds its way to our database.
So what we want to do is to basically create a variable
and let's say filteredBody,
and then we're gonna create function in a second,
but let's just already use it here,
just so you see how it's gonna work.
And then in here we pass the data,
so the object that we want to filter,
so req.body, because that's where all the data is,
and then we pass a couple of arguments.
One for each of the fields that we want to keep
in the object.
So we want to keep the field called name,
and the field called email.
And again, a bit later we might then add more fields here,
for example later we might allow the user
to upload an image.
And of course that we then also need to update
in the database.
But for now, all we want to keep
in the body is name and email and filter out all the rest.
And so here, let's now use filteredBody,
instead of x of course.
And so now what we need to do is to actually implement
this function which will take care of filtering the object.
So let's do that here.
FilterObj,
which will take in an object
and then the rest parameters for all the allowed fields.
And so this will then basically create an array
containing all of the arguments that we passed in.
So basically that were passed in after this first one.
So in that case, it is an array containing name and email.
So what we need to do now is basically
to loop through the object and for each element check
if it's one of the allowed fields,
and if it is, simply add it to a new object,
that we're then gonna return in the end.
And probably there are more efficient of better ways
to implement this,
but let's just do it very quick here.
So we're gonna loop the object by saying
Object.keys of the object that we pass in.
So that's one of the easy ways to loop
through an object in JavaScript.
So, this here then basically returns an array
containing all the key names,
so the field names of this object,
and then we can loop through them.
Then our callback function.
And for each element, this is what we're gonna do.
So, if the allowed field array
includes the current element, so the current field name,
then we want to add that to a new object.
So let's quickly create that one here,
so const newObj
which is empty for now,
and in the end, that's the one that we're gonna return.
So newObj.
So if the current field is one of the allowed fields,
well then newObj with the field name of the current field,
should be equal to whatever is in the object
at the current element, so the current field name.
So don't if this looks a bit confusing,
this is again just standard JavaScript,
it has nothing to do with no JS or eXpress
or anything like that.
So again, all we do here is to basically loop
through all the fields that are in the object
and then for each field, we check
if it's one of the allowed fields.
And if it is, then we create a new field in the new object,
of course with the same name,
so still name element, with the exact same value
as it has in the original object.
And then in the end of course, we return that one.
And so this should now all be working here.
Then all we need to do in the end
is to send that updated user to the client.
So, user.
Now of course, we need to put the udatedUser then here,
give it a save again, and so now it should work.
Se really what we did here was..
update the user last, and before we did that,
we actually filtered out unwanted field names
that are not allowed to be updated.
So let's try that now.
And this user here is a regular user,
so we just created him,
remember with the name of J.
And so let's quickly take a look at Compass.
So it's a normal user, with a name of J.
And so let's now update then name,
and also try to update the role,
which again is not allowed.
But to see if our code is working, let's try it.
So there is the name already, and let's say
we're a malicious user
trying to change our role to admin.
So, everything is correct I guess,
so let's send this now,
and indeed here is our updated object.
So we get our new name, which is Jonas Schmedtmann,
and then the role, which is still user.
It didn't update the role to admin.
Perfect. That's exactly what we wanted.
So, give this a save and let's go back
and actually with this we just finished this video.
Next up, we will then implement a functionality
of deleting the current user.
So we worked on updating, next up we want to allow a user
to basically delete himself when he no longer wants
to be part of our application.