Knowing how to work with data
is one of the most important and valuable skills
that you can have as a backend developer.
And that's why in this section
we're gonna dive really deep into
data modeling concepts and techniques,
the model, or the data, for application in multiple ways,
and also learn how to implement, or data model,
using advanced Mongoose features.
And so, all this will really take your backend skills,
and also Mongoose skills, to a whole new level.
So by the end of this section
our API will actually be fully functioning
with all routes and all resources,
a complete authentication and authorization,
and also all established relationships
between all the data sets.
So, with that being said, let's now get started
with MongoDB data modeling.
(upbeat music)