Let's now improve the nested
route implementation that we coded in the last lecture.
And for that,
we're gonna use a special advanced express feature.
So, as you remember, in the last video
we implemented a simple nested post route,
so just this one here.
Right. And so this means that the review route
is kind of within the tour route.
And again, because reviews belong to tours in a sense.
Right?
And so this is a very common thing to do in Api design.
Now, the problem with this implementation is that it is,
of course, a bit messy.
And that is because we put a route for creating a review
in the tour router.
Simply because a route starts with slash tour.
So that's a bit confusing,
and what's also confusing
is that we have something very similar to this here,
also in our review route.
So, basically this here.
So when we create a new review without the nested route,
this piece of the code here is actually exactly the same
as this one. Right?
And so, besides this being a bit confusing,
we also have duplicate code which we would have to maintain
in two separate places in case we wanted to change anything.
And so again, that's a very bad practice.
And so let's now fix this using an advanced express feature
called mergeParams.
So first off let's remove this code here
which doesn't really belong to the tour router.
Next up, we will actually import the review router
into this tour router.
Okay?
So right now we are importing the review controller,
but actually we want the review router.
So let's get rid of this one,
and actually I'm going to delete it altogether.
And now,
the review
router.
And okay.
So, let's actually get this code
and put it here at the top,
just so that we see what we're doing,
because we will actually create some new code
right here at the top.
And so what we're gonna do here
is to say
router.use.
And so we will basically say that this tour router
should use the review router
in case it ever encounters a route like this.
And
Review routes.
Did I call it routes or router?
Should be called router.
Okay?
So, keep in mind that a router itself
is really just a middleware.
And so we can use the use method on it,
and then say that for this specific route here,
we want to use the review router instead.
Okay?
And so this is actually again mounting a router.
So, if you take a look at that,
here in the app.js,
that's actually exactly what we did.
So we did .use,
then the URL,
and then the router.
And so here, what we're doing
is actually the exact same thing.
So this is the tour router, and so then we say
well whenever you find a URL like this,
well, then just use the review router.
And so, right now, when we have a URL like this,
it will start by getting into the tour router here,
okay, because, again it starts with slash tours,
okay,
so basically it's rerouted into the tour router,
then when it reaches the tour router,
then it will match this URL here,
and then it will again be rerouted into the review router.
And like this, we have the tour router
and the review router nicely separated
and decoupled from one another.
But now, there's actually still one piece missing
because right now this review router here
doesn't get access to this tour id parameter, okay.
And so now we need to enable the review router
to actually get access to this parameter here as well.
So let's now move to the review router, okay.
And so this is where the medical mergeParams
that I mentioned right in the beginning
comes into play.
So here, in the express.router function,
we can specify some options,
and here all we need to do is set mergeParams
to true.
And that's it.
But why do we actually need this here?
Well, it's because, by default,
each router only have access
to the parameters of their specific routes, right.
But here, in this route, so in this URL for this post,
there's of course actually no tour id.
But, we still want to get access to the tour id
that was in this other router, right.
So this here.
And so, in order to get access to that parameter
in this other router,
we need to physically merge the parameters, okay.
And so that's what mergeParams, set to true, does.
And so now, no matter if we get a route like this,
so let's just copy it here,
Again it's easier to visualize it with an example.
And so again, no matter if we get a route like this,
or a route like this,
it will now all end up in this handler here, okay.
So in the end basically to this handler function.
And again that works because all of the routes
starting with this kind of pattern here
will be redirected to this router
exactly in this line of code here, okay.
So we redirected to the review router here
and so then in there it will match to this exact route,
okay.
And thanks to merge parameters,
we then get access to this id
which actually comes from the other router before.
Great.
So let's just do some clean up here,
actually get rid of this,
this here,
and
let's quickly try it out now.
So I'm gonna create a new review here
and let's try another tool this time.
So the city wanderer.
And all we need to do is to change
that id right here in the URL, right.
So, the rating is gonna be three,
and then
was kinda okay.
All right, and so this review will still be done with Jonas,
so from this account, okay,
because that's still one
that is logged in at this current moment, okay.
So, let's send that,
and indeed here we get the tour that we just specified,
and still the same user.
So that's again just to make sure check the tour
to see if it now gets this review
and yeah, it did.
And so that merge parameter trick, that we just implemented,
actually works just fine,
and as intended.
Now to see this in action, even better,
we're gonna adapt the henry function
for getting all the reviews for a specific tour
right in the next video.