Welcome back.
So in this video, you're gonna learn a super secure way
of logging out users.
So up until this point, when we wanted to delete a user,
we would simply delete the cookie from our browser.
Right?
So something like this,
and then remove it.
However, the thing is that we created this cookie
as an http only cookie.
Remember that,
and so that means that we cannot manipulate this cookie
in any way in our browser.
So we cannot change it,
and we can also not delete it.
So let's just quickly take a look at that place in the code
where we did that.
So in the auth controller
up there where we actually create that cookie
so that is right here.
And so again, remember, that this means that we can not
manipulate the cookie in the browser in any way.
Not even destroy it.
So delete it.
So if we want to keep using this super secure way here
of storing cookies,
then how are we going to be able to actually log out users
on our website?
Because usually with JWT authentication
we just delete the cookie
or the token from local storage.
But well, again, that's not possible when using it this way.
And so what we're gonna do instead is to create a
very simple log out route that will simply send back a new
cookie with the exact same name
but without the token.
And so that will then override the current cookie that we
have in the browser with one that has the same name
but no token.
And so when that cookie is then sent along with
the next request, then we will not be able to identify
the user as being logged in.
And so this will effectively then log out the user.
And also were gonna give this cookie
a very short expiration time.
And so this will effectively be a little bit like
deleting the cookie
but with a very clever workaround like this, okay?
So let's do that here, right after log in.
So again when we're doing token based authentication
we usually never need an end point like this
but when we want to send a super secure cookie like we do
well, then we have to do it like this.
So, again, on the response we set the cookie,
and the secret is to give it the exact same name.
So just as I mentioned before,
and that is jwt.
So just like here, okay?
But here, we then send the token,
but now we will send simply some dummy text.
So let's say logged out,
and then the cookie options.
So an expire date,
like in 10 seconds from now.
So let's create a new date
based on
date.now
plus 10 seconds.
So that's 10 times 1000.
And also I'm going to set it, again, to http only.
Set to true,
but we do not need to set it as secure,
because in this case there is no sensitive data
that anyone can get a hold of.
Here we're missing the comma,
and so now all we need to do is send this response back.
So status 200
and let's simply mark it as success here.
Then in our route we need to add it, of course, as well
so that's at the user route
so let's do it right here after log in,
but this one will actually be a get request
because we're not going to send any data
along with the request
we're not changing anything,
we actually simply get a cookie.
And so that name actually makes sense.
Or that verb actually makes sense.
So log out,
and so now we are good to actually hit that route
just like we did here with our Axios library.
So export,
log out,
or actually const first
and so just like before
we're using a try catch block
which in this case is not really that important
because there can not really be an error while logging out,
right?
But anyway, just in case, for example,
we have no internet connection.
So in that case, we then will get a nice error
and let's actually do that first here.
So show error
logging out
try again.
Okay, but this here, as I said,
should not happen that often.
So instead
let's
do our request with Axios.
All right.
And so the method this time is get
and the URL is
similar to what we have here,
But it is
log out.
And then as the next step, let's also reload the page.
So that's what we always do manually
when we delete a cookie, right?
And so here of course we need to do it programatically.
Right?
And we need to do it here
because since this is an Ajax request we can not do it
on the back end side.
So we can't do it with express.
And so we need to, of course, do it manually here.
Right?
Otherwise we would technically be logged out
but our user menu would still reflect
so it would still show that we are logged in.
And so of course, we simply need to reload the page
which would then send the invalid cookie basically
to the server,
so that one that we just received without a token
and then we are no longer logged in,
and therefore then our user menu will disappear, okay?
So let's do that if there was a success.
So just like before, rest.data.status.
And so in this end point, we also send back
the status set to success,
and so we can once more test for that here.
And so if this is the case
well we actually don't even need this
so in this case widow location.reload.
And then something really important is that we actually
need to set it to true here,
and that will then force a reload from the server
and not from browser cache, all right?
Now and of course we need to mark it here as async,
and okay.
So this part here is really important again
because otherwise it might simply load the same page
from the cache
which would then still have our user menu up there.
But of course that's not what we want,
we really want a fresh page coming down from the server.
All right?
So we have our log out function
and now in the index we basically need to now trigger it
once we hit that button.
So let's create an element here first.
So the log out button
document.querySelector
and remember how we created this element.
So that's here.
So this one.
So we're selecting now by this class.
All right, and we could of course used an id as well here,
but that's not really important, okay?
What matters here is to now say
if there is a log out button,
then logOutButton.addEventListener.
So we want it to listen to all events happening
on that button whenever there is a click.
So we're waiting for the click event
and when that happens we then call the log out function
which we didn't import yet,
so let's add that here.
So log in and log out.
All right, and that should actually be it.
So, let's test it now.
Reload it again just to be sure,
and now
Oh, we get error logging out.
Try again, why is that.
Well, let's try to get a better look at the error.
But what's important is that actually all of this
is already working.
So this event listener here
and also this log out function is kind of doing its job.
So let's just do
console.log error.response.
So let's reload this here.
Should kind of happen automatically.
All right.
So try that again.
So what is happening here
so cast to object id failed for value log out.
So that's very weird.
Take a look at that route.
Oh, of course,
that's a serious mistake.
Should be log in of course.
Okay, but this kind of course, again, happen all the time.
So let's reload this here.
And try this again.
And now we're getting something here.
Now it's still and error,
but that's no problem at all.
So we have a JSON web token error
because our JSON web token is malformed.
And so it's coming, as you can see,
from the is logged in middleware.
And so we can kind of guess why that is, right?
So let's go back add our auth controller.
And so the JSON web token that we're basically
sending now is this here, right?
So this logged out.
And so then here in
the isLoggedIn that will then basically trigger an error.
So here in JSON web token verify, right?
And since this entire function here is wrapped
in this catchASync it will send this error down to all
global error handling middleware.
And that will then create this error which in this case
we do not want, remember?
So in this isLoggedIn middleware we do not want
to cause any errors.
And so, let's actually fix that
and so we're going to remove this catchASync from here
because we do not want to catch any Async errors.
Instead what we want to do is to basically
catch them locally
and then if there's an error simply say next.
Like this, okay?
So let's do that.
So wrap all of this into a try.
Close it here.
Well, something else wrong.
Ah! Probably we are just missing the catch block.
And so in this case we want to go to the next middleware.
So basically saying that there is no logged in user.
Right?
So, let's test it again.
Go back, oh , and now we're no longer logged in.
So log in.
That was successful.
And now straight away let's log out.
Ah! Beautiful! Now it works correctly.
And so this time what happened here is that of course
this verification here failed
because that JSON web token was not in a format that
this algorithm expected.
But what happened in this case is that the error was
not catched using our catchASync function
but instead it then went straight to catch err,
which then went straight to the next middleware.
All right, great!
So if we now take a look at our cookies,
well we have one in use that probably has already expired.
So you see it only has this life of 10 seconds
and so if I reload this page now actually
then is should already be gone.
So you see zero cookies in use.
Okay, and that's actually all we have to do
in order to log out the user from our website.