In this second part of uploading tour images,
we are now going to process all of them.
But before we start doing that,
there's actually something that I need to fix
in the user controller.
And so actually in this resizeUserPhoto,
and that is that we actually need
to await this whole operation here, all right?
So all of this here will actually return a promise,
and that makes sense, right,
because all of these operations here, they take some time,
and so of course they happen in the background.
So they are asynchronous code,
and so obviously they should not block the event loop.
Now the problem here is that right now
we're calling this next function here,
so the next middleware, without actually waiting
that these operations here finish.
And that is not a good idea.
And so let's simply use await here,
and then of course async, and all that stuff.
So catchAsync in here.
All right, give it a save, and that's much better.
And so now we're actually going to do something
very similar with our tour images.
And so actually let me go ahead and copy this.
All right, and although it's not going
to be exactly the same, it's good to already have it here.
So this one will also be an async function.
All right, now just as before,
in case there are no images uploaded,
then we want to move straight to the next middleware.
So if there are no request.files,
and actually I'm gonna take it one step further,
requiring that there is both the image cover
and also images.
And so basically we want to move to the next middleware
in case there is no request.files.imageCover,
or no request.files.images.
So in that case, next.
Okay, and now let's start by processing the cover image,
and then afterwards all of the other images
in a loop, basically.
So other images.
Now where do we actually get the cover image?
Well remember how I said that it is at request.files?
No longer file, and then .coverImage,
or actually imageCover.
And then remember how it was an array?
So let's take a look at that one more time.
Right, so all of this is request.files,
and then from there we take imageCover,
and that is an array of one element.
And so now we want the element number zero,
and then .buffer.
So this weird looking thing here.
Then we want to resize it to a 2/3 ratio,
and the width will be 2,000 pixels,
and the height 1,333, all right?
And so again, that's a nice 3/2 ratio,
which is very common in images.
Next, we also want to format it as a JPEG with 90% quality,
and then save it as a file.
But this time it is to image/tours,
and here let's actually define our filename separately.
All right, because we're actually going to need it again.
So imageCoverFilename,
and so once more we now need to create a unique filename.
So now it's tour, and then let's again put the ID
of the tour here, where before it was the ID of the user.
And so that is at request.params,
so remember that this route
will always contain the ID of the tour,
and so therefore it's on request.params.id.
Then again the timestamp, Date.now,
and then let's say that this one is the cover image, okay?
And the other ones will then get some numbers.
And then of course .jpeg, and so let's use that here.
So imageCoverFilename.
Okay, and now as one last step,
we actually need to make it possible
that our update tour handler
then picks up this image cover filename to update it
in the current tour document, okay?
So let's quickly take a look
at how the document is actually updated.
And so we're very simply using
this updateOne factory function.
And that one will actually simply update all of the data
that's in the body onto the new document.
So just to prove that to you right here.
So updateOne, it takes in the entire request.body, okay?
And so now the secret is to actually put
this image cover filename on request.body, all right?
So request.body.coverImage.
Oh and again, it's called imageCover instead,
should be equal to imageCoverFilename, okay, makes sense?
And of course it is called imageCover
because that is the name we have in our schema definition.
And so then when it's doing the update,
it will then match this field in the body
with the field in our database.
And actually we can refactor this a bit
because we don't really need this variable name here at all.
So we could simply put this filename here right on the body.
So put that here, and then use it here right away.
So we don't need this line of code at all.
Great, and now before moving on to the other images,
let's actually test it with what we already have
at this point.
So let's get just rid of this console.log,
and so when we now do the request,
then our cover image should already be uploaded
and be put in the tour document, okay?
So these other three images here of course not,
but at least the image cover
should now be working at this point,
at least if we did everything correct.
So let's see if it is somewhere here,
and images is still empty obviously.
But I'm searching now for the cover image, so where is that?
And here it is, so imageCover,
and so that looks a lot like the filename
that we just specified.
And let's actually try to reload our all tours page here,
and maybe our new tour's already here.
Ah, here we go, so that is the new mountain biker tour.
And this here is indeed the image that we just uploaded.
So beautiful.
Now if we try to open up this page,
then the other images are not here, all right?
So they are nowhere to be found,
and so of course that's what we're gonna do next.
All right.
So remember that our images here
are also an array, which then contain
all of these new file uploads.
And so let's now actually use a loop
to process each of them in one iteration.
So request.files.images.foreach.
And then our callback function
in which we get access to the current file.
All right, now here we do actually need
to create the current filename,
and you will see why in a second.
So filename equals, and then something very similar to this.
With the difference that now it is not cover,
but instead we want to call them one, two and three.
And so in our callback function
we actually also get access to the current index, okay?
So we need file, and I for index.
And so here it is not cover, but index plus one.
So plus one, and that's just because this index
is zero-based, all right?
Next up comes the processing step itself,
which is again very similar to this one.
And now we of course need to mark this as async as well.
All right, and down here it is now the filename.
Okay, now why do we actually need this filename?
Well we need it because now we need to push this filename
into request.body.images, and so that's the exact same logic
as we had here before on request.body.imageCover.
So remember that in our collection,
request.body.images is actually an array.
And so now we need to create that array
and start it as an empty array.
So request.body.images
as an empty array, and then in each iteration
we will then push the current filename
to this images array.
So request.body.images.push,
the filename, all right?
And with this we're almost done.
There's just one small problem,
which is the fact that we're actually
not using async await correctly here in this case,
so in this loop.
And that's because this async await here
is only inside of this callback function
of the foreach loop.
And so that will actually not stop the code
from moving right next to this line
where we then call the next middleware, okay?
So again, right now we are actually not awaiting
any of this here, again, because this async await
happens inside of the callback function
of one of these loop methods.
And we run into this kind of problem actually before,
but there is fortunately a solution for this,
because since this is an async function here,
it will return a new promise.
And so if we do a map,
we can then actually save an array of all of these promises.
And then if we have an array
we can use promise.all to await all of them.
And so with that we will then actually await
until all this code, and in this case,
until all this image processing is done,
and only then move on to the next line,
which is calling the next middleware
to really update the tour documents.
And if we didn't do that in this case,
it would really not work at all,
because without this pushing here,
the request.body.images would still be empty
when we call next.
And so therefore, none of these image names
would then be persisted into the document, okay?
So let's now use promise.all,
and actually I'm not even saving this array here
to any variable, instead I will use promise.all
right away on this.
So await Promise.all
on the array returning from this, okay?
So I hope that made sense.
So now let's actually log the body here to the console.
All right, and so with this we should now be ready
to upload all of our images, all right?
Let's go down here and try this again.
All right, so where is our images array?
Well, maybe it was somewhere up here, ah, here it is.
So I missed that somehow.
And that looks very promising, right?
So three nice images,
let's now take a look here at our page.
Ah, there they are, but not quite correct, right?
So it looks as if we simply uploaded
the cover image three times.
So let's take a look at Postman,
but the image names are actually correct,
and so there's something wrong in our processing there.
Let's take a look also at requests.body, oh,
and I forgot to actually put it here.
Okay, but I think it's not even necessary
because we just saw in Postman
that the filenames are actually correct.
So we don't need this one anymore.
Now let's just take a look at the filenames
that we just uploaded, so that's in public and tours.
And so here they are.
So this was probably the first one from the last test.
And so as you see, all of them are, indeed,
the exact same image.
So cover, one, two, and three
are the same images, and so that's not correct.
And I can see actually right away what the problem is.
So you see that we're actually reading, still,
request.files.imageCover,
and not the file from the current iteration of this loop.
Okay, so instead that should be file.buffer.
All right, so let's actually go ahead
and delete all of these.
All right, and simply try it again now.
So let's send that.
Names appear still to be correct,
but now when we reload this, let's see.
Ah, that looks correct.
Beautiful, beautiful.
You see the images are all nicely formatted,
even this one which was, remember,
in portrait and not even landscape,
but we basically cropped that and it still looks beautiful.
Okay, so here we can now confirm that,
so that it's actually in the 2,000s by 1,333 pixels.
All right, it's still a little bit on the big side here,
so maybe we could reduce the quality a little bit more,
but that's not really important.
What really matters here is that the logic
that we just applied here really works.
So just to quickly recap what we did in these two lectures.
So we created a multer upload using the memory storage
and this filter only for images.
Then we created the upload tour image middleware
by using upload.fields, which takes in one image cover
and three images, and then on the request
it will put the files property like this, all right?
Then in our next middleware we resize these images,
and first the cover image,
and then the remaining three images.
And what's really important to note here
is how we put the image filenames on request.body.
And we do that so that in the next middleware,
which is the actual route handler,
it will then put that data onto the new document
when it updates it, okay?
So we do that with the image cover,
and we also do that with the remaining images
by pushing it into body.images,
which as we know from our tour schema,
expects an array of strings.
And so in this case, filenames.
So about these other images,
we had them on request.files.images, so it's an array,
and so of course we loop through it using map.
And we use map so that we can basically save
the three promises which are the result
of these three async functions here,
so we can then await all of them here
using Promise.all, okay?
And only after that we then move on
to the actual tour update handler, okay?
And this part is really important,
so it's important that we only move on
to the next middleware as soon as this part here
is really completed.
Because otherwise, request.body.images will be empty,
and of course our filenames are then not gonna be saved
to the current tour document, all right?
And that actually wraps up the image
or file uploading part of this section.
So I hope that was fun,
I know that for me it was really cool.
So I really like this kind of stuff,
which makes my applications feel like really real world.
Anyway, hope you enjoyed it,
and I'll see you in the next one.