With the file upload part
of the section finished,
let's now turn our attention to sending emails.
And we actually already sent email before,
for the password reset, but in the next couple of lectures
we're gonna take that to a whole new level.
And what we're gonna do is to build email templates
with pug and sending real emails
using the SendGrid service.
And now in this first lecture,
we're gonna build a more robust email handler
than the one that we had before.
So, let's open up our utilities folder,
and then in here, remember, we already have an email file.
But right now what we have here
is just a very simple email sending handler,
which is not able to take in a lot of options.
And so now we're going to build
a much more robust solution here.
All right?
So what I'm gonna do is to create a class,
and that class is gonna be called email.
So module.exports,
and so also this class is what we're going
to be exporting from this file.
And then as always, a class needs a constructor function,
which is basically the function that is gonna be running
when a new object is created through this class.
Now let's actually take a look
at how we would use this class in practice.
And so the idea, basically,
whenever we want to send a new email,
is to import this email class and then use it like this.
So creating a new email,
and then into it, we want to paste a user,
and so that user will then contain the email address,
and also the name in case we want to personalize the email.
And also a URL.
And a good example for this one
is for example, the reset URL for resetting the password.
Okay?
So, a new email object, and then on there
we want to call the method that is actually going
to send the email.
So, let's say sendWelcome.
And so that one is gonna be sent
whenever a new user signs up for our application.
All right?
We will then also have send password reset.
And the way we will set all this up
will make it really easy to then keep adding
new and new methods similar to this one
to send different emails for different scenarios.
All right?
Anyway, since we paste the user and the URL
into a new email, well, our constructor then needs
to take these in as arguments.
So user and URL.
And so what happens in this constructor is that this.to
will be equal to the user.email
Then we also want to define the first name of the user,
again in order to basically personalize the email.
And so that's user.name and let's split it
and take only the first element in the resulting array.
So we did this one before,
but then also this.url is equal to the incoming URL.
Finally, let's also set this.from right here.
so basically at the object level.
And so each object created from this class
will then get this property.
And so this one will be similar to what we have here.
So it's basically this from,
so let's just copy it
but it's nice to have it in a one central place like this.
Now one thing that I really want to do,
is to basically define this email address here
as a configuration variable,
and so an environment variable
that we can very easily change
by manipulating the config.env file.
All right?
So let's call this one EMAIL_FROM.
And then we only want the email address itself.
All right?
So another case where it's very helpful
to use environment variables.
And now let's make this a template string.
And of course plug that in here.
So that's process.env.EMAIL_FROM.
Next up, let's create a method here
in order to create the transport.
So similar to what we have here.
So createTransport.
And now here we actually want to have different transports
whether we are in production or not.
So when we're in production,
we actually want to send real emails,
and we will do that a bit later using SendGrid,
but if we are not in production
then we still want to use our Mailtrap application
just like we did it before when we send emails.
So instead of the email going to a real email address,
it will get caught into our Mailtrap inbox so that
we can actually take a look at it
in our development process.
So that transporter will be exactly the same as this one,
so let's just copy it but first let's say
if(process.env.NODE_ENV).
So, remember, that's how we checked
whether we're in production or not.
And so if that is in production,
and so if we're in production,
then we want to create a transporter for SendGrid.
So let's just put that here,
and again we will do that later.
For now let's just return something from here.
Doesn't matter, lets say one.
All right?
And then basically otherwise
we want to return this nodemailer.createTransport.
Okay?
So this Transport here
will basically return a new nodemailer transport like this.
Or, on the other hand when we're in production,
then the one that's going to be here.
Okay?
So let's actually delete it from here.
Also, we want to delete this one.
And now let's create the send method.
And so this is gonna be the method
that will do the actual sending.
Okay?
And this one will receive a template and a subject.
And you will understand a bit better
why that is once this entire class is complete.
Okay?
So template and subject.
So let's put a comment here of what this will do.
And now before we actually write out this function,
let me show you how we're gonna use it,
and so why we need the template and the subject here.
So, remember how we said up here
that we're gonna have one method called sendWelcome,
and also like a method for sending a reset password email.
And so, let's now actually add that here, so sendWelcome.
And this one doesn't receive any argument
and all it really does is to call send
with the template and the subject
that we want for this email.
Okay?
And so again, this makes it really easy
to then create different emails
for all kinds of different situations.
Okay?
So we have this one route send function here
and then all of these more specific ones,
which will then in turn call the router send function
which is doing the actual work.
Okay?
And actually here it is this.send
because of course these methods here,
they are going to be defined on the current object.
And so that's this.
Then here we paste in the template name.
And so this template name that I put here,
will in the future be a pug template
that we're gonna create.
So, actually in the next lecture,
we're gonna be creating this pug template
in order to send this welcome email.
Okay?
And then just the subject line.
Let's say 'Welcome to the Natours Family!'
And so, just like this, we do not need to worry
about any of the implementation details
when we're actually sending the email.
So for example in the point of our code
where we want to send the welcome email
we do not have to worry about template names
or about the subject lines.
All we're gonna do is to say send welcome email
and that's it.
And then our class will take care
of dealing with the implementation.
All right?
Anyway, let's now actually then build this send function.
And so, what we're gonna do in this function,
is to first render the HTML for the email
based on a pug template.
So basically the one that we're pasting
into here with template.
Then, define the email options,
and so that's once more gonna be very similar to this one,
and in fact let me go ahead
and cut it from here and paste it here.
Okay?
Of course it's not going to be exactly the same,
but we will leave that for a bit later.
All right?
And then finally,
Create a transport and send email.
Okay?
And so that's, I'll leave that one for later as well.
So, starting with point number one.
And usually up until this point, we only ever use pug
to create a template,
and then we pass the name of the template
into the render function on the response.
Right.
So we always just used it like this
res.render,
and then here the name of the template.
Right?
And what this render function does behind the scenes
is to basically create the HTML based on the pug template
and then send it to the client.
Now in this case we do not really want to render,
all we want to do is to basically create the HTML
out of the template so that we can then send that HTML
as the email.
So basically defining it here as an HTML option
into these mail options.
Okay?
So, remember how we can specify text and HTML.
And mainly we are interested in sending an HTML email.
And so that's why we're gonna have a pug template
from which we will generate this HTML.
Okay?
So it's not gonna be working like this,
but instead we actually need to require
the pug package here.
So,
pug like this,
and then we need to use
pug.renderFile.
Okay?
And so this will take in the file
and then render the pug code into real HTML.
Okay?
And so that we can then save into a variable HTML.
All right?
So, where is that file?
Well, it is at dirname,
so D-I-R name,
which remember is the location
of the currently running script,
and so that is, right now, at this utilities folder.
Okay?
And so from there we need to move one step up,
then go into views, and from there go into an emails folder
that we're gonna also create in a second.
And then in there
is where we're gonna have the template file.
So
template}.pug.
So for the welcome email, this template
is gonna be called welcome.
And so let's now actually create that here in the views,
create a new folder,
email, and then in there new file,
welcome.pug.
Okay?
And we're not going to really be creating
this template in this video but I just wanted to show you
how all of this is gonna work.
Okay?
So this welcome will be paste here into template
and then it will grab that file from the views folder.
Right?
So, that is the first step.
Next up, let's define the email options.
So, from is now this.from.
Remember?
So right here.
Next up, we have
this.to, and we also have the subject
which is equal to the subject that's coming in right here,
and so, yah, actually we don't even need to define this one
and we have our HTML.
So like this, or of course,
that is not even necessary because it's the same name.
Now, next up, we also want to include a text version of
our email into the email.
Okay?
And that's actually really important because it's better
for email delivery rates and also for spam folders.
All right?
And also some people just prefer plain simple text emails
instead of having the more formatted HTML emails.
All right?
And so basically, we need a way of converting
all the HTML to simple text.
So stripping out all of the HTML leaving only the content.
And for doing that, we are going to install
yet another package,
and so this one is called html-to-text.
All right?
Let's include that here,
ToText.
require('html-to-text'), like this.
Okay?
Now let's use that to convert our HTML.
So we use htmlToText.fromString
and then that string is stored in HTML.
Right?
So, these are our mail options,
And actually I forgot something very, very important,
here in this first step, so in this render file,
because just like with response.render,
we can also paste data into render file.
And of course, that is very important
if we want to actually do or email personalization
with the name and also paste in the URL.
And so let's do it just like we did normally
in the render function.
So that's firstName, send it to this.firstName,
and the URL is this.url,
and also let's paste in the subject
and you will see a bit later why we need that.
Okay?
So, now let's finally create a transport
using our create transport function,
and then send the email.
So, fair enough, that's this.createTransport.
So, remember that this is just this method here, this one,
and it has the exact same name
as this function here coming from nodemailer.
So that's a bit confusing,
so let's call it newTransport here.
Okay, and so here that's also newTransport,
so that it's a bit less confusing.
All right?
Now let's remember how we did it here before.
So we had our transporter,
which we created separately in this case,
and then onto that we chained sendMail with the options.
So let's just grab that here, delete all the remaining code.
So basically put that here as a reference.
Okay?
So this transporter is now this.
All right?
And so then on to that, we chain send email
and then with the mail options that we defined up here.
Then, we need to await all of this,
because, of course, it's an asynchronous function.
And so let's now mark this one here as async.
Okay?
And so now, we also need to await the function here.
All right?
Because this.send is now indeed an async function.
And so here we await that so that this function only returns
as soon as the email has actually been sent.
And so, of course, mark this one as async as well.
Awesome.
That's actually it for this class.
So we no longer need this example.
Okay?
And so in the next video, we will then actually go ahead
and use this new class in order to send a welcome email.
So, just very quickly recap what we did here.
So we created a new email class
from which we can create email objects
that we can then use to send actual emails.
And to create a new email object, we will paste in the user
and also a URL that we want to be in that email.
So then here we assign all that stuff to the current object,
and also some other settings that we want to have available,
such as the first name and the sender email.
So basically to abstract this information
away from the send function,
and to have it all in one central place.
Then we have here a new transport function
which makes it really easy to create different transports
for different environments.
And so once more, abstracting that logic
away from the actual send function
which should only be concerned about sending the email.
Okay?
So then here is that send function which takes in a template
and a subject, and based on that it creates the HTML
from a pug template which will then be set
into the email options, which will,
at the end of the function, then finally be sent
in this line of code.
Okay?
But it's not going to be this send function
that we will use in our code.
So instead, we're going to be creating
one different function for each type of email
that we want to send.
And the first one that I created here is the sendWelcome.
All right?
And so for sendWelcome, we basically then preset
the template name as welcome,
and the subject as this string.
Okay?
So, I hope that made sense, and I see you in a second.