Let's now, really quickly, create the model
for our bookings so that then, in the next video,
we can actually start creating some real bookings.
So, let's close up some of these
files here, also these folders.
Here is the models folder and so booking model.js.
And so this is, of course, gonna be very similar
to what we already did before,
so I will do this pretty quickly.
So as always, we need mongoose,
and we create our booking schema mongoose.Schema,
and now, remember how we said before
that we were going to use paragraph referencing
here on the bookings, so basically keeping a reference
to the tour and also to the user who booked the tour.
So that is very easy.
We did this many times before.
So mongoose.Schema.ObjectId, right?
And then the reference, and this one
is going to point to the tour model.
Then let's also say these are required,
Booking must belong to a Tour.
Now let's just grab this
and create the same thing for a user, okay?
So that's what we just said we were gonna do
keeping a reference of both the tour
that's being purchased and the user who does the purchase.
Then we also want to know the price
at which the purchase actually happened,
and so that's because the price might change
in the future, and so then we would no longer know
how much a certain user paid for a tour.
And so it's important to also have this here
in the booking, so this is going to be a number,
and we also require this,
Booking must have a price.
Next up, let's also create our time stamp createdAt,
which is a date,
and then simply add default
so that we don't have to do anything.
Finally, I also want to create a paid property,
and this one will be automatically set to true,
but this is just in case that, for example,
an administrator wants to create a booking
outside of Stripe.
So, for example, if a customer doesn't have a credit card
and wants to pay directly, like in a store with cash,
or something like that.
And in this case, an administrator might then use
our bookings API in order to basically
manually create a tour, and so that might then be paid
or not yet paid.
So just a very small detail here,
by the thought of that, and thought that it might be
interesting to include that here as well.
But of course, by default, it will be true
so that we don't have to do anything.
Now finally, let's then create a model out of this,
so booking is equal to mongoose.model,
and then, of course, our bookingSchema
and then exporting the whole thing,
is equal to Booking.
Now what we also want to do here
is to populate the tour and the user automatically
whenever there is a query, all right?
So remember how we used to do that
using query middleware.
So, right on the Schema.pre,
and then here or as usual regular expression
and whatever starts with find.
So here next,
and then this.populate,
and let's do it actually automatically
for both the user and the tours.
And in this case that's absolutely no problem
for performance, because there won't be
many calls to the bookings, because only guides and admins
will actually be allowed to do them, all right?
So basically, for a guide to check
was actually booked their tours.
So that's one of the use cases that I see
for this part of the API, okay?
So, again, this query will not happen that often
so we can easily populate all of this
without any problem.
So let's populate also the tour,
but here I actually want to only select the tour name.
So let's say path, tour, and select just the name, okay?
Now here we have some kind of error, all right,
so that should of course be mongoose not moongoose.
So, one more time, ESLint saved us here.
Oh, and actually there are more.
Save it one more time, and now we're good.
So that's actually it.
This is our bookings model
that we can now start using in the next video.