In this video,
we're gonna implement the my bookings page.
So, basically we're gonna render a nice page
containing all the tours that a user has booked.
And let's start by adding a new route to our viewRoutes.
Okay, so we have me and so let's after that
then create the my-tours.
So I'm duplicating this one, my-tours,
then also this route needs to be protected
so that only currently logged-in users
can access this page, of course.
And then, in our viewsController,
we're gonna have a controller called getMyTours.
MyTours like this, okay?
And that's actually it for now,
so let's go ahead and create this controller now.
Okay, so we have all these gets here,
get tour, get log-in form, get account.
So let's put this one here as well.
And so now, what we need to do here
is to find all the tours that the user has booked.
So, basically, first we need to find all the bookings
for the currently logged-in users
which will then give us a bunch of tour IDs,
and then we have to find the tours with those IDs.
So, basically, find all bookings and then
find tours with the returned IDs.
So basically the IDs of the bookings for the user, right?
Now, instead, we could also
do a virtual populate on the tours,
and it would be great if you would implement
this on your own exactly as we have done it before
with the tours and the reviews,
but here in this function I actually wanted to show you
how we can do it manually
because I think that's also kind of important
and actually a virtual populate
should work something similar to what we're gonna do here.
And so you see that actually we need two queries
in order to really find the tours
corresponding to the user's bookings.
Any way, let's now start,
so let's create a variable for all the bookings, await
and now I think we don't have the bookings here yet, nope.
So Bookings here, and bookingModel.
And here, of course, it's just booking, all right.
So await Booking.find, and now remember
that each booking document has a user ID, right?
So here in the Schema remember
we have the tour ID, the user ID,
and then all this other data,
and so what we're gonna do now
is to basically query by the user ID, okay?
And so that will then return us
all the tours that belong to the current user, okay?
So, not this one.
So tour should be equal to req.user.id.
Then here async, and as always, catchAsync as well.
So these bookings now contain all
the booking documents for the current user,
but really that only gives us the tour IDs.
And so now we want to find the tours with the returned IDs.
And so the next step is to basically
create an array of all the IDs,
and then after that query for tours
that have one of these IDs, all right?
And this will make a bit more sense
once we actually implement what I just explained.
So tourIDs is equal to bookings
and now we're gonna use a map
to create a new array based on a callback function
which is this one,
so the current el.tour.id.
So, what is this going to do?
Well, basically this loops through the entire bookings array
and on each element it will grab the el.tour.
And actually, we don't even need the ID here
because the tour itself is already the tour ID, right?
Then in the end, we have a nice array
with all the tour IDs in there here
and that's because we used a map.
Okay, then having all the tour IDs,
we can actually get the tours corresponding to those IDs.
So await Tour.find and we actually want to find by ID,
but we cannot use the .findbyid
because here we actually will need a new operator.
And said operator,
which I'm not sure if we have used before,
is called in.
So, in tourIDs.
So basically what this is going to do
instead it will select all the tours
which have an ID which is in the tourIDs array, okay?
So that's quite straightforward,
but it's very great to know
that we can use this very handy in operator here, okay?
And so that's actually one of the reasons
why I wanted to do this manually
instead of just doing a virtual populate like we did before.
But again, it would be nice if you would go ahead
and actually implement that also
just for the fun of it, you know.
Okay, and with this we actually
have our tours ready to be rendered.
So, res.status as always,
and then render them, all right?
And actually, we don't even need a new template for this.
We're simply gonna be reusing the overview, okay?
So we're gonna end up with a page
that looks very similar to the overview,
but only with the tours that the user has booked.
So, up here and to get overview,
we then actually passed in all the tours, okay?
So basically all of them.
And so now, we're gonna have something very similar
but of course only passing in the booked tours.
So, where's that?
All right, so the title's gonna be My Tours,
and again passing in the tours variable.
Okay and that should be it.
Now of course we could also have created
a whole new card for these bookstores
with some more relevant information
about each of the bookings,
but in this case that's not really important.
Now, right?
So, we're actually ready to test this
because we already implemented the route here before.
And so that's my-tours.
Oh, but actually let's set this link here
right on the user account page.
So this my-tours should of course have
it's own link right here in the account.
So in that left column,
so that's right here in My bookings,
so we have this first one here
which is for the link, remember.
And so right now, basically all of them point no where,
but now for the bookings we actually have a link.
And so that is my-tours.
And we could have called it bookings as well,
but that's not really important anyway.
So, now we're ready to test this.
Let's actually log out of this user,
and then log in as our other user, Laura.
All right, and so let's see what we get here
and that's taking way too long,
so let's take a look at our code, edit our terminal here.
Okay, so there's no error here,
but also it looks like nothing is really happening here.
So the my-tours route here doesn't even show up, all right.
Now in order to find this bug,
I actually had to do some debugging outside of this video
because it was really a hard one to find, okay.
First, there's a small error here.
So this here should actually be user and not be tour.
So I explained it correctly back then,
where I said that we need to filter by the user,
so tours where the user is equal
to the user coming from the request,
but then for some reason I did it wrong here, okay?
But that's not the main bug actually.
So not the one preventing the page from actually loading.
The error that causes that to happen
is right here actually in the booking model.
And it's down here in this pre find middleware.
And the problem is that we do never
call the next middleware here, now right?
So again, this is a pre-middleware.
And all of the pre-middlewares have access
to the next function and so,
at the end of these middlewares,
we always have to call next.
Otherwise, our process really gets stuck, all right?
So give that a save, can actually close this one.
And so now let's try that again
and now indeed we have my tours,
but it is empty since this user never really did a booking.
So, let's try that out now,
and let's book the forest hiker.
So that should still be working,
and indeed it does, very nice.
We have the email address pre-formatted
and now, as always 4242.
So we did the booking before actually with this user,
but before we implemented the booking model
and so therefore we never really
created a booking in our system.
All right, so payment accepted
and now let's see and here we go, great!
So that logic that we just implemented actually worked
and so really the only problem was
that next missing in the middleware.
And just like that, we completed yet another page
of our dynamic website.
And so next up, all there's really left to do at this point
is to finish the bookings API.