So, in this section, we're gonna start
talking about naming conventions.
And lead on to packages and
statics and so on.
But I'm gonna start with
naming conventions.
And there's actually good
reason why you wanna do this.
And two of the biggest reasons for
adopting these accepted conventions,
which we're gonna be going through in
this video, for naming your variables,
methods and objects in Java, is that it
makes your code easier for others to read.
Now, others here actually include yourself
when you come to look at your code weeks,
or perhaps months, or maybe even years
after you've originally written it.
Cuz trust me when I say that you will
forget why you've done something.
So if you can make your life easier and
the life of other programmers,
by following these accepted conventions,
it's just going to make things
a lot easier for all concerned.
So let's start off talking about packages.
So the things you actually get to
name in Java are packages, classes,
interface, methods, constants,
variables as well as type parameters.
And pretty well all of those you've
actually seen in the course so far.
Let's actually start talking
about packages first.
And the format of the package
is to always be in lower case.
Now, the package name should be unique,
and you need to use your Internet domain
name, reversed, as a prefix for
the package name.
And you've seen me using that in
the course with com.timbuchalka.
And Oracle actually specified
conventions for package names and
there's a link to that, quite a long which
you can actually find out more about that.
But I'm gonna give you
a bit of an overview what
they are anyway on the next slide.
Now some of the invalid
domain name components.
Firstly, if your domain name has got
a dash in it, which is fairly common for
domain names, you need to change that,
when using a package, to an underscore.
Now the domain name components,
starting with a number,
should instead start with an underscore.
And also, importantly, domain name
components that are Java keywords should
have that component starting
with an underscore as well.
So here's some examples of converting
invalid domain name components to
valid ones.
In the first case, switch.supplier.com,
if that was your package name, you should
actually make that com.supplier._switch,
because, of course,
switch is a Java keyword.
Second example,
1world.com with a numeric one.
You should actually change
that to com._1world.
And the third one, experts-exchange.com
would be com.experts_exchange.
I have some example of some package names.
java.lang, java.io,
org.xml.sax.helpers, com.timbuchalka,
which you've seen throughout this course,
.autoboxing.
Okay, let's move on to class names now.
Now class names should use camel case,
the class name should also be nouns,
because the represent things.
They should start with a capital letter.
And each word in the name should
also start with a capital.
For example LinkedList, as you can see
there, the capital for the word linked and
a capital also for the word list.
There are some example class names.
ArrayList, LinkedList, String, TopSong,
GearBox, and main, as you can see there.
And, again, we're capitalizing
each word for the class name.
Okay, interface names, very similar rules.
Capitalize like class names,
like CamelCase.
Consider what objects implementing
the interface will become or
what they will be able to do when you're
actually coming up with the name.
Some examples for that would be lists,
comparable, serializable.
Method names, let's talk about that now.
Method names should be mixed case.
They're often verbs, because I reflect the
function performed or the result returned.
Examples would be size, getName,
or addPlayer as you can see on the screen,
there.
Let's talk about constants.
A constant, so we haven't used
those much in the course, but
they're actually to do to define something
which is actually a constant value,
in other words a value that's never
going to change in your program.
And you can see there's a couple examples
there of MAX_INT, SEVERITY_ERROR and PI.
And some of those are actually used
within the Java framework itself.
So constants should be all upper case.
You need to separate words with
an underscore as you can see below,
and they should also be declared
using the final keyword
which actually tells Java that
you won't be changing the value.
And you'll be learning more about
what final and static and so
forth is in this section
of the course as well.
Okay, variable names,
also field names as well.
And just to remind you,
a variable name, I'm using
pretty much what covers any variable
that you're defining in your class.
But also this applies to fields,
which, of course,
are basically variables assigned at
the class level that we actually signed
using our scope and so
forth at the top of the class.
So, in both cases,
you should follow these rules
generally speaking to be a mixed case.
The actual name should be meaningful and
indicative.
Start with a lower case letter and
like classes,
which are our interfaces
which are upper case.
Don't use underscores for
their variable names.
And you could see some examples there.
i, league, SydneySwans.
And in case you're playing along at home,
SydneySwans is actually incorrect.
Because that's actually
showing a capital S.
So, that should actually
be lower case S for Sydney.
But then after that,
the second word is in uppercase.
I can just confirmation there that
you start off in lowercase, but
then the second and subsequent words,
as you can see that in the case with
boxLength at the end,
should actually be in uppercase.
So that's camel case essentially.
Okay, moving on.
Type parameters.
Type parameters generally are a single
character and capital letters as well.
And you saw that in the generic section
of this course where we actually use
type parameters and
we used just a single letter.
And there's a link there you can go
to to find out more about it for
the guidelines given by Oracle,
who, of course, look after Java.
And they got extended information
if you want to go in there and
find out more about that.
And just as an example
of some type parameters,
you saw this in the generic section.
E as in element, which is used extensively
by the Java collections framework
actually, which you'll be
seeing when we get to that.
K for key, N for a number, T for
type, V for value, and S, U, V, etc,
second, third and fourth types.
So that just gives you a bit of a standard
way to actually come up with type
parameters when you need
to use those in your code.
So that's actually it.
I know it's a quick overview, but I just
thought it was important to give you a bit
of an overview of some of the standard
naming conventions used by Oracle.
And there were links in the slides,
as I mentioned,
where you can actually
find out more about that.
And it's just important to try, again as
I mentioned at the start of this video,
to follow these conventions,
because they can ultimately help you and
other developers in the future who may
have to look at your code at some point
down the track when you've actually
forgotten, how you did a particular thing.
But just by looking at these
standard conventions and
making sure your code implements them,
you can save yourself a lot of time.
All right, thanks for watching, and
I'll see you in the next video.