- [Instructor] In the
video, we're gonna start
learning about Java networking.
Now, firstly we're gonna start
off with some terminology
just to make sure that
you're on the same page.
Now, a network is a system of computers
connected together so that
they can share resources
and communicate with each other.
Now, networking refers to
how the connected computers
communicate.
Now, when using Java, the java.net package
contains the classes you'll
generally want to use
to establish connexions between computers,
and then send messages
between those computers.
Now, when writing networking code,
you need to be familiar with threads
and input/output streams,
and I've covered those
in other sections of this course already.
So if you haven't watched those sections,
I suggest you do that before moving on
with networking in this section.
Now, these days networking
is usually discussed
in the context of the Internet,
but computers may also communicate
across a private network,
also known as an intranet.
In fact, that's where
networking actually began,
and intranets are still
common today in business.
For example, office computers
don't usually have a printer
at their desks, they share a printer.
When the print a file or document,
the document is sent to the printer
over the business's intranet.
Now sometimes a single business
will have multiple intranets
one for each department.
Most software teams use version control,
meaning that developers
have to check files
into a central repository,
and other developers can
then check out the files and work on them.
Now, some teams use version
control applications
available in the cloud, such as GitHub.
But others use version
control that's in-house,
running on the business's intranet.
And as you'll see, you
can also use networking
when you want applications
running on the same machine
to communicate with each other.
So networking can be
involved even when only one
machine is involved.
But, let's stop saying machine.
When discussing networking,
a machine is usually
referred to as a host.
Now a common networking configuration
that you've probably
heard of is client/server,
meaning that one or more
hosts on the network
are acting as servers, and
the other hosts are clients
that connect to the server.
Now, at a high level, that's
how the Internet operates.
The browser is the client,
and when you type in
a web address, it connects to the server
that has the files for the
website at that address.
Now, of course, that's overly simplified,
but essentially, that's
how the internet works.
Now, as I mentioned, you
can have a client/server
interaction on the same host.
For example, the MySQL
database comes with software
called workbench that you can use
to perform database operations.
So the workbench is the client,
and it connects to the
MySQL database server
on that local host.
And of course, it could
also connect remotely
to another server if needed as well.
Now, another example is
local web development.
It's possible to run an
apache IIS web server
on your computer, and connect to it
using a browser on that same computer.
And in fact, that's often
what web developers do
when they're working on
a website for a client.
So, computers on a network,
which includes the Internet,
communicate with each other
using a transport protocol.
Now, we'll use the TCP and UDP protocols
moving forward in this section.
Now generally a computer will
have one physical connexion
to a network, and anything
sent to the computer
from other hosts on the network
will arrive through that connexion.
But, sometimes the same
computer will be running
multiple application that
want data from the network.
For example, at any one time
you might have a browser open,
a chat application open, and
you might be streaming music
and so on and so forth.
So when data arrives at
the one physical connexion
to the network, how does it get routed
to the target application?
Well that's where ports come in.
Each application that
needs data from the network
is assigned a port, this includes clients
connecting to a server
that's on the same machine.
And when data arrives,
the port number is used
to route the data for
the specific application
that's waiting for it.
So every host connected to the Internet
has a unique IP address, including yours.
Now to find our what your IP address is,
you can run a command from
your operating system's
command line, but it's
also often just as easy
just to do a search for what is my IP.
So if we do that,
(clicking)
and do a search for what is my IP,
now I'm gonna block my public IP address
so you can't see it, but
that's a way to find out
what the IP address is on your computer.
And you can also do a similar search
on Bing and other search engines.
Now the four numbers that will come back
are in the form X.X.X.X, or
you might also see a series
of eight segments separated by colons.
And that's because
there are IPv4 addresses
and IPv6 addresses.
Now, IPv4 stands for
Internet Protocol Version 4,
and IPv6 stands for
Internet Protocol Version 6.
So, once upon a time there
were only IPv4 addresses.
Now, IPv4 uses a 32-bit address scheme
that allows for over 4
billion unique addresses.
But now that we've got computers, tablets,
game consoles, smart TVs, smartphones,
smart appliances, et cetera,
now that we've got those
all connected to the Internet,
and each device has to
have a unique IP address.
As a result, 4 billion IP
addresses wasn't really enough,
and so IPv6 was born.
Now, it actually uses a
128-bit address scheme,
which allows for many,
many more IP addresses
than IPv4 does.
Now, IPv4 addresses are
written as four integers
separated by dots, and
I'm sure you've seen that
probably before.
And IPv6 addresses are
written in hexadecimal
and separated by colons.
Right now we're in a transition period,
so when you ask for IP addresses,
you may see the IPv4 address returned,
or you may actually see the IPv6 address.
And while we're here, IP
stands for Internet Protocol,
you may have heard the term TCPIP.
Now that refers to using the TCP protocol
with IP addresses, and it
doesn't necessarily mean
the host is connected to the Internet.
Two applications running on the same host
can use TCPIP to
communicate with each other.
Now when the client are
server are on the same host,
usually the IP address, 127.0.0.1,
which is also referred to as local host,
is used to identify the host.
Alright, so with that brief
introduction to networking
terms out of the way, let's
actually start our tour
of the java.net package.
So the package contains two sets of APIs.
Firstly, the low level API,
and then the high level API.
Now when using the low level API,
you have to be more aware
of networking concepts.
Still, when using Java
to do network coding,
you're always working with abstractions
regardless of whether
you're using the high
or low level API.
Java actually makes
network coding much easier
than it could have been,
by letting developers write
code using abstract
concepts, and taking care
of the implementation
details under the hood.
Now because it's so common,
we're go to use client/server
examples in these networking
videos in this section.
But you often want a reliable
two-way communication link
between the client and the server.
Now this is where the
TCP protocol comes in.
Now TCP, which stands for
Transmission Control Protocol,
establishes a two-way
connexion between hosts,
and this connexion is reliable
in the sense that the two
hosts talk to each other.
When used with internet addresses,
you get TCPIP, which uses
the client/server model.
So, when communicating using TCPIP,
the sequence of events are as follows,
firstly, the client opens
a connexion to the server,
secondly, the client sends
a request to the server,
third, the server sends a
response back to the client,
and step four, the client
closes the connexion
to the server.
Now, steps two and three may be repeated
multiple times before
the connection's closed.
Now, when using the low
level networking API,
you'll use sockets to establish connexion,
send requests, and receive responses.
Now a socket is one end point
of the two-way connexion.
The client will have a socket,
and the server will have a socket.
Now when you have multiple
clients connecting
to the same server,
they'll use the same port,
but each client will have its own socket.
Now, you'll use the socket
class for the client socket,
and the server socket class
for the server socket.
Now what's wonderful about Java
is that all you have to do
is provide the IP address
and port when you create the socket.
You don't have to
understand how TCPIP works.
So underneath the
covers, specific messages
have to be sent to establish a connexion
between the client and a server,
and this is a process
that's called handshaking.
And the data has to be sent as packets,
which must be in a specific format.
But you don't have to take a
course in computer networking
when you write network code using Java,
and that's because it takes
care of all these details
under the covers.
Now since we're talking about networking,
we're gonna have to write two applications
to demonstrate how to
do networking coding.
So once application will be the server,
and the other will be the client.
So in the next video, we're gonna start
by writing a server application
that just echoes back to the client,
whatever text the client sends to it.
So I'll see you in the next video.