alright let's discuss regular
expressions so regular expressions are a
way to describe a string or a pattern
and you probably already used regular
expressions without actually knowing it
some methods in the string class accept
a regular expression as a parameter for
example the matches method replace all
method and split methods all actually work
with regular expressions so regular
expressions are often used to search
strings for a specific pattern or to
validate that user input matches a
specific pattern for example we may want
to verify that the users provided an
email address by checking the input
against a regular expression that
describes how an email address string
should look the best way to learn about
to regular expressions is by example
so I've created a new project called
regular expression so start a new
project in IntelliJ we're going to start
typing some code into the main method
going to start by typing string....
....
...no surprises as to what
that's going to watch shows you see the
string I am a string
yes I am printed to console so the
simplest form of a regular expression is
a string literal so for example hello in
double quotes is a regular expression so
lets actually use the replace all
method to replace all occurrences of the
word I with the word you so the
replace all method accepts a regular
expression that describes that pattern
we want to replace as the first
parameter the second parameter is the
actual replacement string so in terms
of how to use this will do something
like string....
....
let's actually print out the results and
fix the typo...
let's just confirm that works we can see
the text showing you am a string
yes you am obviously that's bad english but
you get the point of what's happening
here we are getting strings replaced the
regular expression I'd match the source
string in 2 places and each match or
occurrence was replaced with the string
you now all we could do was match
string literals in this way regular
expressions wouldn't really be very
interesting but we can actually do much
more by using what's called character
classes and boundary matches so a
character classes like a wild card
it represents a set or class of
characters and a boundary matcher looks
for boundaries such as the beginning and
end of a string or a word
let's start by declaring a new string
in main and we will call
it alphanumeric gonna set that to.....
....
....so looking at
character class matches any character so
let's start try it out by using replace all
method so we're going to do....
....
...lets run that you
can probably guess what that that will do if
we know that a . matches any
character you can see that the entire
string which we said on line 11 is
replaced with all ys
so it's basically a wild card for any
character now the carrot boundary
matcher that's located doing a shift 6
that is always followed by pattern which
could be a string literal or something
more complex when we use this carrot
boundary matcher the regular expression
must match the beginning of the string
so let's try it out with the replace all
method again let's just say we want to
replace that first part of the string
that ABCdeee with something else lets have a
go at doing that so we're going to
print out again....
....
note that the length of the regular
expression doesn't have to match the
length of the replacement so we actually
run this you can see that we've got a
match
we got ABCDeee was found at the start of
the string and just the first three
letters were replaced because we told it
to replace what it found with just
those first three characters the three
ys that we put in the rest
replacement string so basically the
regular expression match those
characters that occurred at the
beginning of the string and again
because we specify the carrot
boundary matcher that's is why its only looking
for the start of the string and replaced
it now just to show that this is only
going to show it only
replace it at the start of the string
let's add another occurrence of ABCDeee
later in the string now since it doesn't
occur at the beginning it shouldn't match
the regular expression so the second
occurrence shouldn't be replaced
let's just create a new string to do
this to keep it easy to make it easy i'm
just going to take a copy of the
alphanumeric one will call this one
second string will put it somewhere here
....so we got two versions of
that showing now and if we just print out
....
.....if we run the second
occurrence you can see in this case the
ABCDeee second occurrence hasn't been
replaced again because we specify the
boundary matcher the carrot which
indicates to only match at the start of
the string so it's probably good time to
point out what I think is a really nifty
feature of IntelliJ so when we place the
cursor inside a regular expression like
here notice we've got a pop up on the
left-hand side there in the gutter
or near the gutter so we actually click
on that we can click on check reg x
which is of course abbreviation for
check regular expression so I click on
that get this little pop-up then we can
type different strings into the field
intelliJ will actually tell us
whether the string matches the regular
expression now the default entry would
normally pop up to be a sample text but
because I've actually used this before i
got a different sample we can actually
change that so we can we made that like
sample text....
notice how its red and it's actually
showing that there's no match is
basically saying the regular expression
we've typed in here and what the result
of that is against this in this case
it's there's no match so it's actually
in red if i go back and type in abcdeee
again we get a match as you
can see and it actually converted to
green
so this is a really handy way to test a
regular expression without actually
having to run your application all the
time but however it requires that the
string as a whole must match the
expression so it doesn't actually match
parts of a string for example if we put
our second string value into the sample
text field will tell us that doesn't
match the carrot ABCDeeee but the replace
all method actually disagrees but still
depending on the regular expression it's
a quick way to check whether the
expression will match what we expected
to match gonna close that down by
pressing escape now before we actually
look at other character classes and
boundary matches
let's actually try these or try out
the string . matches method now this
method accepts a regular expression as a
parameter and returns true if the string
matches and false otherwise so let's use
the example alphanumeric string and pass
the regular expression carrot hello
since the alphanumeric string
doesn't start with hello will expect
this to be expected to return false so
we do s out will be alpha numeric....
.....
....
clearly hello is not in there we look at
our alphanumeric string on line 11
so that should return false for us
no surprises there it does actually
return false but now let's pass the
ABCDeee as a regular expressions so
copy that line again this time going to
change it to make it the carrot
boundary matcher.....
so the string begins with ABCDeee and we've
already used the regular expression to
successfully replace the characters with
3 y's so you would expect here the
matches method to return true so lets
actually run this but as you can see
when i ran that we're not getting the
results that perhaps you expect the
value of false is printed here
the question now is what's going on well
it turns out that when using the string
matches method the string as a whole
has to match the regular expression in
order for true to be returned
that's not good enough for only part of
the string to match this is the same
behavior that i mentioned with the
IntelliJ quick check
in fact I wouldn't be surprised if
IntelliJ internally is calling this
matches method under the covers
so when using matches with the begins
with boundary matcher the carrier in other
words the entire string has to match the
regular expression and to see what I mean
the following will actually return true
so if we come back here and do a print
out....and we actually
get the contents of alphanumeric copying
that and pasting that we should find
that will actually return true then we
could put a boundary match their our
carrot match at the start of the string and
run that we also get a true in that
scenario because now the entire string
has matched so either way that will
return true a little bit surprising but
just something to keep in mind i just
wanted to show you that because the
documentation for the matches method
doesn't really make it clear that the
whole string must match for true to be
returned and this actually makes sense
though needing the full string to match
in the context of verifying user input
when we want the entire string or input
to match a given pattern just something
to keep in mind anyway
alright let's move on to more character
classes and boundary matches so the dollar
boundary matcher dollar sign is always
preceded by a pattern and it will
actually match strings that end with the
pattern in other words it's the opposite of
the carrot boundary matcher so let's see
an example of that working....
....
...
....so
basically ijkl99z in my case is
what I've type in there for
alphanumeric we're going to replace that
because we've used the boundary matcher
we are telling it to only replace it if
that's at the end so if we run that you
can see we've got the end replacing the
characters and I actually put in there
in our pattern in case you're wondering I
use replace all rather than matches
because of the matches requirement that
the entire string matches the expression
rather than just part of it
now when we want to match a specific
letter or set of letters we can actually
put those letters within square brackets
so lets actually find and replace all
occurrences of a e and I with X in our
alphanumeric string so to do that we
can do....
....
...so that should replace all
occurrences of a e and I in our alphanumeric
string with the letter X let's run that
and you can see that a e and i have been
replaced entirely with X's in our string
now the length of the replacement string
doesn't have to be one so let's use the
replacement string replace the letter here
just to see what I mean so going
to copy that line again instead of just
replacing with x going to put....
.....
that each letter has been replaced by
the actual phrase are replaced the letter
here instead of the replacing it
with a single letter as we did on the
preceding line just to be clear and you
can probably see that in the example
this regular expression isn't looking
for the pattern a e i instead each
individual characters are examined and if its
an a e or an I then it matches this
expression in the replacement actually
happens let's say we want to do the same
again but we only want to replace the
letters A E and I if they followed by an
F
or a j so we can do something that
something like this to achieve that....
....
...
so what we're going to do is so we're
going to perform a replacement if one of
the three letters A E or I is actually
followed by an F or a J you can see we got
an e their that is followed by an f and we've
got an I that's followed by a j so
we should have a couple of matches there
that we can run through so let's just
run that and you can see we've only
had a few replacements only the X and
the x was replaced because we've got an f
their following the e so the third
occurrence was actually replaced with an
X so only those occurence of A E and
I that was followed by f or j were replaced
and note that both will replace their so
in the case of the the first occurrence
looking at the f there we have ABCDeee
it's ABCDeee notice that the 3rd e and the
f were both ultimately replace with the
X so it took the basically both characters
and replaced them with an x and likewise for
the fourth i we had an I and a J and that
was replaced with the x as well and
that's because our regular expression
needed two characters to match then
both those characters that were
matched were replaced with the X alright so
I'm going to finish the video here now
in the next video we're going to move on
and we'll be looking at other boundary
matchers and other character classes will
also be looking at quantifiers as well
i'll see you in the next video