so in this section of the course we're
going to take a look at databases and
we're going to start with an overview of
what databases are go ahead
and install sqlite which is a free
and open source database tool and then
we'll go through an overview SQL or
also pronounced as sql which is a
database language used to communicate
with databases now we're going to be
using the command line initially as we
start to using sql and sqlite
but than later videos in this
section we're going to progress and move
over to java and start on how to use
databases from java and writing
programs to manipulate databases but
we really need to have this basic
understanding of databases and sql
before getting to the state of writing
code in Java
if you've got some history with
databases you might be wondering why why
am I using sqlite and not my
sql or some other database
the reason is generally speaking the
skills that you learn with sqlite
apply to any database including my
sql so the sql code that you'll learn
as well as the java code that to you
will create in this section requires a
very little change to work on literally
any database now sqlite is ideal
to get started with it's a very small
download is a very simple package and
its really really highly used in fact
it's almost one of the most highly used
programs in the world believe or not and
I've actually put together videos in
this section showing how to get it
working or Windows Mac and Linux as well
but just to make sure that the course is
really a complete in this section
towards the end of the section we're
also going to get mysql up and
running as an exercise so you can see
just how easy it is to switch to another
database and what changes if any are
needed to get that to happen so anyway
let's get started