Alright, so let's discuss the main
differences between an abstract class in
an interface and when to use either of
them and this should hopefully give you
a better overall understanding of both.
So firstly an abstract class well these
are very similar to interfaces, you
cannot instantiate them and they may
contain a mix of methods declared with
or without an implementation.
However, with abstract classes you can
declare fields that are not static and
final and define public protected and
private concrete methods, your abstract
class can extend only one parent class,
however it can implement multiple
interfaces. Now when an abstract class is
subclassed, the subclass usually provides
implementations for all of the abstract
methods in its parent class. However if
it doesn't, then the subclass must also
be declared abstract. So you want to use
an abstract class when firstly you want
to share code among several closely
related classes animal for example with
fields, name, age and so on or if you
expect classes that extend your abstract
class to have many common methods or
fuels or required access modifiers other
than public, so protected in private may
also want to use an abstract class when
you want to declare non static or non
final fields, for example a name and age
so this then enables you to define
methods that can access and modify the
state of an object, you know get names
set name and so forth and also you may
want to use an abstract class when
you've got a requirement for your base
class to provide a default
implementation of certain methods but
other methods should be open to being
overridden by child classes. And so,
general summary the purpose of an
abstract class is to provide a common
definition of a base class that multiple
derived classes can share. Alright,
interfaces, so an interface is just the
declaration of methods of a class,
it's not the implementation.
You know in an interface, we defined what
kind of operation an object can perform.
now these operations are defined by the
classes that implement the interface,
so interfaces form a contract between the
class and the outside world and this
contract is enforced at build time by
the Java compiler. Now you cannot
instantiate interfaces and they may
contain a mix of methods declared with
or without an implementation. Now all
methods and interfaces are automatically
public and abstract. Now an interface can
extend another interface. Interfaces are
more flexible and can deal with a lot
more stress on the design of your
program than the implementation. Now by
introducing interfaces into your program,
you're really introducing points of
variation at which you can plug in
different implementations for that
interface. Now our interfaces primary
purpose is abstraction decoupling the
what from the hell and just a couple of
general notes here, since Java 8
interfaces can now contain default
methods, so in other words methods with
implementation. Now the keyword default
is used mostly for backwards
compatibility and static methods as well
before Java 8, that wasn't possible
and since Java 9 and interface can also
contain private methods commonly used
when to default methods in an interface
share common code. Alright, so when do you
want to use an interface, Well, firstly
when you expect that unrelated classes
will implement your interface,
for example, the interface is comparable and
cloneable are implemented by many
unrelated classes. Now another reason to
use an interface is when you want to
specify the behavior of a particular datatype
but you're not concerned about who
implements its behavior, still another
reason for using an interface if you
want to separate different behavior.
Now the collections API in Java is an
excellent example of interfaces, we've
got the list interface and
implementations arraylist and linkedlist
and more on this later in the course.
Another example is the JDBC API, now that
exists of almost only interfaces,
the concrete implementation of methods are
provided as JDBC drivers, so that enables
you to write all the JDBC code
independent of the database the DB
vendor and you'll learn more about JDBC
in this course.  Alright so that's the
differences between abstract classes and
interfaces. Let's move on now to the next video.