In the previous video we talked about
the for statement which was a way to
come up with a full loop to be able to
process a statement or set of statements
a given number of times and in this
video, we're going to look at the while
and also the do-while statements,
the thing is with looping sometimes you
might want to loop instead of a specific
number of times, you might want to loop
until a certain expression evaluates to
false.
For example, you may not know how
many times you want to loop ahead of
time, so what you need to do in those
scenarios, we don't know how many times
you want to loop but you wonder what
continued looping until that expression
is true until something happens, in other
words is you want to use the while
statement.
So let's go through the syntax
of a while statement, so in this example
I'm going to create a simple variable
called count, set that equal to zero,
I'm going to type while and in brackets
count not equal to five, then I'm going
to type to print out one of these
count value count and I'm going to do a
count plus plus and there we have it.
So if we run this code, so you can see it's
counted one two three four just to be
clear, we can change the count to one if
we one, so we're starting on one and set
of zero, run that again.
So this is
similar to the for statement that we've
used previously to do something
equivalent, it's the for statement
of course, you would have done something
along the lines of for int i equals one
or then less than seven or i plus plus
and then we would have done, so that
would be equivalent statement in the for
loop with the for loop.
So you can see in
the case of the while, there's no
variable that's set up within the while
loop like doing is but in the for loop,
so we need to create our loop if we're
going to do a counting mechanism, before
we start while statement, then we
also need to increment our variable
manually, if that's the way we want to do
it within the loop itself, so that's the
difference between the two
This is future Tim.
Editing this video and creating a new component
due to a bug that I just showed you on the
screen.
Now what I've done is I've changed the color
of this background just to make it really
clear what I'm
doing here to the right hand side you can
see we still got out account value
One two three four five.
That's for our while loop
And what I attempted to tell you was in the
for loop and I've actually duplicated that
for loop
on lines 13 to 15 was identical to the while
loop
And that is not the case.
So let me just show you what this for loop
does
if i uncomment it again.
We run this code bearing in mind that's the
output we can see at the moment
you can see it outputs Not only five times
but six times but it prints the value six
each time.
Now the reason for that is I've introduced
a new variable named here I
but I'm printing out the value count so to
be more correct if we want to do exactly the
same as the while
loop.
In a for loop we would do something like this.
so comment out that wrong loop the wrong code.
and we would do for parentheses.
Count equals one count.
not equal to six count plus plus.
And then we would print out some output.
and we would say count value is + count
So if we run that now
you can see if we correctly now 1 2 3 4 5
showing for the while loop
and we also get 1 2 3 4 5 showing for the
for loop
So that's the identical for loop to what I
showed you in the while loop
All right so let's go back now and continue
the lesson
I'll just delete the
for loop now, I don't need that anymore.
We can also write this in slightly
different fashion as well, it's that of
the above example of the while we could
have written it like while true, if count
equals 5 break and the otherwise we're
going to print the message then
increment the count like so and just to
make sure those worked, you'll set
count back to 1 here because of course
after executing this loop, count will be
set to 6.
So if we run this example and
to be precise, I should change that to 6
the same comparison as the other test,
so I've written it as a slightly different
fashion with the previous example we're
checking to see whether that's not equal to
6,
in this case what we're doing is we're
specifically saying if we get to the
number in other words, we get to the
stage where we want to break out of the
code in this case, where the expression
count equals equals 6
then we issue a break which breaks out
of the loop, but in both scenarios you
need to make sure that you do actually
have the variable incremented because if
you don't, what will happen is something
along these lines, we comment that out
just to show you what will happen if we
don't even read the count, we'll get
into an endless loop and they can see
what's happening on the right hand side,
Intellij is having it carrying having a
bit of a fit, the reason that it's coming
up with that is we're getting to this
loop here while count is not equal to 6
is printing out the count, then we
haven't reset the count we have an
incremented account so it goes back and
does another test to start doing the
test again, so it's continually printing
checking whether the value 6 so we're
not incrementing the count, so make sure
if you're using a while like this,
the while statement you are incrementing count.
So you'll see code like this fairly
often in Java code while true and what
that actually means is it's going to be
an infinite loop, so the loop will
continue going you know processing
forever but the way to get out of the
loop is you do a test some sort of test
to check whether a given expression is
true, in this case we're waiting to count
equals 6 and then we break out on the loop
much like you've seen before when we use
break elsewhere.
So that's an alternative
why to do things.
Now there is another
got you in this scenario, so what can
actually happen
here is that the code may not get
executed at all.
So to show you an
example of that, we'll just call it this
code out for now.
So if we change count
to 6 and then run this, the code never
gets into the while loop at all and
that's because this initial expression
was evaluated to false, so it never
actually got into the code block to
execute any of the code in there.
So that's an important thing to remember
with a while loop and likewise with a
for loop, we did something like this,
we run that, we won't get any output either
and that's because the initial value was
set to 6 and we're doing a comparison
test there to say i is not equal to 6,
so of course the first time it does this
evaluation that's false because i in
fact is equal to 6 so the code doesn't
get executed and since within the code
block itself and likewise for the while
statement as well.
So that can be a
gotcha sometimes, you're wondering why
your code hasn't been executed, make sure
you check the first expression and make
sure going in the for the very first
time that that expression it doesn't
evaluate to false, which means it won't
execute any of the code.
Now there's also
a third type of looping statement called
the do-while and it's got the other
advantage that it will always execute at
least once and if not more times
depending on the way you've defined your
your test expressions, so what we'll do
is we'll do an equivalent thing, we'll
type do which is the keyword we're using
for the do-while statement, then we can
type count value was plus count
and when we count plus plus then our
expression to test to see whether we
should exit the do-while or not is at
the end, we type while after the closing
brace then we put our expression which
would be exactly the same expression
would be something like count not equal
to six and put a semicolon to close it
off, so we change our count here to one
again just to be sure, we'll comment
these other ones out and we run the code
count 1 2 3 4 5 so you can see that it's
operated very very similar to the while
that we've done in there, the only real
difference was we had the word do at the
top then the while
component appeared at the bottom of the
statement there, but the other thing in
order is if we set that to 6 initially
and run up, you'll get a very weird error
as you can see there, so what's happening
is the do-while is guaranteed to execute
at least once, so in this scenario what's
happened is we have the initial print
out, so account would have been the count
value was six then we then incremented
counts, i went to 7 but then the while
expression at the end count not equal to 6,
that is going to be true from now on
and the reason why was can't was equal
to 7 there, so therefore we got into
virtually an infinite loop where it
contingently went through incrementing
the number and running the loop as you
can see there no 190,000 times until I
stopped it.
So that's another thing to
keep in mind with to do while it's
always going to be executed at least
once, so of course if we set that back to
one, that'll work quite nicely and that'll
show 1 to 5, 1 2 3 4 5 as you can see
because we initialized and set it once
and the do-while could also use a break
statement for argument's sake we could
set it up so that we could put if count
greater than 100 break that's going to
break out of the loop again so we could
test that and you should find that well
it'll display up until the hundred the
number 100 and then it will execute
because that'll execute that come on
there did break so we run that you can
see it's executed to the value of 100
but let's look at a better example than
what I've come up with so far so I want
to come at this code out,
I'm actually going to comment the code
out at the top of top as well just
coming to help that variable, so it's
challenge time.
Okay, so the challenge is
to create a method called is even number
and it takes a parameter of type int,
so the purpose of the method is to
determine whether or not the argument
that's been passed to method the int in
other words is an even number or not,
if it is an even number return true
otherwise, return false and give you a
bit of a hint here to you and look at
using the remainder operator.
Alright, go
ahead and try that out and see if you
can figure it out,
pause the video now and come back once
you've tried it out and to check what
I've come up with.
Okay, how did you come?
Let's go ahead and write that method,
so we start off with a public static
boolean, you want to return true or false
is even number and when I tap take a
parameter of int and we'll just call it
number, that's going to be our number
that we're going to use to determine
whether it's true or false, so a simple
way to determine whether a number is
even or odd is just to use the remainder
operator like so so we just do if number
or if the remainder of a number and to
using it the remainder operator don't
need two brackets here actually, so for
that, the answer to that equals zero in
other words there are no remainders what
that means is that is actually a true
that is an even number otherwise, if we
do get a remainder, we know that it's an
odd number, so that's the way they
determine whether our number is even or
not.
Okay so what I'm going to do now is
we're going to create some code that is
going to execute that method.
Okay so
this is Tim speaking from the future
where I've come back and recreated part
of this video and re-recorded it to go
through and make this process this next
step a little bit easy to understand
based on the student feedback,
Alright, so let's continue
so my code here
is going to start with int number
there's a value of four so it's going to
be int number equals four and the number
we're going to finish on in our loop
which we'll call finish number on assign
a value of 22, so int finish number is
equal to 20.
Alright so now we need to
create our while loop and what we're
going to do is type while parentheses
number less than or equal to finish
number, then we want to open a code block
left or right curly braces.
Alright so
now within this code block, we're going
to increment the number so that it
actually starts with five and not four
so with while loop incrementing, that
would usually be the first thing you do
because it's easy to end up with an
endless loop, so in other words a loop
that never ends, so we're going to do
that that's the first statement inside
the code block, so number plus plus
semicolon and now we want to do a test
to make sure that number or test to see
if that number is not even it's in other
words if it's an odd number, so I'm going
to type if parentheses so they're not is
even number parenthesis number 3 gonna
open a code block there and what we're
going to do is add the word continue,
the keyword continue semicolon and we
haven't talked about that keyword yet,
but we'll come back to that then after
that outside of the code block on the
next line we're going to print out some output,
we're going to put even number space and
another double quote plus number and
closing off the parentheses there, well
so what is this code doing?
Well it's
going to start at the number five well
actually number four, but then that
number will be immediately incremented
and that's because we've got this code
on line 31 and so that then gets
incremented as the first statement and
it's going to go through and finish up
up to and including the number 20
because we've got our less than or equal
if test here on line 30 and what we're
doing is we're testing to see whether
the number is an even number
and if it's not an even number and we're
testing for that here on line 32, then
we're going to do our continue which is
something that's different to break,
npw both break and continue have the effect
of interrupting the code, so then in the
case of continuing what happens is that
it'll effectively bypass the print
statement and in case there any more
statements all code would be a bypassed
that's around that error as well so in
other words continue won't do any code
any further down and goes back to the
start of the loop instead, so the loop
gets finished and goes back and starts
on the next number again
but obviously the code is not going to
be executed, so that's what continue does
it allows the loop to continue but it
doesn't actually process any more code
any further down in the while loop it
just goes right straight to the end of
the loop and then back on and start from
the next number if appropriate if that
while condition is actually still valid,
in other words if it's our case if the
value is 20 or less and then when it
starts to loop again the number gets
incremented again, so the first time it
goes through it'll be 5 4 plus 1 is 5
and if it's not an even number it'll go
through and gets incremented, it keeps
coming incremented and in the case
where it is an even number, so if this
clause here isn't executed, so in other
words if the number was 6 for argument's
sake, you'll see that the value we
printed out here on line 36 but then it
too will go back to the start of the
while loop and the number will be
incremented basically until this if
comparison here this test here returns
false, so if when number is not less than
or equal to finish number we know at
that point so if the number is 21 or
higher that the while loop is going to
be exited and the processing will
complete.
Alright so let's actually
test this and see if it works,
we're going to run it, so you can see
what's happened there I'm just going to
put this one window down to the bottom
for now, clicking on this little gear
icon and move to select bottom I can see
to be better and you can ignore this red
arrow here what's actually a warning
that's not affecting the running of the
program and that's been output point
IntelliJ and not from our code which is
output in blue in black as you can see there,
but what you can see there hopefully and
I'll move the code up so you can see it
a bit more clearer, I'll move this up
again is that we've managed to get this
to work, so you can see the output there
is 6 8 10 12 14 16 18 and 20 so that's
what the continue keyword is, so it
basically says stop where you are
continue on to the next sort of test if
you will so the next condition the next
iteration of the while loop and eventually
down there so in this case it was an
even number so if it gets to 6 8 10 12
and you can see in that point it's
actually not exiting it's actually
printing out that code and then going
back to the start of the while loop
again.
So remember here that the do-while
is effectively identical to the while
the only difference with the do while is
that we're testing the value at the
bottom but here of course we're testing
at the top here within the while
condition here.
Now a while loop is
probably the statement you'll use more
often than a do-while loop but they've
all got their place and as you'll see as
you progress through the course where we
start and when we're using these in more
details you'll start getting more of an
understanding of where to use each and
which one and which one to use and which
one's best for a particular purpose.
Alright so hopefully then that makes sense
with what continued us I want to close
down the run window now.
So it's now time
for a challenge, I'm just going to paste
the challenge in here.
Alright, so the
challenge is to modify the while code
above, so you want to leave the existing
functionality as it is but make it so it
also records the total number of even
numbers that it's found and once five
even numbers have been found to break
out of the code and display the total
number outside of the while loop,
so you don't want to break any existing
functionality, we still want the output
working as it did previously we want to
add that extra bit of functionality to
the code.
Alright so pause the video
and go away and give that a try and once
you're ready come back and we can check
out the solution that I've come up with
against yours, so pause the video now.
Okay so how did you get on?
Did you
manage to figure it out?
Well let's go
through my solution bearing in mind
there's always multiple solutions to a
problem, so what I'm going to do here
first is I'm going to take a copy of our
existing code including the int on the
line above right down to the closing the
right curly brace of the body we're
going to copy that and then I'm going to
comment that out then I'm going to paste
the code down here so we're just
starting off with a new version of the
code we've got the old code in there in
case you want to refer to that from the
previous code before the challenge I'm
just going to move it up on the screen a
little bit.
Alright, so what we need to do
first we need to record the total number
of even numbers that have been found
through our loop, so we need some sort of
count variable, so what I'm going to do
is add a variable and add it here after
the the integer number was 20 line I'm
gonna make that int and we'll call it
even numbers found and I can set that
equal to zero it was obviously when we
first start we haven't found in even
numbers.
Okay, so we've declared the
variable so next we need to record every
time that is an even number, so the way
to do that is to add this outside of
this if test for not being for an even
number or an odd number rather because
we're doing a not use even number and we
know that continue bypasses this code
and goes back and restarts or goes to
the next element in the while loop,
so therefore we're pretty safe to put the
code down here to record the number of
even numbers found because that code
only keys executed if we in fact we
found an even number, so I'm gonna type
even numbers found plus plus semicolon.
So now we've got a count our even
numbers found int variable is incremented
by
one every time we find an even number
and we know that this point of the code
is correct because when we ran it last
time it correctly printed out all the
even numbers, so that's working fine but
to confirm in fact that it is working
fine, what we need to do is have some
sort of output and we want to do that
outside of the while loop, so let's do it
out here so I'm going to print out
and top title even numbers found equals
and plus and obviously that was in
double quotes even numbers found.
Alright,
so let's try running this code and see
what happens
you can see that it's
correctly identified that there's a
total of eight even numbers found and
you can see that matches up with the
total here but of course that wasn't
what we wanted to do so why didn't I
exit after five even numbers were found,
well the reason for that was we haven't
implemented that break yet have we?
So what we need to do is I put in an
additional test after the even number is
found, so in other words it'll close down
this so you can make it see it more
clearly, so basically after the even
numbers found plus plus line after this
line here, we want to put a test there on
the next line that if even numbers found
is greater than or equal to five and
then break we'll do that like so so if
even numbers found is greater than or
equal to five they're labeled a code
block after closing the parentheses then
we're going to do a break the break
statement which we've talked about
before and I'll just make it a space
there, so now if we run the code we can
see that we've got the print of four
numbers showing on the screen text down
the bottom there to say total even
numbers equals five and of course the
five numbers are 6 8 10 12 and 14.
However we didn't get the last print out
the number 14 and the reason for that is
if we look at the code up here is we're
actually putting this test in this test
here is being executed before we're
printing out the even number, so what we
should have done to make that clearer is
change the order, so we can just move
this print out here right cut that and
we can actually put that before the even
numbers found plus plus I place it up
here so that are the even numbers
printed and a row of circumstances.
Alright, so now we'll run this to test and
you can see now we've got the five even
numbers 6 8 10 12 14 printing
and the text and the bottom shows
correctly that at that point in time
when we executed the break code that we
had a total even numbers or the total
even numbers that we found or equal to
five.
Alright so that's the while and
the do-while loops.
So hopefully you know
you've got a good understanding of the
various looping statements that exist
within Java and it's time for us to now
to move on to the next video.