alright so let's now look at the flat
map method now we've already seen map
which can transform one object so that
takes a function as an argument which
takes one object and returns a value so
we may want to map a single object more
than one object and we can use a flat
map method to actually achieve that the
method accepts a function that returns
a stream value so we can pass an object
as the function argument and returns a
string containing several objects which
means that were effectively mapping one
object too many in fact that's the
intended use of the flat map method let's
take a look at an example of using that
we're going to add a couple of
classes to our project so i'm going to
create a new class employee and you can
create them either as separate files
or just add them to the main java file i'm going to create a separate files
employee and one this employees
obviously the one that we've used in the
past so I'm just going to copy and paste
the code so you can refer to that
previous definition for employee we had the string name and the age
but whet we are going to do is we're going to
add a two-string method there just to be able
to print the name so we're going
to just override that to string we're
going....
so that's the only change we are making alright
the other thing we're going to do is add
another class we're going to call this
one department
this is a new class so we're going to
create a string first....
....
.....
....so let's start create a few
employees and add them to a couple of
department so....
....
.....
ok so now that we've done that let's
suppose that we want to print all the
employees that work for the company
going to start by creating a list called
departments and all our department
to it so....
....
.....and
of course we could add a get employees
or print employees method to the
department class and then iterate over
this list and print the employees but
because we're working on streams let's
use streams and have a look at how the
flat map method might help us do that
instead we can do that with....
....
.....and
noticing we got the option here department
I can press ENTER for that first
declaration like so and then for the
expression i'm going to put....
.....that's how consice
it can be so lets actually run
this to see that it works and theres our 4
employees so you can see that the flat
map method wants a function that returns
a stream now each department in the
source stream becomes the argument to the
function for each department we call the
get employees method which returns a
list and then we call the stream method
on that list to return a stream of
employees now the items in this stream
were added to the stream that will be
returned from the flat map method in the
case of a HR department we have gone
from one department object to 3 employee
objects method is called flat map
because it's often used to flatten
nested lists now in this case there are
lists of employees nested within the
department list so the flat map method
is the one to use when we want to
perform operations on the list but the
list isn't the source so an object
containing the list as a source in this
scenario and we use the method to create
a stream of all the objects in those
lists now another handy method is the
collect method and this is a terminal
operation so it collects the elements in
a stream into a different type of result
for example we can add all the items in
the stream to list or set after all
unless the purpose of the chain is to
produce a list of items to print we're
going to usually want to save the result
somewhere now you might be using streams
to selectively reduce and sort a large
list because you may want to use the
reduced list in subsequent code so i
would use the collect method to create
the reduced list
so let's say that we wanted to save the
result of our first example where we
uppercase filtered and sorted bingo
numbers instead of printing the list we
could call collect
the collect method and store their
contents of the stream at the end of the
chain into a list and then we'll print
the items in the list so let's actually
rewrite that code to do that.....
....
.....
....and once we've
done that the next line we can put
something like.....
and just before we do that let's
actually put something here....
.....
....alright so let's actually try running
that and there's our g numbers and this
is just telling us by the way that it could
be replaced with the for each which we
discuss previously
alright so we got the same result as
last time but we the difference here is
using the . collect is that we have a
list that we can continue to work with
if we wanted to
now there are two versions of the
collect method one accepts a collector
which is an interface to the java.util.stream package now underneath the
covers this version of the method maps
the collector to the arguments required
by the second version of the method
which accepts or expects rather three
arguments a supplier a by consumer
accumulator and a by consumer combiner
so these arguments that must be
specific about how we want the items to
be added to the result of collect the
collect method for example let's say we
wanted to end up with an arraylist
rather than a list we can use the more
specific collect version of the method to
actually do this let's just take a copy
of this i'm going to just commented out
so we still got the code and I paste that
back in let's actually make a change to
that so the stream the map and the
filter and the assorted are all the same the
. collect is what we can change and we
can do that here by changing this out
I'm going to delete that we're going to
put....
....
....so on that line line 79
first argument to collect is the
supplier if you recall a supplier create
objects now we want an array list so we
passed the arraylist colon colon new as
the supplier which will construct a new
arraylist for us by the way I went
passing method references we use the
name of the class arraylist in this case
colon colon new when we want to pass
the constructor
alright so moving on the accumulator is
the arraylist . add method that's how
we'll add the items to the arraylist and
finally the add all method is the
combiner so the accumulator is used when
the runtime needs to add a single
version or a single item into the list
the accumulator is used when the runtime
needs to add a single item into a result
the combiner is sometimes used to
improve the efficiency of the operation
if and when to do this is really up to
the java runtime now there are many APIs that so we can map to the supplier
accumulator and combiner and this
allows us to do all sorts of things
using collect for example if we have a
lot of employees and their are groups of
employees with the same age we can
create a map of lists based on age using
the collectors . grouping by method
now I won't actually do this but i'll just
show you what the code would look like
it will be something like....
.....
....
alright so the last method that we're
going to look at now is the reduced
method and that combines all the items
in a string into a single result now
they're actually three versions of this
object we're going to take a look at the
simplest one which reduces a stream to
one of the elements in the stream for
example if you wanted to use a stream to
find the youngest employee in the
company would do something like.....
....
.....
so here we're using the version of
reduce that accepts a by function which if
you recall accepts expects two arguments
and returns a result now this function
compares the ages of two employees and
returns the younger employee so the
result of the reduced method will be the
youngest employee in the stream now we
use the if present method on line 93 to
print the result because this form of
reduced method has an optional result
the reduce method is a terminal
operation so the call to if present
isn't part of the stream operation chain
as such here we are just chaining a
non stream method called on to the stream
chain result if we run that you can see
we've got the answers Snow White and
have a look at numbers again we can see
snow white in this case was the youngest
employee alright a few notes about
streams firstly we can't reuse them once
we've called a terminal operation on a
stream will receive the
illegal state exception if we try to
operate on that stream again operations
in streams are lazily evaluated
so what that means is that intermediate
operations are not performed until
there's a terminal operation and look at
an example of that shortly
also we can use more specific stream
interfaces when we're working with lists
of numbers so int stream long stream and
double stream for example now these
interfaces have additional methods like
sum min Max and a few others that are
useful when working with numbers now
there's also parallel streams which we
use when we want to increase performance
by executing streams in parallel now
whether you needed to do that would be
really depending on your application
parallel streams are really outside the
scope of this section I just
really want to point out that we can get
a parallel stream from a collection
by using the parallel stream method
alright so I mentioned operations in
streams are lazy evaluated let's look at
that in a bit more detail and I'm going
to create here a list of....
create a stream of strings and filter them so....
...
....
....if you recall
the filter method accepts a predicate
which takes one argument and returns
true or false
so there's nothing stopping us from
doing other things inside the predicate
now in this case we're printing the
arguments that is passed to the predicate but
when we run you can see we've got
nothing printed the last thing printed
was the snow white code from my line 93
why didn't we get anything printed here
well it's because stream operations are
lazily evaluated in other words nothing
happens until there's a terminal
operation now there isn't a terminal
operation in this chain and that's why it
was not being evaluated and we think
about this
hopefully it makes sense if we have
a long chain of intermediate operations
but no terminal operation then there's
nothing coming at the bottom of the pipe
so it would be a waste of time to
execute all the intermediate operations
so let's actually add terminal
operations to the chain so come back
here and put.....
....so now if we run that we
get our answers and we're actually seeing
the argument to the predicate printed on
the console
ok so before i close off the
discussions on lambda expressions want
to talk a little bit about best
practices now throughout this section I've
intentionally written lambda expressions
in different ways and here the
variations that I've used first one is must
specify the types of parameters
vs letting the compiler infer
them the second one was using a return
statement with curly braces for one
statement lambda expressions vs not
using return because it's implied and
hencec not requiring curly braces three
using lambda expressions that contain
one statement vs lambda expressions that
have more than one statement and 4
using parentheses with a lambda
expression only has one argument vs not using parentheses since
they're optional when there's only one
argument so if you look at the four
variations the two alternatives offered
the choice between verbosity or
vs conciseness which in turn
often comes down to the choice between
readability and conciseness
not all the time of course short lambda
expressions are usually readable no
matter how concise they are but when
striving for conciseness we can
sometimes write lambda expressions that
are difficult to decipher because we
left out too much information now there are
a number of articles and tutorials on
the internet that discuss best practices
when using lambda expressions now many
of them fall on the side of conciseness
but keep in mind that best practices are
guidelines not rules so when reading
code that i haven't written or going
back to code that I wrote months or
years ago
previously it's actually not unusual for
me to come across a lambda expression
that's cryptic and takes a lot of work
to figure out the question I would ask
is was it concise well yes it was it but was
it readable to the human no so yes we
can optionally leave out the parameter types when the compiler can infer them but
will it be easier for a developer
reading the code to do the same
now we don't have to include the return
key word
when a one statement lambda returns a
value but will a developer be able to
tell at a glance what the or that
the lambda expression returns a value in
my opinion when it comes down to
practices that are syntactic and don't
make a difference to the code that's
generated the key thing here is to be
consistent so don't use different styles
within the same file if you're working
on code someone else wrote and they
always leave out the parameter types then
you should do the same now if they always
use the return key word with one
statement lambdas do the same if you're
writing code from scratch do what's
clearer and the easiest for you and also
what you think will be clear for other
developers who may work on the code in
the future
personally I'd rather see a verbose lambda than a concise one with a comment
because i know from experience that
comments aren't always updated when the
code is and that can ultimately lead to
a lot of confusion and waste of time
alright so that's it now i'm going to
finish the video here now the next one
we're going to start work on the
challenge so see you in the next video