so in the main method that time we wrote
just at the end of the previous video we
created the shared buffer an instance of
the producer class as well as two
instances of the consumer class now we
passed that same buffer which we've
created within an array list that's the one
on line 13 to all three instances
then we create a thread for the producer
and start it and we create 2 consumer
threads and start them
so at this point we've learned enough
about concurrency to know that we really
are going to run into problems when we
try to run this application
three threads are showing the same
arraylist now one's writing to it until
reading from it and if we look at the
documentation for array list remember we
did discuss this in a previous video we
notice down here this class is roughly
equivalent to revector except that
it's unsynchronized and that's the point
we made previously so the arraylist
itself isn't synchronized
but even if it was when a class is
synchronized or thread safe
we can be confident that each time a
thread calls method in the class
no other threads will be able to run a
method in the class until the first
thread is finished executing the method
so in other words if thread A is
running synchronized method X in class
y then thread b cant run any methods
in class y until thread a has finished
running method X and that's even if
thread a is suspended
now it doesn't mean that if thread a
would have called three methods in a row
in class y it can run all three
methods without worrying about
interference from another thread if
thread a is suspended after it's finished
running a method in class y another
thread can run a method in class y
before thread a has the chance to run
again
so in other words the following can
happen when using a class its class y
that synchronized or synchronized thread-safe so thread a
runs a method in class y thread b
runs a method in class y thread a runs a method
in class y and again that that can happen
in the case of them being synchronized
and thread safe
so how does this apply to our
application so let's just go back to the
code again
so the consumer class calls the array
list is empty method and just go down
and have a look at the consumer class
so its calling this buffer.isempty
which is ultimately is an array
list is empty method and then it calls
remove or get as you can see in the code
below that
now that could be suspended after
calling isempty
giving the producer or consumer the
opportunity to change the contents of
the arraylist so given that scenario we
can see that one potential problem could
be as follows the producer adds a string
to the buffer consumer one might call is
empty and then that returns false or
consumer one is suspended or consumer 2
calls is empty and it returns false or
consumer 2 remove the string consumer
2 is suspended and consumer one runs again
and calls get 0
the one that's on line 67 and oops
there's no data so we get an index
out of bounds exception
that's just one potential problem that
could happen here
there are other potential problems
another one would be both consumers try
to remove the same string and again the
point here is to remember that
arraylist isn't thread safe so it's
certainly possible for one thread to be
suspended while in the middle of running
the remove method before the item has
actually been removed from the arraylist
so keeping that in mind let's just run
this application and see what happens
and the results I can tell you up
front now will depend on timing
so we could get lucky and find that the
application runs fine or we might get an
exception but the consumers don't remove
the data correctly and loop indefinitely
more likely will get an index out of
bounds exception
let's just run this and we might also
find that the application may not
terminate and we might have to stop it
manually
so I'm going to run the application a
few times and just see what happens and
we should probably get a different output each time
the only thing that we know for sure
with this running these
tests is that
we need to prevent thread interference
so let's run that first time we've run it
we've got a problem here you can see we start
adding some number we removed one we're going
to index out of bounds problem
so let's just run this again actually we will stop now because it's not
hasn't stopped properly
we'll run it again ok
run it again
you can see that example there the
program didn't get to do the final
processing so you can see we are getting
different output each time we run this
and obviously the program is not working
as it should be
so really the only thing we know for
sure here is that we need to prevent the
thread interference it's very
inconsistent in the results that is
currently producing so let's start by
doing what we've already learned
we're going to close down the run window
now we will use the synchronized blocks
and will need to add synchronization to
both the producer and the consumer and
thinking about it since they share the
arraylist it probably makes sense to
synchronize on the arraylist instance
so I was looking at the producer code
first
so we're going to come here into the try
within the run itself
so after we've output the message to
the console and instead of just doing the
buffer.add
lets do a synchronized.....
....and we also
want to add another synchronized block
down here because we're adding the eof
so....
...
so essentially we've synchronized the
two calls to add because array list
again isn't thread safe if we don't
synchronize and the producer is
suspended in the middle of running the
add method and one of the consumers
then calls get or remove the internal
integrity of the arraylist might be
compromised again depending on timing
so I synchronize adding the numbers to
the buffer up here as well as adding the
eof character at the end we don't need
to include the print line and that's
because if the producer is suspended
between printing the line and actually
adding the data
it won't matter a consumer could
read any existing data from the buffer
in that case it won't change what the
producer adds when it runs again
ok on to the consumer code so let's
bring them on the screen
so what we want to do is we want to do synchronizes if buffer is empty
code
let's synchronize that so....and we are
actually going to put the code all of
this code in the synchronized block
we'll talk about that in a sec so
basically we got our while then
everything is synchronized that it was in
that while loop into our synchronized
block
so yes we've included everything in that
block so we don't want the producer or
another consumer to change the arraylist
once a consumer threads checked whether
the buffer is empty
so in other words we want all calls to
methods in array list to take place
as a unit collectively and they're all
running in this critical section
let's run this and see whether we fix
the problem or not
you can see we've got a much better
result by adding that synchronized
blocks just run it again just to make
sure that it wasn't a once of one more time
clearly things are looking good
so we can see there we saw there that
the thread interference no longer occurs
the reason for that was because the
producers sleeps
after adding a string usually a consumer
thread will have a chance at that point
to remove the last string added before
the producers thread itself
runs again and if we just do run this again
though you probably noticing there that
sometimes only one consumer threads ever
had the chance to remove the data and
they're both not necessarily getting the
chance to move the data each time
you notice down here for example when
exiting they both had the chance to
remove the item in the other
sections only one of the consumers has had
the chance to remove it so we could
reduce the sleep time or remove the call
if we wanted the if we want to produce to fill the buffer faster
but in all cases you can see every
time I ran this all the threads exit
gracefully and the application does
terminate normally before Java 1.5 and
the introduction of the java.util.concurrent package synchronization
was really the only error we had in our
quiver when it came to dealing with
thread interference but it does still
have its drawbacks
the first drawback is that threads that
are blocked
waiting to execute synchronize code
can't be interrupted
once they're blocked their stuck there
until they get the lock for the object
the code is synchronizing on and if
you think about it that can lead to
problems and we'll take a closer look at
those in a later lecture but the second
drawback is that the synchronized block
must be within the same method in other
words we can't start a synchronized
block in one method and end the
synchronization block in another for
obvious reasons
the third drawback is that we can't test
to see if an object's intrinsic lock is
available or find out any other
information about that lock
also if the lock isn't available we
can't timeout after we waited for the
lock for a while when we reach the
beginning of a synchronized block
we can either get the lock and continue
executing or block at that line of code
until we get the lock and the fourth
drawback is that if multiple threads are
waiting to get a lock
it's not first come first served there
isn't a set order in which the jvm will
choose the next thread that gets the
lock
so the first thread that blocked could
be the last thread to get the lock and
vice versa
so instead of using synchronization we
can prevent thread interference using
classes that implement the java.util.concurrent locks.lock interface
so let's start looking at doing that in
the next video