So in this video, now that we've actually installed
IntelliJ IDEA and the Java Development Kit,
we need to associate the Java Development Kit
with IntelliJ IDEA so that we can use it,
and we also need to change a few settings
within IntelliJ IDEA as well.
Now just to note that this video is applicable
for the Windows, Mac and Linux installations,
so irrespective, we'll be going through
what you need to do in this video.
So first, I'm gonna come over to Configure.
I'm gonna click on Structure For New Projects.
We're gonna associate the JDK.
Now you can see on the screen there
that Project's not selected.
So come up to Project,
and we come over here and click on the dropdown there.
Now, you may or may not have
a Java installation showing there.
For me, you saw that it said No SDK,
and that I've got Python option there
and that's to do with my Python course,
so nothing there for Java.
So if you don't see a Java option,
just click on New,
select JDK.
Now what we need to do
is if it doesn't automatically show
the option for Amazon Corretto, which is not here,
we just need to expand the folder.
I'm on a Windows machine.
I'm gonna go to Programme Files, Amazon Corretto,
and select the JDK.
You can see it's 11.0.4_10,
but you may have a different number.
Yours might be 11.0.5 or even something else.
That's fine.
Just click on that and click OK.
Noting what's happening on the screen there.
Now if you're running on a Mac,
you saw in the JDK installation video where the path was,
so just select that path to get that working,
noting that you might need to go down
to a sub-folder called Home.
And on the Linux installation video,
I showed you also where it was installed for Linux platform,
so you may need to navigate to that folder,
if you don't automatically see it coming up here.
But you can see now that we've done that.
It's showing.
Now, what it can be a good idea to do
is come back to click on Edit,
and instead of letting on it as 11,
you can change that perhaps and put something
like Corretto-11,
to remind yourself that this
is the Amazon Corretto version.
This is particularly relevant
if you're using multiple JDK's.
But again you can see the JDK Home Path
should point to the Amazon Corretto Installation.
So we've set that up now,
we've got our JDK configured.
That's good.
Next thing we need to do, is just make some changes.
So come back to Configure again,
select Settings, on a Mac
that will probably show as Preferences.
Click on that.
Come down here and click on to the left of Editor.
And to the left of General.
Click on Auto Import.
You wanna check both those boxes,
Add unambiguous imports on the fly,
and Optimise imports on the fly (for current project).
We'll talk more about what that does in a later video.
Next come on down to Appearance,
make sure that Show line numbers is checked,
which you can see it is in my case.
And lastly, come down to Code Folding.
We want to deselect a few options here,
so we're uncheck Imports,
uncheck One line methods,
uncheck "Closures"
(anonymous classes implementing one method, before Java 8)
and finally,
uncheck Generic constructor and method parameters.
Now click on OK.
And we're actually done.
So what we've done is we've just configured
IntelliJ for a couple of options
that make things easier to use.
For now though, that's all the configuration.
We've now associated the Java Development Kit,
Amazon Corretto in this case,
with IntelliJ IDEA and we can now move on to the next stage.
Which is starting to work with creating a Java Programme.
So, I'll see you in the next video.