So, in the previous video,
we started our abstract class challenge,
the solution, and I want to actually
finish it up, hopefully, this video.
Before I actually continue on with the
code, there is actually a way to shortcut
a little bit of this code, and I'm talking
specifically about the add item method,
which is of course in the my linked list
class that we created in the last video.
And the reason we can
actually shortcut the code,
is relating to the methods set next and
set previous.
Of course if I click through to those.
We actually go to the abstract class,
and that's our list item.
Set next and set previous.
And of course we implemented
that in our nodes.
I'm going to the node.
You can see, set next,
we're actually setting the item, and
then we're actually returning the item
as well, and same for set previous, so
because we're actually returning that
reference in here, what we can do is,
we can actually shortcut
some of our actual code.
Cause, at the moment, you can see,
every time we actually add a new time,
we've gotta set the the set next and
the set previous,
unless of course it's a new item for
the first time.
But most times we're gonna
be executing both of those.
We can actually shortcut that by
actually doing something like this.
We can actually put [SOUND]
dot set previous [SOUND],
and then pass the current item as well.
[SOUND].
And that's actually an abbreviation,
instead of having two lines you're
doing it all in the one line.
And again,
this relies on the fact that, a,
the method is actually
returning the right item.
We can actually achieve that,
so we're returning that and
then we're setting the set previous and
we're calling the set previous method
on the item that's been returned from
the set next if that makes sense.
We're actually doing that as well.
That's the first one,
we can actually change, but
we can also make a change, also down here.
You can do the same thing for
that, we can do set previous.
Like so, and then with this one down here,
we can do exactly the same thing again.
Like so, which abbreviates it.
And then the final else down here
can actually do the same thing to
that as well.
[SOUND].
Just a way to abbreviate
the amount of code.
And again, it's reliant on the fact that
we're actually returning the item and
then recalling the method based on
the item that's actually returned.
Okay so
in order to actually test this code,
we actually need to actually start writing
some code for our traverse method.
And it's actually not that hard.
We can start off by putting a while loop.
We start to make sure we've
actually got some data.
While root is not equal to nul.
[SOUND].
Then we're gonna do [SOUND] system out
dot print line root dot get value.
[SOUND].
Then we'll do root equals root dot next.
So we'll proceed to the next entry.
So that's in the case
where there was some data.
But it's probably gonna be wise to
actually also test to see whether it's
nul, we can actually put a message to that
effect, so we can put something like if
root is equal to nul [SOUND], then we'll
change that to the list is empty [SOUND],
and we'll change this here to an else,
while, and I'll indent that code, and
what I'll do is I'll just, actually,
put another semicolon in there, like so.
And then it automatically
gets fixed up as you saw,
by IntelliJ actually indented that for us.
And now we should be after
output the actual link list,
but also display if it's actually nul.
I'm just going back and
actually start running some code
to test some of this stuff.
I'm going to go down
to our main method and
you remember that we wrote that code
at the start, the split code and
I'm going to start typing below that.
Actually, I'm going to start typing above
that because we're actually going to be
adding to that.
So I'm going to put it here.
I'm going to type linked list,
sorry my linked list, my link list,
list equals new [SOUND],
link equals new my linked list.
Nul.
So, we haven't actually
added anything yet.
And if we do a list dot traverse,
list dot get root.
Let's see what actually happens.
We'll actually run that first.
The list is empty,
so it's correctly showing us that there's
no data in the list, which is good.
We can leave that code in there for
splitting the various
capital cities of Australia.
But what I'm gonna do now is actually put
this code in here now, write some code and
actually put it in its place here.
We're actually gonna add the item to our
linked list, to my linked list class.
Let's add item, we're gonna call it,
new, we gonna create a new node,
which courses our list item.
The class that actually implements
the list item, abstract class.
It's the class that is actually,
if you go back and have a look, node we're
extending from list item, and of course
list item was our abstract class.
I'm going back to that code.
We're going to add a new node [SOUND],
which is the actual
capital city in this case.
That should add the title there,
as you can see, and just a confirmation.
We talked about that briefly, but
the string split method returns a string
arise, as you can see on the screen on
line 63 and then it turns a string array
containing all the individual items of
the string, that we defined in line 61.
They can specify the character
that separates the items.
You can see on line 63 after the dot
split, how we actually got space.
The space is effectively the delimiter.
Or the character that sort of separates
each key string in that actual big string
itself.
Now we've done that, we'll actually put
another list in there, list dot traverse,
traverse and list dot get root, so
we'll actually go through now and
actually run it.
The first time we run that,
of course, we passed this list which
was effective at that point nul.
But now if we do this, we've actually
got some data that we've added so
we should get a different result.
And you can see we've now got
the various cities, and we've also got
an error message here, the site Canberra
is already present and not added.
But the rest of the cities, Adelaide,
Brisbane, Canberra, Darwin Melvin, Perfis,
and Sydney are actually added
in the correct order, and
of course the reason that Canberra came up
as a duplicate was that we actually had it
two times in that list purely to
confirm that that would actually work.
Next we need to go back to
our my list link class.
We need to implement the remove item.
Currently, it's not actually implemented.
It's just returning files.
So what we need to do is be
able to actually delete items.
Now, removing items is relatively
straightforward in a link list.
We traverse the list until we
find the item to be removed.
Then we set the previous
link to point to the where,
to where our item to be deleted point,
if that makes sense.
We're basically just sort of filling in
the gaps and making sure that we still got
we're not actually off in creating
any off in records in the link list.
Again, what we're trying to
do is set the previous link
to point to where our item
to be deleted points.
Let's go ahead and actually do that.
First thing, I'm gonna test if it's nul.
If item is not equal to nul, [SOUND] then
we're just gonna print out a message.
So, [SOUND] deleting item
plus item dot get value.
Like so.
And next we wanna do a list item [SOUND],
current item equals this dot root,
so I'll start at the top,
basically, the very first entry.
While count item is not equal to nul.
While we've still got some
records to basically go through.
And then we're gonna type int comparison
equals current item dot compare to item,
item which was the list item
that was passed to this method.
if comparison, now remembering what we're
trying to do is actually find this item
in the linked list.
So we cannot do anything till we
actually find this specific one.
And remember we wrote
the compare to function so
we can do exact match to make sure
that we're deleting the right record.
If comparison is equal to zero then that
means we've actually found the record to
delete or found the item to delete.
But we need to do a test to
see whether this is the root.
If it's only one entry and
this is the root record,
we need to do some
special processing there.
Put current item equals this dot root,
so if this is the root record,
the very first, the head, in other words
[SOUND], then we're going to type,
this dot root equals current item
dot next, so we're basically making
sure that we're setting root what
is going to be the new root.
To point to what currently is pointing
to the next record if that makes sense.
So we're deleting the first entry,
the root entry, and
we're pointing it automatically.
So it's actually pointing now
to what is the next list item.
That list root is currently
pointing to with dot next.
We're setting that, but
we haven't actually deleted it still yet.
We'll do else current item dot previous
dot set next current Item dot next.
Again what we're doing is we're looking at
the previous entry because this particular
record, so
assuming this isn't the root record,
we're looking at what is the previous
entry, and we know that there is
a previous entry because I've already
tested to see whether there is a root.
And we're setting that to point
to what is the current item next.
In other words we're bypassing
this record effectively.
This item that we're
actually gonna be deleting.
And what we need to do is test for now.
If current item dot next,
if that's not equal to now.
[SOUND] We're gonna do
current item dot next dot
set previous current item dot previous.
The same thing there.
We're actually doing
the other side of the coin.
For the next item, we're setting that
to actually point to the current
item's previous, if that makes sense.
Sounds a little bit confusing, but
we're making sure that both pointers,
the previous and the next, are actually
now still pointing to the right places.
Now that we've done that,
in the case where did have a direct
comparison we can return true,
because we did find the record and
were able to make those changes.
Otherwise we need to do another
check we need to do here.
Cause if comparison is less than zero,
then that just means we haven't reached
the point in the linked list yet.
So we'll put current item
equals current item dot next.
So we basically want to continue
navigating through the linked list to
see if we can find the record.
But otherwise, effectively if
comparison is greater than zero.
[SOUND].
If comparison is greater
than zero at this point,
it means we've got passed the point
where we could have actually deleted it.
I spelled that wrong [SOUND], so
basically here, we are at an item [SOUND],
greater for
sort purposes than the one to be deleted.
[SOUND].
The item isn't, is not in the list.
I've reached past the point of where
it would've actually been in the list,
based on the sort criteria.
We're gonna return false at that point
because we can't do anything else.
We know that we can pass that point.
[NOISE] And for a final test and
will return false,
the next defining thing.
[SOUND] Without finding
the item to delete.
[NOISE] So that's basically remove item.
The test is actually create a list
of numbers in our main method and
actually just run through and
actually see whether it actually works so
I'm gonna go back to the main again
below the other code we've added.
And actually for simplicity
purposes let's just do it this way,
let's just put this in here.
And we're going to put five, seven, three,
nine, eight, two, one, O, four, six.
Cause all the other codes actually
there to create our link list.
We actually run that just to
make sure it's actually working.
We're getting the sorted in
the right order, which is good.
Let's actually just, what I'm gonna do is,
I'm gonna paste in a bit of code
here just to save us a bit of time.
Let's actually just paste this code in.
And you can see what I'm doing here is,
I'm actually removing an item,
printing out the list,
removing an item, removing more items.
And actually just running it through.
So let's actually go through and
actually see what it does.
So I can see in the first case,
at the top,
we're moving item three,
so that should leave us.
Remove three, zero, one, to, three,
four, five, six, seven, eight, nine.
Removing item five, zero, one, two, four,
six, that's three and five we're deleting.
Deleting zero, four, and two,
that leaves one, six, seven, eight, nine.
Deleting item nine,
one, six, seven, eight.
Deleting item eight, one, six, seven.
Deleting item six.
When the sevens only left and
deleting our one leaves only one.
And the last entry,
we're actually deleting what is left.
So the last entry, the reason why we
haven't actually specified the number
here, we actually called it,
just to remove item.
We called it with root entry.
Basically the only one that was reaming,
which was the number seven.
Deleted that, and the list is now empty,
so it's actually working.
I'm going to actually end the video here.
I was actually going to actually show
the search tree in this video, but
I'll actually go ahead and
actually do that in the next video.
That's the one where we're actually going
to create the optional search tree,
and I need to actually talk about
the differences which are gonna be in
the implementation of the add item,
remove item, and traverse, and
it really needs its own video.
So, I will see you in that next video.