alright so it's time for a lambda
challenge or rather this case challenges
because what I've done is I've set up
a series of smaller lambda challenges
to help you really understand what
lambda expressions are and hopefully you
can get through all these challenges so
let's start off with the first challenge
the challenge number one is to write the
following anonymous class that you can
see on screen as the Lambda expression
so another words convert that so it's a
lambda expression so pause the video now
and try that out and i'll see you when
you get back alright so let's solve that
so firstly the runnable class so this
was the class was going to paste this
onto into the source code so
that's what we're trying to convert so
how do we convert that to lambda
expression
ok so let's convert that to a lambda
expressions going to be runnable will
call this.....
....and we need to
put semicolon at the end of the runnable
line and then we just take the code that
we want executed which will be
exactly the same in this case gonna paste that
directly into the code block and they're
our runnable and just in case you're wondering
we don't have any arguments so we have
to use empty parenthesis that's why i've
used the parentheses there on line
17 the body of the lambda is the
same body of the anonymous classes run
method and since there was more than
one statement in the body we have to use
curly braces around so it does this lambda
map to any of the interfaces in the
java.util.function package
well actually no it doesn't it doesn't
take any arguments and it doesn't return
the value all the interfaces in the java
.util.function package either
take an argument or arguments or return
a value or do both
alright so let's move on to the next
challenge alright so challenge number 2
i'm going to write the following method
as a lambda expression you don't worry about
a signing into anything at this stage so
pause the video and I'll see you when
you come back
alright so how do we go about doing that
so we start with the parameter so.....
....
...
.....
....
alternatively we could have actually
been a little bit more verbose and we
could have indicated the type here so in
parentheses string.....
.....so we have got
an error here about the lambda
expression not expected but that's ok
and i will be looking at that next
challenge the main thing was to tell you
figured out how to write that method as a
lambda expression so here the parameter
becomes the lambdas argument and the
body of the every second child method
became the lambdas body and this code
prints out every second character of the
string in case you're wondering and
again in the second scenario where i
indicated the type of the argument have
to use parentheses with the first case i
just use the S so does this lambda map
to any of the interfaces in the java .
.util.function package in this case
yes it does it takes one argument
parameter in other words and returns a
value so it maps to function string comma
string so to actually get this working
we can do the following so i can
actually put that references so...
.....
that should fix the errors and of course where we've
got the parameter type
we can also remove that and just go back
to the native tyoe where parentheses
and the type is implied
because of the function definition that
we've set up on line 27
alright so that's challenge 2 complete
....
let's move on now to the next challenge
alright challenge number three
so right now the function that we just
created doesn't do anything going to
write the code that will execute the
function the argument as you can see
on screen of 1234567890
so go ahead and do that pause the
video now and i'll see you when you get
back alright so how do we do that how do
we actually are execute the function
that we've created on line 27 well to do
that give a space first so we can see
this we just do lambda function.....
....
......
nothing happens because we haven't
indicated is going to be the output and
if we wanted to actually output on the
screen we could do a.....
run that and we should now see the
output in this case 24680 alright so
let's move on to the next challenge
alright challenge number four
so instead of executing this function
directly the one that we just created
suppose that we want to pass it to a
method so your task is to write a method
called every second character that
accepts the function as a parameter and
execute it with the argument 123456789
0 and it should return the result of
the function for bonus points don't
hardcode the argument string within the
method
alright so that's challenge number for
go ahead and try that out pause the
video and I'll see you when you get back
alright so let's go ahead now and
write that function so what we need to
do write that method should say so we
want to write this method called every
second character so it's going to be
public....
....
.....
...so we need to make it
a static so we can do that and it's
going to be string because we're
returning a string it's going to be
every second character and the parameter
function....
....and then
how do we actually return the result we
do.....
.....so that's it
you can see we just needed to pass that
function to the method inside the method
we actually called the apply method with
what we want to process in this case
1234567890 so that's the first one the
bonus points 1 when we wanted to
actually pass the argument as a
parameter just a matter of passing the
second parameter so pass it as a
string source....
.....
well then change that to source you can
see that....
alright so that is challenge 4 completed
let's move now on to challenge 5
so using the bonus version that we just
coded call the method with the lambda
function we created earlier and the
string 1234567890 then print the
result returned from the method so that is
challenge 5 go ahead and try that out
and pause the video now and i'll see you
when you get back alright so let's go
ahead now and call the method that
we've created with our lambda function
and print the result and you can
probably figure out that would be
something like this....
.....
....
and if you just printed it out directly
like I did on line 38 that would be ok
as well so let's just comment out that
first code and let's just run
this and we get our results to 24680
alright so let's move on to the next
challenge
alright challenge number six
so now write a lambda expression that
maps to the java.util.supply
interface now this lambda should return
the string i love java and assign it to a
variable called I love java so go
ahead and try out that challenge number
six pause the video and I'll see you
when you get back
ok so let's go and try this so write
a lambda expression that maps to the
java.util.supplier interface so
we're going to do....
.....
....
....so that is it so
recall that a supplier produces
objects it doesn't actually accept any
arguments and since the lambda body here
is a single statement we don't have to
include the return key word because it's
implied but if we wanted to include the
clarity we could change this slightly to
do that and let's just take a copy of
this line first copy of that and we're
going to comment that so its still there and
the source code which should be able to
download so changing this now to
actually include the return statement we
need to add code block to do that we're doing
it on one line if you want....
....
....and again we're using return
statement we have to use curly braces to
open a code block then we also have to
include the semicolon at the end of the
body statement as well as at the end of
the code block to complete the line
alright so let's now move on to the
next challenge the last one for this
video
alright next challenge challenge number
seven
now as with function the supplier
won't do anything until we use it so use
this supplier to assign a string i love java
to a variable called supplier result and
then print that variable to the console
so that's your challenge
pause the video now and i'll see you
when you get back alright so as you saw
the supplier won't do anything until we
use it so let's use the supplier to assign
the string i love java to a variable
called supplier result we're going to do
that it's going to be....
....
and just run that to make sure it works
i love java so that's it
alright so let's move on now to the next
video and we still got some more
challenges to complete so i'll see you
in the next video