so we went through some of the drawbacks
to using synchronized blocks and I
talked just at the end of the last video
about another way of using or
preventing thread interference and
that's by using classes that implement
the java.util.concurrent.locks lock interface
so this package contains several
implementations of the lock interface
that we can use
and as we're about to see the lock
implementations that java provide don't
have the drawbacks that
I outlined in the previous video about
that synchronized blocks have so let's
change our application now to use a lock
object we use an instance of the
reentrant lock class so let's go have a
look at that we're going to close this
down so I'm going to add a line just
after the buffer in our main method
re-entrant lock to call this one buffer
lock equals....
now you can probably guess by the
name that this lock is reentrant if its
thread is already holding a reentrant
lock when it reaches the code that requires
the same lock it can continue executing
it doesn't have to obtain the lock again
now that might sound as if it should be a
given but to in fact not all
implementations of the lock interface
are re-entrant so we are going to create the lock
instances as I have done their on line 15 and
we're going to share that with the
producer and the consumer remember that
all the threads have to be competing for
the same lock to prevent thread
interference
i'm going to create an instance of that
in the main method as you saw me do and
we have to pass the lock to the producer
and consumer instances
let's do that as well....
....
let's then change the classes that the producer and the consumer
classes we want to add a private...
so that so we can store that in our
class will change the constructor...
....
....the next let's look at our run method
so we're going to do first is take out
the synchronize blocks that we
previously added or we added in the
previous video
....
ok so how do we actually use this
buffer lock it turns out it's quite
simple so we just come up to the code
above where we had the synchronized code
and we just type in buffer lock
....then execute the buffer.add
then we do....then we'll come down and do exactly the same
thing in the end of file after the
system that out to print line...
...so very similar to
the synchronized block in that we are
surrounding the code that we ultimately
want to be thread-safe to avoid thread
interference with .lock and .unlock
that's for the code for the producer
class and just want to clarify something
here that we're using the lock method to
acquire the lock and the unlock method
to release the lock but this is very
important when using lock objects
we're responsible for releasing the lock
it won't happen automatically it doesn't
happen automatically as it would when we
use the synchronized block
so the intrinsic locks we use with
synchronized blocks are always released
when the thread holding the lock exits
the synchronized block
so this is one drawback to using lock
objects in that we have to manage this
lock process themselves by making sure
we call the .lock and the unlock
methods now when a thread calls the lock
method it will either obtain the lock
and continue executing or it won't be
able to get the lock because of thread
already has it
so in that case the thread that called lock
will be suspended until it can get that
lock
if we forget to release the lock threads
waiting for the lock will then start
blocking forever
so in our producers as you saw the code I've
just changed their we get the lock
before we added a number string after
adding the string we then release the
lock and the same goes for when we get
the end of file indicator so lets go
and do similar change now to our consumer
class and we need to add our private...
....
instead we're going to do after the
while true
you guessed it buffer....and write down at the end after the last
statement has been executed...
so you've seen here we've essentially
replace the synchronized statement with
a call to lock and replace the end of
the synchronized block with a call to
unlock
so let's run and see what happens and we
can see that there's a problem and this
could depend on timing because you might
find this all sort of running on a
little bit further but in this case it's
done as a suspected it would
the producer adds the first string you
can see that the output is indicated that
happen then nothing happens for quite a
while and then eventually I will leave it long
enough we should probably get a maximum
lock count exceeded message with an
exception and may or may not come out
come on but the bottom there it is there
now so does take some time but what
happened and i'll just move that over so
you can see that message a bit more
maximum lock count exceeded so clearly
we've got a problem with this code as it
stands
so what actually going on at this
point
well we got the consumer
code on the screen
now looking at the produce lock code
again it seems to be pretty well okay
because we got a lock and then
were performing that one line of code
and then unlocking we're doing that
obviously twice once to add the numbers
and once to add the end of file
indicator but in the consumer code come
down there and have a look at that we
enter the loop and then we get the lock
the lock is the first thing we do after
entering the loop
that's on line 74 we then check to
see if there's any data in the buffer
if there is data we continue executing
the loop code if there isn't
we loop back and get the lock again
because we're still holding the lock
so you can you see what the problem is
here we've never released the lock as
such
so the buffer lock.unlock code is
never executed because that's only the
moment written on line 84 after the
while loop exits
when we were using a synchronized block
the lock was released because we exited
the synchronized block when we return to
the beginning of the while loop by just
exiting the synchronized block that
automatically released the lock but when we
are using the lock object
ourselves we skip over the unlock code
and keep getting the lock again and
again the problem here is this line 76
we are continuing which essentially is
in calling this unlock code
so re-entrant lock objects can keep
track of how many times they locked if the
thread gets the same lock twice it has
to release it twice before another
thread can get the lock and i just want
to give you a pseudo example of what I
mean here we are just going to paste is
this code in but we won't need to do
anything with it just so you can get an
idea of what I'm talking about
so there's an example of what I'm
talking about so when method B calls
unlock
we wouldn't want any other threads to be
able to get lock one because method
a still expect to be holding the lock
surrounded a section of code with lock
and unlock because the code itself is a
critical section now because the same
thread can acquire the same lock
multiple times
the unlock method won't actually release
the lock until the lock count
also known as also called the hold
count reaches zero so in our consumer
case we get the lock so many times that
eventually we exceed the maximum lock
count allowed
also since we never release the lock the
producer is never able to add more data
and that's why you saw it sitting there
sort of frozen after adding one item so
just delete the code so clearly we need
to add more unlock statements to our
consumer class
we need one when the buffer is empty and
we continue the loop but we also need
when we read end of file and break out
of the loop as well so let's add those
statements again the first one here is
here after the test to see whether it's
empty before the continued
we're going to do a buffer lock....and also down here after the break before
the break I should say we do a buffer....
let's just run that to see what happens
so this you can see that we
were successful application is behaving again
so you might be thinking that you know
this could get messy and perhaps you
should be sticking with synchronized
blocks we could have unlocked statement
scattered throughout our code
so our code and in doing that potentially
could be more error-prone and difficult
to maintain
but that's because we're not using locks
in the recommended way so i wanted to
show you this so that we can see why we
always want to enclose the critical
sections of code with a try finally
block but let's talk more about that in
the next video