alright so moving onto a second video
with challenges challenge number 8
so challenge number 8 so theirs many
interfaces in the java software
development kit and sometimes we can use
a lambda expression instead of creating
an instance that implements the
interface that we want to use so given a
specific interface
how can we tell whether we can map a
lambda expression to in other words
what's the criteria that has to be met
so pause the video have a think about
that and see if you can figure out what
that is and i'll see you when you get
back alright so let's have a look at
that the answer well the interface has to
be a functional interface can have only
a single method that must be implemented
now functional interface can contain
more than one method but all the methods
but one must have default
implementations now most of the time
the documentation for an interface will
state whether it's a functional
interface
alright so moving on
next question here is what we just said
in mind can we then use a lambda
expression to represent an instance of
the java.util.concurrent.callable
interface and as a hint here you have
to check the documentation and as a
java developer you have to be really
comfortable looking up a reading
documentation it's a really important
part of the process of being a developer
and theirs a link on the screen you can
see there to the call of documentation
links also in the resources section so
check that out and see whether you
can answer that question and i'll see
or pause the video now and i'll see you
when you get back
alright the answer the callable
interfaces only one method that has to
be implemented the call method so in
other words we can use a lambda for it
and if you went to the documentation and
have a look you could see that you would
see that the documentation states that
it's a functional interface
alright next question is that
java.util.comperator or
comparator i should say interface a
functional interface see if you can
figure that out and pause the video and
I'll see you when you get back with the
answer the answer to that is yes it is
so despite containing over ten methods
only one method has to be implemented
and that's the compare method because of
that it's a functional interface and
there's a link on the screen to the
documentation which you may have
already found done a bit of
research on links also the resources
section
alright so that is challenge eight
completed let's move on now to the next
one challenge 9 and we're going to
get back into a bit of coding
alright challenge 9
so let's suppose we got the following
list of the top five male and female
names for 2015
so with that list you need to write some
code to print the items in the list in
sorted order and with the first letter
in each name upper cased so the name
Harry in lowercase should be printed as
Harry with a capital H and should be
printed after Emily and before Isla
now you want to use lambda expressions
obviously wherever possible because this
is a lambda challenge so go ahead and
try that and pause the video now and
i'll see you when you get back with the
answer just before i do that the list
you can see on screen there it is
available as a resource in this video so
you can just copy and paste that
directly into save you some typing
ok let's have a look at the answer for
that
so I'm just going to start by pasting in
the list of baby names
ok
so want to write the code to print the items
in the list in sorted order so how do we
do that we're going to start by defining
a new array list so its going to be a list of string
....
.....
alright so now that we've done that we
....
then want to sort it so i'm going to do
alright so now that we've done that we
a first uppercase....
then want to sort it so i'm going to do
.....
a first uppercase....
....
.....
so their are many ways to complete this but my
....
solution on the screens is just one
so their are many ways to complete this but my
answer so we create a new list that
solution on the screens is just one
holds all the names with first letter
answer so we create a new list that
uppercase and I used to for each method
holds all the names with first letter
to iterate over the list we use
uppercase and I used to for each method
sub string to get the first letter for
to iterate over the list we use
each name then we upper case that
sub string to get the first letter for
letter then use sub string again to
each name then we upper case that
concatenate it with the rest of the name
letter then use sub string again to
and we added the result of the lambda
concatenate it with the rest of the name
expression to the first uppercase list list
and we added the result of the lambda
now when for each completes the first
expression to the first uppercase list list
uppercase list contains all the names
now when for each completes the first
with the first letters uppercase and
uppercase list contains all the names
then used the sort method to pass it a
with the first letters uppercase and
comparator in our comparator we're calling
then used the sort method to pass it a
the string . compareto method and now
comparator in our comparator we're calling
we've been print each item in a sorted
the string . compareto method and now
list to the console so I've used lambdas
we've been print each item in a sorted
in three places with the for each method
list to the console so I've used lambdas
with the sort method and with the system
in three places with the for each method
. out . print line method
with the sort method and with the system
as i said this is only one way to do it
. out . print line method
there are other ways including using
as i said this is only one way to do it
third-party libraries that manipulate
there are other ways including using
strings but this works and we'll use
third-party libraries that manipulate
this version of the code going forward
strings but this works and we'll use
alright so let's move on now to
this version of the code going forward
challenge 10
alright so let's move on now to
alright challenge 10
challenge 10
so we now want to change the code so that it
alright challenge 10
uses method references remember that a
so we now want to change the code so that it
method reference looks like class ::
uses method references remember that a
method name so based on the
method reference looks like class ::
code that I provided in my solution see if
method name so based on the
you can convert that to use method
code that I provided in my solution see if
references so  pause the video and I'll
you can convert that to use method
see you when you get back alright so how
references so  pause the video and I'll
do we convert that to those two lines to
see you when you get back alright so how
use method references the lines that
do we convert that to those two lines to
we're working to change are lines 67 and
use method references the lines that
68 using the . sort and the for each so
we're working to change are lines 67 and
first thing I'm going to comment those out so
68 using the . sort and the for each so
we've got the original code in there you
first thing I'm going to comment those out so
need to download the source code so in
we've got the original code in there you
terms of making that sort line and
need to download the source code so in
method reference to use a method reference
terms of making that sort line and
....
method reference to use a method reference
.....
....
.....and that's going to be....
....so that's
it and actually have been running this
have I so I just run this to see that it's
actually working probably should have
done with the previous challenge and you
can see we get everything in uppercase
there and sorted correctly so that's
working nicely
alright time for challenge 11
alright so now i want to do the same
thing upper casing the first letter and
sorting and printing the list using a
stream and a chain of stream operations
so pause the video now go and do that
and I'll see you when you get back
alright so how we go about that
converting this or using stream to
sort the baby names
what I'm going to do is I'm just going
to click comment that out and we're going to
come in here and i'm going to type....
actually what we can do is well comment
those out as well because the stream is
gonna handle the sorting stuff as well
so we're going to do....
.....
....
couple of things to note here
first we didn't have to create a new
list to hold the names with uppercase
first letters the map method returns a
stream containing all the transform
transformed names now secondly this
code is a little more concise than the
previous versions and just as easy to
read in this case so we went from java
code that used lambda expressions to
more concise code that used method
references to streams and when
you're first learning how to code
using lambdas or streams this is a good
way to do it
we start by writing the more verbose
version that doesn't use lambdas but
uses anonymous classes you can replace
the anonymous class with lambdas or use
method references where applicable or
when applicable and then finally we can
rewrite the code to use streams but of
course only when it makes sense to use
them
just run this to make sure that it does
work we still get the same output this
that's working nicely
alright let's move on to challenge 12
alright the challenge 12
so instead of printing out the sorted
names print out how many name start with
the letter a in uppercase instead t hints here
you have to modify the stream chain and
secondly you'll have to add another
statement to print the number of items
so that's the challenge
pause the video and see if you can
figure out that challenge and i'll see
you when you get back alright so let's
have a go at doing that
counting the names beginning with the a
would be a long....
....
let's just run that then we'll just talk
about the code solution you can see we got
names beginning with a too and we've
got a merely an a over their so that's
correct
so here we use the filter method to
remove all items from the stream that
don't begin with a and then we use the
count method to get the number of items
in the resulting stream which again as I
just pointed out was 2 alright we got
two challenges to go lets now look
at challenge number 13
alright so challenge number 13
let's go back to the previous version of
the code when we're printing the sorted
names
let's suppose that we want debug what's
going on when the chains executed
instead of printing out the names at the
end of the chain you know maybe we're
not sure the code that upper cases the
first letter is working correctly so
let's use peek to print out the names
after the map method is executed so what
will the following code on the next
screen print to the console there's the
code on the screen so what will be the
result of that code when we executed so
in other words what can be printed out
on the console so pause the video now
and see if you can figure out the answer
and i'll see you when you get back
so the answer bit of a trick question I am
afraid the answer is nothing the chain
doesn't contain a terminal operation so
nothing is printed out remember that
stream chains are evaluated lazily so in
other words nothing happens until the
terminal operations added to the chain
at that point the entire chain is then
executed
alright so let's now move on to the last
challenge challenge number 14 alright
challenge 14 last one
your challenge is to add a terminal
operation to this chain the code that i
just showed you so the peek call will
execute and you can grab that code in
the resources section of this video to
save you having to type it in if you need
to check the documentation for
stream at the link here on the screen
and again that's in also the link is in
the resources section of the video now
since the peek call is printed every
item try to do something else with the
terminal operation other words don't
just print out the items again and see
if you can attempt that pause the video
now and i'll see you when you get back
alright so let's start off with the code
that we know doesn't do anything at
this stage I'm just going to print it
out or paste it in I should say
that's our basic code if we run that we
should find it doesn't do anything
we only got the code the output from
line 84 and again we haven't added the
terminal operation that's why it's
not actually working so let's add a
terminal operation so going to add
one and we'll just use . count
so now that even though were throwing
away the result you should find the peek
call runs and prints out the names at
this stage which aren't sorted so we don't
actually have to use the result of
terminal operations let's just run this
to confirm that it does work you can see
we are now getting output put again and
again it's printing the names at the stage
which they aren't sorted in case you're
wondering because of course the stream
for sorting it is after the peek another
possible result would be changing
count.....
....
run that again like so and what
I did there was used . collect which is
a terminal operation to store the result
of a chain to a list we may want to pass
the results to a method or do something
else with the list at that point
alright so that's it for the lambda
expressions challenge and actually for
this entire section
my advice is to get used to working with
lambdas and streams by practicing using them
at some point you'll think of a lambda
expression first rather than using
anonymous class so i hope you enjoyed
this section of code lambdas are really
quite interesting and useful i'll see
you in the next section of the course