In this video I want to show you
how to approach and solve exercises
and also show you some common errors
when dealing with code exercises.
What I'll actually do is I'll go through and solve one
exercise for you in this video and the next one.
So what we need to do first is
create a new empty project in IntelliJ.
This time without a template.
So with IntelliJ open,
create a new project
and I'm going to select Java if it's not already selected.
And I'm not going to use to project option.
And we're gonna call this one SpeedConverter.
Alright and I'll finish that
and that'll give us a basically,
an empty project to start with.
Alright, so let's now look at the exercise.
I'll just close this down.
We'll swing over and check out the exercise.
This is the speed converter exercise.
And this is coming up in our lesson after these two videos.
So what I would suggest you do is
you leave this open in another tab
while watching this video, so you can come back to it.
So in terms of what we're trying to do here,
we wanna write a method called toMilesPerHour
that has one parameter of type double
and that parameter should have the name kilometersPerHour.
Now the method needs to return
the rounded value of the calculation of type long.
Now if the parameter kilometersPerHour is less than zero,
the method toMilesPerHour needs to return minus one
and that indicates that the value passed
was an invalid value.
Otherwise, if it is a positive,
this is the parameter value passed to the method.
Then we need to calculate the value of miles per hour,
we need to round that value and then return it.
And for conversion and rounding,
check the notes in the text below
which we'll talk about shortly.
So that's one method that we have to write.
And then below that,
if you scroll down here,
above the window where we put in our code,
you got some examples there of the input and output.
Basically what happens when we call the method,
the argument or the parameter that we're passing to that
and what the result should be.
Now I'm not gonna read all those examples,
but you should actually read them carefully.
Now as you can see, the class name is SpeedConverter
and that's also the file name.
So let's jump back to IntelliJ.
We're gonna create some files for this exercise.
So we'll go back.
So the first thing we need to do now is create a new class,
and again the name is going to be SpeedConverter,
and we do that by right-clicking on the src folder,
New, Java Class, we're gonna call this one SpeedConverter,
and we're also gonna create another class called Main
and in that class we can put out main method
so that we can test our code in IntelliJ
before submitting the solution back on
the code exercises web browser screen.
So I'm gonna right-click on the source folder again,
New, Java Class again, and as I mentioned
I'm gonna call it Main with a capital M,
and you can see we've now got our two classes
showing in the left hand corner.
Alright, so let's start working on the SpeedConverter class.
We're gonna add that first method.
So I'm gonna double-click that
to bring that back on the screen.
And if you recall the first sentence in the exercise said
write a method called toMilesPerHour that has one parameter
of type double with the name kilometersPerHour
and needs to return a rounded value
of the calculation of type long.
So to create the method signature, we're gonna type
public static long,
and toMilesPerHour is the name of the method,
and the parameter is of type double,
and it's called kilometersPerHour,
and we'll add our left and right curly braces
as normal for a method.
Alright, so firstly we need to check that invalid value.
And if you recall what we said that the,
if the kilometersPerHour is less than zero,
then the method, this method toMilesPerHour
needs to return a minus one to indicate that
that value that was passed to this method
was an invalid value.
Otherwise if it is positive,
we need to calculate the value of that
toMilesPerHour argument, round it and return it.
So let's start with writing the code
to test for invalid values.
So I'm going to type if, parentheses, kilometersPerHour,
closing parentheses, and we'll add a code block there,
left and right curly braces.
Actually what I'll do is I'll finish that off first.
We didn't finish the expression,
it should be less than zero.
So if it's less than zero,
then what we wanna do is
return in the next line minus one.
Alright, so that's handling the fact now
that we've got an invalid value.
Now looking back at the text,
if we go back and check that out again.
The text didn't specifically mention yet
how to convert kilometres per hour into miles per hour.
Now you could use a Google converter
to find out the conversion,
but let's first move on to the next sentence.
We're gonna scroll down a little bit,
you can see that the second step here
is to write another method called printConversion
with one parameter of type double
with the name kilometersPerHour.
Now that method shouldn't return anything.
In other words, void.
It's void and it needs to calculate the milesPerHour
from the kilometersPerHour parameter.
And you can see then it needs to print a message
in the format XX km/h = YY mi/h.
And XX represents the original value passed
to the method kilometersPerHour,
YY represents the rounded milesPerHour
from the kilometersPerHour parameter.
And we've got to test there as well
if the parameter kilometersPerHour is less than zero,
then we want to print the test or text rather Invalid Value.
And scrolling down a bit further,
we've got some examples of input and output
for that second method,
and I won't read these examples
but I certainly suggest you do that.
And moving on down a little bit further.
After that, you can see there's text and an example
of how to use the round method,
this is the Math.round method I'm talking about.
And basically Math is an in-built class
that comes with Java and enables us to
perform various mathematical calculations,
and in this scenario here, you can see how
it rounds the number 1.5,
go down and have a look at the usage there,
that's the sample usage of it,
and if we scroll down, we can see the output.
So getting the input up here of 1.5,
we can see we're defining that on line one,
and long rounded equals on line two,
and if we come down here and look at the output,
rounded equals two.
So basically what I'm saying there is we pass 1.5,
the round function will round it up to two,
3.9 is another example there,
you can see it's rounded up to four,
4.5 is rounded up to five and so on.
So we'll go back, shortly, to IntelliJ
and we'll see that in operation.
And just going down a little bit further
to read these tips here,
in the method printConversion,
call the method toMilesPerHour
instead of duplicating the code.
And we'll see that working and what that means shortly.
And as a note there,
all the methods should be defined as public static,
and you saw me define that first method like that
and that's because we've been using public static
so far in the course.
And a note here that one mile per hour is
1.609 kilometres per hour.
And finally note there,
do not add a main method to the solution code.
Alright, so this part we now know how to convert
kilometres per hour into miles per hour
and then also how to round the result.
All we have to do is
divide the parameter kilometersPerHour by 1.609.
So let's jump back now into IntelliJ
and finish the first method.
Alright, so I'm gonna come down
and add some code here on the next line.
Add some code here, I'm gonna type long milesPerHour
is equal to, and I'm gonna type Math with a capital M,
and notice you can see that's in-built to Java,
it's a Math class, for type the period or the dot,
you can see that IntelliJ has helpfully popped up
or shown a pop-up with all the available methods.
Now all these methods you can see
are built-in methods that we can use
and we know now by looking at the notes
that we wanna use the round function,
so I'm gonna type in the first few letters of round,
noting you can see that there's two versions of that,
one that accepts the float
and also one that accepts the double.
So I'm gonna select the second one
but it doesn't really matter which one you choose there.
Then within the parameters, I'm gonna type,
sorry, within the parentheses I'm gonna type
kilometersPerHour and divided by 1.609,
which is the calculation to convert kilometres
back to miles, and I'm going to close off that line,
so I'll normally do with a right parentheses
and then semi-colon.
Then I'm gonna type return milesPerHour.
Alright, so you can see that there
we're using the round method,
Math again is a class that contains many useful
mathematical methods that you can use in your code,
it's in-built and comes as part of Java,
the round method that we're using here
will round the double that we're passing into this method
and, as a note, we're saying it's gonna return a long
and we obviously define the long on line nine
and we can get a value of the Math.round function
returned into the milesPerHour variable.
So as you can see here, to call a method from another class,
we have to write the class name, in this case Math,
and then the dot method name
as we've done that on line nine.
Now you'll learn more about classes
and how you can create your own classes later in the course.
But at this point, that completes our first method.
Now, if you are eagle-eyed,
you probably noticed that IntelliJ's showing a warning
on our variable milesPerHour.
You can see it's highlighted on line nine,
if I hover over that, you can see there
it's saying that the local variable
milesPerHour is redundant.
Now, that's because we're only using this local variable
that we've defined on line nine for returning
the result of our calculation.
Instead of using a variable, we can use the return statement
right away with a calculation or an expression.
Now that will also return the result but the code is shorter
and we also don't then need a local variable.
So let's remove the variable and just use return
on the same line as the calculation and that will also,
by definition, remove this warning.
So I'm just going to delete that first part of the code
and just change that so it says return
and the next line is no longer needed,
I'm going to delete that and you can see
the warning has now disappeared.
In this case, the code will work exactly the same as before,
first the calculation or the expression is executed.
So this is the part that's,
basically, is to the right of the return keyword.
That's still gonna be calculated first,
once it's calculated, it will then
automatically be returned, whatever the value is
of that calculation to the method that
calls this toMilesPerHour method,
and you'll see that in the next video.
Alright, so that's the first method.
So I'll end the video here.
In the next video, we'll continue on
and we'll write our second method.
See you in the next video.