so let's try running this program
again i'm going to right click and run
it and as I mentioned towards the end of
the last video when we run it again we
get this sqlite error something went
wrong sqlite error or missing database
table contacts already exists so the first
time the user ran the application or
in our case we ran it we want to
create the table but the second and
subsequent times we don't want to do
that
so how do we handle this when our application
needs to create the database and tables
we don't want to drop the table every
time the application runs because the
user will lose whatever data they've
added to that table
fortunately there is another way what we
can do is we can tell sqlite to
only create the table if it doesn't
already exist by adding if not exists to
create statement so in that scenario
sqlite will only try to add a table
but the table doesn't already exist in
the database so do that we just come up
here to our create table statement and
and add....and let's just break this
into two lines which can often be a
better way of doing things....
...
I like doing that with sql statements
because it just makes it easy to read
o let's just run this and
confirmed that we don't get an error
anymore you can see the program is
exiting normally now and not
showing and error now I said that
we've broken the sql statement up
here for readability to make it easy to
read but right now we hard-coding the
sql and that isn't the best way to do
things but will hold that thought just
for a moment so now that we have a table
let's go ahead and add some data to it
now just to with the command line
when we are using sqlite
we're going to use the insert statement
but once again in Java we need to use a
statement object to make that happen and
lets just reuse the statement object
we've already got because we are able to do
that so below the
statement that executes the create
table SQL the sql we're going
to add a couple of rows I'm going to do
statement...
and the code is going to be....
...
....
so let's just run this to confirm that
it works
we've got no errors that's a good sign
we'll have a look at our db browser again
we can switch over here to the browse
data tab so click on that and you can
see it's now showing a record that fonts
rather small but size it up you
can see that it is showing that the
record has now been added to the
database and just in case you already on
that screen there's gotta refresh button
here can click on that anytime you
go back to intelliJ coming back to
here and that will refresh the view and show
the data
alright so add another two rows
here to the database back in IntelliJ
but before we go do that it's probably
good time to mention that the jdbc
connection class commits any changes we
make to the database for us immediately
after a statement is executed now will
cover the ramifications of that and what
this means in more detail in a later
video in this section of the course but
for now though understanding that
depending on which database you're
working with and what type of connection
you use sometimes you have to explicitly
commit any changes you make to the
database for those changes to persist
and if you don't commit them closing the
connection will also mean that we lose
any changes with made in other words\
they rolled back for example with the
jdbc
connection didn't commit changes for us and
after we added a row to the database and
close the connection we wouldn't see
the row when we looked at the data
table in the DB browser now the default
behavior of jdbc connection objects is
to auto commit all changes so let's
temporarily set the connection to not auto
commit changes for us what will then do
is add another row to the table by
changing the existing line of code to
use new values so after the connection
string or the connection line line
16 we're going to type...
...
alright so I've turned auto commit off
we change the values so if we run we
should find we don't get any errors
and it's finished successfully if we
swing over to the DB browser will
do a refresh note now that we're not seeing
the new records and the new record has
not been added and that's because we turned
off
auto commit by calling the connect set auto
commit method back in the code and
the connection is no longer
automatically committing changes to the
database for us now we can call a method
to commit those changes even with set
autocommit off and we'll look at
doing that in a future video but i'm
mentioning this here now in case you may
have expected the changes were making to
be rolled back because we're not
committing them in other words you've
got some experience in another database
perhaps in another language so now i'm
going to comment out the call to set auto
commit and in addition to inserting
the new jrow we're also going to add
two more row just so we got a
bit of data so go and comment on
line 17
let's copy and paste the statement
that executes that inserts the records
and leave....
....
...
ok let's just run this code now no errors
you can see there the set auto commit has now
been commented out we go back to the
browser now and now we do a refresh we
can see that the other three records are now
showing that's obviously what we want to
do
alright so inserting is working now
let's go ahead and update Jane's
telephone number using the updates
sql command as we learned to do what
previously when we were looking at the
sqlite on the command line what i'm going to
do is comment out these inserts
because we don't want those to rerun
going to do a statement....
...
...again I'm using single quotes
there for strings so that we don't have
to escape and will make it any more
complicated what it is
alright so let's just run this to make
sure that the update works no errors
will go back to DB browser to see Jane
at the moment has got...
refresh you can see the phone
numbers change to....
...so let's go ahead now
and delete Joe just before we move on
importantly again i have mentioned this
before but its vital that we use a
where clause when we want to update or
delete otherwise all the rows in our table
will be updated or deleted which won't
be what we want to happen most of the
time and I can certainly tell you of a
few stories where I've accidentally
forgotten to put a where clause and
deleted production data so always good
to check especially when you're learning
sql
have you got a where clause to make sure
you're not deleting or updating more
things and what you wanted let's
go ahead now and delete joe from the
table and can leave that existing
update in even though the phone is
already set because of the where clause
i'll just leave that in there but I
could have commented that out statement
...
...if I run again now no errors back to db
browser see joes there at the moment
refresh the joe record has now been
deleted
alright so we've seen how to add update
and delete data from the contacts table
or to or from the contacts table now
jdbc wouldn't be very useful if we
couldn't query the data of course we can
do that by using a select statement but
how do we actually process the query
result so let's go ahead and retrieve
all the data from the contacts table
using the sql statement select star
from contacts now the statement.
execute method returns a boolean that
would be true if the statement we
executed returned an instance of the
results set class and false if it
returns an update count or no results
for example when we execute an update
statement the execute method will return
false because the result of the update
statement is the number of records that
were updated now when we query the
database the method returns the records
that match the query as a result set
instance we can actually get the results
by calling the
statement . get results set method
and once we've got that we can loop
through the results so let's go ahead
and try this out going now comment out
the updates and deletes the update and
delete because we no longer need those
and let's actually now add this statement
that ultimately will get us back to
results set we're going to do....
...
....
...so in this code we call execute
to perform select ang get
results set to get the results we then
looping through each record and then
we're printing and we're about to print
out the name phone email and as you can
see we get to the value for a column by
calling the appropriate get method for
the values type string or int depending
on the which column we are working with so lets
actually run that we can see we've got
three records return there in the run
windows so that telling us that
that's worked ok now every results set
has a cursor now this cursor isn't
the same as a database cursor we could
have had several results set objects and
each one will have a cursor
however and this is actually quite
important
if you reuse a statement object to do a
query than any results set associated
with that statement object is closed and
a new one is created for the new query
so if we want to work with several query
results at the same time and it's
imperative to use a different statement
instance for each query reusing the
statement instance was ok when we're
just doing insertions updates and
deletes because we weren't using or
checking the result now we can reuse a
statement object to query but only if we
finished processing the results of one
query before we execute the next query
now keep in mind that a statement object
ultimately can only ever have one active
result set associated with it now when
the results set is created is cursor is
positioned before the first record and
so the first time we call results .
next the cursor will be moved to the
first record when we call it again the
cursor will be moved to the second
record in the result set when theirs no more
records the next method will return
false and what we call one of the result
sets get methods values returned are
those from the record at the result sets
cursors current position now we'll come
back to the resultset cursor where we
work with a database within a GUI
application note that results set is a
resource so we have to close it and you
can see that I added the results . close
on line 35 and that's because its
associated with the statement instance
we have to close it before we close the
statement now we're closing all our
resources at the end of the try block if
an exception is thrown it is possible
that the close methods won't be
executed even though some or all the other
resources have been created now for a
our small application it doesn't matter
when the database objects are destroyed
they'll do the appropriate clean up the
close method forces the closing of the
database resource immediately rather
waiting for them to be automatically
closed because of that we don't have to
close themselves but it's actually good
practice to do so then if our code
belong to a large application which
there were lots of open connections
result sets and statements would have to
be a lot more diligent about making sure
the resources were closed as soon as we
no longer needed them
alright so let's finish the video here
in the next video i want to show you an
easy way to perform queries and getting
the results
let's work on that in the next video