Alright, so at the end of the last video,
we typed in this code and
we didn't really go through
what it's all about, so
let's look at doing that now.
So we start off here, on
line 23 and we set the offset
for the first location into
a variable we can see there,
called startPointer.
Now we need to use this value
to calculate the location's record length
after we've written it to the file.
Alright, so once we've done that,
we then use the seek method on line 24
to move the file pointer to
the first location's offset.
Now we only have to do this
for the first location,
because after that, we write
all the data sequentially.
Now for each location,
you can see down here,
we're actually writing the
location ID on line 27,
the description on line
28 and also then the exits
for each location and you can
see the code for the exits,
basically, on line 30, right down here to,
finishing off, on line 37.
Now that's the same manner
that we've written them out in the past.
Now one drawback to using
the RandomAccessFile is
that we can't read, write objects.
The RandomAccessFile class
doesn't contain read object
and write object methods, unfortunately,
so it's back to writing each
piece of data individually.
Now also notice that we're
not using a buffered stream.
It wouldn't make sense when
accessing a file randomly,
because buffering is just like a cue.
What goes in first is
read or written first,
so, in other words, it's sequential.
So, RandomAccessFile can't be chained
with other types of IO classes.
Also, unlike the stream
and file classes we've previously used,
it can be used for both
reading and writing.
So when we actually write a location,
we build an exit string that
looks like the following.
This is the code here that you can see
that we've used with the string builder.
So it's basically what we're trying
to do there is something along these lines
that we're writing out.
It's gonna be direction, locationId,
direction, locationId.
So as an example of what
we'd be writing out,
it'd be something like N, one,
U, two, for north and
the location ID of one
and then up would be the location ID two.
So that's actually what
this is trying to do,
when we're actually writing that out.
Now the string ends with a trailing comma,
you might be wondering
about that on line 35,
which we don't need and if
we wanted to be diligent,
we'd not write it for the last location,
but it doesn't actually harm anything
and this space isn't a
problem for this file,
so we're not gonna check
for the last exit case
and try and remove that last comma.
Alright, so, after we've written the data
and, obviously, that is where
we're writing the exits,
on line 38.
So after we've done that, we've
come down here to this code,
starting on line 40 and we
create the IndexRecord for it.
Now the start part, for this location,
is equal to the startPointer
value and the record length on
and that's what we've got the value there,
in the IndexRecord that
we're actually passing
and the record length
is the current position
of the file pointer,
which we're getting here
with rao.getFilePointer,
but then we're deducting the startPointer,
so it's the current position
of the file pointer minus the startPointer
and we're then adding the
IndexRecord for the location,
using the location ID
as the key, on line 41
and then we update the
startPointer for the next location,
line 43.
Alright, so that's actually the code.
So at this point, we've now
written the location to the file
and we can now write our index,
'cause we've got the fullest
of indexes available.
So let's go ahead and do that now.
And the code for that'll be down here,
because we wanna make sure
that we've written out all the locations,
which we have there from the for each
that we've got on line 26.
So down here,
what we wanna do is do an rao.seek.
We're gonna seek the indexStart.
Then we're gonna do for Integer locationID
and it's gonna be index.keySet,
rao.writeInt,
locationID
and rao.WriteInt.
It's gonna be index.get locationID
dot getStartByte
and then, finally, rao.writeInt again,
index.get and it's going
to be locationID again
this time and the
pointer is dot getLength,
or the result, rather, is getLength.
Alright.
So, hopefully, you look at that code
and think it's fairly straightforward.
So we're seeking to the offset
that we've saved previously, on line 46.
So that's where we're doing the seek
and indexStart was
actually defined up here.
So we set that to the offset previously,
so we knew what that would be.
So we're going back to
that location again.
Then we're just looping
through all the index records,
using the index.keySet
and actually writing them
to the file.
Right, so let's actually
run, now, the locations.main
and actually just conform
that it actually works
and we might check out the
file that it's created as well,
just to see what that looks like.
Alright, you can see we've got
something written out there.
We've also got this locations_rand.dat,
so double-click on that.
So you can see at the
top of the file, here,
this is a part where
we're saving lots of ints.
You can see that it isn't really readable,
but, if you look down here, you can see
that we've got some strings
in the location section
that do appear to make a bit more sense
and you can see the actual exits there,
east, 12, west, 14, comma, et cetera.
So, it doesn't all make sense, but,
again, it's not a human readable file,
but you can hopefully see
the gist of what we've done
with this random file now.
Right, so let's close that down
and what we wanna do now is
change the static initializer,
so that it reads the index from the file.
So we'll go back and have a look
at our static initializer here.
Now, remember that we won't
be loading the locations
into memory anymore.
We load locations on demand.
Now what that means, is
that our locations.main
method will no longer work,
because it depends on all
the locations being loaded
into memory, so if we wanted
to run the method again,
we'd have to change the static initializer
to load all the locations, but then
that would defeat the purpose.
So, because of that, what
I'm gonna recommend here is
that, if you need to run
the locations.main again,
you copy the static initializer that uses
that buffered reader, or input stream,
from the older project into
this project's locations class
and this'll read the locations
from locations_big.txt
into the locations map.
Once you've done that,
you then comment
out the RandomAccessFile
static initializer,
run the locations main method
and then comment out the
old static initializer
and, finally, un-comment the old one
that uses the RandomAccessFile.
Now, because you may have to do that,
if something goes wrong
and you wanna write
out the locations file again,
we'll actually leave the class as is,
in terms of extending map and
declaring a locations map.
So, hopefully that makes sense.
So, if you do need to access that again,
go through the process
that I've just outlined
and that will work,
but with a bit of luck,
you won't need to do that anymore, anyway,
now that we've got it working.
Alright, so let's now write
the static initializer
that uses the RandomAccessFile.
First we have to declare a
field for the RandomAccessFile,
so let's go up and do that
and I'll declare it just
below the index, here,
that we set up, so we're gonna
call this one private static,
it's gonna be a
RandomAccessFile, call it ra.
Okay, back to our static
initializer block.
Alright, so let's go
through and type the code in
and then we'll discuss it.
Now what I'll do, is for now,
is I'm just going to
comment out the old code,
'cause probably make more sense
to see me type it from scratch.
Right, so we'll start with a try
and then we wanna catch an IOException
and we'll just print out a message,
if we happen to get an exception.
Okay and, in terms of the actual code,
we'll start with ra equals
new RandomAccessFile
and, of course, it's
gonna locations_rand.dat,
the file we just created
and rwd, for the access,
int numLocations
equals ra.readInt
and then long locationStartPoint
is equal to ra.readInt,
then we're gonna do a
while rao.getFilePointer
is less than locationStartPoint
and then int locationId
is equal to ra.readInt,
int locationStart
is equal to ra.readInt
and int locationLength
and then create our index records,
so IndexRecord,
record is equal to new IndexRecord
and the two arguments
will be locationStart
and locationLength
and index.put,
locationId and record
and that's our code.
So we open the file, as you can see here,
on line 66 and then we read
the number of locations
into a variable on line 67 and, also,
the offset of the location
section, on line 68.
Then we load the index into memory.
Now to read the index,
we're looping through,
until the file pointer
reaches the location's offset,
so we've doing the code, the while loop
that we've typed in here
and we're reading the index
and creating the records as we go
and I think that's
pretty straight forward,
as you can see there, we're
creating a new IndexRecord
and then just saving that.
So we're not actually using
the number of locations,
but it's a good practise to
write the number of records
in each file section at
the beginning of a file
that will be accessed in a random fashion.
So we might need this later on,
if we were to modify the application,
so, 'case you're wondering
why that wasn't used,
that's the reason there, so that's really
for future reference and,
again, it's good practise
to do that, in my opinion.
Alright, so at this point,
we're actually done,
we've written the static
initializer block.
Well actually, no we're not done.
Our application won't work and remember,
the way that it's currently written,
it assumes that the locations
are all available in memory,
but of course, that's
no longer true anymore.
When a player moves to a location,
we have to load that
location from the data file.
So let's start working on
that in the next video.