So, in the previous set of videos,
we had a discussion about and
learned about inheritance.
It's time now to talk about composition.
Composition is another component of
object orientated programming and
is very useful in day-to-day programming.
But just as a refresher,
I'm gonna start off and
just go over inheritance very briefly
before we move into composition.
Best way to do that would be an example,
so let's create two quick classes.
First one is going to be Vehicle.
Your Vehicle is going to be very simple,
it's going to have one field.
Private String name, and
it's going to have a constructor.
Very simple concept of the Vehicle.
Let's also create another class,
call it Car.
We're going to extend from Vehicle.
And add a couple of fields.
So the number of doors,
private int_engineCapacity.
Let's set up a constructor.
And there we go.
A very simple little example.
So, the Car extends from Vehicle.
Now it's got a is
a relationship with Vehicle.
Is a meaning that a Car is a Vehicle.
So that's the relationship
between the two.
So you can quite correctly say,
Car is a Vehicle.
And that's essentially
what inheritance is.
The composition deals with
something different, and
that deals with a has a relationship.
And the best way to do this
is to go through an example.
So let's look at
the scenario of a computer.
So our computer has a motherboard,
a case, and
a monitor, three example
things that it's got with it.
So the motherboard, the case, and
the monitor are not computers in
the same sense that a Car is a Vehicle.
But a computer has a motherboard,
a computer has a case, and
a computer has a monitor.
So that's what composition is,
is actually modeling parts, if you will,
parts of the greater whole.
So in this case we're
gonna model the computer.
And we're gonna model
the has a relationship.
So the motherboard,
the case, and the monitor.
So let's start off by actually
creating those three classes.
The motherboard, the case,
and the monitor.
So I'm going to start
with the motherboard.
New Java class, Motherboard.
We're gonna create some fields.
String model,
private String manufacturer.
That's the manufacturer
of the motherboard.
Private int the number of ramslots
that the motherboard's got.
And the number of cardslots for
video cards and so on.
And lastly, the name of the bios,
just some typical things you
would find in a motherboard.
So we're going to create
our public constructor
which will just be all the fields.
We're going to create getters for
all our fields so we don't need setters.
But what we're going to do is add one
public method which we're going to call
a loadProgram.
We're going to pass a parameter
which will be the program name.
And we're just going to
print out that "Program "
programName "is now loading...".
So that's our Motherboard class,
pretty straight forward as you can see.
Nothing particularly complicated there.
So let's now move onto our Monitor
class and create another new class.
Monitor is the name.
It's also got some fields.
We're going to start with
the private String for the model.
Private string manufacturer.
Private int size,
that'll be the size of the screen.
And let's go with another one, which
is going to be the native resolution.
And we're gonna call that
Resolution nativeResolution.
And resolution is going to be a class.
And we're gonna create
a constructor like so.
And we're gonna fix up that
Resolution class in a minute.
We're gonna create that class.
And what we're gonna here is we're
gonna create a public method.
DrawPixel at, and it's going to have an x,
y location, and let's just say a color.
And we'll just do a simple
message that says,
"Drawing pixel at " x the x y
position "in color " color.
Very simple method and then we'll
just create some guesses as well.
Just to get us for this class.
So next we need to create the Resolution
class, and with the Resolution class.
That's gonna be the native resolution,
so what is the maximum width and
height of the monitor?
How many pixels wide and
how many pixels down so to speak.
So we can go from width and height.
Let's just keep it simple there so
that would be the resolution,
constructors and some getters.
So that's our resolution.
So going back now to the monitor.
We find that error's now gone away.
So this is an early example, we're
gonna talk more about this shortly, but
this is composition.
So the resolution class
is part of a monitor, but
the monitor isn't a resolution.
But it has a resolution.
So this is what composition is.
So we're saying that the resolution
is a component of a monitor.
The monitor has a resolution,
which is the native resolution.
But more on that shortly.
So, next we need to create our class for
case.
New class, Case, and
we're going to have model
Private String manufacturer,
private String powerSupply.
And let's also have a dimensions,
Dimensions, just a new
class we're gonna create.
Just gonna be the dimensions,
the width, height, and
depth of the actual case itself.
This is the case that contains
all of the components.
And so the constructor is going to have
to accept those parameters like so.
We're gonna create a function
called pressPowerButton.
And we're just gonna add
a simple print line that
says "Power button pressed" like so.
And we'll just do our
getters as we normally do.
Okay, so we're making good progress now.
So the last thing we need to implant
before we can start seeing how some of
this works,
is of course the dimensions class.
And that's gonna have a width,
a height, and a depth.
Now let's create that.
So Dimensions.
So that'll be width,
height, and depth.
Create a constructor for
the three of them.
And let's create a getter as well.
Oops, like so.
So there's that Dimensions.
So now if I go back to
case the error goes away.
The case has got a model,
a manufacturer, and a power supply.
A case has got dimensions, so
the width and the height and the depth.
That is what the dimensions is.
So of course the case has
got all these things.
It has got a model, has got a
manufacturer, has got a power supply, and
of course it does have dimensions.
And that's what we're doing here
again with our composition is we're
actually creating something, in this case
another object, that is part of the case.
So now we get to the fun part
where we actually create
a class that is comprised of the case,
the monitor, and the motherboard.
So let's create another new class,
we're going to call that PC.
This will be our personal computer.
And instead of using extends,
we're going to type private case theCase.
I have to use the word theCase,
there by the way because if I just
type case, as you know by now,
case is actually a reserved K word so
we'll actually get an error.
So we need to put theCase, we could
call it something else but that will do.
So private Case, so our PC has got a case,
it has got a monitor.
We'll just call these monitors.
And, of course, motherboard.
Motherboard motherboard.
And we'll create our constructor
like we normally do.
This time we're creating a constructor
that's gonna accept three objects,
three different objects.
And let's create our getters as well.
So this is composition again.
So we've created a new class called PC.
It has a case so that's theCase variable
which is the field that we have defined.
It has a monitor, a field monitor,
and a field called monitor and
of course it has a motherboard.
Which is this case a field
called motherboard.
And you can see the obvious advantage
here, because if you're using the extends
option to inherit, you can only, in Java,
inherit from one class at a time.
So you could see that we
run into difficulties and
run into limitations quite quickly.
If we're using standard Java inheritance,
like we used in the last few videos,
where we can only extend from one class.
In this case, what we've said is, the PC
comprises of these three other classes,
namely the case, the monitor,
and the motherboard.
So, the PC has in this case,
is going to have the objects that
we create based off this class.
We'll have an object, case, monitor, and
motherboard in each
instance that we create.
So let's actually run some code now and
see how we would use this in reality.
So what we want to do
first is create a case,
so we can put Case theCase = new Case.
So it actually needs the model number,
so let's start with "220B".
Manufacturer, well let's use "Dell" for
want of a better name.
Power supply, we'll say "240".
And lastly it wants the dimensions.
So it actually wants to know
what the dimensions are.
So we can just type dimensions in there.
And of course what we'll need to do is
create a new dimensions class, so you put.
So the dimensions, let's go with a width
of 20, a height of 20 and a depth of 5.
That would be our case.
Weird size case but for
this example it'll be fine.
So that's our definition for a case now.
Remembering that when we create the PC,
which we're going to be doing shortly,
it needs this reference.
It needs to know what the case is and
think of that as putting a PC together.
PCs generally can't be put
together without a case so
what we're doing here is creating,
what we have done is created a case.
So next we need to create a monitor, so
Monitor, we'll call it
theMonitor = new Monitor.
And the parameters for
this one is a model so
I will call it the "27inch Beast",
manufacturer let's try "Acer".
Size we'll go 27 for 27 inch and
it also needs a nativeResolution.
And I create that, so
we need to create that class.
And let's do that a different way.
I want to show you another way
of creating a class on the fly.
If you don't need to create a variable,
you're not going to use it for
anything else,
you only want to pass it to a method.
You can just type new Resolution.
And this guy for 2540, 1440,
which is the size of my monitor.
So that's created a instance of a class
without using a variable,
which we don't need in this case.
And I'll just fix that typo,
that's monitor.
So we've now got a case and
a monitor that ultimately are gonna
be used to create our PC.
Of course, we now need a motherboard,
so let's create a motherboard.
So, motherboard.
Motherboard = new Motherboard.
We need a model.
We'll go to 200, and let's go with Asus.
Number of RAM spots,
well there's four RAM slots in this one.
Number of card slots,
let's just say there's six.
And bios, let's say it's version 2.44.
So there's our motherboard.
So now we're at the stage
where we can create our PC.
Let's put our PC together.
How do we do that?
Well we type PC, thePC =new PC.
And of course it then needs the case.
TheCase, theMonitor, and
theMotherboard are the three parameters
that will collectively make up our PC.
So we've now created the PC class by
passing those three other objects to it.
Now, of course,
you've seen in previous videos with
inheritance where we're able to use
a method name that is part of the basic
class, the super class, in other words.
But how do we get access to it?
So, for example,
if I wanna draw something using
the monitor, how do I access this method?
So of course,
we've the method drawPixelAt.
But how do we access that?
How do we access that from our PC?
Cuz of course the PC has got getters, but
it hasn't got any way to access that.
We're not overriding a method or
anything like that.
So how do we access it?
Well what we do, one way of using it,
we could type
thePC.getMonitor.drawPixelAt.
So we could do it this way, we could
say drawPixelAt 1500, 1200 in "red".
That's one way of accessing it,
so what that is,
is it's just using the getter function
from here which is returning theMonitor.
Which is the class that has already
been initialized, the object which
has been created in this class,
is returning that to the calling process.
And from there what we're using,
we're then calling the method drawPixelAt,
which is from that object that's
stored within the PC class itself,
in the PC object,
the instance that we've actually created.
And that's invoking that method for us.
So likewise we could put
thePC.getMotherboard.loadProgram.
How would we load the program,
Windows 1.0.
We're doing the same thing in there,
we're getting the class,
the object that's been created
when we created the PC class.
So we're accessing it
within the PC object and
we're getting it to call
the method loadProgram.
Which is in that object, which of course
is in the PC object that we've created.
And of course, likewise for theCase,
thePC.getTheCase.pressPowerButton.
We can do the same thing there.
So I'm accessing ultimately these
functions that are in these base classes,
theCase, theMotherboard or theMonitor,
but accessing them via thePC object.
So this is what composition is,
this is the difference than inheritance.
The PC object that we've created here,
so what we did to call the PC object was
we created our case, our monitor,
and our motherboard.
And in reality,
when you're putting a computer together,
that's what you'd be doing.
You'd go away and you'd actually buy
the case, you'd buy the monitor, and
you'd buy the motherboard, and you're
then putting it together to build the PC.
In this case, what we're doing is we're
passing these to the constructor which
essentially is getting those items and
putting them together which forms our PC.
So the PC has a case,
has a motherboard, and has a monitor.
So this is the way when you're thinking of
whether to use inheritance or composition.
Think about what you're trying to do here.
In this case, we're trying to build
a computer and we need to access the case,
the monitor, and the motherboard.
We know that things, te computer has
got a case, has got a monitor, and
has a motherboard.
And so therefore composition is probably
a great way to go but, of course,
a case by itself isn't just a computer.
A monitor isn't a computer, and of
course the motherboard isn't a computer.
They're part of a computer, but
not actually the whole computer,
which is why we're using composition
here instead of inheritance.
So I'm gonna end this video here.
We'll continue on talking about
composition in the next video.