- [Tim] Alright, so at
the end of the last video
I talked about the fact
that we need to write
two applications to demonstrate how to do
network coding.
One application's gonna be the server
and the other will be the client.
So I've created a new project here
and I've called it Echo Server.
So we're gonna start work
on the server application
and it's purpose is
just going to be to echo
back to the client whatever
text the client sends it.
So the main method in the new projects,
I'm going to start by
creating the server socket
using a try with resources statement.
Let's go ahead and do that.
(typing)
So it's gonna be server socket
from the the java.net
server socket equal new server socket
and I'm gonna use 5,000.
I'm gonna need to catch an IO xcepsn.
And we'll just do one
in e.prints (mumbles)
if we get an error
exception for some reason.
Now the port number itself,
that I've allocated here, 5000
well that can be an integer
between zero and 65,535 inclusive.
Now some port numbers are already reserved
or may already been used
by other applications.
The way to find out is
to assign a port number
and see if the socket instance
is successfully created.
Now of course, depending
on the application, you
can do some research
on the internet and find
what specific applications
or which port numbers
specific applications used
but for now we're just going to assign
the port number 5000 in our example here.
So now that we've done that,
we want the server to listen to clients
on the port that we've assigned.
So to do that, we're gonna call
the server socket.accept method
and that returns a socket instance.
And note that that's a socket instance
and not a server socket.
Now this will be the socket used
to communicate with the client.
Keep in mind that every client
that connects to a server will do so
using the same port but
through it's own socket.
So the code for that will
be the try (mumbles) block
and it's gonna be socket,
socket is equal to server socket.accept.
Now the accept method's
gonna block into a client
that connects to the server.
So to show that,
what we're gonna do is
add a print line statement
after the code to accept.
So if we do that,
we'll put client connected.
(typing)
Now if we run this,
move this down to the bottom.
We get the wording there relating
to the bug (mumbles) have
got with the current version
of the JDK but we don't see the message
client connected.
And that's because the
application which in this case
is our server is waiting for
a client to connect to it.
So, we obviously haven't got a client
a bit of code written yet
so I'm gonna have to disconnect manually
while closing down the app.
(mumbles) side.
Now when a client does connect
the server we use input and output
strings to send data to the client
and receive data from the client.
Now the socket.getinputstring
and socket.getoutputstring methods
will return the input and output strings
associated with the
server socket instance.
So let's write some code for that.
That will be after the
client connected message.
So we're do a buffered reader
input is equal to new
buffered reader and I'm gonna put a new
input string reader and it's
gonna be socket.getinputstring.
And I'm gonna do a print writer
output is equal to new print writer
and it's gonna be socket.getoutputstring
and true is the second argument.
So a common practise here
is to wrap the input string
with a buffered reader
and to string this output
string with a print writer and you can see
that I've done that on line 16 and 18.
Now the second parameter I've adhered
to the print writer constructor,
that's specifies whether you
want to automatically flush
the output string the
print writer is using.
Now if you don't specify true
then you'll have to go
with the flush method
after every string to the
right to ensure the data
is actually sent.
Alright, so now it's time to read the data
from the client.
So at this point, we can
use the buffered reader
as you normally would.
Now there's nothing special
about a buffered reader
attached to a socket.
You want the server to
remain alive until the client
doesn't need it anymore,
so this is one time
where you will actually
intensely use an Infinite loop.
So let's go ahead and write that.
So while true,
so that's our Infinite loop
and then we'll do string echo string
is equal to input.redline
and then we're gonna put
if echo string (mumbles)
to actually exit out of this
.equals exit,
then we're gonna go break
to break out of the Y loop
but then outside of that
if we're going to put output.printline
we're gonna put echo from server
pass echo string.
And we must just change this a little bit
to instead of putting a stack trace,
let's actually change that to drive.
We'll put server exception.
(mumbles) get message.
For that we'll need a stack trace.
Alright so now that we've done that
we've got our infinite
loop part on line 20.
Now within the loop we call in the
buffered reader.readline method.
Line 21.
Now when the server receives this string,
exit from the client.
We're doing a test for that on line 22.
It's gonna terminate so that's the code
that's gonna check for that
and break out of our Infinite loop.
But if it's not exit,
than what we're doing
is we are just gonna echo
the string back to the client
with a prefix echo from
server and you can see me
doing that on line 25.
And we're writing the string to the socket
using the print writer.print
method on that line.
So that's all there is to the
first version of the server.
Now we're gonna make some improvements
to this server in later videos.
But now it's actually time
to create the client application.
Now what we're gonna do here
is we're going to have two
intelli J projects open
so that we can actually
see them both running
at the same time.
So I'm going to create a new project here
File new project.
Java obviously.
And we'll create project from template.
And I'm going to call
this one Echo client.
And I'm gonna click on New Window
so I can have them both open at any time
and I can just switch
between whichever one
I wanna work with.
Okay.
Alright.
Now the main method's gonna start
in the same way that the
one for the server did
except we're gonna create a socket,
not a server socket.
So going back to our Echo server
you can see we're creating
a server socket on Line 13
but for our client programme
we're gonna do something similar
but again we're creating a socket
not a server socket.
So I'm still going to have a try in there.
Try three sources, that's gonna be socket,
socket equals new socket
jave.net and the address
is going to be local host 5000
is the port number.
And we'll send it to catch our exception.
Our exception E then we'll do,
okay.
That's what I tried to do the first time.
Then we'll do it here.
We'll just print out an error.
We'll print out to our client error
(typing)
e.getmessage.
Okay.
So difference here is
for our socket, on Line nine
we need to specify two parameters.
The address of the host
we want to connect to
and the port number.
Now if you used a local
host as you can see there
because you want to connect to a server
running on the same host,
which in this case is your computer.
Now if a local host doesn't work
you can try passing the
IP address 127.0.0.1
which is an IP address that resolves
to this computer as well
but the string, the local host is actually
an alias for the computer's
IP address as well.
So both of those should generally
work on your computer.
So we have to specify
the same port number.
Again going back to our
server right, port number 5000
we need to specify the same for our client
because that's the port
number that the server's
listing on.
So how do we know which
port number to use?
Well if you're writing by client
and the server, you'll know.
But if you're writing a client
that wants to connect to a server that
you didn't write, the
documentation for the API
you're using all the server application
you're trying to connect to
should tell you the port number that
your code has to use.
Alright, so next we
need to create the input
and output strings in the same way
we did for the server.
So let's go ahead and do that
in our try block.
So buffered reader.
(typing)
Echos, we'll call this one
is equal to new buffered reader.
That's gonna be new input string reader.
That's gonna be socket.getinputstring.
(typing)
Now we want to do a print
writer, string to echo
we'll call this one
is equal to new print writer
socket.getoutputstring
and true it's a second argument.
And that's obviously very similar.
We've got the true argument
being sent for our print writer
so it flushes the output automatically
to save us having to manually do that
every time we send the data.
Now we could hard code strings
to send to the server,
but let's actually ask
for strings instead.
So I'm gonna use the scanner to read input
from the console and
once you have the string,
we're gonna write it to the socket.
And we have to also add the check here
for the exit string.
When the user types in Exit,
that means that they want to quit.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So we're gonna start with scanner,
scanner is equal to
it's a java (mumbles) scanner
that we've used before in the course.
New scanner and system.m
we want to string the echo string.
We want another string for the response.
And this time we're gonna credit
do Y loop.
So do and we want to do our,
print out a message here.
We're gonna start by saying
enter string to be echoed.
(typing)
Okay, then when we're gonna
echo string is equal to scanner.nextline.
Now I'm gonna do string to
echo.printlineechostring.
Then we'll do our test here.
If not, echo string.equals
(typing) exit.
Now what we're going to do
when it's not exit
we're gonna do a response.response equals
echoes.readline.
And we're gonna do our print out
system out of our response.
(mumbles) and then we're gonna finish
our (mumbles) Y loop with a (mumbles)
and then print the season
not echo string.equals
exit in double quotes.
(typing)
Alright, so we're using a dual Y loop here
and that's because we want the loop
to execute at least once
because we haven't got
any idea how many times
it'll execute.
First we're asking the user for a string
and then we're sending the string
to the server.
So you can see we're asking that
for a string there for our scanner object
and then we're using the string
to echo to send that to the server
and you can just say we're using that
to print writer to do that.
The print writer object.
And after that we're just checking whether
the string equals exit.
If it does and the loop's gonna terminate
and if a string isn't,
the echo string's not equal to exit
then we're reading the dialect coming back
from the server,
then we're outputting what we got back
from the server.
And Y loop continues
until we receive an exit.
Alright, so hopefully that seems pretty
straightforward now.
We've got our server and our client
so it's now time to run both applications.
So we're gonna start
by running the E under
the echo server project.
So I'm gonna switch over to that
and I'm going to run that.
You can say that's running away now.
Now going back to our echo client project
and if you run this,
and I'll just move the output down
to the bottom.
Now we have a look at that echo server
you can say we've now got client connected
and what I might do is actually just
try and switch this so we can see
both at once.
This might be a better
way of actually doing it.
Alright, so let's actually
just stop both again
so we can see there's more in real time.
(clicking)
So going back to our server
and what I might do is just use a bit more
of that screen real estate.
And run that.
That's over there.
Now as soon as we run our client
you can see we've got client connected
appearing immediately and
probably didn't make sense
to use that screen real estate,
so I'll put it over here so I can see it
a little bit easier.
Alright, so clearly the
client's connected there
as you can see.
So I go back to the client now.
At this point the client's
connected to the server
so the accept method
in the echoserver.main
is no longer blocked.
And the code continues executing.
So we're executing this Y loop right now.
So basically it's
sitting there now waiting
on the read line line,
so Line 21 here's basically
waiting to receive
some input from the client.
So switching back to the client over here
and the string to be echoed,
and if we type in Hello, server.
And press Enter,
we've got an echo from
the server, Hello Server.
(typing)
Another Hello.
Then we're getting the
echo back from the server
again and if I type in Exit,
(typing)
you can see that both applications
have now closed.
The server closed as well as the client.
So at this point you've now written
your first client and
also your first server.
But the server you've
written isn't very useful
because it can only connect to one client.
So on the next video,
we're gonna start
modifying it so that we can
accept connexions from audible clients.
See you in the next video.