So module declaration and statements.
So let's discuss now module declaration and statements to be used.
So as we've discussed in the previous video,
each module is defined using a module declaration using the newly introduced a module keyword.
So the syntax is the following.
You can say we've got module, module name, we've got curly braces and then some module statements
in closing curly braces and optionally we've got this open modify. Now the open modify declares an open
module or in other words a module that exports all its packages to be used by reflective excess.
But more on this later when we start creating modules, so the module name is the name of the defined module
and the module name is mandatory.
We can have two modules inside the same code base with the same name and it's good practice to name
modules with the same name as packages.
And inside the curly braces we have zero or more module statements and those statements can be the export statement,
the open statement, requires statement, uses statement, or the provides statement. So the requires statement
is used to specify the module that's required by the current module.
In other words if our module depends on some other modules we have to specify it
using the require statement.
Now we can use more requires statements depending on how many modules are needed for our module.
Now the export statement is used to specify the packages that are exported by the count module.
Now the provide statement is used to specify the service implementations that the current modules provide.
Now the uses statement is used to specify the service that the current module consumes and
a point here is keep in mind that the open statement can't be used in open modules because all packages
are open in an open module.
So let's move on to the next video that we're going to discuss module types and the module path.
So see you in the next video.