So I wanna let you know that I'm currently
in the process of remastering this entire course.
So this course, firstly this is a 100% free,
the upgrade, this remastering process for you.
But what it involves is going through
each and every video,
and looking at what can be improved,
adding new things. For example adding slides,
because that was something that I got feedback on,
but also common questions and answers.
If there was any confusion in any of the videos,
I'm addressing that, I'm looking at the
questions that were asked,
and improving the content were appropriate,
and adding those answers to the videos.
So it's all about making this a better experience
for you, the student.
And if there was any confusion,
I'm looking to eliminate that in the new content.
So the is that the remastered video content
will still be substantially the same content,
but with that said, it's going to be improved,
and I guess I mentioned for the other reasons
it's going to I think be
a better experience for you.
Now I'm remastering it one section at a time.
It wouldn't work, certainly we're going through
the process and trying to do
one video at a time, because there would be
some continuity issues, flowing from one video,
into new credit content, comparing that
to the old style content.
It'll just put a bait for a confusing experience.
So the best way to get around this
is to do it one section at a time.
So what I'm doing is, as I complete
an entire section, I'm putting all the
newly remastered content for that section
in place at the same time,
at the one time, and I'll be here
sending through an announcement to mention that.
So keep that in mind, also that it is
a work in progress, and it's going to
take a while.
But if you're looking to check out
the current work in progress,
there is actually a work in progress section
at the end of the course.
So we skip on down to the end of the section,
if you want, you can early access
towards section content.
By all mean you can do that.
By all means, you can do that.
But generally though, with that said,
I would suggest you keep working through the course.
Even though some of the other content is old,
it's still 100% relevant.
I mean it may not look quite as good
because the videos are a little bit older
that the ones I'm currently working on.
But the worst thing you could do,
is stop and not actually continue studying
and wait for this new content to be released,
because this is gonna stop and impact
your journey to becoming a programmer.
So you don't need to wait for the new content,
but when the new content is there,
obviously take advantage of it,
and actually use it.
So very important there, don't get into
the trap of actually waiting for
the new content, because I mean,
it's a 77 hour course, it is going to
take a while to finish.
The other thing here just to keep in mind,
the slides for the new content is available.
There's a section at the end of the course,
which gives you the process to go
and grab the slides.
Now those slides will be a work in progress
as well, and as I complete the new sections,
there'll be a new version of the slides file
for you to grab and be able to access
on your computer.
So check that out at the end of the course,
if you're interested in that.
Other than that, as I mentioned I'll send out
announcements of progress as I make it,
as new content's released,
just so you can be kept up to date.
So make sure you got the announcements set,
so you get my educational announcements
on what content is up.
And other than that, I hope you enjoy
this new content.
See you in the next video.