- [Tim Buchalka] In Java 1.4,
a new I/O package was added
to the Java Software Development Kit.
Now they called it java.nio,
and the package was described
back then as an improvement
to Java I/O,
and that's because the classes
in the package perform I/O
in a non-blocking manner.
Now, java.nio was also
meant to fix some of
the inherent problems
developers could run into
when using the java.io classes
to work with the file system.
Now, the java.nio classes
fall into one of two buckets:
those that deal with the file system,
and also those that deal with
reading and writing data.
In this video, we're gonna
start looking at the classes
that read data from, and
write data to, a data source.
Now, when using classes
in the java.io package,
a thread will block while
it's waiting to read
or write to a stream or buffer.
However, threads using the java.nio class
or classes will not block.
In other words, they're
free to continue executing,
and consequently could
really say that Java.nio
was introduced as a
performance improvement.
That said, many developers have argued
that the java.nio package
was a step backwards,
and in fact, there's
examples on the internet
that people have shown that blocking I/O,
which is in the java.io package,
is often faster than the non-blocking I/O
in the java.nio package.
The discussion on threads,
and blocking, etc.,
is covered in the threads section
of the course, by the way,
just in case you haven't seen
that section of the course yet
and are wondering what that's all about.
Now, also working with the
java.nio class is more complex,
and you'll see that when we go through
to start writing some code.
Now, as has happened with other additions
to the java language,
many developers still prefer to write code
using the older java.io classes,
and you may very well
decide to do that as well,
but I do feel it's important
to understand the new way of doing I/O
with the java.nio package,
just in case you're ever asked
to work with code that uses it.
Now, previously, you learned
that the java.io classes
work with streams, that
is, character and binary.
Now, data is read one byte
or character at a time,
and sometimes buffered depending
on what classes are used.
Now when using java.nio,
however, you'll deal
with data in blocks,
and rather than processing a single byte
or character at a time,
one block will be processed at a time.
Now to accomplish this, you'll need
to use channels and buffers,
and you'll see what they
are and how to use those
in later videos in this
section of the course.
So with all that said about java.nio,
you can use java.nio methods
to create a java.io stream.
But, more on that later.
For now though, make a copy
of the adventure game project
that we've been working on in
this section of the course,
that we last used to
read and write the data
as an object stream.
In other words, before we
looked into Random access.
Now to save you a bit of
time, I've put a zip file,
a link to the zip file
in the resources section
of this video, of the
appropriate zip file,
for that video.
Just to save you a bit of time.
Alright, so, I've already
unzipped that particular file,
and put it on my computer,
so I'm gonna switch back now to IntelliJ,
and wipe it up, and we'll
get started with java.nio .
Alright, so I've already got the package.
I've actually unzipped it,
and I'm using the input, well,
I've actually called the
folder input/output NIO,
so I know that it's different
and distinct to the other projects.
I'm going to open that.
Here we're gonna start
making some changes to this,
to support java.nio.
Alright, so now that we've
opened that other project,
let's just quickly run it,
just to make sure that it still works.
And of course, it should do,
it should work just fine,
but it's good for us to check that.
Looking okay, so I'll exit out of that.
Alright, so now that we've done that,
let's start working with java.nio.
Now, the first thing that we're gonna do
is update the locations class,
so that it reads data from
the directions_big.txt
and locations_big.txt files.
Now these files are text
files, as you recall,
and we've done this many times now,
but you'll first run the
locations.main class,
to write out the data,
and then we'll change the
locations class static initializer
which loads the data,
where the first instance of
the locations class is created.
Then, once that's done,
we can call the main
method from the main class
to run the game.
Alright, so let's go
to our locations class,
and the first thing we're going to do
is delete the code from
the locations.main method,
so I'm just gonna delete all that out.
I'll take this comment out as well,
and then we'll get started.
So, we just start by typing Path.
That's a java.nio, what's
from the java.nio package.
And, locpath, location path
is equal to fileSystems.
And we'll talk about this
as we go through, but again,
fileSystems is another
java.nio package or class.
fileSystems.getDefault()
.getPath("locations_big.txt")
And, do the same for
directions, so dirPath
is equal to
fileSystems.getDefault() .getPath
This time it's gonna be
("directions_big.txt").
Then we oughta try with
resources, so that's gonna be
Try (BufferedWriter
locFile
equals Files
dot
newBufferedWriter
(dirPath)
And then the second one is going to be...
Actually that should be
locpath, the first one.
Using both the files, so we need
to have a BufferedWriter set up for both,
so
BufferedWriter
dirFiles
is equal to Files.newBufferedWriter,
that's gonna be (dirPath), this time.
Then we're going to go through,
and loop through all the locations,
so for(Location :
location
location.values())
Then locFile
dot
write
and it's going to be location,
so we location it,
and everyone else is going to be location
dot
getLocationID,
we're writing that out, plus
comma
plus
the location desriptions,
so location.getDescription,
and now, add an end of line
character to the end of that.
Slash end.
And the arrow we're getting
at the moment is a topper,
it should've been one there.
One right parentheses, not two.
Let's fix that up.
And, then we're gonna go through all
the directions of the exits.
So for(String direction
Hold on, this time it's gonna
be location.getExits().keySet
Then, we're gonna do a test
to make sure it's not
the default location,
so if( !direction
dot
equalsIgnoreCase("Q")).
Then we've gotta do a dirFile.write.
Then we're going to
write the location of it,
so location.getLocationID + ","
+ direction + ","
Plus, we'll just go to
a new line for this;
that's gonna be
location.getExits().getDirection,
and then we're gonna do
an end of line character.
Now that should be it, and
then we just need our catch.
We're just gonna catch an IR Exception.
And if we happen to get an error,
we've just gotta print out the message.
IRException
e.getMessage.
Alright, now what I'm going to do
is just paste in the code that we used
when we read the file using the java.io,
that BufferedReader, just so
we can see the difference,
even though we ultimately
aren't gonna use that,
I'm just going to include
everything but the final catch,
so this is what we did.
Even though it's at a
different indent level,
we should still be able to
get the gist of it here,
so we're comparing the
code starting at line 22,
to the code that's starting on line 35.
So, all that's really changed
is the way that we create
the BufferedWriter.
Instead of creating one directly,
by calling the BufferedWriter constructor,
which we've done here on line 35 and 36,
we're using the java.nio.file
class to create the instance.
Here's Files here,
files.newBufferedReader(locpath),
on line 22, and same for line 23.
So the Files.newBufferedWriter method
accepts a java.nio.path instance,
and we obviously declared
those a path instance
on line 20 and 21, locpath and dirpath.
Now, we are gonna look at the Path
and the fileSystems classes
in more depth later,
when you learn how to
work with the fileSystem.
For now, just understand
that the Path class
is meant as a replacement
for the File class,
so it's a more robust class when it comes
to working with files.
Now classes in the java.nio package work
with path instances,
and not file instances.
It's recommended practise
to work with the Path class
if using java.nio wherever possible.
Now sometimes you will
have to use the file class.
That's because the method or constructor
wants to file instance as a parameter,
but when you do have a choice,
make sure you use path over file.
So, creating a BufferedWriter this way
creates a writer that uses
java.nio to do its output.
Now remember that the BufferedWriter
reps another I/O class,
So when we use the Files
stuck to a new BufferedWriter,
here on line 22 and line 23,
a BufferedWriter is
returned that performs I/O
using an instance of the java.nio
class called bytechannel,
and you'll learn more about channels later
in this section of the course.
So let's get rid of that extra code
that I copied and pasted in.
Clean this up a little bit.
Alright, so what we can do now,
is we can actually run this class,
or run this method rather, locations.main.
You can see that it's seemed
to have processed something.
If you have a look at the files,
they're still pretty much,
I'm sorry, directions_big was one of them,
and also locations_big.
Now, the two files, they're pretty much
like they were before.
The situation is the same
when reading from a stream,
so what we will do now
is we're gonna update
the static initializer so that it uses the
files.newBufferedReader method
to create the BufferedReader.
The actual method will
want a path instance.
Looking at our static intializer,
I'm just gonna delete all that code out.
I'm gonna start again.
So we wanna have two paths,
and they're gonna be pretty
much the same as they were
prior to us changing the code
here, or after, I should say.
We have those two paths again,
then we're gonna do a try,
(Scanner scanner = new
scanner(files.newBufferedReader
We're gonna start with locpath.
We're gonna accept that input.
We're getting a java.io.IOException,
we'll look at that shortly.
So this scanner.usedelimiter(","),
let's mix this up a little bit.
What I was trying to do there
was a Try with resources,
so I fix it up like that,
tab that over, and put
another right curly brace.
We've still got our IOException
that we need to fix.
So, we've specified that the scanner
is gonna use the delimiter of a comma.
We're gonna go through now,
so do while(scanner.hasNextLine).
Int loc = scanner.nextInt.
Scanner.skip, and we'll be
talking about this shortly.
Scanner.delimiter.
String description = scanner.nextline.
Then you're gonna print it out,
and we'll type it out as
imported location + loc + ":"
+ description, starting to
see some output on the screen.
Then we're gonna do
locations.put(loc new Location
It's loc and description
as the two parameters.
Then we need to put a null there,
and that's because our code at the moment,
if we look at our constructor,
we talked about this previously,
it's got the code built in
to test to see whether null's passed,
and it's going to create a new
LinkedHashMap for our exits if it has,
otherwise it will just decide the value,
or save the map if one
was sent to this method,
but in our case, that's not happening,
because we're not passing that,
so we go back to our locations code,
leaving this null,
and what we still need to do,
is just finish this off,
so we got at least code
catching some errors.
IOException e, then we're
just gonna e.printStackTrace.
So what I'll do is, I'll
finish the video here now.
When we come back, we'll
actually add the code,
using the Files new BufferedReader,
and this time we're going to
add it for the directions,
i.e. the exits, and
actually add those as well,
so I'll see you in the next video.