All right so it's now time to talk about
something called the Ternary Operator.
So what I'm gonna do is come back here
and undo the latest change that I had for isCar,
so that we are testing to see whether it's true.
But now what I wanna do is below that code,
I'm going to type boolean wasCar equals
I'm gonna type isCar, space, question mark,
space, true, colon, false.
So this is a case where we've got three operands.
Now incidentally the Ternary Operator
refers to the fact that the operator takes three operands.
So the first operand is the condition we're testing
which should evaluate as all conditions to true or false.
So the second operand is the value to assign to wasCar
if the first condition was true
and the third operand is what to assign to wasCar
if the first operand condition was false.
Now the first condition could be a lot more complex
than what we currently have but
if we add some code now and type if parenthesis wasCar
and a code block and we'll put some output
in the code block wasCar as true.
If you run this...
...you can see we've got the output This is true,
but we haven't got the output for wasCar equals true
and what's happened there is with testing here, wasCar,
basically what we're saying is isCar equal to true?
If it is and when I set our wasCar variable to true
otherwise set to false so because on line 72
we've defined isCar as false therefore wasCar
was assigned as false and we didn't see the output.
If you come back and instead below that
I'm going to type isCar equals true
and now if you run the code again...
...this time we've got no difference
of the code and that's because I put that in the wrong place
obviously that should've been before
the boolean because that point in the code,
it tests the value and obviously by assigning isCar
after the fact we didn't see any result
but now if we do this we should see the wasCar output.
And there it is - wasCar equals true.
All right so the ternary operator -
so confirming the ternary operator
is a shortcut to assigning one of two values
to a variable depending on a given condition.
So think about if the shortcut
of the if-then-else statement,
and of course we haven't discussed else at this point
of the course but we will be discussing that later.
So consider this example - int ageOfClient equals 20
boolean isEighteenOrOver equals ageOfClient
equals equals 20 question mark true colon false.
So operand one - ageOfClient is equal to 20,
we're using the equals to operator,
so that's the condition we're checking for
and that condition, remember, needs to return true or false.
Operand two - true here is the value to assign
to the variable isEighteenOrOver
if the condition in operand one is true.
In operand three, which is assigned to false,
that's the value that's going to be assigned
to the variable isEighteenOrOver
if the condition in operand one was false.
Now in this particular case isEighteenOrOver
is assigned the value true and
that's because the age of the client has the value 20
and our condition for operand one ageOfClient is equal
to 20 returns true.
Now it can be a good idea to use parentheses
like this example below to make the code more readable
particularly in the ternary operator.
So boolean isEighteenOrOver equals,
we can just put in the condition for operand one
equal to 20 in parentheses to make it clear.
All right so let's end the video here.
I want to talk a little bit more
about operators and a bit of a summary
and then we're going to get into a challenge
and talk a bit about operator precedence
and all of that's coming up in the next video.