alright so let's take a look at how we
can work with background threads in the
UI applications now with the javafx
section of this course we took a look at
the javafx.concurrent package when
working with threads in a UI
application this is the go-to package to
use when we want to perform a background
task we use a class that implements the
worker interface or a class that extends
the task class let's take a look at
extending the task class now the task
class implements the runnable interface
and we can use task objects whenever or
wherever we use runnable objects so
let's start by creating a new javafx
project so i'm gonna click
on create new project going to select
javafx next and let's call this
one task example and get that started so
what we're going to do here is we're
going to simulate fetching data from a
database on a background thread which is
a common situation in a UI application
another example would be fetching data
from the internet so we'll get that data
on a background thread using a task so
the first thing we need to do then is
create an anonymous task object we need
to access the task within the controller
so if the simplicity we're going to
create it in the controller java
file
let's go ahead and do that and we've got
that open as you can see there and what
we'll do is set up and will need a need
to add a method in this class called
initialize and we need to create the
task within that if you recall the
initialize method is run whenever the
controller instance is created we went
through that in detail in the javafx
section
alright so let's get started....
and if some of this is not making sense or you want to know more about
javafx do go back and check out the
javafx section it might actually be
worthwhile to go back and look at that
and before going through this examples
particularly if something its not making sense
so we are defining our task first and let's
create our public void initialize method
which is used by javafx to initialize
and then want to initialize a task a
task.....and you can see by
doing that I managed to get it to create
a lot of this code for us come down here and put a semicolon to make it
valid to close the statement off and the
idea there is that when creating a
class that extends task we have to
override the call method and that's
obviously I did their now let's suppose that we are
fetching a list of employee names so
we're going to return the list as an
observable list of strings you can see
that we got the return type defined in their
the call method and so we've specified
that return type and declaring the task
variable so obviously when we got
IntelliJ to generate the code for us it
knew based on what I've typed in here
under the Declaration of tasks that it need
to return that observable list of string
objects
alright so inside the call method we
need to perform the background task
itself so we're going to put some code
in there i'm going to delete this null
return null statement first I'm going to
get it to sleep so...
...then we'll
just return...
....and what I'll do
is type some names...
....so I'll pretend
database query is going to return six
records and as you saw on line 15 we have
introduced a sleep for one second and
that's simulating simulating the
database fetch and we need to make sure
that any of our imports or the javafx
varieties in other words if you're
getting any errors here most likely its
because the javafx wasn't used in the
import so do check your import lines
if you are getting errors now notice that
we are throwing exception from the call
method here on line 14 now we do so
because the thread.sleep method can
actually throw and interrupted exception
now rather than using a try-catch block
we just throwing the exception from the
method to keep the example code simple
but in a real world application you'd
probably want catch that
error and do something with it
alright so next we need to start this
thread from the user interface now in the
sample.fxml file that comes with all
the javafx projects we need to add a
button its going to start the task when
that button is pressed lets just go and open
it up and grab that file or at least open
it so we can work on it...
and we'll add the button so within the grid pane
we're going to do a....
...that will be the method that
is executed and its in red because we
haven't written it yet and....
....
....so next
we need to add this action listener that
we just defined here on line 8 into
our controller going to add
this down here underneath the initialize
method
its going to be....
we need to annotate that as we need to
do for FXML.....and if
you go back and look at our sample now
notice that that's now change color
because it's now linked it to this code
here and in terms of what we're going to
do to process this what actually
need to take after the button is clicked
we're going to do a new thread and
task
and we defined
the task on line 10 and then we've actually
put what's going to happen what's gonna
happen in terms of functionality in our task when we defined that in the
initialize method we're going to pass
or do a new thread task.start to
start the thread
alright so let's actually just run this
alright so I just press the get employee names
button now looks like nothing happened
but in fact the task did run but we need
to show the employee named in the user
interface but recall that we can only
access UI controls on the main thread
the javafx applications thread that is
because the controls themselves aren't
thread-safe now rather than making them
thread-safe javafx enforces the
rule that all code that touches the user
interface must run on the javafx
application thread that way threads
can't interfere with each other when
they're updating or when updating the UI
component so how do we update the UI with the results of a task we ran on
a background thread
well it's actually a couple of ways to
we can do this let's go back we're going
to close down the program first let's go
back to our fxml file just close down the
run window so let's add a list
view which will display the list of
employee names so below the button it's
going to be....
....
......we need to reference
the listview in the controller so i'm
going to set its fx ID...we are going to set that equal to listview so
that we can update that and reference that as I mentioned in code so let's just run this
to make sure that we can see the listview first okay i can expand the window
if we need to expand the window to make
it larger you can see we can clearly see
the listview there so that's good well
close it down so we have to increase the
height and the length of the window to
see the entire listview as you saw me do now  we
could increase the height when we create
this scene but i'll leave that as an
exercise for you to look at later since
we've worked on code similar to that in
the javafx section in any event since
there's only six items we won't need to
increase the height very much to see them
all anyway
alright so going back to the controller
we need to define the listview we are going
define it up here below the task we've
implemented on line we've defined on line
10 and the do....making sure the names are the same
and I'll import that making sure that i
select the javafx.seen and not
the javafx.swing and we need
to annotate that and fxml make sure that
that's valid and it links correctly so now
that we've done that we can update the
list view by using the platform.run
later method now this method accepts
runnable accept a runnable and runs it
on the UI thread now our task is a
runnable but we don't want to run our
task on the UI thread we want to update
the list view when the tasks complete
will call run later when the task wakes
up from sleeping will have to create our
observable list earlier rather than the
return statement so that we can use it
to set the listview let's change the
code a little bit here instead of
doing a return there
we're going to do observable list....
...
and what we had defined their previously
then after that we're going to do is do
a platform.....like
so and you can see that IntelliJ
helpfully added the extra code for us
and the code that we want to run it will
be listview....but
also what I need to do is put a
return.....because we've gotta
some data that needs to be returned so
put that in there
alright so let's run this and see
whether it works I'm just gonna expand
this in preparation and click on get
employee names you can see that there
was a delay their over a second then the
listview got updated so you might be
wondering why we're returning the list
from the task this is the line that i
added just before we ran it on line 38
since we're updating the list view from
the task we don't have to return the
list when we use performed.runlater
to update the UI but we do need to
return it for the second way that
we can update the UI from a task so
while we can use platform.runlater to
update the UI it's not good practice to
tie a task to the UI in this way if we
have a change the UI would also have to
change the task so in general the UI
code and the code that processes data
should be kept separate so there's a
better way to update the list view and
this is the recommended way to do it
so instead of using platform.run
later we can use what's called data
binding so the task class is a property
called value which is the value returned
by the task in our example it would be
the observable list of strings the list
view control has a property called items
and that contains the items that the
list view is displaying what we're going
to do is bind the items property in the
tasks value property whatever the value
property changes the items property will
update
accordingly we no longer have to
explicitly update the list view by
calling platform.runlater so lets give
that a go so I'm just going to close
this down the run window again so
basically all this code here remains the
same right until the end of the
Declaration what we then do is remove
this platform.runlater so we're going to
be doing that anymore and then below
afterward we defined the task we do.....
we're going to bind task.value
property as you can see so after
declaring the task we bind the list
views items property to the tasks value
property can see that on line 34 so lets
run the codes to check that it
works you can see there was a pause
there after a while and then it did
actually work we saw that the employee
names appear in the list view so great
so we're performing a long-running task
on a background thread and updating the
task on the UI thread better yet the
task doesn't know anything about the UI
all it's doing is returning a list of
names and it doesn't actually care what
happens to it after that
so a list can be written to a file display
it on the screen printed to the console
or used for something else
it actually doesn't matter to the task
code and it's not tied to the UI now in
any way so we can do other things with
tasks such as passing parameters to them
and executing code when they completed
if you're interested you can what
you can do with tasks you can read more
about the task documentation here i'm
just going to quickly bring that up in
a browser
so there's a link which will be in the
resources section so you can find out a
lot more information at that link if you
so desire
alright so the application is working
fine but we're going to actually look at
enchaining this in the next video
let's just imagine that it takes 10
seconds to fetch a large group of
records from a slow database would be
great to have a progress bar so that we
can see that something's working in that
the updates happening
let's look at implementing that in the
next video