Well so let's have a look at a
useful web page on Oracle's website
to give you a summary of the operators
as we've discussed in this section of the course.
So we're gonna go to a web browser
and we're just gonna do a search for
summary of operators Java.
So the link is in the resources section of this video
and the one we want down here is the second one
summary of operators and it's the
docs.oracle.com link we want, so I'm gonna click on that
and this will give us a handy list of the operators
that are available in Java
and you can see we pretty well
talked about all of those operators now.
One that we haven't talked about at this stage
lets scroll down and have a look
is the Type Comparison the instanceof
and there's a reason for that
and that's because that really needs you
to understand the concept of classes
so we'll be talking more about instanceof
when we get to the stage of
working on classes in the course.
And the other ones are the Bitwise and Bit Shift Operators
these are ones that are very rarely used in Java
the important ones are the conditional operators
conditional AND and conditional OR
which we've talked about at length in this course.
So I say it's a handy list, I suggest you
access that if you want to find out more information
but you can see that we've pretty well come through
and dealt with most of these
as we've gone through the course.
Alright, next I want to go back
and I'm gonna open a new tab here
and I'm gonna do a search for java operator precedence table
and this first link here, this cs.bilkent.edu.tr
we click on that.
That gives us a handy list of the precedence table in Java.
So what that means is it shows you
how Java decides the priority
of evaluating things in an expression.
So note for example that the highest precedence, 15
has parentheses and that's so therefore
that's a way to ensure that your condition
overrides standard precedence rules
for things like you see, in say precedence 12
which is multiplication, division and modulus
and precedence 11, which is addition and subtraction.
So a bit of a hint there to keep that in mind
when you get to the stage of
solving the challenge which I'm gonna talk about.
So you can see that multiplication, division
and the modulus, the remainder operator
have a higher precedence than do addition and subtraction
and that means that you may not get the results you expect
using those operators depending on
the precedence and the order that you're doing things.
Now for now keep in mind
that you can use parentheses to override other things
like multiplication and sort of to force
the condition to be evaluated
in the order that you think it would be.
So this is one reason why it's often
a good idea to put parentheses around conditions.
And if you get stuck come back and refer to this table
when you're going through the challenge
and I'll actually, my solution to the challenge
I'll be talking more about operator precedence.
Alright so let's test what you've learnt about operators
with this operator challenge.
There's seven steps to go through this challenge
so you might want to have this video paused on this section
while you're going through and refer back to this
as you're completing the challenge.
Step number one is to create a double variable
with a value of 20.00.
Step two create a second variable of type double
with a value 80.00.
Step three is to add both numbers together
then multiply by 100.00.
Step 4 use the remainder operator
to figure out what the remainder
from the result of the operation in step three and 40.00 is.
Now we have used the modulus
or remainder operator on ints in this course
but I'm confirming here
you can also do the same for double
a variable of type double.
Step 5 create a boolean variable
that assigns the value true
if the remainder in step four is 0.00
or false if it's not zero.
Step 6 output the boolean variable
just to see what the result is
and step seven write an if-then statement
that displays a message 'got some remainder'
if the boolean in step five is not true.
Don't be surprised if you see output for this step
where you may expect it not to show
I'll explain that in my solution.
So pause the video and try it out
and come back and I'll go through my solution
and I'm gonna show you your potential issue
you may come across with operator precedence
in my solution as well as I'm sort of
giving the game away a little bit there
but see how you go, pause the video now
and I'll see you when you get back.
Alright so welcome back
hopefully you managed to finish the challenge
or get a lot of it done.
So let's step back over to our code again
and start solving the challenge.
Firstly we're gonna type double myFirstValue
which is my first variable, we assign that to 20.00
and we'll put a d on the end, just to be specific
and for the second variable, it was my second value
will be what I'm calling it
but of course this can be anything you like
we assign that to the value of 80.00.
As step three called for us
to add both numbers together and multiply them by 100
so let's do that, I'm gonna type double
I'll call this one myValuesTotal
is equal to myFirstValue plus mySecondValue
multiplied by 100.00.
Alright so step four we need to calculate the remainder
that's gonna be double theRemainder
is equal to myValuesTotal
we use the remainder or modulus operator
so it's the percent sign and was 40.00d
and this is what I'll do there on
add a line after the myValuesTotal definition
let's just print out the value.
So we say myValuesTotal is equal to plus myValuesTotal.
Right so theRemainder let's also print that out
I'm not sure whether I told you to do that
I don't think I told you to do that
but it doesn't hurt to print these things out
whether you did or not doesn't matter
so theRemainder is equal to plus theRemainder.
Right so moving on next we need to create a boolean variable
that is true if the remainder was 0 or false otherwise
we're using the ternary operator
you didn't have to use a ternary operator
but hopefully the hint there was to use it
because we just talked about it in the last video.
So boolean isNoRemainder is equal to
and in parentheses, which were optional
theRemainder is equal to zero
we're using the equals to operator not this hamon operator
then we put a question mark and our true answer
the value we want signed, in other words
if the expression the remainder is equal to 0 is true
a colon, false if it's not equal to 0.
And then we're going to print that out
isNoRemainder equals plus isNoRemainder
alright go down that a bit so you can see it
and the last thing I'm gonna do is do an if-then statement
if parentheses, I wanted to test if the
boolean we've defined on line 89--
So you could do that a number of ways
I'm just going to use the not operator
bearing in mind we can do it a few other ways
any of those ways is valid
so long as it's actually successfully testing for false.
So if it's not isNoRemainder
so we're testing to see whether it's false
we're gonna print out a message if it's false
got some remainder, alright so that's our challenge
or that's my challenge solution.
Right so looking at the code
we've got our assignment of 20 on line 83
and 80 on line 84, so line 85 we've got
FirstValue plus mySecondValue
so it's 20 plus 80, is 100.00
multiplied by 100.00
that should give us the answer 10,000 right?
So therefore the remainder 10,000 divided by 40
which we're testing on line 87
should give us no remainder
because 40 goes into 10,000 exactly 250 times.
So technically if we run this code we should see
myValuesTotal set to 10,000
we should see theRemainder set to zero
we should see isNoRemainder set to true
and then the if-then statement on line 91
shouldn't be executed because there isn't any remainder
and what we're returning was assigning the value true
to our variable if there isn't any remainder.
Alright so let's run this and see what happens
and we'll just put this low window up a bit
so you can see a bit more
so what's actually happened there was
myValuesTotal printing 8,020 and we got 20 as remainder
and therefore our isNoRemainder was set to false
so pretty well looking at the code
what we thought wouldn't happen has actually happened
so why is that doing what it's doing?
Well this is operator precedence in action
and this is the reason that I've coded it this way
to give you an example of it.
So firstly we go back to our operator precedence table again
let's have a quick look at that again.
So I did hint at this a bit, note that multiplication
has a higher precedence than addition
so what is actually happening if we go back to the code
so the code on line 85, what's happening there
is that mySecondValues which is value 80
has been multiplied by 100 first
so Java has evaluated that
and looked at the multiplication operator
and decided that okay I need to calculate that first
so it's defined mySecondValue times 100 to be 8,000.
After it's finished the multiplication
it's added 20 to that, which is the value for myFirstValue
and 8,000 plus 20 is 8,020, so that's the reason
why we didn't get the results that we thought we might get.
What we wanted to do was get 20 plus 80
is 100, times 100 equals 10,000.
And by doing that we should probably get no remainder
and the message won't be output down the bottom
and this is why we can use parentheses here
to clarify the meaning, parentheses around
myFirstValue plus mySecondValue and we know that
parentheses have got a higher precedence than multiplication
so that's going to be evaluated first now
the result of that will be then multiplied by 100.00.
So if we run this again
you can see now we've correctly got
myValuesTotal equals 10,000
theRemainder set or has the value of 0
because 40 goes into 10,000 exactly 250 times
leaving no remainder.
The isNoRemainder variable was set to true
because there's no remainder
and consequently we now no longer get the output
got some remainder.
Alright so now it's working as it should.
Alright so that's the challenge completed
hopefully you managed to complete that
and if you had or did run into difficulties
because of the operator precedence
hopefully you now understand
why it's important to use parentheses
or to code expressions in a specific order
knowing that they're gonna be evaluated
with the precedence table that I've shown you.
Alright so that's this video and challenge completed
and in fact that's the entire section now done and dusted.
What we'll do is we'll have a quick summary
of what we've actually achieved in the next video
and just a reminder that you can grab
the slides for all the videos
with a handy PDF format that you can review
by checking out the lecture at the end of this course.
So I'll see you in the next video.