All righty, so this is the end of the section.
Now it's a summary.
We went through quite a bit in this section of the course.
We looked at Java keywords.
We looked at code blocks.
We looked at variables, primitive types.
We looked at expressions.
We looked at operators and operands,
the ternary operator, the if-then statement,
and a whole lot more.
So we really covered quite a bit of ground,
and this is the fundamental,
sort of building block section of the course.
From here, we'll take the basic knowledge
that we've gathered in this section
and move on to more complex stuff.
Now, if you're stuck in any video
in this section of the course,
don't be afraid to go back and rewatch the video again.
I would suggest that when any time anything's unclear,
there's no shame in going back
and watching a video the second time.
Look, use the analogy of watching a video.
If you're like me and you watch a video, a movie rather,
for the second time, you generally will pick up things
that you missed at the first time you watched the video.
The same is true with training.
If somebody's not quite clear,
just rewatching the video again, retyping the code,
will make things clear, so don't rush.
Again, this is not a competition
to get to the end of the course as quickly as possible.
The goal is for you to learn Java so that hopefully,
you can become a productive Java programmer
and earn some good money in the meantime.
So keep at it.
Well, now time to move on to the next section.
We'll get into the next level of Java code
and build on the concepts that we've been through
in this section of the course.
So, see you in the next section.