- Alright, one thing to
keep in mind as I mentioned
at the end of the last
video, is when you use
absolute indices, the buffer
position isn't updated.
So for example when
you used this code here
on line 46 and 49, when
we used end buffer dot get
into zero, that is, to read an integer
after the method call, the
buffer position remained
wherever it was before the call.
So to demonstrate this, we're
going to change the code
to flip the buffer, then do
an absolute read and
then do a relative read.
So let's make a change
to that code slightly.
So going to flip which is
going to remain the same
and we're going to readintbuffer
and we're going to go to the next line
and print out end buffer
dot get as per normal,
do another flip, and go
straight into another read.
And here we're going to do another flip.
So end buffer dot flip and
we're going to print out
using the get indices
zero there, but then also
after that we're going to do a print-out
and might as well reformat this document.
End buffer dot getint, like so.
Right, so if we just run this
you can see the results down the bottom.
So we're now reading the second integer
from the buffer twice.
So after the second channel dot recall,
we flip the buffer and
that sets the position
back to zero, and then
we're doing an absolute read
and then a relative read.
So we're doing the flip here,
we're doing the absolute read here,
along 50 and then along 51 we're doing
the relative read.
And you can see down the bottom in terms
of results, we get the
negative integer 98765
printed twice.
And if the absolute read had
changed the buffer's position
then we would have gotten
a Java.nio.underflow error
as you'd seen before,
because the buffer's position
would have been pointing
to the end of the buffer
after the absolute read.
But an absolute read doesn't change
the buffer's position and that's why
the relative read on line
51 actually succeeds.
So I hope by now you can see that mixing
relative and absolute
reads could very quickly
become error prone.
So as I said earlier in the last video,
be consistent in your approach.
I suggest you do it one way or the other.
Mixing them up would make your code
a nightmare to maintain or at least
potentially make it a nightmare.
Alright, in terms of the
examples we're using here
at the moment we've
reused existing buffers.
Now of course we could also
have allocated new buffers
using the bytebuffer allocate method
and if you come up here to have a look
you can see we were using that when
we were retrieving our integer parts
we used bytebuffer.allocate on line 21.
But let's do that for
actually reading the string.
At the moment you can see on line 17
we're using bytebuffer.wrap for the string
so let's change that to use
the allocate method instead.
So what we're going to
do is change the call
on line 17 from bytebuffer.wrap to
bytebuffer.allocate and this time
it's looking for the link
or the capacity I should say
of the buffer so we need to pass in
the link of the byte array
so we use .link after outputbytes.
The other thing we want to do after that
is use a buffer.put and
now outputbytes, like so.
So again here instead
of using the wrap method
and passing a byte array we changed this
to line 17 to allocate a buffer
and after we've allocated
the buffer based on the
link on line 18, we're
using the put method
to copy the contents of the output bytes,
byte array into the buffer.
So it's important to remember that when we
use the wrap method, the byte array
parse method is used as the byte array
that backs the buffer.
But that is clearly not happening here.
Instead when we use bytebuffer.allocate,
as you can see on line 17,
a new byte array is created
and that's used to back the buffer.
Now earlier when we
used the buffer created
by wrap to read the
string, the output bytes
byte array was updated
because it backed the buffer.
That won't be the case
anymore as you'll see
in a minute.
So let's actually run the code based on
what we've changed to see what happens.
And you can see here what happened.
Firstly the byte buffer looks like it has
some random characters there.
But also we got an exception,
java.lang.outofboundsexception.
If we click on the line number down here
where it's crashed, we
can see it's crashed
right down here and it's an
index outofboundsexception.
So based on the code that we've added,
obviously that has caused it to crash
because it was working prior to us using
the allocate and the put,
so this is a mini-challenge for you
to try to figure out what's gone wrong.
Now you should be able to figure out
what has happened and fix that code,
so you don't get an exception.
So I'm just going to pause the video now.
How about going to see whether you can fix
that problem and stop the exception,
the indexoutofboundsexception, and
I'll see you when you get back.
Alright, so how did you go?
Hopefully you worked it out.
I want to give you a mantra with
fixing errors with java.nio.
So learn this mantra,
learn it, and keep it,
just don't forget it!
The mantra is, "When
something goes wrong, flip."
So the above code isn't
flipping the buffer.
The code that's after line 18 is not
actually flipping the buffer
between read and write.
Recall the put method on line 18,
reroute it to the buffer,
and when we call
binchannel.write, line 20,
you're reading from the buffer, but
you have to flip between
those two actions.
That's actually the issue here.
So if we come back here
after the buffer.put
and we add a...
Well I'll just put it down
here just to clear it,
it doesn't really matter,
buffer.flip.
But if you put the call
there, run the code again,
and this time we get the correct results.
Alright, so now it's time
to read the string back in.
Now the way we're doing
it right now is fine
because we're calling the
byte buffer.array method
to get the byte array back in the buffer
and if you come down
and have a look at it,
this is the code right
here, bytebuffer equals
on line 43.
Bytebuffer array is again
the method we're calling
to get the byte array back in the buffer.
Now when you're using the wrap method
to route the string,
we didn't have to call
the array method because
the output bytes array
was backing the buffer, but
now that we're not using
the wrap method, that's
no longer the case.
So just to demonstrate that
we're going to temporarily
change the code to print
out the output bytes array
instead of the one we get
from this array method call
here on line 43.
So let's comment that out temporarily,
instead replace that with output and
it's going to byte buffer equals plus and
then we'll actually add new string and
it will be our output bytes array.
So if we try running that,
notice the output ablo world,
so the problem here is
since the output string
isn't backing the buffer anymore
the first two characters
you set aren't overwritten
when you use the buffer to read the string
from the file.
So we'll be using that code on line 41.
So far you've been reading and writing
variables individually.
You write a single variable to the buffer
and then you write the
buffer to the channel,
and often you'll want
to write a bunch of data
to the buffer before writing
the buffer to the channel
or read a bunch of data into the buffer
before pulling data from it.
So let's actually update
the code, so that it reads
and writes all three values,
that is the string in two integers
in the one shot.
Now we're going to start
with writing the data
since we are doing that in
the first method at the top.
In addition to the data
that we're already writing,
we're going to write
another string an integer.
Now you can delete or
comment out the existing code
in the main method, let's actually do that
and we'll basically start from scratch and
go through it all.
Just before I do that
let me line comment that
and comment out that other one, in case
we need to refer to this code later.
So what I'm going to do
is just keep literally
that first line, the
output bytes hello world
and I'm going to comment
everything else out.
Absolutely everything
out, as you can see there,
all commented out, so
we've got nothing in there
other than the try and catch
and this first line here.
So we got our byte array, output bytes,
is going to contain a string to output,
but before that we're
going to create a buffer.
So we're going to do
bytebuffer, we'll call it buffer
is equal to bytebuffer.allocate and we'll
allocate a hundred.
Then we got to mention our
byte array output bytes.
Let's go ahead now and output some stuff,
so buffer.put outputbytes,
and we can do buffer.putint245
and we can do buffer.putintin
negative 98765.
Then what we'll do is
write that extra string
as I mentioned.
So another byte array,
we'll call this one outputbytes2 equals
"Nice to meet you" in
double quotes .getbytes.
So there's that byte array
and let's print that out or write that out
so buffer.put outputbytes2
and let's put another
number on the end there,
so buffer.putint2000
buffer.flip then binchannel.writebuffer.
Okay, a few things to note here.
Firstly, we allocated
more buffer than we need,
but that's fine.
So we allocated a hundred here on line 15.
The buffer knows how many lines have been
written to it, and second
we only have to call
the flip method, which I've
defined on line 23 once,
after we've written all
the valleys to the buffer.
So you do so at that point because
you're flipping from writing to the buffer
to reading from the buffer
to writing its contents
to the file channel.
Now third, you haven't specified an index
or any put calls, and so all the rights
are relative rights for that reason
which is what we actually want here
when we're writing the
valleys sequentially.
And you can see that consequently
the code's a bit cleaner
than the previous versions
we worked through when you're
using multiple buffers.
Alright, let's end the video here
and in the next one we're
going to have a look
and see what happens when
we remove that flip call
but then continue on and
start reading the data back
from the fall as well.
I'll see you all in the next video.