Alright, so this is the bonus solution
the optional part from the challenge
that introduced two videos ago. So this
is the solution we're going to go
through and show you that bonus part so
the bonus part was the display a leading
0 if we only have one number for minutes
seconds or hours and we can use an if
statement to check if we've only got the
one digit but when do we actually have one digit,
well there's one digit for the number is
less than 10 so the number 10 is the
first number with 2 digits. Now there are
many ways to format or in other words to
add leading zeros but we're going to use
only the knowledge presented so far in
the course with this solution, so the
easy way is to use an if statement so
what we're going to do is split the
return string into 3 parts namely the
hours, the minutes and the seconds so
let's go ahead and start that and we're
going to come down here after the
calculation this is in the first method
with minutes and seconds and we're going
to start after we've defined that we're
going to put string hours stream is
equal to hours + H and double quotes
so that's the first step, so we've
converted the number of hours to a
string with the word the letter H on the
end of it now and edit that to a
variable called our string. Now there's
also some methods that we can call
instead of appending the letter H but
we're going to be covering those methods
later in the course, so what we now have
to do is check if the hours are less
than 10 and in that case we have to
prepend the leading 0 to the existing
hour string, so what we can do there is we
can put if parentheses hours if they're
less than 10 and a code block and we're
gonna put hour string equals double
quotes 0 plus hour string, so let's go
add a leading 0 to the hours if the
hours the total hours is less than 10.
Now for minutes and the seconds we can do
the same, so what I'm going to do is
paste in the code and we'll do the same
for both I'm going to take this down
here copy copy those lines well paste it
once and we'll do this for the minutes
so we'll call 1 minute
string in a string and the test error is
going to be remaining minutes, so if it's
not hours anymore it's going to be
remaining minutes that's less than 10
I'm going to add 0, so then we're going
to paste in minutes string for both of
these so in other words we're adding the
zero to the minute string if that's the
case. So we need to do the same
it's a seconds and what I need to do is
just take a copy of this again and the
other thing I need to change their
course before I do that
it's remaining it's who they're dealing
with remaining minutes there so I'm
going to copy this next line paste it
down I mean now at the stage of doing
seconds, so seconds string that's gonna
be equal to seconds plus s the other
thing I didn't do here was change the H
to an M there for minutes, so let's do
that then we're going to do if seconds
if seconds is less than 10 then we're
going to do 2nd string equals 0 plus 2nd
string so you can see what we've done
there we've got hours calculated here
then we've got minutes calculated and
then we've got seconds calculated. So the
last thing we now need to do now that
we've done those calculations is use
those in our return, so I'm going to come
down here instead of hours we're gonna
be returning the our strength so hours
stream and now the other thing is
because we've already added the H we no
longer need to do that so we just need
to add space, so I'm going to delete the
H and leave the space so with this style
a gap between them I'm gonna change
minutes now to a minute string and get
rid of the M there and for seconds
that's going to be second string and get
rid of the S on the end there because
it's already added by our code here on
line 28. So that's joined the three three
three strings now with spaces.
Now there's a method called join in Java
that we could use for this but again
what we're doing is we're using the
knowledge and what has been taught so
far in this course I just want to make
it clear that there are more optimal
ways of doing this but I'm trying to
show you challenge solutions based on
what you've learnt so far, so you're not
getting introduced to things in my
solutions that you haven't already.
Alright, so now that we've done that
let's run the application and see if it
works. Alright ,so you can see there in
that case we've got zero one A for the
hours now because the hours less than
1005 for the minutes because the minutes
were less than 10 and we've got 45
seconds we're working and showing
correctly and that's hasn't got a
leading 0 which we would expect because
there's no leading zero because we're
using a number that's greater than 9
in other words 10 or higher. Alright so
this code can be even more optimized
we've still got some repeating code so
notice how those if statements are
almost the same, so what we could do is
create a method to somehow deal with
that so we didn't have that code that
looked almost the same but we won't do
that for now with the knowledge that
we've learnt so far in the course what
we've got here is a pretty good solution
but before I end the video, I just want
to show you how to use constants.
Now keep in mind that this wasn't part of
the challenge I just want to show you
another way of solving it so firstly
though what is a constant well think of
a constant like a variable but a
variable that we cannot change the value
of once we've assigned it, so it's got a
constant value. Now constants can be very
useful, we repeated the same string twice
this string if we come over here and
have a look invalid value for this get
duration string there and also we reuse
that again up here. So it's used in both
methods we're returning the same string
when the parameters aren't valid instead
of typing the same string twice we can
create a constant instead you know to
use this constant in both methods it
needs to be declared outside of the
method. Now later in the course we're
going to talk more about variables that
are just that are declared outside of
methods but for now let's just focus on
constants so as I've said previously
constants can't be changed once they're
assigned so to assign one we come up
here to the top we're going to type in
here after main and I'm going to type
private remembering that we're gonna be
talking about what private means later
in the course a new static or an all I'm
gonna put in uppercase noticing how I'm
typing in uppercase and invalid
underscore value underscore message
equals and it's going to be equal to
invalid value
and what didn't do there was put the
type that's public static final string
invalid unless value on its core message
equals than the value that we want to
sign it in this case is invalid
underscore value so that's how constant
and notice the key word here final that
key word is used to make a variable
final so in other words once we've
assigned the value which we've done on
the same line here
we can't change its value and then we've
got after final we've got string which
was the type that I missed originally
when I typed it in that's the type of
the constant which in this case is a
string and then our value is typed in
after the name on the right-hand side
then we've also got the keyword static
here and that's because we're using this
variable in static methods. Now later
we're going to talk more about the
static keyword but for the time being
just remember if we need to use this
variable in a static method remembering
that a static method has a method that's
using the static keyword and by default
that's all we've been using so far in
the course, so if you want to use a
variable that's been declared outside of
a method you need to it needs to also be
aesthetic which it is in this case but
again more on that later in the course
and just to confirm that if we come down
here and we try and change the value so
let's try and say invalid value better
invalid underscore message equals
equals hello notice we've got a red
underline by intelliJ hover over it
cannot assign a value to the final
variable invalid value message so
IntelliJ helpfully prevents you from
doing that and the other thing you might
be wondering is why's has topped in
uppercase constants are usually topped
in uppercase so that they're easily
identified as constants in your program
code, that's because they're not going to
be changed. Alright so I've established
that at a constant cannot be changed
let's go ahead and use this in our code
and to use it you can just return and
use that constant belly so invalid
let's call value underscore message you
use it there then we can come down to
the second occurrence of it and also use
it down here invalid that's what value
underscore message so now we're
returning the value of the invalid and
score value on score message which we
defined up here as invalid value so when
we run our code you should give the same as
that we got last time you can see the
same results on the screen everything's
working as it should the other reason
for using a constant here is it can be
really useful in case you're making a
typo so when you're typing the same
string multiple times into a program
it's easy to make a typo for example if
you're giving a letter or typing a
letter in uppercase and so on and that's
where constants can really help us we
will talk more deeply about constants
later in the course but as you can see
they can be very useful, they help us
with changing code so for example if we
change the constant to some other string
both methods would be affected since
they both had the same change in other
words both methods use the same
constants. So now that I've said that
let's actually test this out to make
sure that it's still working and we can
do that by adding one more solution to
our main one more call to our get
duration string and I'm going to pass
a value of negative 41 here for the long
let's run that you can see that we've
got invalid value there so that's
clearly working as well. The other thing
we didn't test which we probably should
have is test to make sure that the
seconds also work if the valleys under
10, so let's save one more for that I've
got a return get duration string again
I'm gonna return 65:9 instead of 45 we
know that that's a number less than 10
so we should get a leading zero for
seconds you can see seconds is now
correctly showing us 9 9 seconds which
is what were you passed so that too is
correct. Alright so as you can see
everything's working and our constants
printing out the word invalid value
which we expected to do and the changes
we've made have now meant that we've got
a leading 0 for hours and minutes and
seconds if the value of those are less
than 10 and just a confirmation here
that there's still space for improving
the solution but again some indicated a
number of times the challenge solutions
that I'm coming up with are based on
what you've learnt so far in the course
so that I'm not putting something in the
solution in my solution of the code that
you haven't already seen or used so far
in the course.
So you'll find later in the course that
once you've got some more knowledge you
would probably approach the solution to
this in a different way than what we've
done here so far. So that's it, I hope
you've got a lot out of that and
let's move on now to the next video.