- [Tim] All right, so at
the end of the last video
we finished off consolidating this code
to make it a bit more streamlined.
And then we went through setting it up
and reading the information back.
But let's actually try
reading the integers back
in the reverse order that we wrote them.
So in other words you wanna
read the thousand first
followed by negative 98765.
And then followed by
245 so you can see here,
it's obviously the reverse.
Now if you're feeling ambitious,
you can try this you
solve as a mini challenge.
That being the case, pause the video now
and give it a go and see
if you can figure out
how to actually read
the integers in reverse.
So pause the video now
if you're gonna do that.
Otherwise, we'll continue on now.
What we're going to do
is we're going to use
the channels position method
to set the far position
before each read.
And remember that you also
need to call the flip method
when you have to as well
for that to be able to work.
All right, so let's look at the code
to read things in reverse order.
So I'll come up here.
We're going to leave the,
actually what we're gonna do,
it'll take a bit longer
but let's actually just comment
out this code all together.
So we've got our channel defined.
We're going to create our byteBuffer.
Call up the readBuffer is equal to
it's going to be byteBuffer.allocate.
And we just need enough for an integer.
So integer.bytes.
Channel.position.
We want to start without int3Pos
'cause it's the last number.
You're reading backwards.
And I'll just put this up
so you can see the code
that we wrote out.
So were' starting at int three position
which we calculated in the previous video
as being the location
for the third integer.
Then we wanna do a read.
So channel.read, readBuffer.
Then we need to know readBuffer.flip.
Then just to confirm
it, we'll print it out.
So we'll try int3 equals
plus readBuffer.getint.
All right, so we'll continue on.
So we'll do readBuffer.flip again.
Then we're gonna do a channel.position.
This time no surprises int2Pos.
Then we're going to read
that into our buffer.
Buffer, and we're gonna do a flip
so readBuffer.flip after the read.
And we'll print it out.
So it's going to be int2
is equal to plus readBuffer.getint again.
Then we need to,
well I'll just pull this
guy up a little bit now.
Read buffer.
Top position.
And that's going to be int1Pos.
Then we can do a readBuffer.flip.
Now of course that should be channel.
So I readBuffer.flip again.
Then channel.read.
ReadBuffer.
ReadBuffer.flip.
And then let's print out the last one.
Int1 equals plus readBuffer.getint.
All right, so that's ultimately the code.
So for each integer, we're first
calling the position method
to specify the start position in the file.
And we then call the read
method with the buffer.
Now if you want to write
the result to the console
as this code is doing,
you have to then call flip
before calling the get method.
And also after writing the value,
you have to call flip again
before reading the next integer
into the buffer.
We then repeat that process
for all three integers.
So we can actually just run that.
We've got the integers returning
in the right order there
from the last one int3 through to int1.
So just to clarify.
I'm just going to make
a bit more space here,
try to be more clear.
So we're doing a flip before the printout.
Which we're doing in all three cases here.
Then we're doing, before
we're doing a channel.position
to go to the relevant position
and we're reading it into the buffer.
We're doing a flip after
reading it from the buffer.
So technically there's an extra flip here
with the channel.position from int1.
So we could probably remove that.
Maybe consistent with our code
and do it exactly what same each time.
And also I haven't got a readBuffer.flip
after the printout here from the int2.
But it would be good to be consistent
to do that as well.
So basically,
(keyboard clacking)
Oh sorry, sorry.
Again we just run it to make
sure that's going to work.
And we still get our same results.
Now when reading in a random manner,
probably you would
normally create a buffer
for each read that matches
the size of the data.
So for example, let's think back
to the adventure application.
Now if we wanted to use java.nio
to load a location on demand,
then we already know the
link that the location record
from the index.
So therefore for each read,
we'd create a new buffer
of that exact link.
Now you might think it'd be more efficient
to create a buffer that's long enough
or large enough to hold
the longest location record
and reuse it.
But you may never need to
load the longest record.
And Java's garbage
collector will take care
of the buffers you're creating.
So they won't actually clog up memory.
So now that we've done this,
now let's write data in a random fashion.
So instead of writing it sequentially,
we're gonna write all the integers first
into the same position as
they've always occupied
and then the two strings.
So let's have a look at the code
and how about to go about doing that.
And I'm going to leave the
code that I've got in there
for reading integers as is.
But you can comment
that out if you want to.
And actually I might just
delete this other code here now.
All right.
So let's start this.
We're gonna start with
a byte, a byte array.
I put string equals hello.
What I'll actually do just
to save a bit of time.
Let me just grab this again.
So I'll just start again,
I think that'll be quicker.
So hello world.Getbytes.
Then we wanna start with long.
str1Pos, string one position.
Make that equal to zero.
Long equal int1Pos equals,
it's gonna be outputString.length.
Then long int2Pos.
We'll call this newint1Pos and newint2Pos.
That equals newint1Pos plus integer.bytes.
Then we want byte, it's
gonna be outputString2,
byte array, that is.
And that's equal to nice
to meet you.getbytes.
So we have long, str2Pos equals newint2Pos
plus integer.bytes.
Then we've got long newint3Pos
is equal to str2Pos plus
outputstring2.length.
All right, so that's our start.
And I'll just move this up.
Then we're gonna create a byte buffer.
ByteBuffer intbuffer is
equal to bytebuffer.allocate.
And we start with integer.bytes.
Then we want to do intbuffer, dot,
and we'll start with putting an int, 245.
Then we're gonna do intBuffer.flip.
Then we're gonna do
binChannel.position int1Pos.
That actually should be newint1Pos,
that we've defined above, newint1Pos.
Then one again,
binChannel.right, go int buffer.
Then we're gonna do intbuffer.flip.
Then write our negative integer now.
So intbuffer.putint negative 98765.
Then we're doing buffer.flip again.
And then we do a
binChannel.position, newint2Pos
and binChannel.right buffer.
All right, that's two numbers done.
And next we're going to
do intbuffer.flip again.
No surprises there.
And intbuffer.putint.
And we're gonna put there our value 1000.
IntBuffer.flip again.
Then binChannel.position.
(mumbling) gonna be position
to newint3Pos, third integer.
Then we're gonna write
out binChannel.write.
And that'll be the intBuffer again.
So that's our three integers.
And now we need to write the two strings.
So to do that,
binChannel.position, str1Pos.
BinChannel.right, and it's
going to be byteBuffer.wrap.
And it's going to be outputString.
And then we want to do
binChannel.position to str2Pos.
And binChannel.right, byteBuffer.wrap.
That's gonna be outputString2.
I'll close it up so we
could see a bit better.
So that's actually the code.
Now there are other
ways to write this code.
But doing it this way
does make each step clear.
So firstly, we're calculating
all the start positions.
And we're doing this
all up here from line 73
down to line 79.
And it should be fairly familiar with how
these are being calculated by now.
So I won't go through them again.
And then with each chunk of code here,
we're actually writing the three integers.
And for each integer,
we're writing the value
to the buffer after flipping
the buffer if necessary.
Then you flip the buffer
to prepare it for writing
to the channel.
And you then set the channel
to the start position
for the integer.
And then you write the value to the file.
And for the second and third integers,
you have to then flip the buffer
before writing the values to it.
Now the strings are simpler.
Let me get down to this code down here
from lines 99 onwards.
Because we're using the wrap method.
And that takes care of creating
and flipping the buffer for us.
So if I actually run this now.
And we see that the
numbers were printed out
just the way before.
Nothing's changed there.
But if we take a look
at the file, data.dat,
you see that it pretty much looks the way
that it's always looked.
We just didn't write the
values sequentially this time.
So again the point here is
that you have to understand
how important it is to make sure
you call the flip method when changing
from reading the buffer to
writing it and vice versa.
Now often the reads and
writes aren't intuitive.
For example, when writing
a buffer to a channel,
the buffer is being read.
Now if you haven't called
flip when you're supposed to,
you'll usually get a
buffer underflow exception
when reading from the buffer.
So in the case of writing values,
you won't actually see the
value appear in the file.
And that's because you
didn't flip the buffer
and the buffer's position
will still be positioned
after the value put.
And thus, so the channel
goes to read the buffer
so it can write the value to the file
and it thinks there's nothing to read.
So if you only take one
thing away from these videos
about doing io with java.nio,
and that is to remember to flip the buffer
when switching from reading
to writing and vice versa.
All right, that's all there is
to randomly accessing a data source.
We've learned the concept
in a previous video
and you know the methods available now
when using java.nio.
In the next video, we're gonna move on
to another topic.
And that's how you can use a file channel
to copy one file to another.
So I'll see you in the next video.