Alright so in the last video we've got
our application working but alluded to
the fact that there were a few potential
problems so let's go through in this
video and discuss those problems and
also how to resolve them so the first
problem is what if the user enters a
negative number for the year of birth
what will happen to the user if they
enter some letters instead of only
numbers so let's actually test these two
conditions by running the application
again so firstly if a year of birth I'm
going to enter minus 20 there and I'm
going to enter my name again and it says
now that I'm 2038 years old which is
obviously not correct so what we need is
to add some condition that would check
if the birth year is positive or even
better check a valid range so what we'll
do is we'll check an age range of 0 to
100 and if the age is not in that range
we'll print an error message to the user
all right so that's the first test but
let's run our application again now to
test what happens if we enter some
letters instead of numbers so here what
I'm going to do is I'm going to type in
10 for the year of birth and you can see
what's happened there we get an
exception an error and the program exits
and in fact it's a similar message to
its similar exception to the exception
we saw in a previous video that has a
number format exception but this one is
an input mismatch exception so basically
the program crashed because next int
cannot pass the text Tim as a number and
a quest for that reason and you can see
that conveniently here main dot Java 11
is telling us that this is where it
crashed on line 11 and that's that call
to next int to try and convert what was
typed into a number so it's clear at
this point that we've got two problems
one is with negative numbers as years
and the other is with entering letters
into the past intimates that are in
other words entering numbers in the area
where it's asking for an age so let's
first deal with the problem of negative
years so after we calculate age we were
checking against a range of years from
zero to 100 so to do this let's add an
if statement I'm going to add that
directly below here the age and I'm
going to type if parentheses age is
greater than equal to zero then two
ampersands two ampersands which is
indicating and age less than equal to
100 we've got the closing parentheses
there and if that's the case I'm also
going to put a left curly brace there
and press enter the right one gets added
for us automatically and what we're
going to do is move the print line
statement into the block so what I mean
by that is I'm going to come down here
I'm going to copy this line going to cut
it out and paste it into that block down
so basically what that's checking is to
see whether age is now greater than
equal to zero and it's less than equal
to 100 and then and only if both of
those conditions are true will it print
out this output so if age is in the
range it's going to print that but if
age isn't in the range what we should do
is print out a message to the user so
let's do that so if I come down here
after the closing right curly brace and
add else open another code block by
typing in a left curly brace and the
right one gets added for us
automatically then we're going to print
out invalid year of birth all right so
this else will be executed if age is out of range
meaning if age is a negative number or
the number entered is greater than 100
so let's actually run this to see that
it works confirm that it works so for
the year of birth I'm going to start
this time by typing negative 20 and now
we want to enter the name so I'll get
into the name is Tim and now it exits
the program but it prints out a message
to say invalid year of birth so that's
good it's no actually working whereas
what it wasn't working before and we'll
run it one more time this time with a
valid value so I'll enter the value
again 54 actually that was an error so
I'll just close that program down and
we'll start it again
so you both should be 1964 and my name
Tim and it's still calculating it
correctly and you can see that the
output we're getting is consistent with
us entering a valid age all right so so
far so good the next step is now to
cater for the fact if the user enter
some letters for the Year important now
for that we want to use a method called
has next int which returns a boolean
type so let's type the code in and then
I'll discuss it so I'm going to come
down and close this window down first so
I've got a bit more space and I want to
put the code here after the year of
birth entry here so I'm gonna put that
here so what I'm going to top there is
boolean this is immediately after the
entire year of birth system output we're
not billion has next int equals scanner
dot has a next int and semicolon so that
method that I've used there that has
next int that checks to see if the next
input entered is a number in this case
in integer because we're using the
interplay component however it will not
remove it from the scanner so in other
words it'll ask the user for input and
check to see if it qualifies as an int
if it doesn't qualify the method will
return false so what that means is it
allows us to avoid generating type
errors when using next int but we need
to add some extra code to add to the
flow so that is the case so what we need
to do is check to see if the boolean now
has next int is true and if it is we can
continue with our calculations so to do
this where you need to add all our code
below the boolean except for the scanner
that closed inside an if statement so
let's go ahead and add that if statement
and close it out after the last else I'm
going to come down here and put if has
next int then we'll open a left curly
brace and the right wing gets added
automatically we then need to take a
copy of all of this code up to but not
including the scanner got close we're
going to cut that and paste it in the
code block so in other words after the
left curly brace and before the right one
I'm just going to clean up these blank
lines here just so it's a bit more
readable so now we're catering for the
fact that it is a valid number but if it
isn't a valid number so in other words
there has next int appear if that
returns false currently nothing will be
printed but we want to inform the user
that they've made an error so let's add
an else to the has next if statement and
just as a side note notice how we're
able to test one if statement inside
another if statement so we've got it if
here on line 14
we of course I got another if here on
line 22 so that's pretty cool so let's
add this else then the else is going to
be now down here and you can see that
IntelliJ helpfully puts a line to show
you where the if is you can see there's
an a line below the first if they're
telling you that this is all related
it's also a line down here telling you
this parts related so we know we want to
put an else there to handle the
situation where someone the user hasn't
entered a valid number in other words if
it has next int billion returns false so
that's the case what we want to do is
print our message
unable to pars year of birth alright so
now that we've written that code we've
catered for an invalid number being
entered if a number has been it hasn't
been entered using valid digits on other
words numbers not using numbers using
letters or symbols we've got that care
before and a voice I've got that catered
for the fact that a an age has been
entered outside of a valid range that
we've defined has been between 0 and 100
so let's run the program we're going to
start again to top ABC for the year of
birth notice that straight away we get
an error unable to pass here of birth
because we used letters and the program
immediately exits and it doesn't do any
more processing including the fact that
it doesn't ask for the name now the
reason it's not asking for the name is
has next int at a value of false we're
only running this code here if the value
was true so that's why that didn't get
executed the only thing that get
executed was the else here because has
next int was false
and we got the error message unable to
pass year of birth so let's try it again
in year with birth I'll enter a valid
one we're still getting the right
results if a valid range is entered and
we'll do one more let's just try another
one we'll try 101 this time which we
know is invalid Tim invalid year of
birth so that's also working and just to
do one other final test Oberon minus 20
again Tim and weave correctly getting an
invalid year of birth showing again so
I'll end on a positive note let's put a
different number here in 1980 Bob and
it's correctly returning 38 which would
be correct in 2018 if Bob was born in
1980 well so she's as you can see that
we've got an application now we've built
in some logic and some validation and
although there's only a few lines of
code there it's managed to do quite a
few things to validate to make sure that
numbers are entered and also a number
within a specific range as well so the
application is interactive meaning that
we can interact with it by entering some
data to the console and you saw in this
case the year of birth and name and the
application then calculating the users
age based on the year of birth all right
so that's all for this video
I hope you got a lot out of it let's
move on now to the next one.