so right now the user can add to do
items but they can't edit or delete them
as I mentioned in the last video and in
addition to what I said in the last
video coding the edit case is really
similar to the add case and will even be
using the same UI if we did that
and because of that I'm gonna leave the
edit case as an exercise for you to do
what I'm gonna do is show you the Delete
case now so we are gonna add the
ability to be able to delete a to-do
item from our list in terms of
implementing that we could add a delete item
to our file menu in much the same way
that we did for the new item for the new to
do item but in the case for delete item it's probably not the ideal place
to add it there no it was ok for the add new
to-do item case in that case because we
don't need any other information from
the user in order to add a new item
because of course all that does is opens
the add new to do item dialogue and from
there they enter the details when the
user deletes an item it's different in
that we need to know which item that we want to delete
now we could assume the user wants to delete the
selected item and that's probably what
do the user will expect but what we should do is
make it crystal clear to the user that
we are going to be deleting that selected item so
let's have a menu popup when the user
right clicks on an item in a list now this type of menu is different to the menu
that we already implemented in our
program and this new type is called a context
menu and the reason this called that is when the is because the menu
that appears depends on the item that's
been right clicked on and let's have a
look at IntelliJ sat context menu just to see what I mean so if you come over here to a
project in the top left window right click
that you can see that is a menu that is the context
menu that's been brought up by
IntelliJ and you can see there's quite a
few options their a significant amount of
options but if you come down to say
external libraries right click that you can see
we've clearly got a different set of
options so that is what a context menu is the
options that come up are relative to
what you've selected or what you have right clicked so we are gonna do
something similar in this application so what you need to
do is go to our controller.java
and that's because we're adding the
context to our main window
let's go ahead and do that so we need to
create a field first and I've already added it here
private context menu list context menu
so you need to add that to the java file
so we added it their as a field and we also in the initialize method we
want to initialize it as well we are going to initialize that by typing...
....to initialize it when
the initialize method is executed
so now we've done that we need to create the delete
menu item that's going to be part
of this context menu and associated an event handler so to do that we are going to type...
....
....and next
we need to add the code the event handler
that is going to be processed when we exit when the right
click happens so to do that we do....
....
.....and you can see its overridden the handle
method which were gonna be using and in
there that's where we going to choose
what to delete to add the code its quite easy we do...
....
...
...and that's all we need to add for our
context menu and we will implement that delete item method
but before you do that what we need to
do is add to delete item menu item
itself to our context menu and we do that
by calling get items in our context
menu and we add the delete item using the add all
method so here we can do that so...
....
...so that has now
added that option to that context menu so
next let's go and add this delete item method so come down here
in a bit further actually I'll just put it down the bottom jsut to
be in order of what we've done before so we
gonna create that method so...
....
now we could just go ahead and delete the
selected item as soon as the user
clicks the delete menu item but it will
be nice here because it's a deletion to
confirm that deletion before we go ahead
and delete it you know because sometimes
users click to wrong item or click on
something and then sort of reconsider the
action so we learn earlier that JavaFX
provides us with a few canned dialogues
for common use cases and we are gonna use what's
called a confirmation dialog to confirm
that the user really was to go ahead and
to in this case delete an item
now the alert class which has only been
available since Java 8u40 is the
class that we gonna use here to create
one of those javafx
canned sort of pre created dialogues now
when we create an instance of alert what
we have to do is pass in the type of
dialogues that we want to create and this
five choices that they give us a
confirmation error information warning and
none and then based on the type that we
choose the alert constructor will
initialize some of those instances
properties for us based on obviously
the type dialogue we choosing and you might be wondering why
would you want to pass a none
well the none case just means that there's no properties
that get initialized and in other words
you be wanting to set each property yourself
manually so in this case we want the user to
confirm the deletion so what we want is
a confirmation dialog sort of are you sure sort of
thing so in that case we are gonna code that in that matter so start here in the delete item method and
type...so confirmation is the
one that is going to come up automatically for us and ask the user for confirmation
before we delete so next we want to set properties that
determine what the dialogue will
is gonna display on the
screen so we need to set the title header
text and content text properties so what
we'll do is we'll set the title to
deleted to do items so its comes up really
literally at the top and we want our header
text to provide information about the
selected to do item sort of as a
recap for the User so the know what they are deleting in other words so the user
can see which item their ultimate
gonna delete if they go ahead and will set the
header texts to delete item followed by
the selected items short description
and then in the content area what we'll
do is we'll ask the user if they
are sure they want to delete the item and that way there is no
ambiguity and the user will hopefully
know exactly what's happening here so to
go ahead and do that so...
....
.....
...remembering that items was pass to this method so we can get the details directly from that and that's obviously the current selected
item and let's set the content text as well so....
....
now in terms of buttons we don't
have to set which buttons we want here and
that's because the alert class will
provide those buttons automatically
based on the type that we
passed with the alert type in this case
confirmation in the case for
confirmation I'm sure you've seen a dialogue before many times
applications that you run on your computer
theirs an OK and Cancel button so all that's
left to do now is really show the
dialogue so we get
that working by putting...
....
....so when
the user clicks on one of the buttons in the
dialogue closes then we need to obviously
at that point check which button they
pressed and if they pressed ok we need to
delete the selected item and
in the case of canceled we don't do
anything so do that test here we put....
.....
....
and that should be it so that's all the code we need
to handle the menu to process that menu
selection when right click is selected and
show the confirmation dialog box so then
we need to go back to our to do data
class we need to add that deletion
the delete to do items so we do that with....
....so that's all that
we need for that method and going back to our controller class the delete to do items is now valid
so we are pretty close to being done there but theirs
actually one more step to do so
if you think about it we created the context menu we associated
handler to it and we've written the
handlers code but what we haven't done is we
haven't associated the menu with the list view
in any way now since this is a
context menu
meaning its going to appear when the user right clicks on a
particular item or cell in this case it
makes sense to associate the menu in our
cell factory now in a cell factory class
we will add the code that associates the
context menu after we've created the cell
now we only want non empty cells to have a
context menu in this case so let's go ahead
and associated the context menu to our cell factory so we need to come up to our initialize
method in our controller and we need to add
some code down here just
below the returns cell so we need to actually
add
this code to do that association we are gonna
add it down here
I'm gonna type in...
..and what I'm going to
here is I'm going to do something we haven't done before on the
course and their is a separate
section of the course dealing with this
I'm going to use an anonymous function
also known as a lambda expression and
i'm not going to looking into to much detail about this but keep in mind there is a complete section in the
course about lambda expressions or their
will be by the time you watching
that section may or may not already exist
but this is just an alternative way to write a
function so I want to show you first part of that
anyway so the parameters for that is we
need to specify them first so....
....
...
...so its an alternative
way of adding a list of class adding
a listener method by using an anonymous
method but again we'll talk about the
lambda expressions in a separate section
of the course the bottom line is now that we've
added a listener for the cells empty
property where the cell becomes non empty
the context menu is gonna be associated
with it the one that we've created in this
video and it does become empty we then
remove the association by setting the cells context menu to null so lets now run this and see if it works
we should be able to select something like
doctors appointment right click that
we now get our context menu showing so click on delete now we can see we got our confirmation dialogue
propping up and you can see the item short
description is displaying....
....question marks has come
automatically from the the type that we
specified and also the cancel and ok buttons have been
added other than that we got our title and the other text
we've added showing up on the screen so
its all seemingly working ok and click on
cancel just to confirm or cancel it and
try it again right click it delete
this time click ok we can see to the left
the to do item did get deleted and the list
got refreshed
now notice we didn't write any code to remove the item from the
list and that's because we're using data
binding and the list  view notice that the
item was deleted from the collection
then updated itself accordingly
now another way we could let the user to delete item is to listen for the delete key
so when the user selects an item and
presses the delete key we could do
exactly what we did when the right click
is activated and select delete from the
context menu so we'll look at adding that functionality so adding the delete functionality so when you press delete
on the keyboard it basically pops up the
context menu will do that in the next
video