So I continued on with our
discussion of collections and
specifically bond research.
You saw in the last video we ended up
with this bond research code that came
straight out of the java collections,
the source code comes with Java itself.
So I just wanted to reinforce that it's
interesting how this does work and
you saw how efficient it was when this
little white dot in there to see,
How many iterations were required
compared to our version, and
it was significantly more efficient.
So essentially the code,
the algorithms in general that
come with java are very efficient.
They have spent a lot of time with it,
they've worked hard on it And
it's good to know as a result that
we don't have to write our own
versions of these algorithms
that are included.
Rather, we can take use of that
functionality that's included.
And just to recap that a binary search
relies on the list that you're searching,
being sorted.
Now, we saw in an earlier lecture
how to use the collections.sort
method to sort a list, but
that was providing the items in that list.
Implement the comparable interface.
Now we generated our seat
numbers at assorted order, so
there's no need to sort before performing
the search, but with that said,
the collection and
sort method is available if needed.
And interestingly enough,
it uses a very efficient merge sort.
This is the collection sort, and
that performs much better than the bubble
sort we used in an earlier challenge Now
as we have already used the sort method
we're gonna have a look at the reverse
sort method that the collection class
provides sort a list in reverse order.
Now so
that we don't mess up the seats list for
our theatre we have to really look
at a way to use the lists wireless.
Instructor to copy one list into another.
The collections framework does
provide a method to copy lists and
other collections objects, but
it doesn't really work as you may expect.
In fact, it'll only copy a list into an
existing one, but at least the same size.
We're going to demonstrate the problem
after the next few examples Now, so
that we can look at these methods
easily in the main method.
What we're gonna do is change the theater
class so that seats filled is public, and
the seat class itself is always public And
the seat class itself if also public.
So I'm just gonna make that charge.
So I'm gonna change this to public.
So again you wouldn't normally
do this will a real program.
But it's just gonna make our
testing of these concepts that come
through a bit easier.
So made that public, and
also our seats we're going to create that,
convert that I should say,
to public instead of it being private.
So that's now an array list as well.
So let's go back now
to our main method and
we're just going to delete
this content out for now.
And let's add some code so
we're gonna put four.
Actually what we'll do is we'll
write the print list method first.
So we're gonna create
a method that does just that.
Prints out the list.
It's gonna be public static void print
list list as theater .seat.
We're gonna accept the import for
Java util list.
That's gonna be list.
Then we'll have a simple 4H
list theater.seat seat list.
I'm gonna print out without a space +
seat.getSeatNumber() like so.
Then you're gonna print a line
go to next line then we're going to
also put some equal signs there.
To end the line like so.
So what we can now do is create
a new array of seat objects and
if we parse in the existing
seats from our theater object,
we're going to get a new list
containing all the seats.
So the way to do that is
we're going to type lists.
Theatre.Seat
> seatCopy = new ArrayList.
And then we do theatre.seats.
And just to confirm that,
we now do a print List(seatCopy).
That should confirm that
we've got a new list, so
let's try running that
to confirm it does work.
And you can see that we've now
successfully managed to get our copy.
And scroll right over to the right
hand side, but clearly it's gonna go
through and list all the ones How all
the entries seats in our array list.
So the seat copy list contains all of
the elements that were in the original.
Now, the method that we use
to create seat copy and
populate it in all the elements on
theater.seats is called a shallow copy.
So what that does is creates an array list
containing all the elements from the list
that were passed to the constructor,
as you can see.
On this line up here, on line 10.
No note it's very important here
to know that these aren't copied.
Hence the term shallow copy.
Now if we modify one of the seats,
say by reserving it, for
example,, then that seat will be reserved,
which ever list we check for it.
So we may have a new list, but
the contents are a same objects
as exists in the theater seats.
So we're taking a copy, a shallow
copy Of the same data if you will,
putting that into another array list but
they are effectively the same shared
objects and just to demonstrate that is
the case what we're gonna do is
we'll add a reservation after here.
So we're going to after the print we'll
do something like c copy dot get.
>And we'll just get the second element
from your right, docu serve and
we'll just reserve that and
obviously that should be the second seat
A1 is the first one A02 would be
the second one then we'll do if.
(Theatre.reserveSeat("A02")).
("Please pay for A02").
Else ("Seat already reserved").
So you can see what we've done there,
we've used our copy of the Array
list on line 13 to reserve the seat,
the second entry in the array list
which should be seat A02, and
then we're going back, reserving
the seat from the other array list,
which ordinarily if there was distinct and
separate versions of
the objects that should also work,
but let's just run it and
confirm what happens You can see, it's
come up and said seat already reserved.
So clearly, in fact, even now we've
got two separate array lists,
it's very clear that we're sharing
the same data because otherwise,
of course, the second reservation would
also have worked on the other array lists.
This is an important concept
which was also covered
when we discussed link lists which
was of course earlier in the course.
So the two separate lists here
Each containing references
to the same 96 c object so
that's the important thing there.
Separate references but
same objects effectively.
So two separate array lists but
the references are to the same 96 c type.
To objects that we initially created
when we created the theater object
on line nine.
And just to prove that
they are separate lists,
we haven't already proved
that with what we've done.
Let's just sort one with reverse order
then print the other array list out and
see what happens.
So down here, we can do collections.
Collections.reverse and
that reverses the order of any list.
So we'll do that for the seatCopy.
And now if I print out, I'll print
a message say we're Printing seatCopy.
We're gonna printList().
Seat copy.
Then we'll do another one,
printing theater.seats.
The other one.
And for that one,
we'll do print list theater.seats.
Clearly, there's two separate array
lists that we've got working there.
So let's just run that and
confirm what happens.
And you can see here what's happened is,
we've got the C copy we'll reverse that.
And we can see now that C copy is
in reverse order with starting from
what was the last seat that we
created is now in the first position.
But theater.C has still got
the original order that was set.
So again, clearly, they are separate array
lists But the only thing is that they
refer to the same objects that were
initially created on line ten.
There's also a shuffle method in
the collections class and that
shuffles the elements of the latest in
a random or sort of a pseudo-random order.
So we could go back and try that.
Close that down the run window.
It's a bit of a reverse here.
We can change that to shuffle.
Shuffle.
And if you run that you can see we've got
seemingly random order there, T07, E02.
Run that again, AF4, F08, F11, so
that's a Is a good way
of pseudo randomization
of a list using the shuffle method that's
part of the collections framework.
Obviously there are a lot of other useful
methods that form the collections class.
A couple of other useful ones are min and
max.
And what they do is
return the smallest and
highest elements recorded into
their natural sort order.
In other words the sort order that
their compare to method maintains.
So we could do something
along those lines.
Theatre.
Seat, min seat equals
collections.min seat copy.
Then we can do theater.seat max seat
equals collections.max seat copy.
I could print out a message
then min Seat number
is husband seat.get seat number.
Now that it's returning a seat.
And the other one is max
seat number is plus max
seat.get seat number.
So if we run this code now.
And predictably the minimum seat is
aisle one which was the first element.
And H12 is the max, which of course is
the last element in the sorted list.
And obviously it's taking into account
that's not necessarily the last element,
it's the one with the high sort order.
And again it uses the compare to
method to determine that sort order.
Basing the results on that natural
order from the compare to method for
a given list.
And incidentally, these work even
if the lister hasn't been sorted.
So we can go about changing that.
So we could change the reference
here to theater.seatCopy and
just running that again.
So you can see that is still working
even though as you saw with seed copy,
it wasn't sorted.
We used a shuffle method, but it's still
going through that entire list and
determining the minimum and the maximum
based on the compare to sort order
because that of course will still
work out the natural order.
It's just that we haven't
sorted the list at this time.
We've used the shuffle method, so
minimum maximum will always work,
and is pretty handy if you want to
quickly find the minimum and maximum.
Elements in using their natural sort
order based on the compare to method.
Now if you'll want to implement your
own sort or for any other reason,
the collections class provides a swap
method to swap two elements in a list.
So we pass the name on the list and
the index position of the two
elements that we wanna swap.
And what happens is the swap method
swaps their position in a list.
So what we'll do is we'll create
a variation on the bubble sort method from
the arrays challenge.
But this time, we're going to use
nested foreloops, and the reason for
that is we had a student in the course
ask if that was also acceptable.
Notice that when we start typing this
code, actually, I'll type it in first,
then we'll talk about it a little
bit more So let's put the code in,
the top of the code in.
It will be public.
Static, void,
sort list.
It's going to be list,
extends theater .seat,
list, and we start with a for loop,
for(int i = 0, i < this.size -1,
sorry, and I'll explain this shortly.
i++, and then we put another loop.
The next inner loop is going to
be int j = i+1, j < list.size(),
j++ and
we put if(list.get(i).compareTo()),
so we're using the compareTo
method to determine or
to get a result in integer but.
Back depending whether the entries
are less than, the same, or
sort of greater than in the sort order.
They're compared to list.getj.
So we're comparing the two elements.
And if the result of that is greater than
zero Zero that means we can swap them,
we wanna swap them to our sorter, that'd
be collections.swap, this is how we use
that swap method, list and we need to
parse the two elements we wanna swap and
their element positions which is I and j.
Now, just to confirm what we've
done there, and again we're using
a variation of the bubble saw method
we wrote in the erase challenge.
But again we're using
nested four loops and
that's because we had a student ask
whether that was also acceptable.
I want you to first notice that
the end loop doesn't start at zero But
it actually starts after the current
position that the outer loop has reached.
So in other words,
the inner loop is changing fewer and
fewer elements each time around.
That's still very much slower
than the built in merge sort, but
this could be useful in situations where,
for example, speed wasn't so important but
memory was at a premium.
So merge sort requires far more
memory than a bubble sort,
and this could be an issue
with extremely large lists.
Even so, that said, we'd probably be very
rare that you'd want to use your own sort
routine rather than the ones that
are built into the collections framework.
Now, like the print list method,
which was the method directly above,
by starting on line 34 That had to
access the get number seat getter and
therefore only works on c-lists.
What we've done on line 42 is
we've made the method generic,
the sort list method generic.
So that can sort any kind of list of
theater seats so as long as they implement
the comparable interface and obviously
that should be pretty familiar from
the lectures on GenerX where we went
through that concept in great detail.
So to call this sort list method,
sort list method so
we can see swap in action, we're going
to add some code to our main method.
And bearing in mind, we're going
to sort the same copy method, and
if you recall on line 21,
we shuffled it so
we We know that it's out of order,
so let's now try and sort it again.
So we'll go sort list, and
it's gonna be sit copy.
Then we'll do a print out, printing.
Sorted seat copy.
And print list so copy so we've sorted it,
we've sent the list to this method to line
46 and we're printing it out, the actual
results and they should then be ordered
again so let's go and run that and see.
So I can see that on this line here,
below printing copy, at the top,
that we're out of order.
But then down at the bottom,
printing sorted order,
you can see clearly now that
we're actually sorted correctly.
So our mini sort method worked fine on it.
I'm going to finish this video with
a look at a rather odd copy method that
is provided by the collections class.
And what that does is it
takes two parameters.
The destination and the source list.
Now the destination has to be of a generic
type I there's a super set of the source
list I should say and it basically means
it can be collection an iterable or
a list and the source must be a list.
Now the problem that tends to arise
with the collections copy method,
is that people either expect to use it
as we just did when we used the list
constructor to create
our copy of our seats.
We did that all the way
up here on line 11.
Or what happens is the people may
expect to create a deep copy of list.
As opposed to a shallow copy, a deep copy
is a copy where the elements are not just
references To the same elements as in the
original list, but are themselves copied.
And of course, that's unlocked
the shallow copy that we produced earlier
because we determined when we printed out
the results that was the same elements in
the array list that were
being effectively duplicated.
In the second array list.
Now I'm gonna copy a collections copy
method is gonna file as the destination
is big enough to hold all
the elements to be copied into it.
So that actually leads to a problem.
That's pretty typical to see people
try to do something like this.
Then knowing that you need to
have the same amount of elements,
people will actually type
something like list theater.seat
newList = new Array(list).
That would be something
like theater.seats.size.
And then collections.copy
ulisttheater.seats.
So in theory, you'd look at that and
link it's very common for
people to look out and think.
Well, I've allocated the amount of size
for the array list, so I should be able to
run that, but what actually happens is
you get an error Source destination.
A source does not fit into destination.
Now, the reason that's fouled
is the code on line 37,
what that does,
it only sets the capacity of the railist,
giving it the potential to hold that many
elements but initially containing none.
So it still doesn't actually
create a number of elements.
So to get this to work get the copy
to work you actually need to
have 96 seed objects in
that new list in that
list that we created on line 37
before we can attempt to copy.
So with that said it's really hard
to think of an actual use for
the collections copy method would that
would allow all of the elements of a list
to be copied into another collections
object providing the object had been
initialized by enough elements first And I
guess that's probably why it was included.
Okay.
So I'm going to finish the video now,
because we've covered most of the
collection's methods that can be used on
lists.
So in the next video,
what I'm going to do is take a look
at the other collection types.
See you in that video.