In the last video, we started talking
about object oriented programming and
classes.
Let's continue with that in this video.
Okay, moving forward,
let's create our method and
what we want to do is allow
the method to update the model.
So how do we do that?
Well, we start by typing public and
again that's the excess modifier.
So what we're doing is we're
saying we wanna create.
We wanna make this method that I'm
about to create publicly accessible,
much as we've done
the same with the class.
So we're gonna put public void,
cuz it's not gonna return any data.
We're gonna call it set model.
Now notice how I started typing,
IntelliJ came up automatically and
said, oh do you mean set, and it's got
automatically created the start of
a method for all five of our variables,
our fields in this class.
I can come down here and just press model,
and press enter over model,
over set model,
to say that's the one I want.
Then we're gonna introduce a parameter,
and
the parameter we want is gonna be a string
because we want the other class to
send the string that they want to be
created and for it to be updated in here.
So we're gonna call that string model.
That introduces another problem.
Now the problem here is we've got
two different types of variables.
If you think about it, we've got the field
that we have to find up here called model,
but we've also got another
one in here called model.
Now obviously this one
here is a parameter,
that's been passed to this method.
And this first one up here is a field.
So how do we distinguish between the two,
because as far as IntelliJ or
Java's concerned, we need to be specific
to say which one we want to update.
What we want to do here is we want
to actually update this field,
with the contents of the parameter that
was passed to us and updated in here.
So how do we do that?
Well, it turns out there's a way to do
that, and the way to do it is you type
the word, this, when you're
referring to the field of the class.
So in other words, if we're to update or
access this particular field.
We put this,
the keyword this before the definition.
So we type this dot,
you notice when I type model,
it automatically comes up for
us from IntelliJ.
Press Enter.
Equals, then if you type model,
you notice here to the left,
IntelliJ is showing you the little
p which stands for parameter.
So it's saying now,
this is gonna be the model.
Because we haven't specified this dot for
the second component,
IntelliJ is gonna default to that for
us automatically, like so.
So what that's done now it's said,
update this variable here
with the contents of the parameter
model that was passed to us.
So, that's a way of updating the model
using a method instead of
trying to access it directly.
So, just to show you how that would work,
we go back to our main class again.
You notice we're getting
an error here now, and
that's because I changed the definition,
which was the access modifier,
which was public back to private again.
So it's saying it can't access it.
So if we actually want to update that
model, the better way of doing it,
we put porsche dot and
notice how set models come up.
Set model.
Then what we do, we pass a parameter,
the same parameters passed
with methods before, like so.
And that is a way of then calling
the set model method for our object and
updating it with the value Carrera.
Now if we run that, it'll seem to work,
but we won't get any output.
And of course the reason we won't get any
output is because we haven't anywhere
outputted anything.
So we just got a message to say that
it completed with exit code zero.
Another thing I want to show you is what
happens if we don't do this first line
here the new car.
If I comment that first bit out there,
so we've just got a variable.
So comment that out.
So just define the variable.
We haven't initialized it.
We haven't put equals new car.
Already, InteliJ is saying, variable
porsche may not have been initialized, so
it's sort of saying there
could be a problem there.
Cuz unlike data types,
there isn't default values with classes,
you normally you have to initialize
them using the new keyword.
If I don't do that, this is what happens.
We get an error to say that it may
not have been initialized properly.
So that's a compile error, but
also if we don't initialize it,
we can actually get it to crash.
For example, if I undo that change,
this is like for, more or
less forcing it to crash.
Lets sort of trick IntelliJ now and
run it.
We actually get an exception which
you can't see too much there,
but it's basically got an error.
No point of exception.
And what that essentially means is,
you have to find a type.
Type code porsche, but hasn't been
initialized so in other words we haven't
created an object from the template,
which of course is the class.
So that's why you need to make
sure that new is always executed.
And again, I sort of more or
less just fudged this to actually
cause that error to come up anyway.
The bottom line is I'm trying to
say here is that make sure when
you're creating classes, you always
have to use this new, the keyword new,
and then pass the name of the class,
and then the brackets.
You need to initialize it with
the new keyword as I've shown there.
So run that again to see what it does.
And that works but
of course it's still not doing anything.
So let's go back and add the ability for
us to print something out.
So I go back to our Car class.
Let's create a getter.
So we've created what's called a setter.
And again, these are standard methods.
But it's just the word set and you see
that I'm about to use the word get.
These are known as setters and
getters in Java.
So I'm gonna create a getter
now called public String.
We wanna return the type, and we wanna
return the type getModel this time.
Then we return this.model, like so.
And just to be clear there, when I type
that, this.model, notice that little f.
Little f by IntelliJ is saying
this is a field, just so you know.
So if ever you're unsure of the type of
variable or of the type of anything you
can see on the screen here, IntelliJ is
really quite smart at showing you, so f,
in that case for field, m for
method, so on and so forth.
And there's also other things here,
the little padlock,
is telling you that is a private
method because the padlock is on.
But in the case of method,
the padlock is open.
Which is saying, this is a public method.
Which is accessible to other classes.
So you'll get to know these various
graphics in IntelliJ which are really
there to help you at a glance, see what
particular variable or method is set as.
So this case you wanna return models,
so I'm gonna do, like so.
And we've now got a method
that can be call else where to
return what the current model is.
So I go back to Main java.
And if we now do our system output and
we put model is +, and
we can type porsche dot,
notice how there's two now there's get and
there's also set so we got to get now.
Get model is the method we just created.
So now if we run that.
Model is Carrera.
And just to show you what happens there,
let's try also putting a print
before we've actually set the model.
So obviously, this line here,
this first line, is executed before
we've actually set the model to Carrera.
So let's see what happens when we do that.
You can see it says, model is null.
Null is the eternal default state for
a class and also for a string, and
if you recall we go back to Car.java,
String is actually a class.
A string is a class,
it's actually a special class and
we'll be talking more about string and
how it sort of bends the rules.
And it doesn't need to be created in
the same way that we're creating this car.
So it's early days yet but
you can see the functionality of
Java is allowing us effectively,
because string is a class we can have a
class within a class if that makes sense.
So the model, model, engine, and
color are all classes in their own
right because their of top string and
that's stored in a class of the name Car.
So you can see how this concept of
a user defined data type is coming back,
because we've introduced really
a super data type of type Car,
that has got five fields.
Doors, wheels, model, engine, and color.
But we've also assigned
some methods to it as well.
So both the state and
the behavior are part of the class.
Very, very powerful as you can see.
So let's talk about the concept of why
would we want to use getters and setters?
So we'll get rid of that first
one cuz we don't need it anymore.
But why are we doing this set model?
What is the advantage to that?
What that means, by using the .setmodel,
what we could do is, for example,
we could go back to our car.java.
And we can have a look in
this set model method.
Our setter, and
we could do some validation.
So what we could do is we could put
String validModel = model.toLowerCase,
so we're gonna convert whatever was
passed to us to lower case for starters.
Then let's introduce a test to make
sure that the only values we're
gonna accept for this method are gonna
be a type Porsche and Holden.
So what we could do in here,
we could put if(validModel.equals.
Now .equals like this is a way to
test that a particular value of
String is equal to another type.
So we can, by typing validModel, which
is again of type String, .equals, and
typing in what we wanna search
it against in brackets.
We can actually test that, and that will
return true or false if they're equal.
So what we're saying is if
the model equals a porsche, and
then we can put the or operator,
or validModel.equals (holden).
If that's the case, then what we can do,
is we can assign that value.
So only if, what was passed to
us equals a porsche or a holden.
Will we allow our internal state,
our internal model field to be assigned
the value that's been passed to us.
And that might because we've actually got
a role when we're creating our class to
only define those two types.
So maybe you want to put something
like else this.model = Unknown.
So now also that I'm
putting this.model = model.
So, I'm still saving
what was passed to us.
But I'm actually testing it.
When I'm testing it, I'm testing it
in lower case so we're testing for
all scenarios.
But we're actually testing
the lower case version.
So we've now got that set up, so
if we go back here to our main
java again and have a look.
Actually, I've got that wrong.
I'll change that to it'll be porsche cuz
it's the top, we'll say it's a carrera,
instead of the porsche,
cuz that was the name of the car,
and we'll put commodore
which is a type of old car.
So we're now actually testing the model
to see whether it's carrera or commodore.
Sorry about that.
So we go back here now and do a test.
Now, at the moment, we're passing Carrera,
which should be a valid one.
So if we run that.
Model is Carrera.
So that accepted it.
The fact that we're actually displaying
them, that the model was Carrera and
have a look at our code again.
We're only saving it to this type model
if it's a valid carrera or commodore.
Otherwise, we're setting it to Unknown and
then this is imprinting that
out with a get model, getter.
So if we actually change that say to
a 911, which is another type of Porsche,
we run that.
We get, Model is Unknown, and that's
because in our validation, in our set
model method, which is our setter,
we're actually explicitly only allowing
Carreras and Commodores to be valid
models, that are created for this object.
So you can see how it's very useful
to have this type of functionality,
the validation.
Not done at this point, but
done within the Car object itself
via the methods that we're
setting up in our class.
So it means when you're creating a class,
what you're doing is you can set up
all the rules related to that class,
what is valid, what is not valid.
And have it all set up, all that
functionality set up within the car
class itself, so that is inherited
when we create the object.
What that means is the code
that is creating objects,
can't make invalid objects so to speak.
In other words, it can't create in this
case, for example, it can't assign a model
number, that we haven't defined
as being valid in our car class.
So that's the reason, so that's really the
whole concept of encapsulation is that,
we're not allowing people to
access the field directly
by forcing in this case
to assign the model.
Using a method, we can really make
sure that the data within our
objects are more valid and
have been validated and are correct.
So that's enough now about
the basics of classes.
In the next video, what we're going to
do is we're gonna start talking about
constructors, which is
this component here.
So when we actually issued
that command new Car,
you actually used a constructor
to create the car object.
So we're gonna talk about
constructors what they are, and
how to create our own
constructors in the next video.