so as I mentioned their is a second way of
creating a thread and that's to use the
runnable interface and the advantage
of using that is that it only requires us to
implement a single method wondering
can you guess what the name of that
method would be for using the runnable
interface well very similar to the
previous way of creating threads we
need to implement the run method
so instead of implementing the run
method of a class that sub classes
thread we can have any class implements
runnable interface and then all we have
to do is add run method to
that class of course will then want to
write the code in the run method to
execute on a thread that we created
but we'll get to that in a minute so
first let's create a new class is going
to implement the runnable interface
go ahead and do that and call the class.....and this time we are going to do a
implements instead of an extends....
....and you can see its complaining because it
was saying it must be declared abstract
or implement the abstract method run so
we obviously need to do just that we're
going to override or implement that
method
so come down here to implement the
method which is going to be run
we're going to use another color lets use red for this one so....
.....
.....so we go
back to main now
so to run this code on it a new thread we create an instance of the thread class
not a subclass but this time we pass an
instance of the my runnable class to
the thread constructor and we can call
the threads instances start method just
like we did before
so let's add this code just before
the second output here so we're on line
20 so....
....and this time we pass a
parameter of the new object which we
create by typing....
so we have now created a new thread
based on the my runnable class that
we just created a short while ago
then from there we can type...
so if we run that we get hello from my runnables implementation of run which
obviously was in red which we selected
for that class so just when creating
threads by subclassing the thread class
we can also have an anonymous class
implements runnable and pass an instance
of it to the thread constructor
so let's change the code that we just
write on line 20 to do something like
that so I'm going to.....
....and let's create
anonymous class
so do that by putting.....and then we can override so I can do
an override and notice how its come up with
com.timbuchalka.myrunnable
so it knows where overriding
that particular run
select that
close off the brace and instead of the super.run need another bracket we can leave
the my runnable thread.start their first
of all if we do that and run that
notice how we still get the same output
because we use super.run
so its running the run method from the my
runnable class so we close that down and
instead if we get rid of the super you put
something like.....
....
....when we do
that we should see that we get the
output from the anonymous classes this time
because we have overridden the run
method hello from the anonymous class
implementation of run
so question now you may have is why
should we use runnable vs sub classing
the thread class in other words which
you know when should you be using the way
well most of the time developers use the
runnable way of doing things
now the reason is that - it's more
convenient and
there's also many methods in the Java
API that when a runnable for instance
passed to them
for example since the introduction of
lambda expressions it's become even more
convenient to use anonymous runnable
instances
so when we have a choice because we're
not calling a method that requires one
or the other
there isn't really a right or wrong answer but
most developers use a runnable because
it's more flexible so that would be my
recommendation is to consider doing that
but when we read code written by others
you'll probably see that more often than
not that we're using a runnable version
so one thing we haven't mentioned is
that a thread will terminate when it
returns from its run method either
implicitly because it reaches the
methods end or explicitly because it
executes a return state now a common
mistake when creating and running
threads is to call the threads instance run
method instead of the start method
so remember that we have to implement
the run method but we don't call it
directly
the jvm
actually call that for us what happens
if we make this mistake well our
application won't crash but instead of
running the code in the run method on a
new thread the code is going to be run on the same thread that called
the run method that sounds a little bit
confusing but lets see this in action
another good thing that we can do is we
can set the name of the thread by using
the set name method
let's do that for the thread that we
created earlier to distinguish should
from another so we know exactly where
our code is running so i will change the
another thread here in line 12 and let's
set it to another name so...
.....will call
that something like....
....just so it's clear and you will see why
shortly
and if we go back to the another thread
class hello from another thread but
instead of putting from another thread
lets change this and put...
....return the name of the current thread
that's being executing or being
executed
so if we run the code now back in main
you can see hello from another thread
because we set the another thread
instance to set name to another thread
there that's doing is we thought it
would it's creating and running the code
in that thread so if we close this down but if
we make the common mistake now of
calling the run method directly rather
than start method will see something
different pop-ups so will change now
on line 14 .start to .run
....and then we run it you can see
we've got an entirely different result
we've got hello from main so clearly
its now not running in the same thread
it's running on the main thread which
the main method is actually running on
so that's a very important reason why
you don't want to be calling the run
method directly what you want to be
called the start method instead let's
change that back now to start
run it again and we should see the blue
output is now running which it is on the
other thread
so now that we know how to create and
start threads let's look at - what else
we can do with threads when they're
running now we can ask them to sleep or
to stop executing for a specific amount
of time now you might want to do that to
give other threads the opportunity to
run and you might also want the thread to
do something every time a specific
amount of time has passed
for example we might want to write
something to file every 15 seconds or
we might want to check for data and
requested every two seconds
we might also want to thread to sleep when
we know that it's gotta wait for another
thread to do something and we know
that the other thread and only does it
every 10 seconds for example
so what we could do is put the first
thread to sleep for 10 seconds rather
than having it continued to run we know
it's going to be at least ten seconds
before it gets any results from the
second thread so that all sounds a
little bit like hocus-pocus let's go
back to the another thread and put some
code in practice and we going to put
some code in the run method for the another
thread so let's add a try block and get
it to sleep for 3 seconds so i'm going to type....
....and notice how the input the arguments looking for
is in milliseconds so three seconds will
be three thousand milliseconds
we need to catch the exception here
which is interrupted exception which the
exception we need to catch and we're
using a thread.sleep and i'm going to
put that message there...
...because that will be
executed if another thread did just that
then after that we can put in some
message here to say
....
ok so you can see we've done their we've
added a try catch and we've got the
thread or told the thread to sleep for
three seconds and the exceptionally
will only thrown
if there are another thread did wake us
up so if that's the case we're printing out a
message just to indicate that that
doesn't happen we come down here after
three seconds have elapsed to say that
we are now awake
so to see this let's just have a look at
main we're gonna run main and just watch
the output when we run this you notice that
it printed the initial message and that's
because we had the initial message
message going back to our
another thread the first message printed
immediately then there was a pause there for
three seconds and then it finally came
back and said three seconds have passed
and i'm awake and just out of interest
we just go back and have a look
where we added the .sleep show that briefly before sleep has
got two options their we got the
first method we used was just had a
parameter of milliseconds and we use
that for 3,000 but the overloaded method
also accepts the milliseconds but
also in nanoseconds so that seconds an
hour it's gonna add two together to
determine what the sleeping interval is
we want to be a bit more precise in other
words in our case we just used the first
method and specify exactly three seconds
or three thousand milliseconds
so as i alluded to it's possible
for our thread to wake up prematurely
because another thread interrupts 'it
which we talking about in a moment
and of course when that happens as i
mentioned the interrupted exception is
thrown you know if the thread isn't
interrupted as you saw it woke up after 3
seconds and then print the line about
being awake and that worked
obviously because at this stage none of
the other threads we created has got
got any code that interrupts this thread
and so of course we didn't get the
exceptions thrown
it's important to note that it is never
guaranteed that the thread will sleep for
the interval that was specified it could be
interrupted just as we discussed also the
jvm has to call the underlying operating
system to put the thread to sleep and
it's possible that the operating system
may not support the granularity that is
asking for so for example it may not
support nano seconds
so its really operating system dependent
and operating system and JVM
independent as to how long it will be
again as you saw there was clearly a
delayed their and if i run it again
see the first mention is output and we wait
for three seconds and we'll see the
second come on the screen after the
three seconds had elapsed
so just before we finish this video
let's talk a bit more about interrupts
so we interrupt a thread when we
want it to stop what it was doing and to do
something else
no more often than not when you do that
you need interrupt a thread because we
want it to terminate
so as an example suppose we've got a
thread that is monitoring a buffer for data
that another thread is fetching
so when the other thread determines
that there are will never by any more data to
fetch for whatever reason we can interrupt
the monitoring thread and then it will
terminate
so there's two ways for threads to
notice that they've been interrupted the
first ways to catch the
interrupted exception and we're at the
code for that in the run method for the
another thread class we saw that will
be throw within the sleep method there
when the run method doesn't call any
methods that thorwn interrupted exception
it should call the interrupted method
periodically to check whether it's been
interrupted and that method will return true when
another thread has interrupted it or has
interrupted it but how does one thread
interrupt another when it calls the
interrupt method on the thread instance
that it wants to interrupt
now of course that means that it will need
a reference to the thread instance to be
able to do that to be able to call the
interrupt method on the other thread so
we're gonna end the video here in the next
video what we're going to do is we're
gonna modify our code to have
one of our other threads interrupt the
another thread instance when it's
sleeping just to see how that works
so let's work on that in the next video