ok so let's now implement a way for the
user to delete items by pressing the delete
key now when the user selects an
item and presses the the delete key we
could do exactly what we do when they
right click and select Delete from the
context menu and that's probably the
easiest way to do it so let's do that
now so to achieve this we want to start listening for when a user presses a key when
the list view itself has got focus so
typically a controller is given focus when
the user clicks on it or clicks within it now for example when the user clicks
within a text field it would be given focus
when the user presses a key a key event
is raised and a key event handlers
associated with the text field will then
be called and if their are key event handlers
associated with other controls they won't
be called at that point so the focus
determines which controls event handlers
are called when an event is raised so to associate a key event handler with a list
view what we need to do is set its on
key press property in the fxml
then we'll call upon our event handler once that is done so lets go to our fxml
for the main window because that
of course is where the list view is and
on here on line 26 we want to add that so
we needed an ID which we've already got
there we need to put the set the on key press property and call our method
which is.....
....
.....
.....if the selected item isn't null what we need to do is check to see if
the user has press the delete key so
let's go ahead and add the code for that so...
....
...so once that's
done if they have pressed it so we have determine
that we got a valid selected item and they have pressed the delete key we confirm that
then we can call the delete item passing the selected item which was the
item that is currently beyond
that we have selected on the screen so let's try running to see if it
works so first we should be able to
click on some things and do a right click
that still works but now if I come down
here say to this one here and press the
delete button del button on my keyboard we get
the same pop up dialog which we would expect for delete and note that in that case
that's the equivalent of this one so
this one's got an extra option the
context menu press delete then it brings up the dialogue but
when we actually press Delete of course
we get the confirmation dialog
straightaway and just confirming if I delete
that by click ok the items get deleted successfully
and just incidentally those confirmation
dialog if I select it again on the screen they
can sometimes irritate users and the thing
also the user can develop a
blindness towards those dialogue that
often pop up
in other words they just stop reading them
and click OK very common to see that
and what you probably want to do in a real-world
application will have a way for the user
turned off the confirmation dialogs
now possibly by offering a settings a
setting rather in the Settings dialog or in
a Settings dialog
but we won't worry about that right now because at this point
we got a functional UI and it's not
pretty and we certainly wouldn't leave it
like this but learned quite a few things not the
least is how to layout a main window
populate a list view control handle
selection and key events create menus
provide a cell factory and even
create context menus in addition to that
we've also learn that using data binding means we
don't have to explicitly update the UI
when the data backing control changes
and that's obviously a good thing and the
other good thing to note is that everything
we've learned in relation to the
ListView control can also be applied
applied to controls like the table view the TreeView and the tree table view
and these all display data collections so let's
do a few more enhancements to our UI
just so that we can see how to
do some other common tasks what we gonna do
is we want to start by adding a tool bar to our application now its only gonna have the new
item on it but that's ok because it
will still serve as a good example how to
add a tool bar to an application now since
we want both the menu and the toolbar
to display at the top of our application
we are going to move our menu into a VBox so let's go back to our FXML
looking at implementing that change back to main window we got our menu here so let's go ahead and put the menu bar in a Vbox and move the menu itself
into the Vbox....
now we are gonna add our tool bar
below the menu because that is a conventional position when both exist we are
gonna layout our toolbar items within an Hbox
so.....and within the tool bar
we want this new item to be a button and the good news is
that we can reuse the event handler that
we have coded for the new menu item now there
isn't any code in the event handler the
assumes that the event was raised so the handler doesn't care enough in other words whether
the user click the Menu Item tool bar item will perform some other action and
speaking about that that is a really good idea
to always keep in mind with this sort of
thing when you are coding event handlers trying to make them as generic as
possible so in other words always be
thinking about reusing that code in some
way so to add the button to the toolbar we add...
...
....so that should be all we need to do now to add the toolbar
until we have re-positioned things so they both appear on the screen you can see we still got our file menu
it should still work which you can see we've now got our toolbar I can click on new and that
does the same thing that also brings up
the dialog box so that we can add a new
to-do item that's great and it's working
but we usually display icons on the
tool bar so let's go back and change
our button to display an icon
rather than the text and what we do is
we used the same icon jar file
we use in the JavaFX controls lecture I'm gonna close it down so let's go ahead now and
add that same jar file to the projects class so we can go back in a couple of way we can go to file project
structure and select modules and click on the +
button down here and click on jars or directories
and what we wanted to do their is navigate to the folder that contained our
earlier project which is the JavaFX controls
lecture so in my case i believe i called
it controls so scroll up here
controls if I click into that project
this is the file we want their
jlfgr-1_0.jar so select that click on ok and IntelliJ pops up and asks what's
inside the jar file we select classes even
though the jar contains icons and that's
because certain classes adds the jar file
to the class path so that those icons can be
basically found by IntelliJ and that is what we
want to do here so click on ok
and you can see its has been added successfully so clicking ok will close the dialog so I want
to do is now change it so we're
using that graphic so come back here
to button leave the text new for now but we're
going to open this up here so we are gonna remove the
closing tag for now and I'm going to add
a section in here we are gonna add...
...
....
....and the other thing
here is with the text now actually let just run it first we get this
error because of the import and its having a
problem with this reference on line 27 to
graphic
and that will probably fix if I close the button tag so.... that fixes it like their because
it was obviously part of the that was
obviously associated with button so if we try running it again now
and incidentally that's normal I think you
saw in previous video IntelliJ complains
that it can't find the icon we found
that in that previous example so long as you type it
exactly like this it will still work at
run time that's more or less an IntelliJ
bug their so we run it again and we can see its now working we've got our icon our new icon we've also got the text as
well and I think we should remove this text to
the right of the icon but if we do we
move it the user might not understand
what that button is for even though its
probably fairly clear that its a button
to create something new what we should
probably do in its place after we removed
the text is to add a tool tip that pops up
when they hover their cursor up the toolbar
button to tell them what the
functionality of the particular button is
and lets close it down and do that
button itself has got a tool tip property
so let's go ahead first and remove the
texts property...
....
...so when we run that we get an error and
if we scroll up that is the error their
we get unable to coerce add a new to do item to
class Javafx.scene.control.tooltip
now this is one case where the
obvious way isn't the way to do it and
it's where IntelliJ can lead us astray so
what's happening here why we
are getting that error its because it looks like we've
done the right thing we just introduced
the tool tip property and set it correctly
why it isn't working well the thing is the
buttons tool tip property expects to be
assigned an instance of the tool tip
class not a string then we run the
JavaFX runtime loads the FXML it's
going to convert the value we've assigned
which is a string into an instance of
the tool tip class it obviously
can't do that because they're separate
classes and consequently the reason why
throw an exception now what's interesting
here is that IntelliJ didn't complain
about the FXML and actual fact that
suggests tool tip when we start typing our button
element if remember I just delete that
briefly tool tip so IntelliJ
it telling us giving us a tip that's its the right thing to type put it back and the reason for that it
knows that tool tip is valid and does that from inspecting the button class that
there is a tool tip property in there but
for some reason didn't understand that
the tool tip property expects a class and
not a string now you may have noticed some
FXML elements begin with a capital letter and
others don't
with generalyl start with the capital letter when
defining a class we start with a
lowercase letter when referring to a
property within a class for example
let's take a look at the button element
and you can see that button on screen
on line 21
is a class and so begins with a capital
B text is a property of button
which we've now deleted but its obviously started with a lowercase
T previously and on action is another
example is still on the screen there
start with the lower case letter and
expects a method name and graphic is also a property of button that we've used to
surround our image view in and that expects a Node instance for its value
and we can't directly assign it in our case of
course you can see on the screen on line
23 we assing an ImageView and the ImageView image
properties expects the instance of the
image class and fxml allows us to define
without having to put up with an image
tags so FXML seems to be inconsistent
about this in other words sometimes when
assigning a property that takes a class
instance we have to write the definition
within the properties tags
sometimes we don't as in this case so the
image class has a URL property which was
set to the path for the icon that we want to
see there you can see that on line 24 so
it's all this mean well it means we have to
assign the tool tip for our button in the same way
that we assign its graphic so we are gonna remove the
tool tip from this line here...
...
....
so let's run that and see that it works you
can see its now working we haven't got
an error anymore if we hover over it theirs our tool tip on the new to do item
obviously if we click its still working so I'm going to finish the video here now in the next video let's look at
enhancing this UI in some other ways see you
in the next video