- So in the last video, we actually binded
the results of the task,
the artist's observable
list, to the table views items property.
Or we actually worked
on that by creating the
listArtists() method, as you can see
on the screen, but also
putting those changes
for the cell value
factory in our main.fxml
here using the property value factory.
Now because the controller
isn't created until
this fxml is loaded, and that happens
in the start method, and also because we
want to be sure that the user interface
has been built before
we try and load these
results, the ones that
we've been working on.
So we really wanna make sure that the UI
has been built before we try and
load those results into a table.
Because of that, we're going to initiate
the query of the artists from the start()
method in our main.java class.
So we're gonna work on that in here.
Now what we need to do is get access
to the controller, so we're gonna
change this code around just a little
bit to be able to achieve that.
So we're gonna start
with FXMLLoader loader is
equal to new FXMLLoader(), and then
I'm gonna copy this code here that's
currently on the next
slide, this getClass()
after the load and left parentheses.
I'm gonna cut that out and paste that
into the parentheses on the line above.
And I'm gonna change this line a little
bit to read where it reads currently
parent route equals FXMLLoader.load().
We're gonna get rid of that and use the
variable we created on the previous line,
so that's gonna be loader.load().
Then next, we want to get access to
the controller as I mentioned, so we
can do that by typing
Controller controller is
equal to that's loader.getController().
That's how we get an
instance of the controller.
And lastly, we want to
query the artists now.
So to do that, controller.listArtists().
All right, so that's how we do that
from the start() method
from our main class.
Now as the code exists at the moment,
it's got an error, so
if we actually run this,
we'll see that we got a problem here
in the simple integer property in our
data source, and that's because I didn't
go through the artist class,
properly setting that up.
So let's go ahead now and fix that up.
So we're gonna go to artist.
Now at the moment what we're doing here
is we're sending and receiving while
the setter and getters to simple name
integer property, but we should
be actually sending the type.
The int and the string to other
classes that are using this.
So what I'm gonna do there is change this.
So instead of returning a simple
integer property, it's
gonna return an int.
Then we need to make little
change here to return
ID.get(), same for the getName().
We can return a string in name.get().
Now in terms of the setter,
we're gonna do a similar thing.
This time we're going to receive the type,
as an argument, which will be int.
And then to save that back into
our SimpleInteger property,
we use .set() and pass the int to it.
Now a similar thing with setName().
Convert that to a string.
Then use the .set() like so, and then
lastly, what we need to do now is create
a constructor to make sure that we
initialise both the ID and the name
to avoid, say, getting
a NullPointerException
or something along those lines.
So I'm gonna create a constructor.
We're gonna select none, 'cause we're not
going to be getting these as arguments.
Rather, we're initialising them.
So this.id is equal to new,
simple integer property.
And this.name is equal to
new simple string property.
So I've now initialised that
in the constructor as well.
And if you go back to
data source, you can see
the error has disappeared, and we're
actually creating a new
instance here on line 202
of the artist object, or
creating an object, I should say.
So that's gonna be using that constructor,
which we can then be sure has
initialised the ID and name fields.
Okay, so at the moment,
there's one other problem.
And we won't get an error anymore, but
we'll find if we go to
run this, it won't work.
So I'm gonna run it, and
when I say it doesn't
work, we're not getting
our artists appearing here.
For some reason, so this is actually gonna
be your challenge to figure out why
we're not seeing the list of
artists showing here automatically.
Because what we've done
now, again, is we've
setup and changed our start() method
to invoke the list of artists.
And obviously in the
previous video, we setup
a cell factory, cell value
factory and a property
value factory to associate that, and
we should be returning from our artist,
and should be returning a name.
So clearly something's amiss there and
something's not working, and again that's
the listArtist() method that is
being invoked by the controller.
So your mission, if you
choose to accept it,
is to figure out why this is happening.
Why aren't we seeing a list of artists?
To give you a little bit of a hint there,
there's an extra line of code
that we need to add somewhere.
All right?
So that's the challenge.
See if you can figure
out and fix this so that
the artist does actually,
or the artists do
show in the application when
it starts automatically.
So pause the video now and
come back once you've fixed
that, or if you're stuck,
play the video again
and I'll show you how to do it.
So pause the video now.
Okay, so how did you get on?
Did you find out how to do that?
Well, the trick here is that firstly,
the controller, going
back to the controller.
That is calling this method successfully.
Sorry, I'm saying controller, but the
main start() method I'm talking about.
So this is actually calling
the Controller.listArtists()
method, and the listArtists()
method seemingly
is creating a task and it's doing the bind
to bind it to our FXML,
but actually the problem
here is we're not actually
kicking off the task.
So what we need to do is here,
type in new Thread task.start().
So we need to kick off the task so it
actually does actually go
through and start that for us.
And actually then go through the process
of retrieving the records
from our SQLite database.
So now that we've done that, we should
find hopefully this will work.
Now, weirdly enough, sometimes, you will
find that this actually happens.
Now looking at this,
you can see that it has
tried to load some records in,
but for some reason, they're blank.
So you might be wondering,
"Well, why are they blank?"
They shouldn't be blank, 'cause
clearly it's tried to do something.
And I've found this to
occasionally be a bug
with the -- seemingly, with IntelliJ.
Because if I go back, and if
I paste the code in again.
So we've got this columns code here.
And if I just come through
in here and paste this code.
This code we've used before,
and just to be clear,
looking at that, we should see that
both those, to my eyes, it's identical.
As you can see, there doesn't seem
to be anything different there.
But if I actually then do that,
leave the new pasted byte in there.
Now if we go back and run this again.
We find that it works,
which is very bizarre.
So I'm not too sure what's going on there,
but if I close this down again,
and go back, and if I undo the changes,
so I've undone it, so we've definitely got
back to the original version of this file.
Even if, for some reason, I couldn't
see what the change was.
So we're now dealing with this
exact code from the previous video.
And if I run this again, we find it works.
So there you go.
That seems to be a bug somewhere, so
if you get something like
that and I'm wondering
whether it's something you've
done wrong, no it's not.
It seems to be a bug with IntelliJ
or something of that nature.
But anyway, the good thing here now
is at this point, we have finally
got a list of artists correctly showing
when we boot up our music
database application.
So that's a good thing.
So at this point, you
now know how to perform
a potentially long running query
and bind the results to a table.
So now that we've done that, let's
now implement the show
albums artist button,
so just this button here, this second one.
So what do we need to do when
a user presses this button?
Well, what we need to do is get
the ID of the selected artist, and
so the user will select the
potential artist over here.
So we need to get the ID.
Then we need to query the database
for all albums by that artist, and
then we need to populate the table view.
But hang on a minute.
Our current table view, as you
can see on screen, is showing artists.
Well, we'll actually look at how to
deal with that and
handle that in a minute.
Now, we already have a method in the
data source that queries
the albums by an artist.
We have a look at that.
Close this down.
That's our query albums for artist.
This one here.
So I've already got that method existing.
But the thing here is
that it uses the artist's
name correctly, so it passes that to
what gets passed in as an argument.
But it actually doesn't inter-join.
Now we could use it, but since we know
what the artist ID is,
let's use that instead.
And that's because querying based on
an integer and without using a join
will actually be much quicker.
And that could make a
significant difference,
especially if you're dealing
with larger data-sets.
Now we'll still use a
prepared statement, and
since the user can't sort the data,
or tell us how they want it sorted,
we'll always display the results
sorted in ascending order.
Now when it comes to sorting, we may
want the results returned sorted.
That's what you do.
Or alternatively, we may want
the application to sort them.
We then have to decide based on the
characteristics of the application
we're working on, for example,
how large we expect the returned
datasets to be, or whether the
user can change the sort order.
But let's go back talking
now about this query.
And we're gonna go back up to the top
and we're going to add a few constants.
So the one we want is going to be
public static final
String, and that's going
to be queryAlbumsByArtistId.
And that's going to be equal to --
that's gonna be SELECT * FROM and it's
gonna be plus from table, underscore
albums plus WHERE, and I need
a space there before I start typing
WHERE, a space after, plus column.
And it's gonna be album_artist.
Plus space then equals ?, so we can use
a prepared statement,
ORDER BY, space again
plus column album_name plus space.
That's gonna be COLLATE NOCASE.
All right, so there's our query.
So that query's gonna result in this.
So SELECT * FROM albums WHERE artist
= ? ORDER BY NAME COLLATE NOCASE.
And obviously the prepared
statement will insert the ID.
Okay, so that's our query.
So let's add a prepared statement.
That's gonna be private PreparedStatement.
And we'll call this one
queryAlbumsByArtistId.
And in our open() method, we're going
to initialise that, so it's going to
be queryAlbumsByArtistId is equal to
com.preparestatement, and the argument
or the parameter, rather, that we're
going to be sending to that is going
to be query_albums_by_artist_id, which
is the one, again, we created.
And then also in the close() method,
we want to make sure that
we are trying to close that.
We do that before we close the connexion.
So if query happens while artist ID is
not equal to null, it'd be query
happens while artist ID dot close.
All right, so let's end the video here,
but we'll just quickly run it.
And then in the next video, we'll
continue on to running our method.
So let's just run it to make sure
there weren't any errors.
It looks fine.
And we'll close this down.
We've got no errors, it
closed down successfully.
So we know that everything's
working with our prepared statement.
So as I mentioned in the next video,
we'll start looking at writing the method.
And that's gonna be our
queryAlbumsForArtistID method.
I'll see you as always in the next video.