- [Tim] Alright, so the last
video we finished off queries,
and we've got our
application working okay,
but how about inserts,
updates, and deletes of data.
How do we go about doing that
given that we only really
worked on queries today?
So, we do handle them the
same way, but the question is,
how and when do we update
the user interface?
Usually we'll already be displaying data,
and the user will do something
that will add a new
record, update a record,
or delete a record, there they
would think of it that way.
In our case, they'd want
to update an artist name,
perhaps to correct a spelling error
or delete an artist
because they gave away the only album
they had by that artist
or they'll want to add a new album,
which could result in
also adding a new record
to the artist's table.
So, we wanna keep the
database and the UR in sync.
There are a couple of ways to do this.
The first is to re-querie the database
after every successful
insert, update and delete.
And when working with a small data set
like the artist's table, that's okay,
but for larger data sets,
it may not make sense.
Now this is one area where it
will depend on the databases
and application you're working on.
So another alternative
would be to perform the database operation
and then manually update
the user interface.
We wouldn't re-querie the
database, in our case,
when doing an insert, we get the list
the table view is displaying
and add the new artist record.
And because we're using data binding,
when we add the new record to the list,
it will then automatically
be displayed in the table.
So that was for an insert.
For an update,
we kept the list the
table view is displaying,
find the record,
and update the field.
Once again, because of data binding,
the change will be reflected in the table.
And lastly, for a delete,
same deal as insert,
except I would actually delete the record.
So, we'll update the user interface
after the database operation
has successfully completed.
Now if something is going to go wrong,
it's more likely that the
database operation will fail.
So we don't want to update
the user interface first,
because if the database operation fails,
the user interface will be
out of sync with the database.
But if the database operation succeeds,
but for some reason the
user interface update fails,
that's not really as bad.
The user won't see the change,
but most likely there
will be a refresh button,
either a new application,
or the browser they're using,
if they're using a web application,
in which case though,
they'd have to manually refresh
the data to see the change,
just as we sometimes have to do that
when using the sequel lite browser.
And they don't even have to do this
if the user interface update failed,
and that would probably be pretty rare.
So how does that all translate to code?
So it would run the insert,
the update would delete using a task,
and then would run the UI
update using the task.set
on succeeded method.
So lets go ahead and do
that method of updating,
and we're going to start by
coding an update example.
Now, to avoid having
to code a dialogue box,
we're gonna assume that the user wants
to change the name of AC DC, AC space DC
to AC slash DC.
Now we're gonna assume that the user's
pressed the button called update,
we've displayed a dialogue box
showing the current name
of the selected list,
and then typed in AC slash DC
and pressed the okay button.
Now, because we have the selected artist,
we know what the artist ID is,
and we'd use it to update
the appropriate record
in the database,
and we'd then update the
selected artist record
and the table would update.
Alright, so we need to
open our data source,
and we need a new prepared statement
and associated constants.
And we also have to create
the prepared statements
in the open method, and close
it in the closed method.
Lets go ahead and do that.
So to start off with,
we want a string containing
our prepared statement,
in fact through the sequel
code we're gonna be using.
That's going to be PSF,
and my course would update.
Artist name
equals this will be update
space plus table and it's graphs.
There would be a name here.
Her top product, so string that will be.
A table and its artists.
Plus, space and set in double quotes,
plus, there's gonna be column
underscore artist underscore name.
I'm sorry, plus in double quotes,
space equals question mark space,
where space, plus column artist ID.
Plus equals question mark.
Alright we want our
private prepared statement,
that's gonna be private
prepared statement,
and we're going to call
this one update artist name.
Alright they are now open.
Our method, we want to
put update artist name
equals conn dot prepare statement.
And there's going to be our
update underscore artist name
and then for the close, the close method,
just before we close the connexion,
we'll test to see whether the
update artist name
prepared statement is open.
If the update artist name
is not equal to null,
update artist name dot close.
So basically, the update state
we're gonna be running here
is gonna be update artists
set name equals question mark space where,
ID equals question mark.
That's effectively what we've done here.
Alright so next what we
need to do is add the method
to update an artist name,
which will be very similar to
methods you have already seen.
So its going to accept the artist ID,
and the new name as parameters,
and return true if the update succeeded,
and false otherwise.
So were gonna write that
down at the end of the class.
Actually what I'll do, we got some,
I'll actually put it in
here after the insert album.
Because insert,
so technically we can get rid
of that method all together,
but I won't do that now.
That was relating to a previous app.
But we're working on the non-gooey part
of this music database,
and of course we deleted the song classes
earlier in the section.
Alright so, the update artist name
is going to be public
boolean update artist name,
and we need an ID and the new name.
Wanna try there,
and we'll add the catch already,
so the catch is going
to be SQL exception E,
then we'll do
bring out a message with query,
and we'll put update failed
rather than query failed.
Take failed, plus E dot get message.
Then the actual code is going to be
updateartistname.setstring.
First one's going to be the IDs
so its going to be one comma new name
'cause the first parameter was new name,
or rather the first part of that query
if you go back to the top and have a look,
we've got the first one here is
where column artist name
equals and a question mark.
So that's our first one we need to use
and then the second
one is gonna be the ID,
so that's right, we're in the right place,
doing the right thing.
So one's going to be the new name,
and then update artist name dot set int
for the second one for the key,
for what the ID is to come up ID.
Then int affected records
is equal to update artist
name dot execute update
'cause we're updating it obviously.
And we gotta return, affected
records is equal to one.
So returning true if we
only updated one record
for the artist, otherwise false.
Then right down here,
if we get down to here,
well actually what we'll do is
we'll put it in there, so return false.
So we get an exception
we gotta return false
because there was some sort
of problem updating it.
Alright so that keeps intelliger happy.
Alright so next we need
to update the vent handler
for the update artist
button to the controller.
And that's also gonna look similar
to what we've done before,
So let's go back to our controller,
and we'll add the code.
Like so, and it's gonna be public void
update artist.
Alright so the code for this is gonna be
final artist artist, is equal to
that's going to be casting as an artist,
then it's artist table
dot get items dot get two.
That's gonna be task, boolean,
equals new task,
and we're just going to press enter there,
to get the code written for us.
How I've written in method call,
and we got a return here, data source
dot get instance dot update artist name
and we're gonna do artist dot get ID.
And then we're going to have
the new name be AC slash DC.
Like so.
Finish that off.
And once I wanna set up that
task dot set on succeeded
so, task dot set on succeeded.
So set up our lambda,
lambda I should say.
And its going to be if
task dot value property
dot get, oops dot get that should be.
Then in that case, we're gonna do artist
dot set name
ACDC with a slash.
And artist table dot refresh.
And of course, right down the bottom,
all importantly, we need
to invoke the threads.
So new thread,
task dot start.
Alright, so that's our
update artist method.
Alright, so let's just
go through this briefly
but we're actually done here.
So first thing we're
getting the actual record
that we wanna update.
Now normally we'd get this
by calling the table view selection model,
and that would be the code
that will actually look like this.
And I'll actually leave this in here,
so normally we'd do final artist, artist
and you've seen this code
before, equals artist.
Gonna be artist table
dot get selection model
dot get selected item.
So that would be what
we would normally do,
but I'll comment that out.
And again the reason that
we're doing it this way,
with code on line 57,
is we're simulating this
to avoid having to create a dialogue
that accepts a new name.
But, as an optional exercise
you can go ahead and do that.
Then we can see from the
data being displayed,
or we will be able to see that shortly,
that AC DC is in position three,
so we're gonna get that record
from the table views items,
which will actually be index two.
So let's just run that to
confirm that that is the case.
Okay, so there's AC DC,
it's the third element,
the third entry in the table view,
and it's going to be
in index position two,
so that's where the
dot get two comes from,
and notice that it doesn't got a slash
in the name at the moment.
Alright so we'll close that down.
So when we run the task
that we've defined,
it's going to be calling
the update artist name,
passing the ID.
So it's passing the ID which
from this entry alone 57,
so we know that's the right one.
And we're passing the new name
which is gonna have a slash
between the AC and DC,
and notice that the actual task
actually returns a boolean,
and that's because the
update artist name method
returns boolean.
Now, when the task succeeds,
we gotta trick the value
return mother method
from the tasks value property,
that's here on line 67.
If it's true, meaning
that the update succeeded,
then we go ahead and
actually update the UI.
So we change the artist
name to AC slash DC,
as you can see there
and we then refresh the table.
Now, we should not have to
manually refresh the table,
I just want to point that out,
but there is a bug in the
current version of Java Effects,
when it comes to table
views and observable lists.
Now the table view is not always noticing
when an element in the list changes.
So this is actually a
workaround to force a refresh,
and in fact the refresh method
was only added in Java 8U60,
perhaps in response to this bug.
So maybe fixing this bug will
be complex we don't know,
the documentation of
interest suggests or states
that its useful in cases,
this is the refresh method,
where the underlying data
source will change in a way
that's not observed by
the table view itself.
So, the way that I read
that leads me to suspect
that yes, the method was added,
because the developers know
that data binding is broken in some cases.
So we're adding the refresh
share to force that update.
So the refresh method
forces the table view
to redraw its visible area.
And, it won't redraw rows
that are off the screen,
but since those will redraw,
if and when the user scrolls to them,
it doesn't matter in our case.
Alright, so let's actually
run this and see if it works.
So it should be up, now we
have to click on update artist
and we should see AC DC
change to AC slash DC.
And when you run this, you wanna make sure
this is visible on the screen,
otherwise the refresh method
is not going to redraw the row.
Alright, so update artist.
And of course, what we haven't done,
you might be wondering, "Well
Tim, why isn't that working?"
we haven't actually
bound the actual control
to our new method, have we?
So we need to do that,
we need to add the event
handler in the fxml.
So lets go ahead and do that,
so the third button update artist,
we need to add our on action.
On action is equal to hash,
and that's gonna be update artist.
Alright, so let's try that again.
Okay, AC DC on the screen,
we click on update artist,
and there you can see that
it's been updated, AC slash DC,
and if we actually close
this down and run it again,
in reloading the data,
we should find the AC slash DC is showing,
which tells us the database
was updated correctly.
Alright so that's it for using a database
from a gooey application.
You now know the basics
and I think you've got enough knowledge
to research anything that
we haven't covered here.
Alright so, as always, I'll
see you in the next video.