ok so we've learned how to create our
UI using FXML and then we've been
doing so by editing the fxml file now
instead of writing the fxml ourselves
we could use the javafx scene builder
tool now scene builder is a GUI builder
graphical user interface builder now we
can actually use it to build our user
interface by dragging and dropping
javafx controls and containers into a
Content area scene builder then generates
the fxml code for us and it's written
using javafx so it's an example of a
complex javafx application now at this
point you might be wondering why we've
spent so much time learning how to code
fxml when we could have really just
used a tool like scene builder instead
well gui builders can be wonderful
tools that do you make our life easier
but when using any tool that generates
code it's really important to learn how
to write the code yourself first and the
reason for that is tool might get
discontinued or we might want to tweak the
generated code or perhaps you need to
debug the code when it doesn't work as
you would expect now gui builders should
always be seen as a way to help us
create the user interface they shouldn't
ever be used because we don't actually
know how to write the code ourselves so we
don't understand what's happening behind
the scenes and that's why we spent so
many lessons in this section learning
the manual way of creating fxml so that
scene builder tool is going
to really make things really going to
complement our skills now that we
sort of started off the manual way and we
can now save a bit of time using scene builder now
when it does come to scene builder the
javafx communities wondering and on
the same boat here whether the Oracle and
that's the company obviously that own Java
and everything related to it will
actually keep the tool under active
development now to give an example of
that oracle used to offer installer
for scene builder but they no longer do
oracle instruct developers who want to
use the tool to download the source code
to build the tools themselves and also
oracle have made the scene builder code
open source and potentially that could
mean that oracle have don't have
any
long-term plans to work
on anything anymore pure speculation but
in any event
fortunately the javafx community has
stepped up to the plate and they've
actually kept the scene builder code in
sync with javafx update something that
oracle haven't been doing but of course
that could change at any time for now
the scene builder is still a tool that we can
use and it is still very useful now if
you search for scene builder you might
find some old binaries from oracle that
you can use but that actually include
the latest updates to javafx so i'm
going to do is in the next few videos
I'm going to actually show you how to
find an alternative way to get scene
builder installed on a windows machine
and also on a Mac machine and although i
won't have a video for linux users I will also
outline how you can go about getting that
for your platform so let's continue in
the next video when I actually show you
how to install scene builder and get up and
going for windows and if you're on a Mac
skip that video and move straight onto the
mac video which is the one after that
so I'll see you one of those videos