ok so moving on we are now going to talk about
layouts now what with JavaFX layouts allow
us to add controls which are UI
components to a container without having
to write the code required to manage the
positioning and also the resizing
behaviour of those controls now the layout
will manage all of that for us which is
pretty cool so JavaFX has got 8 layouts and you
don't need to memorize this but the eight
layouts are called the grid pane the anchor pane the
stack pane h box v box flow pane
tile pane and also the border pane
now before we get into playing with
layouts I just want to discuss what I mean
by the preferred size for JavaFX controls
because preferred sizes is actually an
important concept so every control
computes its preferred size based on its
contents so what i'm talking about
preferred size what I mean is the
preferred width and height of the
control when it's displayed as an
example JavaFX has got a button control
now obviously if your familiar with buttons
especially ones for ok and cancel which
we've seen in applications in the past by
default the button control will size itself so
there's enough room to display its
content whatever is actually in their you know text
in other words so if we were working
with an ok button the button control
will size itself so that it's border fits
around that text ok in this example
so it wouldn't stretched itself across the width of the entire window for example it will only be just
wide enough to accept that text so layouts often used a preferred size of the
controls they are laying out to determine how
much space I control I ultimately
get so when the controller is placed into
a layout it becomes a child of that
layout so some layouts will ensure that
their children display at the preferred
widths or heights and sometimes it
would depend on where controllers place
within the layout so that's the theory
let's actually get started and go through
what some of this looks like in code so
so I'm gonna start a new project now click
on new project and as before I'm
gonna choose JavaFX here making sure I got the correct project SDK as you can see and I'm
gonna call this one layouts put in the right
folder for me for my Java programs and click on finish ok to
create the folder and what we are going to do firstly you will see as per normal what
IntelliJ has done is it has created a default project for us you can see it is a default code that has been added which
we talked about in the previous example
so that's the default you can see on line 15
at the moment it is set to 300 275 and if we run that to confirm what it does their is our window so that's
fine let's give ourselves a bit more space
to work with so I'm going to change that
so lets change this 300 being the width to 500 run it again so you can see the window
now stretches wider because we've told it to increase the width from 300 to
500 so that's good so lets now take a look at some code and what we are going do is look at the grid pane and the
reason for that is that's the layout
used in the generator project by default
so we don't have to change it to see
that now from the grid pane
documentation grid pane lays out its
children
inflexible rows and columns in other
words it lays out its children in a grid
hence the name grid pane now each
position in a grid is called a cell
by default rows and columns will be size
again to fit their content which we've
talked about and a row can be as
tall as the tallest controller it contains and a
column will be as wide as the widest
control it contains so switching back
to the fxml and you can see on line 2 we got an import
their for grid pane and obviously line 6
relating you can see the word grid pane their so that's basically a grid pane layout that has been
configured
so what we're going to do is add 5
buttons to this grid pane so we used the
button controller in JavaFX to create
ok buttons cancel buttons or any other
type of button the application needs we are gonna use the Text property in this example
to set it to different values so that we can see what they look like so I'm gonna
go ahead now and add that so I'm going to come down here within the grid pane because
we're saying we're adding a child of
the grid pane layout so we're adding a
button which is part of that layout and will type.....
.....
..so if we run this application now so you can see what's
happened their the actual buttons are
stacked on top of each other and that's
the reason that is we didn't specify a
row and column for each button so because
we are using a grid pane we need to do
that in order to get them to appear
how we would expect them to do in the
right area without overlapping each
other so I'm gonna close it down again and incidentally running it again by not specifying a
row and column for each button the grid pane is adding all the buttons in the default
position so in that case you are wondering why this is
happening why this is overlapping the
default position is row 0 column 0 and basically
the buttons have all appeared in that same
row and columns and that's why they're
actually overlapping so going back to the fxml
we can actually change so
we can come in here for each part so we can
type...
...so what I'm going to do
is just copy that now for each of the other
buttons then adjust the row number and
the column number for each after we have done that so........ok so the first one we're going to put at
row
index 0 column index 0 which is the default as we saw and the second one we are going to put on column 1 for the third one
lets go to a new row because we only want 2 buttons on the same
row so it's gonna be row one
remembering the counts starts from 0 so we start on column
index 0 for that one and in the second one
we are gonna put.....and finally the 5th button 5th and last button we're
going to put on row 2 and also leave that in column index 0 so if we run that now we should find
we can see all the buttons and again if I
just put this down so we can see the code a little
bit as well we are now seeing what we expect though we got button 1 and 2 on row 0 which of
course is because we've coded it that way on lines 8 and 9 button 3 and 4 are both
on row index 1 which is the second row
as you can see and the button 5 is on row index 2 and obviously from a
column position[ going left to right when we are adding
them as we increase the column index the
controllers get added automatically left to
right in the column and of course row as you
can see is adding them top to bottom so
it's basically doing what would expect
the other thing to note is that each column is
the width of the widest controller in that
column so that's another important
thing to keep in mind their so you can see
that it's keeping enough space to hook this button in forward places as well now as for the
rows we can't really see this here because
our buttons have the same height so we can't
see whether it's actually made
them longer or anything
on those lines but each row is the heigh
of the tallest controller in the row so
if we had a taller control in one of the rows
for argument sake the rows height
would be greater than the other rows
now when IntelliJ IDEA generates the
grid pane definition for us as we
created a new project it set the I'm
talking on the code on line 7 it has set the h gap the v gap the
alignment properties and now we are where
what we can now start seeing what they
actually do so the alignment is set to
center and so the grid is centred with the grid panes width and height and you can see
that basically it's using the middle
part of the Windows so in other words the
grid pane is occupying the entire
window and the grid is centred within
that window is the point I'm trying to
make their so we can see that
we probably can't see easily but there
is actually a 10 pixel gap between
the rows and the reason that's
happening is of course we've got h gap and
v gap set to 10 up here on
line 7 and that's also taking into
account the gaps between rows there you can see or you can't see but their is 10
pixels between each row and again that's got
to do with the v gap we defined and looking at the
the gap their is also a 10 pixel gap between the columns in the second row as
specified by h gap so the gap
looks larger for the first row because
the first button doesn't occupy the
entire width of it cell so help us see
this we can use a debugging property that
grid pane has so we will set the grid lines
visible property to true and now when we run the application you
will be able to see this little bit more
details so I'm going to close it down then
come ahead here on to line 7 and I'll just press
enter their and tab over and do....
....so we can actually see this
a little bit more detailed so if I run this now
so now you can see that the grid lines and the 10 pixel gap between the rows and
columns buttons 1 3 and 5 have
stretch to fill the width of their cells so
that's why it appears it has a larger gap between
the first and third columns but there
really isn't as you can see so the grid lines
properties useful when the children in a
grid pane don't appear the way we expect so any
time you've got difficulties and things
that aren't aligning the way you think they should be make sure you do something like on line 8 where I
added gridlines visible equals true and you can see
these lines appearing quite helpfully
sort of showing you what's going on
so it does help you debug the actual
problem the next thing to think about
now is what happens when we resize the
window containing the grid pane so
we'll see that the grid remains in the
center so lets just do that and notice the grid is actually
staying in the center so as we go
smaller or larger its still centering
itself automatically the reason for that
is its alignment is set to center but that
said it doesn't resize because its
already large enough to accommodate the
children in all its cells so let's add
some more text another button to make
it really really long and see what
actually happens so come back here to
our already ;long one really long button
4 i'm just gonna put more text....
that should be enough so if we run this again now so you can see the text for most other buttons have been cut off particularly
the ones now in the first column but
when we resize the window see that the
grid pane will resize until it's large
enough to accommodate all its children so once its
resize to that level it doesn't try
resizing anymore so again just going back
down smaller you can see that with the
three dots is indicating that its not feeting but if I keep
resizing eventually it will get to that size and
now it's just changing or just
moving the alignment to be centred but its not
actually resizing anymore and the reason for that
is that it's large enough to contain all
the text for each child so right now the
rows and columns have been sized based on
the grid panes default behaviour so when we
change button four's text to be really
really long as you saw it
just put it down a little bit so you can see the code so initially grid pane gave more space to the second column because the text was so
long as before we resize it but I'll just run it again just to confirm what I'm talking about here so obviously it gave more a more
of a small size here to try and
accommodate as much of the texts as it
can actually fit in now what if we always want each column to be given fifty percent of the
grid panes width for argument sake that can
be quite handy to do we can actually
do that  easily we can use the columns
constraints class so lets just to have a look at
that's so closes this down and the way we
do that is we actually come here
after grid pane before our 1st button press enter their and type....
......
....so what we doing there is we are using the column
constraints class to set the initial
width of each column and we can actually
use pixels or via percentage now the thing here to
remember is that the ordering is
important we add a column constraints child
element to the grid and within it we add a
column constraints element for each
columns so each one of these that we're
adding within this column constraints
sort of block is the column the
percentage width for the column in order
so the ordering is actually important
here so the first column
contraints element will apply to the first
column the second to the second column
etc so lets run that so you can see columns each column now occupies
50% of the width we also notice that the grid occupies the full width of the window
and I can make it bigger if we want...but notice when I'm making it bigger it is still utilizing the entire space of the window
that's the important point here that's
because we told to grid pane that we want each column
to be fifty percent of its width
rather than being only large enough to
accommodate the widest controls
preferred width so lets now delete the columns
constraints again actually I'm just gonna comment that out and run it again to
make sure it's working
and we are back to the behaviour we want before and we can make this a bit bigger and is now
aligning to the center and the notice
how it is not using the full columns spacing again because we
removed the column constraints alright I'm gonna end the
video here in the next one we are gonna
continue on and we are gonna start looking at
alignment at the moment we've got alignment
working by default based on what
was generated the cpde that was
generated by IntelliJ going to the
center but will look at moving this around
and aligning it at different areas in the next
video