in this video we're going to install the
sqlite commanded line shell for the Linux
computers if you're using Windows or Mac
refer to the previous two videos where
we actually set up for those platforms
but if you're running linux you're in
the right place so let's get started
writing database code straightaway
isn't the easiest way to learn about
sqlite and the sql language
because if you get errors you have to
work out if the errors in your code or
the sql statements that you actually
use so what we're going to do is we're
going to start by using the sqite
command line shell so that we can create
databases and use sql commands without
having to worry about code at this stage
now on ubuntu linux turns out this is
really easy going to start by opening a
terminal session so i'm just going to
use the shortcut on ubuntu which is control
alt t that opens the windows you can
see they're obviously I can come up
here and just type terminal in there and
open up that way as well
alright so installing sqlite three
firstly we check to see whether we've
got it we type....you can see that
it's saying that currently we haven't
got the program installed so again on ubuntu
linux we do a sudo...
...
....
and you can see that was really really
quick installation is only a small
program because we are only getting the
command-line shell not sqlite
itself this point we can then check to
see whether sqlite three is installed
type....and you can see instead
of getting an error like we did
previously we can see it showing
the sqlite version number . help
instructions etc and incidentally you
might see a slightly different version
number to what I've got on the screen
but that's ok so long as you can
actually get it working and you can see
that we actually started the sqlite
command line shell then you are good to go and
just keep in mind specifically with a
ubuntu i'm using 14.04 but if
you're using Ubuntu 1604 you will
actually get out much later version but
both versions will actually work fine
with the course theirs no prerequisites for
a specific version of sqlite three
alright so at this point we've completed
the installation type dot quit to get
out of the sqlite 3 command line shell
type exit to close down the terminal
session and at this point we're done so
let's now move on to the next video
we're going to go through a bit of an
introduction on using sqlite see you
in the next video