just before we move forward and start
talking about maps and the maps interface
and hash maps I did allude to a
potential problem that could come up
when you're using the compare to
function or compared method I should say
and I just wanna go to that briefly before
we actually move on to the map
issue so if you actually go ahead and
read the Java documentation on the
collections frame work you find that
there's a lot of talk about it and they
used words like and ordering being
consistent with equals the sort of their
phrase and much of the discussion doesn't do a
great deal to shed light on what that
phrase actually means and again the
phrase an ordering being consistent with
equals but it really comes out to be
quite simple, a method that produces
ordering that is consistent with equals
will only return 0 if the elements
being compared actually are equal now our
compared method to behave in this respect
so looking at our compareTo method
so our compareTo method behaves well
in this respect so as you can see on the
screen there so too seed objects have the
same seat number then they have same
seats effectively and the string dot
compareTo method will return 0 and that's
quite correct but looking at are
comparators compare method though we go back up to
the top here, this is the compare method here I'm
talking about this is definitely not
consistent with the equals so comparing
any of the seats with the same price will
return 0 when they are obviously not the same
seat because of course we can add
multiple seats with the same price so
this causes problems with sorted sets
and maps if the sorted maps use a comparator such as ours then that's
inconsistent with equals now actually it
turned out to be quite easy to fix all
you need to do is do a further tests on the
seat number whenever the price is equal
just as I described for last and first
names in the previous video, but I'm gonna
leave it as it is for now so that we can
see the problems that can arise with sorted
sets and sorted maps later in this
video the bottom line is you can't use
the compare method as we got here
without more work by using the
price because it's gonna be more than
one seat that would return an equals
returning a zero because the process the prices the same, we need to break it down further
so lets move on now and start talking
about the map interface and again you see an
example of what I mean by of this error
later on so right now we're gonna leave
the collection side of the Java
Collections Framework for now, I'm gonna have a
look at the map interface and also some
of the Java classes that implement it
now the map interface part of the collections framework
even though it's not a true collection in
a true sense of the word as we've talked
about in the previous videos
and just to say what I mean lets just open a browser, paste in this link
which will be available for you, so you can see
obviously a map is out here on it's own its not
part of the collection exactly like it says
a list of q and a dq is
now the map interface replaces the now obsolete
dictionaries abstract class and like the
class that replaces it maps keys to
values, so a language dictionary is a
classic example of a map with the keys
being the words in the dictionaries and
the values being of course the
definition
of the words now unfortunately the analogy falls a bit with the
English language and the reason for that
is many English words have the same
meanings, so the word put for example has
four different points two is a ver two
is a noun
now a java map cannot contain duplicate keys and each
key can only map to a single value
so in the next few lectures we gonna have a look at the
two classes that implement the map interface
And they are Hash Map as well as
Linked Hash Map in as well as going into
Tree Map that implements the sorted map interface
now maps like all the core collection
interfaces are generic they take two types
one for the key and one for the value
know it is possible to use raw maps
where the types aren’t specified but as we've seen in the
lectures in generics this isn't a good idea
So what I’m going to do I’m going to start with
an example using hash map to store descriptions
of a few computer languages so I go back to college IntelliJ
And we create a new class name and notice I got collections code open
so for now we're going to be using the same project
were just going to create a new file in here
so new java class he was gonna call this map
and what we are going to do is to add a public static
void main so we can actually run our code so we can do psvm and press tab
and that creates the definition for us
automatically as you can see on the
screen
so let go on ahead and type some coding now so
we are going start creating our map object
so… ,
we are getting an error there because I need to change my language level
but will see how i go, so…
and just looking at the error, ok I see what the problem is here now
and what i was gonna do is restart the
video but I think I might be better to
just to show you this scenario
how to get out of it so what
I've done there I use the name map
To be the name of the class and I'm trying
to add a variable called map as well
what we can do to get out of that is
two ways firstly we can
refactor it we can just click on that
refactor, rename, that's probably the quickest way
to rename the class to get out it
but the other thing we could also do is
we could do something like…
…and we could put…
… do something like that and that should actually fix the problem so if you run into
a situation again where you've used a
reserved word for a class name this is a way
to get around it by typing in the
actual name and by typing in the
complete declaration if you happen to
know what the package name is you can fix that, with that said
I'm going to changes this anyway
because it's just gonna save a bit of typing
so refactor, rename I'm gonna call this
map program and then I can actually
remove the definition here at this point
and just delete and java will come up and ask do you mean this import java.util yes thats the one
so moving on we have defined a map with two generic parameters there a string
that's the key and the value
that's the types and the objects we
are gonna be using and to add something we
just add… and we can start with…
and we can say a compile high level, object-orientated platform
independent language, so lets add a few more
languages so we are gonna do… and again the first
parameter in there is the key and the second is
the value associated with it
so we type… Python, and interpreted object-orientated high-level programming language
with dynamic semantics, ok so… Algol, an algorithmic language, and I’ll do a couple more… BASIC, YES I’m not to
proud to admit that and of course that’s
beginners all-purpose symbolic
instruction code, and one more lets do Lisp, and will say Lisp, therein lies madness, ok thats our languages and that has stored
each of those references a key and value
pair into the map object and I made a typo there
so how to retrieve them?
well we obviously certainly using the
put we retrieve them using a get so
we can to type in something like
languages… and if we run that
I need to right-click this first and run the
new program so it gives us an option to run it on here
so run that first and you can see that we've
compiled high-level object-oriented
platforming language which was clearly the setting the value
I should say that we define for Java
so that's good
and obviously if you want to get access
to the other ones you have to do the
same thing you have to specify that the key
and by default .get returns the value
associated with the key so that's good but one
important feature of maps is the keys are
unique so in other words if you try and
use a value again what happens is the
new value gets overwritten now you don't
get an error but the the new or old
gets overwritten, so we put languages…
lets put java again… and put this course is about Java, and now if we reprint it again
after doing the change and run that, you
can see what happened there
we didn’t get an error it didn’t come up with it already exist or  anything but clearly what's
happened it's overwritten the value so
that's the important thing to remember
is that for a particularly key can only be
one value and if you try and insert more
than ones using the put more the once then
the value gets overwritten, now the put method itself
can be used to tell if a value is being
added for the first time it can be
useful in certain circumstances to know
that the reason it returns the
previous value if the was one so, we changes
lines here to show you what I mean
lets changes this two here and instead of just
putting the language put will put a System.out
there, will around it in that like that will do the same for the Lisp as well
So were now surroundings that in brackets and if we comment this out briefly and run this again now we got the returned object null
for both cases and that essentially
means is that this was a brand new
reference a brand new key value pair
that was added to the dictionary but again
if we know un comment this again
and run this again, actually what I’ll do is I’ll comment this out we don’t need those
those are just print outs but what I want to
show you is this line here System out print out
results of running that, you should find it because we've
added java the first time on line
13 when do it again on line 20 we should get a different response, so we run this
and you see what happens with that
printout we actually get the version
the value that already existed prior to this
being added so the lines gets process
the line 20 output, if we actually this line out
so we can print it we will find that the value has been changed, so its changed
as you can see but has returned what previous value was, so this is just a way for you to determine
whether you need to know that a value is being added for the first time that how you go
about doing it, so that's obviously helpful to tell
you what the previous value was but it
didn't prevent you from adding it, in other
words it's still got added whether or not
you wanted to or not so if you do want
to determine an unpragmatically only
add a key if it's not already there we can
do that as well and we go about that is used the
contains key method to check to see
whether it exists
so we could do something, so I just delete that line now, and up here we put something
like if…
…I can print…Java is already in the map…else…
that where we can put our languages put again
and fix it like that, so that would be a way
to pragmaticly ensure that your only adding an
item once and its never gonna be
overridden by adding it a second time to
check in that works we run it
java is already on the map has come up
successfully and told us that and just to be
really hundred percent sure we can
also put something here
if…Java…
Java already exists…else…and we can just put the java line in there, and obviously its pretty clear that
should return the normal
message, the else here, because we just
created the map on line 12 but just to confirm that it does anyway and I didn’t
put a message there i need to put message there to say, Java added successfully and of course we added code on line 16
but we didn’t put any message on the screen, so run again,  Java added
successfully and the two nulls
relating to basic enlist and we got Java on the map down the bottom line
on line 25 so that's how you go about doing
that there's also another method called put if absent and
that's only gonna add to the
map if the key is not already present but
that's really intended to prevent
concurrency issues that one thread does
not add to the map only for that entry to be
overwritten by another thread, so it doesn't help in the null case
because it will overwrite
keys with no values now the other thing
we can do is we can also remove items
from the map but before doing that would
be really useful to print our maps contents
so that we can checked that the item are gone when we remove
them one way to do that is to look
through the keys in a map using the key
set method and it returns a set of all the keys
and we are going to cover sets in detail
later in this section so all we doing
here in this code I’m writing is looping through the contents of the
set of keys case so what I’m going to do is add
some code, so right down here… print out…lets just add some equals signs to separate
our code like so and let's go use the key set method so to
print out all our keys and values we can put…
and you can see that returns a set, and will be taking about sets in
this section
and we can do something like…
and that’s gonna loop
through the map and return all the values so lets run that to confirm that it does work
and we go through and they all work fine, and in with the code in line
25 we didn’t redo Java, so java is already being added once, so
the result is showing the original
interpretation of Java because we've
added some code to pragmatically check to
see whether Java exists and we printed the message
we didn't actually updated so that's
what its showing the original one but as you can see that's
going through the list of objects printing up the
key and also the associated values
now if you looked at that there is no specific
order there, bviously the order does not
relate to how we entered them the first time because we started of
with Java which is still does in this case two dozen this case but
basic obviously wasn't at the top of the list
it still towards the bottom and there's no guarantee
in ordering I guess what I'm saying with the hash map so
the key has appeared in the order we added
nor in alphabetical order and that's the thing to point out
with it with default hash map is you can’t
presume that objects are gonna
return to you in the correct order so I’m to finish this video here in
the next video we are going to talk
about ways to remove items from maps and
look at some other bits and pieces
relating to getting the most out of
maps so see you in that next video