so continuing on from the previous video
and we went through an example showing
how by just changing the instance
variable we got a completely
different result with our multiple
threads and probably at first glance you
think that it wasn't doing what it should
be doing
so when i introduced terminology
relating to threads i briefly mentioned
the heap and that's the applications
memory that all threads share now I also
said that every thread has a thread
stack and that's memory that only that
thread can access
so in other words thread one can't
access threads 2's thread stack
and vice versa but they can both access
the heap now local variables are stored
in the thread stack that means that each
thread has its own copy of a local
variable in contrast the memory required
to store an object instance value is
allocated on the heap
in other words when multiple threads are
working with the same object they in
fact share the same object or share that
object so they don't have their own copy
as such and so when one thread changes
the value of one of the objects instance
variables the other threads will see the
new value from that point forward
so how does that relate back to our
application
well we're passing the same count down object to both threads and you saw that
defined on line 8 and 10 on
the screen when we used a local variable
for i that was ok because when the
jvm allocated the space for the local
variable it used each threads stack
consequently each thread has their own
copy of i on their respective thread
stacks
however when we switched to using an
instance variable the jvm allocated the
space
for i when it created the count down object
and it did so at that point on the heap
now threads share the heap so in that
case or in this case the two threads
don't then have their own copy of the
variable I but in fact share the
variable that's on the heap
so what that means is that
so when thread one executes and change
changes the the value of i and then get
suspended
so that thread 2 can execute thread 2 will then see the new value of I
as it has been updated from thread one
it won't see the value of I that it had
when it was last suspended and that's
why each thread is sometimes skipping a
number and why numbers can appear out of
order
so let's take a closer look at the
output above in this screenshot that
I've got there and try and make some
sense of it
now we have to keep in mind that a for
loop is actually several statements
i'm talking about the for loop on line 36
the first time it's executed it assigns
the initial value to the variable it
then checks to see whether the for
condition is met
if it is the code within the loop is executed and I'm sure you
understand that because we have been
for loops throughout this course
but when we return to the for statement
it will then decrement I in this case
and then check the condition again
so basically a for loop consists of
several steps and a thread can be
suspended between each step this is the
key point i'm making here so a thread can
be suspended between steps as an example
a thread could be suspended after the for
has decremented the I variable but
before the condition has been checked
again another example it could also be
suspended after executing all the code
associated with the for loop but before
executing the print line
so let's thinking about that let's list our some potential suspension
points here
so in the for loop a thread could be
suspended just before decrementing I
just before the condition or just before
printing out the value so three spots
there and thinking about it theirs actually
more suspension points in this because
the print line statement involves
concatenation and IO and effectively
calls multiple things but this is
really a good enough
understanding of what's happening
the point here is that there's multiple
points where the thread the current
thread could be suspend
so when we analyze the output all we can
really be sure of is what the value of
I was when each thread printed it
at that point in time
so both threads thought the value of I
was ten the first time they executed the
print statement that means that thread
one was suspended before it could
decrement I from 10
in other words reducing it to nine
because when thread 2 print the value
it still had the value of 10
now when thread one gets the chance to
print the line again
the value is 9 so from this we can
guess that thread one decremented value
from 10 to 9
so how do we know that well if the
thread 2 had beaten thread 1 to it
and decremented the value from ten to
nine when thread one had the chance to
run again it would have decremented the
value from nine to eight so it would
never have printed the value 9 at
all but because it does
we know that thread one decremented it and
by the same reasoning we know that the
thread one was suspended before iti could
decrement the value from 9 to 8
thread 2 then decrement the value from
nine to 8 and then prints
8 so the 2 threads go back and
forth like this for a bit
with thread one decrementing the value
printing it and suspending and then
thread 2 decrementing the value
printing it and suspending now
rather than each thread being able to
count down from ten to one that keeps
skipping numbers because of the
interference from the other thread in
fact when problems arise because threads
are inter leaving and accessing the same
resources
the situation has a name its known as
thread interference and we can see why
it's called thatp now from what was
shown here on the screen
these two threads keep interfering with
each other because whenever they get a
chance to run the other thread has
changed the value of i and as a result
each thread can no longer count down from
ten to one and hit all the numbers will
also see this situation referred to as a
race condition which is the more common
term for when two or more threads are
writing a share
resource it is important to note that
there wouldn't be a problem if both
threads are only reading the shared
resource problem will only arise when at
least one other threads is writing or
updating the resource
so let's think about what might have
happened when the numbers two and three
were printed out of order from the
pattern we've seen before we could guess
that each thread was decrementing the value
checking the four condition executing
the print statement and then suspending
so they're going back and forth
except on the numbers four and two were
printed by thread 2
so we can guess from the output that the
two threads still interleaved but thread
1 didn't get a chance to print the value
3 before it was suspended
so you might wonder you know why it printed the value 3 when it got the
chance to run again after all wouldn't
thread 1 have decremented the value to 2
so why didn't thread one print the value
of three
so in this case our over simplification
of the possible suspension points
don't work now I mentioned that there are
potential suspension points within the
print statement itself and that's what's
actually happening here so let's take a
stab at how these threads are executed
thread two prints the value of 4 and
has then been suspended thread one which has
printed the value 5 previously and then
suspended
decrements the value to 3 thread 1
starts to execute the print statement
it builds the string that it's going to
print and at that point in time the
value of i is still 3 thread one calls
println and then is suspended while the
printlns method is executing but
before the string is output to the
console thread 2 decrements the value to
2 and prints it and then it suspends
thread 1 continues to execute the println method and print out the string
it created when the value of i was still
3 then suspends thread 2 decrements
the value of i to 1 then prints it out
now that the value of i is 1 by threads
at this point exits the for loop and terminates
now I know that is a bit of a mouthful or
bit of a little bit to get your head
around but you can see that every time
we run this we going to get a different
result
and there really is just no way to
predict which thread is going to print
out which numbers and obviously in the
case when i run this previously we've
got a completely different result
to my example image here so hopefully you
can see now that threads are deceptively
simple to work with
we just have to create an object
subclass from thread and call the start
method or create an instance of the
thread class with a runnable object
which we've done in this section
but even when we have only two threads
that are doing something
you know really simple like in this case you can
see how problems and come about because
object instances are stored in the heap
which is shared across threads in an
application
so I'm going to finish the video here
now in the next video will continue our
discussion about race conditions
see you in the next video