ok so its now time just for a mini challenge we have another challenge to
will be coming up in a later video but for this one now looking at the code what why did I actually declare
loc file at the start of the method
that's the code that its on line 19 why
did I declare it there's instead of saying coming into here on line  21 and
doing something like file writer....and doing it their and obviously
we got an error here because we already defined it but what's the reason that I chose to
put it in here on line 19 instead of
actually doing it within the try block
os have a think about that and if you know
the reason well when you figure out the
reason come back and un-pause the video
and I'll show you or tell you what it
was so pause the video now
ok so did you figure out why we want
to do that well the reason we had
to do that was that
try catch and finally blocks introduce new
scope so file writer declared inside a try
block would not be available in the finally
block so if I deleted this code on line
19 we find we get errors on line 30 and 33
and that's because try is a block in its own right and the finally and the
catch are also their own blocks and
consequently any variables defined are given
block that is available to another block or inside another block so that's why we did it that way to get
that to overcome that and we did it
outside basically the first block now
looking at this code and thinking
there's quite a lot of code in that
method to write our data and most of its
concern with catching the exceptions
that the file writer might actually
throw so I mentioned in the videos on
exceptions in the section that there
really isn't much point catching an
exception unless your going to do
something about it all with it in all
this code is doing at the moment is
printing out a stack trace so what going
to do is we are going to use very similar card to read the
data back in when the game starts and if the
game data can't be loaded then the rest of the
game isn't going to work very well so
there's really not much that can be done
when a file can't be opened so the best
thing we can do here in that situation
is to send the exception back to the
calling program and alert the program or
the user I should say to the error now
I actually said at the start of the
program that Java insists that we handle
checked exceptions but there are two
ways to handle them now as we saw doing
nothing
wasn't an option but the alternative to catching them is to throw them
back up the call stack obviously as this
main method is the entry point for this
part of the program we don't actually have any
calling code that can handle the
exception but the idea of throwing the
exception instead of catching it is very
useful so we're gonna have a look at now on how to do that though the Java
documentation uses the term catch or
specify for dealing with checked
exceptions this means the
method must either
catch the exception or specify that it's
going throw that it throws it now often
it'll make more sense to specify rather
catch so we are going to do that with our main method
so lets actually have a look at doing that now so what we do is we come to our main
method and we adjust this and the end after the arguments and after the closing
bracket we type.....so we
basically specifying the main method
throws an exception and now we've done that the caller knows
the exception can be thrown from this method
and because IOException is a
checked exception the caller then must
either catch the exception or also
specify that it's going to throw it so
well actually at that point now we can also
remove this part of the try catch block
because we're not actually dealing with
the IOException of such anymore were
actually just throwing the error will
leave the finally block in because we
still want to actually process the correct
closing of the file so you can close that one
but we can also closed the second one as
well because we are throwing the
IOException so will come down here and get rid of that one....so if we close
the try block and again we've got no catch as
a result we can actually change our
block now to remove the try all together
because we've thrown that exceptions so you can
see the code has been made easier now
because if there is an IOException
that's thrown in the finally block it is
actually going to be thrown back to the
or thrown up the call stack because of the
reference we made on line 18 that
throws IOException so we still want that finally closed because we do want to
test to see whether we closing it properly
and if you've got a loc file reference
we do want to try and close it so that's
why I'm leaving that finally close
in there but in some scenarios
with the way we've defined this
now if you throw the IOException you can probably do without a try block altogether because you're
basically passing the responsibility for
dealing with the IOException and in this
case to another method but in this
particular example we're actually
leaving the finally clause in because we're actually doing some
processing just to check to see whether we
can close the file
alright so let's actually delete locations.txt again so delete that delete it before we
gonna break it yet again so click ok click on do refactor which will delete it now you can see IntelliJ
is smart enough to know that that file
was being referenced on line 21 but we removed it so that is
fine
now I mentioned a few ways of this code could break
including insufficient permissions on
the file or its containing directory in
the file being read only but we can
actually also break the code by
deliberately throwing an exception to
simulate somethings has gone wrong and that can be something that's
very useful to be able to do so we saw
how to throw exceptions in earlier
videos and as a result I'm gonna throw on in the loop that
actually writes out the data so lets come down
to the line after line 23 that's
writing the data and we are gonna throw an exception
their so type...
...and leave everything as it is and doing this
actually throwing your own exceptions
can be a really useful technique while
testing but obviously you wouldn't want to leave the
throw statement in the code when the
code went into production
now you can place throw statement in code
that you want to test to make sure that
your catch and finally blocks do actually
work but make sure again that you
actually delete them immediately after
you've actually tested to avoid this
situation where they're actually in
production code I have seen scenarios where
that has been done by mistake in the
past so we actually run this now so do that
you should find it creates a location file and it still
successfully closes it so we get a text exception
their you can see locations.txt was actually created and if open it up
and have a look at it we can see we've got the
first entry the first location and
that's consistent with going through
the for loop and writing the first
location and then actually throwing the
exception then the not that the finally claus or
the block got invoked and we're able to
successfully close the file because that
was invoked first
before basically after the
IOException was actually raise so it's
in other words it still actually
processed the finally clause to close
down the file
so you can see this is a very useful technique and
we are going to be using it again as I look at
different ways of performing IO operations
for now though I'm gonna delete the throw statements so that our code works again and again if you are
testing this make sure as soon as you tested it you just commented out or just delete it so I'm gonna
deleted in this case
so we've now successfully written the locations data to a file so its actually time to also write the
exits know the old way before Java 7
would involve creating a new file writer
object for the exits file then writing the exits for each location in a
loop similar to what we've done with the
loop for locations and finally
checking that the file writer object is not null and closing with a
finally block now the code has already been
messy and that would make it worse
slightly worse but Java 7 added a try with
resource statement that at actually makes
everything look cleaner and I just
wanted to allude you to the documentation
for this its quite useful to have those
resources so let's just go in there quickly
paste that in you can see the link on the screen in there I suggest you
do have a look at that so the try
resources statement again introduced with Java
7 so let's go ahead and actually change
the code that we already written to use this
try with resources just to see how much
easier it makes it streamlined it our code but the way we
do it is I'm just going to comment this code for now so that you still got access to it in the source code at the
last lecture of this course iso the
format we will now use is try....
....
you can see the format is different with having the file writer
object being created in brackets then we
put our loop so....
.....
....
..and I'm getting this error here and if you do get this
that means that we haven't got the right
language level set for our project and you
can see its saying try with resources are not
supported on this language level so if you get
that just right click you project here at the
top
go down to open module settings flash out briefly and here
you will see it selected version 6 so
we will select version 8 version 7.0 would have been enough in that case multi catch etc but which is
using version 8 because you know this course is all
about Java 8 so giving an ok to that should remove
that error and you can see the error is now gone so the code is a lot neater and finally block has been
removed because of the good things with
this try with resources it introduced with
Java 7 it automatically ensures that the
file writer stream is closed wether the code
executes normally or an exception occurs which is pretty cool and especially in this
case now when we are writing data it's
actually perfect for that so the documentation
that I just called up has a section on
the differences in the way that
exceptions can be thrown so it's worth
noting that this code does behave
differently to the code we just tried out
previously the try finally version
and the differences occur if an
exception is thrown when closing the
stream in addition to an error in the
try block
so in the try finally example it
would have been exception that was
thrown by the close method that was
thrown up to stack but writing the code this
way causes the exception to be
suppressed and the exception from the
try block is the one that is thrown
back up the stack so that does make
sense as it's very likely that you know
whatever problem occurred while opening or writing
to the stream is probably more interest
than the error closing the stream so in
fact the first error is probably the root
cause of the error when closing if you
think about it so using try finally
the first error would be hidden by the
exception when closing the stream
whereas this method ensures that the
first error is the one being thrown back and that's
highly likely to be the error that you
actually want to be working with so its a
subtle difference but definitely worth
bearing in mind if you are converting
existing code to use try with resources
so I'm gonna end the video here now in the next
video we are gonna run this version and just
go through what we've done so we'll see
you in the next video