So in the last video we went ahead and
implemented our test program and
got that up and going.
Now, what I wanted to do was
just show you another way of
these two particular methods,
the modify item and the remove item.
Cuz at the moment,
you can see they're actually passing
the position number that we want to edit,
and good programming practice would
dictate that we not require the client
in other words, the program that's using
the grocery list class to have to do that.
To actually know what the array
element is or anything of that nature.
We should really be creating a class in
this case the grocery list class that's
self-contained.
And leave it to handle I should say the
actual element numbers and from the point
of view of the calling person, it should
work much the case in the add item,
you just pass the item you want to add and
leave the rest to the grocery list
class and likewise for the search item.
We just basically centered the name
of the item we want to search for and
it did the hard work for us.
So what we're gonna do now is change
the modify item and the remove item.
So then, we just pass the item that
we want to either edit or remove.
And the grocery list
class will do the rest.
So what that's gonna require is we
go back to the grocery list class.
We need to create a method.
Because you can see that ultimately to
update the grocery list array list,
we need to pass a position.
So we need some way to find out what
a position for a particular string is, and
where it is in the array list, so we've
got that number that we can actually use.
And to do that is pretty simple.
So I'm gonna create a method, and
we're gonna call it modify list as well,
modifyGroceryItem, this
time it's going to have
just one parameter cuz of course, we're
already using the one below us, as you can
see on the screen there that's got the two
parameters, the position and the item.
So what we're going to do is we're
going to find the number and
then pass the the number and the string
to the modify grocery item method,
which is gonna do the set there.
So we're not gonna duplicate code
by having the GroceryList.set
in both methods.
So consequently,
what we need to do is create a method that
returns as that integer at that position.
Now, we have got a method that already
exists to help us out, the find item.
But currently that's a returning a stream.
And that's not really what we want, so
what we're going to do is I'm
going to actually change this.
And I'm gonna get that
to return an integer.
Like so and we're gonna change the code
and we're gonna get rid of the exists and
we're gonna make this a lot simpler.
All we need to do here is have one line
of code and the code's going to be return
groceryList.index, search item,
get rid of all that other code.
And that's gonna return an integer,
and if it does exist,
it's gonna return a number that's zero or
greater, in other words, zero or higher.
If it doesn't exist, it's gonna return
a number that's less than zero.
So what we can do now,
modify grocery item,
we can put int position = find item,
new item.
So is that item, does that exist?
And then we can put if position is
greater than or equal to zero, then
we're gonna call modify grocery item, pass
position, and pass the new item as well.
And that's the trivia, that's all we
need to do for the modified item.
So we've created an overloaded method.
It's looking for,
it's trying to find the item.
It's returning the number based on here,
returning an index of that string,
in this case,
the grace router whether it exists or not.
If it's greater than or equal to zero,
position that's returned on a fine item.
It means that it does exist in the array
list, we didn't pass that position number
and the item to the modified grocery item
method with the overload perimeters, and
it'll do the set and then it will
actually say that it's been modified.
Let's modify grocery, which is good.
We want to do a similar thing
to remove grocery item.
Now, remove grocery item is
a little bit different in that,
it's only got the one parameter, but
it's pretty well the same concept.
So we can do public void
remove grocery item.
And we'll put string item.
And we're just gonna copy that code,
same code.
And of course it's gonna
be item in this case.
If it's greater than zero,
what we're gonna do is we're
gonna call remove grocery item.
And just past the position, like so.
So again, the main item accepts
the print of this item number.
So again, we're not having to
deal with these internal numbers.
And determines whether it's on file and
if it is only for this,
in other words if its the position
returned is greater than or
equal to zero which means it's in
the array list, then we actually return.
So the other thing to do here at this
point is, with the modified grocery item
we don't want it really to have it
available as a public method anymore.
That is now an internal method that we
don't want accessible to anything but
the internal workings of
the grocery list class.
So that would be a candidate to make
as a private method by doing that,
it means that we're forcing
the people who are using our class
to use only the methods
that we want them to use.
So that would be valid for that and
likewise for this internal
a new method cuz it's dealing with
positions, you want to do the same thing.
So from now on,
I need to use the modified grocery item
passing the parameter of the name of
the item they want to have modified,
or have removed and the rest happens
as you can see there on the screen.
And we can actually
delete that line there with the remove
grocery item cuz we don't need that.
Literally we're just gonna pass
that cuz we've already tested and
recording this method, were testing
to make sure that there's actually
an entry there and
that we're actually removing it.
So that's the code there, but what we now
need is to go back to our main method
we're gonna find we've got some errors and
we need to fix those up.
So instead of asking for
an item number, what we actually now need
to do is actually ask for what the old, or
what the current grocery item
is that we wanna modify.
So instead of an integer, we're gonna
make the item number to be a string.
So we're gonna put .nextLine, like so.
That will read that next line.
And so we've got the old item number and
the new item number.
So we need to then change the method,
what we're calling.
And actually what I did was,
I made a slight mistake there.
What we do need to do is, of course, we
don't pass the position number any more,
but we need to pass the old item there.
So what we need to do is
put item number there.
Because we need to pass the old
item number and the new item.
So, we actually need
a method that covers both.
The item number in this case is now
the actual text instead of the integer, so
I actually neglected to do that last time,
so
what we need to do is go back into grocery
list and just to change our item here.
Well, it should be actually string,
we'll call it current item, New item.
So what we should be doing here,
is putting a test here to say,
checking to see whether the current item
exists, and if the current item exists,
then we wanna pass the position number,
and what the new item is to save that.
So it's checking to see whether
the current items on file, and if it is,
then we're passing the new item.
So in the case of remove grocery item,
we only need to pass the old item
cuz we haven't got a new parameter,
we're not actually trying to update it to
anything, we're just trying to remove it.
So, that should still work so
long as we're passing the current item.
We'll go back to my code,
the modified grocery item should now work
cuz the item number is being passed.
Which is now on stream the item name,
let's put that current
item name into new item and for move into
item name, and this should be next line.
Of course, it will be a string.
And there's no minus ones or
anything like that anymore because
it's all happening automatically.
And the other thing was to search
the find item is now no longer working
because that was returning a string.
So what we need to do to here is
instead of calling the fine method,
we need to create another method.
Cuz that fine method should now
really be an internal method only.
Because we don't want to expose that
necessarily cuz we don't need to,
we don't want to expose the integer
to the calling process.
So we want to remove that to make
that a private, only using the class.
But with that said, we do need to
create another method to enable
someone to actually pass in the name of
a grocery item and to return that item, or
to check I should say,
whether the item is on file.
So to do that,
we're gonna create a public boolean,
and we'll put on file string search item.
Then we're gonna put int position
= find item, search item.
And then we're gonna put a test here
to put if position is greater than or
equal to zero, return true.
So that's there is, if we do find
a record, return true, otherwise,
return false.
So that's just changed
a little bit from what it was.
We know, again, we're getting the search
item that we wanna search for,
checking to see whether it's there.
If it is there, if position is
greater than or equal to zero,
we can return a true to say yes, it does
exist on fall, or it's in the array list.
Otherwise, we're gonna return false.
So go back to our main item here now,
and we'll change this to put on file.
Instead of putting not null
we can remove that now.
And that should now work.
So we've now got searching for
the item that's searched for,
checking to see whether it's on file, and
if grocerylist.onFile, in other words
that's checking to see whether that's true
we're gonna say that it's found,
otherwise we're gonna put not on file.
So you can see now that by removing
the need to actually add the index and
so forth, and having to pass a number,
we're leaving all the complexities of
the internal handling in the grocery list
class, so that's where it should be.
Because from the point of view,
if you're accessing this grocery list
class, you shouldn't need to know,
wanna know how it's been implemented, how
internally these items are being saved.
All we wanna do is just
pass on the item number.
In the case of remove,
cuz wanna remove and it'll get removed.
Likewise, in the case of,
to modify an item, we need to pass
the item number we're gonna modify.
We want the, and the pass the contents
of the new item to what we want to be
replaced to, and so on and so forth.
So let's just run that now, and
make sure that it does work.
So firstly, we'll just add an item.
[SOUND] Add a couple of items.
Print them out, that's three, that's good.
So, we'll try the modifier now.
What I'm modifying is existing
item into the current item name.
So you auto name that modifier,
we're going to put, let's just try milk.
Enter new item, in other words
what you want milk to become, so
we'll call that cereal again.
Item two has been modified.
We didn't change the message.
But we probably would have
wanted to have done that.
Let's just check that that's been updated.
Print the list again.
You can see cereal has now replaced milk.
So that's good.
That's now working.
And let's go and try to remove.
We'll try to remove bread again.
Then notice there's no number, this time
we'll need to type it in, so if we type in
bread, we didn't have a message to
indicate whether it was successful or not.
But if we have a look out at
the results by printing them,
we can see that's been removed and
just to check now,
if we actually put in something
that isn't there, so we put remove.
Nothing's happened but
it hasn't crashed as well, so
we'll just go back and print the list,
that's good that's still working, and
look at the menu options again, so that
modify and remove is still working and
we should still be able to search now.
I can just search for eggs.
Found eggs.
So that's working.
And we'll try it again.
Something that wasn't there.
Bread, because we've now removed bread.
Bread not on file.
So that's the way that I
recommend to use an array.
Let's just make sure that you're
not putting the functionality in
the wrong place.
Normally, the functionality should be in
the class that has got the,
where the array list is being added,
where the entries are being added
to the array list, I should say.
And by putting it all in this class,
it's all self contained and we're
not releasing any extra functionality
out in the wild, so to speak.
So we're not letting other programmers or
other parts of the program get access to
the internal workings of the grocery list.
So, we've talked about encapsulation
obviously in the object oriented
programming parts of the course, but this
a practical example of why you wouldn't
want to do that and where you want
to keep that all self contained.
Cuz you can change out the implementation,
in terms of the array list you might
change to [INAUDIBLE] to change this back
to just a regular array that
we talked about earlier.
And you can actually do that.
You could change this whole
thing out to a normal array and
it wouldn't change anything from the point
of view of the people who are calling or
accessing this class.
It would still work.
Okay, so couple of other things
I wanna do when I talk to.
I just show you a couple of
other ways to access arrays and
to do one of those things we need to
add a getter here in our grocery list.
I'm gonna add a getter because we'll need
the array and I'll explain why shortly,
so we're just gonna add the ability to
retrieve the array list from there.
So what I'm going to do is actually
add additional, actually down here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm
gonna come back up to here and
just at the start of the class.
I'm gonna make that option seven,
I'm gonna add another option.
If we do go into option six,
we're just gonna execute a bit
of code that we're gonna create.
And we're gonna call
that process array list.
And then you'll need
to create that method.
Process Array List.
And then what I want to do is
just show you some other ways,
that you can copy one array list to
another array list cuz there could be
situations, where we've shown in previous
array code, where we'd want to do that.
The first thing,
we can create a new array list.
Array list
One way that we can actually do that,
is we can actually just create
a new array like so, and
then we can actually put new array.add,
actually add all, and
it'll be groceryList.get the array list.
So what that command does, that takes
the contents that are in grocery list,
the .getGroceryList, which if you recall
is just returning our array list,
our grocery list array list, and that's
why I added the getter there to do so.
That's one way of adding the entire
content to the new array.
So it's just a quick way to copy, instead
of having to go, create a full loop and
go through each record, determine
the entry and then actually save it.
That one line of code will
actually save the entire array.
So that's a really good
way of copying an array.
So that's one method.
There's also another
quicker way of doing it and
to do that we'll do another array and
that could be, array list, string.
We’ll call that one next
array = new array list.
And if you know that the array list that
you want to copy at the point that your
creating the new array list,
you can actually just
put in groceryList.getGroceryList and that
will actually create a brand new array
list that's initialized to
the contents of this array list.
It's pretty much identical to
what that previous line did, but
it's happening at the point of
time that you're declaring and
initializing the new object for
our new array list object.
So, that's another handy
way of copying things and
these are the types of things that
you'll want to do wherever possible.
You'll want to try to find the java
shortcuts to your code, so you don't have
to do this sort of stuff and creating
all this extra code that's unneeded,
and lastly, there's one other way to do it
if there's some reason you wanted to take
the contents of the array lists and
convert that back to a regular array.
There is a way of doing that as well,
it's actually two statements to do that.
The first one will create the array,
so it'll be string.
We'll call this on my array.
And you put in create
the new string array, but
to start off you put
groceryList.getGroceries.size.
So we're initializing it
to the correct size first.
And then you can actually
type in myArray = and
the groceryList.getGroceryList.toArray and
notice the to Array it's actually
got the parameters it's expecting.
What's going to be turning is
an object in array format.
An object will be what the object
that we're working on, and
because we're using the toArray
on the getGroceryList,
effectively that's gonna return
an array list of strings,
which matches our declaration on
the previous line, so we can put.
So what that basically does,
we have a look at our code and
see that's returning in
a registered strings in this case,
because it knows it's the get grocery
list converting it to an array and
that's returning an array of whatever
the elements are, and we need to put in
the actual name of the variable
that we want this to be updated to.
And by passing to the two array method,
that variable, that's gonna be updated so
my array will actually contain
the contents of our array.
So that's the precious array list method.
What I was actually going to do,
was to do some printouts just to make
sure these were actually working but
we're getting a bit late in this video,
it's getting long again.
So I want to move on to the next video,
which is actually the challenge.
So, I'm gonna leave that there now, but
the main thing that I just wanted
to show you was an alternate way.
If you wanted to copy array lists,
just to get you starting to think about
how to go about looking at documentation
and different ways to access things with
code that's build into Java already.
So that's the array lists
functionality done and dusted now.
And in the next video,
we'll finally get to the challenge.
We're gonna go through and
get you to consolidate this and
put this all together.
And issue with a nice meaty challenge to
further help you with your understanding
of array list.
So, I will see you in that next video.