so now that we have actually learn about the layouts that we can to create our
user interface lets take a look at some
more of the user interface controls
that we can add to these layouts now JavaFx itself has got a wide variety
of controls and your already familiar with two of them namely
the button and the label controls so
going to start with those two and then
we'll move on to other controls so what
I've done is I've created a new java
fx project I've called mine controls so
you want to do the same and just set it up so
the default code is actually added so once
you've created that what we gonna do is
make a few changes so firstly we going
to just increase the size of our scene so
I'm going to come over here into the main.java code and where we got a size
currently of 300 x 275 let's make that
much larger make it 800....
by 500 like so and then go to our sample.fxml file and in there we are
gonna add a button so going to keep the grid pane as it is but we gonna add a button within its so....
....
.....we are adding a button for the grid pane row 0 and index 0 and
column 0 and....
...so lets now run this it should obviously
work and its nothing that we haven't
seen before will run it anyway and it's a very simple
window their that its working and obviously the
buttons are in the middle and if we do
click it at the moment nothing's happening and
the reason is that we need to attach an
event to that and we will be looking at
advanced later on we are not going to be doing that right
now because we're focusing on controls
but eventually we'll get to the stage
where we can actually capture that click
and perform some processing when a click is actually
made by the user in this case so
I'm gonna shut this down now
so obviously the property that we've
used here is text so we've actually been
able to assign a text some text to the
button so that it actually shows up in
the area where it can be clicked but
what else can we actually do with
button control now anytime you wanna
know what properties you can set on a
given control its a good idea to check
the documentation that oracle put
together for that control so you want to make sure your accessing the java 8
documentation so lets go over to google I'm gonna open a browser and I can either give you the full link or you can
often find it easy enough by doing a
search so in this case we know that
working with the button class so lets type in....
...so we are gonna do a search for
JavaFX 8 as in JDK 8 button class and that
should give us a link and the very first
link there that's coming back is the
official documents from oracle you can confirm that its / 8 in the path javafx 8 whicgh is the current version click
on that and we got some basic
information here now about the button class
and usually when you do a search
like that you usually get the
documentation come up it's the first
result which is pretty cool at least
when using Google so as you can see on
the screen that right at the top theirs a
class hierarchy for the button control
these are all the other classes that
basically the button classes extended from
looking at the list you see that one of
the ancestors is the control class this
one up here and further up the hierarchy
as we move up there is also node as well and from a previous lecture you
hopefully recalled that the node class
is the base class 4 all scene graph nodes
now the control class is the base class
for scene graph nodes that the user can
interact with and this tells us that
there can be nodes in the scene that aren't user
interface nodes because obviously their are
2 types their but we'll be looking at
those types of nodes in the later
lecture for now we're going to focus on
control nodes that obviously can be
interacted with so that's the various
classes that collectively make up a button
now as you scroll down a little bit
you can see we get to the property summary and
in there we can find out what properties
a particular controls got now in the case of
the button control you see this property
their for cancel button and default button and
basically the cancel button is the
button that receives a keyboard
vk_escape press or if no
other node in the scene consumes it and the default button is one that receives
keyboard enter so a bit of a difference their when your defining the type of button but that's the two properties that come
with it but there's also a lot of
properties that are inherited from these
other classes that make up the button
class so scrolling down just seeing a list
of them you can see that we've got one here
for height which is from the region ultimately
is going to be the height of the button if
you click on that and scroll up and have
a look you can see height is actually filled
that is part of the region class their there's
height of this re-sizable node
and going back and another property if we go
down and looking at control there is skin and if we have a look at skin and scroll up again and have a bit of a look
skin is responsible for rendering this
control
so lots of properties here that collectively
do makeup this button so its quite a complex
set of classes that have been defined by
JavaFX just a good thing to keep in mind
is that when you checking out the
documentation don't just look at the
properties that are directly relating to the class in this case button you've
also got a lot of inherited properties
as well
that collectively add functionality to our button or to whatever control your looking at for that matter now
talking about skin that is belongs to
the skinnable interface and if we just
got up to the top again all implemented
interfaces skinable is actually one of
these so its an interface that is this
button
implements so if we click on skinable you can
see that there's also quiet a few classes here
that are actually implement the skinable interface
and it's obviously useful also when you
searching documentation to go into an
interface to see all the various
controls in this case that actually
implement this interface so what this
allows us to do is determine how a controller
should be rendered so every javaFx
control provides default
implementation of this interface but if
we wanted to we could subclass a
control and override the methods in this
interface or we could even create a
custom control that implements this
interface but these are really advanced
topics that we're not going to cover in
this section but I just wanted to make
you aware that we're not limited to a
control's default appearance or do a
set of controls that JavaFX offers out of
the box is certainly got that capability
of creating new controls or extending
functionality but let's get back to our button so as you've seen controls have lots
of properties and many of them are
inherited from classes in their parent
hierarchy so getting back to our code
again the Text property well where is that
come from if you go back and have a look at
our documentation and do a search for text
eventually will hit text and there it is
over here you can see that's part of the labeled
class basically coming out from control.labeled so all controls can have text as
part of the content inherit from this classic
label class so right now we can't cover every
property so what we'll do is we'll touch
on those that you probably most likely
wanna set now text is obviously one of those
and we have seen how to use that or how to
set the buttons text using this
particular property but the button can
also have an image
so either in addition to the text or on its
own and java has actually got an icon repository
that's pretty old now and shouldn't be
using real applications but will
actually use it for our applications because
the icons arep free and we've got
permission to use them so to get the icon
package I'm gonna copy a link and put
it on the screen and this link will be
available in the Resources section as
normal
and i pasted it in there their is the link on the screen if you go to this link now you can see we got a java a look and feel graphics
repository here and there is a download button so click on download and the link we want is the one up here click on
Accept licenses and I'm going to click
on this downloads so we can download it and
save this in my case to the desktop
just put it somewhere on your computer and then
I'm going to open it I'm going to show it in finder and unzip it so next now I've done that I'm going to
add it to our
projects so go back to the project and click on controls right
click open module settings and click on
+ and and select jars on directories I'm
going to navigate to the folder where
I've just unzipped that jar file in this case
its gonna be on the desktop going to
select the jar file and click on ok and
this message will pop up automatically that
Idea can't determine what kind of files so even
though their is images in there we're
going to choose classes because really
the newest match and the reason that
we are selecting classes here is that its gonna
add the jar to the class path which is
what we want so click on that point we have now got access to that
jar file and if you wanted to another way
of doing this would be to actually
delete this and ok that and we could instead just
right click click on reveal in finder
and it might be on explorer if your on Windows click
on that that's going to navigate to the
folder containing these files and then
what we could do is we could take the jar
file copy it and paste it into that
folder and we are going to the controls
directory where my code is paste it in
there and that way the actual jar file
is in the project which might be easier
in case you're sort of moving
or you accidentally delete the jar file from
the desktop so that's the case do the
same thing though you come back here notice
how it appeared automatically there right
click open module Settings
add it jars directory this time i'm going to select it
from there because its in our project click ok
choose classes and ultimately click OK and
that's now available in the class path
that will be able to actually use it so now
that we actually got these icons in our
class path lets actually add 1 to our buttons contents just to see what it
looks like so what we are gonna use is
just click over here we can actually go
into their you can sort of see them now so we got toolbar button graphics and their is a general folder
we got all these various images here but
the one we are gonna look at is the tip of the
day tip of the day 24 and if I just click that we can see
what that is that is that image there
we are going to put that on our button so
close it down and obviously that was a light
bulp icon so we are gonna add a graphic child element
to the button element and inside that an
ImageView element so that this actually
shows up so how do we do well we
come back here to button we need to get rid of
this closing tag because we need to add
something in there and I'll actually add the one manually like so and just
move that over because within their now what we need to do is firstly we need to add graphic
like so and then within that we need
add an image so......and then
we specify our image so how do we do that we'll put....
....
...and how do we
access these
well we got this in our class path we can just put.....
.....
.......and if we run that
notice how the icon has now appearing to
the left of the text which is pretty
cool looks pretty nice so just before we
finish this video we added obviously the icon
for the button you can see how we used an actual property to ultimately enable us to
actually put an image so that covers
what we mostly commonly do with a
button set its text and graphics
its  the two main things you
probably use it for so really button
can just have text or just a graphic
or both and obviously in this scenario we are showing
both on the screen so let's just have a
look at the label control before we
finish this video I know we've already seen it
so we're are not gonna spend a lot of time
onit but like the button will most often
change the label's text or graphic and
I'm we are gonna do it in the same way so we'll add a label...
to the grid
this time we are gonna add a column index one go
ahead and do that inside the button so....
.....
..I won't close it off
because we're going to put these same
items in the middle their so lets also add an image for
that so....
.....
....
.....and again
just to be sure in case you're not
following
ampersand / means to go to the root and by
specifying toolbar button graphics we are
basically saying to look in the jar file
which is in the class path / general is the
sub-folder
and information24.gif if we scroll down we should see the gif their and that's the
little gif that we gonna be actually using
for the label ok so I'll run that
you can see that's working ok we got a label and also
an image to the left hand side so I'm gonna
finish this video here now in the next view we are
gonna come back and we're going to make
a few other changes we are going to change the
color and font which we have done before
and play around with a few of the
other settings relating to this control
so I'll see you in the next video