in this video we're going to start
taking a look at streams which were
introduced in java 8 now when you
think of a stream you might be thinking
of IO streams like input stream and output stream but those aren't the type of
streams that we're going to be covering
here streams in this context are
completely unrelated to input output so
in this video when we referred to a stream
we made a sequence of computations so
another way of putting it is a set of
computational steps that are chain
together now we saw chaining in the last
few videos and we can chain predicates
functions and consumers we do something
similar when working with streams let's
start by creating a new console project
called streams and inside the main
method we're going to start by creating
a list of strings that we're going to be
needing here so make a bit more space
so I'm going to create a list of strings
this string....
....so we are
converting it to an array or more
specifically to list of string objects
and we're going to be putting in some
numbers here so...
....
.....
...alright so there's our list and i just use
the arrays as list method to create and
populate the list as you saw now looking at
this list let's say that we would like to
print out the bingo numbers that are in
column G now we could use a for loop to
iterate through the list and print those strings that begin with g but now that
we know that we can use the for each
method in a consumer let's have a go at
doing that so to print the numbers in the
root G row at the line 12 we
could start with something like....
....
.....I'll just check my code level and make make sure that is set to 8 project
....ok
that's obviously all pretty
straightforward we're using this starts
with method to find all strings in the list
that begins with g if we run this we
should see that the four numbers that
are in column G or the columns that got g in
them should actually appear so let's just try
running that you can see we're got our
4g number so that's working well let's
move this down to the bottom
alright so let's now add another
number but we're going to add it to the
same column but we're going to use a
lowercase g just to see what happens so
going to do.....and if we run this so we
find that we still got the same results
as we got last time so in other words
the g64 with the lowercase g wasn't picked up
and that's of course because our
test at the moment using starts with a
capital G so we go then changes and put
a number....
....and that should allow us to see the
fifth number that we added g64 is now
showing as well but lets now sort the
strings before we print them because we
expect g49 to be printed before g53
we're going to add each item that passes
the starts with conditioned
into a new list and once we've checked
all the strings we can sort the list but
wait we've got an issue here were using
for each which operates on one element
at a time can we declare the list before
the for each call and use it with the for each lambda expression argument let's try
it and that will keep the print
statement in there while we're doing
this so we could do something like
outside of the for each time we can do....
....
....now IntelliJ
is not complaining but remember the
scoping rules when using lambdas now the
scope of this lambda is within the scope
of the main method body so we can use
variables declared in main in lambda
expressions inside main as long as
variables are effectively final in this
case we're changing the contents of a
our g numbers list but the object
reference stored in the g numbers variable
doesn't change and so G numbers is
effectively final and therefore we can
use it within the lambda so now that we
know it will work let's actually remove
the print from the lambda and add the code
that's going to do the sorting and
printing so I'm just going to remove the
print out there and then outside of the
for each because we've got our list of
numbers we want to sort now in the g
numbers variable the arraylist that we
created on line 17 so we can do something
like.....
....
....alright let's first just try running
that see that it works and sort things
correctly and you can see things that
are now sorted in the right order now we
could have used an anonymous class here
for the comparator and add a for loop
instead of a for each but this is a lambda
expression section that's why we're
using lambdas here now we're using two
for each calls rather than looping we're
using a lambda for a comparator and we
don't need to specify the parameters of
the parameter types in any of the
lambdas
but sometimes like to see them there
for readability so I've kept them there
for the sort and print lambdas since
without them we wouldn't be able to tell
at a glance that we're working with
strings as we can when upper casing and
calling starts with apart from that
perhaps a more concise way to accomplish
what we want to do even though this is
already pretty concise code so to
create a new list gather all the g
numbers and sort them and print them
were using for statements so obviously
creating the g numbers list initially
on line 17 now we're then adding all
numbers beginning with g to the list and
we're doing that on line 21 we are sorting the
list on line 26 and line 27 we are printing the list
now what if i told you that you could
actually do everything there in one
statement
well this is where streams come in i'm
going to update the code to use a stream
and then we're going to actually discuss
it in fact what I'll do here is I will
actually just comment out this
code here we got the reference the old
material then do the equivalent
code stream we can literally replace
that with one line as I mentioned and that
could be some bingo numbers....
.....
....
.....that's actually it
alright so let's just run this going to
confirm that it works we can see that has
worked it still sorted but did you note that
the number for g64 is now printing with an
uppercase G we'll see what happens when
we step through each part of this
statement shortly but the first method
we call is stream so its time now to define
officially what a stream is
now we take a look at the documentation
you can see that oracle defines it as a
sequence of elements supporting
sequential and parallel aggregate
operations so what does that actually
mean well in practice a stream is a set
of object references the stream method
which was added to the collections class
in Java 8 creates a stream from a
collection now each object reference in
the stream corresponds to an object in
the collection and the ordering of the
object reference matches the ordering of
the collection now when we want to use a
stream that uses a collection as a source
well as its source the stream method
will always be the first call we make
back to the source code so note that the
source collection which in this case is
the some bingo numbers list won't be
changed when we work streams in fact any
stream operations that we use have to
meet two requirements first they must be
non-interfering which means that they
don't change the stream source in any
way and secondly they must be stateless
so the result of an operation can't
depend on any state outside of the
operation example of that would be that
it can't depend on variable values in a
previous step
so each operation should be seen as an
independent step that's operating on a
stream argument so the result here the
stream call is a stream that contains
all the items in the some bingo numbers
list in the same order that they occur
in the list so next coming down to line
30 we call the map method and we're
passing it a method the string . to
uppercase method but note that we've
written it is a string colon colon to
uppercase with no parentheses
now you may not have actually seen
methods referred to using the colon
colon notation now this this notation
is called a method reference so we can
use them when all a lambda does is call an
existing method we could have been using
them all along but I figured it was a
good place to introduced them here
rather earlier on
so the map method accepts a function
and from previous videos in this section
we know that a function accepts one
argument and returns a value in this
case we're mapping a string . to
uppercase method to function so the
method itself doesn't accept the
parameter but there is a source string
and it's the string object were using to
invoke the method so that's map to the
argument function and the return value
is a string returned from to uppercase
so another way to look at this if your a
little bit confused by that would be
this code here just going to paste some
card on the screen looking at this
statement here that effectively would
map to something like so....
....that's just another way of sort of
showing on the screen there and because the
string . to uppercase method can be
mapped to function in this way we can
then pass it to map method as a method
reference now there's nothing stopping
us there just delete this
extra code here now we could actually come
back here to the map and we could
actually written the old way we could've
done something like.....
....and that
would be valid as well but here we are
looking at this new format with the double colon so put that back as it
was before
so we use a reference for a method
that takes parameters the compiler has
to be able to infer what the
arguments are now we can't use a method
reference for the starts with method on line 31 because there's no way for
the compiler to know that the argument
should be G and for more information
about method references before we finish
the video check out this link useful for
you to spend a bit of time looking at
that and just going through that
information there
alright so let's continue on this in the
next video