Hello, and welcome.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the module Adapting Kanban within Larger
Organizations in the course Deploying Value with Kanban. The outcome of
this module is to provide you the necessary knowledge to help you employ
Kanban techniques more effectively in larger organizations or multiple
interconnected development teams.
First,
let's see where Kanban usage falls relative to other agile or
lean techniques in companies today. Kanban, in some capacity, is
used in 61% of all companies surveyed, so Kanban is pretty widely used.
You might want to check out my reference,
the 13th Annual State of the Agile Report.
It's a very interesting read, so check it out.
Here are the topics we'll cover in this module: complexities of large
organizations, adapting to large organizations, the order of work,
estimates and milestones, communicate, communicate, and communicate,
dealing with late dependencies,
handling buggy dependencies, and leveraging fakes,
stubs, and mocks. And lastly, point of view and the module summary. Okay, let's get started.