Kanban versus Scrum: a deeper look. Here is my approach to a deeper look.
What I really like about this module is that most of us have had some
amount of familiarity and experience with Agile Scrum.
That's great.
As I talk through the key points of this module,
I'll be comparing Agile Scrum activities and best practices
with Kanban's activities and best practices.
I believe this approach will help accelerate your learning. But into this
module, I'll have provided you a good frame of reference between Agile
Scrum and Kanban terminology and practices.
Here are the topics of this module that we'll be comparing and contrasting.
We will look at creating backlogs within the context of
both Kanban and Agile Scrum, next,
how backlog planning and work selection differ, then
onto comparing work in progress,
comparing workflow constraints, and that would be bottlenecks, blockers,
and buffers, so we'll dive into those three areas. Then handling
unplanned work and using metrics to manage work.
So for all these topics,
we will compare and contrast how each approach handles them differently. Okay, let's get started.