Let's begin with looking at how backlogs are created
in both Kanban and Agile Scrum.
How are Kanban and Agile Scrum backlogs different?
Well,
they're pretty close to the same thing. Their backlogs are in
organized, prioritized lists of pending features and tasks for
delivering a complete product.
So, no surprise there.
Now let's look at backlog management.
In the case of Agile Scrum,
it's the product owner who defines the product or the backlog,
which is a collection of features, use cases, et cetera. And the
process is typically facilitated by the Scrum Master.
The Scrum Master is ensuring that the process by which requirements
are gathered, added, and prioritized are followed.
Keep in mind,
the Scrum Master usually does not perform any analysis or backlog ordering,
but ensures the process is managed and run well.
Of course, there are exceptions to everything.
It is not uncommon for a project manager or business analyst to play this
role, as well as to provide other support to the Scrum team.
Now let's look at Kanban backlog management. In the Kanban framework,
there is no dependence on this rigid division of labor,
so contributors to the backlog may be project teammates,
customers, end users, you name it,
and this could evolve according to the project's needs and preferences.
Now, I'm going to put product owner on my list.
I like that term.
It is well understood by the Agile Scrum community,
and though Kanban can be more flexible, which I like a lot,
but having too many cooks in the kitchen,
that is, too many sources providing requirements,
may be a bit too much.
I prefer a smaller group, but that's me.
Remember,
Kanban is flexible to handle anything that supports the flow of work, so you
can decide what makes the best sense, and that is why I use the phrase
"facilitated by Kanban," because it is your choice on how best to handle it
with no rigid rules. Let's recap backlogs.
So when it comes to creating backlogs, they are similar,
and Kanban promotes a more open and flexible approach to who can represent the
customer base. That is nice, but season to taste, please! Too many
'requirements' cooks in the kitchen can be unproductive,
so just be aware of your customer environment.
I really do like the product owner concept,
and the term is widely recognized and understood,
and there can certainly be more than one product owner.
You have to use your leadership and interpersonal skills,
whether Kanban or Agile Scrum, to form a creative approach to backlog management.