Finding the optimal order to do things in a single Kanban team
with a single product owner may not be too bad,
but can you imagine doing that over many product owners,
teams, and requirements?
Let's see how we might handle that.
So now that each team understands the vision and overall project
outcomes and they have their MVP backlogs in place,
you need to figure out what order is everyone doing
their work. This is critical.
The order of work that your team produces is determined by the
downstream teams that depend on your work outcomes.
They will give you their preferences on when they need what they want.
Conversely,
your team should influence the order of work
performed by your upstream partners.
The bottom line in a large organization is that this is
a very challenging problem to solve, and there is no silver bullet.
You need a solid digital real‑time representation or virtual model to
make all this work and your ordered and scheduling of when you need
things or when you're downstream partners need things could change every
day. For very large projects, there would be no way to do the complete
planning without automated tools.
Here is a list of tools you might want to consider.
I do not endorse any tools,
and you need to pick the tool or tools that best meets your requirements.
And it may be that some tools work best for large chunks of work
and other tools for smaller chunks of work.
When you're planning the order of work,
you must allow adequate time of iterative planning to get the
planning complete enough to begin work.
The bottom line is that you need more than one tool to get the job done,
but try and get the fewest tools to do the most work.
This helps you avoid product integration issues.
One approach should be higher article ordering, that is top‑down decomposition.
We start with project‑based ordering. Order and
prioritize large use cases and services.
Here, the work items are very large use cases and major service
features and then determine the ordering of those.
This would be the overall ordering of the entire project,
independent of what teams work on what. Next, groups of
teams. They order and prioritize those large,
chunky features into midsize use cases and services. Here, the work items
are smaller and then determine the ordering of those.
This would be the overall ordering of each of the pieces
or chunks of the one above. And lastly,
the team determines the order and prioritize at the team level for its backlog.
Then you need to iterate on this and how I like to say it is wash,
rinse, and repeat until the ordering looks pretty good.
Do not spend a ton of time since things will soon change once the development begins.