Now let's go through an example of using a version
control system with a kanban board.
Let's first get a firm understanding and importance
of done rules in a kanban board.
The work in progress is done only when the done rule is satisfied.
A card is only moved from left to right through the value stream steps
when it satisfies the definition of done for that step.
So the resource in the next step cannot pull the work forward unless the
done rules are satisfied by the previous step's resource.
The definition of a work item being done is in fact the done rule.
The done rule is also known as the pull criteria.
That is,
it is okay to pull the work forward into my step and begin working
on it only if all the done rules are complete.
Each step should have at least two columns, work in progress and done.
This is the real reason why we have at least two columns per step,
so it makes it absolutely clear what work is in work in
progress versus what work is done.
Now I apologize for the term pull because Kanban has the
term pull to pull to work forward, and, of course,
a version control system has a term pull or pull
request for doing the merging up.
Just make sure you have both of those clearly in mind,
and they are in fact different.
Here is our typical value stream from left to right: Backlog,
Specify, Implement, Validate, and Deliver.
And, as I just mentioned,
before any work item can be moved to the DONE column
from the WORK IN PROGRESS column, all done rules must be satisfied.
In this example, we're going to focus on the Validate step,
and I'm sure you have noticed that each step has a WORK
IN PROGRESS column and a DONE column.
Now let's expand on the Validate step.
Let's look at how we may modify the value stream to incorporate the important
features of a version control system into our kanban board.
So we have R4 as a branch off of the mainline and three
work item branches as well off of R4, 345,
346, and 347.
Here is a close‑up view of the Validate step.
Remember,
our Validate step is our last step to be sure everything is
perfect before we give it to deliver.
Okay, let's drill in.
We have our WORK IN PROGERSS column.
This is our DONE column.
The work items have met all of the done rules.
That is, the complete pull criteria is satisfied. Now first,
I have labeled the column DONE and PR,
which represents the pull request has been made.
So I have basically added one additional done rule,
and that is the pull request.
And to make it more explicit, the column is labeled DONE + PR.
I have set up an area to collect the done work items targeted for release
4, and so far I have work items 346 and 347 in that area. And I have
another release, R5, and even one more for hotfixes that may be flowing
through our value stream as well. When the target branch owner of R4 has
merged up into the target branch,
I move the work item to the right in the DONE + M‑UP, or merged up, column.
And at some point,
when all of the work items, 345, 346, and 347, are complete, then,
and only then, will R4 be done because those were the
four work items targeted for release 4.
I did this to provide greater visibility into a typical DONE column.
I wanted to see things that were done and a pull request made,
and I wanted to see things done by releases.
Remember, you can set up your steps, columns, or areas in any way you want to better manage the flow of work.