In the previous section, we talked about late dependencies.
Now let's move on to how we might handle buggy dependencies.
So what the heck is a buggy dependency?
Let's find out. Unstable or buggy dependencies.
So when an upstream use case or service was delivered to you into your
backlog, and is unstable, buggy or has quality issues,
that's what a buggy dependency is.
Incorporating unstable upstream work items into your work stream
will certainly have major implications on your quality and
timeliness to your downstream partners as well.
Let's see how we might mitigate that.
If you are informed by an upstream partner that a use case or service is buggy
or if you determine it yourself and cannot move forward,
treat the situation like a late dependency.
You are not responsible for how another team determines its work items as done,
tested or complete, but you should share with them how Kanban defines and
uses done rules to ensure the highest quality, that could help, or simply
work with them on how to improve their quality.
That will be time well spent.
If you want to know more about done rules in a value stream,
please check out my course, Kanban for Agile/Scrum
Practitioners, but let me give you a quick review.
So let's first talk about sharing done rules with your upstream
partner, and then I'll show you another example of working with
buggy dependencies in your Kanban board.
It's very important to know what done means in Kandan, so what done does mean
is work in progress is done when the done rule is satisfied,
satisfies the definition of done for that step, and again,
the definition of done is, in fact, the done rule.
Now it sounds kind of silly the way I'm saying it,
but no work is done, no work is complete until all items listed for
that step in the done rules is satisfactorily completed. And done
rules equal the pull criteria, in other words,
work will not be pulled down the value stream by a resource unless
the done rules are complete. And two things cause those things to
be done. One is the person doing the work say in the implement
step and say they're done,
but also, before it's pulled forward in the verify step, that
resource has to say, I agree they're done.
If not, there's a discussion.
This is the reason why we have two columns per step, at a minimum,
of course,
so it makes it absolutely clear what is work in progress versus what is done.
If it's in the WIP column,
don't touch it, it's being worked, and if it goes to the DONE
column, then you know all the done rules were satisfied, so it's
just a very simple way to do things.
Here's an example of a done rule for an implement step. Code is
developed and unit tested, the specs are updated as necessary, the
code is checked into the repository, and a clean build was
created, or something like that.
Your done rules might be a little more complex.
The done rules are also visible by everyone, clearly documented and
agreed to by the whole team so there's no fuzz there.
To me, this one feature of Kanban, if followed, is a major quality booster.
So let's mark up this board on how we will work with buggy dependencies,
which is almost the same as late dependencies.
So I added an area in our backlog called LATE and BUGS. Next,
I modified the column name in the implement step from LATE to LATE/BUGS. Let's
say this purple work in progress item found an upstream bug,
and maybe we're consuming a component from another team.
Let's assume we're also using a ticketing workflow
system to manage all of our work items.
This one is tagged as buggy and sent back upstream to be fixed,
hence we are blocked.
We will move the card to the LATE/BUG column and
mark it block with a big B for bug.
The freed resource in Implement can now pull new work forward
from the DONE column of Specify, and try and keep as much
work moving forward as possible.
That's the beauty of Kanban.
Work is almost always moving forward. When the work item is corrected,
it lands into our backlog area in the area we called LATE/BUGS. Again, I want to
keep the late and bug dependencies in a separate area so we can easily identify
them and later match them up with the work item.
So when there is an available resource in the implement step,
I can move the blocked purple item back into the work in
progress and consume the bug work item from the backlog
area into my implement work item.
So you see the two items are overlapping each other.
And when we're all done with that particular work item,
only the original backlog work item card is pulled forward.
Is this the only way to do this?
Well, certainly not,
but it is certainly a place for you to start and evolve as you see fit.
And so the point of this slide and the previous one on late dependencies
is to give you a feel of the flexibility of Kanban, and you can evolve and
mold your board any way you want to provide the right visual information to keep the work flowing forward.