Continuous integration greatly reduces workflow friction,
especially in the Implement and Validate steps relative to our example.
Let's explore.
Here is how version control systems and continuous
integration affect the implement step,
both the work in progress column and the done column.
So first, the implement step work in progress column.
So our best practices will be to run automated tests,
do daily commits, and do frequent merging down.
Next, for the done column, done rules are complete,
merge downs are complete, automated tests are complete,
all code is committed.
So now we're done,
and we feel much more confident that our code is of
a much higher quality standard.
Here is how version control systems and continuous
integration effects the validate step,
both the work in progress column and the done column.
Our best practices will be to perform feature testing,
rerun all the automated tests if you've made any changes to daily commits,
of course, and frequent merging down, if required,
during the time the work item was in your responsibility.
Next, for the done column, the release is ready,
that is, if all the work items tied to this release are complete,
the build is made, running all the automated tests in the process,
and the build package is ready for delivery.
And again, now we're done,
and we should be feeling pretty good about all of our work.
Now, for an important point.
No two best practices of kanban boards are the same.
No two best practices of version control systems are the same.
And that's how it should be.
Use your creativity to evolve and shape your board for continuous improvement to enhance the quality outcomes of your workflow.