Now let's move on to buffers.
Now let's talk about buffers in Kanban. In our running
example, in the DONE swim lanes where the gray arrows are
pointing are also known as buffers,
and controlling the quantity of items in the buffer is important.
Too many work items in a buffer is a waste, because the workflow
for those items is paused, and as we all know,
waste is what Kanban wants to eliminate.
Still, buffers are important to have,
so that the work is immediately available when the next
downstream resource is free to pull more work forward.
So, what is a perfect buffer size?
Well,
actually 0, but 0 would only work if a resource was always available
the split second a work item hit the DONE buffer.
So in order to ensure there is work for the downstream resource,
having just the right amount of work items in a buffer
makes perfect sense, just not too many.
The concept of a buffer in scrum isn't like Kanban at all.
Instead, buffer might represent extra time to do something,
and in the scrum world, it's slack.
Slack is time earmarked within an iteration or sprint that
will be used for unanticipated activities.
Basically, you are setting aside time in reserve, like a buffer.
I have always used the term slack, and maybe you have to.
The term buffer is used in agile/scrum,
which is also a bucket of capacity or time for any
interruptions you may encounter in a sprint.
So let's say your team's velocity is 40 points, then we run 35
point sprints with 5 points of slack or buffer for those just in
case moments that we all know we will have.
If your sprint is planned for 40 story points and each person on a
four‑person team has signed up for 10 points, that leaves you no room or
margin for any issues at all, likely not a wise move. Though we look to the
sprint as uninterruptible, theoretically,
things can happen, so only by contracting for 35 points
does this allow a 5‑point buffer.
You can see the term buffer in agile/scrum is quite
different than what it means in Kanban.
Let's see how the concept of buffers differ. Let's do Kanban first.
When work is completed,
it is placed in the done column. When the next step has a free
resource, the done work is pulled forward.
Buffers only contain completed work ready for the next step.
With agile, there is no similar concept.
The buffer of work items is basically the backlog,
whereas the buffers in Kanban are in the done columns of each workflow step.
Buffer and slack are, well, basically the same.
Now, one more way to look at it, a backlog, whether scrum or Kanban, is a buffer,
since it is an accumulation of work just sitting there
waiting. Let's recap workflow constraints.
Both have bottlenecks,
and they mean the same thing. Kanban has better visibility,
though, into finding them and remediating them.
Blockers are the same for Kanban or agile too. They are
more easily handled in Kanban, that is,
it is a cleaner process to me. Buffers mean totally different
things. For Kanban, they are staging areas for work, and for scrum it's another word for slack.