Hello, and welcome.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the module, Applying Key Learning Objectives,
in the course, Deploying Value with Kanban.
Well, you made it through the course.
Congratulations.
The outcome of this module will be for me to cover the key
points of this course and encourage you to begin applying what
you've learned quickly and successfully.
I won't just reiterate things,
but instead illuminate topics that are important and provide key takeaways.
Here are the key learning objectives for the module
Kanban versus Scrum: A Deeper Look.
Kanban is a highly flexible and adaptable framework to allow you
to create context‑specific process solutions and is superior at
managing workflow‑type situations.
So when it comes to creating backlogs, they're pretty much lookalikes,
and Kanban promotes a more open and flexible approach to whom
can represent the customer base as well.
Backlog organization is similar,
so the process by which backlogs get populated are similar,
and the process or practices on how to organize a
backlogger are similar as well.
Backlog planning though is very different.
With agile Scrum, you have project planning,
release planning, and sprint planning.
Many shops, in fact,
even skip the release planning and just have sprint planning.
And with Kanban,
your planning is done every day during your standups based on the needs of
the business and how best to add value to the business.
With sprints, you have fixed time periods,
and it's a more rigid process structure,
and again, Scrum has been widely successful,
as it should be.
With Kanban though, it is simply a continuous flow.
With bottlenecks,
you have better visibility and root source to the cause of the bottleneck.
That's what Kanban gives you.
With Kanban, blockers are easier to handle and address daily,
but with Scrum, the sprints are a bit more rigid,
2 or 3 weeks,
and it may take more effort and disruption to handle
and integrate into a new sprint.
Here are a few more key learning objectives for the module,
Kanban versus Scrum: A Deeper Look.
The term buffer has a completely different meaning in each,
Kanban, staging area for work, with Scrum,
it's simply slack.
These terms are not interchangeable, so you need to know the difference.
With unplanned work, Kanban is more agile and flexible,
and for both, you must consider the number of work items affected,
what part of the workflow or sprint is affected,
you know, early or late,
and the overall holistic implication of the change and its implications.
For both,
it's very important that you have the necessary communication and
negotiation skills to build trust with your customers.
And here are the typical techniques to measure work.
First, agile Scrum typically uses the concept of velocity,
and for Kanban,
we will use cumulative flow diagrams as the metric for measuring work.
So with Scrum, it is feature‑based monitoring or measuring,
whereas Kanban is process based and task‑based monitoring.
Here are the key learning objectives for the module,
Implement Continuous Integration to Increase Customer Value.
Continuous integration is a best practice in software
engineering to integrate your completed and tested code back
into the repository as often as necessary.
The key word here is continuous.
The first friction point is between implement and validate,
and the second point of friction is between validate and deliver.
These friction points are not bad things per se,
but in fact, the done rules ensure quality work before you move forward,
but by also using continuous integration,
you will reduce or eliminate the friction and will smooth out the value stream,
thus improving quality and throughput even more.
Automated testing,
this will find and eliminate bugs from being pushed out to the
customers in the production environment.
You need a repository for the source code,
a repo for short, but also known as a version control system,
like Git,
and developers must be mindful to merge their changes back
into the target branch of the code base as frequently as
your team has decided as a group.
For me, that is daily, and it should be for you as well.
So at the end of every day, your project could have a perfect build package,
whether it's deployed or not.
That is the general idea of continuous integrations.
Version control systems are a category of software tools that help
a software team manage changes to source code.
You need to know the most current representation of the latest
production build in any earlier builds or versions as well.
It's virtually impossible for me to think someone is
not using a version control system, even if you are a team of one.
There are a ton of benefits around branching and merging,
such as concurrent development, source code management,
history tracking, earlier testing, to just name a few.
With merging down, you'll want to do that as much as possible,
so you are in sync with your parent branch.
And when you think you are ready, that is your code is all done,
then issue a pull request so that the parent branch's
owner will merge back into the parent.
The bottom line here,
have the process and policies in place that your team agrees to and will follow.
I gave you some examples on how you might want to morph your board.
Remember, you have the freedom to lay it out anyway you see fit,
and let it evolve as needed.
That is the beauty of Kanban.
Now by committing frequently, say daily,
commit events are like triggers that launch automated tests or other actions.
This can detect errors sooner, improve quality,
and ultimately make merging down or up easier.
Here are the key learning objectives for the module,
Implement Continuous Deployment to Increase Customer Value.
Continuous deployment improves quality by moving builds or
releases to production automatically, reducing errors,
improving quality, enabling monitoring and metrics.
We looked at delivery versus deployment.
With delivery, our value stream is complete when we have delivered our products,
whereas deployment is where the release or build is installed
into production and is being used by the users.
Please note, the industry and literature will have slightly varying definitions.
I like these those since it helps my teams understand the
distinction and expectations of each.
There are many benefits to employing continuous deployment,
such as eliminate manually installing software and enabling the automatic
monitoring and feedback collection of your applications.
We learned that DevOps is a set of practices that combine software development,
Dev, and IT operations, or Ops.
Its goal is to shorten the system's development lifecycle and provide
continuous deployment with high software quality.
My view, everyone should be using some form of DevOps today.
A deployment pipeline is a set of automated processes that enable a smooth flow
of work from Kanban delivery through production operations.
These pipelines are getting extremely sophisticated.
You can provision and configure servers and lots of
other infrastructure capabilities.
For example, there is Terraform software,
which is an open‑source infrastructure as code software tool.
It enables users to define and provision data center
infrastructure using a declarative configuration language,
so you might want to check that out as well.
Implementing continuous deployment will be a challenge,
and I recommend assembling a strong and disciplined team and
picking the best‑of‑breed tools to get you there.
Plus,
architecting a solid CD pipeline process is the most
important element of moving to CD.
Continuous everything, so without a solid continuous integration process,
you can't have the best continuous deployment.
One approach would be to start with building out your CI process and keep
your existing more manual deployment process for a while.
Then when the CI process matures, and you are ready,
extend the continuous flow of value to the customer by
building out your continuous deployment pipeline.
Here are the key points of the module,
Adapting Kanban within Larger Organizations.
Larger organizations can present challenges to development teams,
such as concurrent release schedules, larger team sizes,
integrating large components, systems, databases,
you name it.
Another challenge is the presence of a variety of
development approaches or methods, such as Kanban,
Agile, Scrum, Waterfall, or custom approaches,
and determining and assigning work to multiple team's
backlogs takes a thoughtful approach.
One approach may be to divide the backlog by work
types like use cases versus services,
and possibly even a hybrid approach of a little of both.
I like the hybrid approach the best.
The flow of work into a team and out of a team is
more complex with multiple teams.
This can get really complicated very quickly,
and so we need to pay special attention to the order by
which teams are fed work as well.
This is critical.
Here are a few more key points of the module,
Adapting Kanban within Larger organizations.
Regular, organized,
and consistent communication is essential and crucial
to the success of your projects.
Now this is often overlooked, so please don't overlook this.
With large projects in large organizations,
I strongly recommend a focused project management level of effort,
and in fact, even in smaller organizations,
that makes sense as well.
So please consider the role of project managers to keep things
moving forward more smoothly and professionally.
Late and buggy dependencies can just wreak havoc on
your productivity and flow of work.
We talked about how we modified the Kanban board to
better track late or buggy work,
and reintegrate the corrected or late work back into our value stream.
We also discussed how fakes, shims,
and mocks can be used as placeholders to enable work to keep moving forward,
albeit not perfectly.
Lastly, late dependencies can be really challenging and exhausting to your team,
but it will happen, so be prepared with the techniques we discussed and how to handle them.