We will first discuss velocity and how it's used in the Scrum world.
Velocity means the speed of something in a direction,
and in our case, it means the amount of work a team can produce in a
single sprint. In sprints, it is typically measured in user story points.
User story points are a relative estimate of the amount of work to be
performed to finish a task or a feature.
Velocity, therefore, equals the total points for a fully completed
user stories in a sprint. Velocity is used for both sprint planning
and managing your work in progress.
Velocity‑driven sprint planning is based on the premise that the
amount of work a team will do in the next sprint is roughly equal
to what they've done in prior sprints.
So if your velocity is 20 points over a period of 30 sprints,
you have a pretty darn good understanding of what your team can do,
that's 20 points per sprint. Because we now know what to expect during
the sprint, we can measure our work in progress.
This will help us track how we are doing for each workday of our sprint.
Let's see how we'll do that. For tracking work in
progress, you can use the burnup chart.
I am sure you've heard of the term burned down,
but I like to term burnup instead.
Both forms of the burn chart would be fine to use.
It is just that the burnup sounds more positive to me.
Now why is a burnup chart important?
It shows a quick and easy way to determine the health of a sprint, that is,
how well are we doing. A burnup chart provides a quick view
of the project's progress, or the release's progress, and
also the sprint's progress.
Burnup charts show the aggregation of only completed story
points over time, that is important,
completed stories only. And the flip side of that is burndown
shows the remaining story points for a sprint,
a release, or a project.
Metrics of burnup are tied to the unit of measure for the sprint, and of course,
they are typically story points. At the end of a sprint, their burnup value is
the velocity of that sprint only. Now let's see an example.
Okay,
let's go through a burnup chart. On the left, we have a 2‑week sprint over
10 work days in the green box. You can see the sprint backlog, 3 user
stories, 7, 2, and 1, and the estimated story points,
plus the completed or done story points in the third column.
And below that is our burnup chart showing the completed
story point by week with our goal being 44 points as decided
in our sprint planning meeting.
Our velocity is 32 story points for the sprint shown on the left.
So we can see that our sprint goal was 44 points,
but our sprint result was only 32 points,
12 points shy.
Is that good or bad?
And here are some reasons why we may be short of our goal.
The team may be too aggressive of what they think they can accomplish.
The business domain may be complicated so it took more
time to figure things out, the team, may be new to Agile Scrum,
or just be new to each other, that is the team may be Scrum experienced,
but just still getting to know each other. What to do next? Well,
you might set your target to 32 points for the next sprint or I would set
your target to the revised average velocity of the release you are in or
the average over the last couple of releases.
Do your retrospective, see what improvements can be made as well.
And don't forget, your sprint cadence will vary and it is not perfect,
and that is totally fine and normal.
So our burnup chart helps us understand where we are
relative to are work in progress.
We can see for each week how many story points have been consumed and completed, and we can track our progress throughout each sprint.