Now let's look at how Kanban typically tracks work in progress.
In Kanban, there is always a value stream of steps in a workflow,
so it's important to know how well we are doing in each step along the way.
Hence,
we want to measure the quantity of work in each step and a
cumulative flow diagram will help us do just that.
So Kanban measures work in progress for each step.
So what's a cumulative workflow?
Let's find out.
With Kanban,
we measure work in progress by typically using a cumulative flow diagram.
A cumulative flow diagram is a graph that shows the
quantity of work in a workflow step over time.
By observing the graph,
you can see the number of backlog items, work in progress
items, and delivered work items over time.
Sure, but how does that help us?
Let's find out.
So let's see why you seeing cumulative flow diagrams are very important,
or sometimes what I call CFDs. CFDs help you keep
track of your work in progress.
You always want to know where you're at and what you're
doing, it helps you identify bottlenecks.
That's really important to know where things get stuck. Remember, Kanban
is all about workflow, consistently good workflow,
and therefore, ultimately, it'll help you increase your team's
productivity and it's a continuous improvement tool.
And the CFD is typically an area graph that depicts the
quantity of work in each value stream step, but can also
be a stack bar chart as well.
Here is an example of a cumulative flow diagram.
Each colored area represents a workflow step from our sample
Kanban board. As you can see, the steps in the legend on the
right backlog, specify, implement,
validate, and deliver. The horizontal axis on the bottom shows the time
period and the time periods I have chosen are daily,
and the vertical axis shows the number of tasks in each step for that day.
Here is the backlog, specify, implement in the reddish color,
and validate in the light green, and lastly,
deliver. The size of the areas indicate how many work
items are currently in each state for the selected time
period, and in our case, per day.
By using the CFD, you can measure the amount of work your team has delivered.
If the area, the purple area of our CFD represents the deliver step,
then the slope of that line between any two points is your
average throughput between those two points.
As you can see between April 20th and 22nd,
the number of tasks per day completed was growing,
and if the top of the purple line was flat or falling,
then our productivity was also falling.
Then you can inspect and talk about the reasons, maybe you lost a
resource, someone was on vacation, you added a new tool, or you just
can't quite figure out the reason and it might take a little more
thought, but as you can see,
this chart can provide a wealth of valuable
information to ensure a smooth workflow.
I would look at the CFD every single day in every single standup
to look for any variations or any issues that might be occurring,
it gives you so much more visibility into the process of what
you're doing than Scrum does.
Let's recap using metrics to measure work in
progress for Agile Scrum and Kanban.
Certainly, there are other tools and metrics for each,
but I wanted to show you the two that seem to be the most common.
Scrum is feature‑based monitoring in that we are tracking story
points primarily. With Kanban, we are looking at the process and
looking at the slopes, the buffers, and other indicators to help us
improve our workflow.
And we are also looking at the number of tasks moving through the process.
I think this gives Kanban an edge up in that you have more insight into what's going on and can more quickly take action to correct.