Here is my point of view, thoughts, and opinions.
There is no perfect way to do anything.
Yes, you should study and learn the academic way to do scrum,
agile, and Kanban, that is very important, but then the real world hits you.
You've heard of the fog of war to describe the
uncertainty commanders face in battle.
It is no different for you.
There is the fog of your work environment to describe the
uncertainty IT leaders, like you, face in a project.
There's turnover, budget, issues, skills needed, delays,
downtime, bugs, changing requirements, you name it.
I think I will always be a fan of agile/scrum.
It is a powerful tool and I would never hesitate to deploy it.
Kanban is highly flexible and highly adaptable over scrum,
and I really like it too.
It's a very powerful tool.
I am a planner by nature, so whether agile, scrum or
Kanban, I think you must do a sufficient amount of planning
before you embark on any project.
So I do like the structure of scrum planning at the project and release level.
I do like the fact scrum has distinct and regular events.
It sets a good precedence and cadence for your team, and it might even be
easier to schedule your product owner for those events as well.
And it might be easier to keep your team organized.
But, again, Kanban is simpler, more flexible,
more adaptable, and more streamlined. Which is best? Kanban or
agile/scrum? I knew you were going to ask me that question.
Well, here's the answer.
Based on the type of organization, culture, business,
the problem you are solving, and experiences, one
might work better than the other.
So the answer is, well, it depends.
Here are the key points of this module.
Kanban is superior at managing workflow. If your team's practices are
a series of steps in a workflow or as conditions of completing steps
in a workflow, then Kanban is for you.
Kanban is a highly flexible and adaptable framework to allow you
to create context‑specific process solutions.
So when it comes to creating backlogs,
they are similar, but Kanban promotes a bit more open and flexible
approach to who can represent the customer base.
Backlog organization is similar, so the process by which backlogs
get populated are similar and the process or practices on how to
organize a backlog are similar as well.
Backlog planning is very different.
With agile/scrum, you have project planning,
release planning, and sprint planning, and with Kanban your planning is
just done every day during your standups based on the needs of the
business and how to best add value to the business.
With sprints,
you have fixed time periods and it's a more rigid process structure.
With Kanban, it is simply a continuous flow of work.
The notion of bottlenecks is basically the same,
but Kanban provides better visibility in determining the cause and the
remediation. With Kanban, blockers are easier to handle and work
through, since with scrum the sprints are a bit rigid and it may take
more effort and disruption to handle. The term buffer has a completely
different meaning in each. With Kanban, it is a staging area for work,
you know, the done column, and was scrum it's slack. With unplanned
work,
Kanban is more agile and flexible, and for both, you must consider the
following: the number of work items affected, what part of the
workflow or sprint is affected, early or late,
and the overall holistic implication of the change. For both, you
absolutely need good communication and negotiation skills to build
trust. Regarding metrics, agile/scrum typically uses the concept of
velocity, and for Kanban we use cumulative flow diagrams as a metric
for measuring work.
Scrum is feature‑based monitoring,
whereas Kanban is process and task‑based monitoring. Up next is
Implement Continuous Integration to Increase Customer Value. I'll see you there.