Here are my final words and closing remarks for this course.
Wherever your career path may take you, with or without Kanban,
always remember the bottom line is your ability to deliver business value.
Do not forget that! It is going to be one of your
biggest assets as a professional.
Thank you very much for taking my course.
I,
like you, have been challenged over the years in how best to provide
value to the business. I hope and trust that this course has been able
to provide you with the essential tools,
methods,
approaches, and renewed confidence to help you be more
successful in delivering value with Kanban.
Lastly,
I hope to see you again at one of my other courses, and I wish you the best in your professional journey, and never stop learning.