In this next section, we will cover pipelines.
A pipeline is a set of processes that enable a smooth flow of work
from development through production operations.
Now, for a slightly different definition,
a deployment pipeline is a set of automated processes that enable a smooth flow
of work from Kanban delivery through production operations.
So in the days past,
you were likely to have a situation where the Kanban
development team handed off, that is,
delivered their releases to a Kanban deploy team.
So the deployment team pulled the releases forward and began
installing it in a preproduction environment,
testing, configuring, and ultimately monitoring the release in production.
Even if the dev team used continuous integration with their version control,
automated testing, and the likes, the chances are is that the delivered product,
the release, that is, was simply a package of artifacts,
as I described earlier, and it was later manually
deployed by the production operations team.
That's typically how things worked for many, many years.
So with DevOps and pipelines, that process becomes automated and connected.
So, we went from the handoff to a connected pipeline.
So using modern tools available today,
you can now define deployment pipelines and automate
the entire process after delivery.
So in a sense,
there's not the same need for using Kanban in the old manor where
there was a clear separation between dev and operations. Now
Kanban can and should be used to handle all issues and tickets
that occur in the pipeline, including end‑user tickets,
one common Kanban from beginning to end.
So instead of a human pulling forward work from a done area of a step,
the pipeline automatically pulls work forward, reducing labor needs.
Here are a few common tools. I won't endorse any particular tool,
but here is a starter list to get you going.
All tools are different and may spread over a wide variety of feature sets.
So first, figure out your general needs and document them, and then
check out the tool's features against your requirements.
My rule for tools has always been find the fewest number of
tools that'll do the most work. Remember,
it's a lot of work to learn and integrate several tools together.
Now some tools may be better at Kanban, some better at
continuous integration, and some of them better with
pipelines and continuous deployment.
If you can find the right tool, or I should say maybe the right
platform of integrated tools, to get the job done, all the better.