If you haven't figured it out already, Kanban is a great fit for
CI/CD and let's see why. With Kanban, each completed task is
production ready and thus ready for deployment, that's the whole
philosophy behind Kanban.
If your Kanban team is deploying yourself, then you can simply move your
card to the right to a deployed area of the deliver step.
If you are handing it off to operations,
you could move your card to the done area in the
delivery step so the workflow is just fine.
Here are the key takeaways of this module.
Continuous deployment means moving builds or releases to production
automatically conditional on the successful completion of the previous steps
in the value stream. Delivery versus deployment. With delivery, our value
stream is complete and we have delivered our product and continuous
deployment is where the release or build is installed into production and is
being used immediately by the users.
Remember,
the industry and literature will have slightly varying
definitions. I like these since it helps my team understand
the distinction and expectations of each.
There are many benefits to employing continuous deployment,
such as an eliminate manual installation of software and enabling the
automated monitoring and feedback collection of your applications.
This is important.
DevOps is the bridge between development and operations.
We learn that DevOps is a set of practices that combines software development,
the developers, and IT operations, ops or production.
Its goal is to shorten the system's development lifecycle and provide
continuous deployment with high software quality.
A deployment pipeline is a set of automated processes that
enable a smooth flow of work from Kanban delivery through
to production operations.
Implementing CD, continuous deployment, will be a reasonable challenge and I
recommend a strong and disciplined team. Also, expect some additional cost,
training, and new tools and skills to get the job done.
Continuous everything. Without a solid continuous integration process,
you really can't have continuous deployment.
Maybe start with building out your CI process and keep your existing
deployment manual process in place for a while.
Then, when the CI process matures and you are ready,
extend the continuous flow of value to the customer by
enhancing your deployment pipeline.
This may take some time, so be patient. Up next,
adapting Kanban within larger organizations.
Lots of great topics in that module. I'll see you there.