Hello welcome to toil.
And today we're going to talk about the second main application for the second application is deep natural
language processing.
So first let's start with natural language processing or also called an LP.
So natural language processing is basically the data science branch that allows to do a lot of magic
with text text or even voice.
So if we talk about the classic natural language processing well that consists of taking some text as
input and returning as output a class like a category.
For example let's take the very classic example of sentiment analysis.
Well as inputs you can have some text like some reviews or some articles or some Twitter tweets or even
some messages whatever you want.
But the same kind of text and as output will return if the text is positive negative or even neutral.
So for example you can predict with an B if A review is positive or negative and this doesn't even have
to be binary your inputs can be some books or some articles or some stories and the outputs can be the
jars of the text of the books.
So for example nobody can predict if a book is a romance or a drama or comedy or even horror.
So that's the classic example of an LPN by the way.
I highly recommend because this course is to always recommend the first step.
If you're interested in a specific field to start with sentiment analysis and speaking of this in our
mission or in course we have a full section.
We have a full pars on an LP and we deal with the sentiment analysis problem because that's the best
way to start.
But then even inside sentiment analysis you can have some complex problems.
For example it's much more difficult to predict the jar of a book than whether or not a review is positive
or negative.
You can also predict the difficulty level of a text if you want to apply that to education for example
or you can try to tackle some even more complex problems.
But sentiment analysis is the starting point of an LP and then once you get some notions about this
then you can attack deep and P which consist of leveraging deep learning to make some fantastic applications
of natural language processing.
So let's talk about these applications.
So first of all you have machine translation you can basically not basically because it's not easy but
you can build a translator like the one you use on Google Google Translate or whatever you want.
You can build a translator by implementing a deep and a model which is the combination of deep learning
and natural language processing.
You can build this with a model called to set to Seck Moe and which is the most popular and the most
powerful model in deep and peak this is the exact same model that is used to build chapbooks and I'll
be talking of chapbooks in a few seconds.
But first be aware that you can use the SEC to seek more oil to make a translator from one language
to another and actually get heard.
You can find a lot of translator implementations using this model which is the main deep end of the
model.
And speaking of this I'd like to recommend an amazing platform to use to build not only DPR animals
but also AI models.
And of course deep in our model is by torch by torch is one of the best platforms with tons of flow
to implement deep green models and Emile's lets press enter here and why am I showing you by torture.
That's because if you go to pite watch tutorials you will see in the documentation and implementation
of deep learning for a.p which is exactly what we are talking about deep natural language processing.
So let's click on this and you'll have a great explanation on DeBerry for an MP with by torche one of
the most powerful and moreover if you're interested in that sector sick moral for translation as I've
just been talking about well you can just type here sick too sick.
And what will you find.
Translation with the sequence to sequent network and attention.
So let's click on this and there we go.
You can find exactly a to sec implementation in pine torch to translate.
I think it's yes.
From French to English and you have all the code and all the explanations well-explained.
And of course that's only if you want to go deep into deep and Oppy.
So it's good to start with this and now I'm going to move on to the second main application of DePinho
P which of course the chat but you can build a pretty smart chat but with deep a.p and the good news
is that it's going to be almost the same implementation.
Stick to say model for translation because you know it works the same way you have the inputs and outputs
and translation the inputs is a sentence written in French and the output is a sentence written in English.
Well for a chat both the inputs and outputs are kind of the same the input will be a question or something
said by yourself and the output will be another sentence which is the answer of the chatbot.
So basically it's kind of the same technique and almost the only thing that changes are the inputs and
outputs.
And so now how exactly does the chat but learn how to speak.
Well the way it does this is pretty amazing.
We feed the chat but a huge amount of text to chat.
But we'll look at all the questions or all the input sentences and all the answers or the output sentences
of these text and we'll learn how language works how we talk to each other.
And so these compositions can be anything you can train your child but on all the Twitter conversations
for example of 20:17 you can train the jackboots on hundreds of thousands of conversations taken from
movies.
And that's exactly what we do in our deep now because.
Or you can train it on any other text or any other compositions.
Basically what you only need is input sentences and output sentences and then the chat but we'll understand
how this works how you know you need to start with a subject yourself or anyone.
Then you add a verb then you add something which makes sense based on how the conversations work.
So basically it's kind of exactly the same as how a baby learns how to speak a baby or a very young
child doesn't know how to speak well at first and it makes some kind of weird sentences in the very
beginning but then learns by hearing his parents or her parents talking all the time how to say sentences
that make sense.
And that's exactly the same here to be able to chat with we train it for quite some time actually it
can take several days or even weeks to train a chat but so basically exactly like a child to learn how
to speak.
And so that's pretty fascinating because you know the goal of all this is the goal of deep learning
AI and all that stuff is to build a brain an artificial brain that is closer and closer to the human
brain how the real human brain works.
I can relieve you if you're worried about all this a conspiracy taking over the world.
We are still very far from the real human brain.
Jeffrey Hinton is making some great progress with the capsule networks.
This is this might be a new revolution in deeper.
If that works well well this will disrupt the whole deeper in theory but at the time I'm speaking which
is February 2018 we are still very far.
So there we go.
I hope you liked this introduction too deep and I'll definitely check out the sector model.
But before this if it's your real first step in natural language processing Don't forget to start with
natural language processing first without any neural networks.
And the model you need to check out for sure is the bag of words model which is a model that cleans
your text make the inputs and outputs in the right format so that your Leszek natural language processing
model can make amazing predictions.
All right so I'll see you in the next to toile for the final introduction of all these amazing David
signs branches which is of course artificial intelligence.