All right let's finish with the final and most exciting application of deep learning.
Yes this is an application of deploying but I prefer to call it separately artificial intelligence.
Here we go.
That's artificial intelligence.
Well it's more fun and more exciting to call it artificial intelligence.
But what it really is and that's why I'm also categorizing it as a deepening application.
The other word for it the more technical term for it is deep reinforcement learning.
Basically you combine deep learning and reinforcement learning reinforcement learning is a branch of
science or branch of machinery which is the foundation of artificial intelligence all the artificial
intelligence we managed to build today are based on reinforcement learning.
And when you add deeper into it your artificial intelligence is even more powerful.
So we can call it however you want artificial intelligence or deeper enforcement learning.
But anyway that's the final and definitely most exciting application of deep learning.
So how could I introduce you to artificial intelligence.
Well first there is this one book that I more than anything recommend to start your journey in reinforcement
learning and that is I'm going to write it up.
I'm going to type it here.
Reinforcement learning an introduction that you can see this is one of the first suggestions.
So where is that book.
Well let's have a look at it on Amazon.
Here it is reinforcement learning an introduction adaptive station and machine learning series by Richard
as sudden.
So this is a great book.
This will give you the right foundations of your intuition and understanding of reinforcement learning.
And I highly recommend it.
If you want to go far into artificial intelligence because even if this is the beginning of the journey
you must start well in order to become successful in this field.
And so that's the first step I recommend.
Definitely then the next steps to follow because I don't think a book is enough is to practice and to
practice you need to have the right environment to practice and there is an amazing environment for
this which was made by entrepreneurs like you know Musk and Peter Thiel.
This is opening a jim.
So that's the next thing I want to show you here.
Open a gym because it's hard to practice on artificial intelligence.
You know it's not like machine learning or the UCI and Mail repository which I'll show you in the next
section or the section on Python to practice making machine models on data sets here to practice doing
AI you need an environment with several things not only simple data in tables or C as follows.
Here you need an environment that includes input data and that can be some data in tables but that could
also be images.
Know I'll show you an example in the end and then you need to define a whole environment where you define
the actions that the eye can play.
The rewards that we give to the AI when it's successful and the rewards when we have to punish it because
you will see that it works on the trial and error process in which you know you give.
As I said a good word to the ear.
When it does what you want it to do and you punish it with a bad word when it fails at doing what you
wanted to do.
So that's what you have to define this whole environment with the input data the actions that he has
to play the rewards you want to give to the AI and other sorts of environments.
For example if you want to make a self-driving car well you will have to make an artificial intelligence
inside the car to make it self-drive well to do this you have to create the whole environment.
You have to create a map you have to create obstacles on the map.
You have to create basically an application in which you will try all this.
But the good news is that you don't have to do all this because here we go gym open.
I build some environments for you so that you don't have to make the environment and you just have to
build the artificial intelligence.
Then you can connect your artificial intelligence to the environment.
That's one example here.
And then you can test it out.
So there we go that's the best way to practice.
And now in order to get the knowledge and practice of artificial intelligence.
Well this book is a first step but definitely not enough.
You need to proceed with online courses so you have a lot of grades on and course on the Internet on
your Desailly on me or on yak's or Coursera.
We also offer an artificial intelligence course in which we do by the way some amazing and exciting
applications of AI.
We build a self-driving car in module 1 we build an area that plays the game of in 2 and a third AI
that plays the game of break out in modules 3 and the self-driving car.
We actually made the environments from scratch but the second modules Doman break out we use of course
this gym opening a gym platform to implement the AI because otherwise this would be a ton of work you
know to make all these environments.
All right.
So these are the first three steps.
First get this fundamental reinforcement learning introduction book then get familiar with the open
gym environment for future practice and eventually choose your favorite online course.
And now that's when things start to get interesting because the next steps for you now is to start the
real journey of artificial intelligence and this real journey comes in several steps.
First of all you're going to start with the basics of artificial intelligence which is learning that
artificial intelligence without any deep learning without any brain.
So it's like a combination of mathematics equations still based on this trial and error process you
know with good and bad words.
But without any brain executing the actions.
And that's the first step you need to understand really well.
Q learning because then the next step after cure learning is to combine Q learning with a brain.
You know we are adding a brain and that's where the burning comes into play.
Because by combining learning in deepening your AI becomes what we call a deep learning model and that's
the next step to understand and to know how to implement the deep Guler IMHO.
But the deep Killary model is the simplest deep reinforcement learning model that is the simplest neural
network implemented for an AI because it only has neurons.
Basically you only use a classic artificial neural network to build this AI.
And so basically this AI can only take some input data in the form of encoded data.
You know with numbers of vector of numbers that encodes what's happening inside the environment and
more precisely we say that it encodes a state of the environment which means that your AI is actually
blind because it couldn't execute some actions based on some visible real observations.
And therefore you guess what the next step is the next step is to add some eyes to the eye and some
eyes to the eye.
Well we need to add the convolutional layers in the artificial neural network and therefore your AI
becomes a deep convolutional Q learning model and that's really exciting because basically now you not
only have a visual neural network you have a convolutional neural network inside the brain of your AI.
And that's why with the eyes while your AI is able to see what's really happening in the environment
to execute the future actions which are predicted by the neural network following the convolutional
layers.
And that's already a big next step.
But then there is an even more advanced step which is to add something else.
Can you guess what it is.
Well again this is all about trying to mimic the processes of the brain trying to mimic the human intelligence.
And therefore we can add to it is some memory and therefore to do this you need to integrate what we
call an Ellas T.M. a record rence neural network inside the brain so that not only the brain of your
AI has eyes but also some memory.
And that becomes even more powerful and even more intelligent.
So you can add this memory and therefore your AI becomes a deep convolutional Alice.
Q learning model the name starts to become complicated doesn't it.
But that's what it is a deep convolutional A.P.M. Q learning model but that's not all there is even
another step again can you guess what it is.
Well the other step is to add something else that we humans also have which is a critic sense a critic
sense can be added to the AI and that's actually the most powerful a model you can implement today at
a time and speaking again in 2018 which is called the A-3 see as synchronous advantage.
As a critic agent because it not only has a brain with some eyes and some memory and some neurons predicting
the right actions to play but also there is also this other brain which we call the critic.
And that will basically bring this critic's sense to the action splayed and that adds even more power
to your AI.
So there we go that all the steps of the AI AI journey you need to go through the steps progressively.
And I highly recommend to not only try to understand them but to implement them.
Every single one of them and I'm sure there are a lot of great artificial intelligence courses on the
Internet.
But if you're interested in this path if you're interested in this journey that's exactly the approach
we take.
We build these successive steps of building an AI first a simple AI that has no brain.
Then we add a brain to this AI but only containing neurons.
Then we add some ice to the AI.
Then we add some memory to the AI and then we add a critical sense to the AI and we do that for very
exciting applications such as a self-driving car smashing doom or smashing the game of breakout and
now we're going to finish this tutorial on an exciting note.
Let's watch these two AI's playing Doom and break.
Remember for Doom it's going to be a deep convolutional cool learning and for Breakout it's going to
be a Nathu DC as synchronous advantage.
Active critic and Joe the show.