Welcome back into today to science today we're taking our first step in the Ultimate Guide to the data
science and the first step is statistics.
So you've got a pleasant image of a normal distribution which in my imagination is a classic I can of
statistics.
And so the question is why are we starting our very first step into the world of data sets with statistics.
And moreover it will be even more confusing if you've already taken any of our other courses because
you've probably heard me say there that you don't need to know statistics to be a data scientist is
that counter intuitive.
Isn't that contradictory even that on one hand I'm saying that we don't need to know statistics theory
is just on the other hand.
The first step in our journey is statistics.
Well the answer is quite simple.
I truly believe that you don't need to be an expert in statistics or know it in depth to be a data scientist.
In fact you don't even need to know most of the statistical concepts that people think you should know
or people spend a lot of time learning in preparation for becoming a data scientist.
The thing is that historically it so happened that people are quite a have this attachment to the thought
that data science and statistics are similar or similar or even the same thing and that some people
think of data scientists statisticians of their sides as actuaries.
And while historically indeed a big component of data science came from the world shows us that this
sticks with time it has the science has evolved so much and has taken on so many things from different
industries and from different professions that it is very very different now.
And you can still have that logic that logic no longer applies.
There are parts of the signs where indeed you will need statistics like if you're doing research in
machine learning or if you're doing quite advanced things in the space of health for instance.
But there are lots of other component or other types of datasets like visual or that sort of visual
data mining or maybe just a deep learning in application rather than going in-depth into declaring there's
lots of areas of science where you can do all that very in-depth statistical knowledge.
Now having said that I really also need to point out that statistics is of the core fundamentals of
statistics are going to be helpful for us starting data scientists because that will prevent a lot of
mistakes.
So that's why we're putting statistics as the first step in our guide because if you get to grips with
just the basic easy principles of statistics like just having that mindset of life for instance what
is a statistical significant result.
What is it will prevent you from for example reporting to your manager something that is completely
statistically insignificant.
Things like that are indeed important.
That's why we've put it here.
So let's have a look at the list and I'll be a bit clearer from there.
So statistics fundamentals the eight things we feel we think are important for a data scientist who
knows statistics.
Number one is distributions and it has some subcategories here normal distribution standard deviation
mean median mode types of distributions.
Number two is the central limit theorem.
Then my theory is hypothesis testing which has a score and T-test which we've identified as important.
Number four is statistical significance and Pyu values.
Number five is confidence intervals.
Six is AB testing and seven principle the 80 20 rule.
That's also known as that.
And number eight is Law of Large Numbers.
That's my favorite line.
So those are things that we think are important in data science inlike not advanced mystical.
But just general data science in terms of the stakes.
And now I want to apply what I said before that even out of these not everything is is absolutely necessary
to get started.
Like you can get really stuck trying to learn all of these and master them it'll take you a couple of
months or you know at least a couple of weeks to get your head around these properly and be using them
efficiently.
We followed having you know like reference materials and things like that.
So even out of these We're going to point out three the top three that you really should look into before
proceeding with the next step in your data science guide.
And the top three in our opinion are distributions and just the parts of what you need to know what
a normal distribution is.
A standard deviation is you need to be able tell the mean median mode from each other especially when
there's a skewness and distribution then you need to know about statistical significance and P-value
is very important because it again helps prevent reporting on things that are not statistically significant
and therefore driving bad business decisions or bad insights.
And finally AB testing it's it is important many industries whether it's marketing online marketing
or whether it's the health industry and so on.
And from there it builds the right mindset for comparing side by side different results so that's also
important.
And all of these are quite simple.
You can really get the grips of these things in a couple of days.
You can understand them.
And the main point is not to become an expert but to build the right mindset around them and they will
help you.
Going forward will just help you think differently about all of the data that you're looking at about
all of the lyrics about all of that insight.
And that's what we mean when we say that statistics is a good first step.
It's not a good first step if you're going to dive into it and spend five months learning it is a good
first step if you're going to spend a couple of days just to refresh your knowledge if you've known
if you knew these things back in junior high school or to learn them afresh if you didn't know.
And I didn't even point of law Ledger numbers even those my or my favorite of all of them because you
can still get by even knowing that.
So there we go.
That's the world of statistics.
And there is a list for you to look into and depending on how deep you want to go you can look into
more or less points out there and I'll see you back here next time.
Until then enjoy design's.