Hello and welcome to this new life and so we are adding for data sets in the previous tutorial and now
you code section.
We are going to split the data set that is we're going to split x and y into a training set and it tests
it.
So I remind that a training set will be the subset of the whole dataset which will train our future
model that will build in the next Etoile and a test set will be to test the model on new observations
that weren't used for the training and therefore it will be exactly like having some brand new observations
on which the model has no idea of the outcome because it wasn't trained on this set and therefore it
will be interesting to see the predictive power on new observations.
But we'll see that in the final story of the section.
But for now let's split this data set and to do this we're going to use a function by sikat learn and
sikat learn welcome to it.
It's one of the best machine learning libraries.
It contains an amazing collection of machinery models all into classes objects.
Functions that you can use to make your predictions whether you're dealing with regression classification
or clustering.
No new right now we're going to cycle learn to split the data into training set in a set but also the
model creates in the next tutorial will also be taken from sikat learn.
So here we go.
Let's use for the first time cycler.
And so what we want to do now is to take a function by sikat learn which is called the train test split
function and this function is taken from a module by Cyc learned because the cycling library is divided
into several modules.
One module for data pre-processing one module for regression one module that will contain some classification
models.
You have a lot of modules and sikat learn and the ones who want to use right now is model selection
because this is in this module that will find the function we want to split our data set into a training
set and a test set.
So here we go.
Let's import this trend to split function.
So we need to start with a from because we will import this function from sikat learn that has a good
name as Kaylor.
That's the name of the library.
And then as we said we're not directly importing it from Second learn but from a module of sikat learn
which is called moral selection.
And basically this model selection module contains a lot of tools to do some model selection.
That is to select the best model for the specific challenge you're dealing with because you know that
there is not there is definitely not the same machinery model that will work best for every problem.
Each problem has its own best machine learning model that will work the best for this specific problem
and that's why there is a whole model selection Mudgal anti-cyclist And so there we go.
As Kaylor and model selection and from this module we will import the function we want which is train
test split with underscores separating prenticed and split rights.
That's the function here.
The interesting thing to see is that we have our very first warning in Python.
A scale model selection or trying to split that is Trenta split is important but unused no worries.
Were about to use it right now.
So this trend to split function actually returns for variables.
The first one is X train which will be a subset of X containing the training said data.
That is the observations or the lines that will go into the training set but of course containing the
independent variables because X is the matrix of the enviro's.
And the next test which same will contain the observations that will go into the test set and also containing
the independent variables.
Only then why train which will contain the dependent variable values that will go into the training
data and eventually weightiest which same will contain the dependent variable values that will go into
the test data.
And therefore since this train to split function is now going to return for variables.
Well the first thing we need to do is get these four variables separately which are extra in X test
Y train and why test and now we can call the function because it Trenta split function will populate
these four variables.
All right so now it's time to call this function train test split.
And since this is a function we're going to add here some parenthesis by the way the warning just disappeared
because now we use it.
And so now we have to specify for arguments and let's check what these arguments are to check them.
We can go here just in front of the name of the function and then press command and control plus eye
to inspect this function.
And as you can see I just pressed Kim and I because I'm on a Mac and this automatically showed up which
as you can see contains all the information of this train display function.
So that's very practical and that's why I like spider and that's why I was saying that spider is very
user friendly because it helps you on the same studio containing several windows implementer model.
So I just said that we're about to input for arguments in this train display function and the first
one is the arrays which are respectively the array of independent variables that contains the whole
data set and that is X and the array and more precisely a vector of the dependent variable that contains
the whole dataset.
And so that's our first two arguments.
These arrays here and therefore inputting first here X the matrix of an been invaluable.
And why the vector of the dependent variable.
That's our first two arguments.
And then let's see what we have to input.
Well it's the test size to test size which is the percentage of data you want to include in the test.
And a common value we choose and which is the value I recommend is 20 percent.
You want to keep a large enough amount of data for the training that is to train your model.
And by large enough I mean 80 percent 80 percent is a good value.
And then you can keep separately 20 percent of your data to test the predictive power of your model
on your observations.
And that is why right now I'm taking the test size arguments and I'm choosing to value 20 percent 0.2.
All right.
Perfect So now since the days that had around 10000 lines that is 10000 observations that means that
I will have eight thousand observations to train the model and 2000 observations to test its predictive
power and that's good enough.
All right.
And then let's have a look at the other arguments.
There is a trend size but you don't need a trend size.
If you put the size because basically to size and size equals one that would be redundant.
But we're going to use this random state because this will introduce a seed in our implementation so
that when we execute it several times we get the same split of the training set and test that if we
didn't include a random state arguments with a specific value well by executing the code several time
we would have different test sets and training sets.
So you know it's just for you to have the same training center set as mine as to what I'm about to have
here.
All right so let's include random state here and we are going to choose the value zero you can choose
any value you want.
But basically if you want the same training set and to set as mine well just put random Seddiqui zero
will get the same thing.
And here we go.
That's actually done we are ready to select these two lines of code and I'm going to go back to avoid
we'll explore first.
We select just like them again.
We select these two lines of code.
And what happens when we execute.
There we go.
Executed properly and now we have extrem X test Y trend Y test.
So now I'm going to open all of them but I'm not going to show you this because this will take me a
while.
Let's do this.
And here we go.
I gathered everything.
So here is extra in here is X test.
Here is why train.
And here is why test.
And so basically what you need to understand is that we are going to train our regression model on these
two sets extreme and why trends so the MO is going to understand the correlations between the independent
variables of X strain and the dependent variable.
In y train.
And then once it is trained it will have all its parameters configured in a way to predict new observations
and we will test the predictive power on some new observations which will be the observations of X test
and weightiest.
So what we'll do is we'll take the values of X test and put them as inputs of the moral of our future
model then this model will outputs some predictions and we will compare these predictions with the real
values content in weightiest So we'll have operations here and we'll see if they're close to the real
values and if they're close to the real values that means that our model was trained well well enough
to understand the correlations between the temperature the pressure the vacuum the humidity with the
energy so that it can predict the energy on new observations.
That is a new data here that werent use any time for the training.
So I can't wait to show you this model we're going to build a powerful model.
Actually one of the best you'll see that in the next tutorial.
Until then enjoy the science.