Hello and welcome to the second challenge of the section The second challenge will be about classification
which I don't mind is another data science branch in which you have to predict a category or also called
a class.
And our starting point for this new challenge will be exactly the same one as progression.
We're going to start with this UCI machinery repository which again I recommend to use when you're starting
to practice as much as possible.
And then when you're ready start with Kaggle.
But this contains again a great collection of data science problems grouped into classification regression
and clustering and even other types of data science problem.
And so the one we're going to tackle now is a classification problem and that's why I'm clicking on
this to get all the data set.
There are three hundred and fourteen days said about classification.
And as I told you this time it's not going to be an energy related challenge.
It's going to be about health.
Another industry in which machine learning and artificial intelligence could have a great impact.
We're going to start with a simple problem.
It's to predict whether or not a tumor in the breast is cancerous and this is indeed a classification
problem because we have to predict two classes the first class is the tumor in the breast is cancerous
and the second class is the tumor in the breast is benign.
And so the data will be dealing with to solve this challenge is a classic one.
It's got the breast cancer as you can see there are four versions of this breast cancer data.
We're going to take the original one breast cancer Wisconsin and again we have all the description of
today's set just below the days that information here.
But what we're interested in are mostly attribute information because remember the next step now is
to figure out what you want to predict.
So I already told you we have to predict the outcome whether or not a tumor in the breast is benign
or malignant.
So we have a code for this.
Our class voidable will take two values to four benign and four for malignant.
So we have to depend and viable.
That's first step done.
And then remember the next step after that is to understand with which independent variables you're
going to predict is dependent variable and well all the independent variables are just above.
These are all these ones.
And so basically we're going to predict if a tumor is benign or malignant thanks to 10 independent variables
the one selected here and more precisely we can already see that we want to use probably the simple
code number because this is just an identifier.
And of course this has no impact on whether or not a tumor is malignant.
So more precisely we'll use these nine independent variables.
And so what are they.
Well we have the clum thickness uniformity of cell size uniformity of cell shape.
The marginal adhesion single epithelial cell size.
Forgive me I'm not a doctor but feel free to check on the Internet what this means exactly if you're
interested in knowing more nuclear plants.
Chromatin normal nuclear only and mitosis.
All right so basically these are our nine independent variables which we'll use to understand some correlations
between these and the fact whether or not a tumor in the breast is benign or malignant.
We can see that these variables were already normalized because their range is from 1 to 10 for all
of them.
So that's just a normalization that was done.
That's great.
The data set is some way already partly pre-processed but you'll see that we'll have to do some other
kind of pre-processing which will be related to the following.
We can see and I actually recommend to check that as well.
We can see that there are some missing values.
Yes.
And so I will explain this to toile how we can handle these missing values very efficiently without
losing any significance.
All right.
So to finish just before we get the data sets I'd like to give the full credit.
And thank you to the author the creator Dr. William Walberg from the University of Wisconsin and also
the daughter of the man Ghazarian.
Thank you very much.
And now let's get the data set.
Data sets and data folder and we can see that this time we have many files.
But the one we were interested in is this one breast cancer Wisconsin that data and if we click on it
here is the data set.
So as you can see when I clicked on the link it didn't download a zip file it with a data set in the
Excel file like what we had for regression.
So here what I recommend to do is just to press them in a to select everything then copy and then you
can just open a text editor like for Windows users notepad plus plus or for Mac users Sublime Text or
text in it.
I did that on subcontext open Sublime Text I pasted all this inside it and then what I did is I also
if you come back.
I also got the names here which are at the bottom here.
I added all these names separated by a comma because as you can see the values were separated by a comma
in the data and I added all the attributes in the first line of my text file so that in our final dataset
we can have the names of the attributes.
But then there is another thing that I did which is quite important in the data.
You can notice that we have some missing values and actually it is precise in the days a description
and those missing values are not specified by an empty space or even nothing there are specified by
a question mark.
We can actually find one here.
Here is a question mark.
That's a missing value.
The thing is that in this data set there are very few missing values there.
Only I think 11 of them and there are different ways to handle missing values.
One of them which can actually be very relevant is to ignore the missing values and to do this you simply
need to delete the observations that contain missing values.
And so since there were only 11 missing values here that is 11 observations containing missing values.
Well what I did is I simply removed these observations.
Besides we are dealing with sensitive data about cancer and therefore it could be dangerous to replace
the missing values by something which is another way of handling missing values.
You know you can't replace them by the mean of the values of the future or by the median or by the max
or by the men.
There are several ways of replacing missing values but here for two reasons I chose to ignore them.
First of all because there were very few of them and second reason we are dealing with sensitive data.
So I just did a control f or a comment F on my text editor to find all the question marks and each time
I found a question mark I removed the observations containing the question marks and therefore contained
the missing values.
And then I got the final dataset.
I saved it as a C as well.
And that's how I got the final data set on which we're going to train our classification model which
is great and boosting to solve the challenge.
So I didn't want to do all this in front of you in this tutorial because that could take a while.
You can either do it yourself or just wait for what's going to happen after the end of the Statoil.
You will find an article in which I'm sharing this data set all pre-processed without missing values
and with the names of the variable.
So make sure it either do the same thing or download this preprocess dataset in the tutorial.
After the article to solve the challenge.
Until then enjoy data science.