Hello and welcome back to the course and fight and programming in the previous tutorial we completed
the challenge.
Among other things we created this lovely facet grid with lots of different scatterplot on it.
So which allows us to analyze how audience ratings and critic rating has evolved over the years for
different genres.
We also created some amazing charts some while in plot a bomb explodes.
Cady diagrams are kiddie plots more kitty applause applause.
We created some amazing histograms which took us quite some effort to create and we did some analysis
.
So quite a lot of things were done and more or less the challenge is over.
However I still wanted to throw in a few bonus tutorials to demonstrate how we can build dashboards
in Python.
Now I know we don't really need to build a dashboard for this challenge it wasn't requested but at the
same time it's really fun and useful topic.
So if you are in a rush or if this you find that this is not something you need then feel free to skip
these 2 tutorials they're not compulsory but if you'd like to learn some additional skills and hacks
and tricks then stick around and we're going to kick it off right now.
All right.
So what is a dashboard.
How do we build a dashboard in Python.
Well a dashboard is a combination of charts.
For instance this is a radio dashboard.
This even though it's just a figure of two plots is actually a dashboard because it combines two different
types of flaws two different sets of information and so on.
So that's what we're going to be focused on.
We're going to be using the subplots function.
Let me zoom in here so we can see better.
We're going to be using the subplots function to create dashboards and populate those dashboards with
different types of chart.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We're going to need plots dot subplots we might as well just copy it now.
And let's kick things off.
So here I'm going to I'm going to add are guilty subplots.
You know what for consistency purposes I'm actually going to copy this whole hit or that we use for
our imports.
So that way we don't miss out.
So even if you jump just into this tutorial you'll be able to follow along as well.
So I'm just going to put this above here and then let's get rid of this for now.
So there is our hitter.
Just make sure you run that and that prepares our workspace for creating dashboard.
And now we're going to use BLT dots or plot.
It returns two values.
F is our figure axis or axes is the axes and T Dot subplots and let's say we want a dashboard with two
by two.
So four in total four plots on the dashboard and you can see it's rather small right now so let's increase
settler's go and say Fig's size equals 15 15.
So if I were on that.
Now you can see that it's bigger.
OK.
That's good.
And what we want to do now is we want to start populating these.
But before we do let's change the styling let's say as soon as Dot said style so Seaborn that said style
and all say dark grid.
So now we have the grid.
OK beautiful so what are we going to populate these plots with.
Well let's go through our chart and let's decide which ones we might want to see in the final dashboard
.
It's totally up to you you can choose any one of them or just follow along with the code.
So what I'm going to choose I would like to see this one this one so these two that we've already put
in dush in our previous dashboard then I'd like to see the violent plot in the results and to finish
off.
I would like to see this beautiful Katipunan.
I know there's quite a few Kaytee plus but they are quite useful.
And that's kind of going to be the theme of our dashboard.
So what are we going to do here.
We're going to actually copy these lines of code and we'll just take that all of that including the
limit and move it over here.
There you go.
So now we've got K-1 equals as soon as Cady plot.
Movies budget millions movies.
Audience ratings.
And then a x equals x rays axes.
So this axes and this time it's not just 0 because as you remember we discussed axes is now a two dimensional
object.
So we have to parse the exact coordinates we want to put this chart over here so it will be 0 0.
And just so that it looks better.
We're going to move that to a new line some of this one here.
So the second one we want to put it on the second spot so there's going to be road zero column one.
Remember numeration starts from zero and then said lym is going to be minus 22 and 60 so will keep it
like that for now.
But notice that we're not using share X for they're sharing the access and therefore this limit will
only apply to the first plot.
So let's have a look at that by click shift enter.
You'll see that there it is.
So the limit did apply only to the first part minus 20 to 160 the second plot is still up to 300 or
above.
So we can either show the axes but because we've got other plots involved it might not be the best idea
right now.
So until we know how they look and what axes they request we are just going to set the X limb for the
second plot by itself.
So there we go.
That's that's our first plot that's our second plot.
Now we want to populate these two.
So let's put the violent plot in here.
Go up.
So for example if you want to mix it up you can use a box plot just to practice something else.
Or if you'd like for long with the code as it is then feel free just to use the while employed as well
.
So if I scroll down now as you can see it's very straightforward you just copy the code that you've
already created and you place it into your charts.
Just don't forget to specify a x as Xs.
Now with the violin Plaut we also need to finish off this code.
So if I just run this now you'll notice that of course it's not specific.
Even though the van plot is being added to the dashboard it's all being added where we wanted to be
added is just being added to the last plot that was created on the dashboard.
The last plotting space.
So we need to specify exactly where we wanted to go.
Will say X equals axes and then we'll say first.
So this is our first roll call them number zero.
So if I do that and run this doesn't really matter what name you give to the Plaut they go.
Now it's been placed in the correct space.
OK so I copy this remove that there.
All right.
And finally we want to put one more in here.
So let's go ahead and select that last Katie plot that we wanted to add this one over here.
The beautiful Katy plot.
Got two parts to it.
Is got the feeling and then it's got the outline so we're going to copy everything because as you remember
we can put two plots into one plotting space.
So if my space specify this here so for now let's comment this out.
We won't be running this right now.
This will call.
It's called K4.
As NSK the plot.
That's correct.
And then we just want to add where exactly it will go.
So here will say X-C cause let's fix this up a bit.
Sickles axes.
So this one's going to roll one column one so far on this.
That's going to add the plot to that last block.
That's correct.
But now you can see it's a bit edgy and that's because we haven't added the outline as you remember
we can add several plots into one.
So for instance I can add this k k for B S and S K D plot and then we're going to just keep it like
that and then just for example I'm going to say axes just to explain the whole concept.
I'm going to say X He's 0 0 so I'm going to add this outline onto the wrong plot.
I'm going to add it to here and we'll see what that looks like.
There you go.
So you can see that outline that was supposed to be out on top of this plot has been added to the wrong
plot but it's just to illustrate that these two concepts are these two Charsadda separate the filling
and the outline.
We're just adding it for styling purposes and now we're going to overlay it on top of our actual plot
here.
So just remember how that looks and looks a bit edgy.
It's not a smooth and an outline doesn't look like there's a contour so far on this it will make it
look much neater.
There you go you can now see it looks very nice and neat and very well presented.
So that's exactly what we wanted.
So those are the things we want.
Now here we want to fix this up because we don't want to see that we want to just see the plots against
a plot show BLT dog show.
OK so now we don't see that line at the top we just see the plot.
That's that's beautiful.
And that is what I wanted to discuss here so you can see that it's pretty simple to add charts that
you've already created into a dashboard you just pretty much copy the code and then add this line a
x equals X is now one more thing that we need to look at.
Here is what if we want to add a plot that is not a seaborn plot into our diagram.
So here you can see that in the dashboard we've got only seaborne plots they're all asinus.
What if you want to add one that's not a seaborn plotless go find one and see how we can at it.
So let's say for instance let's say this plot plotted on hist for the critic ratings right.
So we're going take this and you know that's.
And now I'm going to copy it into our code just like we did with the seaborne part.
So let's say I want to replace this last diagram with that plot that I have copied just now.
So let's say there it is.
And I would just do the same old say Komarr a x equals x he's won one so far on this which he'll see
is I will get an error.
You get an error.
And what it's saying is enter got multiple values from argument a x.
So basically and there is nothing in our plot what is happening here is that for non seaborne plots
the procedures are a bit different.
It's so Seaborn actually it's a situation where there was a standard approach and then Seaborn had to
change legs that's a way to think about it that a seaborne plus use a different approach to the standard
approach.
So the standard approach is actually not to specify asexuals axes but it's to say axes.
So instead of PBT down here as you say axes one one that you specify where you want to plot you were
specifying we're going to plot in here and then you say Daut and then you specify a char so if I run
this this time it should work.
Let's have a look.
So if I scroll down you can see that our charts in there are we didn't comment out the outline.
So let's come in and outline it looks pretty cool though.
So if I scroll down you can see there's our chart.
It has been placed in there so that is the standard pipelined approach and you can look up more of this
information if you check out the PI plot page.
So let me show you this page.
All right.
So this is the map plot Lippa page for pi plot or it's got some examples of the subplots So this is
subplot demo and you can go you can find it at my pod libbed org slash example slush pile AB underscore
examples slash subplots underscore demo dot html or you can just google for it.
It'll be one of the top results.
And so here's a few examples of how the dashboards that they have been created here and you can read
through these to get a better grasp around Pipelet.
Or actually subplots how to use them.
But in this case what we did is we just said the plot space that we want to add a char to Daut and then
the chart that we want to add.
So that's how it works with seaborne you can do the same thing.
So for instance if I wanted to let's say with a violent plot I wanted to do the same thing.
Let's say I want to remove this and instead of S as well and plot out say a second so remove that instead
of s and as that will implode.
I would say same thing axes 1 0 1 plus if I try to run this then that will cause an error.
Now you can see that that doesn't work so well in plot doesn't appear and actually the second plot doesn't
appear either because it comes after the world plot.
So what is going on here is that you can call violin Plaut from axes because axes is a PI plot object
.
So this is important on this and this is the fundamentals around how does all this stuff work so axes
is being created over here right so f axes comes from Piel tee'd dot subplots.
So basically you can see right away that axes just as f is a PI plot generated object.
So that means axes is created within the pipeline package.
And if it does have access to certain functions and methods then they will all be PI plot.
The thing about seaborne is that Seaborn is an upgrade on top of pipelined.
It's like an add on.
So therefore X has no way of knowing about things that are contained within the seaborne package because
Pipelet is a basis package seaborne comes on top of pipeline.
So xes has no visibility of Katie Plaut a violin Plaut and so on.
So even though you can call axes dot hissed you cannot call axes dot violently because hearsay is also
part of the pipeline package right.
It's not part of Seaborn as part of pipelined and therefore axes does have visibility of hist but axes
will not have visibility or bandplan.
So hopefully all that makes sense and thats why for the violent plot we need to say Zed equals violent
Plaut and then here will say x.
This is the way that the seaborne guys have circumvented that problem that you cannot call axes not
violent plots so theyre saying how about we just pause an extra argument inside our Seaborn functions
so here we get to say S and S in all Seaborn functions and will called a X and that will specify where
it needs to go.
So its kind of two different methodologies and the only reason they're different is because seaborne
came later than pipelined and therefore had to come up with a new approach and approach to circumvent
the problem that Pipelet objects don't have visibility of Seaborn objects.
So if I run this you'll see that everything works just fine.
All right so now let's let's remove this distribution and let's replace it with our Keady plot that
we wanted originally but that was just to illustrate that indeed we can put any type of plot's into
our dashboard sometimes it might just require a bit of research just to make sure how that plot is going
to be placed in there what the methodology is because some packages come before others some come after
.
But at the end of the day it's all possible and you get some beautiful dashboards as a result.
So let's see this one pop up.
There it is.
I might zoom out a bit.
Let's put it 100 percent.
There you go so you can see it's a lovely lovely dashboard which you can including report.
So hopefully enjoy this tutorial we had some practice.
We put some charts together you could see it was pretty simple.
Just after you've prepared those charges you just copy them into a dashboard.
Also we talked about some theory some fundamentals how things happen in the background or in the back
end of Pi thin white packages some some packages have some certain approaches and some packages.
So some other approaches and also we had a look at where you can find more information on subplots.
So lots of information this tutorial.
Hope you're digesting this quite well.
Practice that tried put in some different Plus we've created lots of plots in this section try put some
different plots into your dashboard make you maybe make a dashboard bigger maybe make it a three by
three or four by three.
Try adding different Plus see how you go.
And in the next tutorial we're going to have some exciting new features we're going to learn how to
style our dashboards so I'll give you some tips on styling dashboards to make them look fantastic and
I look forward to seeing you there.
Until next time happy coding
.