Alone.
Welcome back to the course on mice and programming.
Today is going to be a quick tutorial we're going to learn how to rename or old daughter frame.
All right let's get started right away.
First thing we're going to do is we're going to look at our table and we're going to use the head function
because that will save us the trouble through all of scrolling through the whole doorframe so that our
head is our doorframe so we can see that the column names here that are displayed here and they all
have spaces some of them for instance here the are is not a capital they use on a couple So it's not
consistent.
And often you'll find that when you upload a data set you might need to perform some cleaning.
So what I'm going to go into Jeff on cleaning yet because we haven't mastered Python to the level that
we need to to understand how to perform those kind of things.
But at the same time.
For this section we are going to need to rename the columns.
You will see this further down in the next upcoming tutorial so why don't we learn how to do it right
now.
All right.
So how do we access how columns were very talked about this stat start columns.
And if you run that you'll get your columns beautiful.
And now what we want to do is we want to rename our columns.
It's very simple to do you just take this object as well and you just say stats columns equals and you
can give them a different name so you can say pretty much anything.
A.
So we've got two columns five columns say A B C D and E.
So if I run that and I look at stats Daut head you'll see that the colors have been renamed as simple
as that.
But of course we don't want those names we're just going to copy this these names from here so this
is going to be a list of names.
And when we put this over here by the way I would like to show you right away how to create a new line
in Python so or tenue your code on your line so let's say I want to continue my code like that.
I totally can.
In Jupiter notebooks I can write a way without any problems because the cell gets run everything in
the cell gets run if you want to do it in Python the way the correct way to do it is put a backslash
or here.
And that way your code will get continued onto the next line.
All right.
And now we're just going to change the names so they're consistent we're going to remove the spaces
and you will notice why further down in the section and we're going to replace lower case letters with
the Capitals birthrate Internet users and income group.
Beautiful.
So let's run that let's run that line.
And if you look at the top Rosenau it's all consistent and it looks lovely.
All right so that's how your name your columns in your doorframe.
I look forward to your the next Tauriel.
And until then happy coding