Hello and welcome back to the course in Python programming and today we're talking about boolean variables
and operators.
So let's dive straight into it.
So I'm going to create in your notebook file in your notebook and this one we're going to call boolean
variables and operators.
All right.
So what are boolean variables or values in Python.
So Boullion are basically logical another word for gillion is logical values.
So we have two values in Python they are true and false and they basically represent answers to certain
questions that you can ask that's like a very simple way of thinking about it.
And let's have a look at a couple of examples So let's say I want to check for is less than five is
for less than five.
Then if I run this line I'll get an answer which is true which is great because four is indeed less
than five.
Let's have a look at 10 and 100 is 10 greater than 100.
If I run that I will get false because indeed 10 is not greater than 100.
And now let's check if four equals to five.
Run that line.
Again we get false because four is not equal to five.
So those are just some examples of boolean operators variables.
So now we're going to have a look at the operators that we can actually use in Python.
So we've really just talked about the equals So that's a double equal sign.
Be careful here because in some languages a single equal sign is a logical operator so to check four
equals five you just put a single equal sign like that.
But in this case it's not the right approach.
In Python has to be double equal sign that is an operator that checks if two values are equal then the
next one is the opposite so the not equal in Python you can approach it in two ways so the summation
Mark equals or you can just type in the brackets.
So less than and then more than and the this operator and this operator are exactly the same.
They are from identical function.
They will check if what is on the left is not equal to what is on the right.
Then we have is less then than we have is greater than Then we have less than or equal to greater than
or equal to.
And then we have and or let me scroll a bit and we have not.
So with these arms also be careful because in programming languages especially if you're coming from
a programming language like are you would have and like that and all like that well in Python they mean
different things.
They're actually bitwise operators so they're not used for logical expressions the correct way of evaluating
logical expressions are creating logical expressions is using the and or and not keywords so be careful
about that.
But otherwise it's very straightforward and we'll have a look at a couple of examples right now.
So let's create another mark so escape and then enter realigns shift center.
That gives a solid delimiter.
And now let's have a look.
Let's say we want to once again check that for is less than five.
But instead of printing out the value now like we did hear what we want to do is we want to store this
value inside a variable so let's say result equals to 4 is less than 5.
So what will happen is this expression is logical expression will be evaluated and then the answer will
be stored inside this variable.
So let's go ahead and run that.
And now if we look good result you'll see that it's true.
If we look at type of results you'll see that it's a rule meaning it's a boolean.
All right that's good.
And let's have a look at another example.
So now we're going to use the not OPERATOR So we're going to say result two equals.
So we want to check if five is greater than 1.
But instead of just looking at the answer of that we want to say the opposite of that so I want to say
not 5 greater than 1 so what will happen is this expression will be evaluated.
And as you can see because five is indeed greater than one the answer will be true.
And then it will be placed inside these brackets for the not operator will be placed here and then the
opposite of that expression or that's logical value will be taken.
So basically because this is true we will have not true which means false so far on this.
And then we look at the result too we'll have false.
OK.
So there we go that's how the not operator works.
All right.
And one more thing that I wanted to show you is how we use that and and or statements.
So let's have a look.
Let's say now we have two variables right.
We can still work with them result and result 2.
So we know that this one is true and this one is false.
So let's see how the and and or operators work.
So if we'll say result or result two.
So basically what this will do is it all check.
Is this one true or is this one true.
And then you'll give us results so at least one of them is true then the result will be true the output
will be true so far on this.
It's true because one of them is indeed true.
But if we say result and result two here both of them have to be true for this statement to be evaluated
as true.
So we'll have you know this one is true but this one is false.
So true and false means what the end means that the answer will be false because once again if the and
this one has to be true and this one has to be true for the whole thing to be true so far and that will
get false.
All right so that is logical expressions logical operators and logical variables and logical values
we looked at all four of those.
As you will see further in the course they will be very handy for us when we are working with things
like loops and if statements Al statements and things like that so they will definitely come in very
handy so have a play around with that and see what other combinations you can create.
What other usage you can find for these different operators and I'll see you in the next tutorial.
Until then I'd be coding