Hello welcome back the course in Python programming.
How did you go with the previous quick exercise in the previous tutorial with the negative indexation
or the negative step.
To be precise.
Hope you had a chance to play around with that.
We'll quickly look at that just now and then we'll have a very short brief tutorial on tuples because
tuples are a very very simple concept for us now that we know so much about Python already.
So let's go ahead and do that here I'm just going to quickly put a delimiter.
I'm going to change that.
Marked down put a delimiter in.
All right.
So what did we say we said what happens if we look at the whole list but with a step of minus one.
Right.
So what happens then.
Then what happens is the list is actually reversed.
So we're stepping off minus one we're looking at the whole thing from start to finish or to be more
precise from finish.
To start with step of minus 1 and we'll look at will see that and bit more detail now.
Just a quick comment that most likely you won't be using this a lot this negative step concept but it's
good to understand because maybe someday you'll be looking at somebody else's code and you'll see it
in there some tricky situation where they had a negative step.
And yes it's going to be quite it's going to it's a useful piece of knowledge to have and to be able
to understand this type of code.
So let's quickly have a look so let's say I want to look at letters something we already looked at letters
2 and 2 2 7 so 0 1 2 starting here would go up to here.
There's three four five six or seven other.
That's what we should get right.
That's exactly what we get.
But what happens if I say and this is the same as saying two to seven step one right because we're taking
a step of what we're what happens if I say two to seven with a step of minus one where we know we've
already seen let's say step up to where you know we know what happens there from two in this one of
course I should go this 0 1 2.
So this example C D F G.
This is 2 2 here.
That's what we get not not that example and 6:58 footstep of 2 0 1 2.
So you see then you get the you get G.
Right.
But what happens if I say a step of minus one.
What do you think will get.
Well here we get nothing because the reason is you can get from Item Number 2 to item number seven using
a step of minus one step of minus one you're going to go backwards right you're going to go backwards
you'll never get to step down and that's why we get nothing.
So if you want to use and I get an exception these have to be reversed.
So once again it's still the same concept where you starting and where are you going.
But just remember that when you use negative in succession you can only go to the left that will say
letters.
Let's say we want the same result but reversed right.
So how would we say that would say we want to start at liturgy start here so that is letter numbers
0 1 2 3 4 5 6 6 not over 7.
Remember that whole concept that.
Were you ever going to.
So the the end is not inclusive.
It makes things a bit tricky so here we want to start at six.
Then go to Five four three two.
But we need to specify one because it's going to be not inclusive.
So we want to go from 6 to 1 not inclusive of a step of minus 1.
So let's try that 6 to one with a step of minus one.
That's right.
I need to put the s here.
Forgot this goes 6 to 1 for step of minus 1 G F E D C.
So we basically reverse that.
So you can see just to be two two segments of a one because sound was not.
Now this is inclusive.
So six to one one is Nickolas a step of minus one and simple thing you can just say minus two.
They'll give you every second letter in that sequence going backwards.
So play around with that.
That's that's just say I know it's a bit tricky it's kind of like smoke and mirrors but at the same
time it works and sometimes very I wouldn't say often but sometimes it is used in Python especially
when you want to like reverse a whole list.
It's taken me until 10.
All right.
And for today's topic what we wanted to talk about was Jubal's let's look at them.
So some say topples them so tuples some say some other things let's just call them triples.
So what is a tuple.
A tuple.
It's very simple.
It's happened here.
Immutable usable list.
And that's that's like the easiest way to understand it or immutable sequence of values.
The correct definition.
So what is a tuple how we can check on so let's say to you one rule for a list would say square brackets
would say 345 274 and nine hundred and thirty four.
Right.
For a tuple.
Same thing but just use normal parentheses instead of square brackets.
Run that line you've got a triple.
And so what's the difference between.
But well we can still access the elements we can say zero right.
T one one we can still access in the same way.
The only difference is this word.
It's immutable meaning you cannot change it.
So if you try to change it.
So if you say t 1 1 equals 45 you get an error because object does not support item assignment.
Tuples are not.
You cannot change them.
And the reason for that is kind of something that is used mostly and the core of this concept of the
way we're programming things that sometimes you need to parse lists two functions or two objects and
you need to be sure that they are not going to be changed or the function by taking a tuple instead
of a list guarantees to you that there will be no changes made and things like that.
So it's not something that you often frequently use in data analytics or a science is more related to
the actual programming and development that is used in Python.
But still you're going to come across it because quite a few functions in Python that even will be working
with.
They require tuples to be passed to them so it's just good to know how to create a tuple.
Just quickly on the fly to pass into a function.
So just the only thing to remember here is that it's sort of square brackets use parentheses and then
that means that those values or that object cannot be changed.
Are you guaranteed that that object will remain constant for the remainder of its life.
There we go so that is how we create tuples in Python.
Hope intro to this story.
And I look for scenics them.
Until then happy coding.