Hello welcome back to the course in Python programming.
In today's tutorial we're talking about the for loop.
Let's get started.
I'm going to create a new notebook and this one we're going to call the for a loop.
All right.
And the first thing I want to do here is I want to take the code of the while loop and I want to copy
it so that we can compare them side by side.
So let's get rid of this hello and if we run this shift enter There's a while loop which we spoke about
previously and now we are going to look at the for loop and see how they're similar and how they're
different.
All right so for our keywords then we'll say I in arr. 5.
So let's just type it out and then we'll discuss what's going on.
We'll say print Hello Python and let's run this line.
Let's see what we get.
So you get help either.
Hello Python Hello Python.
Hello Python help Python 5 times.
And what is going on here.
So basically as you can tell by the similarity with the While loop it's got two parts.
This part is kind of like the condition over here and then this part is the body.
So the body is has the same function.
The body is just basically the code that needs to be executed and then the condition is different.
So here we were just taking a logical condition which is quite a simple thing to do.
Here we've got something going on something a bit more involved going on what is going on here.
Well to understand that we will take this range five will copy and paste in essence in its separate
line.
We'll run that.
And what we have here is basically a range of zero to five.
This doesn't help us at all.
And the reason here is this is a bit different to Piscean 2.7.
In Python 3 they've changed it a little bit.
So the way to see what this actually means is we need to change it into a list.
I don't we haven't discussed this yet but they're definitely coming further down the track so let's
just run this code as well and see what it gives us.
So basically this explains what this range 5 actually does.
And as you can tell from the name arr. 5 is a range of five values or in here in more detail is just
a short way of saying range 0 to 5 and it's basically listing all the integers that start from zero
.
So this first number is inclusive and go up to 5.
The last number is not inclusive so 0 1 2 3 4.
So basically a range 5 is a very quick way of creating a set of five numbers.
In this case is there are 1 2 3 4.
And so what does this mean for us.
Well what it means is that what is going on here is we a variable that we're creating inside this loop
which is all the iteration variable of the loop.
And here what it's doing is I is iterating over this range.
So this range of 5 values 0 1 2 3 4 I is iterating over them.
And every time I iterate this executable code gets executed.
So that's how it works and then once the ranges over the code Stobbs been executed because the loop
has completed working.
So what are we going to do now is we're going to have a look at a bit of a different example to kind
of put this all into perspective.
So I want to add another cell above this.
So if you want to add another cell you just click plus and then you move it up with this button.
Or another way.
So I'm going to get rid of that now just copy it cut it another way is to remember like if we're in
the edit mode.
Get out of it a small click escape and then B is as a cell below or a on the keyboard as a cell above
so click.
So you can see the cells at and above.
This turned into a markdown cell enter triple line so let's just put a line there so that we're not
kind of getting lost.
And also let's copy this copy here and then paste paste the cell.
Actually we don't need that.
That was unnecessary.
All right.
So let's have a look at another loop.
But this time it'll be a bit different.
So again we need this cell.
So C is copy and V is paste.
So we're just going to take this loop and altered a little bit so it will help us understand what's
going on.
So for I in rage 1 to 5 We're going to say hello PIF and then on space and then after this quotation
marks we're going to give print another argument so we're going to say comma II.
So all we're doing here is we say OK print.
Can you please print out two things.
Can you print out this string and can you print out the value of the variable.
I whatever it is at the time of printing.
So if you're on this line you'll see this code you'll see that.
Hello Python 0.
Hello Python 1 2 3 4.
So as you can see I is actually iterating over these exact values that we have in our range.
0 1 2 and 3 for that is how the loop works.
And so that is the essence of the for loop so you have some iterative action going on here in the first
part.
And then you have some executable code.
And again if you want to execute a bit more code you can add in some code so you can say print Hello
Python and you can say second line something like that.
So for on this you'll see Hello Python 0 second line so that's the first direction.
Second interation third fourth and fifth and to finish off we'll look at one more example.
I will show you that we can actually change what is going on in this iteration so we can specify our
own iteration doesn't have to be arranged so one thing is you can increase the range you can say 50
or I could say like say 7 here let's get rid of this line so it doesn't get in the way.
So if I run that you'll see that the tradition is has more instances.
Now I'm just going to create another for loop.
All right so here we're going to look at another way.
So let's type that in another way.
And the first thing is create my list.
Once again we haven't spoken about lists yet.
They're coming but let's just copy this code.
It will look very similar to what we saw here.
So we're creating a list of three values 10 100 1000.
Let's run that line.
So now we have a variable which is my list so if I print my list you'll see that it's 10 100000.
And now what we want to do is you want to iterate over these values just as we did iterate over this
range.
So we're going to say four we'll get it we'll create a new variable for the Trishul we call it J or
we can call anything we can call JJ for example.
And I'll say for JJ in my list call on and perform the following.
Print quotations and we'll say JJ is equal to coal on space comma and they don't just put in JJ.
So if we run that you'll see JJ is equal to ten hundred thousand.
And basically what we're doing is this variable J J is iterating over these values 10 a hundred thousand
.
And that's what this key word in means it means.
While JJ is in this list then perform this action.
There we go.
That is how the for loop works.
Have a look at that.
Try experimenting with a different versions so try the range option or try crane them through the list
and see how it all compares to the while and a good exercise is actually to try recreate the while and
the for loop like recreate the same loop but you know in one way using the wild version and in another
way using the four version that's always a good challenge to set yourself.
Hope we have some time to practice that.
It's definitely a good idea because as I always say programming is about practice practice practice
and then it will all make sense.
It will all become very intuitive and I look for it see you next time.
Until then happy coding