Hello and welcome back to the course in Python programming.
Two quick recap on the previous tutorial.
This is the solution the proposed solution for the mini homework exercise.
So to calculate player accuracy we took field goals divided by field goal attempts and then what I did
here is I use their own function but I rounded to two decimal points and then multiplied by 100 to get
percentage.
So these values here are percentages in terms of play accuracy.
How many basketballs they get in the net out of the attempts that they take at the shot.
So there we go and using the same principles as we discussed with the dictionaries we can create a similar
approach to Xs different players and different seasons.
One thing you'll notice is that even though we have all the data it is pretty hard to navigate because
these matrices don't have column names or row names.
It's pretty tedious to always find that the player always finds their daughter we can still do it but
it's just not as intuitive and not as simple and at the same time we can even though we have the data
we can really see the trends is so much information here that we get distracted and we don't see what's
going on.
And even though in this table as we will see further down in this section of the Course is a very interesting
trend happening right now we can't really spot it with just by looking at the table.
So the question is how do we proceed how do we derive insights as a scientist how do we analyze this
information to derive their insights.
And that is a great segue into the topic for today which is Alsation.
So today we're going to build our first installation and we'll finally start putting these tables of
data into plots which will allow us to see trends and anomalies and find out what we want to investigate
further.
So quite an exciting tour ahead actually very exciting story ahead.
Let's get started.
In order to start building recessions we're going to first need to do some imports.
We're going to be our standard import of an umpire.
And I say standard because it's already become quite normal that we do it.
And in fact we don't really have to do it because we've imported before.
Up up top here somewhere.
We don't really need to do it again or we can just rely on that but as a habit which is going to put
it here and another imported it will definitely need is a mat plot lib and Dot pie Plaut as GLT.
So once again my plot lib comes in the Anaconda distribution so the way we installed Python in this
course if you installed Python in a different manner then you might need to download and install this
package separately or put it on your computer and then you'll be able to import it.
But otherwise if you're falling along tutorials you can simply run these two lines and that will give
you some pie as MP.
And my Pipelet as PLDT.
Another thing that we'll need to do in order to proceed because we are using Jupiter notebooks we need
to specify this line and plot lebe in line and what that will do is it will put the plots in the actual
Japan notebooks rather than putting them in a separate window which can get quite annoying.
So if you're using def Japan or notebook's then definitely specify this line and run it.
You don't need to do that once just as with the imports.
And that way the Plus we're going to be creating are going to be shown inside your notebooks.
All right.
So let's get started.
We're going to create our very first plot how we're going to do this.
Well in order to create plot we're going to say T Dot.
And here you can click tap which will bring your pop up and I'll show you all the different items available
inside appeal to you which is pipelined.
And the one we are after is called Just basically Plaut.
So if you're here this is the one we're after the Zarian tab where was it BLT.
So just plot and we'll just basically type it up there.
That's what we after.
Inside the sport like I know there's going to be quite a lot of new stuff right now.
Just bear with me we'll go through it bit by bit and then we will see how this plot is coming to life
.
All right.
So first thing is we need to supply some daughter to this plot and we're going to supply salary.
So from our salary matrix we can take the first role which is Kobe Bryant's salaries right.
So this finished typing of course salary first row or row number 0.
So if I just run that by itself you'll see that if we already have a very descriptive plot so we can
see that Kobe Bryant's salary started here at 1.6 even though we can't really tell what this 1.6 means
right now and went all the way up to three to tell what the 1.6 means which is go to salary.
Just quickly have a look at what we have you there.
So 1.6 is basically it means 16 million dollars and thirty three is actually 30 million dollars.
All right.
So just for our reference.
So that's the very basic things so you can really see that it's quite a smart function.
It takes a salary which is just be basically a list of numbers as we saw.
And it puts into Plaut so it knows to add these on the x axis and then plot the values on the y axis
.
So it's already quite interesting.
So let's start building on top of that.
We're going to give us a color.
So C stands for color it's a parameter for this function we're going to say black.
So if you run this now you'll see that the plot is the line has become black.
LS stands for line style.
What we want is dasht.
So just put two minuses for on this.
You'll see that now it's dasht.
So we kind of styling our plot as we're going then what we want.
We want a marker.
And you'll see why in a bit because we're going to soon have more lines on this plot so let's put a
marker and S stands for square and it's very simple to look all these things up so you can just look
up plot lines styles.
You'll get different codes for like cells and get different codes for markers the same way it's all
in the documentation can be found on line.
So then we can say M-S which stands for marker size that say 7 which kind of is already seven.
So just to show something you can see can increase them.
We can say 17 or just keep it at seven.
OK so that's that's a good start.
What else we want here is we want to get rid of this line.
It's just showing it because we're sending the object.
You know how we use print to print values so here you would say peel t dots show instead of just sending
the object into the output.
And that gets rid of that line.
So it looks good.
And one more thing I wanted to do is I want to kind of make it bigger so expand it to the right.
We've got a bit of space so do that.
Now that's also a line that we just need to run once.
Is this just step put up its VLT dot our C programs.
So basically we are setting the parameters of our session figure big size is just something that needs
to be remembered.
Yes.
Or you can always look it up when you need to.
And so now if I run this you will see that it's a bit bigger so it's been stretched outside if you want
to make it even more bigger especially if you're not zoomed into a browser then you can definitely make
it bigger here so change it to six.
You'll see that it's starting to take up more space.
But I want to save some space and still I want to be zoomed in so that we can see all the codes.
I want to I'll just keep it at 8 4 so these things again there's no need to actually remember them off
by heart.
You can always just look them up when you're plotting to change your size.
And it's not the only way.
So there's other ways to change the size of the plot.
But for now this will be sufficient for us.
OK.
So that's a good start.
What we want to do next is we'll just copy this over here.
And what we want to do next is we want to add the takes on the horizontal axis so we don't want 0 to
9.
We want the actual dates.
So the way to do that is to use T-Dog X ticks and the way we're kind of approaching this is all zation
charges so much learning about exertion will definitely jump into visualization in more detail in further
in one of the further sections of the course.
For now we're just learning the bits that we need specifically for this challenge.
I'm going to explain as much as I can and that will give us a head start and fizzles.
Even though we won't know everything we'll know how these things are structured and that's a very valuable
skill to have.
So just follow along with the code and I'm going to now and these tic marks.
So in order to tick marks what we want is ultimately you want the seasons right.
So we have this season's list which has the years we want it to be displayed here right.
So what we want in to specify for X-Tex is what is the output and also what should be replaced.
So we need to replace Are we going to actually create as we learned way back at the start of the course
we're going to create a range so great in your line.
So if I run range by itself and pie from a point.
It's the same as x range in Python 2.
So basically this is not a list yet in order to turn it into lists you have to do that.
So basically what this is is just base a list of numbers 0 1 2 8.
Actually we need a zero to 10 to 8.
So there we go that's a list of numbers and I'm placing it in here.
And then I want I'm saying that for the ticks I wanted to see the season's not the numbers.
So if I run this now you'll see that I actually have the seasons and we can get rid of this.
And one more thing you can do just for aesthetic reasons we can say rotation equals vertical.
So as you can see it's all pretty intuitive stuff and they try to use very intuitive words as well so
rotation of vertical.
There we go so we've now tethered these around.
One more thing that we're going to add here is we're going to say a label we're going to label this
line.
I know it doesn't really matter right now because we only have one player on this chart.
But going forward we will have more so we will need that.
And again because we want to make it as generic as possible we are specifying south through the salary
matrix so we could have just said.
And here there are players who have just said Kobe Bryant as text right so as said Kobe Bryant because
we know that it's him.
But at the same time we just want to be able to then replicate the same line for other players so it's
just easier if we specify it through the players list.
So far on that you'll see that nothing pretty much has changed but that label has been saved for that
specific line.
So there we go that's we wanted to do in terms of the box itself going forward what we want to add to
this lot is we're going to start adding other players so that we can compare them side by side and we'll
get started on that in the next Tauriel right away.
But for now if you would like to play around what you could do is you could just change the player here
or you could just change this and this value is 0 and 0 here and see what you get.
So you can you'll get different charts for different players.
But then we get to change it back so we can continue straight from here in the next tutorial.
And I look forward seeing you next time.
Until then happy coding.