Hello and welcome back to the python program of course.
Today we're going to finally get to the fun stuff.
So we are quite comfortable now with daughter sets where doorframes and how to filter them how to slice
them how to access various parts of doorframes subset them.
And finally we can proceed to some viz..
So today we're talking about the seaborne package the Seaborn package is a very powerful position package
for Python.
It builds on top of matplotlib.
So let's go ahead and import those.
But marplot lib Pipelet plot as GLT and we're going to also add import seaborne as S and S S and S is
a convention where Seaborn also are going to do that command that we know that plot Leib in line so
the Graf's gets applauded in our chip in a notebook and well that's enough for now.
Let's run that.
Running is running's running matplotlib pipelined is quite large and we're also putting Seaborn on there
.
So seaborne we've already worked with pipelined before in this course.
And what Seaborn does is it actually just makes obvious solutions better it gives us more awesome functions
but at the end of the day it still uses matplotlib.
It's kind of like a upgrade on top of my Podley and you'll see for yourself just now how cool it is
how powerful it is.
So let's create a distribution Right-O And of course we're going to use live daughter so the whole point
of this course is to practice with live daughter.
We've got this one we creating this one equals Asinus just Plaut is the command.
So you can just go as soon as Doughton the press tab it'll give you all these different bar Plourde
box Plaut you are facit grid pair grid.
What else is interesting here.
Cluster map but what we want is displayed so click displayed.
And then here we just going to pause it in one variable so we're going to from our doorframes So let
me just click here and I will click be on my keyboard while this is blue.
And that gives us a new line.
So here I am going to go stat's daughter head and we're going to post that one variable we are going
to parse it the Internet uses columns are going to parse this column and we will see the distribution
of Internet users in our daughter said sources stats.
How do we do it.
We say Square Records and then inter net users run that voila.
There it is.
Now we've got this error thing or it's an action Arutz warning come up and say so something visible
depression deprecation warning using a non-integer number so basically it's not our fault it's something
in the package that is going to be deprecated in some of the future versions.
So it's not really in our control and moreover the creators of the package will make sure to update
it most likely.
So what we're going to do is we're just going to ignore this warning.
So it will say import warnings.
And here again to say warnings right away don't filter warnings.
Ignore that so just copy these two lines add them to the top rear on that run that you're on that.
And no more warnings.
That's how we get rid of warnings.
Beautiful.
Very nice.
What else can we do.
Well you know right away we can expand this chart a bit to the right.
Again I mentioned this before if I zoom out I'm just zoomed in so that we can see the code better.
But if I zoom out you'll notice that these charts are actually very crisp and very clear.
There's nothing like all the numbers everything is clear so if on your computer you're falling along
hopefully you are just keep it zoomed out and you'll be able to see your own code and you'll be able
to see the charts very nicely and clearly I'm going to zoom back in so that we can see the code.
It's kind of like a trade off that we go to we've got to make.
But nevertheless everything is good.
So if we go down here what I wanted to do is increase the width of the chart because we got some whitespace
on the right.
Let's go ahead and do that.
We're here in at the top which is going to do that for all the charges.
We're going to peel T Dot R C arms figure fig size 8 come a full it colorful.
Now I'm not going into too much detail about these things because we just need to increase it once and
we don't need to know all of what's going on here and here basically we just into copy this line.
And then if you ever need to know more details about how this exactly works you can always just look
it up on line and this course would rather learn more data science related stuff and more awesome features
of Python.
So here you can see that with has increased and that is our distribution.
OK.
So now we're going to see if we can modify this situation.
All right.
So let's take that and now we'll just keep it as one because we're just changing it a little bit and
here after this I'm going to press coma and ill press shift tab on my keyboard.
What it shows me is is a pop up with some additional information which can do this problem is you can
click the plus sign OK.
So that's not the best I'm going to go to add some lines.
I'm going to say click here could b b b b b b b for below.
And then I'm going to press shift up here.
Now if I look you'll see that it's got all this additional information so you can read up about how
this function works flexibly Portie univariate distribution of observation.
This function combines the Madlib lib his functions he can see it actually tells you how this function
works parameters so you can find out the premise quickly here or he can read about them here.
So the one we are interested in is beans.
It's an argument for formidably behest or non optionals specification of beans of his beans or none
.
So you can actually read more about this specific problem if you go into the mad plot libber.
His function helps you look for that online and read about bins then you'll get even more information
on it.
It's even got examples here and so on.
So what we're going to do is we're just going to use bins and we're going to say beans equals 30 fire
and that you'll see that now I have 30 bins and I don't mind that it goes to the left to the right.
It's just because of this line otherwise.
That is our distribution.
You can see that that's what it looks like.
Further you can again change a number of bins you can say 40 bins you can say 100 bins.
Don't go too crazy because we know we don't have that many observations and now you're starting to see
holes in your daughter.
Or you can decrease the number of bins you can say five bins.
And that changes it all again.
So that's how we create bins.
And once again this is just a quick introduction to seaborne to see what it's capable of let's say box
plots these two equals as an asteroid walks plot and inherence daughter he calls stats and that by this
are specifying that we want to work with this data frame and therefore in here we won't know long.
We will no longer need to specify stat's every time when we call send call on so we're just going to
say X equals income group.
So that's our if we look at a frame that's our categorical variable and for why we're going to use perforating
we're here.
So we're going to see a box poised for income group and we're afraid it's going to be quite also quite
insightful chart and then we'll see what incise we can derive from them.
So there's our chart.
Let's quickly start with this one.
Let's change it back to 30.
So you can see here is that we've got in terms of Burford Internet users we've got a hump over here
.
So quite a few people and a few countries have between 0 and 20 percent access to internet and then
it drops off and then a lot of countries have between 20 or 30 and let's say 70.
That's the internet user.
So this chart basically tells you how many countries fall into which which group we're here and then
it drops off.
So the number of countries we have as you get closer to 100 percent Internet access it slowly drops
off.
So basically the majority of countries are sitting somewhere under 75 percent access to the Internet
.
We have some authors here but then there's quite a lot of countries sitting at 0 to 20.
So it's not not like a bell curve a bell curve you'd expect it to go like that.
Here it's a bit of a different type of distribution.
Interesting observation and here we've got a box plot that talks to Burford by income group so in different
income groups.
Where do the Burford sits in the high income group you've got birthrates sitting somewhere around 12
.
And so you've got the first quarter second quarter third quarter I'll get some outliers so there are
countries with high income of high birthrate.
You've got low income most of the birthrate as high as expected and then upper middle income is closer
to high income all are middle income is closer to lower income.
Again very interesting chart as well.
And one more thing I want to show you is the seaborne gallery.
I'm going to Korea open up a new window I'm going to say seaborne Yeah Larry.
So let's just look for that.
And so this is our one example gallery if you just go to seaborne That's a Web site but it's just easier
to look for in Google.
And then you go to a gallery.
They've got quite a lot of really interesting realisations here so you can click in them and understand
like just have a look at them how they work.
This is all created with Seaborn How beautiful is that right.
And it's not much code at all see.
Once you go through this course you'll be able to go in here find the one you like.
Of course you will know everything but you'll know most of the things that you need to create and then
some of the additional parameters or additional methods that they use.
You could just look them up and understand how they work so that was a deep.
That's a violin Plaut.
I'll just share one more call one and then you can come back here and look these things up yourself
.
I don't know.
Let's have a look at this one for example.
So that's very cool I think.
Very smooth.
So times here is for a door frame.
Not complex at all but it just looks very nice.
So kind of reminds me of gg plot in our that's why I've grown to like this library or his package seaborne
.
So definitely have a look at that.
This can be a useful tool in your analytics and data set when working.
As I look forward to seeing you the next Tauriel until then happy coding