Welcome back to the next real-world project.
So, now its time to use everything
that you learned about ES6,
and asynchronous JavaScript,
in order to build yet another beautiful real project.
This time, interacting with a real API
to fetch and display some real food recipe data.
And along the way you're also going to be using
some modern JavaScript tools
that every modern developer uses these days.
Things like webpack, to bundle together JavaScript modules,
and babel, to convert ES6 code back to ES5.
So besides applying all these cool
ES6, ES7, and ES8 features to a real context,
we're also going to be building a modern workflow,
that you can use in all your future projects.
So this is really exciting stuff,
and this is by far my favorite project in the course.
So I can't wait to show it to you now.