Alright, if you still haven't got enough of this game,
then here come not one,
not two,
but three coding challenges just for you.
So after finishing this game,
I had three ideas about things,
about rules that we could change in this game.
So I thought,
that these were three really cool challenges
for you to do.
So here they are.
So the first one is
that a player loses his entire score
when he rolls two six in a row.
So not just the round score,
but really all of his score.
So two six in a row
and then the player loses his entire score.
And then, of course,
is the next player after that.
And one hint that I can give you about this
is that you should always save your previous dice roll
in a separate variable,
so that you can access the present
and the past dice roll at the same time.
The second one is that you add an input field
to the HTML where the players can,
by themselves,
set the winning score.
And so they can change the predefined score of 100.
And again, I have a hint.
So in order to read the value
from the input field,
you can use the .value property in JavaScript.
And if you can't manage to make this working,
then this is a good case for you to use Google
to figure out the problem.
This 100 here brings me
to correcting what we still had here,
so we still had a 20,
but of course,
the original rule was that the game ended at 100 points.
Alright, so the third challenge is
to add a second dice to the game
and in this scenario,
the player loses his current score
when only one of them is an one.
And for this one,
you're going to need some CSS and of course,
HTML to position the second dice.
So if you have a hard time with that,
you can just look at the CSS code
that I provided for you.
And if you still can't manage to do that,
to position the dice,
then you can simply watch that part of the solution,
right?
So I really encourage you to do all of these
three challenges,
because this really allows you
to get immediate practice with the coding,
but also with the thinking about the solutions.
So that's really the best thing
that you can do right now,
if you really want to learn JavaScript
and that is why I designed these challenges for you.
Okay,
and after you did all of them,
then you can just check the solutions
that I have for you in the next video.