Welcome back.
Now that we have two out of three steps completed,
let's look at what we have achieved so far.
So, this is the updated version of our app's structure,
and now, we also have the new functions and methods
for deleting an item here that we just coded.
So, this is an overview of everything that happens
when a user clicks one of the Delete buttons.
Now, this makes it visible why it was so important
to create the updateBudget function,
because it's used to update and display the budget changes
after both adding and deleting an item.
So, let's move on to planning the rest of our app.
So, this is gonna be the last step
in coding our application,
and so what is still left to do?
The first thing that comes to my mind
is these percentages here that show how much each expense
represents in percentage of the total income.
So, that's the main thing that we're gonna take care of now.
So, we calculate the percentages, and of course,
update them in the User Interface.
Another thing that we have left to do is to display
the correct month and year at the top of our app,
because currently, we only have some placeholder there.
And there are actually a couple more things
that we can do to improve our app,
like getting this nice number formatting
that we see all over the place here,
and improve the user experience of the input fields,
in order to make it more clear for inputting
an income or an expense.
Alright, so yet another to-do list for us to work on here.
And after doing all of this,
we're gonna be finished with our application.
So, are you as excited as I am
to continue with this right now?
Then, join me right in the next lecture.