It's Coding Challenge time again.
So here we go.
And let's remember the first coding challenge,
where Mark and John compared their Body Mass Indexes.
So let's now implement the same functionality,
but this time with objects and methods.
So for each of them, create an object with properties
for their full name, mass, and height,
then, add a method to each object to calculate the BMI.
And what I want you to do here is to both save the BMI
to the object and also return it from the method.
And then in the end, I want you to log to the console
who has the highest BMI, together with the full name
and the respective BMI value.
All right?
And again, don't forget that they actually might
have the same BMI.
And if you don't remember the formula for calculating
the Body Mass Index, then it's down here again.
And you can also go back to the other challenge
and find the solution there.
Just keep in mind the mass has to be in kilogram
and the height in meter.
Okay?
So this, again, is using the knowledge that we just learned
in the last two lectures.
So I think this is a fun way for you
to retain that knowledge immediately.
Okay, so good luck, and see you once you're finished.