Maven is the most widely used build and dependency
management tool for Java projects.
When you're a professional Java developer,
you'll undoubtedly work with Maven at some point.
When you're going to use JAXB in your Maven project,
and you're using the code-first approach,
you'll want to be able to let Maven call schemagen during the build process.
In this clip, I'll show you how you can set up your Maven project for this.
To make it easier to explain the example,
I'll first give you a super quick overview of Maven.
The central concept that Maven is based around is the concept of a lifecycle.
A Maven lifecycle consists of a number of phases.
When you run Maven, it's going to go through all the phases of a lifecycle.
Maven's default build lifecycle consists of a long list of more than 20 phases.
Some of the phases in the default build lifecycle are,
for example, validate, compile, test, package,
and install.
During each phase, Maven executes a number of tasks called goals.
These goals can, for example, be compile Java source files,
run unit tests, and package the compiled classes into a JAR file.
The goals are provided by plugins.
There are a number of plugins that are provided with Maven itself to perform
the common tasks that are needed to build a Java project.
Each goal belongs to a particular phase in the lifecycle,
and the sequence of phases determines in which order the goals are executed.
There are many plugins available for Maven,
and for working with JAXB,
we are going to use a plugin that provides goals for running schemagen and xjc.
You configure a Maven project using an XML file named pom.
xml.
In the POM file, you configure the build lifecycle in a declarative way,
which means that you don't specify a list of tasks or commands to execute,
you only specify the structure of your project and what dependencies it has.
In other words,
in the POM file you just describe the what and not the how of the build process.
It's the lifecycle and the activated plugins that determine the how.
The advantage of this is that it makes it easy to
understand the structure of the project.
Finally, Maven is not only a build tool,
but also a dependency management tool,
which means that it can automatically download and keep
track of libraries that your project needs.
If you're not familiar with Maven and you want to learn more,
then there's a Pluralsight course available,
Maven Fundamentals by Bryan Hansen.
You can find Maven on the web on maven.
apache.
org.
Now let's get to work with example ps-jaxb-30-maven-schemagen to see
how we can set up the plugin to call schemagen.
In this example,
we have a set of Java source files with JAXB annotations in the package com.
jesperdj.
jaxb.
domain, and we would like to generate an XSD from these sources using Maven.
The aim of this example is to have a JAR file that
contains not only the compiled classes, but also the generated XSD.
Let's take a look at the POM file and see how we can configure this.
First, we have to activate the JAXB plugin.
There are several different Maven plugins available for working with JAXB.
The one I'm using here is jaxb2-maven-plugin from MojoHaus,
which provides goals for calling schemagen,
as well as xjc.
In the pluginManagement section of the POM,
I've specified that I want to use jaxb2-maven-plugin version 2.
3.
1, which is the latest version at the moment.
To configure what the plugin will do exactly,
we will need to add a configuration for the plugin
in the plugin section of the POM.
Besides the groupId and artifactId that identify the plugin,
we will have to add a few things here.
First of all,
we have to define an execution in which we specify which goal of the
plugin we want to run during the build process,
which is, in this case, the schemagen goal.
Note that we don't need to say during which phase in the
build lifecycle this has to be called.
The plugin binds this goal to a default phase,
which is, in this case, the generate resources phase,
which is part of the standard build lifecycle,
and which is executed before Java source files are compiled.
Besides the execution,
we have to specify some configuration parameters in the configuration section.
For this example, there are three things to configure.
First,
I want to tell the plugin where to find the Java source
files of the domain model classes.
By default,
the plugin will pick up all source files in the directory src/main/java,
but I want it to look at only the files in the package
that contains the domain model classes.
Second, I specify the output directory that I want the XSD file to be written to.
For this example,
I'll let the plugin write the XSD to the directory
that's specified by the Maven property, project.
build.
outputDirectory, which means that it will go into the target/classes directory.
By putting it there,
the JAR plugin will automatically find it and add it to the JAR
file in a later phase in the build process.
Finally, I'll add a transformSchemas section.
Here I can specify that I want the schema for our example
namespace to be written to a file named purchaseOrder.
xsd.
That's all for the configuration of the plugin.
Let's run the example and see what output we get exactly.
I'll open a terminal and compile the project using mvn clean package.
If you look at the Maven login,
you'll see that a number of goals have been executed to build the project.
First, the target directory is deleted by the maven-clean plugin.
Then the schemagen goal of the jaxb-2-maven-plugin is called.
Then there are a few more steps, such as copying resource files,
compiling Java sources, some steps for unit tests,
and finally,
the maven-jar-plugin is called to package everything into a JAR file.
If I look at what's inside the JAR file which is in the target directory,
I see that besides the compiled classes,
it indeed also contains the purchaseOrder.
xsd file.
That's what I wanted to show you in this example.
This is just a simple example to give you an idea of how this works,
but the plugin has many more possibilities for other scenarios.
You can find the documentation and more information
about this plugin at the following URL. You can find this link also in the readme file that's included with example 30.