Let's take a look at what exactly the schema-first approach is,
how it works, and how it compares to the code-first approach.
JAXB offers two ways to work with XML.
In the previous modules, we've been using the code-first approach.
We defined our domain model by writing a number of Java classes,
and then we generated an XML Schema from those Java classes.
You can also do it the other way around by defining the domain
model in XML Schema and then generating Java source files for the
domain model classes from the schema.
Each of the two approaches has advantages and disadvantages.
Let's take a look at these so that you understand what you should
think about when you are deciding which of the two approaches
you'll want to use for your projects.
First, let's think about the code-first approach.
One of the advantages of the code-first approach is that it
is easy to use if you're a Java developer.
You probably know Java better than XSD,
so it's easier for you to write a number of Java classes than to write an XSD.
Also, if you write the Java classes yourself,
you have precise control over the design of your classes.
You decide what fields and methods your classes will
have and how they are implemented.
This allows you to design your classes so that they will integrate in an
optimal way with the other parts of your software.
On the other side,
a disadvantage of the code-first approach is that you have
less control over what the XSD looks like.
As you have seen in the previous module though,
the JAXB annotations do give you lots of options for
controlling the generated XSD.
But to use these effectively,
you do need to understand how JAXB annotations translate to the XSD.
Now think about the schema-first approach.
For some projects, the schema-first approach will be the only option.
For example,
maybe your software has to communicate with an already existing system,
and you get an XML Schema from the maintainers of that
system that you will have to work with.
Or maybe a business analyst or a software architect has
defined the domain model in the form of an XML Schema that
you'll have to use to build the software.
Even if you are defining the domain model yourself,
it can be a good idea to start with an XML Schema instead of with Java classes.
For example, if you anticipate that many different groups of developers,
perhaps of different organizations, are going to use your domain model,
then it's a good idea to define it using a standard language such as XML Schema,
which is independent of any particular
implementation technology such as Java,. NET,
or any other programming language or framework.
So one advantage of the schema-first approach is that it
allows you to design your domain model independent of what
particular programming language is used.
A disadvantage of the schema-first approach is that you will
have less control over the Java classes.
Sometimes the generated Java classes may contain constructs that
are cumbersome to work with in your own code,
for example, wrapper classes for collections.
You can often make these better by modifying the XSD so
that better Java code is generated,
and you'll see some examples of that in this module.
If you get the XSD from someone else,
then modifying it to suit your own purposes is
normally not what you will want to do.
Fortunately, besides modifying the XSD,
you can also control how JAXB generates Java classes by using binding files.
You will learn how to use binding files in this module.
Of course,
there's no exact formula to tell you whether you should use
the code-first or the schema-first approach. It depends on the particular requirements for the project you are working on.