Before we start writing code,
it's important to understand how the JAXB API is organized
and what the main concepts of the API are.
The JAXB API is in the package javax.
xml.
bind and related packages in Java Standard Edition.
Take a look at the API reference documentation of this package,
which you can find on Oracle's website.
The entry point into the API is the class JAXBContext,
so we'll take a look at that class first.
The first thing you need to do if you want to use the JAXB API
is get an instance of class JAXBContext.
The JAXBContext object will give you access to everything else in the API.
You get an instance of JAXBContext by calling one of the new
instance static factory methods in the class itself.
In the next clip, you'll see exactly how this works.
When you have a JAXBContext object,
you can call a number of other factory methods on
it to create other JAXB objects.
The two most important ones are the Marshaller and Unmarshaller objects.
In JAXB terminology, converting from Java objects to XML is called marshalling.
So when you want to write XML, what you need to do is create a Marshaller object,
which has methods that you can call to marshal your Java objects into XML.
Vice versa, converting XML back to Java objects is called unmarshalling.
When you want to read XML, you create an Unmarshaller object,
which, of course, has methods for unmarshalling XML into Java objects.
Besides factory methods to create Marshaller and Unmarshaller objects,
class JAXBContext has a few more methods to create
Binder and JAXBIntrospector objects.
These objects are for more advanced purposes,
and we'll take a look at them later.
The reason that creating all these objects works via factory
methods is because the JAXB API was designed to have
multiple possible implementations.
Besides the default implementation, which is included with Java Standard Edition,
there are indeed other implementations available,
for example, EclipseLink MOXy.
Reasons to use a different implementation of JAXB rather than the
default are because a different implementation might offer extra
features that are not part of the default or because a different
implementation might have better performance.
In this course, we'll use the default implementation.
But if you're going to use JAXB in a real project,
it might be worth it to investigate if using a different
implementation has benefits for your project.
There's one more important thing to mention about the JAXBContext,
Marshaller, and Unmarshaller objects.
You should normally create a JAXBContext object only once in your
application and then reuse the same object whenever you need it.
The JAXBContext object is guaranteed to be thread-safe,
so it's safe to reuse the same instance for multiple threads.
Creating a JAXBContext object is a relatively heavy operation.
So if you would do that every time your application needs it,
then it will degrade the performance of your application.
Marshaller and Unmarshaller objects are not guaranteed to be thread- safe,
so you should not use these objects for multiple threads.
Creating Marshaller and Unmarshaller objects are not heavy operations, so creating them when needed does not cause a performance problem.