JAXB provides a number of annotations to specify how you want classes,
fields, and properties to be mapped to XML elements and attributes.
In this clip,
you will learn what you can do with the following five
annotations and how you can use them.
To show you exactly how to use the annotations,
there is an example named ps-jaxb-04-anno-basic.
Let's open that example in the IDE.
The first annotation we'll look at is the XmlRootElement annotation.
You can use this annotation on classes and on enums.
What it does is very simple.
It tells JAXB that the class or enum maps to an XML element.
In terms of XML schema,
it maps it to an element declaration at the root level of the schema,
which means that the element could potentially be used as
the root element of an XML document.
The obvious class to put this annotation on in our
domain model is the purchaseOrder class.
When you use this annotation,
then the code to marshal and unmarshal a purchase
order can be made slightly simpler.
Remember that in the marshalling example in the previous
module we had to create a JAXBElement wrapper that we had
to pass to the marshaller.
When the purchaseOrder class is annotated with XmlRootElement,
this isn't necessary anymore.
We can pass the purchaseOrder object to the marshaller directly.
Likewise when unmarshalling,
we can now use a version of the Unmarshal method that will directly
return a purchaseOrder object instead of a JAXB element from which we
have to get the purchaseOrder object.
You can optionally specify a name attribute with the XmlRootElement
annotation if you want the XML element to have a different name than the
name that JAXB derives from the class name automatically.
The next annotation is the XmlAccessorType annotation.
In the previous clip,
I explained that JAXB can either work directly with the fields in the
domain model classes or that it can treat them as JavaBeans.
By default, JAXB will automatically map public fields,
as well as properties, in your classes.
You can change this behavior by using the XmlAccessorType annotation.
You can put this annotation either on a class or on a package in
which case it applies to all classes in the package.
In the example,
I've used the XmlAccessorType annotation on the package
that contains the domain model classes.
To put an annotation on the package, you need to create a package- info.
java file in the directory that corresponds to the package.
You can then write the annotation above the package statement in that file.
There are four access types that you can choose from.
NONE, which means that JAXB will not automatically map any fields or properties.
With this setting,
you need to explicitly annotate all fields or properties that you want
to have mapped by JAXB using the XmlElement and XmlAttribute and other
annotations that we'll look at in a moment.
FIELD,
which means that JAXB will automatically map all
nonstatic and nontransient fields.
It will not automatically map JavaBeans properties with this setting.
PROPERTY, which means that JAXB will automatically map all properties.
With this setting,
it will look for getter and setter methods and not automatically map fields.
PUBLIC MEMBER,
which means that JAXB will automatically map all
public fields and also all properties.
You could argue how useful it is that it looks at public
fields because making fields public is regarded bad
practice by many Java developers,
and I would not recommend that you make your fields public.
Nevertheless, this is the default way that JAXB looks at your classes.
Note that the AccessorType option only determines what
is automatically mapped by JAXB.
Fields and properties that are explicitly annotated with,
for example,
an XmlElement or XmlAttribute annotation are mapped in addition
to what you chose to be mapped automatically.
Which AccessorType option you should choose depends on the style that
you choose for designing your domain model classes.
To explicitly map a field or property to an XML element,
you can annotate it with the XmlElement annotation.
You can also use this annotation to customize the name of the XML For example,
in the Customer class,
I've added XmlElement annotations to the shipping address and
billingAddress fields because I want the names of the elements in
XML to be different than the field names.
In some cases,
you might want to explicitly exclude a field or
property from being mapped to XML.
To do that, you can use the XmlTransient annotation.
To show you an example, let's do the following.
Move the XmlElement annotation from the field
shippingAddress to the getShippingAddress method.
We've now annotated the shippingAddress JavaBeans property
instead of the shippingAddress field.
When you now run the application,
you'll get an error that says that the class has two
properties named shippingAddress,
and the error message refers to both the getShippingAddress
method and the shippingAddress field.
Why does this happen?
Remember that we've put an XmlAccessorType annotation on the package where
we've specified that JAXB should automatically map fields.
Because of this, JAXB is going to pick up the shippingAddress field,
but we've also explicitly annotated the shippingAddress property by
putting an XmlElement annotation on the getter method.
Both the field shippingAddress and the property
shippingAddress are being mapped to the XML,
and they clash because they have the same name.
One way we can solve this problem is by putting an XmlTransient annotation on
the field so that the field will be excluded from mapping.
One thing that we haven't yet seen is how to map a field or property
to an XmlAttribute rather than to an XmlElement.
You can do this by putting an XmlAttribute annotation on the field or property.
In class PurchaseOrder,
I've added a field orderDate with an XmlAttribute annotation.
This will cause an orderDate attribute to be generated in the
start tag of the purchaseOrder element as you can see in the output when I run the application.