Besides the schemagen tool,
you can also generate an XML Schema programmatically from your own Java code.
Class JAXBContext has a method named generateSchema to generate an XSD from
the domain model that the context was initialized with.
Take a look at the next example, ps-jaxb-13-generateschema,
to see how to do this.
Let's go to class GenerateSchemaExample.
In this example,
we use the generateSchema method of the JAXBContext to generate a schema.
You have to pass this method an instance of class SchemaOutputResolver.
This is an abstract class that you have to extend and implement yourself.
I did that in this example using an anonymous subclass.
There's just one method to implement, the createOutput method.
JAXB passes two arguments through the createOutput method,
the URI of the namespace that it is generating the
schema for and a suggested file name.
The method has to return a Result object that is used to write the schema.
The interface result is actually part of the XML transformation API,
as you can see, because it's in the package javax.
xml.
transform.
There are several implementations available of this interface,
which can write XML to different targets.
I've used StreamResult here, which can write the output to a file.
Using a different implementation, it's also possible to write the result to,
for example, a DOM node or a SAX or StAX event stream.
In this example, I'm ignoring the suggested file name argument,
and I let it write to a file named purchaseOrder.
xsd.
When I run the example, I'll get an XSD,
which, of course, looks exactly the same as what the schemagen tool would produce.