In the previous example,
you learned how you can call schemagen in your Maven
project using the jaxb2-maven plugin.
Of course,
it's also possible to call xjc in the Maven build process
to generate Java classes from an XSD.
You'll learn how to do that in this clip.
We'll be using the same Maven plugin as in the previous example.
Take a look at the next example, which is ps-jaxb-31-maven-xjc.
What we want to achieve in this example is generate
Java source files from purchaseOrder.
xsd using xjc and then compile the generated sources
along with class MarshalExample,
which uses the generated classes into a JAR file.
Class MarshalExample right now doesn't compile because it refers
to the classes that haven't been generated yet.
I've put purchaseOrder.
xsd in the src/main/resources directory and also a
bindings file with binding customizations,
bindings.
xjb.
Let's first take a look at the POM file and see how we can configure the
plugin to call xjc and then run the build and see what we get.
This time,
we want to use the xjc goal instead of the schemagen goal of the plugin.
What we put in the configuration section is also slightly different.
First,
we specify in the sources element where the XSD is located that we want to use.
Also, using the xjbSources element,
we tell the plugin where the bindings file is.
And finally,
we set the package name for the generated classes in the packageName element.
That's all there is to it for this example.
Let's open a terminal again and run mvn clean package.
Xjc has generated the source files in the directory
target/generatedsources/jaxb.
The generated source files are automatically being picked up
and compiled along with our class MarshalExample so that
everything works as it should.
The JAR file that has been built by Maven contains the
class files from the generated sources,
as well as the class file for class MarshalExample.
This is again a simple example which just gives you a starting point to
see how you can set up calling xjc in a Maven project.
The plugin's xjc goal has more configuration options than what I've
shown you here if you need to customize things further. You can find more information in the documentation of the plugin.