We now have a small purchase order web service up and running,
so let's see how we can write a client that calls the web service.
To create the client, we are going to use wsimport,
which is a JAX-WS tool which is included with the JDK.
The wsimport tool reads a WSDL and any XSDs that it
refers to and then generates a web service client class
and classes for the domain model.
It calls xjc to generate the domain model classes.
Let's open example ps-jaxb-35-jaxws-client to see how we can use
wsimport to create a client for our web service.
In this example, we are starting with an empty project.
In the background, I still have the web service running.
The first thing we'll do is use the wsimport tool to generate
client and domain model classes for the web service.
Let's open a terminal and run wsimport.
I have to pass this command a number of options.
First, using the -s option,
I tell it where I want it to write the generated source files,
which is in the directory src\main\java.
By default, what wsimport does is generate source files,
then compile the generated files by invoking the Java compiler,
and then delete the generated source files.
In this example, we don't need it to compile the generated source files,
so we use the option -Xnocompile,
and we also need to use -keep to prevent wsimport
from deleting the generated files.
Then we use the -p option to specify the package for the generated classes,
the -encoding option, the -verbose option to get detailed information,
and finally, the URL where wsimport can get the WSDL from.
Of course, for this to work, the web service needs to be running.
Otherwise, it won't be able to get the WSDL.
As you see, wsimport has called xjc to generate the domain model classes,
and it has also generated a class PurchaseOrderService
and an interface PurchaseOrders,
which represent the web service and the port that we need
to be able to call the web service.
Let's add a class PurchaseOrderClient and see how we can call the web service.
We first need to create an instance of the generated class PurchaseOrderService,
and then we call getPurchaseOrderPort on the PurchaseOrderService object,
which returns a PurchaseOrders object.
The interface PurchaseOrders declares the four methods
that are available in the web service, to get the list of orders,
to get a specific order, and to add and delete an order.
We can now, for example,
call the addOrder method on the port object to add an order and
call getOrders to get the list of current orders.
The web service is holding all the orders in memory,
so if I run this client application multiple times,
you'll see that every time a new order is added,
and the list gets longer.
That is all that I wanted to show you about using JAX-WS web services.
This was, of course, just a quick demo.
There is much more to JAX-WS web services,
and if you're interested in XML-based web services, there's a lot more that you can learn about.