Let's look at two more annotations that have to do with how fields
and classes are mapped to XML schema simple types.
JAXB maps Java primitive types and a number of well-known standard
classes to matching built-in simple types of XML schema.
Sometimes you might want to map one of these types to a different
simple type than what JAXB does by default.
That's what the XmlSchemaType annotation is for.
It's also possible that one of your own domain model classes
really represents a value type and that you want to map it
to an XML schema simple type.
You can do that with the XmlValue annotation.
To see exactly how to use these two annotations,
take a look at the next example, ps-jaxb-06-anno-simpletypes.
First, the XmlSchemaType annotation.
In the previous examples,
we've added an orderDate field to class PurchaseOrder
that was mapped to an XmlAttribute.
If you've looked closely at the output of the previous examples,
you saw that the value of the purchaseOrder attribute
is a timestamp in ISO 8601 format, containing a date,
a time, and a time zone offset.
It's a timestamp rather than just a date because class java.
util.
Date is mapped to the built-in XML schema type, dateTime, by default.
Suppose that we would want to map it to the
XmlSchemaType date instead of dateTime.
We can do that by using the XmlSchemaType annotation.
This is very easy to do.
We just put this annotation on the field.
With the name attribute of the annotation,
we specify the XmlSchemaType to use for this field.
In this case, it's the type date.
When we now run the application,
we see that the attribute indeed contains just a date.
It still has a time zone offset, but not a time.
Suppose that we want to always map fields of type java.
util.
Date to the XML schema date type not just as one attribute.
To do that,
we can put the XmlSchemaType annotation on the package instead of
on one specific field or JavaBeans property.
When you put it on the package, you do have to specify one more attribute,
which is the Java type that it should apply to.
In this case, the type java.
util.
Date.
It will then apply to all fields and properties of that
type in the classes in the package.
Next is the XmlValue annotation.
This also has to do with XML schema simple types, but in a different way.
Normally, Java classes map to complex types.
A Java class maps to an XML element that contains other elements,
one for each of the fields in the class.
Sometimes, however, you have a class that represents a simple value,
and you want it to be mapped to an XML element with just that value
as its text content instead of an XML element,
which contains another element, which contains a value.
To show this, I've added a new class to the model, class country.
It's used in class Address where the field country is now
a Country object instead of a string.
Class Country contains two fields: code and name.
The field name has an XmlTransient annotation, so it's not mapped to the XML.
When we run the application,
we see that the addresses now contain a country element,
which contains a code element, which contains the actual code value.
Suppose that you want to get rid of the intermediate code element and have the
country code directly as the value of the country element.
We can do that by putting an XmlValue annotation on
the code field in class Country.
This will make class Country map to an XML schema
simple type rather than a complex type.
And the field code is what contains the value of the type.
Note that there are some restrictions when you use the XmlValue annotation.
When you use this annotation,
you must use it on exactly one field or JavaBeans property in the class.
That is because a simple type contains only one value.
Also,
you cannot have other fields or properties in the class that are
implicitly or explicitly mapped to elements.
This is because a simple type cannot have elements as its content,
so the class that maps to a simple type must not
have fields that map to elements.
If I remove the XmlTransient annotation from the name field,
then JAXB will try to map this field to an element,
but this is not allowed.
And if I run the application,
I get an error message that tells me that the class cannot have an
XmlElement and an XmlValue property at the same time.
It is allowed to have fields that map to XML attributes in a class
that has a field with an XmlValue annotation.
For example,
let's put the XmlValue annotation on the name field and put an XmlAttribute
annotation on the code field and run the application again.
The output now contains country elements that have the
name of the country as the text content,
but also with a code attribute that contains the country code.
For those who know a lot about XML schema,
I'll add that technically the simple type cannot have attributes.
So what happens in this case is that the class doesn't
really map to a simple type anymore, but to a complex type with simple content and an attribute declaration instead.