In XML Schema,
it's possible to specify whether an element or attribute is required or not.
If a required element or attribute is not present in the XML document,
then the document is not valid according the schema.
JAXB supports this using the XmlElement and XmlAttribute annotations on which
you can indicate whether an element or attribute is required.
Let's see how to do this, what effect it has on the generated XSD,
and also what this means for marshalling and unmarshalling.
Please open the next example in your IDE, which is ps-jaxb-15-required.
First, let's take another look at the generated XSD from the previous example.
If you look carefully,
you'll see that most elements have their minOccurs attribute set to 0,
which means that these elements are all optional.
Many of the fields in our domain model, however, should be required.
For example, a purchase order should always have an order date and a customer.
The customer should always have a name, etc.
It's easy to specify this by setting required = true on the relevant XmlElement
and XmlAttribute annotations in the domain model classes.
That's what I've done in this new example.
When I run generateSchemaExample and look at the XSD,
I see that most element declarations now no longer have minOccurs = 0.
In fact,
they don't have a minOccurs attribute at all anymore
because the default for minOccurs is 1,
so it doesn't need to be specified if it's 1.
For attributes,
whether the attribute is required or not is specified
slightly differently in XML Schema.
As you see,
the declaration for the orderDate attribute now has use=required to indicate
that the attribute is required on the purchaseOrder element.
That's pretty straightforward and easy to understand,
but let's take a look at what this means for marshalling and
unmarshalling because there might be a small surprise there.
What would you expect to happen if you would try to marshal an object that has
a field that's mapped to a required element or attribute,
but which is set to null?
It would be reasonable if you would think that JAXB would throw an
exception since it cannot generate valid XML because there's no value
for the required element or attribute.
That is, however, not what happens.
JAXB just generates the invalid XML with the
required element or attribute missing.
The required setting on the annotations is simply ignored.
Likewise, when ummarshalling,
when a required element or attribute is missing in the XML,
JAXB will happily unmarshal it without complaining.
The required attribute on the annotations is only used for schema generation,
and not automatically for validation during marshalling and unmarshalling.
It is possible to perform validation against the schema
during marshalling and unmarshalling,
but you have to tell JAXB explicitly to do this.
It does not validate by default. We'll see how to enable validation later in the course.