Let's quickly go over the most important concepts of XML.
XML is pretty simple, and you've most likely worked with XML files before,
so I'm not going to go into too much detail.
XML stands for Extensible Markup Language.
It's the standard text-based format for storing arbitrary structure data.
To explain it, I'm going to start up my IDE and show you an example XML file.
As you can see, this XML file contains information about a purchase order.
It's easy to understand.
Let's look at the main features of XML.
An XML document contains elements, and each element starts and ends with a tag.
The start tag consists of the name of the element between angle brackets.
The end tag is the same as the start tag except that there is
a forward slash before the element name.
The start tag can optionally have attributes,
such as the orderDate attribute on this purchaseOrder start tag,
which are specified after the element name and separated by spaces.
Attributes have a name and a value.
The content of an element is what's between the start and end tags.
This can be text or other elements.
The element's productName, quantity, price, and so on here have text content.
The items, customer,
purchaseOrder element and more have other elements as their content.
The fact that you can nest elements is a very powerful idea,
and that's what makes it possible to store almost
any kind of structure data in XML.
If an element has no content,
the start and end tag can be combined into a single tag with
a forward slash after the element name.
That's just a shorter way to write the start and end tag right
next to each other with nothing in between.
One other feature that I briefly want to explain is namespaces.
Namespaces in XML are a bit like packages in Java.
A namespace keeps a set of related tag names together,
just like a Java package keeps related classes together.
When you define a set of tag names for your application,
it's a good idea to define a namespace to contain your tag names.
Let's look at the syntax that is used to refer to namespaces.
A start tag can have a special attribute with a name xmlns.
The value of this attribute is the name of a namespace,
and it specifies that the tag and its child tags belong to that namespace.
The name of a namespace is a URI, a uniform resource identifier.
It often looks like a URL,
and it's a good idea to choose a URL that refers to a
world wide web domain name that you own.
This is exactly the same as with Java package names where you usually
use a package name that corresponds to a web domain,
like com.
mycompany.
mysoftware.
Note that the URL does not need to point to any real resource on the web,
so you don't need to have a server running that responds to the URL.
Through the XML parser,
it's just a string that uniquely identifies the namespace.
Sometimes you'll need to use text from multiple
different namespaces in your XML document.
You can use namespace prefixes to indicate explicitly
to which namespace a tag belongs.
To declare a namespace with a prefix,
you have to modify the xmlns attribute slightly by putting a
colon and then a prefix name after it.
You then use this prefix name in front of tag names
that should be in that namespace.
That's the super quick overview of XML.
If you feel you need to know more about XML,
then please take a look at the other Pluralsight courses about XML that I mentioned before.