JAXB maps enum type fields to XML schema simple types.
By default, enums are mapped as strings,
and the enum console names are used in the XML.
There are two annotations that you can use to customize how enums are mapped
if you need different mapping than what JAXB by default.
This is not very complicated,
so let's take a look at example ps-jaxb-01-anno-enum.
JAXB maps enums to XML schema simple types with enumeration restrictions.
In the introduction module of this course,
we already briefly saw this in the quick review of XML schema.
Class Customer contains the loyalty field,
which is of type Loyalty, which is an enum.
By default,
the enumeration values in the XML will be the names of the Java enum constants.
In the previous examples,
we saw SILVER as the value of the loyalty element in the XML.
Suppose that in the XML we want to use values that are
different from the enum constant names.
We can do that by putting XmlEnumValue annotations on the
enum constants and specifying the value to be used in XML
for each of the constants.
For example, I can here specify the values 10, 20, and 30 for the 3 constants.
When I run the application, I will now get 20 instead of SILVER in the XML.
Finally, there is the XmlEnum annotation.
You can put this annotation on the enum itself.
This is actually redundant since JAXB already automatically
recognizes enums and maps them appropriately.
The XmlEnum annotation is not completely useless though.
The simple type that an enum is mapped to in the schema is
based on one of the built-in simple types.
By default, the type string is used,
but you might want it to be a different type,
for example, int.
You can specify that using the XmlEnum annotation.
For example, if I specify Integer.
class, then the schema type int will be used.
The values that are specified in the XmlEnumValue annotations must,
of course,
be valid values for the type that is used to represent the enum in XML.
For example, if integers are used, then the values must be integers. You will get an error if you use a value that is not a valid integer.