Collections are, of course, an essential element in almost any piece of software,
so it's important to understand how JAXB handles collections.
For this clip, there are a number of examples to work with.
We are first going to see how JAXB marshals and unmarshals lists,
and then we are going to examine how it works with maps.
Let's open the first one, ps-jaxb-08-anno-lists-1 in the IDE.
In the marshaling example of the previous module,
we saw that the list of items in the purchaseOrder was
mapped to XML in a peculiar way.
For each item, an items element was generated,
which doesn't look right because each items element
is really just a single item.
Let's see how we can improve this and what other possibilities there
are for mapping lists and other kinds of collections,
such as arrays, sets, and maps.
First,
let's look at how we can make it so that each item in the XML is
in an item element instead of an items element.
This is really easy.
We just have to put an XmlElement annotation on the items field in
class purchaseOrder and specify the element name item.
When we now run the application, we get an item element for each item.
Next, think about the following problem.
What if we wanted the list of items in the XML to be inside an
element that represents the whole list instead of having them in
the purchaseOrder element directly?
There is a straightforward, but cumbersome solution to this.
Let's first look at that solution,
and then after that we'll see a much better way to solve this problem.
Take a look at example ps-jaxb-08-anno-lists-1 for the cumbersome solution.
First, I'll run the example to make it more clear what I mean.
In the output of this example,
the purchaseOrder element contains an items element,
which contains the item elements.
How can we make JAXB do this?
Let's open class PurchaseOrder.
I've added an extra class named items and changed the field
items in class PurchaseOrder to be of the type items instead
of list item like we had before.
Class Items is simply a wrapper class for the list of items.
It contains just one field,
which is the list of items that was previously in class PurchaseOrder.
This works, but it's cumbersome.
This extra wrapper class items makes it hard to work with the list of
items in a purchase order in Java code because we have to go through
this extra wrapper object every time.
Fortunately, there is a better way to do this.
Open the next example, ps-jaxb-09-anno-lists-2, to see the better solution.
There's a special annotation to solve exactly this problem.
Open class PurchaseOrder and look at the items field.
I've added the XmlElementWrapper annotation on the field.
This annotation does exactly what we need here,
which is generate a wrapper element around the elements for the items.
If you run this example,
you'll see that the output is exactly the same as with the first solution
without the need to have a cumbersome wrapper class.
Besides lists, there are, of course, other kinds of connections,
such as arrays and sets.
There is not much to say about these.
JAXB treats arrays and sets the same way as lists.
I could've made the items field in class
PurchaseOrder an array or even a hash set,
and the output would be exactly the same.
Let's take a look at what JAXB does with maps.
There's no direct equivalent of a Java HashMap in XML schema.
Open example ps-jaxb-10-anno-maps to see how JAXB marshals a HashMap to XML.
In this example,
I've changed the items field in class PurchaseOrder to a map with
strings as keys and item objects as values.
In the create PurchaseOrder method,
I create a HashMap with two items with product codes as the keys.
Let's see how the XML looks when we run this example.
As you see, the items element now contains two entry elements,
and each entry element contains a key element with a key and a value
element with the fields of the corresponding item object.
That works, and it's a straightforward and generic way to translate a map to XML,
but maybe you want to do this differently.
There are no specific annotations to customize how maps are translated to XML,
but it is possible to customize what JAXB does in a way that allows you
to map fields and properties almost any way you want. You'll learn how that works in the next clip.