In this clip,
you will learn about a slightly more advanced subject that
will take you to the ObjectFactory class,
which is important in other areas of JAXB as well,
as you'll see later in this course.
For the most part,
the correspondence between Java and XML Schema is clear and obvious.
Classes map to complex types; fields in a class map to
elements in the complex type of their containing class; value
types such as Java's primitive types, strings,
and a few other types, and also enums map to simple types.
The XML Schema features that we've seen in the previous clips
also have obvious counterparts in Java,
even though there are some subtle issues that make JAXB behave
differently than you might have expected at first sight.
There are some cases, however,
where there is not an exact one-to-one
correspondence between XML Schema and Java.
We are going to look at one such case now.
In XML there are different ways in which an element can have no value.
The element can be completely missing from the XML,
the element can be present but without a value,
or if the element is nillable,
it can be explicitly set to nil using the XMLSchema-instance nil attribute,
as we saw in the previous clip.
In Java, however, there's only one way in which a field can have no value,
and that is when the field is set to null.
There's no distinction in Java between an object not having a
field and having a field that is set to null.
In fact, it is not possible for an object to not have a field.
An object always has all the fields that are declared
in its class and its superclasses.
For example,
there's no way to have an item object which does
not have a comment field at all.
The only way to indicate that an item object has no comment
is by setting the comment field to null.
This leads to the following problem.
If you've just unmarshalled an item element,
then how can you see in your Java item object if the item
element did not have a comment element at all,
or if it had a comment element that was set to nil.
There is a way to do this which I will show you in the
example ps-jaxb-18-objectfactory.
This will involve using class JAXBElement,
which we already saw in the beginning of this course when you
first learned about marshalling and unmarshalling.
Remember what JAXBElement is.
It's JAXB's representation of an XML element,
which consists of the qualified name and the value of the element.
It also contains a Boolean property nil,
which is the value of the element's nil attribute.
Let's go to the IDE and look at the example.
The first step is that we will change the type of the comment field in
class Item from String to JAXBElement of String.
Of course, we also have to modify the getter and setter method.
The idea is that if we can get JAXB to marshal and unmarshal
this field as a JAXBElement instead of a string that contains
just the value of the element,
we will be able to see the difference between the element
not being present and the element being present but set to
nil in the following way.
If the element is not present in the XML,
then the field will be set to null so there will be
no JAXBElement object at all, and if the element is present but nil,
then we will get a JAXBElement object,
and it will have its nil property set to true.
That was the first step,
but just making the field a JAXBElement is not enough to make this work.
The next step is that we have to create a special factory method to let
JAXB know how it should create the JAXBElement object and wrap the
element value during marshaling and unmarshalling.
To do this, we are going to create a class named ObjectFactory.
This class has to be annotated with the XmlRegistry annotation to indicate that
this is a class that contains factory methods for elements.
Then we create the factory method for the comment
element in class ObjectFactory.
This method takes one argument which is the value of the element,
which is a String in this case,
and returns a JAXBElement object that contains the value.
The last step we have to take is to associate the factory method
with the field so that JAXB knows that it should use this factory
method for the comment field in class Item.
We do this by using two new annotations, XmlElementDecl and XmlElementRef.
We put the XmlElementDecl annotation on the factory method.
This annotation has attributes that specify the XML
element that this method is for, which is,
in this case,
a comment element in our example namespace in the scope of class Item.
Finally, we put the XmlElementRef annotation on the comment field in class Item.
With this annotation, we also specify the namespace and the name of the element.
Because the namespace and the name refer to the same element
as the annotation on the factory method,
the field and the factory method are now associated with each other.
There's one last change we need to make in the marshalling example.
Since the comment field is now a JAXBElement instead of just a string,
we need to change the line in the createPurchaseOrder
method where we create the comment field.
We need to pass a JAXBElement to the setComment
method there instead of just a string.
To make it easy, we can use the ObjectFactory to create the JAXBElement.
Now we've reached the goal.
Let's see how we can now distinguish between no element and a nil
element during marshalling and unmarshalling.
For marshalling, we can choose to either set the comment of an item to null,
which means that there will be no comment element at all,
or we can set it to a JAXBElement which has its nil property
set to true so that there will be an element with its nil
attribute set to true in the output XML.
For unmarshalling,
we can see the difference by checking if the comment field itself is null, or if it does contain a JAXBElement with its nil property set to true.