Hello, everyone, at this point in the course, our website is complete, there are no additional features
that we need to program or code.
However, even though our programming work is complete, this course would not be complete if we didn't
also learn how to actually copy or move or push our WordPress website up onto a real Web host so that
the entire world can view it right.
Because as of this moment, our site only exists on our local dev environment and we are the only ones
that can view it.
Now the act of copying or moving or pushing a website up onto the web is commonly referred to as deploying
and learning how to deploy.
Our website is exactly what we're going to cover in this section of the course.
We're actually going to cover two different strategies for deploying our site.
Now, big picture.
There are way more than just two ways of doing this.
There are probably hundreds of different ways of moving your website.
But in my opinion, these are two of the best ways of doing it.
So we will review what these two paths are.
We will cover the pros and cons of each path and also go over a few factors that will help you decide
which path is right for you.
However, before we discuss those two paths, I do want to address the topic of Web hosting.
Obviously, in order to practice deploying a website onto the web, you need a Web host to push it,
too.
And usually a Web hosting plan costs money.
So if you don't already have a Web hosting plan and you don't feel like spending money on one right
now just to practice deployment, I'd recommend skipping this chapter and rest assured that if you ever
do sign up for hosting in the future, you can always come back to this chapter.
It'll be here waiting for you when you're ready.
If you're looking for advice on which Web hosting company to choose a good place to start is always
the official WordPress dawg hosting page.
So from the official site, it's usually the final link in the top navigation menu.
Now, you don't have to go with one of these three that they recommend, but what I like to do is just
go to YouTube and search for one of these host names, followed by the word review.
That way you can hear real world opinions from real world people about the pros and cons of a particular
hosting company, how fast or slow they are, how their customer service is, so on and so forth.
Also, if a review isn't favorable, they might suggest a different hosting company entirely.
And then you can look into that company.
Ultimately, you just need to perform a bit of your own consumer research and deciding which company
to give your business to is outside the scope of this course.
Now, if you do already have a Web hosting plan and you want to follow along with this deployment chapter,
I'd recommend creating a subdomain such as practice dot your domain dot com or testing your domain dot
com.
And that way you can have a playground sandbox to experiment with for this chapter.
And you don't have to worry about accidentally erasing or messing up your existing real site if you
have one.
Now, in terms of creating subdomains or databases or FTP users, unfortunately, I can't walk through
all of that with you step by step because every hosting company is different and has a different user
interface or control panel.
So we're primarily going to focus on the WordPress specific details in this chapter and the generic
Web host actions.
Those will require you to do a bit of your own research on your particular hosting company.
OK, having said all of that about hosting, now, let's actually discuss the two paths of moving or
deploying a site that we're going to cover.
So let's say there's a path A and Path B, path A is simple and Path B is a bit more advanced.
So which one is right for you?
While they each have their own pros and cons path A is as simple as installing a free plug in within
our local dev WordPress site and this plug in bundles everything up for us.
So it takes a copy of our database and it also bundles up all of our files.
Right, our access JavaScript files and it bundles all of this up into one convenient export file.
So then all you need to do is import that file within another WordPress installation that you want to
copy or move your website, too.
So what are the pros and cons?
Well, the first advantage is that this path is super easy.
There's no other prerequisite knowledge.
So anyone can go with Pathé.
In addition to being simple, it's also very fast.
Once you're familiar with this plugin, you can move or copy a website, I would say within five to
10 minutes.
OK, now the con or the drawback is that making future updates to your website files can be a bit annoying.
Don't worry about the details of Pathé for now, because in our very next lesson, I'm going to walk
through Pathé with you step by step.
OK, now let's describe Path B as well as its pros and cons.
So Path B is a bit more advanced and it takes advantage of the git version control system.
Now we are not going to learn get itself in this course because that's completely outside of our scope.
That would be a course in and of itself.
So if you've never used Git before or if you've never heard of Git, you will want to go with Path A
and then if in the future you do learn git, then you can always circle back to this course and try
out path B..
OK, so moving on, what exactly is Path B and what are the pros and cons?
The big advantage is that making updates to your live website files is super easy.
Whenever you code a new feature or make any changes to your files within your local dev environment
and then commit and push those changes up to your GitHub or BitBucket repository.
Well, those updated files get automatically uploaded to your Web host server for you.
And this is really luxurious.
It's like the Rolls Royce of deployment setups because now you don't need to bother with FTP programs
or file managers or mentally keeping track of which files you've changed and then need to upload to
your Web host.
You don't need to do any of that.
You literally just push your progress up to your git repository like you would anyways.
Only now those updates get automatically synched and uploaded to your live site.
Now, this might not sound like a big deal, but trust me, it's a dream come true.
So what are the cons or drawbacks to Path B?
Well, number one is that you need to be familiar with the basics of git and not everyone is.
So Path B is not for everyone.
That's the first drawback.
The other con is the initial set up time.
There is a bit of a time investment up front for the first one time setup.
After that, it's smooth as silk and super quick.
But there is a tiny time investment up front, whereas with Path A you can be up and rolling within
five to 10 minutes.
OK, so that's an overview of Path A and Path B, we're going to walk through each of them in detail
in future videos.
But right now you're likely trying to decide which path is right for you.
Well, in addition to the git factor, right.
If you're not familiar with Git, you should probably choose Path A.
In addition to that factor, I will give you another question, which is how often do you think you'll
need to make updates to your site files?
So once your website is up on the Web for the entire world to view, how often will you need to update
the code?
If you think that you'll only need to update the files maybe once or twice a year, I would go with
Path A not only because it's simple, but also because it's really fast.
Path B is really only worth the extra effort if you think you're going to be making somewhat regular
or frequent updates to the code files of your live website.
Now, you don't need to make a decision.
You can follow along with both paths if you want to.
Beginning in the next video, I'm going to walk through Path A and then once I'm done with that, I'm
going to completely delete my live website just so that I can start over again and demonstrate path
B.
So if you want to experiment and try both paths, that's OK.
But there's no need to do that.
Either one will get the job done.
OK, that is going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our very next video, we're going to begin learning about Path A.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.