Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to update our front end overlay JavaScript to use our new custom API URL
that we've been building.
So let's jump right into the action and in our text editor within our theme folder, let's look inside
our Jass or JavaScript folder and then inside our modules folder, let's hop into our search JS file.
And if we scroll down to our method that is named Get Results, we see that.
Here's the code we wrote when we were using the built in WordPress API URLs and because the default
API URLs only work with one post type at a time.
Back when we wrote this code, we had to make two separate JSON requests, write one for posts and one
for pages, and then we manually smooshed together the results.
Well, a lot has changed since then.
We've now created our own custom API URL that returns data for all six post types.
So that means we really don't need this old setup any longer.
However, I don't want to just outright delete this code immediately right now because there's still
little bits and pieces from it that we can copy and paste to save additional typing.
So here's what I'm going to do right above this line.
So right at the beginning of our results method, I'm going to add a comment and I'm just going to say
delete this code a bit later on.
OK, so by the end of this lesson, we can go ahead and delete all of this old code.
But for now, we can leave it here for reference.
And now right above this, let's just write it the new way that uses our new custom, Aperol.
So we no longer need to worry about the synchronous versus asynchronous topic because we no longer need
to make multiple JSON requests.
So up on our new line of code, we no longer need to use the when then combo.
Instead of that, we can simply just make one request.
So let's say dollar sign to use J query and then let's use the JSON method.
It takes two arguments.
The first is the Eurail that you want to send a request to, let's just say X as a placeholder.
And the second argument is a function that you want to run once the server or you URL response.
So let's just apply an anonymous function here.
And whatever JSON data this you URL responds with will be passed into this function.
So within these parentheses, we want to be sure to include a parameter that can receive the incoming
data.
So you could call it data or response.
You can make up whatever parameter name you want just to make sense.
I'm going to call it results.
OK, now we can use that within the body of this function.
Before we move on, though, I do want to be sure to use an S6 Arrow function.
So that way the value of this keyword will not be modified within this function.
So remember to use an S six arrow function, you can just get rid of the word function, keep your parentheses
in your parameter, and then right after it you include equal sign greater than OK.
Now within the function, what do we actually want to do?
We want to modify the HTML of our search overlays results div so we know that we've got a property that
we can access by saying this dot results div and right after this we can just target its HTML and remember
that instead of supplying a simple string of text, if we use back text instead of single quotes, then
we can create a template literal, which means we are free to dropdown to multiple lines just like we
would in normal HTML in this time around.
I don't want to begin just by outputting a heading level to instead I want to create a three column
layout.
So let's do this within our template, literal.
Let's create an overall div and let's give this a class of Roe, OK, and then within this div let's
create three children div where each one is a column so we can say div and let's give this inner div
a class of one third to represent a column that takes up one third of the available width and then you
can just copy and paste that so that you've got three of them within our first column.
Let's drop down within the opening and closing days and within that div let's add a heading level two
that reads general information.
All right.
And then in our second column, let's drop dropdown and let's add heading level two that reads programs.
And then right below that, we can have another heading level two that reads Prof's.
In just a moment, we can output the.
The actual list of results, so the resulting programs can go right underneath this headline and the
resulting professors can go right underneath this one, OK?
And then finally in our third column, let's drop down in between the opening and closing div tags and
let's output a heading level to four campuses.
And then below that, we can have another heading that reads events.
Now, in terms of success and styling, I want to make sure that these headlines use the appropriate
font size and color.
So if we scroll down just a bit within our old code, we can see that we were giving this heading level
to a class of search overlay section title.
So in order to save a bit of typing, why don't we just copy and paste this class name?
Copy that and then back up in our new code.
I'm just going to paste that in is the class for all of our heading level twos.
So on this first general information, one class equals and then paste it in and you could actually
just copy and paste the entire class attribute equals that.
Copy that and then you can just paste it in for all of the others.
All right, and before we save this and test it out in the browser, let's first not forget about our
X placeholder that needs to be a Eurail, right, that we want to send a request to.
So to avoid a ton of typing, if we scroll down to our old code here, we are using the jasen method
so we can just copy and paste this first argument.
So it begins with university data.
And if you scroll to the right, we want to select all the way up until Vall and then the closing set
of parentheses.
So let's copy that and then back up in our new code.
We can paste it in to get rid of this placeholder X here.
And now, before we save this, we do need to modify the namespace and the Routt, so WP, JSON is still
correct, but then instead of WP V2, we want to use our namespace, so let's delete that.
And instead, ours is University Igwe one.
OK, and then finally for the root instead of posts, we created a root named search and then the Eurail
parameter that we used is term instead of search.
OK, and then we're just setting that to equal whatever the user has typed in, all right.
And now we are actually just one step away from being able to delete our old code.
So how about we do this within our new code in the first column, right underneath this heading level
to let's output a little bit of code that loops through the general information results, which are
any resulting blog posts or pages.
Now, we've already written the code that does that.
So if we just scroll down to our old code and we see that here is our old heading level two and right
below it are the lines that will generate HTML for each result.
So why don't we just copy and paste these three lines of code into our clipboard and then back up in
our new code in our first column right underneath the H2.
Let's just paste that in.
And now instead of checking to see if an array named combined results exists or I should say has a length
that is larger than zero, instead of checking for this, let's delete combined results and instead
look for results.
Dot general info.
If you're wondering how I came up with this name, let me refresh your memory.
So it results is the name of the parameter that our function is using.
It contains all of the JSON that the server or Eurail is going to send back.
And then I'm looking inside results for an array named General Info.
And this is just a name that I made up in our previous lesson.
So, for example, within our theme folders I n c folder, if you jump in to search Routt HP, remember,
we created an array named Results and within it we have our sub arrays and the array that's going to
contain blog posts and pages is named general info.
So that's what I'm looking for here.
Let's do the same thing on this next line of code.
So instead of combined results, we're looking for results, dot, general info and the same thing on
this line.
Results, dot general info.
Cool.
Now at this point we can go ahead and delete our old code.
We no longer need it as a reference.
So if I scroll down, here's that comment.
Delete this code a bit later on and I'm just going to select from the beginning of that all the way
down until this closing curly bracket parentheses and semicolon that comes right after this line where
we're outputting our error message.
So with this selected, let's delete that.
And at this point, let's save this and test it out in the browser.
You'll want to be sure that in your command line you either run golpe scripts for a one time compile
or run golpe watch, which will automatically trigger any time you save a change to this file.
OK, so over on the front end, if I open the overlay and search for Buyology, woops, we actually
see undefined here.
And that's just because in our code for that link text, we are currently looking for a sub property
named Rendered that belongs to a property named title.
Now this is the structure that a default rest API Eurail uses.
But if we check out Postman on our custom URL, you'll remember that our title simply lives in a property
named title.
It isn't nested in a sub property named rendered.
So back in our code, let's just delete this dot rendered.
And while we're at it, let's also address the link, the RF value, because a default rest API URL
uses a property named Lync.
But in our custom URL and JSON, we made up a custom property named Permalink.
So in our code, let's change this from link to permalink.
OK, let's go ahead and save that.
And then back in the browser, if I search for Buyology again, cool.
There's biologies.
Cool and the link successfully takes me to that blog post.
However, you might remember that we wanted blog posts to say the title by and then the author name.
Now the reason we are no longer seeing this is because in our code we are checking to see if the current
result has a property named type and if it equals post.
And only then do we want to output by the author name.
However, if we look at the custom JSON that our new Eurail is outputting, we don't have a property
named post type.
We only have title and permalink.
So right now why don't we go ahead and adjust the JSON that our custom URL outputs?
Let's add a property here named post type.
So to do that, back in our text editor within our agency folder, let's jump into search route BHP.
And if you scroll down a bit down to where we begin our while loop within this first if block, we are
saying if the current result is a blog post or page, then do this, generate a new array that gets
pushed on to the end of this array.
So within this associative array that we're building, let's just include another property.
So right after this permalink line, let's say comma, and then we could make up whatever property name
we want.
Why don't we call it post type and let's set that to equal get post type.
OK, now if I save that and refresh postman cool.
Now we can see that any results that live inside the general info array will contain a post type property.
So now back in our JavaScript, this code that checks for a property named type, let's just change
that to look for a property named post type or whatever name you just made up in the file.
Now, if this is the case and if it's a blog post, then we're going to want to output the author's
name.
And obviously we just looked at our JSON.
It does not include a property named author name.
So let's just add one really quick.
So back in our search route, right after this post type property that we just added, let's say comma,
and let's create a property named author name and let's set it to equal get the author.
And then if we save that and refresh postman perfect.
We've got a new property author name.
So now back in our front end JavaScript, this will successfully find the data that it's looking for.
So let's go ahead and save this.
And then on the front end, let's test it out again.
Perfect Biology's Cool by Brad.
And now we can just start working on outputting the results for these different headlines with these
different content types for programs and campuses.
Those can use the generic text styling like posts and pages.
But for professors, I want to show a little photograph of the professor and then I want to overlay
their name on top of that image and for events.
I want to use the same styling that we see on the homepage, right with the circle, with the date,
and then a brief description to the side of that so we can work on that custom formatting for professors
and events in the next lesson.
But while we are still in this lesson, let's go ahead and set up the results for programs and campuses.
So back in our code, in our front end JavaScript, before we output the results for programs, why
don't we actually scroll down to the bottom of this template, literal HTML and right after this line
where the template literal closes right after that.
Let's not forget to say this dot is Spiner visible.
Instead, it defaults.
So that way if someone wants to perform another search, as soon as they start typing, they will see
the Spiner icon.
OK, now back to the task at hand.
Let's output any results that are of the programs post type so there's no need to reinvent the wheel.
We can just reuse this template literal loop code.
So I'm just going to copy these three lines of code and then write underneath the programs, heading
little to pasted in.
Only this time, instead of looking within results for a sub array named General Info, I'm going to
look for an array named programs and be sure to do the same thing on this line and this third line.
Also, this time around, when it comes to programs, we do not want the text that says by the author
name.
So right after the title and write after the closing tag, I'm just going to delete this ternary operator
that checks for the post type and then tries to output the author name.
Now, if I go ahead and save this and then back on the front end, if I search for biology again, we
should see a program.
Yep, there it is.
Now, let's do the same thing for campuses.
So back in our front end JavaScript, let me just copy these three lines again, OK?
And then right underneath the heading level to four campuses, we can just paste that in.
Let's be sure to update which Southbury we are looking within.
So instead of programs, campuses do the same thing for these two references as well.
Give that to save.
And now if I search for one of the campus names that I know I have, which is downtown West.
Cool, there we have it.
Now, before we bring this lesson to a close, let's not forget about the little message we see if nothing
matches for that post type.
So this message makes sense under general information, but under programs, we forgot to update the
message.
So it still says no general info matches that search.
So back in our text editor underneath the program section, if we scroll to the right here, we see
no general info matches that search.
Let's change this instead of general info.
Let's say no programs match that search.
And then even after that sentence, we could say view all programs and then make that a link to the
programs page so we could wrap this text in an HTML, a tag, and then give the opening tag an attribute
attribute and set it to slash programs.
And that would work in most cases.
But again, not all WordPress installs are located at the root of a domain.
So to make this flexible, what we can do is instead of outputting a quote here, see how this begins
with single quotes, let's change that to a back tick so we can create a template literal.
So at the very end of this line, let's also change this single quote into a back to just a single back
take.
And now right before the slash programs, right before the slash, let's open up a JavaScript expression.
And within the curly brackets, let's say university data dot route, you are RL.
So if I save that and then search for the downtown west campus again, perfect.
No programs match that search and then a link to view all programs.
Now let's do the same thing for campuses.
If there are no campus results, we want a custom message.
So back in our code, I'm just going to copy and paste this, a tag that we just set up to avoid a lot
of extra typing.
So copy that and then if we scroll down to the campus area.
Let's just update this, so instead of general info, let's say no campuses match that search and then
before I paste in my clipboard here, that contains a template literal, I'm going to update these single
quotes to back ticks.
OK, then right here I can paste in my clipboard and change the end of the euro from programs to campuses
and save you all campuses.
Give that a save.
And now if I search for Buyology, perfect.
No campus match that search with a convenient link to view all campuses.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next one.