Hello, everyone, in this video, we're starting a new three chapter section of the course that is
all about plug in development.
Without further ado, let's review what these three new chapters are going to be about.
So the first chapter will be about.
This will cover sort of the traditional skeleton or building blocks of creating a new plug in.
The next chapter will be about JavaScript.
So it will create a new block type for the WordPress or Gutenberg block.
Ed along the way will learn a little bit about react.
But we need to remember that this is a course about WordPress not react, meaning we won't cover react
as in-depth and as slow the pace as we would in my course.
That's entirely dedicated to react.
OK, and then in the final of these three plugin chapters, we'll talk about databases specifically
when you're plugging needs to store data.
We'll talk about when it makes sense to use the WordPress built in custom post type versus when it makes
more sense to use or create your own custom database table.
So that's an overview of the three chapters.
But if you're anything like me, topics or keywords like this aren't that useful.
And instead I prefer to see the real world result of what we're going to create.
So right now, let's look at a quick preview, take a quick look at the finished product of what we're
going to build together.
So if I visit the blog section of my Web site and then view the permalink or single view for a post,
you can see there's this area called Post Statistics and it says how many words the Post has, how many
characters and about how long it would take to read the post.
So this area of content is dynamically being added to this blog post through a plug in.
Now let's go into the admin dashboard and look at the settings screen that will build for this particular
plug in.
So under the settings menu in the sidebar, we see this brand new area called Word Count.
If we click on that, we have different options.
So you can say if you want the post statistics to be at the beginning or the end of the post, you can
change the statistics headline text to be whatever you want.
And then you can also check or uncheck which one of these pieces of content you want to include.
OK, so that's the first example plug in that we're going to create together.
Let's change gears and look at the second example.
Plug in that will create together.
So in the admin side bar, you'll see an entirely new section called Word Filter.
It has its own custom icon and it actually has its own submenu.
Two different pages.
Let's look at the first page or just the words list.
So here you can include a comma separated list of words that you don't want to show up on your website
or in your blog post content.
So, for example, if I want to filter out Ipsum right the second word and lorem ipsum and then comma,
maybe the word tempore.
OK, and then I'll click save changes.
And then if I go back to the front end of my website, here's a blog post.
And if I refresh.
Notice it filtered out the word ipsum that would have been here and the word tempore that would have
been here now in terms of what we want this replaced bit of content to be.
Well, in the sidebar, the submenu for this new plugin, you can click on options.
You could have included this on the previous page.
But this is just going to be an example of how to have sub pages or submenu.
So this can be anything you want as the replacement text, or you can just leave it blank and that will
entirely remove those filtered words from your content.
OK, so those two example plug ins that we just looked at, those will be in the first chapter about
HP and just sort of traditional plug in development.
Now, let's change gears, though, and talk about the second chapter, which is going to be about JavaScript
in particular.
We're going to create a new block type.
So let me go edit this post.
It's called a new sample post.
If I go into posts, a new sample post, OK, and let's imagine that maybe after this first paragraph,
I want to add a new block.
I can use this button and here we see two new block types that you're not used to seeing.
Quick question and Professor Call-out, so we're going to build both of these together.
Let's start with a quick question.
So if I click on that, you can ask the viewers of your website a question to make sure that they're
paying attention so we could say what color is the sky on a clear and sunny day?
And then you give it multiple options or answers so we could say orange.
Add another answer green and another answer blue.
And then I'm not sure if you can see it, but there are yellow star outlines and that's how you can
mark which answer is the correct answer.
So I'll start the blue answer.
OK, let me go ahead and save or update this post and then let's view this on the front end of our website.
So if I refresh the front end after the first paragraph, cool.
And now if I get this question wrong on purpose, as a viewer of the article, you can see sorry, try
again.
But if I get it correct.
That's correct.
Cool.
And then when it fades back, you can see it sort of lets you know which answers are wrong and marks
the correct answer with a green checkmark.
Also by default, notice this block has a gray background color.
But if we go back into the admin or the edit screen, if I open up the right hand sidebar with this
block selected, you can choose any color you want.
So maybe I'll give it a really sort of like green color.
Click, update, refresh on the front end, you can see that's reflected cool, so that's the first
block type that will create together using JavaScript and react and working with the Gutenberg system
in WordPress.
Let's change gears and look at the second block type that will create together.
Let me scroll down a bit here.
Maybe after this paragraph, I want to show you the next block type.
So at this and it's called Professor Call-out, let's click that and then you can select a professor
that you want to highlight or feature in this blog post.
So I'll say Dr. Bachs a lot.
And now here's the cool part.
This is pulling in the real data for Dr. Bachs a lot on the fly.
So if I save this, this is not hard coded content that's getting injected into this blog post.
Instead, if we ever update the doctor barks a lot post in the future, this content within the blog
post will automatically get updated.
This is made possible by learning how to leverage metadata or post meta.
So instead of using something like advanced custom fields, we can roll up our sleeves and create our
own custom solution where you can store a relationship between different pieces of content.
Anyways, we'll talk more about this when we actually build this feature.
But back on the front end, if I refresh now, you can see below that paragraph there's a callout to
Dr. A and then if you visit Dr Bachs lots page, we can show the relationship coming from the other
direction.
So the plug in dynamically adds this little piece of content to the Professor Permalink, and it's going
to find any blog posts that have a relationship with this professor.
OK, once we finish that plug in together, that will wrap up the JavaScript chapter.
Now let's change gears and talk about the plugin database chapter.
So in this chapter, we're going to add a new section to our website called Pet Adoption.
In the adoption section, you can see there's going to be 100000 randomly generated pets.
So one hundred thousand items that need to be stored in the database somewhere.
Let me zoom in a little bit so you can see what's going on.
So each pet will have a randomly generated name.
Species wait birth year Hobbie favorite color and favorite food.
Now, right about here, you can see how long it took for WordPress to create this page.
So if I refresh every time, it's going to be slightly different.
But you can see that on average on my computer, it's taking about two tenths of a second to load the
first one hundred pets out of the one hundred thousand items.
Now, that's not too bad of a speed.
However, it gets a lot worse.
So this is just a generic query to show us any and all pets.
What if instead I only want to see the pets that are of the species cat and only cats that have a favorite
hobby of scratching furniture?
So if I go up into the address bar and add on questionmark species equals cat and fav Hobbie equals
scratching furniture.
We scroll down a little bit so you can see out of the hundred thousand pets, there are eight hundred
and five that match that specific search.
However, that took almost a full second to complete.
Let me refresh again so we can see sort of an average speed that took one point one seconds.
Everything's subjective, but I feel like that's very slow.
Now, this example that we're looking at right now, this is using custom post types to store the pet
data.
So each one of these hundred thousand pets is a post right.
Of the custom post type called PET.
And then each one of these custom pieces of data about the pet, that's a piece of Medda.
Now, when we actually get to this chapter, we'll discuss this in greater detail.
But essentially, there are many things that you get for free when you use WordPress custom post types.
Every developer has a different opinion, but I believe custom post types are a great idea.
Unless you need to be able to search or query by a piece of metadata.
At that point, it gets very inefficient and very slow because, for example, in this tab we have the
exact same hundred thousand pets.
Only now we're no longer using custom post types in this tab.
On this site.
In this example, I've created my own separate custom database table and I'm writing my own SQL queries.
So if I perform the same search right, if I say only show me where Species' equals cat and fav Hobbie
equals scratching furniture.
You can see if I refresh, that's only taking about a tenth of a second compared to over one point one
seconds using the WordPress custom post type solution.
So that's somewhere in the ballpark of ten times faster.
Anyways, in this chapter will discuss in detail when it makes sense to use custom post types for your
plug in data needs and when it makes sense to implement your own custom database table like this.
We'll also learn how to have this red X to the side so you can delete any one of the pet items.
Also down at the very bottom of this page, there's a form where you can add in a name and then it will
randomly generate all of the other attributes about the pet and add it to the database so that we can
practice sort of the basics of CRUD operations using your own custom database table.
OK, so that wraps up the quick preview or the quick look at the finished product of what we're going
to build together.
At this point, you might be thinking to yourself, but what about topics or features X, Y and Z and
WordPress like widgets or any of the other ten thousand features and WordPress?
Well, these three chapters of the course, they're meant to be a guided tour, not an exhaustive encyclopedia
of plugin development.
WordPress is just too big of a topic with too many different features and APIs and sort of the whole
point of plug ins is that the possibilities are infinite, endless.
Anything that you can think of that you want to extend or customize and WordPress, you can do that
with a plugin.
So every single option, every parameter, every action or every filter that we can hook on to any setting
that we can change anything is possible with plugins.
So it's impossible to cover it all in a course like this.
Trust me, the course would become 400 hours long and everyone would lose interest.
The idea here is just to show you the core basic building blocks and the most common features that you're
going to need to work with in order to build plug ins from there.
Once you're familiar with these basics, it'll be easy for you to Google and do a bit of research on
the specifics of a WordPress feature or API that you need to customize to bring your plug in idea to
life.
OK, so the whole point of these three chapters is to give you a rock solid foundation to build upon,
and I think it's going to be a ton of fun.
Now, in our very next lesson, we're going to get started will be starting with the traditional chapter.
So just sort of creating a new plug in, maybe creating an admin menu, so on and so forth.
I'm excited to jump into this with you.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you in the next video.