Hello, everyone, in this extra credit section of the course, I will be giving you various challenges
for you to work through.
I will not be giving you the exact answers and we will not work through these together step by step.
OK, at this point, I want to take off the training wheels and I want you to work through these by
yourself.
Now, if you get stuck on a challenge, don't worry, because there's a community of other people all
working on the same challenges.
So if you get stuck, just take advantage of the question and answer section.
Each extra credit challenge will have its own video.
And so I want everyone to organize your questions around each video.
Basically, when you post a question, instead of just letting the question float in outer space, make
sure that you link or assign it to the particular video for that challenge.
So that way, if someone struggling with challenge number two, they can view a list of all of the question
and answer threads just for that one video and challenge.
OK, so hopefully this way everyone can help everyone else stay motivated, stay inspired, brainstorm
solutions together and help each other find typos, so on and so forth.
All right.
Now, having said all of that, let's jump into the action and get started with the first challenge.
Challenge number one is an improvement that I want you to make to our fictional university website.
So on the home page, down at the very bottom, right above the footer, we have this slideshow area.
Now, at the moment, this slideshow lives within our front page template, meaning the slide show is
static and not dynamic.
So this means that in order to make changes to the slide show, basically you need to be a web developer.
But it would be nice if anyone on our team or at our company could update the slide show.
Right.
You shouldn't need to be a web developer to change the text or to make the button point towards a new
page or to upload a new photograph.
So for your first challenge, I want you to make the slideshow editable from within the WordPress admin
dashboard.
So what I mean by that is this way, an account person or designer on our team, someone who isn't a
web developer, could just jump into the dashboard and then there can either be an area in the sidebar
named homepage slideshow or they can click into pages and click on the home page.
But either way, if they want to update either the title or the subtitle for any of the slides, they
should just be able to edit a text field.
And if they want to change the background image, it should be as easy as just uploading a new media
file within WordPress.
OK, now I'm not going to give you the exact answer on how to do this, but I will point you in the
right direction.
I would say there's two main ways of setting this up.
For your first option, you can just create a new custom post type, maybe name it homepage slideshow.
So that way it would show up as a new item in the admin dashboard in the sidebar.
And then for that custom post type, just assign it custom fields such as slide title slides, subtitle
slide link text and slide link value and slide photograph.
In this strategy, each slide would be its own post.
So three posts in this custom post type would give you three slides.
If you wanted a fourth and fifth slide in the slideshow, you would just create a fourth and fifth post.
OK, that's option number one.
The other way that you could set this up would rely on a page instead of a custom post type.
So, for example, this is the home page.
So in the admin dashboard, if you went into pages and then remember, we have a home page that is set
to be our front page.
But basically within this page, you could set up advanced custom fields that only display for this
page.
So, for example, instead of page, banner, subtitle and page banner background image, you could
set up fields that correspond with a slideshow.
However, you might be scratching your head thinking, wouldn't that only work for one slide?
For example, when it comes to our page banner fields, someone can enter a text and then in this field
you can upload an image.
But then what if you wanted to create another slide and another slide?
Well, that's a good question.
If you wanted to, you could set up a fixed number of slides.
So maybe there can only be at most five slides on the home page.
So then you can just set up five copies of corresponding fields, slide image one slide image two,
three, four, five.
Or if you want to make things flexible so that people on your team could add as many slides as they
want to.
In that case, whenever I need to set up that functionality for a client website of mine, I reach for
a premium plug in named Advanced Custom Fields Pro right away.
I want to stress the fact that I am not in any way affiliated with this plugin.
Even if everyone watching this video goes out and buys this plug in right now, I will not make a penny.
Personally, I'm just a big fan of this plugin and I use it on almost all of my client websites.
So throughout this course, we used the free version of advanced custom fields, but there's also a
pro version of the plug in.
Now, the pro version has all sorts of features, but really I only buy it for two features.
Probably the biggest reason is the repeater field.
This feature lets you set up a single field or a collection of fields and it makes them repeatable.
So as an example, when it comes to our page, banner, subtitle and page banner background image,
if you wanted users to be able to add more than one page banner per post, you could set up a repeater
field that contains both of these fields.
And then in the user interface right here, there would be a plus symbol.
And if you clicked that, it would just create a new duplicate copy of both fields for you so you could
put in a subtitle, upload an image, click the duplicate button, and then you'd have a new pair of
fields where you could type in a new subtitle and upload a new image.
And you could just keep repeating it as many times as you want, all within a single post.
So this has the potential to be super powerful, but obviously it comes at a price, right?
This is the pro version, so it's not free, but I feel like the pricing is pretty fair as of this moment.
The personal version is twenty five Australian dollars, which I believe is a little bit under 20 US
dollars.
And if you're working on a client website, you can just include that in your bill to the client and
you can use the personal version on as many websites as you want, but you can only receive automatic
updates from one project or one site.
So if you want to avoid having to manually update your plugins and you want to use this on all of your
websites, the price does become a bit steeper.
But the personal version is a great place to start.
Now, I did mention that the pro version comes with all sorts of features, but I really only buy it
for two features.
So the first reason was the repeater field.
And the other feature that I love is the flexible content field.
This is probably my favorite feature that any plugin has ever offered, and that's because it's a developer's
paradise.
This feature in and of itself doesn't do anything.
It's worthless unless you bring your own value as a developer to it.
So what I mean by that is when someone is on a poster page authoring screen, right.
So if someone's in the admin and they're creating a new poster page, basically it adds this ad row
button.
And when they click that, it gives them a choice of what type of content they want to add to the page.
And you as the developer decide what these options are.
So maybe your first option could be to column layout and then the next option could be three column
layout, and then the next option could be slideshow, and then the next option could be data table
or featured.
Professor.
Right.
You can make up whatever features you want and you get to spell out the exact fields and user interface
that each type of content should use.
And then also as the developer, you get to control the exact HTML that gets output for each one of
those.
It's difficult to explain in a quick fashion, but basically this is the most powerful and flexible
feature I've ever seen in WordPress.
In my opinion, this single feature makes WordPress a premiere content management system.
It puts WordPress right up there or above things like Drupal and Joomla and crafts CMS.
I can't say enough good things about this feature.
In fact, other content management systems have actually copied and tried to imitate.
This feature, so I would pay the 20 U.S. dollars just for this feature alone, but I don't want to
sound like a used car salesman.
It's totally up to you.
Hopefully that gives you a lot of different ideas to play with.
And I do want to emphasize the point that if you don't want to spend even another dollar right now and
you're not interested in the advanced custom fields pro version, that's OK.
You don't need to use it.
Remember, option number one was to just create a custom post type named homepage slideshow, and you
could set that up with the free version of advanced custom fields without any problems.
OK, that's going to do it for this first extra credit challenge.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see in the next one.