Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will begin implementing live search results, so, for example, if someone comes
to our website and they know exactly what they're looking for, instead of clicking on one of our links,
we want them to be able to use the search icon up in the top right corner of our header.
Right.
So if someone was interested in biology, they should be able to click this icon and then just type
in the word biology.
So that makes sense.
But you might be wondering, what does Leive search results mean?
What is the word live mean in this context?
Well, to answer that, let me show you an example of the opposite of live search results.
So in this tab, this is an empty demo, separate WordPress site using the default 2017 theme.
And here we see the default search box.
And if I click onto that and begin typing in biology, absolutely nothing will happen until I either
press enter on my keyboard or click the submit button.
Now, the opposite of this behavior is live search results.
Live is just another way of saying real time or on the fly or in the moment.
Live search results would be as soon as I'm typing in biology and maybe just a couple hundred milliseconds
after I type in the final letter and then pause for a second, we would then immediately be presented
with the results for that search query right about here.
Or if I backspace and typed in math just a couple hundred milliseconds after I stopped typing, we could
see the results for that search query right here without having to press, enter or submit the form.
Right.
Because with this traditional way of searching, if I want to search for math, I actually have to submit
this form.
It refreshes my browser, takes me to an entirely different URL, and only then can I finally see the
results for that search.
Now, I don't think that traditional search results like this is terrible and we will learn how to set
this up as a fallback later on in the course.
But I do think that live real time on the fly search results can create a more engaging user experience.
So that's what we're going to set up as our first preference.
Right.
When someone clicks this search icon in the top right header of our website, what I want to do is open
up a full screen, semi transparent overlay or lightbox with a text input field that the user can begin
immediately typing into.
And then a couple hundred milliseconds after they stop typing, we can present them with the search
results in real time.
So how can we make this happen?
Well, let's talk about programming languages.
So in this case, P p cannot help us, right?
P P is great at initially outputting the page that we want to load.
But once the Web browser has loaded the page, if we want to make any changes without completely refreshing
the page, we need to use the JavaScript language.
Right.
JavaScript is how we can manipulate the page in real time.
So right now, why don't you and I begin writing a bit of JavaScript, so let's open up our text editor
and in our theme folder, let's look within the SIRC folder and I want you to open up Index JS now.
This main recipe file is already importing several modules, so mobile menu is for small devices.
So if you resized your browser to be very small and very narrow, you would see a menu icon in the top
right corner that you could click on to view the navigation menu.
Next, we see Hero Slider and that's the JavaScript that powers the slideshow at the bottom of our homepage.
Finally, we also have Google map, and we just added that a couple of lessons ago, so with the idea
of staying organized in mind right now, why don't we create a new separate file that is dedicated to
powering our live search results feature?
So let's create a new file in this module subfolder that lives inside our Sarsae folder.
So inside this modules folder, let me create a new file.
The name of this file does not matter, but just to make sense, why don't I name it?
Search J.S..
And in this course we are going to be writing object oriented JavaScript.
Again, this is optional.
You don't have to write object oriented code.
This has nothing to do with WordPress.
It's just my own personal preference.
But it's a very popular way of doing things in the professional dev world.
And I think that you learning how to write object oriented modular code is only going to help your career.
OK, so let's begin by creating a class named Search So class and then the name of our class, you could
name it whatever you want.
Let's go with search, OK?
And then we add in some curly brackets.
And then in JavaScript, whenever we create a class, we want to be sure to include a constructor function.
So we just type out constructor.
It's a special reserved word in JavaScript and then parentheses curly brackets, OK, and then any code
that we place within the constructor function will be executed as soon as we create an object using
our class or blueprint.
Remember, a class is just a recyclable blueprint that we can use to create multiple objects using this
recipe.
Now, instead of worrying about actually building the live search results functionality right in this
moment.
Instead, just as a quick example and test within our constructor function, why don't we alert a pop
up message that says, hello, I am a search.
All right.
And let's pretend that we are now done creating our class and now we want to be able to import and use
it within our main scripts file.
So back in our search JS file, down at the very bottom of this file, we can just say export default
and then the name of the class search.
And this line of code will allow us to import this file into our main scripts file.
So check this out.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
And then back in our main index JS file in this section of code, why don't we import in that new search
module?
So new line, let's say, import search from and then we just provide a path that points towards the
new search file and will say dot forward slash to look inside the current folder.
And then we just want to look inside this sub folder named modules, look inside that folder.
And the name of the file is Search.
You don't need to include the dot js.
We just need the actual file name search.
All right.
And now that we've imported that file in class, we can actually use it to create a new object.
So down here, let's add a new line and let's create a variable and name it magical search.
The name doesn't matter.
I'm just making up a temporary name and let's set it to equal a new instance of our search class.
Right.
A class is just a blueprint that you can use to create new instances or new objects.
Now, as soon as I save this file, our command line will automatically rebundle up our JavaScript.
Click.
OK, now back in our text editor, we created one object named Magical Search.
But remember, classes can be reused so we could create another variable or another object and name
it amazing search and also tell it to equal a new instance of the search class.
And if we save this, I think you can imagine what will happen.
We see one pop up.
Hello, I am a search and if I click OK, we see a second pop up.
Hello.
I am a search.
So the idea here is that we create a reusable blueprint or class, and it gets to live in its own neat,
organized, separate file, and then once we import that file, we can use it as many times as we want
to create different objects or variables.
Now, in reality, in this instance for our website, we don't need multiple search objects.
We are only going to have one single search object.
I only did this to remind you what a class is, right?
A class is a potentially reusable blueprint.
The code that lives within a class doesn't actually get executed until you create an object that uses
that class as a blueprint.
OK, so let me go ahead and delete the second search and then let me rename the first search to just
simply search the naming.
Doesn't matter, but this will look a bit cleaner for us.
Let's go ahead and save that.
OK, so now we're just back to the one pop up now that's actually going to bring this lesson to a close
now that we are all on the same page and we've got our JavaScript rolling in our next lesson, we will
actually begin writing out the code to power live search results.
This should be a lot of fun.
There's the potential to learn a lot about JavaScript.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.