Hello, everyone, in this lesson, we're starting a new chapter, so this is the third and final chapter
in the plugin development section of the course, and it's all about how we should store our plugins
data in the database.
Now, before we go any further and start to talk about the details of what we're going to learn in this
chapter.
I first want to keep us grounded in real world examples.
So let me begin by showing you this.
So here I have two different sites, two different tabs, and at first the two sites look identical.
So this is a pet adoption page and there are 100000 pets in the collection of pets or the database of
pets.
And you can see each pet is just an item that has a name and six other pieces of data.
Now, while both versions of the site are identical in that sense, they both have 100000 pet records
with the same properties.
They're similar in that regard.
But the two sites are very different in the sense that this tab is using the WordPress way of handling
data.
Right.
Which is custom post types in WordPress.
Basically everything is just a post.
So each pet is a post, the pet's name is the title.
And then these six attributes.
Each one of these is just a piece of metadata associated to that post.
So this tab is the WordPress custom post type way of doing things.
This tab is using my own custom database table and my own sequel queries that I wrote.
Now, at first glance on this initial page that just pulls in the first 100 pets regardless of their
species or favorite color or favorite food, you can see that the speed is very similar.
So my custom database solution took a little bit less than a tenth of a second and the WordPress way
of doing things took a little bit under two tenths of a second.
However, what if we only wanted to see pets where the species is cat and maybe their favorite color
is green?
So, for example, if I go up into the address bar and add on questionmark species equals cat and fav
color equals green and press enter.
Well, you can see that the WordPress way of doing things took one point two seconds.
But if I try this exact same search or query in my custom database solution, so if I say questionmark
species equals cat and fav color equals green, you can see it took just barely over a tenth of a second.
So it's nearly ten times faster.
So the speed difference is night and day.
But before we start to learn about custom database tables, our first goal absolutely needs to be to
understand why the custom database table solution is so much faster in this situation.
The reason it's so important to understand why it's faster is because it's not always going to be the
right choice.
In fact, I would say that nine times out of ten, using the WordPress way of handling data, so custom
post types is actually the smarter or correct choice.
However, I want you to be able to identify these one out of 10 type of situations where your own custom
table is the right choice, because as we've seen, it can result in a site there's literally ten times
faster.
So big picture.
Our project for this chapter is to code the customer database table solution together.
But before we get to that, our goal for this lesson is to really understand the strengths and weaknesses
of storing data in posts.
Now, you and I have already worked with custom post types a lot in this course.
In other words, there's no point in you and I coding this custom post type version together.
Instead, I want you to download the associated zip file with this lesson called pets' custom post type
dot zip.
Technically, you don't need to do this since this lesson is just about understanding the big picture,
not about actually coding yet, but a lot of people learn by doing and having a real breathing example
to experiment with.
So I encourage you to follow along in this lesson.
But essentially we're just going to take the finished product for the custom post type version and activate
it and inspect it and analyze it and even look at the database structure so we can really start to get
a feel for the strengths and weaknesses of custom post types, because ultimately we want to be able
to make smart decisions of whether a specific plugin should use custom post types or a custom database
table.
There is no one size fits all.
Correct answer, every plugin is different, and it just depends on the shape and quantity of your expected
data.
Having said that, let's start analyzing the custom post type finished solution.
So, again, I want you to download the zip file.
Go ahead and extract it so you should have pets custom post type folder directly inside it, you'll
see a file, a file and an ANC folder.
So we just want to move this folder into your WordPress installations plugins folder.
So we're just looking for the installation folder of WordPress where you'll see WP content.
If you go in there, you can go into plug ins and I'm just going to drag this new folder to live alongside
the other plug ins we've been creating so far.
OK, now back in this tab, I have not set up anything to do with pet adoption, so you and I are on
the same page.
So let's go activate that plug in.
We just added so under plug ins.
If I scroll down through this list, for me it's towards the bottom, but I see pet adoption custom
post types, so let's activate that, OK, and then do this with me.
We just want to create a page.
So not a post but a page.
So add a new page and give it the exact title of pet adoption.
We just want to make sure that the slug or permalink is Pet Dasch adoption.
So as soon as we publish or save this page.
Well, if you use The View page linked down here, well, thanks to that plug in, we just activated
it should be using this template.
So pet adoption, providing forever homes one search at a time.
Just a quick note.
This example plug in I created is assuming that you're using the fictional university theme.
So if you're using a different theme and this heter area doesn't align perfectly, that's why.
But really, that's not the topic at hand right now.
I want to show you how we can begin to populate the pet collection with a bit of data, because currently
we have a total of zero results.
So do this with me.
Let's open up that plug in folder in our text editor.
So in the plug ins folder, we just added pets custom post type.
I'm just going to drag this into V code, OK, and jump into the main file.
So pets custom post types B and if we scroll down towards the bottom, you'll see this comment.
Essentially, it's just telling you that if you uncommented this line, this add action around line
number forty nine, when you uncommented this out, then the next time you visit or refresh the admin
dashboard, WordPress is going to generate 10 randomly generated pets.
Now that number ten is defined here, but let's just start with ten.
So if I uncommented this click save now before you do this, do not set this to a very large number.
If you're on a real Web hosting account, if you're hosting WordPress locally on your personal development
computer and you have ten minutes to spare, sure, you can try entering a large number here.
But to begin, let's just start with the default ten.
And now if we go into the admin dashboard or if you were already on the dashboard, then refresh.
But since I wasn't already on the dashboard, just visiting it, this one time will create those 10
pets.
So you could already recommend out this line and save it.
If you don't want to create more pets right now.
But as soon as I look in the sidebar for pets here, we see pets with the custom pet icon.
If you click on that, you will see ten randomly generated pet posts.
So, for example, on this page, I could uncommented that line again.
And if I click save, if I refresh the page, well, now there's too many pets, so it's up to you.
How many pet records are pet posts you want to add?
Again, if you set this to a very large number, your Web hosting account will probably just time out
your entire website.
But if you're on your personal development computer, you could set this all the way up to one hundred
thousand and you will need to wait maybe five or ten or twenty minutes and it will work.
Now, obviously, WordPress is not optimized for creating 10000 or 100000 posts at once, so it's not
going to be the fastest operation.
But if you're someone who likes to have that full 100000 example site to experiment with, then you
can do that, but you don't need to.
So, for example, if I set this to just even one hundred, I'll let it load in real time.
So if I go back and refresh, you can see it doesn't happen immediately.
That took maybe one or two seconds, but now I have one hundred and twenty pets.
So let me comment out this line again.
So again, it's totally up to you how many pets you want to add.
But now if we view the front end of our website and at the end of the homepage, you if we visit PET.
Adoption pet, Dasch, adoption, well, perfect, we found one hundred and twenty results showing the
first 100 and here is the actual data.
Now, as we saw at the very beginning of the video, when you're just performing a base query like this
where you're not searching for a specific species or favorite color, the word press way of handling
data with post types is not very slow at all.
And even further, in defense of custom post types, even if you do want to query based on a piece of
metadata, even that is not going to be slow unless you have a lot and a lot and a lot of posts and
post Medda.
So let me explain.
If we go up into the address bar and at the end say Questionmark Species' equals dog and visit that
quote.
So you can see out of the 120 pets that I had, six of them are dogs.
But notice that the time it took to find that is not very long.
So that's not very slow.
However, as you continue to add more and more pet posts, it's just going to get dramatically slower
and slower.
To understand why, let's go actually look at our database.
If you're using the local WP app, you can just click on the current site you're running.
Click on the database tab and then click open add mynor.
Just a quick note.
If you have more than one WordPress site running at once, I have seen local get confused when you click
open admirer and it will show you the database, not for the current site that you think you're viewing.
So if it feels like you're not looking at the correct data for your site, you might just need to stop
any other currently running sites.
Let's start by looking at the posts table.
So in the left hand area, click on to the post table, then click select data.
Lets go to the very last page of results.
And as you scroll through this list, if you created any decent amount of pets, you'll notice that
each one of these posts is just a randomly generated pet.
However, really, the only piece of relevant pet data is the blog post title, right?
That's their name.
But as you scroll through this, you're not going to find their favorite color or their favorite food,
their favorite hobby, because all of that is post meta or metadata.
We need to remember that at its core, WordPress was originally just about creating blog posts.
So the shape of data or the shape of this table is designed with blog posts in mind.
If you want to store any type of information about something that isn't in the shape of a blog post,
that's where you have to use post meta.
And this is where we're getting into why this approach gets so slow in certain situations.
So check this out.
If we want to actually find any of their favorite colors or hobbies or foods, we need to go into post
meta the post metastable, click into that and click select data and go to our very last page.
And if we look through this notice, we see fave food, birth, your weight, fav color fave Hoby,
and then it already starts to repeat here.
So there's going to be those six or seven properties for each pet or for each post.
Right.
Notice that all of these they have the exact same post IDs.
They're all pointing towards that one pet object or pet post.
But each little piece of data is its own entry, its own record or row in the database.
And there are both pros and cons to this approach or to this database design.
So the big advantage is that it's super flexible.
This is what allows WordPress to store just about any type or shape of data we can think of while still
using that rather limited post table structure.
However, this flexibility comes at a price.
So to understand why and when this approach becomes very slow, let's walk through two examples or two
queries.
Let's go back to our site example.
Number one, let's talk about just this base query where you pull in the first one hundred results and
then query number two.
That will review is when you're searching only for dogs.
Right.
So based on a value from a piece of metadata.
So let's start with query number one.
Just this base query, right?
We're saying the word press.
Just give me the first one hundred pet posts.
So this type of query will always be relatively fast, even if we have a lot and a lot of pet posts.
This is because all WordPress has to do is look in its post database table.
And if you scroll over to the right, it just looks for any post whose post type is set to pet.
Now, once it finds one of those pet items, well, it's going to know it's post ID and then it just
needs to look in the post metastable for any entries where the Post ID column has a matching post ID
value so WordPress can even index.
This column for this table and that way, even if this metastable becomes very large, it's always going
to be at least reasonably quick to perform this query.
However, let's look at the slow query.
So the query, if I go forward where you're only looking for where Species' equals dog.
Now, again, it's not very slow because I only have one hundred and twenty pets.
But what if I had two thousand pets?
Ten thousand pets, a hundred thousand pets?
Well, let's talk about what WordPress needs to do to the database in order to find this data.
So now it's not just as simple as going into the post table and selecting the first one hundred results
where post type equals pet instead.
Now WordPress needs to look in the post metastable and it does not just get to look for a matching posted
where that value can be indexed.
So it's super quick to find it instead.
Think about this.
If we're only looking for dogs, sure, WordPress can index this meta key column and look for the rows
where it has a value of species and then look through all of those for ones where the value is dog.
But that's still not ideal, especially when we realize how quickly this table can become absolutely
huge.
Think about it for every one pet post that's adding six new rows to this table.
Imagine if you were working with some other type of data other than a pet post.
Imagine if you were working on an e-commerce website where a product can have all sorts of information
the shipping weight, the height, the width where it's produced, what it's made out of, who it's
produced by, all these different things.
What if every one of your posts is going to create 10, 20 or even 30 pieces of meta?
And then imagine what if you're going to have a thousand of those posts or ten thousand of those posts
or one hundred thousand.
So you can imagine how this post metastable can get very large very quickly.
Now, let's truly change gears and let's contrast this approach with what our own custom database table
could look like.
So off camera, I just switched to the custom database solution.
So you won't have this on your copy yet.
But notice I have a table called pets, and if I click on that and select data, each row is a pet and
there's no need to look up data anywhere else in any other metastable.
So if I scroll to the right, you can see there's a column for all of the relevant data.
So now if you're only looking for animals where the species is dog, it's as simple as the database.
Just looking in this one column, in this one table.
So not only is the table way smaller, there's less items and rows to have to look through.
Right.
Because each pet only takes up one row instead of each Medda taking a row.
But also now the database doesn't need to look for a specific row where meta name is Species'.
Instead, it just needs to look in this one column.
It knows exactly where to look and what to search for.
And this is why, like we saw at the very start of this video, this approach can be 10 or even 20 times
faster than the custom post type way.
So you might be thinking, this is great.
Why don't we just use our own custom database table like this for everything?
The answer is because we're giving up or forfeiting so many cool free features when we use a table like
this.
WordPress does so many things for us, whereas if we use a table like this, we're essentially going
back to the Stone Age.
We need to do everything ourselves.
We need to babysit every feature, every detail.
And so development time is just going to be exponentially slower.
For example, if you think about everything WordPress gives you with post types, it's giving you an
admin interface where it's easy to perform CRUD operations.
It's giving you rest API endpoints for CRUD operations.
It automatically ties your posts to permission groups or permission rolls.
The list goes on and on.
The point is that WordPress offers so many benefits when you use its post system that you should really
only use a custom database table if both of the following things are true.
Number one, you need to be able to query based on a piece of custom metadata.
So just storing the metadata is not the problem.
It's when you need to be able to search by it.
But even that isn't a problem.
If you're only going to have maybe a hundred posts or maybe a thousand or two thousand pets, it only
becomes slow if you need to search by the meta and you anticipate your users will have lots and lots
of those posts.
If both of those things are true, then I do think your plugin should use its own database table.
And learning how to set that up is exactly what we're going to learn about in the remainder of this
chapter.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you in the next lesson.