Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will learn how to set up a global header and footer.
If you don't know what I'm referring to, let me show you.
So here's the homepage that we set up in our previous lesson.
And on most websites, you're going to want some sort of header area that appears on every page of the
website.
Same thing with the footer area.
So if you want to add content at the very top and bottom of your pages, your first instinct might be
to go into your index file in your theme folder and just add something up at the very top.
So even before the opening tag, you could include an HTML headline that says this is the header area.
And for the footer down at the very bottom after the closing tag, we could say HTML paragraph.
This is the footer area and if I save this and refresh the home page, cool, we have a header and footer
so that works.
But it's not ideal because we want this same identical header on every single page of the site.
But we know from last lesson that Index P doesn't power every page on our website.
So for example, if we click on one of the blog posts, we lose our header and footer because this screen
is powered by a single dot.
And don't forget about Page Dot, which powers individual pages instead of posts.
So long story short, if we wanted this header and footer on every page, we would have to duplicate
or copy and paste this code into multiple different template files.
Now, duplicating code like that is almost always a bad practice because then if in the future, maybe
a week from now, we want to change something in the header, we don't want to have to make that change
in five or 10 or 20 different template files.
Instead, we want our header code to live in just one file.
Right.
We want a single source of truth.
So check this out.
Right now, I want you to create a new file in your theme folder.
So new file.
And let's name this new file header dot p HP.
And in this new file, let's write out a bit of dummy text, so maybe an HTML headline that says Greetings
from heterodoxy.
All right, let's save this and then jump back into index P and let's delete this headline that we set
up a couple of minutes ago.
And instead, let's write a bit of code that will pull in the contents of header P, so let's enter
into P mode and then call a WordPress function named Gett Underscore header.
And remember to call a function you include parentheses right after it semicolon.
And we could close out of here, but because we were just going to drop right back into PHP for all
of this code, why don't we just get rid of this closing tag and also get rid of this opening tag.
So that way we just stay in P mode.
Anyways, back to the task at hand.
This git header function will pull in the contents of header B, so if we save this and refresh the
homepage, cool.
We see greetings from header P next.
Let's do the same thing for our footer.
So back in our text editor, let's create a new file in the theme folder.
Let's name this new file Footer Dot P.
In this file, let's write out a bit of dummy text, so maybe a paragraph that says Greetings from footrot
P save this.
And then back in our home page indexed file, let's replace this down here with code that will dynamically
pull in the contents of the footer file so we could drop into mode down here or we could just write
this code up here while we are still in PHP.
You can probably guess the name of the WordPress function we want to use git underscore footer.
OK, with that in place if we save.
Cool greetings from footrot.
And if we click on one of the blog post links.
We do not see the header or footer, but all we need to do is go into single dot p and call those get
header and get footer functions.
So back in the text editor, let's jump in to our single file and right before the while loop, let's
say get header.
All right.
And then right after the curly bracket that closes the while loop, lets say get footer, let's save
that.
And now our single post screen is in business, so that takes care of individual posts.
Let's not forget about individual pages.
Remember in our WordPress admin dashboard, if we click on pages in the sidebar, in our previous lesson,
we created this dummy page test page one, two, three.
And if I use this view link here to preview it, this screen is powered by Page Dot.
So let's go ahead and jump into our text editor and hop in to page P and let's pull in our global header
and footer.
So get header.
And down here, below the curly bracket, get footer.
Cool, so now whenever we update Hedera or footrot, we can rest assured that our entire website globally
will be updated.
Now, before we bring this lesson to a close.
I have two more tasks for us that are directly related to the header and footer.
First, let's learn how to load our CFS file on the front end of our website.
And secondly, let's learn how to add the black admin menubar that's supposed to sit at the top of our
website.
Globally, you can see the menu bar I'm referring to if you jump over to the WordPress admin screens.
But that bar should also be on the front end of our website while we are signed in.
OK, but let's start with our first task of actually loading our CSC file on the front end of our website.
If you've worked with HTML in the past, you probably already know how to load text file, right?
You include it towards the top of your HTML file in the head section.
So to get started, let's jump into our text editor and open header up and let's delete this dummy text
and start fresh.
Let's begin with the basic skeleton of an HTML document.
So you always begin with the DOCTYPE and then right below that you create an HTML sandwich and then
within that you have two sandwiches, the head sandwich and the body sandwich.
So within the body section is where you include your actual content.
Right?
So maybe you'd have a headline that says Fictional University.
All right.
But back to the task at hand.
The head section is usually where you load your txt file only in WordPress instead of manually including
our CSFs file using link.
Instead of doing that in WordPress, we just call a P function named WP Underscore Head.
And this lets WordPress be in control of our head section.
So imagine down the road we install a few WordPress plug ins and maybe those plug ins need to load CSFs
files of their own.
So this function lets WordPress have the final say and load whatever it needs to load in our head.
All right.
Now, with this line of code in place, all we need to do is programmatically tell WordPress to load
RSS file.
And the way that we do that is by creating a brand new file in our theme folder.
And let's name this new file functions dot p HP.
Now, this new functions file is a bit different from all of the other files we've been creating so
far.
All of our other files are what we might call template files, right.
They control the HTML that the general public will see on our website.
Well, think of this function file as a bit more private.
This is our behind the scenes file.
This is where we can have a conversation with the WordPress system itself.
All right.
But back to the task at hand.
We want to tell WordPress to load our CFS file.
So within this function file, let's open up PHP and then call a WordPress function named ADD underscore
action.
This is a super useful WordPress function that we will use again and again throughout the course, within
these parentheses, this function wants us to give it to arguments.
So, for example, quotes and then A quotes, B, now, obviously, we're not going to pass it in argument
of A and B, I'm just including these as placeholders.
OK, now let me explain what this function actually does.
So WordPress lets us give it instructions and tell it what to do by using this add action function.
The first argument is where we tell WordPress what type of instructions we are giving it.
Depending on what we are trying to do.
WordPress will run this code at different times.
In this case, we want to load a file.
So the special WordPress hook name that we want to hook on to is WP underscore on cue, underscore scripts
and the name here definitely matters.
You need to spell it exactly right or WordPress won't know what you're trying to do.
All right.
So this is our way of saying, hey, WordPress, I want to load some success or JavaScript files.
And then the second argument instead of B, let's delete that.
And what we do here is give WordPress the name of A function that we want to run.
And it's important to point out that this is going to be a function that we create and define in about
10 seconds from now.
So in this case, we need to make up a name.
Why don't we name our function fictional university resources or fictional university files?
How about university underscore files?
OK, for this argument, the name doesn't matter.
It just needs to be something that makes sense to you personally and that you can remember.
All right.
Now, right above this line, why don't we create a function with this exact name?
So we will say function and then spell out that name university underscore files, parentheses, and
then we are defining or creating the function.
So then curly brackets and now within these curly brackets, within the body of this function, we can
load as many sixths or JavaScript files as we want.
For now, though, we just want to load one txt file right.
Our main style DOCSIS So we will call a WordPress function named WP underscore on Q Style.
And within the parentheses, this function is looking for two arguments for the first, we just need
to make up a nickname for our main stylesheet.
This name does not matter.
It just needs to make sense to us.
Why don't we call it university main styles?
OK, and then the second argument is just a location that points towards the file later on.
In this course, we will learn how to point towards a custom folder directories and look up specific
file names.
But in this case, since we just want to work with the main style access file and that's sort of the
default style sheet in WordPress, we don't need to manually spell out a location here.
We can just call a WordPress function named Gett underscore stylesheet underscore you are I OK?
And that's a WordPress function that we are calling.
So include parentheses right after it.
Cool.
And if we wanted to include a second or third txt file, you could just duplicate this line here.
And if you wanted to load a JavaScript file instead of success, you would just change this word from
style to script, singular script, not plural scripts.
But I wouldn't worry about that because I will show you how to load JavaScript file very soon.
OK, but for now, if we go ahead and save this file and let's also be sure to save the recent changes
to header PHP and then if we refresh in the browser, cool, we see that all of the text is orange.
And that's because in our style docs US file, remember, we wrote this as a test in an earlier lesson,
so if I change orange to green.
You get the idea or txt file is loading.
Now, before we move on to our final task for this lesson, which is loading the black admin menubar
up at the top here.
Before we get to that, I want to take a minute to review all of that code we just wrote in our functions
file because this can definitely feel confusing or overwhelming.
So let's break it down.
Really, all we did was create or define a brand new function that we chose the name of.
We got to make this name up.
The name doesn't matter.
Within that function, we called a WordPress function and pointed towards the CSFs file that we wanted
to load.
OK, but remember that when you create and define a function, the function doesn't actually run.
Someone or something needs to call that function later on.
And that's exactly what we are doing in this line of code.
WordPress has a function named Add Action and you give it to arguments.
Let's begin with the second argument.
This is just the name of a function that you want WordPress to call at a specific moment.
And this is how you say which moment that should be.
So WordPress has tons of different hooks or moments that we can hook on to.
So altogether, this line of code is basically saying, hey, WordPress, right before you get ready
to output your code, that's going to go in the header.
That's going to go in this WP head area right before you're getting ready to output that.
We want to tack on to that moment and we want you to run our custom function.
Now, before we move on, I want to go over one last topic.
That is a common point of confusion for people.
You might be thinking, hey, I thought whenever we call or run a function, we have to put parentheses
right after it.
Right.
We did that here and we've been doing that throughout all of our template files.
So why don't we include parentheses after this name here?
Right.
If we want to call this function, why don't we add parentheses here?
Well, we don't add the parentheses because we don't want to literally call this function right now,
which means instead of you and I immediately calling the function right here and now, what we're doing
is just telling WordPress, hey, here's the name of the function, it's up to you WordPress to actually
run it at the precisely right moment.
OK, now let's move on to our final task of adding the black admin bar up at the top here.
So to begin, let's jump in to head HP.
And what I want to do is move the closing body in closing HTML tags out of this file and into footrot
HP.
If that doesn't make sense to you right now, that's OK.
Just follow along with me.
So delete the closing HTML and delete the closing body tag.
All right, let's save this and then jump in to maybe index P just for a frame of reference from a bird's
eye view.
How is our page getting created?
So first we include our header P, then we output the main content, meat and potatoes of the page,
and then we have footrot p so back to header.
We don't want to close out the body in HTML sandwiches within this file.
We want to do that at the very end of the HTML that gets generated.
So in footer P underneath our dummy text, let's close out the body tag and close out the HTML tag.
And now here's the important part right before the closing body tag.
I want you to drop into B and call a function named WP Underscore Footer.
If you've ever worked with JavaScript before, you know that a lot of times you don't want to load JavaScript
files up in the head section.
Instead you want to load them right before the closing body tag.
So this is just our way of giving WordPress the final say before we close out the body tag so WordPress
can use this for all sorts of things like loading JavaScript files or in this case, for adding the
black admin menubar up at the top of the page.
OK, so with this in place, if we save this file and refresh.
Awesome.
There's the admin bar, and that's actually going to bring this lesson to a close at this point in the
course, you might be thinking to yourself, hey, when is the website going to start looking like it
was built in the last decade?
Because right now, this plain white background and the text and the full width of it, it looks like
it was built in nineteen ninety five.
Well, in our very next lesson, we will address the visual or graphic design of our theme.
Let's keep our progress rolling and I will see you then.