Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we have two main goals.
Number one, we will create a new post type for professors.
And number two, we will learn how to associate an image with each professor post.
Without further ado, let's jump right in.
OK, so we want to create a new post type for professors.
So the first step is to jump into your text editor.
And instead of your theme folder, I want you to open up the menu or must use plugins folder.
You'll remember that we created this file named University Post typed up.
So this block of code creates the event post type.
And then down here, this block of code creates the program post type.
So if we want to create a professor post type, we can literally just copy and paste this and use it
as a template.
So copy from the beginning of this comment down to the ending semicolon.
But you'll notice that I'm still within the function closing curly bracket.
So let's go ahead and copy this and then drop down a few lines and paste it in and then let's just change
it out to be four professors instead of programs.
So let's update this comment, Professor post type.
And then anywhere else we see the keyword programmer programs throughout this code.
We also want to update that.
Now, if you're using sublime text or Adam as your text editor, I want to show you a trick.
So notice if I highlight the word program here and then if I press command or if you're on windows,
you would press control D it will select the next instance of the highlighted letters.
Now, the cool part is that our cursor is now in both locations.
And even though this word is singular program and this one is plural programs because we've only selected
the base of the word program, I can just simply begin typing Pro Vasseur and it gets updated in both
locations.
Cool.
And then we can also do the same thing down here where the word is capitalized.
So let's select just the base of the word leave off the S and then press command or control D several
times until all of them are selected and then we can just type in Professor Cool.
So that little tip can save you quite a bit of time in the long run.
Before we save this, let's be sure to give the professor post type a unique icon.
So let's change this from Dash ACoNs Awards to Dash ACoNs.
Welcome.
Learn more if you're wondering how I chose this value or if you want to choose a different icon yourself,
remember, you can always just Google for WordPress dash icons.
OK, and then one last detail.
When it comes to the professor post type, we will not need an archive.
For example, there's not going to be a link up in the header that says professors.
Instead, I want visitors of the website to find professors through the related programs that they teach
or through the campuses that they teach at or through the search functionality that we will set up later
in the course.
So back in our code, since we don't need an archive for the professor post type, we can just delete
this instead of setting this to false because false is the default, we can get rid of that line.
And if we don't need a professor archive, then we also don't need to customize or rewrite the archive
URL or slug so we can also delete this line.
And at this point we can go ahead and save our changes.
And now if we jump into the admin dashboard, we see this new item in the sidebar named Prof's.
Why don't we go ahead and create a few new professor posts right now?
So add new let's name the first professor.
Dr. Miaows A lot pastern, some dummy content, and let's go ahead and create another professor.
So add new.
And let's name this professor, Dr. Bachs, a lot based in some content.
And then let's use this permalink here to preview a professor post on the front end, but you'll notice
we see Page not found up in the TAB title bar.
And that's because we just created this brand new post type named Professor that our permalink structure
is not aware of yet.
So you know the drill back in our WordPress admin, lets hover over settings towards the bottom and
click on Permalink.
And all we need to do is click save changes down at the bottom to force WordPress to rebuild its permalink
structure.
And now if I go back to this professor, slash Dr. Bachs a lot, page and refresh, we can see that
we're in business now.
At the moment, this screen is using the single file as its template.
And we can see that that's designed for blog posts, but maybe not.
Professors write this information that I'm highlighting now.
It doesn't make sense for an individual Prof.
Page, so let's create a new template file just for professors.
So in our text editor, for now we can forget about this.
You must use plugins folder instead.
Let's switch over to our theme folder and in the theme folder, let's create a brand new file.
And the name of this file does matter.
We need to name it single dash Professor Dot BHP.
As always, I like to type just a bit of test content just to make sure that's the right template file
so we can see that that is indeed controlling an individual professor screen.
So instead of typing out a template from scratch, why don't we use our single dash event file as a
starting place?
So I'm going to open up a single event and just copy the entire thing into my clipboard and then back
in single professor, go ahead and paste that in.
Let's scroll up to the top.
Now, if I save this, we see Dr. Barks a lot and the content, but we also see this event home, Dr.
Bachs, a lot area.
And I don't think we need this metabolics at all when it comes to a professor profile screen like this.
So back in our code underneath the page banner, did we see a div with a class of container and write
inside that we see the div with a class of Mbox, so let's go ahead and delete the metabolics div entirely.
OK, and now before we learn how to add a featured image or associated image that represents Dr. Bachs
a lot, let's first work on establishing a relationship between a professor post and a program post.
Right.
So, for example, let's say that Dr. Barks a lot, teaches in the biology program.
So if I use this edit Professor Link here up in the top menubar, what I'm saying is that in addition
to the title and the main content field, we would also want a related programs field down here.
Now, you'll remember that we already set up a related programs field that we used on our events post
type.
So check this out.
If we click on custom fields here down towards the bottom of the sidebar here, we can see that related
program, field group.
Let's go ahead and click on that.
And we do not need to make any changes to the field itself.
Instead, what I want to draw your attention to is this location box.
So at the moment it reads show this field group only if the post type is equal to event.
Well, now we want to adjust things so that it also displays if you're editing a professor post now,
instead of clicking the and button to add an additional condition check, that also needs to be true.
Instead of that, we can use this or feature so we can say if this is true or add rule or if the post
type is equal to and then change this to professor.
OK, let's go ahead and save that change in the published box update.
And now if I go back into professors and try to edit, the doctor barks a lot post cool.
We see related programs and I can just go ahead and say that Dr. Barks a lot, teaches biology and then
update the post and then I can use the permalink to preview the front end for Dr. Barks a lot.
Cool.
Here we see related programs, biology.
If you're wondering why this already works, it's because we duplicated the single event template.
So back in our text editor and single professor, if we scroll down a little bit, remember, we wrote
this code when we were working on our single event file.
So first we get the field named related programs and then we loop through it down here.
However, since this is a professor profile page, maybe instead of saying related programs, why don't
we change this heading level to element to instead read subjects taught, maybe put the S in parentheses
in case the professor only teaches one subject, let's say subjects talked.
Cool, so that feels a bit more customized for a professor profile, and then if we click on this biology
link on this biology program page, we probably want to output any professors that teach biology right
about here.
Right.
We want the relationship between professor and programs to flow both directions.
So if we want to make that edit on this screen, we need to jump into our text editor and open a single
program.
Let's scroll down a bit here.
We can see the custom query we wrote that pulls in upcoming related events and really we can just recycle
this code.
So in terms of what I want to copy and paste in order to save a bunch of typing, let's place our cursor
at the beginning of this homepage.
Events, query object.
So click here and then I'm going to scroll all the way down past the custom query to the end of this
while loop.
So all the way down here where we have a closing bracket for the while loop and then a closing bracket
for the IF statement, I'm going to hold down the shift key on my keyboard and click right here, and
then I'm going to copy all of that into my clipboard.
And then because I want the related professors to be above the upcoming events, what I'm going to do
is scroll back up to the top.
And just right above this section, maybe out a few lines and then let's just paste in our clipboard.
OK, let's scroll back up and let's just start customizing this code, so let's rename the custom query
instead of homepage events.
Let's call it maybe related Prof's.
Let's change posts per page from two to negative one.
So that way we pull in all associated.
Prof's we definitely want to change the post type to professor.
We don't need a custom Medicare to order things by so we can delete that for order by.
Let's order the professors alphabetically by their name.
So let's change this from Meadowvale NUM to simply title.
We can leave orders to ascending and when it comes to the meta query, remember we have two filters
here going on that we used to pull in upcoming events.
So filter one, filter two.
In this case, when it comes to pulling in professors, we do not need this first filter that has to
do with the date being greater than or equal to today.
So let's go ahead and delete this first filter.
So just select from the beginning of the word array all the way to the comma right after it.
OK, so at this point, the custom query looks good, but remember, we renamed it to related Prof's,
so let's be sure to reference that query name down here in the code.
So within this if statement when we are saying only output this code, if the query is not empty, let's
be sure to update this name to related professors.
And then right within our while loop, let's update the query name here as well instead of home page
events related professors.
Woops, and I skipped right over this line within the parentheses of the wire loop.
Let's also update the query name.
They're related professors, OK?
And then when it comes to this wire loop, this controls what gets output, the HTML for each item.
We definitely do not want to output a div with the calendar circle date.
Right.
That makes sense for an event, but not for a professor.
So for the moment, let's go ahead and delete this entire div with a class of events summary.
So I'm going to begin here and select all the way down to there and instead let's just output a list
item with a link and the text that you click on will simply be the title, write the name of the professor
and then the ref should just be the permalink for a professor.
So the permalink.
OK, let's go ahead and save this and see what it looks like.
OK, so first of all, we should change this headline to read biology professors instead of upcoming
events.
There's Dr. Bachs a lot.
But the other thing we noticed is that the upcoming events just completely disappeared.
So first let's update this title and then I will explain why our events disappeared.
So here's the heading level two that reads upcoming blank events.
Let's remove the word upcoming.
So we have an H2 that will say biology or math or English.
And then instead of events, we'll just say professors.
OK, looks good now let's answer the question, why did our upcoming Buyology events completely disappear?
Well, actually, before we get into the explanation of why it disappeared, let me first show you how
to fix things.
So here's our related Prof's code.
Right?
And then down here, this is the custom query for upcoming events.
So in between those two things, right after our related Prof's code is finished, I want you to call
a WordPress function named WP Reset Post Data.
So let's go ahead and give that a save.
Cool.
And now our upcoming events is back in business.
So now the real question to keep things educational is what does this WP reset post data function do
and why does it magically fix things?
Well, it's a bit difficult to explain just with words.
So instead, I want you to follow along with this quick demo or this quick example.
So let's scroll up to the very top of this file and right above this get header line.
I want you to call a function named the IDE.
Right.
This is going to echo out the numerical ID onto the page for us.
So in my case, I see No.
Ninety seven, you'll probably see a different number.
But the point here is that that's the ID number for this program page.
Right.
In my case that's the ID for Buyology.
Next, let's try to show the ID number for this Dr. Bachs.
A lot post so in our code.
Let's scroll down a little bit.
Here's the custom query for Prof's.
Here's the list item where we are outputting the title for the professor.
So right after the title, let's say the IDE.
So we can see that Dr. Bachs, a lot has an idea of 104.
Now, again, your I.D. numbers will be different than mine.
But the point here is that once we perform our related professor's query and say the post that's going
to hijack the Global Post object and functions like the title and the permalink and the I.D., remember
when we called this the ID function up at the very top of the page, it returned a value of ninety seven
for the biology post.
But then down here that same exact function now returns a value that's tied to the doctor.
Barks a lot post.
Now the reason this broke are upcoming events section is because down here in the custom query for upcoming
events, we are relying on a function, get the I.D. and in order for this query to make sense and work
properly, you and I need to be able to depend on this function to return the ID of the actual page
that we're on.
Right.
We are on the biology page, so we want that function to return a value of ninety seven.
However, our while loop for the professors highjacked that get the ID function.
So now it's set to one hundred and four.
Hence why this query was broken.
So long story short, the WP reset post data.
This function resets the Global Post object and all of the data that functions like the title and the
ID return, it resets all of that back to the default U.
RL based query.
So the true long story short is whenever you're going to run multiple custom queries on a single page
99 times out of 100, you're going to want to run this reset post data function in between the two queries.
OK, now at this point, let me remove those example ID numbers.
And then also up at the very top, remove this, the EDEK.
OK, and that's actually going to bring this lesson to a close.
I know we got tied up on a bit of a tangent in terms of dealing with multiple queries and resetting
the post data.
But trust me, in our very next lesson, we're going to learn how to spice this up a bit.
So instead of just boring text with the professor's name, we will pull in a photograph of each professor
and we can display that here.
And then when you click on to the professor detail page, we can also display the photograph here and
we will learn how to manage different image sizes and aspect ratio cropping strategies.
It's going to be a lot of fun.
Let's keep it rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.