Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to learn how to create a block theme.
And more importantly, we're going to fully understand what exactly a block theme truly is.
I think hands on experience is way more valuable than listening to technical explanations.
So let's do this right now.
I want you to follow along with me.
Let's just go create a brand new theme folder.
So on your computer, navigate to wherever your local WordPress installation lives.
So basically you're looking for the directory that has folders such as WP content, WP admin.
So we would dig into WP content, dig into the themes folder.
And in this folder, let's just together right now create a brand new folder.
You can name it whatever you want, but just so you and I are on the same page, why don't we name the
new folder, maybe fictional dash block dash theme.
Okay, now go ahead and open this folder up with your text editor.
Okay.
Now, just like a traditional theme, we want to begin by having a certain file named.
So new file style dot C assets, right?
Some things never change.
And even if we don't want to include any access in this file, we just include a comment.
So slash asterisk.
And then we say theme name colon and then just make up a name.
Let's call it fictional university block theme, close out the comment.
So asterisk slash, that's all we need for now.
We can save this file.
And just like with a traditional theme, we need to have another file named index dot p p.
Now, interestingly enough, we don't need to do anything in this file.
We can leave it completely blank.
I believe in the future WordPress is even considering removing this requirement to even have this file
at all.
But as of today, we still need this file.
Okay.
Finally, let's create a folder within our theme folder.
So new folder and it needs to be named templates.
So this exact name templates.
In this new subfolder of templates, let's create a new file and name it.
Index source html.
Now, in this HTML file, just for a quick test, just say hello or hey.
Hi.
Just for a proof of concept.
Cool.
So we save that.
Now, back in WordPress, let's go activate this theme.
So in the admin dashboard under appearance.
From the theme selection screen.
There it is, a fictional university block theme.
Just click activate.
And if I refresh the front end, cool.
Now we just see the word hello.
So now that we've created this new empty theme with just the word hello, let's actually talk about
what in the world is supposed to be going on in this HTML file because the file ends in a dot HTML extension,
you might assume that you're allowed to have HTML on the file.
So maybe you want a, for example, a paragraph element.
So P tag and say hello there exclamation.
However, if save this, we just broke the theme.
Let me explain.
Technically, yes, that shows up here.
But it's not a valid block theme.
And the whole point of block beams in full site editing has just been destroyed by us, including top
level HTML like this.
Let me show you what I mean.
If you go into the admin and click on editor under the appearance menu.
So editor.
And you can see we're trying to edit the index template.
Well, this block has encountered an error and cannot be previewed.
So to get back to the question of what in the world is supposed to live in this file, you cannot include
each HTML directly like this.
Instead, everything within this file needs to be a block.
That way, this editing screen can treat it just like a regular WordPress poster page.
Right?
Everything is comprised of different blocks.
So if we wanted to include a paragraph, what would we have to do?
You would have to have an HTML comment like this WP colon paragraph.
Then you could have an HTML opening and closing and say hello there.
This is a paragraph.
And then below that closed the HTML comment.
So now it would be forward slash wp colon paragraph.
So if I give that to save the front end still works.
There it is.
Only now the editing screen will actually work.
So if I refresh this screen.
Perfect.
WordPress and the block editor can actually make sense of what was in our HTML template file so the
block editor can definitely handle us making changes to that existing paragraph.
So maybe we change it to just be hello.
And then if we press enter, this is the exact or at least 99.9%, the same interface you're used to
working with when creating posts and pages.
So maybe I want to add a heading level three so you can type forward slash and choose heading or if
you prefer to use this icon right about here or this icon up here, right.
However you like to use the block editor.
But let me just add a heading level three, so I'll change it to page three.
Welcome to our site.
Now that I've made a change to the template from within the editor instead of my text editor, let's
actually click save.
So and then click Save again.
Now if we look at the front end and refresh, we see those changes reflected right here.
However, it's not as if WordPress just automagically updated our text editor file so you can see indexed
are each HTML did not get updated with the heading level three here.
At this point, I think the easiest way to make sense of what's going on is to actually look at the
database that's powering our WordPress.
So if you're using the local BI flywheel software for your website, you can just click on to database
and then click open up add minor.
So Abner will look something like this.
Now let's just go look in our post table.
So WP underscore posts.
We don't want to look at the structure, we want to look at the actual data.
So select data and then just order them or go to the actual last or final page.
So I'll click on last scroll down to the very bottom.
So this is the most recent post that we created or edited, and if you click on edit just so we can
view the content here, notice the post underscore content field.
So this is where the actual body content for the post entity lives.
Well, there it is.
Let me zoom in a little bit, but there's the paragraph and below it there is the heading level three.
So this is the exact code that would live in your template file.
In other words, WordPress is storing the copy of it here because we as the end user or the client or
the non web developer person that's working with the web site, we made our changes within the web browser.
So WordPress is saving or storing the template that we edited into the database.
But now if we want to export this into our actual true template file, well, you have a couple of options.
Number one, you can just grab this value and just copy and paste it into your clipboard right out of
the database.
Or another option from the editor screen, you can click these three dots, click export right about
here.
That's going to download a zip.
And if you look inside that zip file, you'll see template files with the code that you created from
the editor.
In my case, I'm just going to grab the value right from the database and then I could place that into
my actual true HTML template file here.
So now if I save this, let me show you the whole point of having this in the actual file.
So if we save that and then go back into the editor and let's say we make a mistake, so we add a new
paragraph and it's just nonsense.
And we accidentally deleted all of the other content.
And then we click Save and we refreshed and we realize, Oh no, we don't like this.
We liked the starter version that was from our actual template file.
Well, that's the good news.
This actual file always serves as sort of a safe home base that you can revert back to.
So in the admin screen you can click on the top left icon going to templates.
Now you do sometimes need to manually refresh this screen.
So if I refresh.
Cool.
This blue icon here for the index template indicates that you've made customizations from within your
browser.
But if we click these three icons here, we can revert or clear those customizations, right?
In other words, it's going to use the actual HTML hard drive file so we can click clear customizations.
And now our website is back to just using the exact code from our file.
So you can see that there's some give and take.
There's interaction between the editor and our text editor, right?
We didn't have to manually type out this comment for a WordPress heading level three block.
We used the click and drag point and click.
What you see is what you get editor to create this, but then we just pasted it into our template file.
Now at this point, if you're anything like me, you're probably 101% disgusted at the thought of having
to use this approach for your entire theme.
Right?
You probably don't want to be limited and restricted to only using WordPress core blocks like this and
never getting to actually write your own custom HTML structure.
Right.
What if you don't want to write HTML the way that WordPress does?
What if you want to write your own HTML?
Well, don't worry.
We'll address that concern a bit later in the lesson.
I promise we will.
But for right now, I want to keep showing you how a block theme works at its most basic level.
So in our templates folder we just have the one file indexed on HTML.
Now, just like in a traditional theme that would have indexed AP that serves as sort of the universal
fallback file.
However, if you wanted to control what an individual single blogpost URL looks like, well, in a traditional
theme you would have a file named single dot AP, right?
Or if you wanted to control what a page instead of a post looked like, you'd have a file named page
dot.
AP Well, the good news is, is that from what I've seen, at least 99% of the time that exact same
naming system carries over into block themes.
In other words, you just include those same named files in your templates folder.
So if we wanted to control what an individual blog post screen looks like in our templates folder,
we would just create a file named single, but instead of it's single dot html.
So in this file, imagine we just want to copy over a paragraph and we'll say this is a single blogpost
template screen.
Let's give that a save and test it out.
So if we refresh the homepage, we still see that template.
However, we go into our dashboard and maybe just go find a blog post to get the URL right.
So just on any of your posts, click the view link when you hover over one.
Perfect.
This is the URL for a single post and there we see it.
This is a single blog post template screen.
And now all of your knowledge of a traditional theme carries over, right?
So you would have files in this templates folder called archive.org.
HTML page dot html.
And it also works with custom post types.
Right?
So just like you would have a single dash and then the name of your custom post type.
Well, that exact same naming system works here in the templates folder.
So the good news is a lot of your knowledge gets recycled here.
It's not as if we're starting from scratch.
Okay.
Now, before we go any further, and especially now that we've looked at the single blog post screen,
we really need to ask ourselves, well, what if we don't want just hard coded static template code?
What if we want code or content that's actually dynamic for this specific blog post, right?
How do you actually load the title of this blog post in the body content for this blog post?
Right.
How do you do anything dynamic without PHP?
If we can only use each HTML comments and blocks.
Let's give ourselves a super specific and concrete goal right now.
So let's imagine we want to add the title of the current single blog post your viewing right here.
Now we could spell out the block manually, but I think it's way more intuitive to use the WordPress
full site editor screen.
So back in our dashboard, look under the appearance menu and click on editor.
By default, it's going to take you to your home page template.
We're not interested in that.
So you can click the top left click templates and we want to edit the single blogpost template.
So let's click on that.
We don't actually need this paragraph block so you can get rid of that if you want with it empty.
I just like to type a forward slash because you can begin typing the block type you're interested in.
But I'm interested in something called post title.
So there you can see it available post title, click that.
Maybe right below that.
I want post content, so I'll just click that.
So title content if I save this and then refresh the front end.
Well, as you might have guessed, there is the specific title for this blog and here is the actual
content.
Now that was simple enough because we're viewing the URL from one single individual blog post.
But what if, for example, on our homepage URL, we want it to show the five most recent blog posts
or the ten most recent blog posts?
Well, let's try it out.
So back on this screen.
If we go to our templates list just for a quick test, we can edit our index, you know, sort of our
homepage template.
And imagine we wanted to display the five most recent blog posts right here and we wanted their title,
then their date and then maybe an excerpt.
So we can just add a new block here called query loop to the Query Loop block.
I like to choose this start blank option and maybe just choose title an excerpt.
Now, in order to make sense of what's going on here, I think it's almost mandatory to click this icon
right here.
So that gives you a bird's eye view and it makes nested blocks actually possible to understand and visualize.
So we've got the query loop and then inside the query loop there's nested the post template pagination.
I don't want pagination.
So I'll just click on that and click backspace or delete.
So I've just got my post template that lives inside a query loop.
Anything that lives inside of post template will be duplicated for however many posts we want to display.
So if we wanted to display five, let's click on the overall query loop block and then we can click
on this icon display settings and items per page.
Just bump it up to five.
Okay.
Inside the post template, what if we wanted the date for the blog post to sit in between the title
and the excerpt?
So I just click on the title, click insert after and for the block type right here, I would just say
post date click that we can click save.
We refresh the front end.
Now you might be thinking to yourself, Whoa, are we never going to use ever again?
Does this mean that we can just use block types like this for all of our dynamic needs?
No, the answer is no, no, no.
We're still absolutely going to use up the query loop.
BLOCK is incredibly basic.
You cannot build custom powerful queries with it.
So if you click on the query loop and then click on the settings icon in this right hand sidebar, you
can see if you scroll down, you can choose which post type you're querying for.
So that's pretty cool.
You could choose, you know, whatever custom post type you want.
You can choose if you're ordering by the newest or oldest, but that's really it.
I mean, you can filter by category, but that.
Is it?
So there'd be no way to filter for relationships or meta values.
Or if you think back to our actual fictional university website, remember, for example, this upcoming
events area?
Remember we wrote a custom query that looks at today's date and then only shows events where not the
post date but the event date, which is a meta value where it is greater than today's date write upcoming
events.
So my point is, you would still need to absolutely write your own custom API to perform truly custom
queries.
And there's nothing wrong with that.
It's not like PHP is now against the law in WordPress.
And it's not as if avoiding PHP and using blocks for everything magically makes your site more modern
or faster.
Because even if you do use blocks for everything, WordPress is still 100% going to use PHP.
Let me show you an example.
So let's think about that post title block.
If you dig in to your WordPress installation instead of going into WP content, if you go into WP includes
and then go into the blocks folder.
This has a lot of the core default built in WordPress blocks.
And if you scroll down, you'll see a file named post titled Dot PHP.
If you open that up in your text editor and go down to about line 23, you'll see the good old AP function,
get the title, and then below that it's going to perform its own logic.
Like, Do you want to wrap it in a link?
Do you want it to be a heading level one?
Heading level two?
So it's controlling the HTML.
It's actually calling the B function.
There is no magic going on here.
So remember earlier in the lesson when I promised I'd address how we as web developers can actually
control the HTML of our theme?
Well, you're looking at the answer right here.
We are going to create our own custom block types ourselves instead of only relying on WordPress default
core blocks.
That way we can still write our own custom queries and we can control the HTML output if we want to.
Now you might be thinking to yourself, but Brad, how does the new default 2022 theme?
How does it work with basically zero PHP?
In my answer to that is quite simple.
So you can go ahead and open up the 2022 theme and vs code and look through the templates.
And the reason it's able to get by with basically zero custom PHP is because it's not doing anything
custom.
For example, if you dig into single HTML, it's literally just using WordPress core blocks.
At no point does it have any need for custom queries, custom relationships, custom HTML output.
So yes, if the website you're trying to build fits with that.
Sure.
Maybe this approach is great and you can start to use WordPress as a design tool instead of a content
management system.
But that is not the approach we've ever taken in this course.
So where do we go from here?
Well, in our very next lesson, we're going to continue to discuss this 2022 theme a bit.
And more importantly, we'll actually start to begin real work on our block theme together.
Anyways, let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.