Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will finally learn how to load WordPress content with JavaScript into our page in
real time.
So, for example, if a visitor opens up the search overlay and searches for Buyology.
Down here in this results area, we want to load in any posts or pages or programs or professors that
have to do with biology.
Now, believe it or not, the first step in learning how to do this has nothing to do with JavaScript
in particular.
Let me show you what I mean.
So right now for our first step, here's what I want you to do up in the address bar at the very end
of the root of our WordPress, you órale add on a slash WP dash.
Jason, Jason.
So just like you would normally say, WP dash admin to go to the dashboard, instead of that we're saying
WP Dash, JSON slash, WP slash, V2 slash posts and then let's press enter.
Whoa.
So the question is, what in the world are we looking at right here?
Now this might look like pure and utter chaos, but believe me when I say that by learning and understanding
what we are seeing here, we are going to be able to jump up to the next level in our WordPress developer
careers.
So what we are looking at right now is completely raw data for the 10 most recent blog posts on our
website.
And if we go up to the address bar and at the very end of the euro, if we change this from posts to
pages and then press enter, well, we are now looking at completely raw data for the 10 most recent
pages.
But what does that really mean?
Well, this text that describes the ten most recent pages is structured in a very particular way.
It's structured using the JSON format.
Hence why this Eurail begins with WP.
Jason Jason is an acronym that stands for JavaScript Object Notation, which is just a super popular
format for structuring data.
Now, this code is not JavaScript in the sense that it's not going to actually do anything or execute
any actions.
It's only JavaScript in the sense that it's describing an array of objects.
Now, if we look at all of this at once, it looks like pure chaos.
But if we break it down bit by bit, it's actually super simple.
Notice that the first character is an opening square bracket.
A square bracket is how you create an array.
And remember that an array is just a collection of multiple values separated by commas.
So in this case, it's an array of objects where each object is a WordPress page.
So the square brackets starts the array and then this curly bracket is how you begin an object in JavaScript.
So, for example, maybe this first chunk of code is the about US page and then this next chunk of code
is the privacy policy page.
In order for this to make more sense, I'm actually going to jump in to my text editor and you do not
need to type out what I'm about to type out.
This is just a quick demo or explanation.
So we look at this huge chunk of code and it looks super intimidating.
But really all that WordPress is doing is it's giving us an array.
So square brackets and an array can contain multiple values separated by commas.
Right.
Something like this.
Except instead of simple values for each item, it's an array of objects.
Now, in JavaScript, an object is just a pair of curly brackets like this.
So really it's just an array separated by commas of objects.
Now let me space this out onto different lines so it can really start to make sense.
So let me place each object on its own line, and if each one of these objects is a WordPress post or
page, we could imagine that maybe in this first object it would have a properly named I.D..
Right, because every post in WordPress has a numerical I.D. and then in JavaScript within an object,
you can just add a comma to add another property and every poster page and WordPress probably has a
title.
So maybe this is the about us page and every post has a date.
Right.
So then this would have a date of some sort.
So this first object is the about us page and then maybe the second object has an I.D. of four and the
title of privacy policy and it has a different date.
Right.
You get the idea, the big picture.
The big point is that this is nothing more than an array of objects and each object is a post or page.
Now, if you're anything like me or just if you're a human being instead of a robot, this way of spacing
out the data is a lot easier to read than this, where everything is just completely smooshed together.
And if we're going to try to work with this WordPress data, it would be nice if we could view it in
a way that actually made a little bit of sense.
Well, luckily, there's this super popular and free tool named Postman.
It doesn't cost a penny, so I encourage you to go download it right now.
Go ahead and pause this lesson.
As of this moment, the official Eurail is get postman dot com.
That domain could change in the future.
But if you just Google for Postman program, this should show up as the number one result.
Again, it doesn't cost even a penny, so go ahead and download it.
Although I guess before you paused this lesson and download it, you might want to first see what it
is and what it does.
So if I go back to my WordPress JSON tab up in the address bar, let me actually go back to the Post's
URL instead of the pages you are now, OK?
So all of this data is smooshed together and it's super hard to look at and understand at all.
But what I can do up in the address bar is select this URL and copy it into my clipboard.
And then I already have the Postman app installed on my computer.
So if I jump into Postman, here's that app.
In this main text field here, I can just paste in my clipboard.
Make sure that it's set to a get request, which it should be by default, and then you can either just
press enter on your keyboard or hit the big blue send button.
Cool, so now instead of the Jason being all smooshed together and impossible to read, the Postman
app separates it out one property per line and the human eye can actually start to see what's going
on.
So the first post has an idea of sixty five.
It's got a slug of we won an award.
Here's the link or permalink.
Here's the title.
Here's the content.
You get the idea.
Now I want to say that you do not need to use Postman.
It's just a nice optional tool to help you visualize the data that we're working with.
OK, now at this point, the question becomes, how does this JSON data and these URLs that WordPress
provides to us, how does this help us with our live search results?
Right.
If someone opens the overlay and searches for biology, how can we leverage these WordPress, Jason,
you URLs to give us what we want?
Well, check this out.
At the end of this URL, we can add on extra info to tell WordPress what we are looking for.
So by default, this is going to give us the ten most recent posts.
But if I only want the two most recent posts at the very end of the euro, I can add on a question mark
and say per underscore page equals two.
And now there's only JSON for two posts where I could set it to one.
Or if I was looking for a specific post and I knew the numerical ID number of the post, I could go
to this URL, so WP, JSON, WP, V, two posts and then add a slash and then just include the IDE.
So maybe seven for example, and that will give me that one specific post.
OK, so the idea is that there's things we can add to the end of this URL to customize what WordPress
sends back to us.
Now back to the task at hand.
We want to power a search.
So what we are really interested in is this.
Check this out.
Let's get rid of the number and the slash, OK?
And right after posts, let's just add questionmark search equals and then any word or phrase that you
want to search for.
So I know that I have a blog post named We want an award.
So if I search for a ward, it returns the blog post.
And here we can see the title is We Won an award.
Right now might actually be a good time to go create a few new test sample posts just so we have something
to search for.
So in my admin dashboard, I'm going to create a new blog post.
Maybe I will title this one, biology is cool paste in some dummy text, go ahead and save that, OK?
And then back in our JSON tab, if we just change the URL to search equals and then instead of a board
search for biology and this is the JSON for that post that we just created here we can see the title
is Biology is Cool.
Now at this point, the gears in our head are really starting to spin because this search parameter
will work perfectly with the live search results that we want to build.
However, you might be thinking to yourself, what good does it do us to visit this RL in a browser
like this?
Right.
The visitors of our website won't know to do this, and even if they did, they wouldn't know what to
do with this data.
Well, that's a fair point.
But what if I told you that we can use JavaScript to programmatically send a request to this U.
RL in the background in real time, and then we can use this data however we see fit in our code.
So right now, let me show you how that works and how we can get started.
So let's begin by jumping into our text editor and within our JavaScript modules folder.
Let's jump in to search J.S. and let's scroll down to our Get Results method.
Remember, this is the method that will run after the 2000 millisecond gap in between keystrokes.
As of this moment, all this method is doing is updating the results div to say imagine real search
results here.
Now, this is not what we actually want to do, right?
This was just a placeholder.
So why don't we go ahead and delete that line of code and within the git results meant that let's also
delete this line that updates that is Spiner visible property.
OK, so at this point our get results method is completely empty and at this point the question becomes
how can we use JavaScript to send out a request to a user?
All right.
We want to visit this JSON based WordPress you URL.
Well, check this out, Jake.
Query makes this very, very easy.
So in our method, let's just say dollar sign to begin using query and then period to look inside the
query, object and query has a method named get JSON.
Now within the parentheses, this method takes two arguments.
The first argument is the you are that you want to send a request to.
And the second argument is a function where you can say what you want to do.
After that, you are our response.
In our example, this JSON based Uttara responds by sending back all of this data.
So let me show you what we can do.
Let's just fill in these two arguments.
So the euro is simple enough.
Let's just go back to our browser and let's just copy this full you URL that returns this JSON.
Let's copy the euro into our clipboard.
And then for this first euro argument, let's get rid of that placeholder and add in quotations and
then just paste in our clipboard for the moment.
We can go ahead and leave this hardcoded to search equals Buyology.
We will learn how to actually search for what the user types in a bit later on.
For now, let's focus on the function that we want to run after this.
RL responds with the JSON data, so instead of this placeholder X, you could type in the name of a
method or function that you want to run.
Or we could just create an anonymous function in line right here.
And that's actually what I'm going to do.
So let's get rid of the X and say function parentheses, curly brackets and then just to stay organized
in between the curly brackets.
Why don't we drop down to a new line?
And now within the body of this function here, we want to be able to access all of the JSON data that
this U.
RL responds with.
Now, luckily, when this JSON method fires, the callback function is going to pass whatever data this
URL responds with into the function.
So within the parentheses for this function, we just want to be sure to include a parameter so that
we're basically giving that data a name so we can reference it later on.
Now, the name here does not matter.
We can make up whatever parameter name we want, so we could call it data or results or I'm actually
going to call it posts.
All right.
And now within the body of this function, we can use that name posts to access all of this JSON data.
So just as a test, let's give ourselves a goal.
Let's try to create an annoying alert pop up message just as a test.
But let's try to display the title of the WordPress post that this Jasen code is describing.
So remember the.
This is really just an array now in this case, there's only one object in the array.
There's only that one blog post named Buyology is cool, but it's still an array nonetheless.
So we can work with this just like any other array in JavaScript.
So we gave it a name of posts and then to look inside an array, remember, it's square brackets.
In this case, there's only one item in the array.
So we want to access the first item.
Arrays are zero based.
So if we want to access the first item instead of a one, we use a zero.
OK, and then let's look inside that object for the title.
Now, in situations like this where I need to find out the name of a property, instead of looking at
this squished together, pure chaos, this is where I feel like the Postman app is really valuable.
So I'm just going to copy this Eurail into my clipboard and then in the Postman app that we paste in
that you URL and send out a request.
So this way I can see the JSON spaced out in a way that makes sense.
So I can see that this object has a property named title and that is really just an object itself that
contains a property named rendered.
So back in our code, we want to look inside that object for a property named title and then we want
to look inside that for a property named rendered.
OK, at this point, let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So back in our actual website tab, if I open up the search overlay and search for anything.
Perfect, we see this annoying alert pop up message biology is cool, which is the name of that WordPress
post.
OK, now let's take things one step further and actually make the search dynamic.
What I mean by that is instead of hard coding this search parameter to always be biology, let's actually
search for whatever the user types in here in the text field.
So back in our code at the end of that, you URL that we are sending a request to let's delete the hardcoded
biology so it ends in search equals and then the quote ends and then right after the quote, we can
just add on whatever the visitor has typed in into the search field.
So we know that we have a property named this dot search field and we can access whatever the visitor
has typed into it by running the vowel method.
So that way are you URL is search equals whatever the user types in.
Cool.
So let's save this and give it a test.
So if I search for a word.
Perfect, we see a blog post with a title of we won an award, but if I actually do search for biology,
then the search results are different and we see biology as cool.
Now, take a moment to give yourself a pat on the back because you just created your first real time
JavaScript application.
Now, obviously, we don't actually want to create these annoying pop ups.
Right.
Instead, we want to display results down here in the results div area.
And that's exactly what we're going to learn how to do.
In the next lesson, we will learn how to generate beautifully formatted HTML based on incoming JSON
data.
It's going to be a lot of fun.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you then.