Hello, everyone.
In this video, we are going to pick up right where we left off in the previous one, so up in my address
bar, if I visit slash search and if a visitor types in a search phrase and then click on the submit
button, that takes them to this screen with all of the search results.
However, at the moment, this search results screen is being powered by index dot p p and that explains
why the headline reads Welcome to our blog and all of the content looks like a blog post, even if it
is a professor or program or event post type.
Now, luckily, if your theme folder contains a file named Search Dot p, WordPress will use that to
power this result screen instead of index.
So let's make our first goal for this lesson to customize this headline text.
OK, so the first step to making this happen is to jump over to our text editor and within our theme
folder, let's create a brand new file and let's name it Search dot p p.
Now, in order to save a ton of typing, why don't we copy and paste over everything from index dot
BHP and then just modify what we need to.
So I'm going to hop in index, copy everything into my clipboard and then back in search, paste it
in.
Let's scroll up to the top.
So the first thing I'm going to change is the page banner title instead of welcome to our blog.
Let's just say search results.
OK, and then for the subtitle, let's say this pair of quotes and say you searched for and then I'm
going to wrap their search phrase in double quotes.
So the HTML code for left angled double quotes is ampersand l d q you Yuto semicolon and then I'm just
going to place X as a placeholder, but the actual search phrase will go there in just a moment, but
then right after it, let's add a right angled pair of double quotes.
So ampersand r d q you o semicolon.
OK, and if I save that and refresh the biology search query u rl cool.
So there's our updated header text and now instead of the placeholder X, let's work on outputting the
actual phrase that a user searched for.
So back in our code where the placeholder X is, I don't want to write simple string text.
I want to run a P expression or a function.
So what I'm going to do is write before the X.
We can add in a quote to close out this string of text and then right after that we can add a period
to add on something new.
And then right after the acts we could add on a period and then add an opening quote for the final part
of the string.
That is the double right angled quote.
OK, so now instead of the X, what we want to do is call a WordPress function named get search query.
And if we go ahead and save that and refresh, cool.
We see you searched for biology and if we go up into the address bar and change it to a search for math,
obviously we see that that gets updated.
Cool.
But before we move on and address formatting for the actual result posts, I first want to touch on
a bit of security when it comes to outputting something that is user input.
Let me give you a quick example of why security in this context is so important.
What if someone malicious went up to the address bar and said that they wanted to search for opening
script tag, closing script tag and then in the middle, maybe they tried to run a bit of JavaScript,
so maybe an annoying alert pop up that says, hey, well, luckily by default, WordPress has got us
covered.
We see that that string of text was not executed as JavaScript and instead it just gets output as plain
text here.
This is because the git search query function by default provides a bit of escaping, right.
It escapes code into simple text instead of HTML or JavaScript that can be executed.
If we want to.
We can override that default behavior by going inside the parentheses and saying false.
So if I save that and still leave this malicious code up in the address, bar and refresh, we see that
luckily Google Chrome is smart enough and safe enough to go on not to.
I'm not even going to let you load the page because something very fishy is going on.
Someone probably sent this address to you in an e-mail or spam message hoping that you would see that
the beginning of the Eurail looks safe and then you would just blindly click on the you are not noticing
that the end of it contains malicious JavaScript.
This is probably the most popular and basic example of a cross site scripting attack.
Now, you might be thinking to yourself, big deal, Brad, that's not important, right?
Because it's as simple as just not specifying false here.
Well, that's true.
WordPress does provide security against this by default.
So here's the reason I went into this whole security topic in the first place.
This function works perfectly in the following instance.
So just as an example, I'm going to delete this code in about ten seconds from now, but maybe right
above this container did if I had an input field type of text and I wanted to give it a default value
of whatever the user had searched for.
Well, within the quotes, I'm perfectly safe to just echo out the results of git search query.
So if I save that and refresh, here's that example.
Input field and WordPress escaped it and converted the text into a safe string.
So long story short, if you just want to use the value that someone typed in as a value for an HTML
attribute, you can use this function on its own just like this without any problem, however.
And let me delete this sample input here.
However, if you just want to output it within a string of HTML, maybe within a headline or a paragraph,
the way that WordPress recommends we do that is we call a scale each HTML and then place get search
query within that so that it gets escaped as HTML instead of as a value for an HTML attribute.
And then since this function is taken care of, escaping or converting the text within the inner parentheses
for this function, we can just say false.
Don't worry about escaping it because this function is going to take care of that.
OK, now moving on.
If we save that and refresh perfect.
So we've got this malicious code up here and it is not being executed.
So we are safe.
So now we can go back to pretending that someone is performing a normal search like biology.
And our next goal is to control how the resulting posts are getting formatted.
So back in our code within Search P, here is the beginning of our while loop.
Then we are calling the post and then this div named post item is going to be generated once for each
result.
So basically what we want to do is output different HTML depending on the current post time.
Now there are a lot of different ways we could do this.
The first and most obvious way would just be to write an if statement.
So say if parentheses curly bracket and say if I get a post type equals professor only if that's the
case then do something.
So for example, we could echo an output, maybe a heading level one that says I am a professor.
OK, so if I save that cool.
So there we see it and that's only displaying for the doctor.
Barks a lot post because it's the only result that is a professor.
Right.
So the if statement only evaluates to true in this case.
So we could just set up a bunch of these if blocks and say if post type is post, if post type is program
or event or campus, and that would work just fine.
But it's not the cleanest, most concise way of coding things.
So instead, let me delete that and let me show you what I propose.
So right after this, the post line, let's say this, let's say git template part.
You might remember this WordPress function from many lessons ago.
So for the first argument, you point towards another file that you want to pull in and use.
And many lessons ago we created a sub folder named Template Parts, and inside it we have one file named
Content Dash event.
So let me show you how I'm going to handle things.
For the first argument, I will say go inside the template parts folder and then look for a file that
begins with the word content only.
I'm not going to spell it out and say slash event because I don't want to hardcoded to the event post
instead.
For our second argument within these parentheses, so comma and now if I said events or professor WordPress
would try to find a file in that folder named Content Dasch Professor.
So all we need to do to make this dynamic is instead of a string here with quotes for the second argument,
just say get posted.
So now, depending on each result, WordPress will know where to look as an example for this first result.
Since it's a blog post, WordPress would try to pull in a template file named Content Dasch Post.
So let me show you what I'm going to do.
This code down here, this div with a class of post diatom.
That's basically the template for a generic post, a blog post.
So what I'm going to do is copy this entire div, copy that into my clipboard or actually cut it into
my clipboard and then within our subfolder of template parts, let's create a brand new file and paste
that in.
And then the naming of this file is important.
Let's name it content dash post.
OK, and then let's create another file for the Professor Post.
So within the template parts folder, just create another new file.
Let's save it and name it content dash Professor P.
And the question is what should the HTML code be for, Professor?
Well, there's no sense in reinventing the wheel.
So on the front end in a new tab if we visit the programs page and then Buyology, this is the formatting
that we can use for Professor Post type.
So if I want to find the P in HTML that creates this format, I can just look within single dash program.
So in my text editor single program and then if we scroll down a bit, here's the custom query to pull
in related professors.
And right below that, here's another while loop and here is a list item that will generate that professor
card.
So I can just copy and paste this list item.
Copy that.
And then back in our brand new content dash professor file.
Just paste that in.
OK, next, let's create a new file for the program post type.
So within the template parts, let's just create a new file, let's name it content dash program dot
p p and for program I'm thinking we can pretty much just copy but adjust and modify the blog post formatting
a bit.
So to save typing if we go back into content post, let's copy that, paste it into content program
and we can just get rid of the metabolics, we can keep the excerpt and maybe instead of continue reading
we could say Vue program.
OK, so if I save that and then be sure to save my overall search file and then on the front end, if
I refresh the search results for Buyology, this is using content dash post.
This is using content dash program.
We can see the button has different text and this is using content.
Dash Professor.
Now I'm noticing there's not much of a vertical gap between these two and we also don't see a nice,
subtle border like we do between these two.
And this has nothing to do with WordPress.
It's just the CFS detail.
But to fix that, I'm just going to go into content dash professor and maybe wrap this entire list item
within an outer div that has a class of post item that maybe indent this and then down at the bottom
closing div cool.
That looks a lot better.
So that takes care of four of our six post types.
Why don't we go ahead and create a file for pages and four campuses, so create a new file.
Let's name this one content dash page dot p and let's use content post as our example.
So copy everything from content post pasted in content page except pages probably don't need the metabolics
so we can get rid of the metabolics div save that.
OK, and finally, let's create a file for campuses.
So within our template parts folder, new file paste in our clipboard.
Campuses don't need a metabolics, so let's delete that and for The View more button instead of continue
reading let's say View Campus.
OK, and then let's save this file and name it content dash campus.
Cool.
So now if we perform a search for maybe math instead of biology.
Here's the math program, we can see the button reads view program and cool, the event is styled as
an event.
Now, at this point, we are almost complete with our traditional search.
There are just two more things I want to cover.
So first, what happens if someone searches for something obscure and there are zero results?
OK, and then once we address that, the other thing I want to do is down at the very bottom of a search
results screen.
So maybe down here, I think it would be nice to include a search form so you could perform a follow
up search if you wanted to.
So back in our code, let's jump in to our search file.
And if a search has zero results, we just want to output a message that says no results match that
search.
And we can make this happen with a simple if statement.
So let's do this in search right before this wild blue line.
Let's add an if statement for the condition we can just say have posts.
So only if the search query has posts do we want to do something which we will do here.
And then right after the closing curly bracket, we can say else otherwise do this.
So if the search does have results, then we just want to run our while loop.
So I'm just going to move the while loop as well as the pageant links.
Just going to cut that into the curly brackets for if this condition is true.
So instead of x paste that in and since we are no longer mingling HTML with PHP, we don't need to exit
out of here, which means we don't need to reopen here.
OK, and then for the else, we can just echo out a maybe a heading level two that reads no results
match that search.
And just for styling, let's give the edge to a class of headline and headline, dash, dash, small
dash plus.
All right.
So if I save that and refreshed the math results screen, we still see our results.
But if I search for something super obscure, perfect, no results match that search.
OK, and then the last thing I want to do is add in the search form to perform a new search down here.
And I want it to display whether there are results or not.
So back in search, right after this block of PHP, instead of typing out a bunch of HTML to create
a form, we can just copy and paste the form that we wrote in our previous lesson.
So if I jump into Page Dasch, search and scroll to the bottom, let's just copy this form element.
And then back in search, you could technically just paste that in here, but that would be duplicating
your code, which I'm not a fan of.
Instead, let me show you what we can do within the root of our theme folder.
If we create a brand new file and paste in our clipboard there and then name this file.
And the name is super important.
Search form, no spaces, all lowercase.
OK, now back in search of WordPress has a special function designed to look for that exact file name
of search form.
So maybe right below the curly brackets for the elves we can just say get search for.
So if I save that and refresh the search results, perfect.
So now I could search for biology and we're in business.
And just to reduce duplicate code, let's be sure to go back into page dash search where we just copied
the form from and let's delete the HTML for the form and in its place used to say get search form.
Cool.
So then the code only needs to live in that one location and that's going to bring this lesson to a
close.
You might have noticed that this traditional search doesn't pull in results based on relationships like
our overlay search does.
Now, we are not going to take the time to modify this traditional search because I feel like that would
be ultra repetitive and way too similar to what we just did in the last chapter where we searched by
relationship for our overlay search.
But don't worry if you are indeed curious about how to set up custom search logic using traditional
non JavaScript searches that rely on you URL queries, you'll be happy to know that at the very end
of the course, in an extra credit section, I point you in the right direction to make that happen.
But let's not get ahead of ourselves.
We will cross that bridge as we come to it.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.