Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to learn about Jason X. Let's begin by making sure that we understand the
problem that Jason X solves.
So in our previous lesson, we wrote this bit of JavaScript to create a heading level three with this
as its content.
Now, when you just need to create one single element, this code isn't too bad to type out.
But in the real world, in HTML, we often need all sorts of container and wrapper divs and then you're
going to have five or 10 different children, elements that might have nested contents of their own.
In other words, spelling out a real world HTML structure with this type of code is not enjoyable.
I'm about to paste in a bit of example code and you do not need to type this out.
It's going to be an example of what we do not want to have to type out.
I just want to show you we place this in that the create element function can indeed create complex
nested HTML structures.
It's just not enjoyable for you and I to have to manually type out.
So remember, create element takes three arguments, the type of element you want to create any properties
or attributes describing that element.
And then the third argument is the content for that element.
So in this example that I just paste it in, I have a div and then for its content, it's actually just
an array of other elements.
So I have a div with an H1 in an age for you can see the H four instead of null for the second argument,
I give it a style object and I set the colour.
So if I save this and reload.
Cool, you can see that there's a rapper, you can't see the rapper, too, but there's Divx with two
pieces of content inside it.
The color is working perfect.
Only no one wants to have to spell out HTML like this.
It's not enjoyable.
It's slow, inefficient, it's not intuitive.
So if we can avoid this, we definitely want to.
And this is where James X comes into play.
Now again, what I'm about to paste in, you do not need to type this out.
This is just a quick demo.
But what if instead of all of this, we could express this same HTML structure with just this?
This looks almost identical to HTML.
There are subtle differences, but this is very intuitive and easy for you and I to type out.
So this is just X and it's going to make our lives so much easier.
However, we can't just feed the Web browser just directly like this.
If I save this, we're going to run into all sorts of errors and problems, right?
If I reload.
WordPress has no idea what's going on.
We see this error message, and this is because Jason X in this syntax right here, this doesn't make
sense to the Web browser, right?
The Web browser speaks JavaScript.
It does not speak JSH.
So what we need is a tool in the middle that will take our source code and then convert it.
Let me command Z that will convert our JSA into this.
And this is what will actually get fed to the Web browser.
Right.
So essentially you and I will get to write source code that looks like this.
It can live in a folder named Source and then the automatic tool that converts this code myself.
I put it back to this.
This version of the file can live in a different folder called Build, and that's what we'll tell WordPress
to actually load.
So right now, let me put my edit function back to the exact same way that yours is from our previous
lesson.
OK, and now let's start to learn how we can use JSC.
So first we need to make sure that our computer has something called Node JS installed on it.
Now, if you've watched the entirety of this course, odds are you already have node installed on your
computer.
But if you've skipped ahead to this plug in development chapter or if you're watching this course years
later and you're on a new computer, maybe you don't have node installed.
Let me show you how you can check to see if you have node installed.
So inverse code on windows, you can press control and J on your keyboard at the same time on Mac,
you can press command and J.
Either way, that's going to open up your terminal or command line down here towards the bottom.
Now I want you to run this command with me to see if you have node installed.
It's just node and then a space dash dash.
So two dashes version hit enter.
If you see any sort of version number here, cool.
You already have node installed.
If instead you see unknown command or command not found, you just need to go download and install node
so you can pause the video less and go to the official node website node JÖRG.
If you just Google for node, this should be one of the first results and then you can download either
the long term support version or the current version.
You can't go wrong either way.
So pause the video while you're download completes, you should be able to just double click the downloaded
file and then all of the default options are OK.
So you can just click next, next, next.
Once it finishes, you might need to restart your text editor or even your computer as a whole, but
you'll know that everything was installed correctly if you try this command once again, node, dash,
dash version and you see a version.
No, again, remember to toggle your command line in VSG code, its control J on Windows and command
John Mac or instead of a keyboard shortcut.
If you look in the V code view menu up at the top, you'll see an option called terminal that will do
the same thing.
So go install no JS if you need to.
But at this point in the video moving forward, I'm going to assume that everyone has node installed.
Now that we have node, we can go ahead and set up the tool in the middle that will convert our JSC
X into code that looks like this in the past.
Setting up an automated tool like that might have been a bit complicated.
But luckily for us, there is an official WordPress JavaScript package, so it's just the at symbol
WordPress slash scripts.
So how do we download and use this?
Well, when we installed node on our computer, we also installed something called NPM short for node
package manager.
Now, before we use NPM to download that WordPress scripts package, let's first sort of create a grocery
list in our folder that will keep track of any JavaScript dependencies.
We need to do that.
I want you to run the following command with me.
So it's NPM space init space and then dash.
Why press enter.
OK, so that will create a package JSON file that keeps track of everything we're going to install with
NPM.
Really though, we only need to install one package right now.
Right.
We want the at WordPress scripts package.
So type this command in with me now npm install and then the name of the package was at Simbel WordPress
Forward Slash Scripts and in 2021 this isn't 100 percent necessary.
But if you want to.
You can say dash, dash, save, dash, dev to market as a dev dependency, go ahead and press enter
and now depending on the speed of your Internet connection, this will take a minute or two.
The official WordPress JavaScript package makes use of lots and lots of other smaller packages.
So be patient.
This will take a minute.
Once it completes, the question becomes, how do we use it?
Well, the nice thing about this package is that it requires almost zero configuration.
In other words, it has a certain folder and file structure that it's going to look for.
So in our plug in folder, I want you to create a new subfolder with this exact name.
So new folder it needs to be exactly.
S are C short for source.
OK, inside that new source folder, I want you to create a new file and let's name it Index Dot JS
now inside this brand new totally blank index args file.
Why don't we just copy and paste over the contents from our test, Gorgias, to open up test.
Just select everything in this entire file.
Copy it back in our new index JS file, paste it in.
We can save that.
We can actually go ahead and delete our test JS file.
We no longer need it.
OK, now within our index dawgs file, let's try to use a bit of JSA.
So within our edit function, what are we going to return?
Let's get rid of all of this.
So right now, I just have a function.
I'm returning nothing.
What I really want to return well is just a bit of JSM.
So let's have a heading level three and say this is an H3 from Jeff Sachs.
Let's give that to save.
OK, so now we just need a way to tell that WordPress package to convert this file for us.
Here's how we do that.
I want you to jump into the package JSON file.
We're looking for the area called Scripps right now.
There's just this one test script.
So maybe on a new line right above the test.
Let's say quotes build Colen string of text, WP dash scripts build.
So essentially, we're just creating a command that we can run in the command line called Build.
We do want to set up one more script or command.
So at the end of this line, let's add a comma and then on a new line, let's say quotes start Colen
and then string a text WP dash scripts start.
Be sure to end that line with a comma as well.
Let's go ahead and save this and we now have everything we need.
So check this out in our command line.
We can now run one of these tasks, either build or start.
Start is nice because it will watch us on going.
And every single time we save a change to one of our files, it will automatically rebundle up the converted
version on the fly.
So the build command, on the other hand, that just performs a one time build.
So when you're actively developing, though, START is a very, very useful command.
So let's do this.
We just say NPM run and then the name of the script or command that we're interested in, which is start.
So npm run, start, go ahead and press enter.
OK, and here's where things get interesting notice in our folder, we didn't create this folder named
Build, so the WordPress JavaScript package did this for us.
Inside of the build folder is a converted copy of our index JS file.
Now, it's not meant to be human readable, so if you open it up, it's not the easiest thing to look
through.
It's optimized for a browser, not for a human to read.
But if you scroll down for me, it's around line number one hundred and six.
It'll probably be different for you.
Or you can just press command F or control F and search for the text that you typed.
But here you can see it automatically converted our X into create element.
And then those are the three arguments again.
So we don't have to ever write this unintuitive code again.
We just write it the way that we want to write it in the source folder.
And this automated script will do the rest for us.
And because we used the start script, it's still watching us.
So if I change this from a period to two exclamation marks and hit save, watch what happens in the
command line.
Well, it wasn't a huge change, but the point is it just ran again, so if you check the copy that
lives in the built folder, look, it's automatically been updated.
There are the two exclamations.
So the point is we just now want to tell let me close this file.
We just want to tell WordPress to load this version of the JavaScript file in the browser.
So to do that, we would just go into our index file and we're looking for our function that we named
admin assets.
We're just looking for the path that points towards our JavaScript file.
So instead of Test-tube, let's hollow out these quotes, we would instead just say go into the build
folder, slash and load the file named index dot.
Yes, let's give this a save.
And now if we refresh the Post editor screen and WordPress.
Awesome.
This is a H3 from JSH now that it's up and running.
Let's practice with more complex or nested HTML.
So back in our source code, so in the source folder index J.S., if you only have one single element
and a single line of code, you can use this syntax.
However, if you want to have multiple lines and multiple elements, we do want to return a pair of
parentheses and then inside those parentheses.
Now we can have multiple lines html.
Well, technically it's not HTML, it's X, but you get the point.
So let's practice, let's have a div so I'll type div and then hit tab.
Now your voice code might not give you the automatic tab triggers right away.
If you want to make sure that your voice code is set up like mine and that each HTML tab triggers are
recognized inside of JSM.
Here's what you can do.
There are multiple ways to set this up, but this is the simplest and I've yet to see a single drawback
or downside to it.
So open up your voice code settings on Windows that's control and comma on Mac, that's command and
comma.
OK, then I want you to click this icon right here towards the top, right.
So you can control all sorts of different settings and options in this file.
The one that I want to draw your attention to is the one that I'm highlighting right now.
So I've just set a global and permanent file association.
So I'm saying that any JavaScript files should not just use the JavaScript syntax reader or interpreter,
they should use JavaScript react.
Now, this is not a plug in.
You don't need to install anything to make this work.
Very code has JavaScript react or just syntax built in.
You just need to tell it to actually use it for JavaScript files.
Cool.
So with this in place, your HTML tab triggers will work inside a block of joysticks.
OK, so inside our div, let's practice having multiple elements.
Maybe we'll have a paragraph and just say hello.
This is a paragraph maybe below that will have a heading level for that says hi there.
Now there's more to this than what we've seen here, but we don't need to learn too much about JSA right
here, right now.
We can organically and gradually learn more about jazz acts as we go.
For now, let's go ahead and save that.
And if we reload.
Cool, you can see our blacktip type is using our nested or a little bit more complex structure of HTML
really quick.
I do want to show you that if you modify what our save function returns well, you can easily add a
new instance of our block type.
But watch what happens to an existing block type that's already embedded in a post.
So if we make a change to our save function, so what do we want to return just a bit of X?
So maybe parentheses drop down, let's have a div.
Let's actually cover a very important rule in James X, and that is that you can only have one top level
element.
So if I try to have a heading level three here and then below that happening level five, this will
not work.
This is not valid.
JS X in X, there can only be one sort of top level or root level element.
Now, this doesn't mean that you have to have a semantically meaningless div wrapper.
Instead, you can use something called a react fragment.
So we could open this up with this symbol, just sort of an empty opening tag and then you can have
a closing wrapping fragment tag.
So this is indeed valid JSA X.
Let me change what the actual text here is.
If we save that now, because we already have this block, which is an instance of the block we're working
on, if we refresh WordPress says, oh, no way, this block contains unexpected or invalid content.
This is totally normal.
And to be expected and we'll learn more about why this is happening and how to avoid this issue in a
future lesson.
For now, though, you can just click on that block and delete it, and then you can always just insert
a new copy of the block.
Cool.
So if we click update and then if we view that post on the front end.
Perfect, age three and five on the front end, and that is going to bring this lesson to a close.
Let's talk about where we go from here, though, so we don't actually want to create these hard coded
pieces of content in our blog type.
Right.
Instead, we would want something interactive, like a text field where the user can type into it.
And more importantly, we would want to learn how to store the values that they enter.
Well, that's exactly what we're going to cover in our next lesson.
Really quick, though, before this video closes, I do want to show you how to stop the task that's
running in your command line.
So back in our terminal, remember that control or command to toggle your terminal or command line so
that start command that we ran, it's going to keep running and watching you until you tell it to stop.
So to tell it to stop, just click on your command line.
So it's focused and then press control.
See, doesn't matter if you're on Windows, Mac or Linux.
That is the keyboard shortcut.
Command, control, see.
And if you want to start it up again before we jump into the next lesson, it's just npm run, start
cool.
Let's keep the momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.