Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will begin creating our very own WordPress theme.
Without further ado, let's jump right into the action.
OK.
So in your Web browser, go ahead and visit the home page of your local dev environment copy of WordPress
and let's visit the admen dashboard of our Web site.
You can always visit the dashboard by going up to your address bar and at the end of your domain, visiting.
Slash WP dash admen.
Go ahead and log in.
OK.
And if we were not developers, one of the first things you do on a typical WordPress Web site is look
for a theme that you like.
Right.
So you might head over to the appearance tab.
And switch to one of the other themes that WordPress comes with out of the box, or most of the time
you don't want to be limited to just these themes that WordPress ships with.
So instead, you might click add new here.
And then you could search through the thousands of free themes or your third main option is to use this
upload theme button in case you purchased a premium theme from a third party marketplace.
OK, but in this course, we are not going to do any of that because we are not going to use an existing
theme.
We are going to create a brand new theme.
Now, I know at first that might sound scary, creating a theme from scratch, but it's not scary because
I'm here to guide you through it step by step.
And believe it or not, it's very simple to begin creating a new theme.
So, for example, if I click on the main appearance tab again.
Here we see all of our currently installed themes.
And if we want to create a brand new theme that will show up on this screen, all we need to do is create
a new folder in a very specific location.
So let me show you what I mean.
Let's go on a little bit of a trip.
Let's look for the word prest themes folder.
The first step to finding it is just navigating to that WordPress system folder.
We've already looked at two or three times.
So.
Right, click on your site.
Click, reveal and finder.
Click into your folder.
And then app.
And then public.
OK.
Now, everyone in the course, regardless of what you're using for your local dev environment software,
everyone is going to have these same core WordPress files.
Now, at the moment, we are looking for the Themes folder, which is located in the WP content folder.
So click in to WP content.
And here we see a folder named Themes.
Let's look inside that folder.
And here we see one folder for each of our currently installed themes.
So if we want to create a new theme, all we need to do is create a brand new folder in this theme's
directory.
So new folder and we can name it anything we'd like.
Why don't we call it fictional university theme?
Technically, you could name the folder whatever you want, but just to save yourself a lot of frustration
just for the sake of being on the same page as me while working throughout the course.
I want you to name it exactly.
Fictional Dasch University dash theme.
OK.
Now all we need to do is create two new files within this new folder.
And then we will have a real theme that will show up on this screen and that we can activate.
So let's go ahead right now and create the two files that we need to do this.
Let's actually open this entire new folder within our Visual Studio Code text editing program on Windows.
You can drag this new folder onto a V.S. code window or on Mac.
You can drag this new folder on top of the V.
S code icon down in your dock or on any operating system.
You can just use the file open menu, a V.S. code.
And choose your folder instead of a file.
OK, but once you've opened our fictional university themed folder in V.S. Code, then in the left hand
explorer side right here, we can just right click and choose new file.
You should also see an icon right here that will also allow you to create a new file.
When you click new file here, we see a place where we can begin typing.
Let's name this new file index dot p HP press enter.
OK, and what do we want to write within the file?
For now, let's just add a bit of place holder text that reads.
This is our amazing custom theme.
Save again.
All right.
So I said we needed to create two files.
So we created one of the two.
Let's create the second file.
So over in the left hand side bar here, we can just right click choose new file.
And we need to name it style dot c.
S.
S press enter.
Now, normally a CSX file only has one responsibility, and that's to tell the Web page what it should
look like.
So you don't have to type this out cause I'm just gonna delete it in five seconds from now.
But normally in a CSX file, you would say that like the color of all, the text should be orange,
right?
You style the content on your page.
Well, we will do stuff like that as well.
But in WordPress, this style does.
CSX file has another responsibility.
WordPress needs us to use this file to give it a bit of information about our theme and the way that
we give WordPress.
That info is up at the very top of the file here.
We begin a CSX comment.
So slash and then an asterisk.
That's how you begin a CSX comment.
And then on another line to close out the comment, it's asterisk and a slash.
OK.
Now, between those two lines, we can write whatever we want.
So first and foremost, WordPress wants to know what the name of our theme is.
So let's say theme name Colan.
And we don't need the semicolon at the end here.
And now we can make up whatever name we want.
So let's say fictional university.
You might think that we already named the theme when we created the folder name, but in folder names,
you usually want to use dashes instead of spaces.
So this is our chance to use capital letters and have spaces in the name.
You get the idea.
Now, if we save this file and.
Want to point out that it needs to be named styled CSX.
It can't be made CSX or screen DOT, CSX, the name here is very important word.
Press is on the lookout for this specific file name in our theme folder.
OK.
But with this comment in place and we save the file, if we jump back over to our Admon dashboard and
refresh the main appearance theme's screen.
Here we see our brand new theme.
And if we hover over it, we see themed details.
And if we click on that, we can see it looks a bit odd.
Right.
It says fictional university and then version.
And there's no version number.
And also it says by Anonymous instead of our name.
So to fix those two things, back in our text editor on a new line still within our comment, we can
say author don't need the semicolon.
But author Colon.
And then you can just type in your name here.
And then on a new line, we can also say version.
And then we can just make up a version number, maybe 1.0.
OK.
So if we save this again and then refresh our theme screen.
And click on it again.
Cool.
So now we see fictional university version 1.0 by Brad.
Now all we are really missing is a screenshot or photograph or a preview image of our theme.
Right.
You'll notice that all of the other themes have a preview image here.
So to add a preview image to our new theme, all we need to do is go within our theme folder.
Right.
I named that folder fictional university theme.
And we just need to move an image file to live within this folder.
And the file should be named Screenshot Dot PMG.
Now, I conveniently have a PMG files on my desktop here.
You can find this same image file in the resources for this lesson, but I'm just going to move this
file into my folder and then I'm going to rename the file to Screen Shot Dot PMG.
OK.
Because WordPress is on the lookout for this exact file name.
And you can use your own image here instead of this one.
Ideally, you want the photo to be twelve hundred pixels wide by nine hundred pixels tall.
All right.
But with this in place, if we refresh this admin screen again.
Cool.
So now this looks like a legitimate theme.
It's got a preview photo if we click it.
It's got the essential information.
And now we can just go ahead and activate the theme.
So you can click activate down here at the bottom.
Or if you close this out from this screen, when you hover over a theme, there's also an activate button
right here.
OK.
So let's go ahead and activate the theme.
And now if we use this link up here to view the front end of our Web site.
Cool.
So remember, this is what we typed out in our theme's index stop BHP file.
So if we go back to our text editor and jump back into the themes index, stop p HP file, maybe I want
to add the word completely here.
This is our completely amazing custom theme.
Save it.
Refresh our Web site.
Awesome.
So now that we have our brand new theme and we activated it, we can see it on the front end of our
web here.
We really don't have any need for all of these other default themes, like twenty, seventeen, twenty,
sixteen.
Right.
Our new theme is all we are ever going to need.
And since we don't want to ever accidentally activate one of these other themes, why don't we just
go and delete them right now?
So back to the folder structure.
Here's our theme folder that contains indexed BHP style and our screenshot.
If we go up a level.
OK.
So now I'm looking in the WordPress theme's folder.
We can go ahead and delete the folders for those other themes.
2015, 16 and 17.
So just select them and delete them.
Cool.
So now if I refresh this admin screen.
Perfect.
We just have one theme and it's the one that we created.
Now, before we bring this lesson to a close, I want to address a CSF concern that you might have.
So if you're the type of person who experiments with lessons along the way, you might have already
tried to do the following.
So back in our style, that CSX file underneath our comment lines, you might have tried to write a
bit of normalcy SS so maybe you would target the entire page and say color orange.
But you'll notice that if I save that and refresh the Web site, nothing happens.
We would expect this text to become orange.
But that's not happening.
So don't worry.
I don't expect the CSF to be loading yet.
I will show you how to correctly load the CSX on the front end of your Web site very soon.
OK.
Now, having said that, looking forward to our very next lesson, we will learn how to do something
actually useful here instead of just this boring place.
Hold their sentence.
We are going to look at the heart and soul of WordPress and BHP, which is functions.
If you have no idea what a function is.
That's OK.
That's actually good, because in the next lesson, we are going to start with the very basics.
Should be a lot of fun.
Let's keep it rolling.
And I will see you then.