Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will answer the question, what is a function instead of trying to explain with
words what a function is?
Let me show you visually what a function is.
So let's jump into our text editor and open up the index stock, BHP file that lives in our theme folder.
Let's try to write some new code here together.
So delete this sample line of text and then let's drop in or enter into P HP mode.
So remember, from our first taste of pee pee lesson to enter BHP Moad, its less than symbol, questionmark
BHP and then maybe down on this line.
Let's close out of P HP mode.
So a question mark, greater than symbol.
And then in between those two lines.
So where my cursor is now, we are free to write BHP code.
So remember, from a lesson or two ago, we tried echoing out a math problem.
Right.
We could say echo two plus two.
So if I go ahead and save this and then refresh my Web site here we see the answer.
Right.
Two plus two equals four.
OK.
So that should jog our memory of working with P HP.
Now let's have our first look at a function.
So let's delete this line and let's create our very own first function.
We don't even know what a function is yet.
But let's create one.
So right out the word function and then a space and then we can make up a name for our function.
Why don't we call it my first function?
Right.
The name doesn't really matter.
It's up to us to choose a name.
And then right after that, we don't even need a space.
Let's just open up a pair of parentheses.
And then after the opening closed parentheses, let's add a pair of curly brackets.
These are the same curly brackets that you use and CSX.
So you just hold down the shift key and then press the key to the right of your peaky.
OK.
And in between the two curly brackets, I like to drop down to a new line just to stay organized.
And in between the curly brackets, let's right out our echo.
Two plus two again.
Now, if I save this and refresh the browser, we do not see the number four.
We don't see anything.
It's just a completely blank page.
And that's because this code here that we wrote is a function definition.
So really, all we did here with this code is we took the task of adding two plus two.
And we gave it a name.
My first function.
So a function definition like we have here doesn't actually do anything.
It's just a description of an action or a task in order to actually run this function.
Right.
And actually evaluate two plus two.
What we can do is below this function definition.
So maybe on a new line like right here, we just type out the name of the function.
So my first function and then include parentheses and let's include a semicolon at the end of that line.
And now if we save and refresh, we do see for.
So this is how you define a function.
It's like the recipe for the action that you want to take.
And then this is how you actually run or call or use the function.
Now, what's cool is you can use the function again and again and again.
You can recycle that recipe.
So we could say it again, my first function.
Save it.
Refresh it.
And now we see a second four.
This is a little bit confusing because it looks like 44, but really it's just the number four.
And then there's no spacing.
And then the number four again.
So let's try something a little bit clearer up in our function instead of echo two plus two.
Let's delete that.
And instead, let's say echo out a string of text.
So give me double quotes and then let's create an H team L paragraph tag.
Right.
So the opening and closing tag and in between them.
Let's say hello.
This is my first function.
And let's be sure to add a semicolon at the very end of this line to let P p know that we are done with
this action.
OK.
And now if we save this and refresh, cool, we see it twice because we are calling the function twice
down here.
So you only have to define a function once and then you can use it and reuse it as many times as you
want.
So if I copied this and pasted it again, so there's three of them.
Obviously we see it three times.
OK, so now that we've learned how to create a function and then run or call the function, let's go
ahead and delete all of this and try something a little bit more advanced.
So first, let's give ourselves a goal.
Let's imagine that we want to create these two paragraphs.
Hi, my name is John and my favorite color is Blue and.
Hi, my name is Jane and my favorite color is green.
Now, when I say that we want to create these two paragraphs, I don't mean just type them out like
we see here.
Instead, what I mean is because these two lines are so similar to each other.
And the only unique parts are the names and the colors.
Why don't we try to create a single function that can generate both of these paragraphs?
So let me delete these and try this out with me up here and our P p area.
Let's create a new function.
So to do that, we just spell out the word function and then a space.
And now we make up a name for the function.
Why don't we call it a greet?
OK.
And then right after that, we don't even need a space.
Open up a pair of parentheses.
And then after the parentheses, let's open up a pair of curly brackets.
And then in between the opening and closing curly brackets.
Let's drop down to a new line.
And then let's echo or output a bit of text.
So we want to wrap our text in double quotes.
OK.
So in between those quotes, let's just begin an H t Amelle paragraph tag.
Then let's close it out.
And in between those, we will say hi, my name is Blank.
And my favorite color is blank.
And then at the very end of this line, let's be sure to end it with a semicolon.
OK.
And now right below our function definition here.
So down here, let's just call or run the function once for John.
And once for Jane.
So greet, parentheses, semicolon that will run at once.
And then let's just run it a second time.
So if I save this and refresh in the browser.
Cool.
We see the two paragraphs.
So now all we need to do is find a way to pass information about John from this function.
Call into the function itself.
Right.
Because we don't want it to say blank and blank.
So check this out.
When we call the function for the first time in between the parentheses, let's say, John.
And let's do the same thing for Jane.
So in between these parentheses, let's say Jane.
OK.
Now back up in our function definition within these parentheses, let's add a dollar symbol and let's
say name.
Remember from an earlier lesson that the dollar symbol is how you create a variable mph HP.
This isn't a special word.
I just made it up.
We could have said unicorn or pizza.
OK.
The name doesn't matter.
But for now, let's just call it name because that makes sense, right?
John and Jane are names.
So what this is going to do is it's going to create a variable of sorts that we can use within the meat
and potatoes of this function.
So we can use this dollar symbol, name variable wherever we see fit.
So all we need to do now is just remove this blank.
Right.
We don't want that.
And let's replace it with dollar symbol name.
OK.
Now, before I explain what's going on here and give you the technical names of what we're doing, let's
just go ahead and save this and test it out.
So if I refresh in the browser.
Cool.
Hi, my name is John and my favorite color is blank.
Hi, my name is Jane.
And my favorite color is blank.
So let's review what's going on here and let's build up our vocabulary.
So when we call the function down here twice, there's a little bit of data named John in this little
bit of data named Jane.
Those are called arguments.
And within a single function call like this, you can include multiple arguments.
So check this out.
Right after the John, end quote.
Let's add a comma and say blue.
Right.
Because blue was his favorite color.
Let's do the same thing for Jane.
So after this first argument of her name, let's add a comma and include another argument.
Her favorite color was green.
OK.
So if we are calling a function and giving it to arguments, we better make sure that up in our function
definition, we are ready for two parameters.
Think of a parameter as a hollowed out variable or a little container that can receive the incoming
arguments.
So we already have a parameter to receive the incoming name.
So right after that, let's add a comma and then let's just say dollar sign color.
Again, the parameter name doesn't really matter.
You can make it up.
You can use whatever name you want.
OK.
But what's important is that now we can use dollar symbol color within the body of this function.
So let's go ahead and delete this second blank here and let's replace it with dollar symbol color.
Let's save this and refresh.
Cool.
So we see my favorite color is blue and my favorite color is green.
OK.
So that's how you can create your own function and use parameters to receive the incoming arguments
so that your function can be flexible.
OK.
Now let's change gears and bring this full circle.
Let's tie it back to WordPress.
So the beauty of WordPress is that it comes bundled with tons of its own prebuilt functions that we
can leverage.
Right.
So WordPress has already created and defined lots of functions.
And then we just get to come along and run or call or use those functions.
So, for example, down here, once we are out of P HP mode.
Right.
So this line closes BHP mode.
So down here in regular old H t AML mode.
Let's imagine that we want to create a large H.T. Amelle headline and we want the contents of this headline
to be our Web site's overall name or title.
Well, WordPress has a function that will give us our Web site's name.
So check this out.
In between the H1 tags, let's drop into P, HP mode K and then let's exit BHP mode.
OK.
But in the middle of those two, let's run or call a WordPress function named blog info.
So this is a function that has already been created and defined by WordPress.
And what this function can do is give us all kinds of information about our Web site.
And within these parentheses, we just provide an argument to tell WordPress what little bit of info
in particular we are looking for.
So single quotes and let's say name, we want the name or title of our Web site.
And let's add a semicolon right after that, just to tell HP that we are done with this task.
OK.
And if we save this and refresh, cool, we see the name of our Web site.
Now, in case you're wondering where this is coming from, let's hop over and a new tab into the admen
dashboard of our WordPress Web site.
And towards the bottom of this Left-Hand Sidebar, hover over settings and then choose General.
OK.
So see this first field named site title?
That's the name of our Web site.
So if we changed this from fictional university to amazing university and then scroll down and click
save.
Now, if we refresh the front end of our Web site, we see that name change reflected.
Cool.
So this function blog info.
We didn't create or define this function.
WordPress creates it for us.
And then we just get to leverage it.
Now, the cool part is that we don't need to understand how WordPress goes and talks to the database
to dynamically find the name of our Web site.
WordPress abstracts away all of those technical database details so we don't have to worry about it.
All we have to do is run this convenient function.
OK.
And that's really the heart and soul of 95 percent of custom WordPress development.
It's just a matter of knowing the WordPress functions that are at our disposal and then running them
in the right place at the right time.
Let's try one more example before we close out this lesson.
So let's imagine that below this headline, we want to include a paragraph that includes our Web site's
slogan or tagline or description.
In case you're wondering what I'm talking about, back in the Admon dashboard on this general setting
screen, we see that the second field is named tag line.
So by default, WordPress sets this to just another WordPress Web site.
But we could change this to the best university in the world.
And then scroll down and save that.
And then back in our code, if we want to dynamically output that tag line in between the paragraph
tag.
Let's just drop and BHP mode and close out.
But in the middle, let's call that blog info function again.
And then we can give it an argument to tell it which piece of information in particular we want it to
return.
And we will say description.
Let's add a semicolon here and then let's save this and refresh.
Cool.
There's our slogan or tagline.
And now, if in the future we ever change the tag line from the word press admin area.
So if I change this to we are pretty good.
And then save it.
Our front end Web site will automatically always display that value.
OK, so now at this point, we are at least a little bit familiar with what a function is.
And now there's only one more topic we need to go over before we can start doing powerful, actually
useful word pressie things.
And that topic is a raise.
So what in the world is an array?
Well, that's exactly what we're going to cover in our next lesson.
I'll give you a hint right now, though, understanding arrays is what's going to let us start displaying
actual dynamic WordPress content on the front end of our Web site, things like posts and pages.
It's gonna be a lot of fun.
Let's keep things rolling.
And I will see you in the next lesson.