Hello, everyone, in this video we're going to pick up right where we left off and continue styling
our blog.
Let's jump into the action.
So the first thing I want to point out is that in the previous video, I mixed up the background, color
and border color, these two gray values that we see here.
So back in the text editor in our Sarsae folder, let's jump in to Indexers Success.
And I mixed up this color with this color.
So let's just swap those two.
So this should be the EF1 and this should be the Desex.
Let's give that to save and let's make sure our task is running, so in the command line, npm run,
start.
OK, and if we refresh the edit screen, cool, that looks so much better at this point.
Let's focus on the details of this area.
So this star should be yellow or gold instead of black and the delete button should be red and maybe
have an underline.
Also, let's fine tune the vertical alignment.
You can see the stars should probably set up about three or four pixels higher.
So to get started, let's give this star icon a class so that we can target it with success.
So let's jump into our SIRC folder and open up index.
James, let's go down to our James and here is the icon with Star Empty.
Let's just give this a class name of you can make up anything, but I'll call it Mark as correct.
Let's give that a save.
And then in our SCC file, I'm going to create a nested rule and you don't need to do this.
But I like to do this to make sure that my system isn't going to accidentally target anything else in
the WordPress admin screen.
So you could achieve this exact same feature by just choosing a super unique class name here.
But I chose a name that, who knows, maybe WordPress is using this class name somewhere else.
And I don't want to accidentally add random styling to it.
So by nesting inside this selector.
So maybe after this line we can say dot mark as correct curly brackets.
Well, SPSS or SAS is going to output this selector like this.
You don't need to type this out.
But when it converts our SAS access to regular CSFs, it's going to create a selector that looks like
this.
So it would only select Mark as correct if it lives inside of this element.
So this is just something I like to do with personal preference.
But inside this class, let's tell it to have a yellow or golden color.
So color hash tag.
Fifty seven hundred.
Let's tell it to look like a link and have the pointer hand when you hover over it.
So cursor should be a pointer.
Let's pull it up a few pixels to fix the vertical alignments, all state position, relative and then
top, maybe negative three pixels.
Let's give this a save and see what it looks like.
So if we refresh.
Cool, it might not show up in this video recording, but you should be able to see it in your actual
Web browser.
There's the Yellow Star.
Let's go ahead and fine tune the delete button.
Actually, I'm noticing that the button already looks like a link with the cursor pointer hand, so
we didn't need that prop..
We can actually get rid of that here.
We didn't need cursor pointer.
OK, but let's go ahead and give the delete button a class so that we can target it.
So in our X on this delete button, I'm just going to say class name equals and only maybe attention
delete.
Give that a save back in our success, I'll create a nested rule for dot attention, delete curly brackets.
Let's tell it to be red.
So a color of hashtag FNF and then four zeros.
Let's also fix its vertical alignments, maybe position relative and then pull it up from the top negative
five pixels.
Let's see what that looks like.
OK, that's starting to look a lot better.
However, you'll notice that even if your mouse is nowhere near the word delete, it starts to be treated
as a link.
So maybe to reduce some of that vertical padding back in our JSA X on the button element we can give
it a prop of just is link.
And you don't even need to set it to equal anything, just including this if we save that and reload.
Cool.
So that gives us an underline.
I like that.
And I think it also fixed the vertical padding a little bit.
Next up, let's change things so that when you hover over it instead of turning blue, maybe it just
turns a darker shade of red.
So back in our success nested within this rule, we can just say ampersand, colon hover.
So in sasy ampersand will give you sort of the top level rule that you're nested in.
So just the ampersand will give us dot attention, delete, and then we're just adding on the hover
pseudo selector to that so we can just say color hash tag, see two and then four zeros.
Let's give that a save and test it out.
So you can see it's still turning blue when I hover over it, so WordPress has its own hover selector.
So to make sure we override that, we can just add on exclamation important at the end of our value.
Cool now in a hover over it, we see the darker red while we're at it, why don't we add a hover effect
for the star?
Maybe when you hover over the star, it should enlarge or zoom in a little bit and maybe rotate a couple
of degrees clockwise.
So within this mark as correct nested inside it, we can just say ampersand hover and let's say transform
and call the scale function, give it a value of maybe one point two five so it becomes twenty five
percent larger than normal.
Be sure to end that line with a semicolon.
And then within the baseline rule from Mark as correct, we can say transition the transform property
over the course of zero point three seconds and we'll use the easy out timing function.
And then if we want to rotate it clockwise a little bit, we could say rotate and maybe just try 12
degrees.
Let's see what that looks like.
Cool, so now when you hover over the star again, this might be small in the video recording, but
if you try it in your actual Web browser, you can see it sort of zooms in and rotates a little bit.
I like that at this point.
Let's do two things.
Let's make this TextField for the question text.
Let's make it larger.
Right, to show a bit of hierarchy like it's the most important thing because there's only one question.
So answers should be smaller because there's multiple answers.
So it will make this field a bit larger and then we'll make this label text a good bit smaller.
So to increase the font size for the question input, you could give this a class and then use success.
However, when I only need to modify one single property, in this case only font size, I like to actually
just declare it inline in my JS X.
I don't want to create a class for just one property.
So here's how you can do that in X back in our JavaScript file.
Let's find that text control component right with the label of question so we can just give it a prop
of style, just like you would in HTML equals only in HTML.
You would give it a string of text.
Right.
But in JSM we say equals an object to give it a dynamic value and then nested inside here we want another
pair of curly brackets for an object with different properties.
So now we only need to give it the property for font size.
Now you'll notice that in real access this would be font dash size.
But this isn't real success.
This is James X, so a habit you need to get into is when you're writing Gests, you can usually guess
the appropriate CSS property name by just instead of using dashes by using capitalization on secondary
words like this.
So font size Colen and then just give it a value string attacks, let's say 20 pixels, 20 x.
Let's give that a save if we reload.
Cool.
OK, next up, let's try to shrink this text where it says answers because a standard paragraph like
we're using right now, not only is this text too large, but it's also creating too much of a vertical
margin here.
So to adjust that, let's just find the paragraph in our.
Here it is.
And on the opening tag, we can just say style equals curly brackets for a dynamic value and then we
want to give it an object.
So another pair of curly brackets, let's give it a property of font size colon, maybe 13 pixels comma.
Let's adjust the margins of margin call and give it a string of text.
How about twenty pixels on the top, zero on the right, eight on the bottom and zero on the left.
Give that to save if we reload.
Cool.
I think that looks a lot better at this point.
If we look at the finished product, ours is starting to look very similar.
Let's go ahead and add this button towards the bottom that says add another answer.
So back on our Kopi.
And then back in our code at the very bottom, below the closing flex tag, but still in the overall
wrapper, Divx, let's say button and then hit tab inside, let's say add another answer in just this
on its own.
If we save that, you'll see that that doesn't create sort of the standard WordPress blue button.
Right.
We want sort of this style that says update in the top right corner.
So to fix that on the opening button tag, we just give it a prop of is primary.
That's it.
You don't need to set it to equal anything.
Just saying is primary.
If we save that and refresh.
Perfect, OK, for the time being, that wraps up our styling job.
Now, in our very next lesson, we're going to start bringing this to life.
In other words, actually storing the values that the user types in here.
And when the user clicks this button, we should dynamically add another Ansaru on the fly.
And then obviously we also need to hook up the star button to mark one as the correct answer and also
make the delete button actually delete the current row.
I think the next lesson will be one of the most exciting ones in the entire chapter, because really
this is where our knowledge is going to mix with our WordPress attributes and saving it in the database
knowledge.
So we're going to connect a lot of dots.
Should be a lot of fun.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.