Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to actually display information about the selected professor, let's jump
into the action.
So here's our BLACKTIP.
And in this lesson, we're actually not going to start with this preview that should appear here.
Instead, let's begin with the public front end output for our block type.
So if I view this blog post on the front end and scroll down to where that blog type is, we see currently
it's just outputting this paragraph.
We will replace this content soon.
So this is what we're going to work on in this lesson.
We instead want it to look something like this.
So the photo on the left hand side and then a bit of information.
Now, by the end of this lesson, once we have a bit of HTML output right here on the public front end,
well, then in a future lesson, it'll be very easy to reuse that exact same HTML template and have
it display in the admin area.
But for now, let's start with this.
So to begin working in our text editor in our plug in folder, jump into our files, a minds named featured
Professor P, if we scroll down just a bit when we are registering our block type, you can see that
our render callback function is named render callback.
So we're just looking for the method with this name.
So here it is right here.
Now, instead of just returning a string of text with this paragraph, let's actually just completely
hollow out the body of this function and start fresh.
So I'm going to start with an if statement and say if parentheses curly brackets right after that.
Let's also have an else block.
And for the condition, I only want to output a custom string of HTML if a professor ID exists for this
block type.
In other words, if the user has just inserted this block type and they have not selected a value yet
and then they actually save the blog post, well then I wouldn't want to return regenerator output any
sort of HTML.
I would just want to output nothing.
So I'll say if and then we're just going to look in the attributes.
So make sure you have a parameter here of dollar sign attributes will say if dollar sign attributes
look inside the array with square brackets quotes.
We named the attribute Proff I.D. So if that exists we want to do something, but else if it doesn't
exist, let's just return null or nothing.
If it does exist.
Well, let's do two things.
First of all, let's load our CSC file on the front end.
And then let's just start with the d'Hiv so we can see that the styling is working.
So I'm going to say WP on Q style parentheses to call it, and we've already registered our CFS file
up here with this name.
So that's all you need to give this one.
We're on cuing the styles and just quotes paste in that exact name from up here.
Cool.
So we're loading a style that's already been registered.
And then for now, just as a test, let's return and then we're going to have a string of text.
But just so you can use your voice code tab trigger instead of wrapping it in quotes right away, we
can just say div dot for a class.
It's a div dot professor dash call-out and then just hit tab.
OK, now we would wrap that in quotes and be sure to end the line with a semicolon and then in between
the opening and closing div tags.
For now let's just output the word hello.
Let's give this a save and see what it looks like.
So if we refresh on the front end.
Perfect, we see hello, but more importantly, those CSI styles are coming through, so you can see
it has a gray background, very subtle rounded corners and a subtle shadow.
Now that we have this basic output working, I want to stop for a moment and talk about code organization.
What I'm getting at here is we need to output a lot of HTML to create the desired layout, and it's
just personal preference.
But I don't want this file to become huge with a hundred lines of HTML is just my own opinion and preference.
But I want this file to be sort of the top level view or the bird's eye view of everything that our
block is doing right from 10000 feet in the sky.
So I don't want this file to be concerned with the nitty gritty details of an HTML template.
I would rather have the big HTML template live in its own separate file where that's its only responsibility.
So check this out.
Here's what I would do on this line where we're returning the HTML.
Let's get rid of that string of text.
So it's just return and now let's call a function that doesn't even exist yet, but that we will create
I'm going to name it, generate professor HTML parentheses to call it in the parentheses.
Let's be sure to give it the professor I.D. so it will know what to query for.
So that's just dollar sign attributes.
Look inside the array.
So square brackets for Prof Idy.
Cool.
So the idea here is we can go create a function with this name in an entirely separate file and this
way we stay organized.
Now currently if we save this file we will get an error on the front end.
If we reload, that's to be expected because we haven't created that function yet.
So do this with me.
Maybe in the root of your project folder.
I mean you could create the file anywhere, but I think it's sort of a standard practice to create a
new folder.
And again, it could be named anything but let's name it I n c short for includes the name doesn't matter.
This is just so you and I are on the same page and in that new folder, let's create a new file.
You can name it anything, but I'll name it.
Generate Professor html dot p p in this new file.
Let's go into P and let's create a function definitions of function with the exact name of generate
professor html parentheses curly brackets within the parentheses.
Let's be sure to receive that incoming ID with a parameter.
So just dollar sign, I'll name it.
I'd infer now just as a test to make sure that things are lining up correctly.
Let's just return a value of hello from our new file, semicolon.
Let's give this a save.
And now back in our original file, up towards the very top.
What I like to do to stay organized is maybe write about here.
So right above our class definition, I'll just list any and all files that I'm loading or requiring
in so we can just say require once and then I'll use the plug in der path function inside the parentheses,
underscore, underscore, file, underscore, underscore.
After that, concatenate on quotes.
Look inside the ANC folder that we created in the file name is generate professor html dot b and that
with a semicolon.
So now the contents of that file will be available within this file.
So when we try to use it down here, it should work perfectly.
So if we save that and refresh on the front end.
Perfect, hello from our new file at this point, let's go back into that new file and actually start
spelling out the query in the HTML.
Let's actually delete this return line because we aren't ready yet to return anything.
We first need to perform our query.
So let's create a variable.
You can name it anything, but only Proff post equals a new instance of the WordPress provided class
WP underscore query.
Woops, just the first letter of that is capitalized.
So we're calling that inside the parentheses.
We give it an array so array parentheses you can drop down.
So first let's spell out the post type.
So post type arrow symbol would be quotes professor.
And technically this isn't even necessary because we already know the exact IDE of the post.
But I'm including this because if somehow the editor for that blog post included a bogus ID number,
well, our query is only going to actually find that post if it truly is of the professor post type.
So let's also include a comma here and then we would want to include the IDE.
So the option for that is just the letter P and then Arrow symbol and now we would just use the parameter,
the ID for the post.
So a dollar sign I'd.
OK, so WP query will do its job and it's going to store its returned value in Proff post.
So right below this, be sure to include a semicolon after these parentheses, but right below that
we can just loop through that proff post.
So while parentheses curly brackets for the while condition, it's just while dollar sign proff post
look inside it so it's not equal or greater than a dash, greater than we're looking inside it for have
posts and we're actually calling that inside the curly brackets for while it's a dollar sign Proff post
Dasch greater than and then call the post.
So this will make all of the standard WordPress functions like the title and the content.
It'll make sure that those work perfectly.
OK, now at this point below this line, we're ready to start spelling out our HTML.
But remember, we want this function as a whole to return a value.
In other words, we can't just drop out of and start outputting HTML.
We need everything that we want to include here to be returned.
So in situations like this, I like to use the Obbie start function output buffer, start semicolon,
then let's drop out of P.
Now on this line we could start to include HTML for now.
Let's just have a dash to represent HTML here, but then on a new line we can go back into PHP.
I'll drop down and we can do two things.
First of all, let's use WP reset post data because we ran our own custom query and this is our way
of just giving control or setting the Global Post object back to whatever WordPress was doing for the
main query for this current page.
And then after that, let's return Obbie get clean semicolon.
So we're starting the output buffer here and then we're ending it and returning the value here.
So now here where we have the dash, we are free to just list out our HTML template.
So let's get rid of the dash and let's say div dot professor call-out inside that div.
Let's have one div for the photo of the professor and one div for the right hand text content.
So we'll just say div dot professor dash call-out underscore underscore photo.
It's a tab below that d'Hiv, let's have d'Hiv dot professor dash, call-out, underscore, underscore,
text hit tab in this text.
If we can drop down, let's have a heading level five and it can just output the title for the professor.
Posts are going to be inside there.
We can just use the title below the professor name or title.
We can have a paragraph of text.
Let's go into HP and let's just echo a WordPress function called the WP trem words.
You give this function to arguments.
So Akama be the first is the string of text that you want to work with.
The second argument is how many words you want to limit it to.
So I just want to output maybe the first 30 words of the professor content.
And then for the first argument, this would just be get the content.
OK, before we go any further, let's save this and see what it looks like.
So if we refresh perfect, Dr. Markkula, the first 30 words of the post and then the photo would go
right here.
And just to prove that this is truly dynamic, if I went back into the admin panel and changed this
to Dr. Miaows a lot and clicked update as soon as we refresh the front end.
Perfect.
OK, let's work on outputting the photograph right here.
I'm actually going to add it as a background image instead of an inline IMG element.
This way we can use access to very easily make it perfectly fit the available height and space.
So let's do this on that opening div for the underscore underscore photo div.
Let's give it another attribute of style equals quotes.
Background dash image.
Colon, and then you are l pair of parentheses now in these parentheses, we need to do something dynamic.
We need to point towards the file.
So I'm going to go into P and we're just going to call the WordPress function, the post thumbnail,
you RL parentheses to call it.
And now in these parentheses you can tell it which size of the photo you want.
So quotes earlier in the course we already registered an image size called Professor Portrait.
OK, now if we give that a save and refresh perfect.
So the text will handle sizing and centering the image so that it just works perfectly at this point.
Let's switch our focus back to the text content, because if we look at the finished product example,
we zoom in a little bit.
We want to be able to say what they teach, which related subjects they have assigned to them.
And then finally below that, we just want to link that points towards their individual.
Professor Post, you are so back in the version that we're working on together, let's go back into
our FTP.
So we're interested in this text div and maybe below the 30 words summary.
We need to look up any and all of their related programs or subjects.
So to do that, I'm going to enter back into P, close out of it and then we can drop down.
So I'm going to create a variable called related programs.
You could name it anything and then set that to equal gett underscore field semicolon.
And then earlier in the course, when we set up the professor post type, we set up an advanced custom
field called quotes related programs, OK, on a new line only if this exists and there are indeed related
programs.
So if parentheses curly brackets only if dollar sign related programs evaluates to true, well then
I would want to output HTML here, so I'll exit here and then enter back into here.
OK then on this line we're free to go into HTML.
So I just want to have a paragraph tag and I want to say that their name.
So we'll fill this blank in in just a moment.
But their name teaches colon and then instead of a bulleted list, I'm just going to have something
that looks like a sentence almost wherewith list a subject and then a comma and then a space and then
the next subject.
And then we can end it all with a period.
So I'm not ready to close out the paragraph element yet.
Instead, I'm going to drop down right after the colon and I'm going to go into P so I can loop through
all of the related programs and output them so close inside here.
I'm just going to use a for each parentheses curly brackets inside the parentheses we can say dollar
sign related programs as Dollar Sign, Key Arrow Symbol Dollar Sign program.
OK, now inside the foreach I'm going to have one last if statement and I'm just going to check to see
if you should have a comma and a space sort of separating the subjects or if you're the last item in
the array of items.
Obviously we don't need a comma and a space for the very final one.
Also, if there's only one program in the entire list, then we don't need commas at all anywhere.
So before we even get into the if statement logic, we know that each and every program should output
its title.
So let's just say Echo, get the title inside the parentheses, just dollar sign program semicolon.
Now this is where we would use our conditional logic.
So if parentheses currently brackets for the condition, the first thing I want to check for is if you
are not the last item in the array.
So dollar sign key if that does not equal array key last parentheses to call that and then you give
it the array you're checking on so related programs.
So if that's true and double ampersand and let's count to make sure the array has more than one item
in it.
So if count parentheses to call it, give it the array related programs if that's greater than one.
So if both of these things are true, then inside the curly brackets we would just echo string of text
that's a comma and then a space semicolon and then sort of to close out the overall sentence.
Right before we have the closing P tag, let's just have a period.
Let's give this a save and see what it looks like.
So if I refresh woops, you can see there is a space after the final subject and before the period.
This is because I forgot about white space and so be is aware of the white space before our period.
So you would actually get rid of our period.
Here and place it immediately after we exit here this way, there's no output, white space for me to
notice.
So if we save that and refresh, perfect.
OK, finally, let's output the link to the professor detail screen.
So back on our copy in our text editor right below this closing tag here.
We can just have a paragraph tag.
Let's have the entire thing be bold, so I'll wrap it in a strong tag and then we can just hit a tab
for a link.
Let's first add the actual clickable text.
So inside the tags it would be learn more about and then it would be their name.
So I'll just have an X for a placeholder and then let's have a space and sort of a right angle, the
arrow symbol.
So ampersand are a Q, you know, semicolon.
OK, let's replace the X placeholder with the professor's name.
So we would just go into P and call the title, then let's fill in the RF value.
So in the quotes we would just go into P and use the permalink.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So if I refresh perfect so I can click on it and it takes me to that permalink or individual uttara
that is going to bring this video to a close.
But in our very next lesson, we're going to learn how to reuse that same HTML template for the live
preview on the edit screen.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.