Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will actually go through and use our new page banner function in all of our templates.
Without further ado, let's jump into the action.
So right away, let's jump into our text editor and in our theme folder, let's just go through each
one of our template files one by one, and remove any of the duplicate page banner code and instead
replace it with our new function.
So let's just start up at the top.
The first file is archive event.
Here we see the page banner div.
So right above that, within this block, let's drop down to a new line and call our new page banner
function.
And this template file controls an archive screen.
So instead of pulling in a title and subtitle from a post from the database, we just want to use these
custom text values.
So within our page banner function call, let's provide it an array of arguments.
OK, let's drop down to a new line to stay organized.
Let's say that title should equal and here we have it set to all events, all events.
And then let's also target subtitle and say that should equal see what is going on in our world so you
can just copy and paste that sort of typing it.
OK, this looks good.
So now we can literally just delete this entire page banner div.
OK, let's give that a save and then let's go test out that page on the front end.
So that was the event's archived screen.
Still looks good.
Let's move on to the next file in our text editor.
So the next template is archived program, and let's just do the same thing.
So right before the page Banner d'Hiv in the AP Block, it's called Page Banner.
This template is using custom text for the title and subtitle.
So let's provide our function and array.
Let's say the title should equal all programs and let's say that subtitle should equal.
And then down here we can just copy and paste this instead of typing it out again.
Copy paste.
OK, and then we can just go ahead and delete this div.
Save it.
Let's go test it out.
So that was the all programs archive.
Still looks good.
Let's move on to the next template file.
So the next template is archived.
Be right above page banner.
Let's call P function page bannered.
Let's pass it an array of arguments.
Let's say that title should equal and this screen is a little bit different, instead of just custom
static type text, we are running a function named the archive title.
So to refresh your memory, let me show you an example of this function in action on the front end of
our website.
If we click over to the blog section up in the header and then within one of the page metadata boxes,
if we click on the bold author name, this screen is powered by archived FTP and this title of author
Colin Brad is being dynamically generated by this function.
Right?
Or if we click on to the awards category archive, we see category Colen Awards.
So this function is responsible for dynamically stirring up that name.
So our first instinct might be to just copy and paste this function up here.
But remember that when a function begins with the word, the it handles the echoing or outputting for
you.
And in this case, up in our array, we don't want to echo or output anything.
We just want to return a value.
So long story short, instead of the archived title, let's set our title to equal the results of a
function named Get the archive title.
Remember that nine times out of ten in WordPress, if you just want to return a value, you can just
begin the same function.
Name with git.
So title equals get the archive title.
Let's not forget about the subtitle.
So comma and then let's say subtitle should equal.
And instead of the archived description, let's say get the archive description.
OK, now with our page banner function call complete, we can go ahead and delete this page banner div.
Let's save that and check out the front end and it still works perfectly.
If I go back to an author archive screen still looks good.
Let's move on to the next template file.
So we just finished archive.
We don't need to adjust footer or front page or functions or header.
So the next file that we want to edit is index P.
This file controls the home of our blog section.
We see a title of Welcome to our blog and the subtitle of Keep Up with our latest news.
So right above this div up in the block, let's just call page banner, pass it.
An array of arguments title should equal.
Welcome to our blog, let's just copy and paste that comma, then we'll say subtitle equals and just
copy and paste this text.
OK, now we can go ahead and delete the actual div.
Save that.
Let's go visit our blog.
Home page still looks good.
Let's move on to the next template file actually before we move on.
Why don't we copy and paste this function, call into our clipboard so we don't have to type as much.
OK, so the next file that we want to update is page past events.
We can see it's using a custom title and subtitle.
So right above it, let's just paste in our clipboard in this block of PHP and let's change the title
to past events and let's change the subtitle to a recap of our past events.
Then we can delete this div save that.
Let's go test it out on the front end.
So events and then down here, check out our Past Events archive still looks good.
Let's move on to the next template file.
We already took care of Page in our previous lesson screenshot.
PNG doesn't apply here.
So next, let's jump into single event.
And what's nice here is that this screen doesn't need any custom text.
It can just use the intelligent defaults that our function will work with.
So right above this in the P block, let's call page banner.
We don't need to give it any arguments and then we can delete this div.
Let's save that and test it out on the front end.
So that was a single event.
So if I click on the New Year, 2016 looks good.
And just to prove to ourselves that our function is working properly, why don't we go back to the events
home and I'm going to edit Poetry Day.
So click on Poetry Day and I'm going to edit this post to give it a custom background image as well
as a subtitle value so we can just use this edit event up here in the top menu for the subtitle down
here.
Let's just say the greatest day of the year.
And for the background image, let me upload a file.
I have a photo of a notebook that I think makes sense for Poetry Day.
Click select image down here and then let's go ahead and update this post, let's use the permalink
here to jump back to the front end and perfect.
Here we see the subtitle.
And in the background we have that notebook photo so we can rest assured that our function is doing
its job no matter where we call it from.
Let's move on to the next template file, which is a single professor.
Looks like we already set that up in the previous lesson.
So let's jump into a single program.
And this screen doesn't need any custom title or subtitle so we can literally just call our page banner
function.
No arguments, need it and then delete this div save it.
Let's give it a quick test.
Programs click on to a single program like Buyology Perfect and onto the next and final template file,
which is single dot p right.
This controls individual blog posts.
So blog posts don't need anything special.
So we can just call our page banner function without any arguments and delete that div.
Give it a save, let's go test it out blog, click on our first blog post and it works and that's going
to bring this lesson to a close.
In our next lesson, I want to show you another tool that can greatly reduce duplicate code in our project.
We're going to learn about a function named git template part, and it has the potential to make our
code so much cleaner.
So that's the plan for the next lesson.
But looking ahead, beyond that, I want to keep you hyped so you can keep steamrolling through the
entire course.
So just a sneak peek after our next lesson, we are going to create a new post type for campuses.
Campuses should be a lot of fun.
We are going to use custom fields in order to create a pin on a Google map for each of our campuses.
So that way visitors of our site will be presented with an interactive map that they can pinch, zoom
and scroll around and see pins of all of our campus locations and to get you really hyped.
Even beyond campuses, we've still got live search results powered by Ajax and the new rest API.
Right.
We've got the JavaScript aspect to cover still.
And after that, we're going to learn about user roles, user permissions.
Long story short, we've still got a ton of good stuff to cover.
And I want you to stay excited.
I'll admit that not all of the sections in the course so far have been riveting or completely exciting.
But at this point in the course, you and I now speak the same language.
We've laid out a rock solid foundation of working with the basic components of WordPress development.
And now from here we can really start speeding up and working on the fun features.
Anyways, let's keep it rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.