Hello, everyone, in this lesson, we're going to learn how to query our table for data.
Let's jump right into the action.
So back in the custom post type example lesson, we set up this page that has a slug of pet dash adoption.
Now our new custom table plug in.
It's also making sure that when you visit this Eurail, a custom template is being used and currently
the template just outputs an empty table.
Right.
There's just dashes in each column.
So our goal in this video is to actually query our database, our pet table, and display the records
here.
However, before we worry about WordPress or templates or HTTP, let's first just focus a little bit
on sequel.
So open up, add manner and then let's jump in to our pets table, then click select data.
And a really cool feature that I want to draw your attention to is this area right here.
This is a great spot to practice writing your first sequel statements.
So this sort of default query, this is what's controlling the data that we're actually seeing here.
So it's saying select all columns from this table and limit it to just the first 50.
However, what if you and I want to query only for the pets where species equals cat?
Well, we can just click this edit button and we can just practice writing a sequel statement.
So after this from line, we can add a new line and say where all uppercase where species equals and
then just quotes cat.
Okay, then if we scroll down and click the execute button.
Cool.
So now it only returns items where the speciesist cat we can get even more specific.
What if we only want cats whose birth year is 2017 or greater?
Well from the screen we can just scroll down towards the bottom and just adjust our query again.
So at the end of the where line we can just say uppercase and birth year, let's use the greater than
symbol and just say twenty, seventeen.
And what if instead of returning 50, we want a hundred to limit it to the first hundred click execute.
Perfect.
So you get the idea.
We can also control what we're ordering by.
So for example, if we wanted to order by birth year, we could just go back down into our query, add
a new line after where and say order by birth year.
And then you can say whether you want it to be ascending or descending.
Let's run that query.
Cool.
So now they're sorted, are ordered by the birth year.
Finally, just one last little bit of school practice that I want to run by you.
You don't need to select all columns.
So instead of saying select asterisk for all columns, you could just say select pet name Berthier year.
You list out the specific columns you want.
So if I only want maybe the name and their birth year, you can click execute.
Cool.
So then the results only include those two columns.
Now, while there's much, much more complexity to sequel than this, we've at least seen that the very
basics are not rocket science.
So now at this point, our goal becomes running sequel statements like this from within our template.
We just want to populate the table with the results from our query.
So to do that, let's jump in to voice code.
And before we jump into the template file directly, let's first go into our main file.
So new database table.
And while this has nothing to do with databases, I do want to run it by you because it's code that
we've never written together.
But essentially, if you scroll down in the construct function, you'll notice there's an add filter
where the hook is template include.
And then I'm calling a method that I named load template and then we can go look at that function.
Here it is load template.
So I'm just saying if and then I'm checking for a page slug.
So I'm saying if the page slug is exactly this then return and then I'm just pointing towards my own
file that will be used as a template.
If this is not true, then just return the default template that WordPress would use for the current
U.
RL.
So this is similar to when we use the content filter, right.
You have a parameter that's sort of the incoming default or standard value and then you can return something
new to override that or customize it, or you can just return the default value.
So that's all this going on in terms of how I'm loading this custom template file for this particular
Eurail or slug.
Cool.
So that had nothing to do with databases, but it is a good strategy for loading templates that I want
you to be aware of anyways at this point.
Now, let's actually jump into our template file, so it's in the ANC folder and it's called Template
Dash Pets'.
OK, now how about right above the table?
So for me, that's around line number 19, right above the table.
Let's practice writing a query.
So right above the table, let's just drop into PHP within PHP.
Let's make sure that we have the Global Dollar Sign, WP, DB, make sure we have that available and
then I'll make up a variable name.
You can name it anything, but I'll just call it pets and set that to equal.
And then we're going to use dollar sign wp db look inside it for a function called git underscore results
semicolon.
Now in these parentheses we just give it a sequel statement.
So string of text and then it's exactly what we were just typing in admin.
So it would be select and that's all uppercase select, maybe all columns.
So asterisk from for now just to keep things simple, that's hard code the table name to underscore
Pets', but we can make this dynamic in just a little bit and then we'd say where and then do this with
me just for fun.
Let's say where species' equals single quote dog.
Finally, let's end it with limit all uppercase, just the first one hundred.
So the results of this query will then live in our pets variable.
So just to see that on the screen, then right below this, let's just use the P function called var
dump and just dump the results of dollar sign pets'.
Let's save that.
And if we refresh our template.
Cool, so I have an array with 100 items in it.
This first item has all the properties you would expect.
And if we look at the species dog, if we look at the next one.
Yep.
So our query ran.
We got the first one hundred dogs.
Now, before we go any further, we need to talk about security since we're writing our own SQL statements
now, instead of letting WordPress do its own querying through the WP query class, this means that
you and I need to be extra careful.
Maybe you've heard of things like sequel injection or just sequel attacks in general.
We want to be sure to avoid those.
And let's go back into our code so I can explain how this all works.
So this query or statement that we just wrote, this is obviously safe and not malicious because you
and I are not malicious and we wrote or hard coded every single character in this string.
So this is safe.
However, if we think about how we'd actually come up with queries in the real world, usually some
part of it is going to be dynamic.
So you and I just randomly decided that the species should be dog.
But in the real world, how would this choice or preference, how would that get from the website to
our database?
Well, it would usually be communicated through a JSON object, or probably most common is just to communicate
it through the user or address.
Right.
Something like at the end of this and be questionmark species equals dog.
The point is we want to build the query based specifically on what the user or visitor is looking for.
So we need to pull this value and use it.
And this is where the danger comes from because a malicious person could type something super malicious
right there.
So if we're going to potentially use that value dynamically in our query or in this statement string,
we need to be super careful.
And luckily for us, WordPress gives us a tool specifically for this in mind.
So whenever you're coming up with a skill statement and any part of it is going to be dynamic or from
a user generated or user input piece of text, well, we use a different WordPress function that will
generate the string and then we can pass that into get results.
So do this with Millet's Hollow out the parentheses for git results.
We'll fill in a value here in about 30 seconds.
But right above that line, let's create a new variable and make up a name of our query and set that
to equal dollar sign WP DB and we're going to use the function called Prepare.
This function won't actually go out to the database.
It's simply going to return a string of text and then we can feed that string of text into git results.
So let me show you how this function works.
We give it two arguments.
The first argument is your SQL statement, so let's give it a string of text and say select all columns
from WP Pets' where Species' equals, and then this is where it gets different.
So instead of single quotes dog, we just use a placeholder which is percent sine s four string.
And then let's close out the query with limit to the first.
Let's just try and maybe the first 10.
OK, and then for the second argument, instead of this placeholder B, we give it an array with the
actual values for the placeholders.
So instead of B, I'll say array parentheses and we'll just give it a value of, let's say, hampster.
So the idea here is that all of this text is perfectly, completely safe.
We can trust it because we wrote it.
And then anything that is potentially dangerous will live in this array of placeholder values that get
actually inserted into the text.
So altogether that will generate the string and then that's what we can use for git results.
So in these get results parentheses, we just say dollar sign our query, give this is save and test
it out.
So if I refresh, I should see ten hamster's so an array as a size of ten and the species is hampster
perfect.
And what if we only wanted hamster's where their birth year is greater than twenty eighteen.
Well back in our code instead of percent.
S as a placeholder for a string of text you can use percent D for a placeholder for a digit or number.
So right after that we could say we're species' equals that and where birth year is greater than percent
D and then in our array of actual values.
So Hampster comes first because that's the first placeholder and then the second value would just be
comma twenty eighteen if we give that a save and reload.
Perfect.
So hamster's with only a particular birth year.
OK, at this point let's change gears and let's actually try to begin using this data.
To populate the table down at the very bottom, right, we would just want to loop through the array
of results and output, one row in the table for each pet.
So back in our code, we don't actually need to query for the species in birth year.
I only brought that up.
So we had an example so I could show you the proper function as early as possible, because I want you
to get in the practice of being careful with the skill statements you're creating.
But for now, let's just put this back to pulling in the first 100 pets, regardless of species or any
other attribute, so we can get rid of this where blank and blank.
So just from this table and let's limit it to the first hundred.
And because we don't have any placeholder values, we don't even need the second argument with the array
of values.
But don't worry, in our next lesson, we will start using this again.
But for now, let's just pull in the first one hundred pets and let's also make the table name dynamic
because you don't want a hard code, the table prefix.
So maybe right above this line we can just say dollar sign table name equals and then dollar sign wp
db look inside that for prefix and then concatenate on pets and then we can just use this variable here.
So instead of WP pets it would be a dollar sign table name.
OK, in order to use a variable like this in the middle of a string, you do need to be using double
quotes instead of single quotes around our text.
OK, let's give this to save and test it out.
So hopefully that just loads an array with the hundred items.
Yep.
Perfect.
OK, so let's do this.
We can stop using var dump.
We don't need to output the raw data.
Instead we want to use this array of pets to actually populate our HTML table.
So let's keep this very first TR or table row.
It contains all of the labels but below that this next TR.
Well this is what we would want to loop through an output once for each pet so you can just temporarily
cut this table row into your clipboard and in its place.
Let's go into P inside of let's use A for each parentheses curly brackets in the parentheses, let's
say a dollar sign pets'.
Right.
We want to loop through our pets variable as dollar signs singular pet.
Now inside our curly brackets we would want to output HTML.
So what you can do is exit here, go back into here inside the curly brackets on this line.
Now we can just paste in our clipboard and now we would just use real dynamic values instead of these
dashes.
So for the first one I would go into PHP and echo dollar sign Pett look inside it for pet name and then
to save a lot of typing, I'm just going to copy this and paste it into these table cells or TDRS.
OK, and then the second one, instead of pet name would be species and then pet weight and then birth
year fave hobbit, fave color and fave food, if we give that a save and refresh, perfect.
And just to be clear, I do want to point out that because our statement is perfectly safe, we don't
even need to be using prepare.
We could literally just have this inside of our get results.
Right, because we're not using any dynamic or user generated values in our string.
However, I went ahead and left prepared in place because in our very next lesson, we're going to learn
how to take you RL parameters or arguments.
For example, if someone said question fave color equals green, well, we're going to learn how to
use these Eurail values to build out a dynamic query.
And in that case, we absolutely do want to use prepare.
I think it'll be an interesting lesson because it's fun to see our table sort of come to life and actually
start responding to different neutrals or parameters.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.