Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will complete our open registration and also learn how to customize the look and
feel and branding of the login screen.
Without further ado, let's get started.
All right.
Now, before we learn how to customize the login screen, let's first cover something that we probably
should have addressed in our previous lesson.
So if you view the website in a new private or incognito window where you are not logged in, you'll
notice that our login button doesn't do anything.
So for our first task in this lesson, let's go update the address value for the login button.
So over an hour, text editor, let's jump into header up and down towards the very bottom.
The first link we see within our else block is the login link.
So let's just go ahead and update its atrip value instead of a hash tag, let's say P, and we can just
echo out the results of a WordPress function named WP.
Log in.
You are out.
And while we're at it, we can also clean up the Eurail for the sign up link.
I know we just wrote this in the previous lesson and this will get the job done.
But instead of us manually pointing at a specific location instead within this block, we can just echo
out a WordPress function named WP Registration.
You are out in WordPress will take care of pointing towards the precisely correct location.
All right.
So we just updated the address for sign up and log in.
Let's go ahead and save that.
And now we can actually use this login button.
Cool.
Now let's change gears and learn how to customize this login screen.
The first thing that almost everyone wants to customize or change is the WordPress logo here.
You probably don't want to advertise for WordPress.
Instead, you want your company logo or at least text of your company name here.
Now, in just a few minutes from now, we will indeed learn how to remove this WordPress image.
But first, let's address the link value of this object.
So at the moment, if you hover over it, you can see down in the bottom left corner of my browser that
it wants to take me to WordPress, dawg.
So if I click on this logo, it takes us to the official WordPress website.
Now, obviously, that's not what we want.
We want our website to feel unique and one of a kind.
So instead, let's modify things so that if you click on this, it takes you to the homepage of our
website.
So let me show you how to do that over in our text editor.
Let's jump into functions dot, p, p and just to stay organized, let's scroll down to the very bottom
and add a new comment.
Customize login screen, OK?
And what we want to do is add a filter.
And this is a WordPress function that takes two arguments.
The first argument is the value or object that you want to customize or filter or change in some way.
In this case, the name of the WordPress filter hook that we're looking for is login under score header
you RL.
And then the second argument is just a function that returns whatever you want to use instead so we
can make up whatever name we want for a function.
Let's say our header you URL and then down on a new line, let's create a function with that exact name,
our header, you URL, parentheses, curly brackets and then we simply return and then you could manually
type out a U.
RL that you want to link to.
But instead, why don't we just return the results of a WordPress function named site.
You are URL and just point towards the home page or slash and just to keep things extra secure.
Why don't we escape this?
You are so rapid in escape.
You add the matching closing parentheses here.
OK, now if we save that now if I try to click on this header or logo here, cool.
It takes us to our homepage instead of the official WordPress dawg.
OK, let's move on to our next change.
At this point, you might be asking yourself, Brad, why would you bother showing us how to change
this, you R-AL, when we don't even want this WordPress image here at all?
Well, that's a good question.
But in reality, this is not an image file here.
So if I.
Right.
Click on the logo and.
Choose, inspect, we can see that that a or link element does not contain an inline image element.
Instead, WordPress uses a CSI as background image to display the WordPress logo.
So if you instead want to display your company logo or just plain text there, all you would need to
do is write a bit of success that targets the element that lives within a heading level, one within
the div with an ID of log in.
And right over here you can see that exact selector that the official WordPress code is using.
Now, again, this is not a course on success, so we're not going to write the CSFs by hand.
But what I do want to show you is how to load your own success on this login page in the first place,
because that can be a bit tricky.
So by default, WordPress is not going to load your themes CSC file on this login screen.
But it's very easy for us to tell WordPress to please start doing that.
Let me show you how to do that.
So over in our text editor, still within functions.
Let's out a new line down at the bottom and lets say add action.
And for the first argument, the WordPress event we want to hook on to is log in on queue.
I have the hardest time spelling that word correctly.
I always think I'm spelling it wrong, even if I'm spelling it correctly.
So I think that's right.
Anyways, logging on Q scripts.
And then for the second argument, we just make up a function name.
Why don't we call it our login success.
OK, then let's create a function with that exact name.
So function our login success.
OK, and now within the body of this function, there's no need to reinvent the wheel because earlier
in the course we've already written in this exact file a bit of code to load a or JavaScript file.
So within functions we can just scroll up and find our function named university files and the first
two lines of code in the body of that function.
Those are JavaScript files.
We don't need those.
But then these next four lines, these are all CSC files, right?
We have our custom Google fonts.
We have our font awesome icon pack, and then we have our two sixths files with the unique styling that
I've created for us.
So let's just take these four lines of code.
They're all the exact same WP on Q style.
Just select all four of these lines into your clipboard and then back down at the very bottom of this
file within our new empty function called our login access in the body of the function.
Just paste in your clipboard and now let's give this file a save.
You might need to refresh your login screen, but you can see it just received new fresh coat of paint.
So whatever it is that you want to customize, whether it's the background, color, the foreground,
color, the text or button color or anything, really even the padding or the font size or the font
family, the overall width of this box, whatever it is that you want to customize, all you need to
do is write success in your main theme folder style sheet that overrides the default WordPress styling.
So basically, whatever you want to customize just right, click on it, choose, inspect.
And then with that element selected over on the right hand side, you can scroll down and find the WordPress
styling.
So for example, these are the default blue colors that WordPress would have used for the login button.
And now all you need to do is write CSC that overrides this default selector that WordPress is using.
Now, again, this is not a course on success, but I will point you in the right direction if you want
to start making your own stylistic changes.
If you're looking for an idea of how to get started, just jump into your text editor and within your
theme folder, look in the next directory and then modules and then open up the file named Log in DOCSIS.
And here you can see an example of the selectors I'm using in order to override the WordPress defaults
and create my own styling here.
OK, now, before we bring this lesson to a close, there's one more thing I want to cover as of June
twenty twenty, this title here no longer says the name of your website and instead it says Powered
by WordPress, which is obviously not what we want.
So let me show you how to change that back in functions.
Let's add a new line and let's say add filter the name of the filter hook that I'm interested in.
Is in underscore header title and then for the second argument, let's just make up a name for a function,
maybe our login title, and then let's create a function with that exact name.
And then we just return a value of whatever we want so we could say quotes and then just spell something
out and that works well for a one off unique Web site.
But if instead you're building a theme that might be used by a lot of different sites, in that case,
what you want to do is fetch the official site name from the database.
So let's just return, get blog info.
And within the parentheses, the bit of info that we're looking for is name.
OK, so if I save that and jump back to the browser and refresh.
Perfect, and that's going to bring this lesson to a close at this point, now that we've created our
own custom log in and log out functionality, and now that we know a little bit about WordPress roles
and permissions, we are now in the perfect position to start giving our random stranger subscriber
accounts a few fun interactive abilities.
So in the next lesson, we are going to work on giving subscribers the ability to take notes while they're
in class.
Right from the front end of our website, they will be able to create or save a note as well as edit
an update or even delete their private notes.
This should be a really fun exercise for learning how to work with user specific content.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you then.