Hello, everyone.
Let's take a quick break from our project to answer one of the most common questions, and that is,
why do certain functions need to be echoed while other functions don't?
In order to understand the answer to this, let's write a couple of functions together right now.
So jump into your text editor and within your theme folder.
Let's open up index.
We're just going to write a bit of test code for educational purposes that we will delete in about five
minutes from now.
So it doesn't really matter where we type this, but I'm just going to open up a new area right below
the header, OK?
And now we can experiment.
So type this out with me.
Let's imagine we want to create our own brand new function, so function and let's call it double me
parentheses curly brackets.
And let's imagine that the purpose of this function that we are creating is that when you call it,
you give it a number and this function will double that number and give you the result.
So for example, below the function definition, when it's time for us to actually run and call the
function, we might say double MI five.
Right.
And we would expect that to generate 10.
Or if we said eight, we would expect it to generate sixteen.
OK, so let's go ahead and make that happen within the function definition.
So within these parentheses, we want a parameter that can receive the incoming number.
Doesn't matter what we call it, let's just call it dollar symbol X as a placeholder variable.
OK, and then in the curly brackets, in the body of the function, we can just echo out whatever number
that someone passes into this function.
Times two or asterisk to cool.
So now down below this function definition, we could say double me for right.
And we would expect that to echo out eight onto the page.
So if we save this and refresh the home page of our website, if I zoom in a bit there you can see the
number eight.
Cool.
And if we change this to twenty five save, we see the number fifty.
So that's an example of a function that we don't need to echo.
We just call the function and it echoes something out onto the page for us.
However, not all functions are like this.
Most functions, or I should say a lot of functions instead of echoing out there result, they return
their result.
So what does that mean?
What does return do?
It's basically a functions way of saying my work here is done.
I've done my job and now I'm returning this result or I'm returning this value.
So then down here, when we call or run the function and say double me twenty five, this will still
equal fifty P will evaluate this to be fifty.
However, we are not doing anything with that value of fifty.
In this case, it's just going to sit in memory and we aren't doing anything useful with it.
So if we save this and refresh, you'll notice that that value of fifty disappears up here.
So now it's up to us to actually do something with the value that this function returns.
Now there are a million different things we could do with the value.
Probably the most obvious example would be that we could echo it out.
So echo the results of double, maybe twenty five.
So now that will indeed show fifty again.
Now functions that return values like this are really nice because they're so flexible.
Right.
Because in the world of programming, there's a lot of things we need to do other than just echoing
out simple values.
So for example, we could create a variable magical number and tell it to equal double me ten.
Right.
So we aren't trying to echo anything on to the page.
We're just setting a variable to equal this value.
Or for another example, maybe we want to use that function as an if statement condition.
So, for example, we could say if double the twelve equals twenty four, then echo out onto the page.
The function is performing the math correctly.
Cool, so you get the idea this is not a real world example, you'd probably never do this, but the
idea is that you can use the value that a function returns anywhere.
Now, before we bring everything full circle and tie this back into the topic of WordPress specifically,
let's have a bit of fun first.
So right now, let's delete this if statement.
So we've still got our double function definition.
And right now, below this, let's create another brand new function named Tripple Me.
Instead of typing it out, we can just copy and paste this function.
So copy.
Paiste, let's change the name to triple me and then on this line, change this from times to two times
three.
OK, now below this, let's actually call and run these two functions together, because I think this
will really illustrate the power of functions that return values.
They're so flexible that they can fit together nicely.
So let's begin by saying Double MI five.
So that would be 10, but then we can wrap that within the triple MI function.
So then right before that we could say triple MI parentheses and the parentheses here.
So instead of just saying Triple MI 10, I'm trying to show you that you can use the value that a function
returns as an argument for another function.
So let's test this out by echoing it or outputting it onto the page.
If you triple 10, we would expect to see 30.
So save this refresh.
Cool.
And if I zoom in, you can see a value of thirty.
OK, now that's enough.
For the sake of P, let's tie this back in to WordPress.
So when it comes to the WordPress functions that we don't have to create, that we just get to leverage,
it can be a bit confusing whether a function is going to echo something for us or if it's just going
to return a value.
And so we need to echo it.
So let me show you a tip that can save you tons of confusion.
Back in the text editor, I will delete all of this sample code so that we can talk about WordPress
functions.
So, for example, WordPress has a function named the title, but it also has a function named Get the
title.
Also, there's a WordPress function named the IDE, but WordPress has another function named Get the
Idea.
So how do we make sense of this?
Well, there's a rule of thumb that if a WordPress function begins with the word git, that means it's
not going to echo anything for you.
It's just going to return a value and it's up to you to use that value however you see fit.
On the other hand, if a function begins with the word the.
That means WordPress will indeed handle echoing and outputting it onto the page for you.
Now, at this point in the course, I say we just leave it at that.
So I'm going to delete all of this test code from this lesson.
So I'm putting my index file back to the state that it was in before this lesson even began.
And moving forward, I wouldn't worry about preemptively memorizing every function and knowing exactly
what it does, because that's not how people work in the real world.
In the real world, you will Google in plain English terms, whatever you're trying to accomplish,
and WordPress with code.
And in the search results, you'll want to look for two main websites, codecs and developer, WordPress,
dot org.
These are the official WordPress websites and they have a wealth of information.
They will tell you exactly what a function does, how to use it, what arguments you can pass it.
And most importantly, it will tell you if the function returns something or outputs something for you.
Now, having said all of that, you don't need to go and do any of your own research at this point.
Relax, take a deep breath.
You're in this course for a reason.
It's my job to gradually introduce you to more and more WordPress functions.
And by the end of this course, with a little bit of repetition thrown in there for good practice,
you will have a rock solid understanding of what WordPress functions are at your disposal and what they
do.
I'm never a fan of preemptive memorization.
I'm big on practicing, experimenting and organically building up your understanding.
So long story short, even if you didn't understand everything in this lesson, one hundred percent,
I wouldn't worry about it because we're going to keep practicing these same concepts several more times.
Hopefully this lesson cleared up a bit of confusion.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.