Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to create an admin settings page, let's jump right into the action.
So this is a preview of the finished product of what we're trying to build right now.
We want to create a plug in that shows the word count, character count and the approximate read time
for a post.
However, a big part of what plugins do isn't just the feature that they bring to the table, but it's
also letting the user adjust settings and preferences.
So, for example, what if the owner of this site, they wanted the word count and they wanted to read
time, but maybe they did not want the character count?
Well, this is where a plug in setting screen or an admin setting screen comes into play.
So, again, this is a preview of the finished product that we're going to build together.
But if I jump into the admin dashboard and look under settings, there's something called word count
with various settings in the site.
Owner could just uncheck this box for character, count it, save changes.
And if you refresh on the front end, we no longer see the character count.
So all of that is to say that before we worry about actually counting the words and how long it would
take to read in the character count, and even before we learn how to save the user's preferences into
a database, let's first just worry about adding a settings or admin page at all.
Right.
So our very first task is simply to learn how to add a link in the admin settings menu to a new custom
page that we are creating.
So right now, let me switch over to this tab where I do not have the finished product and we can start
to move forward together.
Let's pick up where we left off in the previous lesson.
So we already had a new plugin folder opened up in VST code and inside our only file.
Let's keep the comment in the opening tag.
But everything below the comments, let's delete all of this and give ourselves a clean slate.
Let's begin by adding an action.
So add action.
Semicolon.
The name of the action that we want to hook on to is admin underscore menu.
Then the second argument is just a function that we give it.
So we need to create a unique function name that hasn't been used by any other plugin or by WordPress
itself.
Now, a bit later in this video, once we've actually set up the Settings page link, we can talk about
AP classes and that will allow us to avoid this coming up with unique function names challenge.
But for now, let's just come up with a unique name.
Let's name it our plugin settings link.
OK, now let's create a function with that exact matching name.
So function our plug in settings, link parentheses, curly brackets, OK, and now inside the body
of this function, what do we want to do?
Well, remember, our goal right now is to add a new page or link inside the WordPress admin settings
menu.
Right.
We want a new option to appear somewhere in here.
So within our new function we would just say add underscore options, underscore page, be sure to include
a semicolon.
OK, and now inside these parentheses, we need to give this five arguments.
So I'll just include one, two, three, four, five as placeholders.
And now let's talk about what we need to include here.
The first argument is the title of the page that we want to create.
So, for example, this would be used in the actual tab in your browser, just the overall document
title.
So why don't we say quotes, word count settings?
OK, the second argument is the text or title for the page that will be used in the settings menu.
Now you'll notice there's not very much horizontal space here to fit too many words.
So maybe instead of word count settings for this, let's just say word count, OK?
The third argument has to do with permissions or capabilities.
So this is basically saying what capability does the user need to have in order to see this page?
So this gets into user roles and permissions.
Do you want only your admins to be able to see this page?
Do you want your editors, your average users?
It's up to you, but I just want sort of administrative users to see this page.
So for this third argument, I'm going to say quotes manage.
Underscore options, so only if the current user has permissions to change options and WordPress, should
they be able to see this page?
OK, the fourth argument is sort of the slug or short name for this new page.
And even if we're going to be using AP classes a bit later in this video, we still need this short
namer slug to be unique.
Essentially, this is what will be used at the end of the Eurail for our new settings page.
So why don't we just say maybe word count settings page.
OK, and then the fifth and final argument is just a function that we give it and it will be that functions
job to actually output the HTML content that we want on the new page.
So for now, let's just make up a unique new function name.
I will call it our settings page HTML.
OK, and then let's just go create a function with that matching name.
So function our settings page, html parentheses, curly brackets, OK.
And then in this function instead of actually returning with the keyword return and then a string of
text instead of that, here's what we're going to do right after this opening curly bracket here.
Let's drop out of PHP and then right before this closing curly bracket here, let's drop back into HTTP.
So then right here we can just include regular traditional HTML.
Now a bit later, we can set up real HTML.
That will look nice.
But for now, just as a quick test, let's say hello world from our new plug in.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So within our admin dashboard, just hit reload to refresh and then let's scroll down, look in the
settings menu and there we see word count.
And if we click on it, there we see that HTML Hello World from our new plug in and also notice up in
the tab for your browser.
You see the full title, right?
Word count settings.
Now before we start to add a bit of real HTML here, let's first address the challenge of having to
come up with super unique function names, because I don't know about you, but having to come up with
names like our plug ins settings link and our Settings Page HTML.
That's not an enjoyable process for me, right?
Having to come up with these really long names to make sure that they're unique and that no other plug
in and that WordPress itself isn't already using it.
That can be a time waster.
And also it's just difficult to keep typing these names out throughout your code.
It would be nice if we could use names for our functions that are a lot simpler.
So this is where classes can help us out.
So let me show you what I would do right above this first add action line.
So just right below the comments, let's add a new line and say class that's lowercase and then we make
up a name.
Now, the class name does need to be unique itself, but the nice thing is that inside the class, none
of the properties or methods need to have unique names.
We'll see this in just a moment.
But let's come up with a class name.
How about word count and time plug in, OK?
Now, when you're creating a class, you do not have parentheses right after this like you would with
a function.
Instead, we just begin with curly brackets.
Let's drop down.
OK, now, inside here, this is where we sort of create a blueprint for an object, OK?
But then below this, we would want to instantiate or create a new instance of this class.
So just right here below the curly brackets, let's say new instance of word count and time, plug in
and parentheses to actually use the class semicolon as well.
Now, this would work with the new object just sort of floating in outer space.
But let me show you what I like to do at the very beginning of this line.
Let's create a new variable and let's just name it this exact same thing, but start it with a lowercase
letter.
So word count and time plugin equals so dollar sign for a variable.
This way, if any other plugins need to remove one of our actions or filters, they can actually get
access to our functions or methods that live inside our class.
Right.
They could use this variable and then look inside it.
At this point, let's circle back to what should go inside our actual class right here.
So in any time you create a new instance from a class, you will automatically call the function inside
the class that is named underscore, underscore, construct.
So let's create that function right now.
So inside this class function, underscore, underscore, construct, parentheses, curly brackets.
And now there's no one right or wrong way to set up a class.
But what I like to do is include any of sort of the top level actions or filters that we're adding.
I like to include those in the constructor, so let's just cut and paste this add action line.
Let's cut this to live inside our new construct function, so right here.
OK, so now when we create our new instance from this blueprint, this code will automatically run.
So now it's just a matter of moving our other functions to live inside our class.
So just select or cut and paste these two functions, cut those and now just add them right after the
constructor.
So right after this function, but still in the class.
So Paiste right here.
OK, and now we can sort of circle back to the whole reason we're even setting up a class in the first
place.
Now, we can have a very simple name for this.
So instead of this really long name of our plugins settings link, imagine if instead we just wanted
this function to be named admin page so we can just change that here.
Admin page.
OK.
And now the question is, how do you reference that up here?
It's not as simple as just changing this to admin page.
Instead, we need to use the callable syntax in PHP.
So here's what we do.
Get rid of this second argument here entirely.
And in its place we give it an array.
So array parentheses and we're going to give the array to arguments.
So ACN be as a placeholder.
The first argument is an object.
So in this case, we just want to point towards this class itself or this current instance of the class.
So we'd say dollar, sign this.
OK, and then the second argument is just the actual name of your method.
So that would be quotes, admin page.
And the whole idea here is that you can name this something very generic.
You don't need to worry about this creating a conflict with other plugins or with WordPress so we can
name this something short, generic, easy to type.
We don't need to worry about that conflict issue.
Let's do the same thing with this function.
Why don't we change its name to just be our HTML?
OK, so we change the actual function name then on this line towards the end of it where we are referencing
that function again, we would just get rid of this argument.
Instead of a string of text, we would give it an array, give it to arguments inside the array.
The first is just dollar sign this.
Right?
We're just sort of working with our class.
And then the second argument would be quotes our HTML.
OK, let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So if I refresh, cool, everything works exactly the same.
Only now we don't need to come up with these really long, unique names for our functions or methods.
Cool.
Now, before we bring this lesson to a close, let's adjust the actual HTML really quick just so that
it sort of looks like a real settings page.
So let's get rid of this hello world.
And instead I would begin with a div sort of a wrapper div and give it a class of rap.
We don't need to write any success for this.
WordPress will already take care of that on its own.
Now inside this wrapper div, let's just create maybe a heading level one again.
WordPress will sort of already have styling for that H1 and let's say word count settings.
OK, for now that's all we really need.
Let's go ahead and give that a save.
And if we refresh cool, you can see that gives us a bit of standardised spacing, a bit of standardised
typography and this is starting to look like a real settings page.
Now, let's circle back to what we're going to cover in the next video.
Remember, the whole point of this page is to let the site owner customize their settings and preferences
with regards to the word count statistics.
So look at the finished product.
We want to create a form that looks like this.
This looks identical to a default WordPress setting screen with sort of the two columns and then the
signature blue save changes button.
So that's what we're going to begin doing in the next lesson, adding a form right here together.
Let's keep the momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.