Hello, everyone, in this lesson, we will answer the question, what is an array?
So for starters, even outside the context of programming, we might hear a car dealership say that
a car is available in a wide array of colors.
OK, so let's think of an array as a collection.
Now, with that in mind, let's jump right into the code.
So here I am in the index file that lives in our theme folder.
And why don't we go ahead and delete all of this test code from our previous lesson and let's try something
new.
So if we think back to that first taste of lesson, you'll remember that we learned how to create a
variable.
So let's try that again.
So I will go into mode down here.
I will close out of mode.
And then to create a variable, you just use the dollar sign.
And maybe I want to create a variable that stores my name so equals Brad.
This variable name isn't special.
I just made it up.
It could be unicorn or pizza.
OK, but the idea here is that I'm setting this variable to have a value of Brad and now I can use that
variable anywhere else on the page.
So maybe down here, once I am back in HTML mode, I could create a paragraph that says Hi, my name
is and then maybe drop into mode so I can echo out that my name variable, OK, and then close out the
sentence with a period and then close out the HTML paragraph tag.
OK, so if I save that and test it.
Hi my name is Brad.
So this is an example of a very simple variable that only contains one single little bit of data.
Right, just one single name.
However, what if we wanted to store multiple names within a single variable?
So that's where arrays come into the picture.
So check this out.
Let's start over again.
So let's go into mode and let's imagine that I want to create a variable named names, right?
Plural.
Now, the name of the variable doesn't matter.
So this could be pizzas.
Doesn't matter.
I just chose names to try to indicate that I want to store multiple values.
Right.
Plural.
So what does our variable equal?
Well, we can say array.
OK, and now within these parentheses, right after the word array, we can store as many names as we
want.
So check this out.
I could say Brad, comma John, comma Jane, comma.
Miaows A lot.
You get the idea.
I can store as many names as I want.
So in an array is a special type of data.
An array is a collection of multiple values.
OK, and let's imagine that down here in HTML mode, I want to access one of these names.
So maybe I have an HTML paragraph tag and I want to say hi, my name is Blank.
Right, so I would drop into B to access our variable.
So I want to echo out something that lives in the names variable.
OK, and then to look inside the array or look inside the collection right here we can use square brackets
on your keyboard.
This is directly right of the key.
OK, now let's say, for example, that I want to access the first value in this array.
So, Brad, I would just include a zero within the square brackets.
You might think that it would be a one to access the first item, but it's actually a zero in most programming
languages included.
Arrays are zero based, meaning the first item is zero instead of one.
So, for example, if I wanted to access the second value of John, I would include a one here.
If I wanted Jane, a two.
If I wanted miaows a lot.
A three.
OK, so if I save this and refresh cool.
We say my name is miaows a lot.
If I change it back to a two.
Right.
So zero one two.
We should see Jane.
Cool, but now the question is why, why would we do this?
Why would we want to store multiple values in a single variable?
What is the point of doing this?
What is the advantage of doing this?
Well, there are several reasons, but probably the biggest reason is for something called looping.
So what in the world is looping?
What is a loop?
Well, let's imagine we want to do something once for each item in this collection.
So let's imagine we want it to output this sentence of hi, my name is Blank.
We wanted to do that once for each item in the collection.
So technically we could just copy and paste this line and have it four times and then change this to
zero.
One, two, three.
Right.
So if I save this, that technically works.
But this is terrible code.
This is really repetitive and it's just not an efficient way of doing things.
Instead, what we can do is leverage the power of an array and programmatically loop through the collection
and do something once for each item.
So check this out.
Let me show you what I mean.
But actually, before we worry about outputting these names, let's just practice a very basic loop
first.
So let's give ourselves a goal for whatever reason.
Let's imagine we want to output a bulleted list on the page that counts to 100.
Right.
So imagine we want to create an HTML list item in a series of them, something like this that goes one,
two, three, four, up to a hundred.
So it would take a long time to type that out by hand.
But programming and loops make that very easy to do.
So check this out.
Back up here.
While we are still in P mode, let's use something called a while loop.
So while parentheses and then right after that curly brackets.
OK, so how does the while loop work?
Well, whatever lives within the curly brackets will happen again and again and again until whatever
we place in these parentheses evaluates to false.
So let me show you what I mean right above this while loop, let's create a variable named count.
The name doesn't matter.
I'm just choosing count and let's set it to equal one.
Now, remember, our goal is to output a bullet hit list that counts to 100, so within our parentheses,
let's say that as long as the following thing is true, keep looping.
So in the parentheses will say, as long as our count is less than 100.
Keep doing whatever we tell it to do within these curly brackets.
So then in the curly brackets, let's just echo out an HTML list item, OK?
And in that list item, we don't want to hard code a value of one or two or three.
Instead, let's output our count variable.
OK, so we are saying that count begins with a value of one.
So then the first time that the while loop runs, this will echo out a one.
And then right after this line lets just increment or increase the count variable so we can say count
plus plus and that will add one to it.
So one plus one is two.
So now count equals two.
So then the while loop will run again and it will say, OK, now the count equals two, that's still
less than 100.
So this will evaluate to true.
So then this will run again.
So then it will output two, then it will add one to that.
Right.
So then count will equal three, so on and so forth.
So this will just keep repeating until finally count will equal one hundred and then the while loop
will say hey, 100 is not less than 100.
So then this will evaluate to false and then the while loop will finally end.
I know that's a lot to absorb, so you might need to watch this a few times or paused the lesson and
experiment with a while.
Loop yourself.
But if I save this and refresh cool.
We see a list that counts all the way o actually to ninety nine instead of 100.
So back in our code, let's just change this to less than one hundred and one.
Cool, so now it counts all the way up to 100.
All right, so now that we've seen a relatively simple while loop in action, let's try something a
tiny bit trickier.
So let's delete the while loop and our count variable and let's get back to the task at hand.
Remember, we want to loop through our array of names and do something once for each item in the collection.
So maybe output a sentence that says, hi, my name is blank.
All right.
So here's how we can do that.
Let's use a while loop again.
So while parentheses and then curly brackets, OK, and we are going to need a count variable again,
so let's create a variable and name it count and this time let's set it to equal zero instead of one.
Right.
Because arrays are zero based in order to access the first item in the array, we use a zero.
OK, so down in our while loop within the curly brackets, what we want to do for each item in the collection
is just echo out an HTML list item that says Hi, my name is blank.
OK, so we remember from about five minutes ago in order to access one of these items, we just use
the variable name, right?
They all live in the variable of names.
And then to look inside the array, you use square brackets.
So to access the first item, it's a zero.
To access the second item, it's a one.
OK, so we don't want a hard code, a number here.
Instead, we want to use our account variable.
So in between the square brackets, let's just say count.
OK, so the first time the loop runs, it will be a zero and then let's be sure to increment the count.
So on the new line, let's say count plus plus.
So then the next time the loop runs, count will equal one.
So that will give us John, then it will increment again to two, which will give us Jane.
You get the idea.
So now we just need to tell the while loop how many times it should repeat itself.
Right.
So within these parentheses, we will say as long as the following thing is true.
So let's say as long as count is less than.
And now you might think that we would just say four.
Right.
Because there are four items in the array.
But we don't want a hard code, a number here, because what if in the future we added a fifth name
to the collection barks a lot.
OK, so we don't want to have to babysit this code and keep updating this number here.
So instead, what we can do is have we count the number of items in the array for us.
So we'll say as long as count is less than and then we can use the P tool named Count and then open
up a pair of parentheses, OK?
And then in those parentheses we just give it the name of our variable names is the variable that contains
the array.
So we will automatically count it and say, yep, there are five items in the array.
So as long as count is less than five, this will just keep happening again and again and again.
So let's save this and refresh.
Awesome.
Now, if this is not your first time programming and you've worked with arrays before, you might be
yelling at the screen right now saying, Brad, why on earth would you use a while loop here when you
could have used a for each loop?
Well, that's a great question with an even better answer.
I want us to be familiar with the while loop, because that's what WordPress uses to loop over real
content like posts and pages.
Right.
So instead of this hypothetical worthless list of names here, imagine if we had an array or a collection
of blog posts and we wanted to loop through those blog posts and display them on the front end of our
website for our visitors.
Well, that is exactly what we are going to do in our very next lesson.
It's probably going to be the most fun we've had in the course so far.
Let's keep it rolling and I will see you then.