Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to learn about the settings API in WordPress, let's jump right into the
action.
So currently this is what our settings page looks like.
This area where we would want a form is currently empty.
Now, remember, this is the finished product of what we want it to look like.
And in terms of moving forward here, I think the best way to understand things is to actually look
at the end and then work backwards.
What I mean by that is our real goal here is just to permanently save the user's preferences into the
database.
So let's begin by looking at the WordPress database and seeing where it stores settings and option values.
So how do we look at our database?
Well, if you're using the local WP or local buy a flywheel application, just click on the current
site that you're running.
And then in this area you'll see a database tab.
You can click on that and then just click on this open add mynor button.
Once you click on that, it should open a new tab that looks something like this, and this is the database
for your WordPress website.
Over here we see the different tables.
The one that I want to draw attention to right now, though, is called options.
So let's click onto that options table.
And then instead of just showing the structure for the table, let's click this select data link.
Cool.
So this is where WordPress stores all of your preferences, your settings and options.
It's pretty simple.
This column option name.
You can just look through these and it's self-explanatory, right?
Your site URL, the name of your site, the description.
And if you scroll through this list, you'll see that most of them are a little bit self-explanatory.
And then this column is just the value.
So really, all we're trying to do with our plug in right now is just create a new row in this database
table.
Right.
So instead of site you URL or blog name or blog description, we would want a new row where the option
name is perhaps display location for word count or word count, show word count or word count, show
character count or word count show read time.
Right.
We're just trying to create a new option.
And then in the value column, this option underscore value.
That's where we would just store, for example, whatever the user types in here, their preferences
for each of these fields.
So that is our end goal from here.
We're just going to sort of work backwards and see how we get here.
Right.
How do we end up getting the user's preferences from an HTML form?
How do we get from the form into the actual database?
So let's jump back to our empty example, where we're going to build things together and let's get started.
Let's jump back into our text editor and within the construct function in our class, let's just add
a new action.
So right here, let's say add action.
Sure.
To include the semicolon and the name of the action hook is admin underscore Annet.
OK, comma, the second argument.
Well, we haven't created a new function yet, but let's just point towards a function or I should say
a method, and then we can create it in about ten seconds from now.
So an array the first argument is dollar sign this comma.
The second argument.
Well, we just get to make up a simple name for the method.
I'll call it settings.
OK, now let's just create a function with that name.
So right below the constructor function we can just say function settings, parentheses, curly brackets.
And now let's talk about what I want to do in this function.
So before we worry at all about the HTML that we're going to output for the form, we first just need
to register the settings or the fields.
Right, that we want to store in the database.
So within here, let's use the WordPress function called register underscore setting.
OK, inside these parentheses, we're going to give it three arguments.
So one, two, three as placeholders.
OK, now we're going to use this register setting function once for each of the options.
So you can see overall we're going to have about one, two, three, four, five options.
So ultimately we're going to use this five times.
But for now, let's just register the very first setting, which will be the display location.
Right.
Do you want the word count post statistics to be at the start of the post or at the end of the post?
OK, so let's talk about these three arguments.
The first argument is actually the name of the group that this setting belongs to.
So let's call it you could call it anything, but let's call it maybe word count, plug in.
We'll see where this name comes into play a little bit later in the video.
Let's move on, though.
So this second argument, this is the actual name for this specific setting.
Right.
So in terms of asking the user the display location, do you want to at the beginning or the end, you
can name this anything you want, but maybe I'll name it WCP.
I'm just making this up short for word count, plug in and then maybe underscore location.
OK, the third argument is an array with several different options.
So let's give it an array, OK?
And then inside this array, we want to give it to properties, a sanitized callback.
So how we want to either sanitize or validate the value and then also a default value.
So if no value exists in the database yet, what do we want to sort of consider the standard or default
answer to be?
So let's just say quotes sanitize.
Underscore callback.
And then the arrow symbol, right, so equal sign greater then and let's just set that to underscore,
sanitise, underscore text, underscore field.
OK, then have a comma and then we just need one more property, which is default and arrow symbol.
And let's just say that it has a default value of zero.
Right.
So you could store anything you want in the database.
If we look at the options table again, you can store a string of text, you can store a serialized
array so we can store whatever we want for that option.
We could store a string of text that says display at the beginning or display at the end.
But in terms of being efficient and not storing more data than we need, I would probably just, you
know, are with our own logic, say that zero can mean display at the beginning and a value of one can
mean display at the end.
But that's totally personal preference.
Also, before we move on, I do want to let you know that this value of sanitized text field, this
is just a standard function in WordPress that will sanitize a user's input value.
For us, it's sort of a generic WordPress sanitize tool that I like to use.
In our next video, we'll learn how we can supply a custom function name here and write our own sanitized
function.
So not only for sanitisation, but if we want to validate an option.
Right.
For example, what if we want to make sure that the number is only zero or one and that the user doesn't
somehow enter too or a word?
So we can learn more about sort of custom validation in the next video.
But for now, this just gives us sort of debate in standard WordPress sanitisation.
OK, let's go back to the beginning of this line.
So we registered our setting.
So this gives WordPress the info that it would need to store value in the database.
But now we need to tie things back in to our HTML form.
So let's do this right above this register setting line.
Let's add a new line and say add underscore settings, underscore field semicolon here.
Now, the job of this function is to sort of begin to build out the HTML input field for our form.
So we're sort of tying HTML to this setting that we just registered.
So within these parentheses here, we're going to give it five arguments.
So let's add some placeholders.
The first argument is the name of the option or setting that we want to tie this to.
So basically the name that we registered right here, we chose WCP, underscore location.
So that's our first value.
The second argument is the HTML label text.
So what the users will see on the front end, let's say quotes display location.
The third argument is a function that's responsible for actually outputting the HTML.
So this is really nice.
We can include our own custom HTML, which is very flexible.
So instead of this three placeholder, let's give it an array.
First argument is dollar sign this comma.
The second argument is just a function or method name that we get to make up.
Let's call it location.
HTML will actually create this function in just a moment, but let's keep going through these arguments.
So the fourth argument is the page slug for this settings page that we're working with.
So back up in the address bar.
Remember, we chose word dash dash settings page back in our code.
We chose that value when we added an options page.
And remember, we chose a value of word count settings page for the slug of this page.
So you can just copy that.
And then that is the fourth argument where we were just working.
OK, and then the fifth and final argument is the section that you want to add this field to, we haven't
created any sections yet.
We will in just a moment.
But let's just make up a name.
How about WCP for word count, plug in, maybe underscore first section.
Now, let me pause for just a minute and say that I am well aware at this point in time this code is
not very intuitive and it's sort of hard to see how all of these puzzle pieces fit together.
And there's all these different options and functions and things are a bit cloudy.
Or at least I know the first time that I worked with this API, I thought it was cloudy and confusing.
However, we're almost getting to the point where everything sort of connects and we can begin to see
things take shape visually right here.
And I think once we get to that point, this will all start to make a little bit of sense.
That's just my way of saying if things are confusing right now, that's OK.
That's to be expected.
However, we just chose this name for a section.
Let's go ahead and create that section now.
So right above this line that we were just writing, let's say add settings section semicolon in these
parentheses, we're going to give it for arguments.
So the first argument is the name of the section.
So we chose WCP first section.
The second argument is the title for the section.
Now you can include a subtitle for each section.
For example, if your settings page was going to have three different sections, you could have a subtitle
here, subtitle here, subtitle here.
I don't really want a subtitle.
So while we do need to include this argument, if you don't actually want a visible subtitle, you can
just make this be a value of Nole.
OK, and then a similar thing is going on with the third argument.
The third argument allows you to have a little bit of content towards the top of a section.
So instead of a sub headline, you could have maybe a paragraph of text, just sort of any generic HTML
content you want.
Now, again, I don't really want any content.
So while we do want this argument, I'm just going to give it a value of no.
OK, and then this fourth and final argument, this is the page slug that we want to add this section
to.
So, again, if you're ever confused what that would be, it's up in the address bar on your page.
So it's word count settings page, or at least that's what I chose.
So that's why I'm going to use here quotes, word count, settings, page, OK.
And before we actually start to tie things together and output in HTML form, let's just create this
function that we said we would create.
Right.
We said that our class should have a method named location HTML.
So let's create that really quick.
Right below this function.
We can just say function, location, html, parentheses, curly brackets.
And now where the cursor is, I want to include HTML.
So what I like to do is just drop out of PHP right here and then before the ending curly bracket you
can just go back into PHP.
OK, and right here, we would actually include perhaps an input field or a text area, but just so
we can actually see things take shape in the browser for now, let's just output the word hello and
then we can circle back to the HTML.
OK, now we're finally to the point where we can slowly start to have things make sense and we're going
to connect all the dots now.
So let's scroll down and we're looking for our overall our HTML function.
Remember, we set this up at the end of our last lesson, and right now it's just outputting that wrapper
div with an H1, right?
That's all we see here.
So this is where we just actually start to build out the HTML form.
So below the heading level one, let's have a form tag.
If you're using VTS code, you can just type form and then hit tab for the action.
Let's give it a value of options.
Dot p p.
WordPress will know what to do with this.
That's all we need to say.
Let's also give it an attribute of method and set that to equal post.
OK, now inside the HTML form, this is where things are pretty cool.
We don't need to spell out very much.
WordPress will do a lot of this for us.
So check this out.
We just drop into P and we drop down and then exit again.
But inside here mode, we're just going to say do underscore settings, sections, semicolon.
In these parentheses, we just give the slug of our settings page.
So again, remember up in the address bar for me it's word count settings page, OK, WordPress will
automatically look through any sections that have been registered.
And remember, we added that one section called First Section and we tied it to this same page.
So WordPress will see this and it will automatically loop through the sections and the fields for us
that we registered.
Then right below this, let's have the signature looking WordPress Blue Savours submit button so we
just can call a WordPress function called submit button parentheses to call it semicolon.
Let's give this a save and see what it looks like.
So if we refresh our page, cool.
So we only have one field.
So it's not very impressive.
But the idea is that WordPress will automatically generate the HTML for us.
Right.
Or this column is your label and then this column is the actual input field and then we have the signature
looking blue button.
Now remember, we just set this to be hello as a quick test.
So instead, let's go back right now and change this to be a dropdown write in HTML select form element.
So back in our text editor, we're just looking for this location HTML function instead of hello, let's
have a select element so you can just type, select and hit tab and vs code.
We do not need it to have an ID, but we do want it to have a name that matches the setting that we've
registered.
So remember sort of the variable name that we gave that setting was WCP underscore location.
So that's what we want this name to be.
WCP underscore location.
OK, inside the select, let's have one option you can type option here tab give it a value of zero,
but then the actual text that the user sees would be the beginning of post set dropdown use type option
again hit tab.
Give it a value of one.
But what the user will actually see is end of post.
OK, let's go ahead and save that and then if we refresh.
Cool.
Now if we tried to actually select end of post, I will warn you when we click save changes, we're
going to run into some errors so you can see all sorts of errors here.
Let me show you the solution to this.
The reason this failed is because we're missing one line of code.
So just navigate right back to your word count setting screen like this and let me show you what to
fix down in our overall our HTML function, right where we have our wrapper, Dave.
And the heading level one in the form tags right before this do setting sections line.
Let's add a new line and we just say settings underscore fields', semicolon and we just give it the
name of the field group that we chose earlier.
So remember when we registered our setting, we made up a group name of word count plug in.
So that's what we would use here, quotes, word count plugin.
And what this is going to do.
WordPress will do all of the hard work for us.
It's going to see this and then add the appropriate hidden HTML fields with the nonce value, the action
value, it's going to handle sort of the security and permission aspects for us.
So just by including this, if we save.
And reload the page now, if we try to set this to end of post and hit save, it actually worked and
we see settings saved.
Now, we don't see that value here.
And that's because we didn't program that select HTML that we just wrote to actually pull the current
value from the database to change this.
Right.
So that when you refresh, you actually see the most current value in the database.
We can set that up in the next video.
I don't want this lesson to go on for too long, but to make sure that things actually worked, all
we need to do is look at our database.
So remember back in this tab where you can look at your WordPress database in the options table, you
won't see it if you just scroll down.
And that's because you need to go to the very last page.
Depending on your WordPress site and how many plug ins you've installed, you might have five, 10 or
even 15 or 20 pages of different options.
But just click on to the final page.
And down at the very bottom, perfect, we see an option named WCP location, and it has a value of
one, right?
And that was the final value that we associated with end of post.
Cool.
So we are well on our way to building a fully functional setting screen.
Now that we've got these basics out of the way, we can start to move a lot faster in our next lesson.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.