Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to build dynamic queries, let's jump into the action.
So in our previous lesson, we set up this template that pulls in the first 100 pets.
However, now we want to be able to go up into the address bar and say maybe questionmark species equals
dog.
And we want our template to react to this data and then only show dogs in the table.
Now, setting this up for the most part, has nothing to do with WordPress or sequel.
This is really just an exercise in dynamically building a string or concatenating together a string,
because essentially we're just taking values from the incoming Eurail and then pasting together a string
of text.
That's a skill statement.
In other words, because we're not truly learning anything about WordPress or sequel, I'm going to
move very quickly in this lesson.
But this should be a good example of how you could set something like this up.
Having said that, let's get started.
So within our IAC folder, in our template pets' file, we've already written the IP that loads the
first 100 pets.
Now, this only took five or six lines of code, so I didn't mind including that right here within the
HTML.
But now that we need to dynamically generate a much more complex query where we say where species' equals
blank and favourite colour equals this.
And we'll also need to build the array of placeholder values for prepare, so on and so forth, because
this is going to require more code.
You don't need to do this, but I actually want to keep it in a separate file so that this file can
really just be about the HTML.
So here's what I would do.
Select these four lines of code and the here and just cut that into your clipboard.
We can get rid of this block and then maybe up at the very top of this file, when we first drop into
PHP, I would just say require once plug in Dürer path, use the file constant and then concatenate
on and I'll call the file, maybe get pets.
We haven't created this file yet.
We'll create it in just a moment.
But in that file I'll have a class.
So that way inside the class I can use whatever simple function names I want without worrying about
those names, conflicting with anything.
So then on the next line I would just say lowercase git pets' equals a new instance of our pets class.
OK, then before we go, create this new file really quick.
If we go down into our table HTML where we're looping through each pet, well, we would just change
the array that we're looping through to B get pets and look inside that get rid of that dollar sign
for a property called Pets'.
So when we go create that class, we'll just make sure that it has a property named Pets'.
That is the array of results.
OK, but everything else here can stay the same.
So let's save this.
And now within our I n c folder, I'll just create a brand new file and name it get pets' p in this
way, this new file.
This is responsible for building the query and talking to the database and this file can just be our
overall HTML template.
So in our new empty file I would go into PHP.
I'll create a class and get pets' curly brackets inside.
There I'll have a function with the exact name of underscore, underscore, construct, parentheses,
curly brackets just to get started within the function.
Let's paste in our clipboard and for now all we would need to change is this line.
So instead of creating a variable called Pets', we can just say sign this Dasch greater than to create
a property and name it pets.
And now the template that's including this file should have everything it needs, right?
Just this pets' property so we can save this and test it out.
Make sure you save your template file as well.
And if we refresh the front end, perfect.
Nothing's changed.
Now, before we worry about making our query builder truly dynamic so that it could handle things like
species' equals dog and fav color equals green and min wait equals twenty and max weight equals fifty.
Before we worry about how to handle all of these things, let's first just sort of hard code things
where we do pull in the dynamic value for Species'.
Once we have that up and running, then it will be clear what we need to do.
So here's what we can do back in our pets.
P We would just adjust this statement to be select all columns from our table name after table name.
We'd say where species' equals percent string or two percent s as a placeholder.
And then remember how the.
Repair function works, you give it a second argument, so after our quotes, there exists a comma and
then you give it an array with your actual placeholder values that you want to substitute in.
So right here, we would want this to be dog or cat or whatever value the visitor has specified four
species equals.
So to access that in and it's just dollar sign, underscore gett because it is a request, not a post
request, and then square brackets and then just look inside it for species.
Now the proper function will escape our code from a school perspective.
But in the real world, I would probably run this through a generic sanitized function as well.
We'll get to that in just a moment.
But for now, this is a quick example.
We can go ahead and save that.
And if we refresh, cool, now we're only getting dogs or you can change this to hampster.
Perfect.
You get the idea.
So now that we have things sort of up and running and you see the general idea of you give prepare a
second argument with the actual values from the euro.
Now we need to take a step back and think about how to make our query builder truly dynamic.
Right.
So that it could handle something like Species' equals Hampster and Minne weight equals twenty and max
weight equals 70.
We need some way to loop through all of the available arguments and then build a string of text.
Also, in addition to this one SQL statement, we'll also want to send off another.
That is just the overall count because we're displaying the first 100 matching results.
But what if our query finds 500 results?
We would want to display that right here on the website.
Found X number of results showing the first X.
So to get started, let's write sort of a skeleton or pseudo code of the overall big picture steps.
Then we can go through and sort of actually build the methods that take care of each responsibility.
Let's actually get rid of this line entirely.
So this line where we're calling prepare, I will just delete that entirely.
Instead on this line when we're calling, get results inside these parentheses instead of our query,
I would just feed it.
Well, whatever the prepare returns for dollar sign wp db look inside it.
Call prepare.
We know we're going to give prepare to arguments.
The first is the query string text that we need to build.
The second is our placeholder values.
Let's actually start with the placeholder values because that's super simple, right?
It's just an array of the incoming values.
So here's what I would do above that line.
First, I would probably create a property on this class or object that just stores and sanitizes all
of the incoming you oral arguments.
So I would say dollar sign this, create a property named ARGs, you could name it anything and say
that that equals.
And then I want to keep this area just big picture, this sort of the steps that I'm taking.
I don't want any actual complex code here.
So I'll create a method that's responsible for creating this and we can write that method in just a
moment.
For now, though, let's just point towards a method that doesn't even exist and we can call it git
args.
So in this method we will just pull everything from the Eurail, sanitize it, so on and so forth.
Once we have those sanitized arguments, then on a new line, I'd probably just have another property
on my class called placeholders and I would just set that to equal.
And then again, we can have a method that's responsible for building that array.
So I would just say this call a method, maybe create placeholders.
OK, so now down on this line, we know that this second argument that would just pull in are placeholders.
So instead of the B, I would just say sign this, look inside it for placeholders.
OK, and now let's talk about this first arguments.
And this is the actual string of text.
That is the school statement we're trying to build.
So right about here, I would just create a new variable.
It doesn't need to be a property on our class because I know I'm not going to need to access it from
with any of our methods.
So for just a simple variable, just dollar sign and only query equals a string of text semicolon.
And now this is the one part of the string that we can hard code.
Right.
Which is select all columns from dollar sign table name.
And then we know that there should be a space after that.
But that's it.
That's all we can hard code.
Everything else in our query needs to be dynamic.
Now what comes next in the query?
This is where you would normally say upper case, where blank equals blank.
So here's what I would do on a new line.
I would just say dollar sign query dot equals this is how you can add on to an existing value.
So I want to add on to the end of this string and then I'll just have a separate.
Method, whose only job is to generate the where species equals this, where favorite color equals percent
s, so on and so forth.
So I'll look inside the class and we can name that method.
Maybe create where texts.
OK, after that I will add on something else.
So query dot equals and what I'll add on is a space and then limit 100 semicolon and that's it.
So all of that together will create a string that we can use right here.
So instead of the a placeholder we would just a dollar sign query.
Now that we have sort of the big picture spelled out, let's just start building these methods one by
one.
So let's start with get args.