Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will continue to work on our campus post time.
OK.
Up in the header, let me click on the campus's archive link.
And in our previous lesson, we created this interactive Google map where visitors can zoom around and
scroll around.
And we pinned on the map locations for each of our campus posts.
Remember, this is the post that has a title of downtown West.
And this is the post that has the title of downtown East now in its current state.
This map isn't very useful for visitors because if you click on a pin, nothing happens.
So our goal in this lesson is to set things up so that if a visitor clicks on one of the pins, it pops
up a little bit of info with the name of the campus, maybe the address.
And if you click on the title of the campus, it will take you to the permalink detailed screen for
just that one individual campus post.
OK.
So if we want to customize this screen, we need to jump over to our text editor.
So over in our theme folder, let's jump in to archive campus.
Here's the while loop that outputs this H.T. email once for each post.
So remember that our JavaScript code is looking at these data attributes of data latitude and data longitude.
And the JavaScript is also going to look inside the div for any content that we want to use for a pop
up.
Right.
So check this out in between the opening div tag in the closing days of tag.
So right here, if we say hello.
One, two, three.
As a test.
Now, when I click on one of the pind locations, we see.
Hello, one, two, three.
So instead of hello.
One, two, three.
Why don't we output maybe the title of the post.
And then also the street address.
So let's delete.
Hello, one, two, three.
And maybe create a heading level three headline for the title of the post.
And within the H three tags.
Let's drop in to BHP and just call the title.
And just to stay organized, we could drop down to a new line right before the beginning H3 tag and
then right after the H3 tag, we could also dropdown.
OK.
So now underneath the heading level three, we can output the street address for the campus.
So to do that, let's go back into BHP and let's echo out a property that lives within our map location
variable.
Right.
This variable gets all of the information associated with the pin, the location on the map.
From this custom field.
So down here, let's echo out map location, that variable.
But let's look inside it.
So square brackets to look inside the array.
And just like we did up here for latitude and longitude.
Now we can do the same thing with a dress to get the street address.
Okay.
Let's go ahead and save this and refresh.
The front end.
So now if I click on downtown west right here.
Cool.
Perfect.
So now let's just take things one step further and set it up so that you can click on the title to go
to that individual detail screen.
So here's our heading level three.
Let's just wrap the text in an A tag to create a link.
And on the opening one, a draft equals.
And then we just want the permalink.
So go into BHB, the permalink.
Click on downtown West and the titles got an underlined indicate that it's a link.
Let's go ahead and click it.
Cool.
And we're on the permalink.
The only issue is that this template is designed for blog posts and not campuses.
So in order to create a unique, detailed view for campuses, let's just create a new template file.
So in our theme folder, let's create a brand new file.
And we need to name this new file, single dash campus dot p HP.
And in order to save a ton of typing, why don't we use the single dash program file as our guide or
starting place?
So I'm going to go into single program and just copy the entire thing into my clipboard and then back
in the new single campus.
Let's paste that in.
And then let's scroll up to the top and just start customizing this for a campus.
So for example, the first thing that I want to change is this breadcrumb or meta info box.
So instead of all programs, it should probably say all campuses.
So here's that text.
Let's change that to all campuses.
And let's also change the H graph for that link.
So get post type archive link for campus instead of program.
So now if we click this, it takes us back to the campuses archive.
Cool.
Let's go back to downtown West.
Why don't we customize this area a bit?
So first, why don't we pull in a map with Just Dippin for this one campus location?
So back in our text editor right underneath this div with a class of generic content and where we're
outputting the WordPress, the content function right below this div.
Let's add a new line and instead of typing everything out again, we can just go back into archive campus
and we can just copy and paste this code.
So let's begin from the beginning of this div with the class of HCF map.
So let's begin selecting there.
And then let's just select all the way down.
Oh, actually, before we copy and paste this, I see a mistake.
We can fix.
So on this campus archive screen, we don't need to echo out any pagination links.
So let's actually delete that.
And then these two P P tags can sit on the same line.
OK.
Much better.
So now we can get back to copying and pasting.
So let's copy from the beginning of this div down to this closing div right after the ending BHP tags.
Let's copy that into our clipboard.
And then back in single campus right underneath the main the content div.
Let's just paste it in.
Except this time we don't need any of this while loop code because we're already on the single permalink
for just the one campus.
So let's just delete this opening block of BHP and then we can also delete this closing while loop curly
bracket.
Perfect.
Give that save refreshed individual downtown west screen.
Woops.
Looks like we're out in the middle of the ocean.
I think I know what's causing this problem.
So when we just deleted that opening while loop code, I also accidentally deleted the code where we
created the variable named map location.
So let's do this.
We could add a new line in between these two lines or even just right up here.
It doesn't matter where we do this, but let's drop into P HP and let's just create a variable named
map location.
Right.
So all of this code will work.
And let's set it to equal get field and the field name that we're looking for is map underscore location.
OK.
So with that variable back in place, let's save this and we should no longer be in the middle of an
ocean.
Cool.
So now that we're on the individual screen for just one post or campus, if someone clicks on the pin,
it makes sense to show this information.
But we no longer want this to be a link, right.
Because it would just be linking to the page that someone is already on.
So let's just go ahead and remove the A tag that's wrapping that text.
Perfect.
Now, I can no longer click on the title.
It's not a link.
OK.
Now, before we bring this lesson to a close, I also think it would be neat if on this template for
each individual campus, if we had a section right about here that said programs available at this campus.
Now, in order to create a relationship between a program and a campus, we're going to need to create
a new custom field.
So right now, let's jump into the admen.
And down at the bottom of the sidebar, let's click on Custom Fields.
Let's create a new group.
So add new let's name this new group related campus.
Or you could put.
Yes, in parentheses, right.
Singular or plural is up to you.
Let's go ahead and add a field.
Let's name the field related campuses.
But for the actual variable name or short name for the field, let's get rid of those parentheses.
So just related campus.
So it's easier to remember and type can than here's the important part for field type instead of text.
Let's set it to relationship.
After that, let's set this filter by post type two.
Only use campus under filters.
I'm going to uncheck everything except the search box.
Let's scroll down to the location box.
So show this field group.
Only if post type is equal to.
And let's set this to program.
OK.
Now let's scroll back up to the top and published this new field group.
And let's go test it out and take it for a spin.
So let's go into programs and let's say that the math program is available at the downtown west campus.
So if we scroll down, we see that new custom field related campuses.
Let's click on downtown West.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and update or save this.
And now let's just go back to our downtown west single view.
Front end campuses click on to downtown west.
And now let's just right the BHP code to output a headline here that says programs available at this
campus.
And then we can write a custom query to pull in any applicable programs.
So let's jump back into the text editor.
Here's that map code that we modified just a moment ago.
Now, because we created this single campus file by duplicating single program, you'll notice that
right below this map code, we have a few extra custom queries left over from the program template.
So we've got this related professor's query.
And then below that, we've got code that checks to see if it's empty or not.
And then it outputs an H2 accordingly.
So what we can do now is just modify this.
Instead of looking for related professors, we can look for related programs.
Right.
And that will save us a lot of typing.
So let's change the variable name to related programs.
Let's modify this query.
So posts per page looks good post type.
Let's change this to program instead of professor.
Order by an order.
Look.
Okay.
We do, however, need to modify this meta query.
So for the key instead of related programs, let's change this to related campus.
Cool.
So altogether we're creating this new query.
We're saying give us any program posts where the related campus contains the I.D. of the current campus
that we're viewing.
OK.
So we've got our custom query.
Now, let's just use it in this code, that output stuff onto the page.
Remember that we renamed our query variable from related professors to related programs.
So let's update that here.
Then let's also update it here and here as well.
They did programs and related programs.
OK.
Let's first adjust this heading level two that we're echoing out.
Only if there are indeed related programs to show.
So originally this would say math or English.
And then professors in this case, we just want to say programs available at this campus.
So we can just delete everything inside the H2.
So now we've just got one string of H.T., AML.
And then inside the H.
Two programs available at this campus.
OK.
And then within this while loop, we don't want to output a professor card for each item.
Right.
Instead of that, let's just output a plain text link to a program.
So let's delete this class on Ally.
Let's just have a regular ally.
And then also the element.
It doesn't need a class either.
We don't need to output an image.
So we can delete this image element entirely.
And then we don't need a Spann element.
We can delete that.
And we don't need the closing span tag.
Move this up on to the same line.
So basically, we just have a list item with a link in it with the title that points to the permalink.
And then before we save this, let's change the UL class.
Right.
All of these list items will live within.
Instead of professor cards, let's just change this to mean dash list and link Dasch list.
That will give us appropriate CSF styling.
OK.
Let's go ahead and save that.
And now if we scroll down underneath the map, we see programs available at this campus, math.
And if we click on it, perfect, it takes us to that screen.
Now, we do want to make sure that that relationship flows in both directions.
So maybe at the bottom of a program page, we should have a section down here that says this program
is available at these campuses.
Right.
So to set that up, the template file that controls this screen is single dash program.
So in our text editor, let's jump into a single program and let's scroll down to the very bottom.
And at the end of this, while loop code, while we are still in P HP, we can just write a little bit
more of P HP.
So first things first.
We do not need to write any new custom queries because remember, the custom field that creates the
relationship lives on the program post.
So we don't need a custom query.
We can just look at the value of that custom field that's associated with the current post.
So why don't we begin by creating a variable and name it related campuses?
And let's set it to equal get field.
Remember, we named it related underscore campus singular semicolon at the end here.
Now, before we actually try to do anything with this variable, I do want to point out that right above
this line we should call.
BP reset post data, right, because that will give us a clean slate.
Otherwise, when we try to get a field with this name, WordPress might think that we're talking about
whatever posts we just loop through in this custom query code up here.
OK, so reset post data gives us a clean slate.
So now we've got this variable with an array of related campuses.
Now let's just set up an if statement to only output a headline onto the page.
If this is not empty.
Right.
Only if there are campuses to work with.
So we can say if parentheses curly brackets for the condition, let's say only if related campuses exists.
That's all we need to say.
This will evaluate to true as long as it's not empty.
OK.
Now within the curly brackets, let's say we want to echo out a heading level to.
Semicolon at the end.
Let's make it say blank is available at these campuses.
Except we don't want it to say blank.
We want it to say math or English or biology.
So let's delete the word blank and then add another single quote to close out this string of text of
the opening age two.
And then we can add a single quote to begin text again right here.
But then in between that, we can use a period to concatenate on or add on and we can just call get
the title.
Then we can add another period to concatenate on the rest of the text.
Let's be sure to add a space, though, before the word is so that the text doesn't run together.
OK, let's save that.
So so far that's going to give us.
Math is available at these campuses.
Why don't we adjust the CSF styling so that this headline looks like these headlines that we've already
established.
So let's just give our H to a class of headline and headline.
Dash.
Medium.
OK.
And then right underneath this line, after we output the headline, let's just output one link for
each campus that lives in this array of related campuses.
So to do that, you can say for each parentheses, curly brackets inside the for each parentheses,
let's use our related campus's array.
And say for each item in this array, let's say as.
And then we can make up a temporary variable name which is called campus.
And now we can use this variable name in the body of this for each loop to get the title and permalink
for each item that lives in this array of related campuses.
Now we could echo out a string of H t Amelle and Mass with the concatenation in the periods.
But I feel like that gets messy pretty quickly.
So instead, why don't we drop out of BHP and then drop right back into BHP.
But in between there we can write good old HDMI oil.
So let's just create a list item and a link.
And inside the link, let's output the title for each item.
So BHP Atco get the title and what post do we want to get the title for?
Well, within those parentheses we can just pass in the campus variable.
So the current item in our array of campuses.
Then let's do the same thing for the permalink.
So drop in BHP and go out, get the permalink and in parentheses campus.
Now from an h t AML perspective, since we are creating list items, we want them to live within a U,
l or unordered list.
So right before the four each.
Why don't we just go out.
You l.
So my colon.
Let's give it a class of men list linked list for CSF reasons.
Then right after the for each loop we can just echo out a closing you l tag.
Let's give that a save and test it out.
Math is available at these campuses.
Cool.
Before I click on this to test it out.
Why don't we add a horizontal rule right here to create some much needed vertical spacing here.
So right before this heading level two, why don't we just echo out a horizontal rule and let's give
it a class of section break?
That looks a lot better.
And we can now test out our link.
So it takes us back to downtown west and that's gonna bring this lesson to a close.
Our next lesson should only be five minutes or less.
And we will finish up our campuses post type.
And then right after that, we can jump into the new topic of live search results.
Powered by JavaScript.
Let's keep things rolling.
And I will see you in the next lesson.