Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will learn how to search for a keyword phrase within our custom query that is powering
our new epidural.
Let me show you what I mean.
So in our previous lesson, we worked on this new custom, you, R-AL, WP, JSON, University, V1,
one search.
And at the moment, just as a test, we are returning all profesor post types.
But that's not what we actually want.
We want to be able to search for a phrase.
So for example, if someone comes to our website and searches for Bachs a lot, well then we would only
want to return.
The doctor barks a lot post.
All right.
In the first step towards making that happen is for us to revisit the custom query that we wrote that
is responsible for getting this data.
Let me show you what I mean.
So right now, let's jump into our text editor and within our theme folders I.
C or includes folder, let's open up search routes up and down here we see our WP query object named
professors.
And at the moment we haven't been very specific with this query.
We're just saying give us any posts where the post type equals, Professor, but why don't we go ahead
and get a bit more specific with this query?
So at the end of this line, we can add a comma and then we are free to add on another argument you
might remember from previous lessons, arguments like posts per page and order by or meta query.
Well, right now, I want to introduce you to a new argument that we can pass on to the WP query class.
So on this line, let's give it a new argument of simply S.
S stands for search and we can set this to equal whatever we want.
So just as a test, let's set it to barks a lot.
Or if you named your professor something else, just choose a professor name that you know exists in
your WordPress.
All right.
And if I go ahead and save this and then refresh postman.
Perfect, we see that that s argument s research is doing its job, except we don't actually want a
hard code.
The key word here in this file, right, because you and I, as the developers of this site, we are
the only ones that have access to type in a new phrase here.
So instead of hard coding a value here, what we want to do instead is we want to make our API URL flexible.
And what I mean by that is we want to be able to add on parameters at the very end of the euro.
So, for example, at the end of this euro, we should be able to add on a question mark and then say
term equals barks a lot.
There's nothing special about the word term.
I just made it up.
You could instead say keyword equals barks a lot or phrase equals barks a lot.
The name of the parameter doesn't matter.
The key point here is that we want to be able to use this value.
Whatever gets passed at the end of the Eurail here, we want to be able to use that within our custom
query.
We want to set it as the value for the S or search argument.
Now, luckily, WordPress makes it very simple for us to access this data or these parameters.
So check this out back in our code.
Remember when we ran this function named Register Resprout?
This is where we chose the namespace for our URL and the root name.
And perhaps most importantly, this is where we chose which function we want to use to return relevant
data.
Well, when WordPress runs this callback function that we list here, it passes along a bit of data
about the current request that someone is sending.
And we can access that data that WordPress is sending along by simply adding a parameter name within
the definition of this function down here within these parentheses.
Let's just add a parameter.
Let's call it data, but you could call it whatever you want.
The idea, though, is that now we can use this parameter anywhere within the body of this function.
So down here, instead of hard coding the search value to Bachs a lot, instead let's just say data.
And what this is, is an array that WordPress puts together.
And within this array, we can access any parameter that someone adds on to this new URL.
So, for example, in this case, we said term equals Bachs a lot.
So you could think of this as a term is the property and barks a lot is the value.
So back in our code, in order to access that term property, we could just say data and then look inside
the array with square brackets and then just quotes and the name of the property.
So look inside the array for term, which will obviously give us a value of barks a lot.
Or instead, if someone said sky color equals blue and grass color equals green.
Well, in that case you could access the value of blue by saying sky color.
Just look inside the array.
Or you could access green by saying grass color.
The point that I'm trying to drive home here is we are in complete control of the naming scheme here.
So let's set this back to term.
And now if I save this and then back in postmen, if at the end of our Eurail right, JSON University
V1, one search, if I add on and say questionmark term equals miaows a lot, or the name of another
professor that you have as soon as I send that off.
Oops.
Looks like we've got an error here.
I think I know what the problem is back in our code.
We definitely do not want a semicolon here at the end of this line.
So that was my mistake.
Let's get rid of that semicolon, because when you're creating an array, you just add a comma in between
each item, not a semicolon.
And you don't need anything after the final item in an array.
So let's go ahead and save this again.
And if we give Postman another try.
Perfect, we only see the doctor miaows a lot post because we passed along a search term value of miaows
a lot.
Now, before we move on any further, I want to cover a quick security note.
So back in our code, WordPress already performs its own security checks when you run a search.
That's why you can't just visit any WordPress website in the world and immediately hack it with a sequel
injection just by searching the Web site.
However, having said that, it never hurts to be extra careful.
So whenever you're writing your own custom code and you need to work with input that a random visitor
from the Web is typing in, you always want to be sure to sanitize that input.
So if, for example, someone tried to pass along in this URL, they said term equals and then instead
of miaows a lot, they typed in some malicious code.
Well, back in our code, let's just wrap this within a WordPress function named Sanitize Text Field.
OK, so this is a WordPress function, so let's just cut and paste the term that we are looking for.
Let's just move it to live within the parentheses of this sanitize function.
OK, so if I save this and then test it out again, maybe if I search for Rogerson, cool things still
work.
We see Dr. Rogerson and now we are just a little bit more secure.
And that's going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our next lesson, we will learn how to return data for all post types instead of only the professor
post type.
And once we have that up and running, then everything will really come full circle and we can start
working on the display for our search overlay, where we output general information from posts and pages
and then programs and professors and then finally campuses and events.
This is where things really start to come together and it should be a lot of fun to build out.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.