Hello, everyone.
This lesson is going to be super quick and short, and then I promise in our very next lesson, we will
indeed learn about custom fields.
OK.
But first, in this lesson, there's just a few miscellaneous things I want to cover.
The first thing that I want to address is excerpts.
So in our previous lessons, we used the word press trimm words function to just pull in the first 18
words of the main content field for each one of these posts.
But in the real world, sometimes you don't want to just pull in the first 18 words.
Maybe instead you want to create a handcrafted excerpt that you write yourself to show you what I'm
talking about.
Let's begin with this blog section.
And then once we mastered that, we can move on to working on our custom post types here.
So first, with the blogs, let's just go and edit this.
We won an award post so I can show you what I'm talking about in the admen click on posts.
You might not have the exact same post titles as I do, but just go ahead and edit one of the posts
that's being pulled in on your home page at the moment.
OK, now, at first glance, we don't see a field anywhere where we could type in a handcrafted excerpt.
However, in the right hand side bar, not under the block menu, but under the document menu towards
the bottom, we do see an area named excerpt.
And if we click on that here, we see a field where we can enter a handcrafted summary.
I could say our school has won another award this year.
Right.
Doesn't matter what you type.
Just type something.
And then if I click update, we still won't see that excerpt here on the front end.
However, now it's just a matter of editing this P HP code to do what we want.
So in your text editor within your theme folder, jump in to front page dot p HP and you can scroll
down a bit until you get to the from our blog's headline.
Here's the custom query.
Here's the while loop.
Here's the title headline for each post.
And right below it here we see the Trimm words and it will pull in the first 18 words of the main content
field.
Now, instead of this, let's try pulling in that handcrafted excerpt we just wrote.
So let's hollow out this BHP opening and closing tag.
And instead we can just say the excerpt.
So we see some good news and some bad news for the Post that does have a handcrafted excerpt that looks
beautiful.
Right.
But for this post where we didn't assign a handcrafted excerpt, it's going to pull in the first fifty
five words of the main content field as a fallback.
Now it is possible to customize that value of fifty five words to something else.
But that will be used as the excerpt length globally on your entire Web site.
And oftentimes you might not want to adjust the global setting or preference.
You might want excerpts of different lengths depending on the post type or depending on the template
you're on.
Right.
The home page versus an archive.
So on and so forth.
So let me show you how I personally handle excerpts.
What I do is combine the power of this excerpt field with that TRIMM words function that we were using
before.
So again, let's hollow out this BHP opening and closing tag.
And this time, let's begin with an if statement.
So I'm going to say if and then parentheses.
And then let's open up curly brackets and dropdown.
Let's begin with our condition within these parentheses.
Let's call a function named has excerpt.
This function will only return a value of true if the current post has a handcrafted excerpt.
So if this is true, what do we want to do within our curly brackets?
Let's just display the excerpt, OK?
But if this evaluates to false, what do we want to do then as a fallback?
Well, right after the curly brackets for that condition, we can just say LS and then it's own pair
of curly brackets.
And now whatever we say here is like our insurance plan.
So if a post doesn't have a handcrafted excerpt, let's just rely on the first 18 words of the main
content field.
So let's echo out the results of WP trimm words.
It takes two arguments.
The first is what you want to trim.
So get the content.
Second argument is how many words you want to limit it to.
So let's say 18.
So if I save that cool.
This post uses the handcrafted excerpt.
This post doesn't have an excerpt, so it just uses the first 18 words of the content.
Now, from a design perspective, I'm noticing that there's vertical gaps around this excerpt.
And that's because our the excerpt function handles echoing and outputting the content onto the page
for us.
So instead, we can use a function named get the excerpt.
And then right before that, we can just say to echo it.
So if I save that, we can see those awkward vertical gaps that we're being created by the extra P tag
have been removed.
OK.
Now, I like the ability to have a handcrafted excerpt like this.
So we probably want to apply that to our events as well.
But if I try to go edit one of these event posts, for example, Poetry Day.
So in the admen, click on events in the sidebar.
Then edit Poetry Day, you'll notice that we do not see an excerpt field down here.
And even if I click on screen options in the corner, there is no excerpt checkbox to check.
And that's because when it comes to custom post types that we created, it's up to us to specifically
tell WordPress that our post type should support.
Excerpts.
So right now, I want you to dig into your must use plugins folder and jump into the P p file where
we called the register or post type function.
So within our top level array, maybe right before the rewrite line, ordering doesn't matter.
But this will work.
What we want to do is use a parameter named supports.
And then we set that to equal its own array.
OK.
Now, within that array, we don't have to assign values to sub parameters.
We can just mention key words that we want to support.
So by default, new custom post types support the title field.
And the main editor or content field.
And then it's up to us to add on any extra features that we want to support.
So, for example, we could say excerpt.
All right.
Now, as soon as I save this, if I try to edit an event post now down at the bottom of the screen,
I do indeed see an excerpt field.
If you don't see an excerpt field at the bottom of your screen, let me show you what you can do.
So earlier in this lesson, we already learned where to find the excerpt field using the modern WordPress
block at its screen.
However, for reasons we will discuss in just a moment from now, our custom post type is using the
old or classic edit screen.
In that case, when you're using the classic ED up towards the top right corner, you can click on screen
options here and you just need to make sure that the excerpt option here is checked.
OK, now, before we move on and actually add an excerpt value here, I first want to explain why our
custom post type is using the classic ED instead of the modern block editor.
And actually, before I jump into the verbal explanation, I want you to follow along with me.
So back in our text editor within our Ayumu Plugins folder in our university post type's file right
above this supports line that we just wrote.
I want you to add a new line.
And let's say quotes show underscore in underscore rest.
And then arrow symbol, so equal, greater than and just give it a value of true.
Be sure to add a comma at the end of this line and hit save.
Don't worry.
I'm going to explain what this line means in just a moment.
Once we save that back in the ad, man, if you refresh.
Interesting, right?
So now our custom post type is indeed using the modern block editor.
This is because the new editor in WordPress relies almost exclusively on JavaScript.
So in order for it to work, we need to make sure that our custom post type shows up or is available
within the rest API.
Now, at this point in the course, we have no idea what a rest API is.
So don't worry about that.
Trust me, we will learn all about the rest API in future chapters in the course.
For now, all you need to know is that the rest API makes raw WordPress data available for JavaScript
to fetch.
Right.
And if the modern block ed is powered by JavaScript, obviously that needs to be enabled for our post
type.
One other quick note.
When you include the supports array here.
If you don't explicitly list Ed, that will also have the post type fallback to the classic editor.
So, for example, if I get rid of this editor and then hit save and refresh the edit screen, you can
see we're back to the classic ED.
Now, if you don't have the supports array at all.
So if I deleted that entirely, that will use the modern editor.
But just be aware that if you're spelling out what you want to support, you do need to spell out Ed.
If you want to use the modern edit screen, OK?
So with that back in place and still having our show and rest, this is how I'm going to move forward.
So that will give us the modern block editor.
Now, let's get back to the actual task at hand, which is simply assigning a handcrafted excerpt for
this post.
So let's just say Poetry Day is going to be amazing and say that.
And then let's just update our home page template to pull in handcrafted excerpts here.
So now let's jump back to our theme folder.
And within front page dopp BHP.
There's no sense in us typing out all of this BHP logic again.
This if statement that checks to see if there's an excerpt and if there's not.
So why don't we just copy from the beginning?
BHP tag to the closing BHP tag.
Copy that in your clipboard.
Right.
Because if it worked for blogs, it will work for events.
And then let's just scroll up to our events, custom query in the loop for events.
And then here is where we used to just output the first 18 words so we can just delete that and instead
paste in our clipboard with this custom conditional logic.
And we should be in business.
Perfect.
So that takes care of excerpts.
Now, let's change gears.
And the next thing I want to work on is this view all events button.
Right now, it doesn't have a real H RF value.
So if you click it, nothing really happens.
So back in our text editor within front page DOT, BHP right below that event loop.
We were working on is that link that says view all events.
So we just need to update this hash tags so that when you actually clicked on it, it knows where to
go.
So let's drop in to BHP and let's echo out the results of the function, get post type archive link.
Remember, this function will automatically get the correct archive.
You are well, it only needs one argument, and that is the custom post type that you're interested
in.
So if I save that now, when I click on View all events, it takes me to the events archive.
Perfect.
Now, before we bring this lesson to a close, there's just one more thing I want to work on, and that
has to do with our header navigation.
Why don't we go ahead and make it so the events link actually works.
And beyond that, it should stay lit up as yellow when you're on an events based page.
So within our theme folder, let's open up the header dot p HP file.
Here's the events list, item and link.
So first, let's just update the graph value going to BHP.
You could just copy and paste what we use.
Just a moment ago.
But it's echoing out the results of gate post type archive link for the event post time.
OK.
But beyond that, we want that link to be lit up as yellow when you're on an events page.
So just like we did for the About US link and the blog link within the opening list item tag for events.
Let's go into BHP and let's write an if statement.
So we'll say if and what is our condition?
We want to check for, let's say, if get post type.
So that's a function.
It gets its own parentheses.
If that equals or if that returns a value of.
Event.
Well, then we want this link to light up as yellow.
Now if you're if statement is going to live all on one line, you do not need curly brackets.
So on the same line, we can say what we want to do.
If this is true.
So we just want to echo out a bit of H.T. email.
And we want to say class equals double quotes.
And the class name is current menu item.
Cool.
So let's save that.
And we can see that we're on the event's archived and it's lit up as yellow.
And if I click on one of the individual events, we're on the single page and it's still lights up as
yellow.
Perfect.
That's gonna bring this quick lesson to a close in our next lesson.
We will get to custom fields.
It's a very powerful topic.
Let's keep things rolling.
And I will see you then.