Hello, everyone.
This should be a fairly quick lesson, I just want to cover another big tool that can help us reduce
duplicate code in our project.
So let's learn about a function named git template part.
All right.
Now, let's begin by giving ourselves a goal.
When it comes to duplicate code, you might have noticed that we are displaying events like this in
four different places throughout our website.
Right.
So here on the home page is one.
And then if we go to the All Events archive, that's two.
And then if we go to the past events page, that's three.
And then if we go to a program page and check out the related upcoming events, that's four.
So that means we've duplicated this exact same event block code four times and we can do better than
that.
We can write cleaner code than that.
So our goal for this lesson is to move or consolidate this code into its own individual file, and then
we can just call and recycle that file wherever we need to.
So right now, let's jump in to our text editor and why don't we start with our home page.
So let's jump in to front page dot p if we scroll down a bit, here's the custom query that pulls in
the two most rapidly approaching events and down a bit further.
Here's the while loop and this div with a class of event summary.
This is the duplicate code that I'm referring to, right?
This is what controls how each event gets displayed on the front end.
So from this opening div tag down to this closing div, this is identical in all of those four locations
that we just looked at on our website.
So why don't we do this?
Let's go ahead and highlight and select this div and let's copy it into our clipboard, or actually
why don't we cut it into our clipboard and then in its place, let's just add a temporary X as a placeholder.
We will circle back to this in just a moment.
But for right now, I want to go and create a brand new file for that code.
Now, we could go ahead and create the new file in the root of our theme folder.
But to stay organized, why don't we create a new subfolder?
So in our theme folder, new folder and we could name the folder, whatever we want doesn't matter.
But just to make sense, I'm going to name it template parts.
OK, so in the theme folder I've got this new subfolder template parts.
Let's create a new file in that folder and in the new file.
Go ahead and paste in your clipboard.
OK, let's go ahead and save.
We could name the file whatever we want, but why don't we call it a vent.
OK, and now if we jump back to our front page file, the question becomes, how do we import in the
contents of that new file where it used to live right here?
Well, let me show you.
So this used to be HTML, right?
That's why we were dropping out of here and then entering back into HP here.
But now that we're just going to import in that other file, we don't need HTML at all.
So we can delete this placeholder X and then we can also get rid of this closing tag and get rid of
this opening tag here.
OK, and then right below this line, let's drop down.
This is where our HTML used to live and instead let's just call a function named git template part.
And this function takes two arguments, although the second one is optional for the first argument that
is required, we basically just point towards that new event file that we just created.
So quotes and then we want to point within the new folder that we created.
So the folder name was Template Parts Forwards to look inside the folder and then we named the file
event.
Now I want to point out that you do not say event.
You don't need the full file name.
You just need the slug name of the file.
OK, let's go ahead and save this.
And if we jump back to our home page on the website, cool.
We see that our events look exactly the same.
Now, before we move on and update the other three duplicate locations, I first want to let you know
about the second argument that we can pass along to the template part function.
So we learned that the first argument points towards the file that you want to include.
But we can also pass this function a second argument.
So comma, and then I can include any word here that I want so I could say pizza or unicorn.
But for an example, if I say excerpt, so with this in place now, this function is going to try to
include in a file that lives in the template parts folder that is named Event and then dash excerpt.
So WordPress adds a dash.
At the end of this base slug name, and then it just depends on this specialty name.
So just as a quick example, with this code in place, let's rename our event file that we created just
a moment ago.
So in our template parts folder, let me rename Event P and let me rename it to Event Dash excerpt.
So if we go ahead and save this, see, nothing changes on the front end.
Now, at first glance, this specialty name might seem pointless and you definitely don't need to include
a second argument like this.
However, it does allow for some pretty cool setups.
So check this out.
What if instead of the base name being event, what if we say the base name is content?
And then for the second argument, the specialty name, what if instead of a string of text, what if
we pass along, get posted.
Right.
And this function will return event or professor or post or page.
So the idea is if we use a function for the argument now, the file name that this is going to search
for is dynamic.
Right.
In this context, this will try to pull in a file named Content Dash event, and that can be a nice
way to set things up, for example, on an all search results screen, because then in your template
parts folder, you could create different files named content, dash event content, dash post content,
dash professor, write for all of your different post types in each file can use its own unique and
formatting and styling and WordPress will know which file to use depending on the post type.
So that's a bit of a tangent.
You don't need to use the second argument here.
I just wanted you to be aware of it because you can get fairly creative with it.
In this particular instance on the homepage, we know that we are always going to be working with event
post type right here.
So there's no need to call a function we could just say event.
But maybe later on when we work with global search results, that dynamic way of doing things will be
a great benefit to us anyways.
Long story short, this is going to look for a file named Content Dash event.
So why don't we rename our template part file to match.
So within template parts, let's rename our file to Content Dash Event Gain if we refresh our homepage.
Cool, there's our events at this point, let's just work through the three other duplicate locations,
so if we go to The View, all events, archives, screen, let's update this to use our new template
part file.
So this screen is powered by archive event.
So in that file, we can just scroll down to where we see the div with a class of event summary.
Let's go ahead and delete that entire div.
And then again, since we don't need to be in HTML, we can get rid of the closing tag here and this
opening tag.
And let's just call git template part for the argument.
Let's look inside that new folder template parts.
And since we're not using a function to dynamically decide which file to look for, we can just type
the entire file slug right here.
We can say content dash event.
Let's save that.
Cool.
We're still in business and we just removed a bunch of duplicate code.
Next, let's move on to the past events archives green down here.
So this screen in neutral is being powered by page dash past events.
So let's jump into that file page past events, but scroll down a little bit.
Here's the div with a class of event summary.
All that duplicate code.
Let's just delete that.
Get rid of the extra tags that we don't need and then let's call get template part and go inside our
folder and grab that file.
Perfect, still looks good.
And finally, let's go to a program detail screen like biology, and down here we see upcoming events.
So let's remove this duplicate code.
The screen is powered by a single dash program.
You know the drill, let's scroll down until we find that event summary div, here it is.
So let's just go ahead and delete all of this duplicate code, get rid of the tags called git template
part.
Go inside our folder and grab the file.
Perfect.
Now, before we bring this lesson to a close, I want to address a question that you might have.
You might be thinking, hey, in our last lesson, we learned how to create recyclable functions to
reduce duplicate code.
And now in this lesson, we just learned about git template part.
So how am I supposed to know which route to choose?
I know that most of the time duplicate code is bad, but how do I know which tool is right for the job
to remove the duplicate code?
Well, there's not necessarily a right or wrong answer to that question, but I can tell you how I make
my choices.
So if I want the duplicate code in question to be flexible, right.
If I want to be able to pass it arguments to make it do different things like we did for our page banner,
then that's when I create a recyclable function that lives and functions.
On the other hand, if I have a bunch of duplicate code that doesn't need any custom arguments or parameters
and it's literally just a blob of HTML, and that's always going to be the same.
Those are the times when I reach for git template part.
That's just how I do it.
Personally, you're free to use whichever option you feel is right.
What's important, though, is that either way we are getting rid of duplicate code.
All right.
That's it for this task.
In our next lesson, we will create the campuses post type.
It should be a lot of fun because we are going to create an interactive Google map with pins to all
of our campus locations.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you then.