Hello, everyone, in this lesson, we're going to bring our blacktip to life.
Let me explain.
So at this point, we've completed the basics, styling and interface for the block.
Now we need to start thinking about how to actually store the data that users type into the fields and
actually have our joysticks start changing.
For example, if the user tries to add a second or third or fourth answer, so where do we begin?
Well, let's start by adjusting the attributes for our block.
Let me show you what I mean.
So within our Sarsae folder, make sure you have the index JS file open and towards the top when we're
calling the register block type method, remember, we outlined our attributes.
Now they are still the example sky color and grass color from a previous lesson.
So right now, let's adjust the attributes so that they make sense for a multiple choice block.
Let's change the first attribute instead of sky color will change it to question.
And yes, that can indeed be a string of text.
Still, let's get rid of the grass color and then we can come back and add additional attributes here
once we've finished the question field.
For now, though, let's go down into the J.C. Watts and hook up the question field to this piece of
attribute data.
So if we scroll down, we're looking for this text control.
You know, it's the right one because it should have a label of question.
So let's just give this component a prop of value and set it to equal curly brackets to do something
dynamic and then just say props, dot attributes, dot question.
OK, so when the page first loads, this will pull in the current value from the database if one exists
next after every keystroke while the user's typing into this field, well, we would want to update
the value of this attribute that's being stored in memory.
And to be clear here, nothing new actually gets saved into the database until the user actually clicks
update or saves the post.
Nevertheless, we do want to update the value that's being stored in JavaScript memory in real time
after every keystroke, so that when the user does click the save button, it's working with the newest
data.
So on this component, we just give it in on change prop and set it to equal curly brackets and then
just point towards a function that we want to run.
You could name it anything, but let's name an update question.
OK, now let's go create a function with this matching name.
So right above the return parentheses for the ASX, right above that we can just add a new functions,
function, update, question, parentheses, curly brackets.
And this function is going to be a little bit different.
Then the update sky color and grass color functions that we've already created because these were tied
to traditional HTML input fields, whereas our new function, it's tied to a WordPress text control
component.
Now the WordPress component here actually makes things a little bit easier for us instead of having
to receive the event and then look inside the event for the element that fired the event and then grab
its value.
Instead of all of that, the text control component just passes into your function, the actual new
value.
So for our parameter here, you could just say X or value.
And then in the body of the function, that will be very similar to the sky color and grass color function.
So we'll look inside props for the WordPress method called set attributes.
We give that an object that will sort of get merged into all of the other attributes that WordPress
is storing in memory for us.
So in this case, we just want to update the property called Question Colen and just give it a value
of whatever we named our parameter here just to stay organized.
Let's delete the update, sky color and update grass color functions.
We no longer need those.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out in the browser.
Do be sure to have your task running in the command line.
Remember, that's NPM run.
Start back in the browser.
If we refresh, let's practice typing something into the question field.
What is two plus two.
Let's click update or save and then let's try a hard page refresh.
Cool, so you can see that that data was successfully stored at this point, let's start working on
the answers area.
So I think we should begin by giving ourselves a new attribute to work with.
So up towards the very top of our code right now in our attributes, we just have questions.
At the end of that line, we can say comma and then let's have a new attribute named Answers Colen give
it an object instead of string.
It should have a type of array because instead of just one string of text, the user could type in three
or four answers.
So type should be array.
Let's also give it a default value.
So say comma default colon and let's give it an array.
So square brackets with just one empty string of text in it.
So the reason I want its initial value in the block is first empty.
To just be an array with one item in it is because when the page first loads, we do want there to be
one textfield row.
And if we think about how we're going to output this area, really we just want to loop through the
array of answers.
Right.
If there was four answers, we would want to loop through this code that I'm selecting right now four
times.
So when the page first loads and the user hasn't typed anything in yet, well, we would want there
to be at least one item in the array instead of zero items in it.
Right that way there's something to loop through.
Just to make this clear.
Here's a quick example.
And you do not need to type this, but eventually its actual value would be red, comma, orange, comma,
third answer here.
So we're not having an array of the JSC that builds the rows.
It's just an array with the actual answer text strings.
But the idea is, however many items are here in this array, we want to loop through the array that
many times to output the appropriate gests for each row.
So hopefully that makes things clear.
Let's set this back, though, to just an empty string of text and only one of them.
OK, at this point, let's go down into our X and make that area come to life.
OK, so here's the label or paragraph of text that says answers colon.
So we want to keep that, however, this entire Fleck's area.
So from this opening Fleck's tag to the closing Fleck's tag, that's what we would want to duplicate
once for each one of the answers.
So do this with me.
I want you to cut this entire Fleck's area into your clipboard, because we're going to want this code
in just another 30 seconds from now.
But for now, let's get rid of it.
Let's cut it.
And in its place, let's have curly brackets to do something dynamic.
And we're just going to start working with our answers, attribute and loop through it.
So let's say props, dot attributes, dot answers.
And then in JavaScript, every array has access to a method called map.
So we're going to call map in these parentheses.
You just give it a function and it will run that function once for each item in the array.
You could give it an S6 Arrow function if you want to.
But just to make this lesson is easy to follow and make it obvious what I'm doing here.
I am going to spell out function parentheses, curly brackets, this dropdown inside those curly brackets,
not for the parameters.
For now we only need one.
So you could call it anything.
You could call it X or pizza, but let's call it answer.
So each time map calls our function, it's going to pass into it the current string of text from the
answers array.
We'll see where this comes into play in just a moment.
But now, inside the body of our function, we would just want to return a bit of JSM X, so return
and then parentheses, remember?
And if you want to have multiple lines of gests, you need parentheses inside the parentheses.
You can just paste in your clipboard, OK, and then to pre populate the text input with the existing
value on the text control.
Let's just say value should equal curly brackets and just say answer.
So if your answers array had two values, strings of text that said Red and blue map will call our function
twice the first time.
It'll pass this as a value of red.
The second time it'll pass this value of blue.
I think the best way to test this out, to make sure we understand what's going on would be to actually
change the default value up here so that it has a couple values so that we can see it looping.
So maybe give it a value of red comma, give it a value of blue.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So if we refresh.
Perfect, red, blue, and if you gave it a third value, so green, give that a save refresh, you
get the idea.
So this is great.
However, you'll notice that if you try to click on a field and type, nothing happens.
This is because in react, if an input has a dynamic value or I should say a value that's being pulled
from state or an attribute, well, that state or attribute is our single source of truth.
The DOM elements are not a source of truth in react.
What I mean is react isn't going to let us change the value of this DOM element.
Instead, we need to give each one of these and on change prop right where you give it a function that
manipulates the attribute or state data.
So let's go do that down in the ASX.
Here's the code that's looping with map.
Here's our text control with value equals answer.
We need to give it a prop of on change equals curly brackets.
And now instead of creating a separate named function somewhere else, I am actually going to use an
Essex arrow function right here.
Our function only needs one parameter.
You could call it X or maybe new value.
But just remember that text controlled doesn't pass the event that just happened.
It passes the actual new value.
So that's all we're receiving right here with our parameter.
Then let's have the arrow symbol, curly brackets within these curly brackets.
Let's drop down.
And now we might think that we just call props, dot set attributes, parentheses.
However, things are a little bit more complicated this time around because instead of just completely
updating the entire value like we did with question, right, you could just use the entirety of the
new value in this case.
We don't want to update the entirety of the array.
Right.
When you're typing into one of these fields, for example, if you were typing into that third row that
contained Green as the user types, we only want to be manipulating perhaps that one item in our array.
So we need to be careful.
We can't just completely wipe out this value.
We want to be precise and just update a portion of the value.
Things are also a little bit complicated because in react, you don't want to directly mutate the state.
What I mean is we don't just want to directly mutate the array with the three answers in it.
So, for example, you do not need to type this, but we might be tempted to just say props, attributes,
dot answers and look for the third item in the array and just change that and say that it should now
be whatever the user is typed in in react.
You do not do this, you do not directly change an existing value in state.
Instead you just give react your new value and it handles performing that update.
So I know we're getting a bit off track and this is not a course about react.
This is, of course, about WordPress.
So we can't go too deep into this topic.
But let me show you how I would handle this situation.
I would just create a new copy of our array that we are free to mutate.
So I would say const you can name it anything you want, I'll name new answers equals.
And then I just want to create a copy of our array.
So Prof's attributes, dot answers.
And then in JavaScript, every array has access to a method called concat.
And if you just give that an empty array, it's not going to actually add anything onto it, but it
is going to return a brand new copy of this array.
So now on this separate copy, we are free to mutate it.
So now on a new line, I would say new answers.
Look inside it.
We can use hard code, a number for a quick example.
So that would be the third item in the array and then just assign a new value.
So that should equal.
And then we named our parameter new value write whatever the user is currently typed into this field.
Now, we wouldn't actually want a hard code, this number to be two.
This should be whatever item you've currently looped through.
Right.
Whichever specific input the user is actually trying to type into.
So how would we get that dynamic number?
Well, luckily for us, the map function in JavaScript, in addition to passing in the current value,
if we give ourselves a second parameter here, so after answer, we can say comma and you can make up
a name, but we'll call it index because that's what makes sense.
So now Map is going to give us the current index of the item that's been looped too.
So then that's what we would use here instead of the hardcoded two.
OK, and then finally putting it all together on this line set attributes.
You just give that an object that you want to get merged into the attributes.
So we just want to change the answers value to have this new and.
As its value, so new answers.
Let's give this a save and test it out, so if we reload, let me try to change red to be purple.
Awesome.
Let's go ahead and save this to really test it out.
So if we reload to make sure that we're actually pulling that value from the database, perfect at this
point.
Let's change gears and make this add another answer button.
Come to life to all we need to do is find that button in the J.C. Watts down towards the bottom.
Add another answer and we'll just give the opening button tag and on click prop set that to equal curly
brackets and now you could create a separate named function.
But why don't we just write an arrow function right here?
We don't need any parameters whatsoever, so we'll just have an empty set of parentheses arrow symbol.
And you don't even need curly brackets if you're just going to have one statement.
But I am going to add curly brackets just because it's going to be a long line of code.
And just for readability, I want it to be on its own line.
But let's just call props, dot set attributes, give that an object.
And the attribute that we want to change is answers Colon.
And then we just want to add a new empty string onto the end of our answers array.
However, remember, we don't want to directly mutate the existing array in state, so we don't want
to use the array method called push that adds an item to the end because that would directly mutated.
So instead, again, we can just use the concat method because that returns a new copy of the array.
So I would just say props, dot attributes, dot answers and then every array has access to the concat
method.
So you give this an array, so square brackets and then it's going to add this array onto the end of
the original array.
So just have one item in this new array, just an empty string of text.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So if we reload and if I click the blue, add another answer button.
Awesome.
Before we close out this video, let's learn how to make the delete buttons come to life.
So back in our let's just find the delete button on this delete button.
Let's just give it in on click.
Prop said it's equal curly brackets.
This function will have enough complexity that I want to write it as a separate function.
But right here, let's use an E6 six arrow function to call a function while giving it an argument.
Let me show you what I mean.
We don't need any parameters such as parentheses, arrow symbol, no curly brackets, because it's just
one single statement and the function that we're going to create in just a minute from now will be called
delete answer.
So parentheses to actually call it in in these parentheses, let's give it the index number of the current
answer that we're trying to delete so we can access that from just index.
Now let's go create a function with this matching name delete answer.
So right up above our overall JSM will just say function, delete, answer, parentheses, curly brackets.
Now in the parentheses we do want to have a parameter called index to delete.
Right.
That's what's getting passed into the function when we call it inside the body of our function.
We just want to update our attributes of props, set attributes, give it an object.
We want to update our answers, attribute only.
We don't know what to make this value yet.
So just for a quick placeholder, you can just have a dash or an X.
So just like before, when we're modifying an array, it's a little bit tricky.
We don't want to mutate it directly.
So instead we need to create a separate copy of the array first.
So right here I'd say const new answers equals props, attributes, answers only.
Instead of using concat, we're going to use something called filter.
So every array has access to the filter method.
In these parentheses, we give it a function as a function in parentheses.
Curly brackets and filter will call our function once for each item in the array now within the body
of our function.
If we return a value of true, the current item that's been looped through will be included in the new
array we're building.
If we return a value of false, that item will not be included.
So we just need to be able to compare the index that we want to delete to the index that's currently
been looped through within filter.
So in our function parentheses here, let's have two parameters.
We don't need the first one.
So you can just call it X comma.
We do need the second parameter.
Let's call it index.
Now, in the body of our function, we'll just say return of value and this is going to be either true
or false.
So let's say return if the index.
So the number that you've currently looped through.
So that'll be zero one, two, three.
If that does not equal the index that we want to delete.
In other words, return true for every single item in the array.
Except for the one that we're getting rid of, OK, so Filter's going to return that new array that's
going to live in this new answers.
So that's what we want to set this to on our attributes.
So answers equals or Colen new answers.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
If I refresh, let me add a new answer and then I can click the delete button.
Perfect.
Or if I want to get rid of green.
Let me click update to actually save that I reload.
Perfect WordPress remembers, and that is going to bring this lesson to a close in our next lesson,
we'll work on the ability to mark which answer is the correct answer.
Let's keep our momentum rolling and I'll see you then.