Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will answer the question, what is a custom query?
Now, I think the best way to answer that question is to begin with its opposite first.
So what is a normal WordPress query or what is a default query?
Well, so far in the course, you and I have not had to manually query any content or data ourselves.
WordPress automatically queries the appropriate content for us based on the particular URL that we are
visiting.
So, for example, up in the header, if I click on the about US page, WordPress will look at that
you url and see the about US slug and then WordPress knows to only query the database for that one page
named about us, things like the title and the content.
Let me show you another example of a standard or default query.
So up in the address bar, if I visit slash blog, remember in the WordPress settings we designated
this page named blog to be our posts page.
So WordPress knows to query the most recent 10 posts when we visit this URL.
So you get the idea.
So far in the course we've been able to rely on the default queries that WordPress makes for us automatically
based on the current U.S. URL.
So back to the question of the hour.
What is a custom query?
Well, a custom query is you and I saying, hey, WordPress, I don't care what you URL we are currently
on.
I'm going to tell you the exact content that I want to query, meaning custom queries allow us to load
whatever we want, wherever we want.
And this is where WordPress starts to get truly powerful.
So right now, let's give ourselves a goal and then use custom queries to achieve that goal.
So let's jump back to our Web site's homepage.
I can click this logo in the top left to go there.
All right.
And in this beige column, we are going to need to load in the two most recent blog posts at this point.
Let's jump into our text editor and make it happen.
So within our theme folder, remember that our home page is no longer powered by indexed PHP, but instead
front page dot p.
So go ahead and open up front page and then let's just scroll down a bit until we see a headline that
reads from our blogs.
All right, here I see a heading level two that reads from our blogs and remember, the front end is
showing two blog posts.
So one, two.
And if we look in the code, this div with a class of events summary that begins here and ends here.
That's the first post.
And then right below it is another div with that same class event summary.
So ultimately what we want to do is hollow out all of this hard coded HTML and instead create a while
loop that loops through the blog posts and uses this HTML structure as a template.
So that's the ultimate goal.
But before we get there, let's scroll back up to that heading level two that reads from our blogs and
right below this line.
Let's just add a little bit of code that says Hello, world testing, one, two, three.
OK, so if I say that here we can see that text message.
And before we worry about pulling in dynamic data into this exact template that we see here, let's
just write a few practice while loops and custom queries up here where this custom messages.
So back in the text editor instead of this hello world testing, one, two, three line.
Let's drop in to P.
And first, let's see what happens if we create a while loop without running our own custom query.
Right.
Let's see what WordPress automatically queries for us by default so I could drop down to a new line
in between the opening and closing tags.
You don't have to, but let's just write out a while loop.
So while parentheses curly brackets within the parentheses in the condition for the while loop, this
is where we say how many times it should repeat itself.
So we just say as long as you still have posts.
OK, so as long as this function returns true, our while loop will continue looping until all of the
blog posts have been accounted for.
Now within our curly brackets, the first thing we always want to do, each pass through the loop is
called the function the post because that gets all of the appropriate data ready.
Now, at this point, we are free to actually do something with the post, so I want to output a bit
of HTML.
So why don't I drop out of P on this line and then on the ending curly bracket line, we can go back
into P, so then on this line in between we can write HTML.
So let's just output a list item just as a test and within it let's output the title of whatever blog,
post or page is being queried so we can just say the title.
All right.
Now if I save that and refresh the home page, we only see one list item and it reads home.
And that's because the post or page associated with this U.
URL, the root of our domain is a page that just happens to have the title of home.
So that's the only thing that WordPress is going to query for by default on this homepage.
You URL if you're wondering why that's the case, let me refresh your memory.
If we jump into the WordPress admin and hover over settings towards the bottom of the sidebar and then
we can click on the reading option, remember that several lessons ago, we customize this option front
page displays and then we set it to a static page.
So front page is your home page and you can set it to any of your WordPress pages.
And it just so happens that we set it to a page named Home.
And on a similar note, we set our posts page to be a page named blog.
So that's why when we visit blog, WordPress automatically queries the most recent blog posts.
And when we visit the home page, WordPress is only querying this one single page in order to make it
super clear what's going on, we could actually go ahead and edit the title of that page.
So, for example, click on pages in the sidebar and then find the page that has a name of home and
click on it to edit it.
And we can change the title from home to testing.
One, two, three.
And if I update that and then refresh the front end of the homepage, we see that reflected.
OK, so if that's the only page that WordPress is going to query by default on the home page, we obviously
need to take matters into our own hands and manually query the content that we want.
Right.
We want the two most recent blog posts.
So let's jump back to the text editor and create our first custom query.
Let's create a new line right above the while loop line.
And whenever you want to create a new custom query, you begin by creating a variable so we could name
our query, whatever we want to.
Let's call it home page posts.
Name doesn't matter, but that's what I'm going with.
And then let's say that it equals a new instance of the WP.
Query class, if you're familiar with object oriented programming, this line of code makes complete
sense.
But I want the code to make sense to anyone and everyone.
Now, luckily, you don't need any object oriented programming experience in order to create your own
custom queries.
Having said that, I don't think it would hurt for me to give you a quick one to two minute introduction
to object oriented programming so you don't have to type out these lines that I'm going to type right
now.
This is just for a quick demo.
But let's imagine I had another variable named Dog and I would set it to equal a new instance of a class
named animal, or maybe I would have a variable named cat.
And it would also be a new instance of a class named animal.
So the first question here is, what is a class?
Well, think of a class as a blueprint or a recipe that you can use again and again to create different
objects.
So in these examples, dog and cat are objects and obviously animal is the class or the blueprint or
recipe.
Now, there's a lot of differences between a dog and a cat, but there's also a ton of similarities
right there, both animals.
So the idea here is instead of creating a dog from scratch and a cat from scratch, let's create them
from a handy blueprint.
And we could imagine that this class of animal will give these objects access to useful functions.
So, for example, what's something that all animals do?
I'm going to say drink water.
Right.
So maybe this class gives these objects access to a function or method named drink water.
So if I wanted my dog to drink water, now that I've created an object with this class as the blueprint
down here, I could just take that dog object, look inside the object with dash greater than symbol.
And then I could just call the function or method name.
So drink water.
And the idea is that the code for the animal class could be tucked away nice and neatly in some other
file.
And once it's created, you can just forget about it.
Out of sight.
Out of mind.
So this can keep your code really clean.
You just create an object based on a class and the hundreds of lines of code that create the animal
and all of its functions, like, for example, the drink water function.
That code isn't cluttering up this file that we're in right now.
Right.
That code is tucked away.
We don't have to worry about it.
We don't care how the drink water function is created.
We just know that it exists and we can leverage it.
OK, so let me delete these animal lines.
But that's exactly what's going on with this line of code.
WordPress out of the box comes with a class named WP query that we can leverage.
So we are creating a new object with that as our blueprint.
And the beauty of this is that you and I don't have to know or care how this class really works.
The creators of WordPress maintain this class and it will do all of the heavy lifting for us.
It'll do the tricky stuff like connecting to the database and writing SQL statements to query the database.
So we don't have to do any of that.
All we need to do within these parentheses is tell this class what type of content we're looking for
or what do we want to query now, we don't just want to include a simple parameter like this.
Instead, we need to supply this class with an array of arguments.
So within the parentheses, type out the word array and then give it its own set of parentheses.
And then within the array parentheses, I like to drop down to a new line just to stay organized.
And now we just create an associative array to tell this class what we're looking for.
So to refresh your memory on associative arrays, that's where we would say something like CCAC equals
MÃ right.
Or Dog equals bark.
So what do we actually want to type here?
Well, let's begin with a parameter named posts per page.
So if I jump back to the home page, remember that we only want to output the two most recent posts.
Now, by default, queries will return 10 posts.
So if we want our custom query to only return to, we can just say posts per page equals two.
Now, there are all sorts of other parameters that we can string together here to build the exact custom
query that we want.
But for the moment, this is all we need.
OK, so at this point we have an object named homepage posts and all sorts of useful stuff lives inside
this object, namely the two most recent blog posts.
But even beyond that, this object also contains functions or methods that can help us loop through
the content.
So check this out, watch out easy.
It is to use this custom query.
So down within our while loop the functions have.
Posts and the post, these functions are tied to the default automatic query that WordPress makes on
its own right.
The default query that's tied to the current You URL.
So instead of using these functions, we want to use functions or methods that belong to our new custom
query object.
Now think back to a few minutes ago when we had the example dog and cat objects.
Remember that example, function of drink water to use it.
I just began with the dog object and then I looked inside the object with dash greater than and then
I just called the function.
Well, that's exactly what we're going to do for the have posts and the post functions.
So check this out.
Let me delete this example dog line and within the while loop condition, we don't want to use just
have posts because that's tied to the default query.
But right before it, we can just look within our custom object.
So homepage posts and then look inside it for a method or function named have posts and then let's do
the same thing for this.
The post function, just this on its own is tied to the default query, but right before it we can take
our object home page posts and look within it for the function named the Post.
Cool.
So now our loop code is referencing our custom query.
So if I save that and refresh perfect, we see the titles for the two most recent blog posts.
Now back to that associative array we were creating.
Posts per page is just one of many parameters you can use.
We could add a comma here and add another parameter.
We could say category name only give us posts that are categorized under the awards category.
So if I save that, I only have one post under that category.
But you get the idea.
Or we could also say, I mean, delete these, we could add a parameter called post type.
And this defaults to post write blog posts are of the post type of post.
But if you say page, well that will query all of your pages.
So we see about US privacy policy, our history, our goals.
Anyways, long story short, there are tons of different parameters that we can experiment with here.
We are going to be writing a ton of custom queries before this course is over, but for now, all we
really need is posts per page equals to.
Now, let's spend the remainder of this lesson using this styling and template for the two posts that
we are outputting.
So back in the text editor, here's our While Loop.
And instead of just outputting a list item HTML element with the title instead of just this one line
of HTML, let's output this entire event summary div because this has the styling and structure that
will give us this visual appearance.
So here's what I do.
I would just copy one of these events, summary divs into my clipboard and then I would go ahead and
delete that one that I have highlighted.
And the second event summary div OK, but then within r while loop let's just delete this list item
line and then paste in our clipboard.
Cool.
So if I save that we see two of the exact same thing, but now all we need to do is hollow out this
hard coded fake data with real dynamic data.
So let's do that bit by bit.
The first thing I see is the month that the post was created on.
So let's delete this fake hardcoded Jan for January and instead will drop into P and called the function
named the time.
And then the code for a three letter abbreviation of a month is just uppercase M.
OK, and then for this fake hardcoded 20th day of the month, let's just copy and paste this code we
just wrote and delete the twenty and then paste in your clipboard and the code for the day of the month
instead of uppercase.
M is just lowercase d ok.
The next thing we want to hollow out is this headline.
So instead of this fake hardcoded title, let's delete that and instead just drop into P and call the
title and let's also provide a real H ref link value.
So when you click on this link, let's delete this hash tag and instead drop into P and called the permalink.
Now this short excerpt or description text is a bit tricky, so let's delete this fake hardcoded content.
But it's not as simple as just using the P function named the content because that will output way too
much content.
Right.
That looks terrible.
So instead we only want to output maybe one or two lines worth of text, just a brief snippet so we
could say the excerpt instead.
Of the content, but let me show you something even better, so let me delete this, the content function
call and instead let's echo out the results of a WordPress function named WP Trem words, and then you
give this function to arguments.
The first argument is the content that you want to limit.
And then the second argument is how many words you want to limit it to.
So for the first argument, let's just say get the content and then comma and the second argument,
let's limit it to maybe the first eighteen words only saved that.
Test it out.
Cool.
That looks pretty good.
Let's not forget about this.
Read more link.
So back in our text editor, here's the read more link in the graph.
Instead of typing out the permalink again, let's just copy and paste it from right here.
So the permalink, copy it.
And then right here, delete the hash tag paste in your clipboard.
And while we're at it, why don't we make it so that if you click on the date, that also takes you
to the permalink.
So the date is already wrapped in an element.
And here's the atrip.
Let's just delete that paste in your clipboard.
Cool.
Now, before we bring this lesson to a close, there's one habit that I want to instill in you whenever
you use a custom query.
And that habit is once you've created your custom query and used it in a while loop right after that
while loop ends.
So here's the ending curly bracket for the while loop.
Right after that, I want you to get in the habit of calling a function named WP Reset Post Data.
And really this is just our way of cleaning up after we run our custom query.
This will reset different WordPress data and global variables back to the state that it was in when
it made its default.
Automatic query based on the current URL right before we came along and made a custom query calling
this function isn't always 100 percent necessary, especially if you're towards the bottom of a template
file, but it's a really good habit to get into.
OK, so if I save that and refresh, we've got our two most recent posts and we can click on the date
the title or read more to go to that individual post that's going to bring this lesson to a close.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see in the next one.