Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to set up the HTML preview for a professor within the edit screen.
Let's jump into the action.
So in the previous lesson, we set up this area for the public front end.
But now in this video, back on the edit screen, we want to include that same template for the professor.
Right.
Sort of a preview right here.
And it will update each time you change this to a different value.
Now, trust me, I know that I've said the following about 50 times in the course so far, but perhaps
out of all the examples, it rings the truest here, and that is that there are no less than a hundred
different ways that you could set this up.
There are so many different ways that you could blend JavaScript in B to get the job done here.
I believe they all have their own pros and cons.
If you're aware of a perfect approach here, please do let me know.
But right now I'm going to explain the approach that I'm going to take and why.
So because this block here is a react component and we have the power of X at our fingertips.
Our first instinct is probably to try and rebuild the same HTML interface.
Right.
So this layout using X, so we would pull in the dynamic values from JSON, from the rest API and use
JSC for the overall HTML skeleton to put it together.
And while that approach would work, it's far from ideal because we'd then be duplicating our code.
I really do not want to have to spell out the exact same HTML layout or template once in.
And then once in Jacks.
I just want to spell out the template once and now whether that's B or I don't really care, but I only
want to spell it out that one time now JSON JavaScript are super cool, but ultimately we do want server
side rendered HTML for our public front end for search engine optimization reasons, for accessibility
reasons, so on and so forth.
Now if we were not talking about block types and we were just talking about WordPress websites in general,
there is a way to define a template in JSM and then also have it work for server side rendered HTML.
But that's completely outside the scope of this course and what we're trying to build in terms of block
types.
If that sounds like something you're curious about, though, you might want to perform a Google search
for something called Front Tity.
So it's a react framework for WordPress, but this is a completely separate topic and really you would
need to build your entire website and strategy around front.
Anyways, the reason I even bring front party up at all right now is because it would allow you to define
your templates just once in acts.
And then not only have that being used on the client side, but also the server side rendered HTML.
However, we're not going to build an entire website with frontages.
We're just building a block type.
Also, most Web hosts, or at least most affordable basic web hosts are not going to let you run a node.
Jessopp alongside your WordPress site.
In other words, unaffordable basic web hosts.
There is no way to have your JSM be used on the server side.
This is my super long winded way of saying that even though it might not feel like a modern, trendy,
cool best practice, I'm going to use the P p rendered HTML for our On the fly prevue within the editor.
OK, so we've established that we're going to recycle and leverage our generate professor HTML function
again here.
But now the question is how do we want to deliver the results of that into our react component to display.
For example, remember this command in the console, you don't need to do this, but if I run this command
that's going to give us this JSON or this array of objects and if you expand one, it has these default
properties.
But you and I could very easily use P p to add on a new property and we can name it something like Professor
HTML and just have it be that big string of HTML and then we could immediately access that and use that.
However, I'm not going to go with that approach because what if we had 70 or 80 professors?
And when we initially load this list for all of the professors, do we really want all 70 or 80 of the
objects to have that extra property with potentially five or 10 kilobits of HTML?
Well, no, we would not want that.
We only need to load that HTML for this specific one that you choose.
Or click on so what I'm going to do is just create my own totally new custom rest API endpoint.
Let me show you how we can set that up.
So in our text editor jump into featured professor.