Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will learn about a more advanced way of going live with a WordPress website.
Now, in this more advanced path, we are not going to use a plug in to do everything for us.
Instead, we are going to learn how to do things manually by hand.
Why would we do this?
Well, one, it's a good opportunity to learn more about WordPress.
And too, it will allow us to implement automatic get deployment so that making future updates to the
code files of our live website is a piece of cake.
OK, now the act of moving or copying a WordPress website manually really only involves two parts.
Part one is the WordPress database that stores all of our posts and content and settings.
And part two is all of our files.
The WordPress system files our theme plug ins and any photos that we've uploaded through the WordPress
media system.
In this video, we are going to start with part one, moving the WordPress database.
And then in our next video, we will cover moving our files, and that's when we will learn how to set
up automatic get deployments.
OK, but first, before we learn how to copy and move our database, I'm going to begin by completely
deleting my live Web site that I set up with The Simple Path.
A, I'm going to completely delete it so that I can start over from scratch and move the site again
with Path B, if you followed along with Path A, you will probably want to do the same.
Right?
We basically want to hit a reset button and get a clean slate so we can learn how to move things the
more advanced way.
So in order to delete this live Web sites, files and its database, we need to log in to our Web hosting
account.
So in a new tab visit site, ground or whatever Web hosting company you're using.
And actually, before I show you how to delete everything, I do want to stress the point that there's
no sense in deleting a perfectly good Web site unless you want to practice the more advanced path.
B and again, if you're not already familiar with the basics of the git version control system, then
Path B doesn't make sense for you right now.
OK, so I just want to make that clear.
Not everyone needs to learn about Path B, but if you feel like it's right for you, then let's go ahead
and delete this Web site so we can start all over again.
So within your Web hosting account, just look for the file manager for the domain that you're working
with.
It's located in a different place, depending on your Web host.
But the file manager where we can delete our files.
OK, click into your main domain folder here, OK?
And now let's click into the public underscore HTML folder.
And now within this folder, we just want to delete everything so you'll know that you're in the right
directory, that you want to delete everything.
If you see folders like WP Admin, WP content and WP includes.
So I'm just going to click just once, not a double click, just a single click on this first folder
or file and then scroll all the way down to the bottom and hold shift on the keyboard and click this
very last file or folder.
So that selects everything that I'm just going to.
Right.
Click and choose.
Delete.
Go ahead and confirm.
OK, cool, so we've deleted all of our files, now we just need to go and delete the existing database.
Now, this will definitely be different depending on your Web host company, but you're just looking
for either database or something called my sequel or Maisky.
Well, OK.
From this screen, if we scroll down a bit, we can see towards the very bottom an existing database
that we have towards the very right hand corner.
We see these three dots and if you click on that, we can then choose delete.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Let's delete the database, click, confirm.
Cool.
So now we've deleted both our files and our database.
So at this point I have a completely empty, clean slate.
We've basically got a brand new fresh web hosting account now and now we can go ahead and learn how
to move our local dev environment copy of WordPress up onto our Web hosting account.
OK, and this time around, we're going to do it in a more advanced Hands-On manual way.
Remember, there are two main parts to this.
Number one, the database, and number two, all of our files.
And in this video, we are going to begin with the database, right?
Because within our local dev environment copy of WordPress.
So my fictional Dash University Dev local website, this website's database contains all of the posts
and pages and settings and all of our data.
So instead of having to manually recreate each post and professor and campus, we just want to copy
that database onto our Web hosting account.
So the question becomes, how can we create a copy of the database that's powering this local website?
Now, if you have prior experience with HP and databases, but maybe not WordPress, specifically,
your first instinct might be to look for something called my admin or open up a MySQL client like SQL
Pro for Mac or Heidi Ezekial for Windows.
However, even though those tools are great when it comes to WordPress specifically, not only do we
need to create a copy of this database, but we also need to perform a basic find and replace on the
database.
We need to find any and all instances of this domain.
We need to find all instances of that in the database and replace that with the live Web site domain.
So in my case, I want to find fictional university dot dev and replace it with Brad s dot you cite.
Now, again, you could use one of those tools I mentioned just a moment ago, my admin or SQL Pro or
Heidi Escudo.
But you're still going to have to open that export a database file in a text editor and manually perform
a find and replace.
Now that works OK.
And I've done that in the past.
But if your database is fairly large and your computer is not super powerful, that can really bog down
your text editor.
So instead, let me show you my preferred way of creating a copy of my local database and how to perform
the find and replace all in one simple step.
OK, so from your local dev environment copy of fictional university login as the administrator and
then in the admin dashboard, I want to install a new plug in.
Don't worry, this is not some all in one plug in that's going to do everything for us.
This is a very focused plugin that just performs a very specific task for us.
So from the sidebar, hover over plug ins and click add new.
And in the top right search field, let's search for WP, my great D.B..
This is the one I'm interested in.
It has the exact name of WPE Migrate Debe, it's created by delicious brains.
So let's go ahead and install it.
And then click, activate.
OK, and with that new plug in activated, now, if we hover over the tools item in our sidebar, we
have this new option named Migrate Debe.
Let's click on that.
OK, let's be sure to leave this first option selected, we do not want to run a find and replace on
this actual database, right.
Instead, we want to export or create a copy of this database and we can perform a find and replace
on that copy of the database.
So for this first field, we want to find any instances of slash, slash, whatever your localhost domain
is, and we want to replace that with slash slash.
And then in my case, it's Brad s dot s g edu dot site.
For you.
It will be different, right?
It'll be whatever domain name you're using or whatever practice or testing subdomain you want to use
right now.
Just be sure to not include the HTTP or https.
OK, we just want slash and then your actual domain.
OK, so cool, this first row will ensure that the database works within its new live environment.
We actually do not need this second row.
Ideally, you could perform a find and replace for the absolute file path, but this is not necessary.
Only certain plug ins make use of this field and it's not an absolutely essential part of WordPress.
So I'm actually just going to click the X here to remove that row.
OK, so we're just performing this one global find and replace and let's go ahead and click export.
Cool, you can see that that automatically downloaded a file for me, so you can either click this X
to close this or I think you can just click anywhere in the background of the page.
Yep.
And now if you check out the downloads folder on your computer, perfect.
We've got a brand new file that is a copy of our MySQL database.
This contains all of our posts and professors and campuses, all of our WordPress data and settings.
So now back on our Web hosting account, we just want to create a new database and then import this
file.
So back in my Web browser, remember earlier in the lesson, this is where we deleted our existing database.
And so now from this same screen, let's just click this create database button.
OK, so now we have this empty shell of a database, so it exists, but it's completely empty.
So now we just want to modify it by importing that file that we just exported from our local WordPress.
In order to do that, we're looking for something called P p, my admin.
So you can see here it is for me, but every Web host is different.
So just look around for my admin and you'll know that you found it because it should look something
like this.
OK, in this left hand sidebar here, you can see that randomly generated name of the new database,
the new empty database that my Web host just created.
For me, yours will almost certainly have a different name, but go ahead and click on that and the
left hand side bar.
OK, now, at the moment, this database is completely empty.
So what we want to do is import up here.
There's an import button.
Let's click on that.
OK, and then right here, we can choose a file to import, so click on that and then select the new
file in our downloads folder that we just created a moment ago.
Right.
This is our copy of the database.
Let's choose that.
OK, then down at the very bottom of the page, we can click the go button.
Cool, so the import was successful, and if you've ever been curious about how WordPress stores all
of your data, well, this left hand column gives you a good idea.
So the database is made up of individual tables with certain responsibilities.
So there's a table named WP Posts, which contains all of our posts.
If you click on it, then you can see all of your data.
Right.
And it almost looks like a giant spreadsheet.
Each row is a post or a revision of a post, and you can see they have different columns like ID, the
date, even post content.
So this is the main body field where the actual content for a post lives.
And back in the left hand side bar, there's also a table for users.
So all of the user accounts, there's a table just for options.
There's a table just for comments.
You get the idea.
Anyways, at this point, we have successfully copied the database from our local dev environment and
pushed it up onto our Web hosting account.
And remember, there's only two aspects of moving a site.
No one is copying or moving the database.
And number two is the act of copying or moving all of your files.
Right.
So all of the WordPress system files, all of our theme files, any plugins that we've downloaded,
any photographs that we've uploaded to the WordPress media system.
And in our very next lesson, not only will we learn how to move all of those files, but we are going
to do it in a nice, luxurious, automated way that leverages the git version control system.
This is going to be a lot of fun to set up.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you then.