Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will learn how to deploy our WordPress files from a repository up onto a Web host.
In our previous lesson, we learned how to move a database.
Now, in this lesson, we are focusing on files.
However, before we actually move any files to our Web host, I first want to cover a topic that is
related to both files and the database, and that is that when you are manually moving a WordPress website,
you need to account for the fact that the database that lives on your local dev environment and the
database that lives on your Web host require different login credentials in order for WordPress to be
able to access them.
Let me explain what I mean by that.
I think the best way to understand the issue that I'm trying to describe is to open up the config file
for our local dev environment, WordPress.
So right now, let me show you where you can find that file within the local by flywheel app.
You can right.
Click on your project, choose, reveal and Finder, dig into your project, dig into app and then dig
into public.
And then within this folder that contains WP content, WP admin and WP includes, there is a file named
WP Dash Config Dot.
So right now, let's go ahead and view this file in our text editor within this file.
If you scroll down to about line number 23, there are four values that I want us to focus on.
They are Debe name, DB User DB Password and DB host.
Now these values of local root, root and localhost, these work for our local dev environment and they
allow WordPress to successfully connect to our local database.
But the database that lives on our Web hosting account, it requires completely different values.
Now at first you might think, big deal, who cares?
Why don't we just update these values to whatever our Web host database requires?
Well, it's not that simple because if we make any change to these values whatsoever, so if I change
the database name to just something random and save that, well, now, as soon as I visit my local
dev environment website and refresh, it's completely broken, right?
Because now it cannot establish a connection to its database.
Let me put that value back really quick.
OK, so the question becomes, how can we set up this config file to please both our local dev environment
and our Web hosting environment?
Well, there are probably a hundred different ways to do that.
But let me show you my favorite way.
So right above this comment that says the name of the database for WordPress, right above that line,
let's create an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets and actually right after the closing curly bracket, let's say else.
OK, and then for our condition, check within these parentheses, let's say, if so, in terms of that
condition, in order to save a bit of typing, why don't we just jump in to our functions file in our
theme folder?
Because we've already written that if statement wants.
So, for example, if you jump into functions, B, this is in our theme folder and if you scroll down
and find our function named university files, you can see we've already written that exact if statement.
So I would just select from the beginning of this story start and then select until just the one closing
parentheses.
So don't grab both of them, just grab one and then copy that into your clipboard back in our WP config
file right here.
We can just paste that in.
OK, so if that's true, then in this if block we would just want to cut and paste these four values
to make this a bit cleaner.
Why don't we actually get rid of these comments?
So I'm going to get rid of the comment right above the DB name, get rid of the comment above user as
well as databased password and MySQL hostname.
So I'm just going to cut or move these four defined lines into the block.
OK, let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So on the front end of my local copy of the website, if I refresh, everything still works perfectly
and to make sure that our logic is actually running, you could just change this address a bit so that
it doesn't evaluate to true.
So if I add it on a few extra L's at the end of local and save now when I reload.
We see an error message, right?
We cannot establish a connection to the database.
Cool.
So let's put that back to just dot local.
OK, and now let's take these four defined lines, these values.
Let's copy these and just create a duplicate copy in the else block.
So now we just need to modify these values or find the correct values that would work with our Web hosting
account.
Now, it's important to point out that every Web hosting company is slightly different.
So you might need to look for your hosting companies frequently asked questions, page, or see if they
have any documentation on setting up a database or even get in touch with customer support.
But the point that I'm trying to drive home is that I can't guarantee what values you should use here
because every host different.
However, let me walk you through what I would do with this particular Web host.
So when I log into my Web post, I'm just looking for the database section or the MySQL section.
And because your Web host isn't going to look like mine, it's not so much about looking at where on
the screen I'm clicking.
It's more about the actions I'm performing.
So right now I'm just navigating to the database section because I'm trying to find the database name.
Right, the name of the database that we created on our Web host in the previous lesson.
So here it is.
I'm just going to copy and paste this into my text editor on your Web host.
It might be a randomly generated name or it might be some sort of name that you chose to enter.
But either way, we're just looking for the DB name, the database name, and then back in our text
editor within the else block for DB name.
Let's change this from quote, local to quote and then just paste in your clipboard.
OK, next is the database user.
So back inside ground, you can click on this user's link or user's tab here, down at the very bottom,
we should have an existing user.
So, again, this is a randomly generated username.
You can just copy that into your clipboard.
Back in our text editor instead of root for the DB user, just paste that in the quotes.
Next up is the password for this user.
Now back in site ground on this user row here in the far right corner, you see these three dots and
if you click on them, you can then click change password.
Unfortunately, there's no way for us to view the current password.
So our best bet is just to change the password to something that we know.
So let's click change password.
So just go ahead and type something in that's eight or more characters or you can click the generate
button.
OK, then click confirm and then back in our text editor, whatever you just chose for the password
that goes on this line.
So here's the super secure password I chose.
Please don't hack me 20 20.
OK, and before we move on to the fourth and final value here, I do want to show you something back
in the site, ground control panel.
So down here under Manege users, this is the user name and we just set a password.
But we also want to be sure to give this user access to the new database that we created in the previous
lesson.
You need to make sure that your database user has access to the desired database itself.
So to do that towards the right hand corner, we can click on this icon here and you can see we're just
adding a database for our user.
So by default, it selects the one database that I have and I'm just going to give this user all privileges.
So click confirm.
Cool, so now this database user actually has permission and access to the desired database at this
point.
Let's jump back into our text editor and work on this fourth and final value.
We could likely leave this as localhost and it would work.
However, I did notice that site ground by default sets this to so quotes one two seven zero zero one.
Now, I am aware that localhost essentially equals one two seven 0.01, but who knows, maybe Cytron
has a reason that that's what they set it to by default.
Now, when I say that every Web host is different, that's especially true when it comes to DB host
values.
A lot of companies do use localhost here, but I know in the past when I used Dream host, they would
give you a MySQL subdomain that you would use here.
So if you think you have the DB name, user and password, correct, but it's still not working for
you, you might need to contact customer support or look through the web hosting wiki and discover what
you should use for your DB host value here.
OK, let's go ahead and save this file.
And now our database set up is complete.
This code is able to successfully connect to our local database as well as our live database.
Now that's going to bring this part of the lesson to a close.
In the next part, we will get to the moment we've all been waiting for.
We will implement deployment's that automatically happen every time you update your GitHub or BitBucket
repository.
It's a super luxurious workflow that makes future updates to your code, files a piece of cake.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you then.