Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to continue building the settings form for our plug in, let's jump into
the action.
So in our previous lesson, we successfully set things up so that we were able to save this value of
display location, end of post into the database.
Right.
That's what this WCP location with a value of one instead of zero.
That's what that signifies.
However, it would be nice if when you refresh this admin page, if that was actually the selected option.
Right, instead of it just always selecting the first option when you reload the page, so essentially
let me show you how to make this HTML select element actually come to life.
So back in our code, we're looking for our function that we named location HTML.
Right, with the select element.
And we just need to add a little bit of P on each of these options.
So on this first one, maybe after the value attribute, let's enter into P and close it out right here
as well inside.
We just want to output the selected attribute if the value in the database matches this current value.
Right.
And then we do the same thing for this one as well.
Now, you could write your own code to output that, but luckily, WordPress has a function named selected.
We're going to call that in these parentheses.
We're going to give it to arguments and use give it to values and it will compare the two.
And if they're a match, it will output the word selected into the HTML.
So for the first value, let's load that option from the database.
To do that, we just say git underscore option and then you tell it the name of your setting.
So remember, we named ours WCP underscore location.
Right?
So that's this value in the database and it's going to be either zero or one.
So for the second argument, we would just check for this first option, which would be zero.
So string of text zero.
OK, now let's just copy and paste this entire block of P here and then just add it for this option
and just change the value that we're checking for from zero to one.
Now, before we save this and test it out, because this is the first time we've seen this git option
function, I want to let you know that there is no performance hit by using it several times.
So, yes, this value that we're loading is coming from the database, but it's not like WordPress needs
to access the database again and again.
Each time we use this function, essentially, WordPress will load any and all options from the database
in one trip.
I'll let you know that in the database.
Notice this third column called Auto Load.
Now, these other rows on the screen, they're set to know because they're sort of temporary transient
cache data.
They're not actual options.
But if you go back to maybe the first page of your options table, you will see that almost all of them
are set to yes for auto load.
And that just means that if it's an option, a user preference, WordPress is going to load that into
memory.
So we're not making round trips to the database over and over again anyway.
Anyways, let's give this a save and test it out.
So back in the admin panel, if we refresh perfect, it selected that option that we have currently
set it to in the database.
OK, so this field is looking good.
Let's move on to the next field.
So if we look at the finished product, the next field would be the headline text.
Right.
That lets the user type in whatever they want for the post statistics headline.
So to set that up, let's just jump back into our text editor in setting up our first field with a lot
of work, but now adding subsequent fields and settings is going to be very easy.
So, for example, in our settings method, let's actually just add a space here just for our own organization
in between these lines.
So notice these two lines are grouped together.
Add setting field and register setting.
Let's just duplicate these two lines.
Right, because these two lines are for that first field.
So just select the two lines, copy right below paste.
So now you can add comments if you want to.
You can add a comment, say this one is for location.
This one is for the headline text.
But essentially now we just make very minimal changes to these new two lines.
Why don't we name the option WCP underscore headline.
Change the label.
Maybe headline text, OK, then we'll need to create a method that is responsible for outputting the
HTML.
Let's just name that method headline HTML.
We can create that in just a moment.
These settings look good.
We don't need to change those.
OK, let's look at this line register setting so the group for the setting would stay the same.
We do want to change this to WCP headline.
We can use the same generic sanitized text field, but why don't we give it a default value of post
statistics?
OK, now before we save this, let's create a method with this name headline HTML that actually outputs
a bit of HTML for the form element.
So Rapallo our settings function.
I would just say function headline html parentheses curly brackets.
I would drop out of here, go back, end up down here, right here.
I would just want to output a little bit of HTML so you can type input in vs code and then hit tab.
OK, let's be sure to give it a name of WCP underscore headline.
And before we save this, let's just go ahead and pre populate the field.
So if there's a previous value in the database, let's display that here so we can say value equals
and then let's drop in to inside these quotes and let's just echo and then we can use that git option
function again to load the value, get option.
And we named it WCP headline.
OK, and just for one extra layer of security, even though only admin users will be able to get to
this page for best practices, we do want to escape our output any time we're taking a dynamic value
and trying to put it into HTML.
So here's what I would do.
Just take this git option, cut that into your clipboard.
We're just going to wrap it in a WordPress function called SC for escape, underscore ETR or for attribute.
Call that function and then inside that, just paste back in your clipboard.
Cool, but save this and test it out so you refresh your plugin settings, page headline text, lets
enter something really custom here, maybe let's change it to word count info and click save.
Cool.
You can see the page reloaded.
We get this confirmation and that value is sticking in that field.
Even if you reload, it's still there.
You can go look in the database if you want to.
WCP headline with our value.
So that field is now done, let's move on to the next field, so if we look at the finished product,
that would be a checkbox for if you want to display the word count.
And then the same thing for if you want to display character, count or read time.
So three checkboxes, they're going to be identical.
So let's just work through this one, the first one together.
And then to avoid repetition, you can pause the video and I'll have you set up these next two on your
own.
But let's be sure to set up this first checkbox together.
So back in our code within our settings function, let's just duplicate these two lines again.
So this next one will be for the new field.
Let's change the option name to maybe WCP word count.
Right.
And then it will be zero or one or true or false if you want to display it for the label.
Let's just say word count for the HTML callback function.
Let's just change this to word count HTML.
The next two options can stay the same.
Let's look at the next line.
The group can stay the same, let's just change this to WCP word count, everything else can stay the
same except for the default value.
Let's give it a default value of one, right.
By default, we want it to be true or we want that box to be checked.
We probably do want to display the board count.
OK, now let's just go create the HTML method so below our settings function, say function.
Scroll down a little bit.
Function word, count, html parentheses, curly brackets exit.
Here, enter here inside, let's type input and then hit tab in vs code for the type.
Let's change this to check box.
OK, let's be sure to give this a name that matches the setting.
So that's WCP underscore word count.
Let's give it a value of one which is just a shorthand way of saying yes or true.
OK, and then let's write a little bit of conditional code so that it looks at the existing database
value when you reload this page and it will check this box or not check it depending on the database.
So just like WordPress had that function called selected, it has a similar function called checked.
So let's just enter and exit it here.
Inside we can use the WordPress function called checked.
You just give it to values.
It's going to compare for the first value.
Let's use the git option and our field or settings named WCP underscore word count.
And for the second value to compare it against, let's just compare it to the value of one.
OK, let's save this and test it out.
So back in the browser, if we reload word count.
Yes, we told it to be true by default.
Let's uncheck it and then try to save perfect.
We get confirmation and even if you reload, it remembers to stay unchecked.
But if we test it out and check it, click save again.
Perfect.
It remembers that preference.
We can go look in the database.
There it is now at this point to avoid a super repetitive video.
There is nothing new for the next two fields, right?
If we look at the finished product, these two checkboxes are exactly the same as this checkbox.
The only thing you would need to change is the variable names or the option names that you choose.
So right now, I want you to pause the lesson video and everything that we just did for this word count
field, this checkbox.
I want you to do the same thing and just add these new fields called character count and read time.
Welcome back.
So if you're resuming the video, I'll assume that you've added the two other checkbox fields.
I will talk for just a minute about how I added the next two checkboxes so you would want to register
the new setting and add the setting field.
However, when it comes to the HTML callback functions, yes, you could have just created two additional
copies, right?
Just literally copied and pasted the checkbox HTML function.
However, it might have felt dirty to create three copies of essentially the exact same function because
the only thing that's different here is the actual variable name for the option.
So while you could have just duplicated the functions, here's what I did.
I created a single reuseable function called checkbox HTML and I made sure that can receive an incoming
parameter.
We'll talk about what the incoming parameter is in just a moment.
But here you can see it's an array.
I'm looking inside the array for something called the name.
I made up this property of the name, but essentially I hollowed out the only part of the function that
is unique.
Right.
So the variable name and then over towards the right, the variable name again when we're checking it
with git option.
So this way the function is reusable.
Now, let's talk a little bit about where this ARGs is coming from.
So if we look at ad settings, field, whenever you use ad settings, field for the three checkboxes,
if you scroll over to the right, this section used to be our final argument.
I just added a comma and included one more argument, and it's an array.
WordPress is expecting this to be an array and it's going to pass this in to your HTML callback function.
Now, yes, there are specific property names that WordPress will know what to do with, but you can
also just give it your own made up properties.
So I just made up the name and then gave it a value for each one of these specific variable name.
So that's just how I handled it.
So you don't have to have these comments about, you know, three copies of the function, but it's
totally up to you anyways.
Let's move on.
So the final thing that I want to cover in this video lesson has to do with custom validation logic.
So let's take the display location field as an example.
So, yes, we programmed the select to only have two options.
Right.
This first option has a value of zero.
This option has a value of one now, even though only trusted admin users are going to get access to
this page.
What if one of them is weird and uses their chrome dev tools, so if I inspect that select right, there's
the select element and what if I just click on this and change this to have a value of one hundred?
Right.
And then I go back and I make sure that I click beginning of post, click save.
Well, if we look in the database, WCP location now has a value of one hundred.
So this final topic of custom validation is what if we really want to make sure that this is only allowed
to have a value of either zero or one?
If you give it any other value, it should fail or it should just reset back to its previous value.
So back in our code, we want to find the sanity's callback for that field.
So here is the display location when we're actually using the register setting.
Remember, the third argument is an array and one of the properties is sanitized callback.
Now, up until now, we've just been using the WordPress provided generic sanitized text field function.
So instead we can just point this towards one of our own functions and WordPress will use that instead.
So let's get rid of the quotes in this sanitized text field and instead give it an array.
Remember, this is the callable syntax when you want to have a reference to a method from your class.
So the first argument is sign this comma.
Second argument, we just get to make up our own method name.
So quotes and let's make up a name of sanitize location.
OK, now let's just go create a method with that name.
So scroll down a little bit.
Just below that function settings create a new function, sanitize location, parentheses, curly brackets.
Now in the parentheses, we do want to receive a parameter let's call a dollar sign input.
So when WordPress calls are sanitized function, it's going to pass into it the value that the user
is trying to save.
So now in this function, the first step doesn't have anything to do with WordPress.
This is just basic programming logic.
We just want to check to see, you know, whatever logic we're checking.
So in this case, for this field, I want to check to see if the value is not zero and it's not one
when we have a problem.
So let's set up that conditional logic.
I'll say if parentheses curly brackets for the condition, if input does not equal, so exclamation
equal, if it does not equal zero and if input does not equal one, if that's the case, then in this
if body, I want to do two things.
I want to add a red error message up here.
And then number two, I also want to return the old value.
So not with the user, just input, but the previous value that was stored in the database.
So ultimately this function needs to return something that is going to get saved into the database.
So let's start out with the error.
So we'd say add settings, error, semicolon, and we're going to give this three arguments.
The first argument is the name of the option that the error is related to.
So this would be WCP underscore location.
The second argument is sort of a slug or identifier for this particular error.
Essentially, WordPress will add into our HTML ID equals and then whatever name we give it here so you
can make up a name.
I'll just say WCP location underscore error, but any name would do.
And then the final argument, this is the actual message that you want to display to the user.
So let's say display location must be either beginning or end, OK, after that line, but still within
the if block.
We now want to return the old value from the database.
Right.
We definitely don't want to return whatever incorrect value the user tried to submit.
So let's return and then just use git option.
So McCallan, the one we're looking for is WCP underscore location.
OK, now if this is not the case, meaning if the user did enter a value that is correct or that we
want to allow, then just below the if so, right here we can just return dollar sign input, write
whatever they tried to send along.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So if I refresh, if I choose one of the normal values, it should work.
No problem.
Cool.
But if I refresh and if I use my dev tools and I try to set the value of this first option to five hundred
and then select that and save perfect, we see this red error message and the.
Save did not go through, so if you look in the database, it still has that previous value of one,
right?
Not five hundred.
All right.
And that is going to bring this lesson to a close in our next lesson.
Now that our form is complete, now that we're saving the user's preferences, it's time to actually
build the plug in itself.
Right.
So if we look at the finished product, it's time to actually write the code that assembles the text
that gets added in to a blog post detail screen.
It should be fun to sort of connect the dots and get our plug in truly up and running.
So let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.