Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to work on our banner block so that you can actually edit the content.
Let's jump right into the action.
So in our previous lesson, I had actually jumped into a blog post just to get a quick instance of the
WordPress block editor screen.
But because this chapter is all about full site editing, why don't we dig in to the appearance menu?
Click on editor and let's just begin editing the index template.
So in a previous lesson, you and I had added the query loop block.
It doesn't really matter what is in this template.
We can fine tune that later for now, just anywhere in the template.
It doesn't matter where.
I just want you to insert an instance of our banner block.
So I've added one here to my index template.
Now our goal here is to make it so that you can actually type in different content here for these headlines,
the different text for the button, upload a different background image, choose a different color for
the button, so on and so forth.
Now there are several different ways we could handle this, but I want to aim for maximum flexibility,
and here's what I mean by that.
So we could start shaping the attributes of our block to exactly match the content that we see here.
In other words, we could have an attribute called large headline text value, you know, medium, small
headline text values.
We have an attribute named button, text button, color button, link address.
But if we set things up like that, we'd be locking them in this exact order and this exact combination.
What if in the future we wanted to create a banner that has two medium sized headlines and two buttons,
or three small headlines, or just any possible combination and ordering other than this exact literal
layout that we have here.
So here's what I have in mind to take full advantage of the block editor.
I think it would be cool if this overall banner block allows you to nest other blocks inside it.
Better yet, we can set things up so that you can only add specific block types inside the banner block.
We can create our own new custom block types, for example, called generic headline and generic button
and then make it so.
Those are the only block types allowed to be nested inside the banner block.
But that would allow for all sorts of different combinations and ordering of this content.
I realized that was a lot to absorb.
So if my overall plan there didn't make perfect sense, that's okay.
We're going to work through it together step by step.
Right now.
I think our first step should simply be to jump into that JavaScript file that's powering this block.
So in your text editor with the fictional block theme folder opened up jump into the Our Blocks folder
and open up banner dot js.
Okay.
Now the question becomes, how do we set up a block so that you can nest other blocks inside it?
Well, there's something in WordPress called inner blocks.
So up at the very top of our file and for the next 20 seconds, you don't need to type this in because
I'm going to show you a more modern or quote unquote best practice way of importing it.
But inner blocks lives in the JavaScript that WordPress itself loads into the global window scope of
the browser.
So technically, we can always access it by just saying WP Dot BLOCK Editor Dot inner blocks.
However, since you and I are using the app WordPress Scripts NPM package, right, the official WordPress
JavaScript package, we can just act like we're importing inner blocks.
So now this is the code that you can actually type in with me.
We can just say import and you know, de structures of curly brackets, inner blocks from quotes and
then the NPM package would be at WordPress slash block dash editor.
Now you and I did not even use NPM to install this package name.
That's okay.
The official WordPress Scripts package has web pack configuration and it sets up different aliases.
So when it sees this, it will know to look in the browser global scope.
So this is really just for the benefit of you and I.
We get to write this elegant import code that we're used to writing.
Anyways, the actual point here is, well, how in the world do we use inner blocks?
Well, check this out.
Within our edit component function.
Let's just hollow out this HTML logistics a bit.
Now we don't need to delete it because we're probably going to want this just as a reference in a future
lesson.
So why don't we do this?
Start selecting from the heading level one and select all the way down to where the A or link element
closes.
And let's cut that into our clipboard.
So let's keep that in our clipboard.
We're going to use it in just a moment, but in its place.
So now within this hollowed out HTML, we can just say, well, we're just using the inner blocks component.
Really quick, let's empty our clipboard just so we don't lose that code as a reference.
So maybe within edit component before the return line, let's create a variable.
So contrast use mean later equals parentheses in the parentheses.
Let's start with just a react fragment and then in that react fragment.
So right here you can paste in your clipboard.
So the idea is we're saving this code just as a reference.
We're probably going to want to borrow it later on.
But for now, let's focus on what this inner blocks is going to do.
So this is going to let you click the plus symbol in the block editor to start adding new blocks inside
of this block.
So that takes care of the edit functionality.
Now we need to take care of the saving functionality, right?
So that when someone adds, you know, three headings and five paragraphs into this, we need to save
that into the database somehow.
So why don't we do this instead of this paragraph placeholder?
Let's get rid of that.
Why don't we return an actual bit of HTML?
That makes sense.
So parentheses in the parentheses.
Let's just copy the entire edit code.
So this entire bit of divs in html js.
Just paste that into the return parentheses.
Okay.
And now in our save component function, instead of a component of just inner blocks, we're going to
say inner blocks dot uppercase content.
So this is what's actually going to be output for the block or, you know, get saved into the database.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
You need to make sure that your start task is running.
So in the command line we can just run, NPM, run, start.
Okay.
Back in the browser.
As soon as I refresh, this block is going to be gone because I didn't save this template.
That's okay.
We can just re add it so I'll refresh.
Once again up here, I'll add in my banner block and there you have it.
So you'll notice it says Type Backspace to choose a block.
Or you could use this little plus symbol here.
So right now, we haven't restricted which block types you can use.
So every single block type is available.
But just for a quick test, let's add a paragraph and say hello.
This is a nested element.
Now check this out.
If we actually go ahead and click Save to save the template and then refresh the index on our homepage,
there is the output HTML.
So that's what the save function in our JavaScript file did for us.
It actually saved that JS ax and then it saved any nested blocks into the database.
I think it's helpful to really see what that looks like in the database.
So in admin or if you go into your post table, click Select Data.
Click on the very last page of results and then just scroll down and click edit on the very last post.
You can look in post content and there you see it.
So this is the template we just saved.
WP Our block theme slash banner and there you see our JS acts, right with the classes that we're using
for our success and then nested inside of that, right?
So it starts right about here.
You see a WP paragraph nested inside of our banner.
Next, I want to show you how we can restrict which block types are allowed to be nested here.
So back in our code within our edit component, not in the use me later JS Acts.
Let me scroll down a bit when we're actually returning a bit of gsx and we have the inner blocks component.
We can just give inner blocks a prop of allowed blocks, send it to equal curly brackets inside here,
give it an array and let's give ourselves a goal.
Let's say we only want to allow paragraphs, headings and lists and nothing else.
So quotes.
Core slash.
Paragraph.
Comma quotes.
Core slash heading.
Core slash list.
If we give that a save and then back in the edit screen if I refresh.
If I click on to this text and then push enter to try to add a new block and then type forward slash,
I can only choose between heading and list.
It doesn't show paragraph because paragraph is just the default assumed block type.
But there you have it.
We can only use those blocks that we spelled out.
That's pretty cool.
However, I think you can see how this gets much cooler very quickly.
What if we only allow custom block types that you and I create?
Well, that's exactly what we're going to do.
In our very next lesson, we're going to begin working on new custom block types called maybe generic
heading and generic button.
The idea is they're custom blocks and their job will be to output content that mimics this old template
code.
Right?
And instead of core, we'll give them a namespace of our block theme slash and then their specific name.
Just like we've done with this banner block.
I think it'll be a lot of fun to set up.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.