Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to set up the post metadata that will allow us to truly create a relationship
between the blog post and any of its featured professors.
So currently we're storing the idea of a featured professor simply in a blog type attribute.
So if we look in the database for this blog post that I'm currently viewing, we're just storing the
ID number of that professor right here as an attribute.
Now, this works perfectly for querying for that professor post within the blog post.
However, just this alone leaves us no way of querying and finding this blog post from the professor
detailed screen.
In other words, right now it's a one way street.
Our blog post can find the professor, but the professor can't find the blog post.
So this is where something called post metadata can save the day in my database.
If I go back just to the home of the database and jump in to the table called Post Medda and then click
select data and I'll just jump to the final page.
But you'll see there is an entire table in WordPress for storing metadata for posts.
So let me explain how we're going to use this in this lesson.
We're going to create a new post meta and you can see this column key is sort of the name of the meta.
We could name it something like Featured Professor.
And then this column posted.
This will have a value of the blog post that is featuring the professor.
And then this column, the actual value that can just be the ID of the professor.
Now, once we have an item, a record like that in the database, it'll be a piece of cake to search
for this relationship from within the professor detail screen.
So here's what we're going to do in our edit screen block component.
We already have a use effect that will run any time the professor posted an attribute changes.
So let's just do this.
Any time that changes on that same event.
We can also just update the meta for this blog post.
Let me show you what I have in mind.
So in our text editor jump into the Sarsae folder index JS.
So down within our edit component, we already have this use effect.
And remember, we're watching for any changes to the Proff ID attribute.
So this function is going to run whenever that changes.
So let's just do this, not inside our async function, but just right above that async function line.
Let's make up a new function that we can create in 10 seconds from now, but let's call it update the
meta.
There's nothing special about this name.
I just made it up but parentheses to call it.
Now let's go actually create this function.
So maybe right below our use effect and right above this all prof's we can just say new function with
the name of update the meta parentheses curly brackets.
To update the meta, we can use a WordPress JavaScript tool that will be available on the global scope.
So we can just say WP dot data dot dispatch in these parentheses let's say quotes core slash editor
at the very end after the parentheses will say dot edit post parentheses to call that we give that an
object, just say Medda Colon and then we set that to be an object, OK, and now we just make up a
name for a piece of meta.
So remember back in the database, the Medicare column, that's sort of the name or label for your piece
of meta.
So that's what we're selecting here.
Let's just give it a property of featured Professor Colon and then you just give it the actual value.
Now, at first we might be tempted to just say props, dot attributes provide and that would work perfectly
if we were only ever going to have one instance of the Professor Block type in a blog post.
However, that's not the case.
You can have as many instances of this block type as you want, so let's get rid of that for right now.
We're not exactly sure what we should set this to equal to for now.
I'll just put a question mark so we know to circle back to this.
But let me explain what I'm referring to.
So back in the edit screen.
Yes, right now I only have one instance of the block type, but I could insert another Professor Call-out.
And if I set it to Rogerson, well, we wouldn't just want the ID for Frog Person to overwrite the value
for Dr. Bachs a lot.
We don't want a situation where just the most recent one that you've set is the only ID being saved.
So what I'm getting at here is we need.
To zoom out a little bit, instead of thinking about this from just the current block component that
we're writing code for, we want to think about this from the block ed screen as a whole.
I'm going to update or save this post just so when I refresh.
I already have multiple professors to test with.
But right now, let me show you what I have in mind back in our text editor within the update meta function
at the very start of it.
Let's have a new line.
Let's create a variable so const you can make up a name, but I'll call it Prof's for Medda equals.
And then I just want to select any and all block types on the edit screen and then from there we can
filter through them just for the featured professor block types.
So I'll say wp dot data dot select call that give it quotes core slash block dash editor at the end
of that call, get blocks.
OK, this is going to return an array of all of the blocks.
So basic default paragraphs, unordered lists.
So I just want to filter that array to only include blocks where their name is our plug in slash featured
professor.
So let's do that back down in the code we were writing.
We have get blocks at the end of that.
We just say dot filter.
Now you can see this line of code is already getting quite long.
So what you can do is just drop down before each dot, just personal preference.
But for example, right before dot get blocks here, you could drop down and then you could even indent
to just show to yourself that this line of code is still part of this line.
And then you could also do that right here.
So dot filter.
OK, but in the parentheses for filter, we give it a function, let's give it an arrow function.
We'll just have X as our parameter arrow symbol and we don't even need the word return if we stay in
a single line here.
So I'll just say if x dot name equals double equals signs.
Quotes our plug in slash featured Dasch professor.
OK, so what is this going to return?
Well, it's going to be an array with just those block types, but each item in the array is going to
contain all sorts of different properties about that block type.
And really the only property I care about is its provide value.
And at the end of the day, what we're really trying to get here is just a simple array of post ID numbers.
So what I'm going to do is take this filtered result and then at the end of this, just drop down and
use map.
So you give map a function will give it an arrow function.
So X arrow symbol.
Again, we don't need the word return if we stay on a single line and I'm just going to return X attributes
dot proff, I'd.
So this way, it's not going to be an array of complicated objects, it's just going to be an array
of simple post ID numbers.
OK, for now, this line of code is done, but right below it.
So we don't need to be indented any longer.
Let's log it to the console just so we can see it visually.
So console log Prof's for Medda and also we would want to use it here for the value that we're setting
for the Medha.
So instead of the question mark, it would just be Prof's for Medda.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So if I refresh and open up my console, well there are other things being logged to the console, but
cool.
There is an array.
I have two instances of that block type and so I have an array with two items and it's just two numbers.
The post IDs for barks a lot.
And from Grishin.
Now, before we take the last couple of steps to make sure that that Medda is actually being saved into
the database, let's first make sure that we aren't storing duplicates.
And what I mean is if I add another instance of that block for the exact same professor.
Right.
So for fraud person.
There's no need to store the ID for frog person twice in Medda, but maybe the author of this post would
want to include this block once at the very top of the blog post and then once again at the very bottom
just for review.
So while visually there's a reason to store it twice, there's no need to store the meta twice in.
What I'm getting at is if we look at the console, well, now the array has three items in it and you
can see it has a duplicate of forty one.
So we don't need to store Rogerson twice like that.
So let's just adjust our code a little bit to remove any duplicates or make sure that it only includes
unique values.
So at the end of dot map I would just dropdown be indented because it's part of this overall line but
I would just say dot filter once again, call that, give it an arrow function.
But this time we do want parentheses because we're going to have three parameters, let's say X for
the value comma index for the index that it is in the array and I said the first one zero, the next
one's one and then comma, let's just say a R and this is the array itself that we're working on in
between the parentheses here we have the arrow symbol, curly brackets, let's drop down and now we
only want to return.
True, if the current item that's been looped to doesn't already exist in the array.
So in JavaScript, every array.
So this is the array that we're working with.
Every array has access to a method called index of so parentheses to call that and let's just give it
the actual value.
So X so what in the world is index of do?
Well, we're essentially asking the array, do any of your items have this as their value?
If the array does contain an item with this matching value index of will return the index of the first
instance of that value.
If the array doesn't contain that value, it will return negative one.
So we can really use this to our advantage to make sure that we only have unique items.
Let me explain so we can just say if that equals double equals sign index, the current index that we've
looped to, if you're anything like me, this is not the most intuitive code in the world.
I had to read through it several times for it to really click and have an aha moment of how this only
leaves unique items.
But essentially for every item we're looping through it and we're saying, is this current index the
first example of a value?
If it's not the first example, then that means it's not unique anyways.
If we save this in refresh, I don't believe I saved the post with the double Rogerson's.
So you can just add the instance again.
Professor Call-out, let me have two Rogerson's and if we check the console, perfect.
So now our array only has unique values.
In other words, now we can just really work on making sure that that value or this array of values
is actually being saved into the database.
So first of all, when we're dispatching this action that doesn't directly save anything into the database,
this just updates the WordPress datastore in JavaScript memory.
In order to actually save anything to the database, you would actually have to click the update or
save button for the post.
However, currently even doing that wouldn't work yet.
It wouldn't save it to the database because we need to do something in first.
We need to use to register our new custom made a name.
So do this with me in our text editor in our folder.
Jump in to our file.
So featured Professor P, and we're looking for our on init method.
So if you just scroll down a bit, here it is.
This is the same area where we registered script style and our block type.
So just anywhere in this function, maybe right here, we're going to use the WordPress function called
Register Medda semicolon in the parentheses.
We're going to give it three arguments.
The first argument is the type of metadata.
So this would just be post, right, as opposed to comment metadata or user metadata, a post.
The second argument is the name for this meta.
So that would just be quotes.
And we want to call it featured professor.
So just make sure this perfectly matches whatever you set back in your JavaScript as the meta name.
And then the third argument is just an array of options.
So array parentheses.
Let's have one option called the show in rest and set that to true comma.
Let's have another option called type and set that to no comma.
Let's have another option called single and set that to false.
Let me explain what single false means.
So if you set that to.
True, well, in the database, WordPress would try to store an array of data for the value, but I've
seen that in certain situations that could serialize the data and then database lookup performance is
a bit slower.
So by setting single to false, we're just saying you don't need to try to save all of the professor
yds in one row or one entry instead.
If we had three featured professors in one blog post, we would have three rows or three entries in
the database.
Right.
And the posted would all be to the same blog post.
The key name would be the same, but the value each one of these would just be one professor post here,
one professor post here and one here.
We'll see this in just a moment.
But let's go ahead and save this up, OK?
And with that saved, now back on the edit screen, just to be safe, I will reload or refresh.
OK, but now with the two featured professors in place, if I actually click update or save for this
blog post, we can go look in our database.
So just click on the post metastable.
You can click, select data, click the very final page, and then if you go down to the very bottom,
perfect.
I have two pieces of medical featured, Professor.
They are from the same blog posted, but each professor has their own entry.
This makes it super easy to look up this relationship from a professor detail screen, and that's exactly
what we're going to work on in our next lesson.
But before we bring this video to a close, there are two details I want to take care of.
So first of all, if I was to click on one of these featured professors and delete that instance of
the block from my post, well, we want to make sure that that would delete the appropriate item from
our post meta.
So let me show you how I would handle that within our REACT component.
So back in our indexed JS file, essentially we need somewhere where we can respond to the event of
our component on mounting or getting deleted.
I'm sure there's more than one way to do this, but here's how I would handle it.
So we already have one use effect right below it.
I would just create a brand new use effect, so use effect parentheses to call it.
Remember, you give it to things.
So the first is a function, so just give it an arrow function.
The second argument is what you're watching for changes now if you just give it an empty array.
This is super useful.
React.
We'll only call our function the very first time that this component renders.
However, inside our function.
If you return something, well, what you can return is called a clean up function.
So we return a function right here and then react will call that function when this block gets deleted
or unmounted.
Right, if it's no longer being rendered to the DOM.
So let's just return an arrow function here.
So and now if you really wanted to test this out, you could have an annoying alert pop up.
But I'm very confident that this is going to work just the way we want it to.
So instead of testing it out, I'm just going to do what I actually want to do, which is simply call
update the meta.
Right.
Once that block has been deleted.
I just want to run this again so it gets a fresh copy of the existing professor post IDs.
So inside here, I would just say update the MEDDER.
Let's give that a save and test it out.
So if I refresh and if I go down and delete Dr. Frogh person and update or save the post, and then
if I go into my database and refresh, you might have to look around a bit.
You can see the ordering changed a little bit, but perfect.
Now there's only one featured.
Professor Cool.
There is one more tiny detail I want to take care of in this video.
You might have already noticed this in our previous lesson, but here's what I want to fix.
So you'll notice that if I insert a new instance of Professor Call-out, it's showing your first professor
in my case miaows a lot before I even selected a value.
So when you first insert this block type, this area should be blank until you actually select a real
value.
Let me show you how I would fix this within our first use effect.
That's watching the Proff ID attribute for changes.
I would just wrap everything inside here in an if statement.
So do this with me.
I'm going to select from update the meta all the way to when we call our go function.
Just cut that into your clipboard temporarily.
Wrap it in an if statement for the condition.
I would just say if props dot attributes proff id if that evaluates to true meaning, if it's not empty
or undefined, only then do we actually want to perform these actions.
So then you can just paste back in your clipboard.
OK, now if we save that, go test it out.
If I scroll down and insert a new block type of Professor Call-out perfect.
It's empty the preview, but as soon as I select something.
Excellent, and just in case you're curious, I am going to go at it off camera, my doctor miaows a
lot post so that it doesn't have the script code here because I'm not trying to cross site script attack
myself.
OK, just so you and I are on the same page anyways, that's going to bring this video to a close.
I'm excited to connect all the dots in our next lesson.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.