Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will learn how to work with multiple post types when it comes to the WordPress rest
API.
So, for example, at the moment our search overlay only works with a single post type.
So, for example, I know that I have blog posts named Biologies is Cool and we won an award.
So if I search for either of those titles, Buyology or Award, those results obviously come in successfully.
But there's more to our website than just blog posts.
For example, we have a page named about us, but if I try to search for about, we won't see any results.
Now, the reason that this is happening is simple.
This is quite literally the way that we programmed our JavaScript.
So let me show you what I mean in our text editor.
Let's open up our search JS module file.
And if we scroll down to our method named get results.
Remember, this is the Eurail that we are sending a request to.
And towards the end of the euro, we have posts and then we add on our search string.
So this is why at the moment it's only going to search through that one post type posts.
So if we wanted to, we could change this from posts to pages.
And then if I save that now, if I try to search for about, we do successfully see the about us page
as a result.
But now if I tried to search for a blog post, we'd be out of luck again.
Right.
So if I search for Buyology, we don't see the biology as cool blog post.
So that didn't solve anything.
Now we've just got the opposite problem.
Now we are only searching through pages.
So the question is how can we have our cake and eat it too?
How can we search through both posts and pages?
Well, the WordPress rest API does not have a native way of doing that, but it's not a problem because
we can just send out another request to a second U.
RL and then we can manually combine and smush together the two resulting sets of incoming JSON data.
So let me show you what I mean.
Let's set this current URL back to posts instead of pages.
And then down here within this code that will not run until the server has had a chance to respond with
the Jaison data.
Let's actually cut all of this highlighted code into our clipboard.
So let's begin selecting on this line and let's select all the way down to the is Spiner visible false
line.
OK, let's cut that into our clipboard.
Cool.
Now, right now where my cursor is blinking, any code we type is not going to run until the server
has a chance to send back the data.
So within this callback area, let's just set up another JSON request, right?
Let's send out another request to a U.
RL that uses pages instead of posts.
So down on this line, let's just say dollar sign to use J query and then let's look inside it for the
get JSON method semicolon at the end of that.
And remember that get JSON takes two arguments.
The first argument is the Eurail that you want to send a request to.
And the second argument is what you want to do once that you URL has actually responded.
So this is where we would typically create an anonymous function.
Why don't we use the S6 Arrow syntax?
So first you just type in the name of a parameter you want to use.
You can make up whatever parameter name you want, like data or results.
But in this context, I'm going to use pages and then we just say equal greater than to create the arrow
symbol.
And then right after that, let's just add a pair of curly brackets and then in between the brackets,
I like to dropdown just to stay organized.
And now within those curly brackets, let's just paste in our clipboard, OK?
Now that we've got that pasted in code back in place, let's shift our attention back to this temporary
X placeholder that I used.
We don't actually want an X here.
We want the Eurail that we want to send a request to.
So in order to save a ton of typing, why don't we just copy and paste what we already wrote up on this
line?
So I'm going to begin selecting at the beginning of this university data and then just select all the
way to the right up until the end of Dot vao parentheses.
So right before this comma here, let's go ahead and copy that.
And then down on this line, instead of this placeholder X, let's delete that and paste in our clipboard
and then we can just change this from posts to pages.
Now, I know that the last few minutes has just been a lot of me telling you what to do without really
explaining what's going on, but trust me, in just a few minutes, we are going to break things down
and analyze everything and actually check this out.
I think after our next step, everything will start to make sense.
So what I want to do now is right above this line, this line where we are targeting the HTML of the
results div right above that.
Let's add a new line and let's create a new variable.
We could name it whatever we want, but I'm going to name it combined results and let's set it to equal
posts.
And let me refresh your memory of what posts is in this context.
If we scroll to the right when our first request goes out, all of the JSON data that the server is
going to send in response will temporarily live in our parameter here named posts.
So back in this brand new line of code posts is the array of the incoming JSON data, and in JavaScript,
every array has access to a method named Concat.
This stands for concatenation, and this is how we can combine multiple arrays, so we're starting with
the posts, resulting data, and then we're saying let's add on.
And then within these parentheses, let's just say pages.
Right.
Because pages is the name of the parameter where all of the resulting JSON data from this you URL will
temporarily live.
So on this new line of code, altogether, we're creating this brand new variable that basically smashes
together the two different sets of incoming results.
So now all we need to do is down here within our template, literal when it comes to looping and displaying
the results instead of looking within an array named posts, let's just look inside our new combined
array and it's named combined results.
So let's change this.
And if you're using sublime text or atom, you can just highlight the word posts here and then either
press control D or command D, and that will select the next instance in the next instance.
And then you can just say combined results that will get added in in all three spots here.
Cool.
So let's go ahead and save this.
And now if I search for history, I see our sub page named our history.
And if I search for biology for that blog post, biology is cool, perfect.
It's there.
And if I search for lorem as in lorem ipsum, we see just about every page in post in my website, which
is what I would expect.
So this means that new JavaScript code we just wrote is working properly.
However, we can do better.
This is not the best way of coding things.
What I'm referring to is the way that we nested one JSON request.
We nested this inside another get JSON request.
Now, this might be the simplest and most obvious setup, but in terms of creating the fastest user
experience for our website visitors, this is not the best way of coding things.
Now, in order to learn why this is less than ideal and what we can do better, instead, we are going
to take a quick vocabulary break and learn about two terms, synchronous and asynchronous.
Now, in order to explain these two terms, I've come up with an analogy or a diagram.
So imagine you're standing in the very center of a grocery store and you're there with a group of three
people.
So there's yourself and two friends or family members.
And imagine that there are three items spread out across the grocery store that you want to place in
your basket.
Now, the terms, synchronous and asynchronous, represent the different strategies for getting those
items into your basket.
So let's walk through both.
But let's begin with Synchronoss.
So here's what that would look like.
The first person starts walking towards this item, but while that's going on, the other two people
are completely frozen.
They just have to sit and wait and watch until the first person completes their task.
Now, once this first person successfully brings an item back to the cart, only then can the second
person begin their task.
And while that's going on, the third person is still completely frozen and cannot begin anything yet
themselves.
Right.
So then once the second person completes their task, only then can the third person start their business.
So clearly, this is not the fastest possible way of getting all the items into the basket.
Right.
Because there's a lot of just sitting around and waiting for other people to finish their tasks.
But that's how synchronous code works.
Now, the opposite of this is asynchronous.
So in an asynchronous world, all three people could be simultaneously walking to get their item in
the grocery store.
Right.
So this person starts walking, this person starts walking.
So does this person.
Now, there's no guarantee or predictability of who's going to finish first, but in this case, it
doesn't matter.
The idea is just that all three people are working at the same time.
Right, so maybe they all finish very close to one another and it's clear that this is probably going
to be a lot faster than the synchronous way the three people are not just sitting there idle waiting
for each other.
They can all simultaneously be getting work done.
So this means that asynchronous code has the potential to be a lot faster, but it's not always the
right tool for the job.
It just depends on the situation.
Now, having said all of that, let's get back to the task at hand.
And that task is us wanting to send out multiple JSON requests to these different Yarl's.
Now, at the moment, we have set things up in a rather synchronous way, right?
Because this inner JSON request is not even going to begin until this first JSON request has completed.
Now, there are a lot of different ways we could set this up, but in my opinion, our best bet is to
sort of mix and match synchronous with asynchronous.
Here's what I mean.
Why don't we adjust this so that the two get Jason requests can run together at the same time asynchronously
and then only once they both complete.
Do we want to run any of this code.
Now, that's exactly what we are going to set up together in part two of this lesson.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next video.