Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to begin coding the actual feature of our plug in.
Let's jump into the action and let me explain.
So this is a sneak peek of the finished product.
And on a single detail blog post screen, you can see that the plug in is dynamically adding this word
count statistics before the actual body content.
So in this lesson, we just want to write a bit of PHP that's going to output the headline.
And then the three statistics write the word count, character count and the approximate read time.
So let me jump back over to a tab where I have not completed this yet and we're going to work on this
together.
So let's jump into our text editor.
And what we want to do is filter the content for a post.
Now, we've actually already seen this filter hook a few lessons ago.
So in our constructor function, let's just add a new line and say add, underscore, filter, semicolon.
We're going to give it to arguments.
So the first is the underscore content, comma.
And then let's just point towards a method that we're going to create in about ten seconds so we can
use the array callable syntax.
So array, the first argument is sign this.
The second argument is just a name that we get to make up.
So you could choose any name you want, but I'm actually going to name it if rap.
OK, then I would just create a function with that.
Names function if wrap parentheses curly brackets.
Now I'm doing this because we only really need to change or filter the content.
If a you're on a single blog post screen and B if the user has any of the three checkboxes checked.
So for example, if I go into settings word count, if someone uncheck all three of these checkboxes,
then we don't need to filter or manipulate the content.
Now, you could have wrapped this overall add filter line in an if statement.
That would make a lot of sense.
However, it's just my personal preference that I like my constructor function to be very clean and
minimal.
I like to be able to look at the constructor, function at a quick glance and immediately see the actions
and filters that I'm using.
So this is just how I'm going to do it.
But in our if rap function inside the body, let's set up an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets for the condition in these parentheses, let's say only if this is
the main query parentheses to call that, and if this is a single blog post page.
So parentheses to call that.
OK, so we've already used and in our condition now I also want to use or in our condition.
So here's what I'm going to do, wrap both of these in a set of parentheses.
So right before the word is another opening parentheses.
And then in between these two closing, I have another closing, OK?
And then I'm going out of space right here.
And then I'm going to say end and then another set of parentheses.
And now in here I'm going to use or and I'm going to include all three of our checkbox options.
So if this one is checked or if this one is checked or if this one is checked, so if even just one
of them is checked, then we are going to want to manipulate the content.
So in this set of parentheses, I would just say get underscore option.
The first one we named it WCP, underscore word count now after that string of text.
But still inside there, I would say comma, the default value of one.
This default value is important because if the user just installs your plugin and then they haven't
actually checked in unchecked and rechecked boxes and saved all their settings, well, this option
won't actually exist in the database yet, right?
If the users just using the default option, we won't find anything in the database.
So then WordPress will use this value that we're providing here as a fallback.
OK, so just after that one set of parentheses, now we can say or if get option, this one will be
quotes WCP underscore character count after the quotes, comma default value after just the one closing
parentheses one more or get option quotes WCP read time again.
The second option, the default value.
I realized that line of code was very difficult to follow along with so you can pause the video right
now.
I've broken it down to fit on multiple lines or also know that you can always download my finished code
for each lesson.
There's a downloadable zip file that you can find after each video.
Anyways, big picture, we just want to make sure that both of these are true and any single one of
these is true, if that's the case right then in the curly brackets for our if statement, let's return.
And what do we want to return?
Well, we want a chance to manipulate or change the content for a blog post.
So in this function that we're creating, let's make sure we have a parameter you can name it anything
like maybe input, only content.
So dollar sign content.
And then since this function already has a bit of complexity to it, I'm just going to pass the task
off to a new function.
They will only have the one single responsibility of manipulating the string of text.
So I'm just going to say sign this right.
Our class or this instance of the object.
Let's look inside it with dash greater than and then we can make up a method name that we'll create
in about ten seconds from now.
You can name this method, whatever you want.
I'll call it create HTML parentheses to actually call it semicolon.
And then in these parentheses, let's just pass along the default version of the content before we get
to manipulate it.
So dollar sign content.
OK, now that was if our condition is met, if our condition is not met, well then just right below
the if statement right here we can simply return dollar sign content without modifying it in any way.
Cool.
At this point let's just go create a method now with this name, create HTML.
So right about here I would just say function create html parentheses, curly brackets.
Let's make sure to have a parameter again.
You could call it anything, I'll call it dollar sign content.
OK, before we move forward, if you want to make sure that your code is working so far in this function,
you can just return dollar sign content and then concatenate on maybe just a space and the word hey
or hello semicolon and let's hit save and test it out.
So if we refresh on a single blog post detail screen down at the very bottom of your content, you should
see hello.
And to truly test that our logic is working, you can just go into your plug in settings screen and
uncheck all three of these.
Save changes, reload again, notice the hello goes away cool, so let's put those settings back.
OK, and let's move forward and actually begin quoting the real content to back in our code.
Actually, I do want to take a quick time out and explain the difference between this syntax where we're
calling a method in our class versus this syntax where we're providing a reference to one of our methods.
So down here, we didn't need to use the array callable syntax.
We could just directly begin looking inside the class or this instance of the object and then simply
call the method.
This is because we wanted to call and execute this method right here.
Right now up here, we are not the ones calling the method, so we don't want to call it right here.
Right now, we're just passing a reference to the method into WordPress.
And then WordPress is responsible for actually executing and calling the methods at just the right moment.
OK, so hopefully that clears up the difference between this syntax and this syntax.
Also, just a quick note.
While I'm looking at this code, I'm realizing that we actually didn't need the entire set of parentheses
to group these two conditions.
I think I was sort of caught up in the moment of thinking of the actual logic and not so much thinking
about the code syntax itself.
So you could get rid of this inner parentheses right before his main query and then you can get rid
of this closing parentheses right here.
Right.
There's really no need to group these two.
So we're just saying if this is true and if this is true and if any one of these three is true, cool.
Now, at this point, let's actually get to the fun part of the lesson, building out our creative HTML
method.
Why don't we begin by outputting a heading level three that says post statistics or whatever the user's
typed into their custom title field, so we don't actually want to return the content.
Plus, hello, we can give ourselves a clean slate in this method and why don't we create a variable
that we can keep adding on to as we go so we can name it anything we want, but I'm going to name it
Dollar Sign HTML and let's set it to equal string of text.
Let's just add a semicolon right now so we don't forget in the string of text let's have had in level
three after the heading level three, let's have an opening P tag and then a bit later we can actually
fill in that paragraph and close it out.
But for now we just want to open it.
OK, now inside the H3 tags, this is where we want to say post statistics or whatever the user entered.
So let's do this.
Let's close out this first part of the string and then concatenate on something else.
For now, you can just hit X as a placeholder and then you'd want to concatenate on and then just open
up another string.
OK, now we didn't actually want the X as a placeholder.
Instead, what we would want here is get option in back in the admin panel.
Remember this field where the user can type in their own custom headline text.
We named that option or that field WCP underscore headline if the user hasn't entered a custom value
yet or if they just installed the plugin and we need a default or fallback value, let's say quotes,
post statistics.
OK, we're almost ready to test this out on a new line, but still in this function.
Now, let's just add this onto the standard blog post content.
Now, we do want to pay attention to whether we should add it to the beginning of the content or to
the end of the content.
So here's how I would handle that.
I would just open up an if statement for the condition if get option.
We named it WCP underscore location, comma, and we'd actually want that to have a default value of
zero.
Remember, we said by default it should be at the beginning of the post and we set the value of one
to mean at the end of the post in between these two closing parentheses, I'm going to say if that equals
zero, obviously this one equals zero.
But we want to make sure if it's coming from the database, if the user has actually saved that option
or changed it from the default value, if that is zero, then we would just want to add on our content
to the beginning of the blog post content.
So if that was the case, I would just return our HTML plus or concatenate on dollar sign content.
If this is not the case, then we would want to add our HTML at the end of the content.
So right below this if statement we can just say return dollar sign content, concatenate on dollar
sign HTML.
So just the reverse.
OK, let's give this a save and test it out.
So back on the front end, if we reload, cool up the very top of the post.
See post info, and if I change this to end of post and save the changes and then reload, cool, now
it's down at the very bottom of the post.
At this point, we're ready to actually start outputting the word count, character count and retire.
So right after this line where we have dollar sign, HTML equals our headline right below that.
Let's just begin adding the content that would live inside this paragraph.
So I'll write a comment to ourselves and let's say let's calculate or get the word count once and save
it in a variable because we're going to need the word count for both outputting the word count and for
calculating the read time.
So we don't want to have to calculate or count the word count more than once.
OK, now we can make up any variable name we want, but I'll call it word count equals.
And then there's a function called s t r word count semicolon here.
And then you could just include dollar sign content inside here.
However, to be more accurate, let's first use strip tags so that we don't count individual HTML element
tags, we just count actual content.
So strip tags call that and give that the WordPress content.
Now you could leave this line on its own.
However, if your blog post had thousands and thousands of words, maybe you would only want to bother
counting how many words there are if the word count or retimed checkboxes were checked.
Right.
Because if only the character count checkbox was checked, this would just be a wasted calculation.
So what you could do is just cut this line into your clipboard and say if parentheses create brackets
and the condition would just be if get option WCP word, count the default value of one for yes or if
get option wcp read time default value of one.
If either of those are true, then we do actually want to calculate the word count.
Cool.
So now let's just actually add a little bit of text into this paragraph.
So right below this we can just say if parentheses curly brackets if word count is set to.
Yes.
So you could actually just reuse this copy and paste this to save a bit of typing.
If this condition is true, then we would just want to add on to our HTML variable so you can just say
dollar sign html dot equals sign to add on to the end of it.
And we can just say this post has have a space concatenate on word count and then concatenate on another
string, have a space after the word count number and say words and the sentence and then let's have
a B-R tag semicolon.
OK, now let's just do the same thing for character count.
You could actually just use these three lines as a template and copy and paste that.
So this would just be WCP character count and then we would change this.
This post has this would be Kerry Derse and instead of dollar sign word count, we would say Starlee.
And this is a function that will give us the length of a string.
So call it now.
You could give it content, but I'm going to use strip tags and then give that dollar sign content.
Why don't we give this a save and test it out?
So if I refresh cool.
This post has this many words, this many characters.
Finally, let's add the approximate read time.
Now, there are a million different ways that you could calculate this, but I performed a little bit
of Google research and it said that the average adult reads two hundred, approximately two hundred
and twenty five words per minute.
So with that in mind, here's how I would set that up right below this character count option.
I would just say, well, I would actually just use these three lines as a template.
Again, some copying page, duplicate them if get option WCP read time, OK, this entire text would
be instead of this post has I would say this post will take about and then we can change this in just
a minute.
But imagine this was five, the number five and then it would say minutes to read.
So it just changes minutes and you could put the S in parentheses like it's optional minutes to read
for a bit of extra credit.
If you didn't want the parentheses and you wanted to say minute if this was one and then minutes if
it was any other number for a bit of extra credit, just look up p p ternary operator.
But for now, this will do the trick anyways.
Instead of dollar sign word count what we would really want right here.
Is word count divided by two hundred and twenty five, and then we don't want an awkward decimal, so
I would just round this up or down to the nearest whole number so you can just use the round function.
So opening parentheses there, closing parentheses here.
Let's save this and give it a try.
So if we refresh cool, this post will take about two minutes to read and let me go find a shorter post
so we can see if it'll just say just one minute.
Another example post.
Yep.
This is a much shorter post with only two small paragraphs and you see take about one minute to read.
Cool.
Just for one final detail, let's not forget to close out the ending tag for this P or paragraph element.
So just write down here before this.
If logic where we're actually returning something just right here, I would say dollar sign HTML.
Just give it a string of a closing paragraph, tag semicolon, give it a save and we're in business.
So let's test this out.
If you put this back to the beginning of the post.
So beginning of post save reload.
Perfect.
I think this looks pretty good.
One last security detail that I forgot because I was just trusting our admin users.
But even if our admin users are super trustworthy, if our database somehow had malicious data injected
into it, we never want our front end to output dynamic content without escaping it.
So on this heading level three line, just wrap this git option, wrap that inside the escape HTML function
just like this.
And that's going to bring this lesson to a close in our next video.
Before we start working on a new plug in, we're actually going to take a break to learn about translation's
or localization.
In other words, how to make your plugin easy to translate into any language in the world.
Imagine you make a plug in and it becomes very popular and people from around the world would volunteer
to translate it into their language.
So we want to make sure that our WordPress code makes that easy to do.
It should be a lot of fun to set up.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.