Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we will continue to work on our live search results, JavaScript, to be more specific,
when someone opens up the overlay and actually begins typing into this input field, we want to respond
to that event of them typing.
But as we discussed in our previous lesson, we don't want to send a search request off to the WordPress
server the millisecond someone types in the letter here.
Right.
So, for example, if someone was going to search for math, well, when they very first press the key,
we want our JavaScript to wait a second.
Right.
We don't actually want to search the WordPress database for M.
So what we're going to do is every time a user types a letter in here, we can begin a countdown or
a timer maybe to 800 milliseconds or three quarters of a second.
And then as soon as they type in another letter, we can reset that clock.
So the countdown starts over again.
And then once they finally finished typing, whatever it is they're typing and they pause for a split
second, then at that moment we can use our JavaScript to send off this search request to the WordPress
server and then we can display the results right here.
Right.
So any programs or professors, campuses or events that have to do with math.
But first things first, before we worry about managing time in JavaScript, let's first begin by just
responding to this event at all.
Right.
The event of a key being pressed on a keyboard while this text field is focused.
So right now, let's get started by jumping into our text editor and in our theme folder, let's go
into the JavaScript folder and then modules and let's open up search jass.
And if we want to be on the lookout for an event, we can just write a new bit of code within our events
section, write each one of these lines represents a different event that we're on the lookout for.
So why don't we just add a new line and we can look to the line right above it for inspiration?
Right.
Because the event of pressing down a key on your keyboard is still the event that we are looking for
this time around.
But the big difference here is the element that we want to attach this event listener to in this line
of code.
We chose the page as a whole or the document object.
So no matter where you are on the page or what you've clicked on or given focus to, the key down event
will still be registered.
Well, in this new line of code that we're going to write, we don't want to target the page as a whole.
Instead, we want to target just this one textfield element that users can type into.
We want to add the key down event listener to this specific single element so we can begin this line
of code by using query to select that element.
I can't remember the class or idea of that element off the top of my head, but if we jump into our
footer file.
And scroll down to the very bottom.
Remember, this is where we wrote that little bit of search overlay HTML.
So here's the input element, the TextField, and you'll see that we gave it an idea of search dash
term.
So back in our JavaScript, we can select that element by saying hash tag to look for an ID and then
just type it out.
Search dash term.
OK, so now that we've got that one element, we can just use the query on method.
So this takes two arguments.
The first is the name of the event.
So instead of click, we're going to use key down again.
And then the second argument is a function that you want to run in response.
So the name of this function does not matter.
We get to make a name up.
We're actually just going to call one of our methods.
So before we make up a name here down in the method section, why don't we create a brand new method
where we make up a name?
We could call it whatever we want, but why don't we call it typing logic?
Right.
Because this method is going to contain all of our logic for weighting 800 milliseconds before continuing
on.
OK, so we will build out this method a bit later on.
But back up here on this new event line for the second argument now, we can just point towards that
new method.
So this to look inside our object and then dot and then the name of that method of typing logic.
Now, before we save this and test it out in the browser, let's do a couple of things.
So first, instead of selecting the search field element right here with G query, why don't we instead
select the element up in our constructor and create a property just like we did for the open button
and the close button and the overlay div itself?
Right.
Let's do that same thing for the search field element.
My reasoning for wanting to do that is I know that we are going to need to access this element again
and again.
And remember that accessing the DOM, the Web browsers document object model is very slow compared to
the lightning fast speed of JavaScript reading its own properties.
So what I'm proposing is up here in the constructor, you could add a new line right below this at the
very bottom or stay organized and keep all of the elements near each other.
You could add a new line here and let's create a new property.
So this dot and we could name it whatever we want, why don't we call it search field and then just
set it to equal this query selector that we already wrote.
So I'm just going to copy that into my clipboard and then in its place have X as a temporary placeholder
and then up in the constructor, set this new property to equal based in our clipboard at a semicolon
at the end.
Cool.
So now down here, instead of the temporary placeholder X, we can just reference this property so we
can just say this dot search field and then we can call the on method on that property.
So this way we have this reuseable variable that points towards that element instead of us needing to
touch the dom again and again and again, which can be slow.
Cool.
Now, before we save this, one last thing I want to do is inside our typing logic method.
Why don't we add just a quick test so we can alert maybe just a pop up message that says hello from
typing logic.
Right, just so we can test things out and make sure that it's working.
So at this point, let's go ahead and save this and make sure that you have golpe watch running in the
command line.
Right.
So your JavaScript will get rebundled up and then let's go over to the browser and test this.
So open up the overlay.
And as soon as I start typing in a letter, cool.
We see that annoying alert message.
Hello from typing logic.
So that means our code is working properly.
Now let's learn how to manage and work with time in JavaScript.
Right, because we don't actually want to do something the millisecond a key is pressed down on that
text field.
So within our typing logic method, let's delete this alert test line.
And instead I want to show you how we can wait a little while in JavaScript before doing something.
So just as an extreme example, let's imagine we wanted to wait a full two seconds after the event happens
and this method runs.
So within the method we can use something in JavaScript called Set Timeout.
Set timeout takes two arguments.
The first argument is a function that you want to run.
I'm just going to say X as a temporary placeholder.
And then the second argument is how many milliseconds you want to wait before running that function.
So if we wanted to wait two seconds, that's 2000 in terms of milliseconds.
Now, back to the function that we want to run after this amount of time has passed, you're free to
type out the name of a function here, write a function that has been defined somewhere else, like
one of our methods.
Or you can always just create an anonymous function right in place here.
So to create an anonymous function, we can delete that temporary placeholder and you just type out
the word function and then parentheses and then curly brackets.
Right.
So instead of including the name of a function that points somewhere else, you could just create a
function right in place.
And then within the curly brackets, let's log out a message to the console as a test so we could say
console dialog.
And for the message, we could say this is a time out test.
OK, let's go ahead and save that.
And now back in the browser, I'm going to open up the JavaScript console so I can see if that test
message is coming through.
So click on the console and I'm going to resize my main browser window so I can see the console window
at the same time.
Cool.
OK, so let me open up the search overlay.
Remember, we still have those open and closed text messages from our previous lesson whenever you open
or closed the overlay.
But as soon as I click onto the text field and press a letter on my keyboard, you'll notice that nothing
happens immediately.
Instead, the browser waits a full two seconds and then it shows us this text message so cool.
That means our set time out is working as intended.
However, let's not forget the entire reason we wanted to add a pause or a timer in the first place.
Remember, we didn't want to flood the WordPress server with random or short, meaningless search strings.
So pretend that where we are logging this text message out to the console, pretend that this is where
we are actually going to send a request to the WordPress server.
Now, what I mean by this is if I just press one letter, right.
So if I type in the letter A now.
We see the number two here to signify that that has been ran twice and if I type in another letter.
We see this goes up to three, right, because this is brand three times, however, watch what happens,
even if I type very rapidly, like you would normally do so if I come to the website and search for
Buyology.
Whoa, we see that it climbs all the way to 12, and this is because at the moment, the way our code
is set up, every time we press a key, it's going to fire this method.
And each time that's going to create a new unique time out.
Right.
Each one of those timers with each key press is its own entity.
So if I go back and refresh the page.
And open up the search, if I type in biology, that will take me seven keystrokes, right?
And there we see seven, and this is not what we truly want.
We wouldn't want to send seven different requests to the WordPress server or in other words, we don't
want to create seven different timers or seven different time outs that are all independent of each
other.
Instead, why don't we work with just one single time out and then we can clear or reset that timer
each time this method runs.
So let me show you what I mean.
Instead of just having this set time out floating in outer space, what we can do up in our constructor
is create a new property.
So we just say this dot and then we can make up whatever name we want.
Why don't we go with typing timer and we don't even need to set it to equal a value.
We can literally just declare this as a property.
And now down in our typing logic method, instead of creating an unnamed set time out that's just sort
of floating in outer space.
Why don't we say this dot typing timer equals a set time out this way.
We are giving this time outer timer a name that we can access.
Right.
We are assigning it to this property or variable.
Now check this out right above this line.
Still within the typing logic method, we can use another tool in JavaScript named Clear Time Out.
And this is how you can reset a time out or timer.
So now within the parentheses for clear time out, we can just use the name of our property, this dot
typing timer.
So this way, every time we press a key while we are in that search field, we know that this method
is going to run and the first thing we do is clear or reset the timer.
So, for example, maybe it had been one point five seconds since the last time we had pressed down
a key.
So that would mean that there was only 500 milliseconds left on this countdown of 2000.
So this way we are resetting that or I should say we are basically getting rid of that time.
Our timer, the timer that was going to expire or execute in five hundred milliseconds, we are saying,
nope, forget about it, OK?
And then right after that, we are just re-establishing a timeout that will execute this code in two
thousand milliseconds from now.
Cool.
Now, before we save this and test it out in the browser, we do need to talk a little bit about the
keyword.
This, right.
Because the this keyword is what's allowing us to reference this variable that lives within our constructor
or I should say this property that lives within our constructor.
So down within our typing logic method in order to access the properties and methods of this object,
we are counting on the this keyword pointing towards our object.
However, remember, this function is being called by this event handler and by default, the on method
is going to set the value of this keyword to equal whatever element triggered the event.
So in this case, at this very moment within this method, the this keyword is pointing towards the
main text input field instead of our object.
Now, to fix this, that's why we've been using DOT behind this on all of our function calls.
So for this search field key down event, when we call this method, let's just be sure to add on DOT
behind this cool.
Now, at this point, let's save this and take our clear timeout reset functionality for a spin.
What we are hoping to see is that this code will not be executed for every single key press.
Instead, only when someone has truly waited 2000 milliseconds in between key presses would we hope
to see this code.
So back in the browser, let's open up the search overlay and if I start typing in biology at just a
regular typing speed.
Perfect, our code waited until there was a two second gap after a keystroke, and then our code ran
only once and that's exactly what we want.
And that's actually going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our next lesson, we will continue working towards being able to pull in real data from the WordPress
database.
So instead of this text message, we will send a request to WordPress and then we will even display
the results right here for the visitor.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.