Hello, everyone.
This video is a quick update that I'm filming in June of 2020.
So in this chapter, you and I just completed the life feature for Professor Page.
However, we wrote this JavaScript using J query.
So right now, I want to provide you with an alternative version of the file that does not use J query.
So the file we're looking at right now.
This is what we wrote together and this uses J.
Query.
But in this window, this is a version of the same module that I wrote that doesn't use J.
You can find this file available for download in the associated resources for this lesson.
This new file is a 100 percent compatible drop in replacement for our existing like Dot J.
S file.
So I can just select everything in this new file copied into my clipboard back in the existing like
J.
S just delete everything pasted in hit save.
As long as your NPM run dev task is running in the command line, that will automatically rebundle things
up.
I can refresh to make sure my event handling is not doubling up and if I click this like box it toggles
the like or removes my like.
And if I click it again it adds it back on.
Perfect.
Now in terms of the JavaScript, there's really nothing new to review in this code that we haven't already
reviewed in the other two.
J.
Query free lessons.
So once again, in the constructor, I'm wrapping things in an IF statement because I only need to run
this JavaScript.
If we're on a page that contains an element with a class of like box, I've set the WordPress nonce
access code just once up here globally.
So then that way down below in the create request and in the delete request, I don't have to provide
it each time.
Other than that, the code largely stayed the same.
OK.
That's going to wrap up this video.
I strongly encourage you to download and use this drop in replacement file as not including Jake Query
in our project will result in a smaller final bundled file that our visitors need to download.
OK, let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next one.