So you might be wondering how to have that nice.
This is the page you're on feature when using your own menu HTML.
Well, let me show you how we can do that.
So in the text editor in Header P, here's our navigation menu and here's the link for about us.
So all we need to do is use the power of PHP and if statements and only add a special class to this
element if certain conditions are met.
So let's do this in between the eye and the greater than symbol.
Let's drop in to P and let's say if parentheses curly brackets and actually if we're going to write
this if statement all on a single line instead of breaking down the new lines, we actually don't want
the curly brackets.
Now we will fill out the condition that lives in the parentheses in just a moment.
But if it's true, what do we want to do?
Well, we want to echo out a little bit of HTML, so single quote, single quote.
And within the quotes we want to echo out class equals double quotes.
And the class that we want to add is current menu item because that corresponds with the special classes
and counts that I've already written for us.
So that will make the element light up as yellow to indicate it's the current page.
So now all we need to do is fill out the condition within these parentheses.
So check this out.
There is a function in WordPress named is Underscore Page and then you can give it an argument of the
slug for the page that you're looking for if you can't remember what a slug is or refresh your memory.
So, for example, on the about US page, notice how the Eurail ends in about us.
So that means about Dasch.
US is the slug for this page.
So in our code is page about us.
And this function that I've got highlighted right now will return.
True, if that's the page you're on, otherwise it returns false.
So then we will only echo out this class if it makes sense to write.
So let's save this and refresh.
Perfect.
Now, the only other thing we need to account for is if you go to a child page of about us.
So on our history, ideally we would still want the about us link in the header to light up, even though
we're not on that page directly.
We're on one of its children pages.
So here's what we can do in the code to make that happen within the parentheses for our if statement
for the condition right after this first condition here in between the two parentheses, we can say
or and then list another condition.
So let's say or if the current page has a parent of about us.
So to check for that, we can say or WP get post parent ID and it's a function, so give it its own
set of parentheses.
And within those parentheses we need to tell this function which page we are trying to find the parent
ID of.
So we just want to tell it to make that look up for whatever page the user is currently visiting.
So we could say get the I'd call that function, but in order to save ourselves some sanity, instead
we can just say zero and WordPress will understand the zero to mean look up the current page.
OK, so this code that I'm highlighting right now will return an idea of the parent page.
And then let's say if that returns an idea that matches the idea of the about US page.
Well, if that evaluates to true, then we want to echo out the special class.
So here we just need to type in the numerical ID for the about US page.
So to find that out, you can jump into your admin because your number might be different than mine.
In fact, I can almost guarantee that it will be so if I click on the About US page on my computer,
it has an ID of sixteen, but yours might be something different.
So now back in our code we can just type in sixteen.
Cool.
So altogether what our if statement is saying is if the current page is the about US page or if the
current page is parent page is the about us page then echo out this special class.
So let's save this and refresh the front end of our website.
Cool, so I'm on a child page of about us, but it's still knows to stay lit up up in the navigation
menu and that's going to bring this lesson to a close.
At this point, you now have a basic understanding of using one of two setups, dynamic WordPress menus
or your own custom menus.
It's totally up to you.
But I encourage you to follow along with me because I think it's nice to know how to have fine grained
control like this.
Now, in our next lesson, we're going to switch gears and begin building out the blog section of our
website.
Should be a lot of fun.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you then.