Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to continue working on our live search results, JavaScript.
OK, so the first thing that I want to work on is if someone opens up the search overlay and after they
type something in and then pause for a second or two, instead of waiting 2000 milliseconds to output
this test message to the console instead, why don't we practice outputting real HTML content into this
area of the overlay?
Right.
Because that's where we want the real search results to be displayed.
Now, before we worry about JavaScript, why don't we first make sure that we have an empty HTML div
that's positioned to sit right about here.
So in order to edit the HTML for the search overlay, let's jump into our text editor and open up footer
dot BHP.
And down at the very bottom of this file, remember we added this search overlay div OK, now right
below this inner search overlay top div, so right below this, but still within the overall search
overlay, outer div.
Let's dropdown and create a brand new div and give it a class of container and then within this div
let's create another give and give it an idea of search overlay.
Underscore, underscore results.
The name doesn't matter.
I'm just making this up so that it's something unique we can target in our JavaScript for now.
Just as a quick test, if you typed hello one, two, three and go and refresh the page and there we
see it.
Cool.
So let's delete that.
Hello text message from the HTML so that this div is completely empty and instead let's use JavaScript
to add content to this div after the two thousand millisecond delay has passed.
So right now let's jump in to our JavaScript folder and then modules and into the search JS file.
And let's begin by creating a new property in our constructor that selects that new empty div that we
just created.
So in the constructor function, maybe at the very top of it we can just say this dot and then we can
make up whatever name we want.
I'm going to call it results div and set it to equal.
So dollar sign parentheses to use J query and then for the selector we use hash tag to select by the
IDE and remember we gave it an ID of search overlay, underscore underscore results.
OK, now next, let's scroll down to our Taiping Logic method.
Remember this is where we created the set time outer timer that's going to wait two thousand milliseconds
after a keystroke before running this code.
Right.
This is what's logging out to the console.
This is a time out test.
So now instead of logging out a message to the console, we want to output content into that empty results
div so we could write code right within this anonymous function to add content to that div.
Right.
We could delete this console log line, but in the name of staying organized and writing clean code
instead of using an anonymous inline function like this, why don't we delete that.
Remember a set time out takes two arguments.
The first is a function that you want to run and then how long you want to wait.
So instead of spelling out the function, write in place here.
Why don't we create a brand new method right below this?
And let's name this new method.
Get results, parentheses, curly brackets, OK, and then let's tell our time out to call that method
once the time has passed.
So for the first argument, we can just say this dot get results and then while we're at it, why don't
we tack on dot find this so that we can access our object properties and methods from within the git
results method.
Now, a bit later on within this method is where we will actually make a request to the WordPress server.
But for now, let's just try to output some sample text into that empty results div.
So remember, we can access that empty div with this new property we created up in the constructor.
The name is results div.
So down in our new method we can say this dot results div and then we can edit the HTML for that div
by using the query method named for each HTML and then within the parentheses, let's just say quotes.
Imagine real search results here.
OK, let's go ahead and save that and test it out, open up the search overlay, type in a bit of text
and then two thousand milliseconds later we see.
Imagine real search results here, so that works, but in my opinion, the user experience is quite
bad because there's this big gap in time from when the user starts typing until they finally see some
sort of feedback here.
So what I propose instead is the millisecond that someone types in even the very first letter, we should
display a spinning loader icon animation right here in that empty results div.
And then once our results method finally runs, this text can replace the spinning load or animation.
So let me show you what I mean.
Back in our code, within our typing logic method, right above this line where we create the time out
and right below this clear time outline, let's add a new line and let's just target that empty results
div so this dot results div and let's just set its HTML single quotes so that way we can use double
quotes within the HTML that we want to add.
And let's just add an empty div and the important part.
Let's give the opening div tag a class of Spiner Dash Loader.
I've already written the CSFs for us that corresponds with this name.
So if we go ahead and save this and jump back to the browser, let's open up the search overlay and
as soon as I press even one letter.
Perfect, so that way, as soon as someone types a letter, they get immediate feedback with that spinner
loader icon, but we are still waiting for a pause in their typing to actually create or send off a
request.
Right.
Or in this case, display this sample text.
So we're sort of getting the best of both worlds.
However, you will notice that if I type in something like a full word, you'll notice that after each
keystroke, the spinner animation is resetting.
So that looks pretty choppy.
So what we should do instead is write our code in a way that we only apply this code that adds the spinner
div.
We only do that if it's not already being displayed.
So that way we don't constantly overwrite it on each new keystroke like this.
So let me show you what I mean.
The way that I would achieve this is up in our constructor function.
I'm going to create a new property that keeps track of the state that the spinner is currently in.
Now, it doesn't matter where in the constructor, but maybe right underneath this line, let's just
say this dot and then we can make up a property name, let's call it is Spiner visible and by default,
let's set it defaults.
OK, now down within our Taiping logic method.
Remember, this is the line of code we wrote just a moment ago that adds the Spiner Llodra div.
So let's just wrap this within an if statement.
So I'm going to cut this line into my clipboard and then in its place I will say if parentheses curly
brackets and the condition that I want to check for is if this dot is biner visible only if that is
false, meaning if it's not already visible do I want to make it visible.
So you could say if this equals false.
But remember a shorter way of checking if an item is false, as you can just place an exclamation mark
right before it.
OK, so only if that is false do we want to and then just paste in your clipboard.
OK, now if this line of code is going to make the Spiner visible, then right after that still within
the statement, we should probably set that property to true.
So let's say this dot is biner visible and just set it to true.
OK, now before we save this, remember that this get results function.
This is what's going to hide the Spiner once it's ready and it's going to override the div with this
little bit of text.
So in other words, as soon as this line of code runs, then the spinner will no longer be visible.
So right after this line of code, let's just say this dot is Spiner visible and set it to false.
OK, so this way we are managing that property so we can truly trust its value in this if statement.
So let's go ahead and save this and test out Taiping to open up the overlay.
And if I type in biology, notice that after every keystroke the Spiner icon is not resetting.
So it's no longer copy.
And this is now a great experience.
And once I stop typing for a second there we see our immagine search results here message.
However, you might notice that in this TextField, if I even use the arrow keys on my keyboard to move
my cursor around, that counts as a keystroke.
That will trigger the loading spinner and also try to send out another search request potentially.
And the same is true with the control key or the shift or windows or command keys.
So why don't we change our JavaScript so that if you press a key that doesn't actually change the search
string in any way, then there's no need to trigger the lotus spinner or do anything at all.
Now, there are a lot of different ways to code this, but what I'm going to do is up in the constructor
function.
I'm going to create a property that keeps track of the previous search value.
So check this out.
Up in the constructor, let's create a new line.
Let's create a new property.
So this dot and we could name it whatever we want, but I'm going to call it previous value and we do
not need to set it to equal anything yet.
We can just declare it as a property and then down in our typing logic method right before this method
ends.
So down here at the very bottom of this method, let's just update that property.
So let's say this dot previous value equals and then let's just fetch the value of the search field
so we can access our search field by saying this dot search field, because remember, we created a
property that points towards that element.
And then we can just use the vow method in January, and that will give us the value.
OK, so this method is going to run after every keystroke and we aren't updating the previous value
property until the very end of this method.
So up here at the very beginning of this method, why don't we write an if statement?
So if parentheses, curly brackets and for the condition, let's say only if the current value does
not equal the previous value.
Only if that's the case do we want to run all of this other code.
So for the condition, let's say if the current value so this search field dot, Val and Val is a function,
so it gets its own parentheses.
So if that value does not equal the previous value of this dot previous value, so only if the keystroke
that they just pressed actually changed the search string in some way.
Do we want to run any of this code?
So now we can just cut and paste or drag and drop this code to live within this if statement.
So I'm going to select from clear time out all the way down to our set time outline.
So basically everything except that previous value line that we wrote just a moment ago.
Let's cut that into our clipboard and then let's just paste it into this if statement.
OK, let's go ahead and save that and test it out in the browser, open up the search, search for by
all gee, OK.
And then if I press an arrow key on my keyboard, woops, we still see the loading icon.
So something's going wrong here.
Aha.
I know what the issue is.
So it comes down to key down versus key up.
In this case we want to use key up instead of key down.
So let's change this and then I will explain why.
The reason for this is because the key down event fires.
So immediately after a key press that it doesn't even give the search field a true chance to update
its own value.
In other words, when this was set to key down and then we were trying to update the previous value
property with the current value, the key down event was being fired before the Web browser had truly
even updated the internal value for that field.
So by changing the event to keep up instead of key down, the Web browser will have enough time, an
extra couple of milliseconds to actually register the input value.
OK, so with this change in place, let's go ahead and save tested out one more time, open this up,
search for a term.
And now if I pressed the arrow key or the shift gear control key or any other key that doesn't actually
manipulate the search string, our code is working as intended and it doesn't trigger any changes.
Perfect.
Now, the next thing I want to work on is if someone completely deletes the search string so that the
search field is empty.
In that case, there's no need to show the spinning loader animation.
So let me put it back to biology.
If someone deletes it.
So there's nothing there, I think we should just immediately completely empty out the results div and
reset or clear any timeouts that are currently counting down.
So that way we don't potentially send a search request to WordPress for literally nothing.
So in order to make that change, back in our text editor, if the keystroke in some way changed the
search string in this case, hitting the backspace key on your keyboard would indeed do that, then
we still want to run the clear time out.
Right, because if someone empties out the search field, we definitely do want to cancel that countdown
timer.
So we want this line of code to run no matter what.
But right below this clear time outline, let's drop down and write a new line of code and let's create
a new if statement.
So if parentheses, curly brackets and for the condition, let's say only if the search field value
is not blank.
So we can say this dot search field and then we can get its value or whatever the user has currently
typed in by running the vowel method.
And as long as the field is not completely blank, this will evaluate to true.
So if that's true, then within the curly brackets, we will do something here very shortly.
But if this is false and if the field is completely blank, we want to do something different.
So right after the closing curly brackets for this if statement, we can say else curly brackets as
a backup plan, do this instead.
So if the field is empty in this else code runs, let's just completely empty out the results div so
we can just say this dot results div and we can change its HTML by running the bakery method html and
then let's just set it to equal an empty pair of quotes.
Now after this line of code runs, there's a zero percent chance that the spinner loader icon will be
visible.
So right after that line, let's be sure to set this dot.
Is Spiner visible.
Let's set it to equal false.
OK, and now before we save this, let's not forget about the do something comment instead of that comment.
We just want to move this code that we were running before to live where this is.
So let's cut and paste or move this.
I'm going to begin by selecting from this if statement checks to see if the Spiner icon is currently
visible or not.
So select that if statement and then let's also select our set time outline.
So let's cut that into our clipboard.
And then up here, let's replace the do something comment by pasting in your clipboard.
Let's go ahead and save that and test it out.
Let's search for something, and then if I delete or empty the text field, perfect, our results area
is immediately cleared and we don't see an unnecessary loader icon.
Now, there's only one final remaining thing I want to take care of in this lesson.
So if I closed the search overlay, we can see that behind the scenes right here, I've temporarily
added a test input field.
Now, this placement doesn't make much sense, but that's not the point.
The point is, is that you're probably going to have a text input or a text area field somewhere else
on your website, maybe on a contact us page, for example.
And I want to make sure that our search module doesn't negatively affect other inputs.
So, for example, if I click into this field, I can start typing.
Right.
But if I press the esky, remember that the ASCII is going to trigger our overlay to open.
So that's really awkward.
And it could be frustrating for users.
They think they're typing in a field, but then if they hit the esky, they accidentally open something
that they weren't intending.
So what I propose here to fix this is if a text area or input field currently has focus, then in that
case we do not want the keystroke to open our overlay.
So what we can do back in our code is scroll down to our key press despatcher method.
And remember, this block of code is saying if the key that was just pressed has a key code of eighty
three, which is the key, and if the overlay is not already open, then open it.
So let's just add a third condition right here.
We can say ampersand, ampersand and let's check to see if any text fields on the page are currently
focused so we can use J query and we can select any inputs or comma any text areas.
And then once we've selected those, we can use the query method named IS and provide it in argument
of quotes, call in focus.
So if any field is currently focused, this will evaluate to true.
But if we want to check for the opposite of that, we can just put an exclamation mark right before
it.
OK, and this is the perfect condition.
Check now all of these stars have to align in order for the overlay to be opened.
So let's save this and test it out.
If I click on to this TextField here and type the ASCII, nothing happens.
But as soon as I click out of that text field and press the ASCII, there's the overlay.
Perfect.
And that's going to bring this lesson to a close.
Now, here's the exciting part in our very next lesson.
We are finally going to learn how to actually send a request to the WordPress server or database.
Let's keep it rolling and I will see you then.