Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to add the ability to both create a pet and delete a pet from our front
end.
Let's jump into the action.
So we're on our slash pet adoption page and maybe down at the very bottom below the table.
Let's add a form where you can type in the name for a new pet and then submit the form and it will actually
get added to the database.
Now, to reduce the amount of boilerplate busywork we need to do, I'm not going to have fields where
we choose the species and the weight and the hobby.
I'm just going to have a field where you enter their name and then we can use our generate pet function
to sort of fill in random values for all of the other fields.
The point is, once you learn how to do this for one field, you can make the form as complex as you
want to to get started.
Let's jump into our template file.
So in VS Code in our ANC folder template pitstop, let's scroll down and look for the closing table
tag.
So after the table, I will say, well, let's go into PPY.
I'm going to begin with an if statement to check to see if the current user has admin privileges.
Right.
Only admin users and not just random guests should be able to even see this form to create a new pet.
So I'll see if parentheses curly brackets, the condition would just be if current user can.
And let's give it quotes.
Administrator.
OK, now I want to include HTML here, so I'll exit here and enter here inside.
Let's type form and then hit tab.
We will absolutely circle back to the action value here.
So let's leave that blank for the moment.
But first let's get the form up and running visually.
So let's give it a class of create pet form.
And while we're here so we don't forget, let's give it a method of equals.
All caps post OK, inside the opening and closing form tags, let's have a paragraph.
So just P tab and say enter just the name for a new pet.
It's species weight and other details will be randomly generated.
Maybe below this paragraph we can have an input, so just input it.
Tab type can be text.
Let's give it a name, you can name it anything, but maybe just incoming pet name.
We can give it a placeholder and just say name, dot, dot, dot below that.
Let's have a submit button.
So button hit tab and just type add pet.
Let's give this a save just for a quick visual test.
And if we refresh down at the bottom, I'm not logged in as an admin user, so I don't see anything.
You might need to do this too.
But I'm going to pause the recording and log in, OK, now that I'm logged in with my admin account,
perfect.
I do see this form area.
Now let's talk about what should actually happen when you submit the form.
There are a few different ways that you could handle this.
So by default in HTML form will sort of submit to its own.
You RL you might remember back in the first chapter of this plug in section, we had a settings page
that used to sort of submit to its own Eurail and we checked to see if a certain variable had been set
so you could use that same strategy here and just include code to handle the processing within our template.
However, I want to show you what I like to do in this situation.
Back in our code on the opening form tag, let's talk about the action value.
So which you are l do we want to submit the form to.
Well, in these quotes drop into P and we're going to echo and let's use escape.
You throw in these parentheses, let's give it admin U RL, which is a function itself and finally give
it a value of admin Dasch post P.
So we're posting to a WordPress system file.
Now when most people see the name of this file or address, they get a bit scared.
They think, oh, for security reasons, we should never have the front end post to an admin file.
Right.
Well, if you do a bit of research, the WordPress team fully expects us to use this on our front end,
as we'll see when we set this up in just a moment.
This is a very flexible way of having server side code run when a specific event happens.
This way, we can keep our code tucked away in our main maybe index plug in file instead of in this
template file.
Right.
I don't want to have to litter this file with code up at the top that checks to see if a certain value
is set.
I would want to keep that handling or processing code somewhere else before we save this file and see
how in the.
World admin post VP works, we just need to add one more detail to our form, so maybe right above this
input, let's have another input.
So input tab on your keyboard.
Let's change the type to hidden.
We need to give it a name of exactly.
Action so we're not making this up.
WordPress will be specifically looking for this value or name of exactly.
Action.
And now the value that we give it, we can make this up.
So I'll make up a value of create pet.
OK, now let's save this and let me explain how admin post works.
Essentially, when we post to this U.
RL WordPress, we'll see our field that has a name of action and it's going to use this value to create
a specific hook that we can hook on to in our main plug in file.
So remember this create pet value.
And right now I want you to jump in in our sidebar to our main plugin file, which is named New Database
Tables.
So up towards the very top of this file where we're adding different actions and filters.
Check this out.
We can just add a new actions.
Also add action, parentheses, semicolon, just like always.
We're going to give this to arguments.
The first argument is the name of the action hook.
So we would just give it a value.
So string of text of admin, underscore, post, underscore, and then whatever name we gave it.
So we gave it a name of create pet in that hidden field.
So now admin post P will recognize that we've hooked on to this action and it will simply call whatever
function we provide here for us.
Within that function, we can do whatever we want.
We have complete freedom and then when we're done, we can perhaps just redirect the user right back
to this same template screen.
So do this with me instead of the placeholder B, let's make up a method name that we can create in
just a moment.
So I'll use the array callable syntax first argument dollar.
Sign this.
Let's make up a name of maybe create uppercase pet.
OK, now I'll just create a function with that name.
So function create pet parentheses, curly brackets.
Within this function, the first thing I want to do is check to make sure that the current user actually
has admin privileges.
So if parentheses curly brackets I'll even have an else curly brackets.
So the condition would just be if again current user can give it a value of administrator.
So it include the real code here.
But if they're not an admin user, I would just redirect them to our homepage.
So WP redirect semicolon and to get the homepage URL, it's just a function of site.
You URL if they do have admin privileges, what do we want to do.
Well, let's use our generate pet to randomly generate a pet object or pet array, so I'll just create
a variable so it's equal generate pet but then I'll overwrite the pet name with whatever value the user
typed into this field.
So I could just say I'm pet look inside that array for the pet name item and then just set it to equal.
I'll start by using the sanitized text field function semicolon inside here.
Well because our form was submitted using a post request and you can just say dollar sign, underscore
post, look inside that array.
And remember we named our input that you'll actually type the name into.
We gave it a name of incoming pet name.
So that's what we would include here.
Just quote incoming pet name.
Cool.
So now we would just want to save this pet array into the database.
So on a new line, I would just say Global Dollar Sign WP DB.
We can now look inside that for its insert function.
So dollar sign WP DB look inside it for insert semicolon.
We give this to arguments.
The first is the table that we want to insert into which we can just look on our class for table name.
Second argument is just dollar sign pay.
OK, once we've done that, let's redirect the user back to the pet adoption page.
So it's just our home page URL and then slash pet adoption.
So WP redirect parentheses to call it site.
You rl inside there.
Just give it a value of slash pets dash adoption.
Before we save this and test it out, I'll let you know that WordPress will actually only run this exact
hook if the current user is logged in.
Now it doesn't check to see that they're an administrative user, just that they're logged in with any
even just a guest or basic editor account.
So here's what we can do.
You can duplicate this exact line of code, just copy and paste it on this copy, change the hook name
to admin post, underscore, no priv underscore and then whatever your name is.
So create pet.
So I didn't make up this no priv no privileges portion.
WordPress will now call this function if a user isn't logged in at all.
In both cases we're calling the exact same create pet function, which is fine because we're making
sure that the user is an administrator actually within that function.
Anyways, let's save this and test it out so I'll refresh the front end just to make sure the form is
submitting to the correct you URL and I'll give it a test name of miaows a lot and submit.
It redirected me back to this page, but because I have over 100000 pets, there's no easy way for me
to see that pet in these results.
However, if we go into Add Mynor and click on our table, click select data and then go to the very
last page of results.
Perfect.
You can see the very last row has a name of miaows a lot at this point.
Let's use the strategy.
We just learned to add a delete option for each row so you can imagine there's an extra column here
with maybe a red X that you click on to delete that pet.