Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to start working on the front end JavaScript for our BLACKTIP to put things
into perspective, let's preview the finished product of what we're going to build together.
So when you're viewing the public front, end of our website in a post, uses the are you paying attention,
Blacktip?
Well, this is how we're going to present the question in the answers to the user.
So if I click on one of the wrong answers, real time with client side, JavaScript will show that sorry
message.
But if you click on the correct answer, we can show them this message and then after it fades away,
you can see we've sort of indicated the correct answer as a review.
So then as they're scrolling through the article, if they come back to that piece, they can see which
answers were correct and incorrect.
So right now, let me switch back to this tab where I have not written the front end JavaScript and
let's set it up together.
So if I open a blog post in this version of WordPress, you'll see that all that's getting output for
that type is today.
The sky is blank and the grass is blank.
So let's move forward from this point together.
Let's begin by jumping into our text editor and in our source or SIRC folder.
Right now, we just have the one index Morgus file and this represents the edit version for our block
type.
Let's create an entirely separate JavaScript file for the front end output of the block.
So in the Sarsae folder, all click new file.
You can name it anything, I'll name it front and dot js in our new file, just as a quick test to make
sure that it's actually loading, let's say alert.
This is the front end.
J.S. Let's give this a save.
And before we move on, we do need to slightly adjust the WordPress automated JavaScript package so
that it's aware of our new file.
To explain what I mean, I need you to jump in to our package JSON file.
Right now, we're interested in the build and start task, so by default, without us configuring anything,
these two tasks, no to look in a folder called SAAC specifically for a file named index DOT.
In other words, these tasks have no idea that our new front end JavaScript file even exists.
So we just need to modify these two scripts a little bit.
So do this with me within the quotes here, right after WP scripts build, let's say, space, and we
just list out the files we want to work with.
So SIRC indexed JS space for another file, S.A.C. slash front end JS and then just do the exact same
thing for the start task so you can even just copy and paste those two values, add them on right after,
start inside the string.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
We'll know that it's working properly.
If in the build folder we see a new front end JS file.
So let's fire it up, open up your command line and run npm run start.
If yours was already running, just quit and restart it perfect, you can see that generated in the
build folder, front end jazz.
OK, now before we go ahead and use HP to tell WordPress to load this file on the front end of our Web
site, let's first set up a little bit of success.
But because this is a course about WordPress and not writing hundreds of lines of success together,
I actually want you to download an CSC file right now.
So in the downloadable resources for this lesson, you'll find a file named Front End Dot, SPSS.
I want you to pause the video lesson right now.
Download this file and move it into your SIRC folder.
So this is my WordPress plugin folder we've been working on together.
I'm just going to move the front end access to live inside the S.A.C. folder, right.
So that it's side by side with our index access file.
Cool.
Now, let's tell our front end jobs file to use or load or import that CSC file.
So up at the very top we can say import, string, urtext, dot slash for the current directory and
then front end dot s success.
As soon as you save that, you'll know if it was successful or not because you should see a front end
dot CSC file appear in your build folder.
So now that we have our new front end JavaScript and access ready, let's go right the IP so that WordPress
actually loads those files.
So let's jump in to our index file.
And just like almost everything else in WordPress, there are many, many different ways to achieve
the same thing.
So, for example, within our admin assets function, when we register our block type, we have these
properties like editor script and editor style.
Well, you can include properties simply called script and another one called style.
And you just point towards an asset, even though that's very easy and intuitive to set up.
I do not use this approach because it loads your files, even if a poster page isn't currently using
that block type.
So, for example, on our blog listing page, if I go to a post, for example, example, blog post,
this post isn't using our quiz or are you paying attention block time.
So I don't want to even load the front end JavaScript or success in that case.
I only want to bother wasting the user's bandwidth and loading those files if the current page actually
needs them.
So while that approach would have been very intuitive, instead, let me show you an approach that might
seem weird at first, but has worked perfectly for me.
So we actually want to look for our HTML render callback function right now.
It's just responsible for outputting the HTML that says today this guy is blank and the grass is blank.
I like to load the files within this function because we know that this will only run if the current
page or post actually uses our block type.
So here's what I'll do within the body of this function right before this Obbie start.
Let's add a new line.
Let's say WP on Q script, parentheses, semicolon.
We're going to give this three arguments.
The first is a short name that we make up.
Let's call it a tension front end.
The second argument is just a path pointing towards our file.
So let's say plug in Dürer, you rl after that, concatenate on quotes, build slash front end js within
the parentheses for this plug.
WRAL, let's say underscore, underscore, firehole, underscore, underscore.
And then for the third and final argument, it's just an array of dependencies.
So array parentheses and we only need one dependency substring a text called WP Dash Element.
We will explain in detail what exactly WP element is in just a moment.
OK, right after this line, let's add our CFS file.
So WP on Q style semicolon.
Let's make up a name, maybe a tension front end styles.
The second argument is just a path so you can even just copy and paste from plugging you RL to the end
of this string.
Just copy and paste that and just change the file that we're looking for to dot CSC instead of Jase.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So the first thing I want to show you is on the admin screen.
If you go into the editor for a post that uses our block type, you can see that it's loading our JavaScript
and we don't want this.
We only want to load it on the front end public portion of the website.
Now, the fix for this is very simple.
Just wrap these two lines that we just wrote that load the assets, just wrap them in an IF statement.
So I'll just cut those two on queue lines.
We just wrote into my clipboard and then I'll say if parentheses curly brackets for the condition if
exclamation to check for the opposite.
If is admin, it's right if we're on the admin dashboard backend opposite of that.
So only if on the public front end and then just paste back in those two lines if we give that a save.
Now the editor screen doesn't load the JavaScript perfect.
But if we go to the front end.
But let me go back to the blog page that actually uses that block type perfect.
Our JavaScript is loading.
I really like this approach because even if you're on a blog or category listing page that's going to
show five or ten blog posts and maybe they're all using our block type, WordPress is smart enough that
if it sees this line of code again using the exact same.
Short name for that asset, WordPress, is smart enough to not try to load the file again, it's only
going to load the file once.
So I'm sure there's 10 or 20 different other ways that you could load these front end files.
But I've had very good luck with this approach.
Let's talk about what our next step should be.
So I think we should write a bit of actual front end JavaScript to render a react component here.
Right.
Instead of this today, the sky is blank.
We want JavaScript generated content right here.
So let me show you what I would do back in our FTP.
Let's find the code that's currently outputting today.
The sky is blank.
So right now it's an H3.
We don't want this line at all.
So I'm going to get rid of that entire line.
And instead, let's have a div an empty div for now.
But let's be sure to give it a class that we can reference in our JavaScript.
So I'm going to say div class equals just so you and I are on the same page, let's name it paying dash
attention dash update dash me.
And while we're here, let's just copy that name into our clipboard so we don't have to remember it
in our JavaScript.
So just be sure to select and copy that.
Let's give this a save.
And now I want you to jump in to our brand new front end JS file that we created at the start of this
video.
OK, so we no longer need this alert test message.
Instead, let's create a variable that stores any and all elements with that paying attention.
Update me class.
So let's say const you could name it anything I'll call it divs to update equals document query selector
all I spelled that wrong one is right there.
OK, that's a method inside it.
You give it a string of text and then this is where you would say a dot for a RCSC like class selector
and then just paste in your clipboard.
And actually before I go any further, I do want to explain my thought process here.
But I think to make things clear of why I'm doing things this way, we need to make sure that our blog
post page is using more than one instance of our block type.
Let me explain.
So let's make sure we have more than just one instance of the block type.
So if you edit your blog post, we have one quiz question here, maybe one or two paragraphs down below
it.
I'm just going to add in another instance.
So are you paying attention?
Phrenologists say what species is barks a lot.
Fish, hamster or dog they dog is the correct answer and click update.
So the idea here, let me jump back to the JavaScript is from a JavaScript perspective, we don't know
if there's one instance of the block on the page or if there's twenty instances.
So we're just selecting all of them and then let's loop through that collection.
So Divs to update DOT for each parentheses, we give it a function, function in parentheses, curly
brackets.
Let's make sure to have a parameter.
I'll just call it div.
So now right here inside the body of our function, div will represent the current element that's been
looped to.
And just for a quick test before we get in to react, let's say div dot inner html equals hello, just
for a proof of concept to make sure your code is working so far.
So if we save that and then go refresh the front end, you'll see one instance of hello right here.
And if I scroll down a little bit there it is a second time.
Perfect.
So from this point now we just want to use a react component instead of just using this built in inner
HTML approach.
So let's delete this line and let's talk about how we use react from the front end of our website.
First of all, let's create an entirely separate function down here that will be our react component.
This will be very similar to the edit component with our JSM from the admin side of things.
So let's say function and we want to start it with a capital letter.
The name doesn't matter, but let's call it maybe just Cui's parentheses, curly brackets.
Let's return a little bit of JSM so parentheses so we can have multiple lines of James X, let's have
a div with a specific class so type div dot paying attention front end and then hit tab on your keyboard
for now inside the div.
Let's just have a string of text that says hello from react.
For now the question becomes how do we actually render or display this react component onto the page.
Well do this with me up at the very top of our file.
Let's import a few things.
So import, let's say uppercase react from quotes, the react package.
Now you might be thinking to yourself, Brad, we've never said npm install react.
That's OK.
We'll see.
Where this comes into play in just a moment, let's also import react, Dom, so that's uppercase R
and then all uppercase dom from quotes the React Dom package.
Now, again, we didn't even install this package.
I'll explain what's going on very shortly.
For now, let's go leverage react, Don.
So within our for each function, we're just going to say, react, dom, dot render.
So we're calling its render method.
We're going to give it to arguments.
The first is the react component that we want to display.
So you type it out as if it's in HTML or element.
So less than Cui's self-closing tag just like this, right.
That's what we named our component.
The second argument is the actual HTML dom element on the page that you want to render this into.
So that's why we have that empty div.
So the second argument is just div.
And while we're at it now that we've actually updated or rendered something into that div, why don't
we remove the update me placeholder class doing so is not necessary.
But this way in the future, if you ever want to adapt this code so that it runs on the fly, perhaps
as new posts are getting added to the page via lazy loading.
Well, this should be a step in the right direction, right?
You can at least keep track of which elements have already been hydrated with JavaScript.
So I would just say div dot class list, dot remove and then you just give it the name of the class
you want to get rid of.
So it would be paying attention.
Update me.
Let's give this a save and see how it works.
So on the front end, if we refresh awesome.
We have two instances and they're using a little bit of that success that we imported at the start of
this video.
So things are working.
Now, I want to talk about how the react and react DOM packages are working because we never installed
those with NPM to explain this.
We can actually look at our again when we loaded our front end JavaScript, remember, we gave it and
dependency of WP dash element.
Now I can tell you that WP dash element is really just WordPress version of react.
They've essentially abstracted react into their own script.
Let me explain.
So in your browser, if you open up your dev tools in the console, if we type WP dot element press
enter, if you check this out, this is essentially just react.
So it has the core functions of react, but it also has react Dom sort of built into it because you'll
notice there's a method named render.
So the cool thing here is the official WordPress JavaScript package that we're using when it sees that
we're trying to import, react or react.
Dom, it's smart enough that in its Web configuration, it just looks in the global browser scope for
WP dash element.
So we're not even loading react and react dom ourselves.
WordPress will just load its own version of React for US.
And you can prove this to yourself, because if you look at the file size of our built front end JavaScript,
so if I go into the build folder, here's the front end JS file that our task is building.
If you inspect that, you can see that it's only seven kilobits.
So what I'm proving here is that this does not have react and react.
Dom bundled up in it here in my downloads folder.
I have react and react, Dom, and you can see that there are a hundred and twenty one plus eleven kilobytes
large.
The reason this is so cool is because it makes it so effortless and seamless to use react across multiple
plug ins.
Right.
So you and I could create 20 different plug ins that all leverage react and we have 100 percent confidence
that we're not making users download unnecessary code.
We're always just pointing towards this one copy of React that WordPress loads for us.
Now, this is going to bring this video to a close.
But in our very next lesson, we're going to talk about how to bridge the gap between PHP and JavaScript.
In other words, how can we access the actual attributes within our react component?
Write the attributes are the actual question and answer values and the correct answer property.
This should be fun, and I also think it'll be a real aha moment.
Let's keep the momentum rolling and I'll see you then.