Hello, everyone, in this lesson, we're going to learn how to take the attributes for a block type
and pass that data into our client side JavaScript.
Let's begin by assessing the situation so we have our instances of our block type.
I have one instance here and another here, and these are being stored in the database along with the
other content for this post.
So if we look at it in the database, here's the content for that post.
So it starts with a standard default paragraph.
Then we have an instance of our are you paying attention, blacktip?
Right.
There's the attributes.
So there's the question and then there's the array of answers.
The correct answer is the third item in the array.
And then we have another standard paragraph and then another instance of our block with the attributes.
The question, answer, correct answer.
So the challenge of this lesson is how do we get this data, these attributes into JavaScript?
Well, if we jump back to P for a moment, so if you go into your index file within our render callback
function that we named the HTML, we've already seen that you can access the data from this parameter
that we set up dollar sign attributes.
Remember in previous lesson within this function we output today the sky is blank color and then we
dug into the attributes parameter.
But now we don't just want to output traditional static text onto the page.
We need a way to hand the data off to JavaScript and let JavaScript do the work.
Now, here's the tricky part, though, as far as I can see, even after extensively researching this
topic, I don't believe there is a, quote, official WordPress way of handling this.
Now, don't get me wrong, it's not very difficult to set up.
It's just that WordPress itself doesn't really offer any guidance or documentation or functions that
we can use.
So we need to get a little bit creative.
And that means that if you ask a hundred different developers how to use JavaScript and react to render
your block types on the front end, you'll likely get 100 completely different answers.
Having said that, let me show you the approach that I like to use.
So we already have this empty div, right, paying attention.
Update me.
Let's just add a little bit of content inside this div.
So inside it, I'll go into AP and I'm going to echo the results of a function called WP JSON in code.
In these parentheses, let's just give this function our dollar sign attributes.
So dollar sign attributes, let's give this a save.
But before we go test it out, let's update our front end JS file and just temporarily so we can actually
see what the P is outputting.
Let's comment out this line, this line where we're rendering our react components for the start of
that.
Just for a moment, let's comment that out.
So slash, slash, give that a save.
Be sure that your command line is running with NPM run, start.
OK, if we go refresh on the front end, cool.
There's the first instance and there's my second instance.
So to follow what's going on, essentially p loaded that data from the database.
Now in the database it's stored in the JavaScript or JSON syntax and then because we're using a dynamic
block type.
Well when we receive it in our function as attributes that's getting converted into a P array, but
then we can convert it right back into actual JSON with this function.
However, it isn't actually JSON, right.
It's just text being output to a webpage.
For example, these quotes around the properties you can see instead of a simple plain quote, they're
angled quotes, which usually messes up the browsers.
JSON interpreter So here's what I like to do.
If we go back into our FTP, this code that we just wrote that outputs that, let's wrap it within a
pre tag.
So at the start of this we'll say pre for a pre tag and then just close out the pre tag right before
the closing div tag like this if we save that and give that a try.
Cool.
So that puts out the actual true content for the text.
So now that's just a plain quote and we should have no problem parsing this as true JSON.
So let me show you what we're going to do.
We don't need anyone to ever visually see this data, so why don't we just set it to display none,
but it will still exist in the dorm.
So let's do this in our HTML on that pre tag.
Let's just give it an attribute of style and set it to equal display colon none.
OK, so it's hidden now, but it's still a.
Exists in the domme, meaning our JavaScript can very easily access it.
So here's what I would do now.
Let's jump into our front end.
James file within our foreach function right before this comment, that outline, let's create a variable.
So let's say const, you can name it anything, but let's name it data equals.
And then every modern web browser has a function if we look inside all uppercase JSON for a method called
pass.
So you give this a string of text and it will pass it into real usable dynamic JSON.
So in these parentheses I would just say div, which is the current element or the empty div while it's
not empty anymore, but you know what I mean.
The current placeholder div that's been looped to so div dot and then we'll look inside it with query
selector and then give that just a string of text with a CFS like selector of pre then in between the
two closing parentheses.
So right here this is selecting that pre element.
We would just say dot inor html.
So now we have something called data that is all of that attribute data that we wanted.
So check this out.
Let's actually use it and react now so we can remove this comment, let react, actually render our
component.
And when we're rendering our quiz component, let's just give it a property or prop.
So let's say question equals curly brackets and just say data dot question.
So it's just data dot and then any of the attributes.
You could also look for the array of answers or the correct answer property.
But let's just start with question now.
Down here within our actual component definition, within these parentheses, let's be sure to have
a parameter.
The industry standard is to name it props.
And this is just anything that you're passing into the components.
So we gave it something called question.
So just as a test instead of hello from react, let's have curly brackets to do something dynamic and
say props dot question.
Let's give this to save and test it out.
Refresh perfect.
Now, before we start outputting the actual HTML interface for the questions and clickable answers,
I first want to talk about an efficient way to give the data to our component because spelling out each
individual property like this.
Sure, this works, but it's not very efficient for us to type this out for each one.
Right.
We wouldn't want to also have to say answer equals curly brackets, data, not answer and then do the
same thing with correct answer.
So there are a few different options.
You could just say quiz and give it something.
Data equals our entire object and then down in the component, you would access that by saying props
dot data dot question.
Right.
That would work if I save that and refresh it works just the same.
But even that is sort of an extra layer nested DB It would be nice if you could just say props dot question
like this down in the X but have an efficient way to pass it into your component.
Well here's what we can do.
So let's get rid of this.
Data equals data.
We can just say curly brackets, dot, dot, dot data.
This is effectively the same thing as actually spelling out question equals data.
Dot question answers equals data, dot answers.
Now, if you've never seen this three dot syntax before, let me explain how it works in the browsers
console.
Just as an example, you do not need to type this out.
But let's say I have two variables called A and B, and then let's also say I have something called
other, which is an object and it contains two properties.
Let's say it contains a property called C and a property called D, OK, and now imagine I want to create
sort of a grouped object that contains A, B and C and D.
Well, you could say let new combined.
I'm just making up a name.
But here's the syntax in question.
Let that equal.
And so I would create an object where I pull in A comma B and now I don't want to nest this object inside
of this object.
I want to d structure all of the items inside it so you can just say dot, dot, dot, other and JavaScript
will see this and know that it's going to take one by one each property from inside that and add them
here.
So if we push enter and we actually look at what new combined is, it's just an object with A, B,
C and D.
So the dot, dot, dot is a very useful tool in JavaScript for situations like this.
Anyways, the point is down.
In our case, we can now access whatever we want just by saying props dot and then the attribute name.
So why don't we do this?
Let's spell out the basic structure.
We'll have a paragraph tag so just P and then hit tab on your keyboard inside.
It will do something dynamic will output the question.
So props dot question right below that.
Let's have a unordered list with all of the answers.
So you'll hit tab inside the list.
We want to loop through the answers.
So curly brackets to do something dynamic.
Let's start working with that array of answers so its props dot answers.
And then in JavaScript, every array has access to the map method.
We'll give this a function, a function parentheses, curly brackets in our parentheses.
Let's be sure to have a parameter to receive the incoming answer that's currently been looped to and
then inside the body of our function.
We just want to return a little bit of JSA now.
We don't even need parentheses because the parentheses are just for multiline JS X and we only need
one line of JSON or HTML here, which is a list item.
So L I had tab inside it.
We're just going to dynamically output answer.
Right.
The current one that's been looped to.
Let's go ahead and save this and if we refresh the front end, perfect.
However, because we haven't yet let the admin choose the background color of each instance of our block,
there's really nothing for these answers to shine through.
So I want there to be a semi transparent layer around each answer so it looks like a clickable button.
And actually I've already written that CSFs for us.
It's just that we can't see any difference because it's a semi transparent white button on top of a
white background.
So for now, just so we can see what it's going to look like, you can do this with me in our source
folder, jump to front end s success and up towards the very top, maybe right before this first line
of overflow hidden.
We can just say background dash color, Colen hash tag, EBR, semicolon.
We give that a save refresh.
Cool.
So now they look like a.
You can see when you hover over them, they look like they'd be clickable only.
Nothing happens yet.
Now, that is going to bring this video to a close.
But in our very next lesson, we're going to begin to bring this to life.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.