Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to start working on a new plug in first, let's look at what the plug in
does and then after that will review why we're creating this plug in or what makes it different from
the first plug in that we created.
So right now, let's look at a sneak peak preview of the finished product of this next plug in.
So it's called word filter.
You give it a comma separated list of words that you want to filter out of your content.
OK, and then you'll notice that in the admin menu for word filter, there's a sub menu of links.
So this first page that we're already looking at is called Words List.
But then there's another page called Options.
If we click on to that, this is where you can type in whatever you want to replace those words with.
So maybe you want to replace them with dollar sign, exclamation pound at symbol.
So click save changes.
And then if I go on the front end and find a blog post that uses any of those words, cool.
There we see one instance where it was replaced.
Here we see another.
You get the idea.
So that's really all the plugin does not super impressive.
However, the reason we're building this plugin is because it's a good exercise to learn some new techniques.
So what I mean is on this first page that we were looking at, this page is not going to be built using
the WordPress form generator functions.
We will build it ourselves, will also learn how to apply a little bit of our own success if we want
to.
And perhaps most importantly, we're going to write the piece that actually handles the submission and
processing of this form.
Right.
Actually working with the data.
So this is a bit more customer hands on instead of letting WordPress do everything for us.
There's no right or wrong way.
I would say if you can get away with the first approach we took with our last plugin, you should.
However many times if you need that extra bit of customization, this is a great tool to have in your
toolbox.
OK, the other reason we're building this plugin is to get familiar with this idea of having our own
top level admin dashboard menu with a sub menu and even providing your own custom SVG icon.
OK, at this point.
Let's jump into the action.
So if I switch to this tab where I do not have this new plug in already created, let's start creating
it together.
So within your WordPress installation folder, find your plugins folder and let's just create a brand
new folder for a new plugin.
You can name the new folder anything, but I'll name it our word filter plug in.
OK, then just open your new folder in your text editor in our new folder.
Let's create a new file, I'll name it indexed P and to save a bit of time I'm going to paste in a bit
of starter code.
You can either pause the video and type this out or you can just copy and paste and borrow the first
few lines from our previous plugin.
So we're just opening up http.
We're giving it an appropriate name description version.
Author The only thing new here is this line.
I've seen lots of the top plug ins in the WordPress community use this line of code before.
Essentially if someone tries to visit this file directly from our plug in directory, well, we don't
want them to be able to access the file directly.
I don't mean that they could view the source code.
What I mean is that just by viewing the Eurail for the file in their browser, that could potentially
load or trigger or execute the code in this file.
And depending on the code that you're plug in contains, that might trigger some unexpected behavior
with your code.
So this is just a nice little safeguard against that that I've seen.
OK, moving on.
Let's go ahead and begin by creating a class.
So I'll say class and you could name anything, but I'll name it our word filter plug in, no parentheses,
just curly brackets.
OK, then below that, let's just create a new instance of our class.
So just new and then you can even just copy and paste this parentheses semicolon.
And then at the very start of this line, I like to save this new instance into a variable in case any
other plugins perhaps want to remove one of our actions or filters, or if our plugin has a reusable
method that we want the outside world like other plugin developers to be able to use.
Well, they can access it all from our variable name.
So right here we can just say dollar sign.
And then let's start with the lowercase.
Our word filter plugin equals that new instance.
Cool within our class.
Let's create the constructor function.
So we just say function.
With the exact name of underscore, underscore, construct, parentheses, curly bracket, and now let's
ask ourselves, what do we want to work on first?
I think we should begin by adding our own top level menu in the admin sidebar.
So to make that happen in our constructor function, let's add an action semicolon.
The action hook name is Admen Underscore Menu.
And then the second argument is just a function that we give it.
So let's use the callable syntax.
We just give it an array dollar.
Sign this.
The second argument is a method name that we make up.
You call it anything, but only omit our menu.
Then we just go create a method with that name.
So below the constructor function, we can just say scroll down a bit, function our menu, parentheses,
curly brackets, OK?
And then inside the body of this function, we're just going to use a WordPress function named add menu
page.
Let's call that semicolon.
We're going to give this seven arguments.
So just for quick placeholders.
OK, let's go through these one by one.
So the very first argument is the document title, right?
So that's the text that would show up in the actual tab in your browser window.
Why don't we call this words to filter?
OK, the second argument is the text that will actually show up in the admin sidebar.
So how about we say word filter?
The third argument is the permission or capability that a user needs to have in order to see the page.
Let's just go with Manege.
Underscore options.
The fourth argument is the short name or slug variable name for this new menu that we're creating.
So we get to make up a name.
Why don't we call it our word filter?
OK, the fifth argument is a function that outputs the HTML for the actual page itself so we can use
the array callable syntax will say array.
The first argument is dollar.
Sign this and then let's make up a method name, word, filter page.
We'll be sure to actually create this method in just a moment from now.
But let's finish out these two final arguments.
The sixth argument is the icon that will appear in the admin menu.
For now, let's just use a Dash Hakone for a quick test.
And then a bit later on, we will indeed learn how to use our own custom SVG file.
So I'll just say quotes Dasha seconds, dash smiley for a quick test.
OK, and then the final seventh argument.
This is a number that we give it that will control where our menu appears vertically.
Right.
Does it show up at the very top of the admin panel or down at the bottom?
So if you give this a very small number like one, it will appear up here, give it a larger number.
It's going to appear down here.
This is totally up to you.
I'll just give it a value of 100.
So it's down at the bottom.
OK, before we save our progress and test it out, let's create the method that's responsible for outputting
the actual HTML content for the page.
So we named it word filter page.
So below this function, you can just create a brand new one function, word, filter, page, parentheses,
curly brackets right where the cursor is, I want to be able to write HTML.
So right here, I'll drop out of P.
Then before this closing curly brackets, we can go back into groups.
And then right here, for now, just as a quick test, we can say Hello World.
OK, let's go ahead and save our progress.
And then in the browser, let's refresh.
Now we need to activate our plug in before we see anything.
So go under plug ins.
I named my plug in our word filter plug in, so just be sure to activate your plug in.
OK, now down at the very bottom, well, if we can see logo translate clearly, used a number larger
than 100 because theirs is at the very bottom.
But there we see our new plug in word filter.
If we click on it.
Cool.
We see.
Hello, world.
Next, let's go ahead and add a submenu to the word filter item in the admin sidebar.
Imagine we want a secondary or sub page called options that should live under this menu item.
So back in our code within our our menu function, below this add menu page line, let's add a new line
and just say add sub menu page semicolon.
This is a WordPress function that we give six arguments to.
So for placeholders, the first argument is the menu that you want to add this page to.
So that would be this short namer slug name that we chose for the parent page or menu.
I chose the value of our word filter.
So that's what we'll put here for the first argument.
The second argument is the actual document title that you would see in the tab of your browser.
Why don't we say a word?
Filter options.
The third argument is the text that you'll actually see in the admin sidebar.
Let's use a value of just options.
The fourth argument is the capability.
So again, let's use manage options.
That's the capability that's required to see this page.
The fifth argument is the slug name or short name for this page.
So you'll see this reflected in the UCLA address bar.
When you visit the sub page, we can make up a value.
Why don't we call it word Dasch filter Dasch options for the sixth and final argument.
This is just a function that outputs the HTML for the page so we know what to do.
You give it an array.
First argument is dollar sign this second argument.
We make up a method name.
Why don't we call it options sub page.
OK, let's go create that new method right now to save a bit of typing.
We can actually just duplicate this function.
So I'll just copy and paste those three lines on the new copy, change the name to options sub page
and then say Hello World from the options page.
Let's give that a save and test it out.
So if we refresh down in our menu, cool, we now have this sub menu in.
The second item in it is options and there's the new page.
Cool.
However, you might have noticed something a bit weird, and that is we have two items in the sub menu.
So yes, we just added this one on purpose, the one called options.
But you'll notice that the first link is just a copy of sort of the parent level link.
At first this seems a bit weird to have it twice, but you'll notice that in default WordPress areas,
for example, under posts if you click on posts.
Well, the first item in that submenu is all posts, and it doesn't matter if you click on the top level
link or just this first item in the menu, both of those take you to the exact same Eurail and page.
So that's what's going on with our menu, with word filter.
It just seems a bit awkward because we didn't provide different text.
So the point I'm getting at here is if this first link said something different other than the exact
same word filter text, I think it would not look or seem awkward.
So even though clicking here and here take you to the same page, let me show you how we can customize
the text that this first link uses back in our code.
All we need to do is create a duplicate copy of this submenu page line.
So just copy this entire line and then right above it pasted in.
Now we want to make sure that we're adjusting or manipulating the first copy.
From what I've seen, this line needs to come directly after the parent page line in order for it to
work.
But essentially we're just manually spelling out a submenu page that uses the exact same slug as the
parent page.
This way we can control the link or label text.
So let's change the second argument.
This is the document title will change it to words to filter.
The third argument is what's important here.
This is what's actually used in the admin sidebar.
So imagine we want this to say words list, right?
I think it will seem less awkward if this text says words list instead of word filter again.
OK, we do need to change another argument or two.
So if we keep scrolling to the right, we do want to change this argument.
So we want this to be the slug name for the parent page.
Right.
So when you visit the overall parent page, notice in the address bar, the slug that we chose is our
word filter.
So we just want to associate that exact same name with this entry.
So our word filter and then finally the HTML callback function should be the exact same for the parent
page.
So this would be word filter page.
All in all, this was a lot of work to spell everything out again, but now it's going to use our custom
text.
So if we save this and reload down in our menu, perfect word filter words list.
But if you click here or here, it's taking you to the exact same page.
Cool.
And that is going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our next lesson, we're going to learn how to provide our own custom SVG icon instead of just using
the built in dash icons that we can pick from.
Also in that lesson, we'll start to build out our own custom HTML page here.
So we'll see how we can add a bit of our own success that's unique to just this one page that we're
creating.
So that way we can really control the design and styling of our custom form page.
Then in the lesson after that, we'll actually start learning how to handle the submission of the form
and also processing the data with our own code.
It should be a lot of fun to build a totally custom solution like this.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.