Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to bring our generic heading block to life.
Let's jump into the action.
So here I am in the template editor.
Overall, this is our banner block.
But in this lesson, we're interested in this heading block.
Currently, it's hardcoded to just say the word hello.
We want to make it so that you can actually click on it and edit it.
Also beyond that, we're going to set things up so that this hover toolbar here has options such as
small, medium and large that you can use to control the size of the heading.
Let's get started.
So in verse code inside your our blocks folder jumping to generic heading JS.
Before we worry about actually building the edit interface, let's first set up our data or our attributes
that will need, right?
So we know we need to keep track of the text that you type into the heading and we need to keep track
of what size you want it to be, small, medium or large.
So let's do this.
When we register our block type, maybe right after the title property, let's have a property named
attributes colon curly brackets.
Be sure to include a comma here in the curly brackets we get to just start making up names.
So let's make up a name of text for one attribute colon, curly brackets, comma, let's make up another
one called size colon curly brackets.
For both of these, the data type will be string, right?
It's not a number, it's not a boolean.
It's just a string of text.
So type colon string, let's do the same thing for size type colon string.
And let's say that for size, the default value should be large.
So comma default, colon large.
Cool.
So this is the shape of our data.
Now let's actually start building the edit interface.
We're actually going to use a component that WordPress provides to us called Rich Text, and it's a
great component.
It does a lot of the heavy lifting.
So up at the very, very top we just say import curly brackets.
What do we want to import?
Well, something called the rich text and that's uppercase are in T and we import it from quotes at
symbol WordPress slash block dash editor.
Cool.
Now how do we actually use rich text?
Well, we just include it in our JS acts.
So down in our edit component, instead of returning a div, let's get rid of the div.
Let's return parentheses so we can have multiple lines of JS acts in the parentheses.
Let's start with a react fragment.
So just an empty opening tag and empty closing tag.
In the next 10 seconds.
It might look like we don't need the React fragment.
For example, inside the React fragment, we just want to include the self-closing rich text components
like this.
Right?
And you might be wondering, why don't we just include the rich text directly?
Why do we have the React fragment?
Well, you can only have one top level element in Gsx.
And later in this video, when we add the small, medium and large clickable buttons, well, they can
live inside the React fragment right alongside rich text.
But for now this is all we need anyways.
On Rich text, we start giving it props.
So first of all, let's give it a value.
So value equals curly brackets and we would just pull in our text attribute.
Now in order to access that, we would look inside of props.
However, we can't access props unless we pass it in as a parameter here.
So in these parentheses be sure to include props.
So now when WordPress calls this function for us, it's going to pass in our attributes through the
overall props object.
So now we can just say value equals props, dot attributes, dot text.
Okay, let's give rich text.
Another prop of on change equals curly brackets.
And now we just provide a function that will update the text value.
And it's going to run.
Every time someone types in a new character or deletes a character, we can either type out an anonymous
function right here in these curly brackets, or we can just point towards a function totally personal
preference, but just to make the code easier to look at and immediately understand, why don't we point
towards a function so we can make up a name?
Let's call it maybe handle text change.
Now let's go create a function with this name.
So within our edit component function, right above the return line, we can say function handle, text,
change, parentheses, curly brackets.
We want to include a parameter just name an x and x is going to be whatever the current value is in
the rich text field.
So whatever the user is currently typed into it.
So within the body of our function.
We would just want to say props, dot set, attributes, parentheses, give it a curly bracket for an
object.
And now in this object we are free to modify the attributes.
So we just want to change the text properties.
So text colon should now be x.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
You do need to have your in the command line, the NPM run start task up and running.
But with that running, if we go back into the browser and refresh the template editor screen.
It might look like there's nothing there.
But if you hover over right about here, you can see there's that one instance of our generic heading
block that already exists.
And we can say, you know, the sky is blue.
And then if we want to create a second instance of that same block type, if I just click off this,
notice the plus symbol right here so we can just add another one.
Grass is green.
We go ahead and save this template with these two instances of our block.
Cool.
So it's working and you can prove that it's working by just refreshing to see that.
Yes, it's loading and saving those values into and from the database.
Cool.
Now let's work on the visual design or the CC.
Right.
These headlines should use a certain font and should be a certain size.
So really to make that happen back on rich text, we're just going to give it a few more props.
Number one, let's say tag name should equal.
Let's just make them a heading level one element and then let's say class name as a prop equals.
Now instead of just giving a string of text with quotes, let's say class name equals curly brackets,
because we want this to be dynamic.
We want the class name to change depending on whether you want it to be small, medium or large.
So let's do this in the curly brackets include a back tick or a pair of back ticks and it would just
be headline, right?
That's the class.
We want space.
We want another class name of headline, dash, dash large only.
We don't want a hard code this too large.
So let's just hollow out the large part.
So headlined Dash, Dash, and then it would be dollar sign curly brackets to do something dynamic within
the back decks.
And now this would just be props, dot attributes, dot size.
Right.
So it'll be small, medium or large.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So if we refresh.
Cool.
Now, in a minute or two we can start working on the feature so that when you click on one, this toolbar
would include icons that say small, medium or large.
However, before we get to that, let's adjust this toolbar a bit.
What if we do want to allow the bold in italic?
But what if we don't want to allow a link or this other more of tools option?
Or what if you didn't want to include the bold and italic icons essentially on our rich text component?
You just give it a prop of allowed formats equals curly brackets.
Now, if you didn't want anything, you can just set it to an empty array.
So let's test that out.
Empty array if we refresh.
Now when you click on one, all of those options are gone.
There's no bold, there's no italic, there's no length, there's no button to see more options.
What if you only wanted the bold?
Well, you can just say allowed formats, quotes, core slash bold.
Give that a save refresh.
You can imagine that.
Now you click on that and you just have the bold option.
So what if I want the word sky to be bold?
You select it.
Cool.
This is why the rich text component is so powerful.
We didn't have to program this from scratch.
It's just instantly available to us.
As you might have guessed, if you wanted the italic option, it would just be comma.
Add an array item of core slash italic.
Cool.
At this point, let's move forward.
Let me refresh.
There's the italic option.
Now let's move on.
Let's add buttons to this toolbar that say small, medium and large so that you can control the size
of your heading to set that up.
We really just need to import a few more things from WordPress.
First of all, when we're importing things from the block editor line, let's add a comma after rich
text and let's also import something called block controls.
Then let's create a new line of code right above this and just say import curly brackets and we want
to import something called toolbar.
Group comma.
We also want toolbar button and we import those from quotes.
At symbol WordPress slash components.
Now let me show you how we leverage these things back down in our edit component.
Well, when we're returning JSF X now, you'll see why we wanted the React fragment.
So inside the fragment.
So a sibling to the rich text, we would just add block controls, not self-closing, but actual opening
and closing tags.
In between there we would drop down and let's add a toolbar group.
So toolbar group.
Inside there we start adding toolbar buttons.
So opening toolbar button.
So we're going to have three of these large, medium and small.
Let's have large first.
So the text would just be large, right?
That's the icon or button that you click on.
Now on the opening tag, we're going to give it to props.
So one is called is pressed equals curly brackets and the other prop is going to be called on click
equals curly brackets.
Let's start with on click because it's more intuitive.
So this is just what you want to happen when you click on the button.
As you might have guessed, we would just want to manipulate our size attribute.
So in the long curly brackets, let's just write an anonymous function right here in the curly brackets.
So for an arrow function, we don't need any parentheses.
So empty parentheses, arrow symbol don't need curly brackets.
Just props.
Dot set attributes, parentheses to call it, give it an object.
The property we want to change is named size.
So set it to equal large.
Cool.
Now let's talk about this is pressed prop.
You give this value of true or false and that decides whether the buttons should look selected or highlighted
or pressed.
So in these curly brackets, let's just write a little bit of code that checks for the equality of the
size.
And is it equaling the word large?
Right.
If it is, we want this button to look pressed so it would just be prop stock attributes, dot size,
double or triple equal sign.
That's a topic in debate for another day.
But if that equals the word large, cool.
Now let's just duplicate this for medium and small.
So I'm going to select this entire toolbar button line and just duplicate it, and then right below
that, duplicate it one more times.
Now there's three of them.
And just change these from medium and small.
So the text you click on should be medium.
The conditional we're checking for this would be medium and the size that we're setting would be medium.
We'll do the same thing for the small button.
So the thing we're checking for is small.
The value we want to sell it to is small and the length that you click on would read small.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So back in the browser if we refresh.
We click on the first generic heading, let's set it to large cool.
But then if we click on the second one, so it's a medium or small perfect.
At this point, the edit functionality of our block is complete, but we do need to still set up the
save functionality.
Let me explain.
So yes, if you click save and then refresh, yes, we're saving loading those attributes, but we're
not doing anything useful with the output.
HTML, Right.
If you look at our code and if you scroll down to our save component, this is all that's really going
to show up, right?
If you go to the front end of your website and refresh, that's all you see, right?
This is our heading block.
So what we need to do now is write a bit of gsx that gives us the desired h html here.
So here's what I would do.
First of all, in the save component in these parentheses, let's be sure to include props then in terms
of what we want to return.
We don't need all of the gsx like we had in our edit component, right?
In the save component, we don't need the block controls in the toolbar and the small, medium, large
buttons.
We literally just want the either H1, H2 or H3 element with the text.
So in this case we can simply just return rich text self-closing.
However, we do want to say rich text dot uppercase content because this doesn't need to be editable
in any way.
This now is about outputting the content, the string of text.
Cool.
So now we just give it a couple of props.
So value equals curly brackets.
This would just be props dot attribute text.
We'd also want to give it a class name to save a bit of typing.
I would actually just borrow what we already wrote up above.
Right on the other instance of rich text, we wrote class name equals, you know, and then the curly
brackets with the template literal.
I would just copy that and use that directly here.
So paste.
So now we've got rich text content.
We've given it a proper value.
We've given it a pop of class name.
Now let's give it a Prop two right here.
Let's say tag name equals quotes.
And this is where you would say either H1, H2 or H3.
Now, we would want that to be dynamic depending on whether you chose large, medium or small.
Right.
Large should be H1.
Medium should be H2.
Small should be H3.
There are a hundred different ways you could set up the JavaScript logic for that.
But what I'm going to do, instead of setting this to equal quotes, I'm going to set it to equal curly
brackets.
And then right above this line.
So still in the body of our function, but just above the return line, I would just create a function
and name it.
The name doesn't matter, but let's go with create tag name.
Parentheses.
Curly brackets.
I would use a switch.
So switch parentheses.
Curly brackets.
The value that I want to switch based on would be props.
Dot attributes.
Dot size.
In the switch.
I would just say, you know, for the first case in the case that it is large colon, not semicolon
colon, then you would just return a value of each one and then just do the same thing for medium and
small.
So case when it's medium colon return H2.
Finally, case where it's small colon return h3.
Okay.
So whatever this function returns is what I want to use here.
So tag name equals in these curly brackets.
Just call create tag name parentheses to actually call it right then and there was give this a save
and test it out.
So remember just a moment ago, this was all we were seeing on our front end.
Now you can sit here and refresh this a billion times.
Nothing is ever going to change.
And that's because at the moment our block is still powered by JavaScript and it doesn't have any sort
of AP component to it.
So in order for this to actually change, someone needs to manually go into the edit screen.
Refresh.
We're probably going to see a conflict message.
Yep.
So you can just click attempt block recovery.
Basically, any time the saved output of a block changes, you can expect that to happen.
It doesn't mean there's anything wrong with your code.
That's just the way the WordPress block editor works.
Don't worry, we'll learn more about that issue in an upcoming lesson where we do implement a bit of
server side IP to combat that exact issue.
But in certain websites, for certain cases, it's not a problem or an issue in the first place.
Anyways, let's stick to the task at hand.
So we're just trying to see if this saved output actually works now.
So we've got one large, one medium if we save it using our newest code and now we go refresh, right?
So those newest values get pulled from the database.
Perfect.
And at this point, our generic heading block is complete.
So where do we go from here?
Well, instead of jumping directly into the button block.
Right.
That you would probably add right about here where you can type in the text, say if you want the button
to be orange or blue where you want it to link towards.
Before we jump directly into that, let's take a break and talk about a big picture block theme concept.
So back in the editor screen, notice how our banner block doesn't take up the full available horizontal
space, even though on the front end it does well that, as well as countless other block theme settings
are all defined in a file named theme dot.
Jason And that's exactly what we're going to learn about in our next lesson.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.