Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to learn about a file named themed JSON, which lets us configure how the
editor works.
Let's jump into the action theme.
JSON can control so many different things.
So really the question becomes, where do we begin?
Well, I'm going to start with the width or the horizontal size of our content, right.
And the way that that's handled in the editor.
So if, for example, our theme doesn't even have a theme dot JSON file yet and because of that, WordPress
is currently using its default or standard or fallback values for the way that the editor handles the
width of our content.
So right now, you can do this with me.
Let's open up one tab with our full site editing template editor.
So I'll open that up in one tab and then in another tab.
Open up just any blog post or page.
Cool.
So here's a blogpost.
And then in this tab, here is the full site editor.
I want you to pay attention to the way that WordPress is handling the width of our content.
In other words, it's not taking up the full horizontal space of your browser window.
It's centered in sort of the middle portion of the screen.
And that's true for both the page and post editor and the full site editor.
However, check this out within our theme folder.
I want you to go ahead and create a brand new file just in the root of our theme folders, a new file
and give it the exact name of theme dot Jason.
Press enter.
For now, we can leave the file empty, but just go back into WordPress and if you refresh the full
site editor screen.
Notice that now the blocks are taking up the full available width and if you refresh your blog post
or page editor refresh, it's also taking up the full width.
Now it's just personal preference.
There's a million different ways that you can configure WordPress.
Personally, in my opinion, I want the full site editor to use the full available width.
Right.
Because if I'm going to let users insert a banner or a header, I want it to be sort of what you see
is what you get.
I want it to take up the full available width.
However, when you're actually writing an authoring blog posts, this would be a terrible editing experience.
Right line length becomes so long that it's impossible to read and work with.
So when you're working with a blog post or page, I want the content to only take up sort of the middle
800 pixels or so.
So how do we customize this?
How do we change this?
Well, that's where Theme Jason comes into play.