Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to work on the design or styling of our plugin, so first we'll add our
own custom icon in the sidebar, and then after that, we'll see how to add a bit of our own success
just for this one admin page.
So let's jump into the action and let's start with the custom icon.
So currently down at the bottom, we have our word filter plug in menu and we're just using as a placeholder
the dash icons, smiley icon.
So right now, I want to show you how we can instead use our own custom SVG icon.
If you don't have an icon that you would want to use.
Well, in the downloadable resources for this lesson, you'll find a file named Custom Dot SVG.
And this is the file that I'm going to use in this video so you can follow along with me.
Anyways, let's jump into our text editor and within our hour menu function on this add menu page line.
Remember, towards the very end, the second to last argument was dash icons Smiley.
So let's get rid of this.
But we can keep the quotes because we do want a string of text and there are several different ways
to include an icon.
The first way that I want to show you is, in my opinion, the best way.
Essentially, instead of pointing towards a file, we just actually include the contents of the file
directly in our code right here.
Let me explain.
So within the string, let's type data call an image slash SPG plus XML, semicolon base 64, OK.
And then still in this same string of text.
So still inside the quotes, Atacama.
And now let's talk about what we include here.
So what I want to do is actually open up my SVG file in a text editor so we can see the contents of
the file.
So I'm just going to drag the SVG icon on top of VTS code to open it up.
Now, just select everything in the file, select everything and copy that into your clipboard.
Now we cannot just directly paste that right here.
Instead we need to take that text in our clipboard that is in binary format and we need to change it
or convert it into ASCII format.
Luckily for us, the Google Chrome Web browser can do this for us.
So check this out in Google Chrome, open up your dev tools so you can just click anywhere and choose,
inspect, then make sure you're on the console tab and type this in with me B to a all one word.
And it's a function that we're going to call so parentheses.
And then for the argument that we give it instead of a simple string of text with quotes like double
quotes or single quotes, let's actually give it a template literal.
So to back Tick's this way, JavaScript won't get confused by all of the quotes in the text that we're
going to paste in.
So in between the two back text, just paste in your clipboard, OK, and let's press enter to execute
this function and just take this string of text that it returns.
Just copy this entire thing into your clipboard.
Now you do not want the quotes at the very beginning and the very end.
So I'm just going to start selecting right inside those quotes all the way up right before the final
quote.
So copy that into your clipboard.
And then back in our text editor right after the base64, comma, just paste in your clipboard.
OK, let's give this a save and test it out.
So back in our admin panel, we refresh.
Cool.
There is our custom icon.
Now, when you refresh, you'll see that for a split second.
It might be even too fast to show up in this video recording, but you will see it on your computer.
You'll see that for just a split second.
The icon is yellow before it turns grey.
I did this on purpose.
So in the real world, you would use your editing software to create an icon that matches the WordPress
Grey.
But I wanted to demonstrate what's really going on here with this approach.
So this is why the inline base64 approach that we took is my favorite way to include an icon, because
we are giving WordPress the actual data for the SVG.
So WordPress is able to change the full color on the SPG to match the exact shade of gray that WordPress
uses.
And this also means that WordPress automatically gives us the blue hover color.
So yes, if you inspect the file that we used, if you zoom in really close, you can see that the outline.
The star is usually yellow or gold in the actual SFG, but WordPress can modify it as it sees fit.
Cool.
However, there are times where maybe you do want a little bit of custom color in your icon.
For example, look at the icon for the all in one WP migration.
So if that's the case and you want a bit of custom color without WordPress adjusting your icon, let
me show you what you can do.
So back in our code, I'm just going to comment about this line that we just wrote, and I'll create
a duplicate copy of it.
The reason I'm doing this is because that's the approach that I actually want to use and I'm going to
revert back to it in a minute or two.
But I'm just creating a copy.
And on this copy, I'm going to show you how you can actually load the SVG file instead of having to
include the contents in line.
So all you would do is find the argument that is the icon.
So let me hollow this out.
And then instead of saying Dasch icons Smiley or including our inline base64, you can just provide
a path to your file.
So instead of a string of text here, let's say plug in, underscore Dürer, underscore Eurail, this
is a WordPress function inside the parentheses if we give it the constant of file.
So that's underscore, underscore, file, underscore, underscore.
This will give us a U.
RL that's pointing towards the directory that the current file is living in.
So from there we would just add on.
So concatenate on now a string of text and let's say custom dot SPG.
Let's go ahead and save this and then let's be sure to move the custom SVG file to live in our plug
in folder.
So here's my plugins folder.
All go into our word filter plug in and I'm just going to move over that as SVG file.
Let's go ahead and refresh.
Cool.
And now you can see that it's using our custom color.
By default, WordPress will have a little bit transparent or see through, but then when you hover over
it, it fully lights up.
So it's up to you how you want to handle this.
There's no right or wrong way.
You are allowed to include a little bit of custom color in your icons.
But personally, I like the fully integrated approach that we saw first.
So that's what I'm going to stick with.
So I'm going to remove that new line we just wrote where we loaded the file and let me uncommented this
approach.
Cool.
One last quick note about the icon before we move on, I made this icon 20 pixels tall by 20 pixels
wide.
Obviously, the entire point of an SVG is that it can scale for any pixel density and screen size.
But I found that 20 by 20 works nicely with the way that WordPress adds in the icon.
Anyways, moving on, let's go ahead and actually visit our page.
And what we want to work on now is the actual custom page right now, it just says Hello World, but
let's begin building out the form that will live on this page.
So back in our code, we're looking for our function called word filter page.
And instead of hello, world, type this out with me, let's have an overall div such as div and then
hit tab.
Actually, I want to give this div a class of wrap.
So a faster way is to just type div dot wrap and then hit tab.
Cool inside this div let's have a heading level one that says word filter.
OK then below that let's have an HTML form element.
We'll talk more about how the form is submitted in our next lesson.
For now though, we don't need the action, but let's just go ahead and be sure to set the method to
equal post.
OK, inside the form, it's dropdown.
So we want the form to have a text field where users can type in a comma separated list of words to
filter out of their content, so let's include a little bit of instructions or a label for the field.
So I'll just say label four will point towards the idea of the actual text field.
So we get to make that up.
Why don't we call it plug in words to filter?
You could choose any name you want inside the label.
Let's have a paragraph and then let's say enter a comma separated list of words to filter from your
site's content.
OK, and just for attention to detail, I'm going to make comma separated bowl, so I'll wrap that in
a strong tag.
Below the label, let's add a div, I'm going to say divorce, and you can make up any class name that
you want.
I'm just making up this class name because I know the success that I'm going to want to write.
I'll say a word filter.
Underscore, underscore Fleck's container tab inside that div.
I want a text area input fields of text area tab for the name and the ID.
I'm just going to give it this plug in words to filter.
We don't need the columns attribute, we don't need the rose attribute, we can go ahead and give it
a placeholder value so the user can see example text as a placeholder equals and let's just say bad
karma, mean karma, awful karma, horrible.
Just so the user sees an example of a comma separated list.
OK, then below the div that is housing the text area.
Let's have a submit button so I'll just type input and then hit tab.
Let's change the type to submit.
Let's give it a name of submit.
Let's give it an idea of submit.
Let's give it a class of button and button dash primary and let's give it a value of save changes.
Let's go ahead and save this and see what we're working with.
So if we refresh, this is a good start, but it's not going to win any design awards.
So let's add a little bit of success to make this text area use the full available width, perhaps be
a bit taller, and then let's also add a bit of bottom margin to it.
So there's a bit more vertical space between the field in the save button.
However, before we can start to write any success, we first need to learn how to load a custom CSS
file just for this one admin page.
Right.
Because there's no need to load our extra access for any other page in the admin that would be wasteful.
So let me show you what we can do within our hour menu function, where we add the parent level page
in the sub menu page.
Within that function, we can add a new line and just say add action and the action hook is load and
then dash and then I'm going to place an X as a temporary placeholder.
But instead of an X, this is where you include the hook name for the specific page you're interested
in.
Let me explain where this is going to come from.
So when we registered our parent page, this function is actually going to return the hook name that
we can use here instead of the X..
So at the start of this line, add menu page, we can just say, well, let's make up a variable name.
So dollar sign and then any name you want, I'll call it.
How about Main Page?
Hook equals whatever this function returns, OK, that instead of X we want to use whatever string of
text now lives in this variable.
So instead of single quotes here around load X, if we use double quotes, well now inside this string
we can do something dynamic.
So get rid of the hardcoded X and instead we can say curly brackets and then inside there we can just
access our variable.
So dollar sign, main page hook.
Cool.
So now we have a hook that is for loading assets just on this one admin page.
So that's the first argument for this add action.
Let's add a comma here.
The second argument is just a method that we want to run.
So let's use the array callable syntax dollar.
Sign this, let's make up a name, let's call it.
How about main page assets?
And then we just create a function with that name.
So function main page assets.
Inside this function we can just use the standard WordPress function of WP on queue.
I always spell that word wrong on queue.
Underscore style semicolon.
We can make up a short name or slug name for the style.
Let's call it filter admin access.
The next argument is just a file path towards our access file.
We haven't created a case file yet, but we will in just a moment.
Let's say plug in.
There you are URL.
We can use the constant of underscore, underscore, file, underscore, underscore and then just concatenate
on and let's just have it be in the main top level plugin folder and we can call it Styles Dot, CSX,
let's save this.
And then in our plug in folder, let's create that new txt file new file styles dot CSC.
Just to make sure that's loading, let's include something super obvious, like asterisk to select everything
and set the color to blue and make it important just so we can really see if the file is loading or
not.
Let's give that a save if we reload on our page.
Cool.
Obviously that's txt file is loading so we can remove that rule now.
And instead let's write a rule that targets this div class we set up called word filter flex container.
So I'll just copy.
His name back in CSA, dot pasted in and all we need to do is say display Fleck's and then a new rule
where we say dot pastie do look inside that element for any text area element and just tell it to be
Fleck's one, which will allow it to use all of the available space and then let's give it a basic height.
So maybe height, 200 pixels.
And then we wanted to give it a bit of margin bottom.
So the save button isn't right up against it.
So you say margin.
Actually a V code tip, you can just type M be short for margin bottom and then hit tab.
Or even better yet, check this out.
You can just type M B 20 hit tab.
It knows what we mean.
Cool.
Let's give this a save if we reload.
I think this looks a lot better now.
Yes.
We did not set up any super custom artistic layout with our success, but this is not a course about
success.
So that's outside our scope.
The point is you can now take whatever skills you have and implement whatever you want.
You can get as creative and custom as you want to write in.
Your success will only be applied for this particular admin page.
Now, that is going to bring this lesson to a close in our very next video.
We're going to actually work on submitting this form and handling the security and the data handling
with our own code.
There should be a lot of fun.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.