Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to work on a bit of attention to detail for our blacktip, let's jump into
the action.
So currently, if you get a question wrong, our message displays, but then if you get it wrong again,
nothing happens.
And we would want to see that error message or sorry message again.
As I mentioned at the end of the previous lesson, the reason this is happening is because it is correct,
that piece of state that we're storing, it's already set to false from when you got the answer wrong
the first time.
So when we set it to false again, it was already false.
There was no change.
So there's no difference for react to react to.
Now, I do want to say that there are an infinite number of ways that you could code this quiz front
end with react.
If you asked 100 developers, you'd get 100 different answers on how to set this up.
And I definitely do not claim to have the most elegant react solutions in the world.
But here's how I would do it.
Let me refresh so we get a clean slate.
So when you get the answer wrong, as soon as that is correct is set to false, I would just wait maybe
twenty six hundred milliseconds so that it sort of lines up with the speed of our animation.
But if I refresh again, so as soon as this happens it gets set to false.
And then after twenty six hundred milliseconds I would just set it back to undefined.
So that way once the animation goes away, if you get it wrong again, you'd be changing it from undefined
to false so that it actually would render and reapply that animation.
So let me show you how I would set that up.
Up at the very top, we've already imported something called use state.
And right now I want to import another react function called use effect.
So in these curly brackets, after you state, let's say comma use effect.
OK, now let me explain how we use use effect down in our quiz component function, maybe below this
const line.
Let's use the use affect function in these parentheses we give it to arguments.
So A comma B the first argument is a function that we want to run at a certain time.
So let's just give it an E six arrow function.
So empty parentheses, arrow symbol, curly brackets.
The second argument is where we get to explain when we want this function to run, or in other words,
what properties or pieces of state are we watching for changes.
And then any time they change, we want to run this function in response.
So instead of the placeholder B, you give it an array of things that you're watching for changes.
And I just want to watch the is correct piece of state.
OK, so now any time it changes inside the body of this function, let's set up an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets, I'm going to say only if is correct is now false.
So if that will equal signs false, then what do I want to do.
I want to set a time out and wait a little bit of time and then just set is correct back to undefined.
So set time out.
We give this to arguments as well.
The first argument is a function that you want to run so we can just give it an E6 arrow function and
let's just say set is correct and put it back to undefined.
Now, the second argument for this be placeholder, this is how long you want to wait before running
your function that you provided.
So let's just wait twenty six hundred milliseconds.
Cool.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So if we refresh I get an answer wrong.
OK, but then if I get it wrong again, perfect.
Next let's talk about what should happen if you get the answer right.
So if I click Cat and we see that is correct.
Well once that message goes away, I shouldn't be able to click a wrong answer.
So instead, let's look at the finished product of how it handles what happens when you get it right.
So if I get it correct, as soon as that message fades away, notice I can no longer click on any of
the answers.
And by the styling, it's clear that this was the correct answer and these were incorrect.
So then it's sort of a review, right?
As the user scrolls up and down the page again, if they see that, it's immediately clear the correct
answer.
Now, before we work on these sort of post answer styles like this, let's first just prevent any further
clicks once you get the answer right.
So back in the tab that we're working on together, jump into our code and let's find the elai list
item element.
You click on so here it is inside the unordered list and on the unclick prop, I actually want you to
cut the S6 Arrow function into your clipboard.
So I'm going to cut this value.
So now it's just equals empty curly brackets.
And I'm just going to use a ternary operator to say if is correct is true.
Don't do anything.
I don't want to pass on a function.
If it's not true, then we can pass along that function.
So for the condition of the ternary operator is correct.
If that equals true, then questionmark.
What do we want to do.
Undefined.
Just don't pass along anything.
Don't pass along a function.
Colen, what do we want to do otherwise.
Well then we can just paste in our clipboard.
Let's give that to save and test it out.
So if I refresh now and I get the answer correct.
OK, but if I try to click on another answer after that.
Perfect, nothing happens.
Now let's focus on the change in styling that should take place after you answer the question correctly
to refresh your memory.
If we look at the finished product, I'm referring to the green checkmark and the red Xs, as well as
making the wrong answers sort of semi transparent or see through.
Now, in terms of exactly when this style change should take place, it's maybe not as simple as you
might think.
Let me refresh and explain what I mean.
So if we started to animate and change the style of the answers, the millisecond that you answered
the question correctly, well, you'd be able to see the answers changing while that green success message
is slowly fading in.
And it's just me and my design opinion that I think that would look jarring or distracting.
Right.
I don't think there should be multiple things animating at the same time.
So instead, what I want to do, I want to wait maybe one second into the animation.
So when I get the answer right, maybe one one thousand and now animate and change the way the answers
look just in time, so that when that green screen starts to fade away to reveal them again, they've
already changed.
And you are using the new styling.
So the approach I'm going to take is not necessary.
It's just something I'm doing because I think the animations will look nicer this way.
In other words, if I jump back to the version we're working on, if you don't mind if multiple things
are changing or animating at the same time, then you absolutely could just build your condition around.
If is correct is true.
However, since I want a bit more of a custom timing, here's what I'm going to do up in our use effect,
maybe right below this if statement, but still within the overall use affect function.
So right here where my cursor is blinking, I'll say if parentheses curly brackets the condition is
if is correct equals true, what do I want to do.
Well I want to set a time out so set time out.
We give that to arguments.
So A comma B the first argument is a function, so let's use an E6 arrow function.
We'll circle back to what we want to do here in just a moment.
But the second argument is how long you want to wait.
Let's just wait one second.
So sort of in the middle of that green screen success fading in and out and then instead of setting
the is correct piece of state, let's create a new piece of state that keeps track of sort of the in
between timer.
So I would just copy and paste and duplicate this line of code where we're creating our piece of state.
And then on the new copy, let's change it to is correct delayed and then change this one to set is
correct.
Delayed.
OK then in our new set time out we would just set is correct delayed and give it a value of true.
In other words, as soon as you get the question right one second after that.
Well we can watch that piece of state change at that exact moment and then change the way the answers
look.
Now in terms of changing their appearance, why don't we begin by showing a green checkmark on the correct
answer?
So if we scroll down a bit into our JSM, we're looking for the list item that we loop once for each
answer.
Now, while this currently fits on a single line, so we don't need parentheses around the JSA that
we're returning, I actually want to start using multiple lines for the list item now.
So let's wrap the list item in an opening parentheses here.
And then at the very end of that line, you can add a closing parentheses.
So just like this.
And then also inside the list item, I'm going to drop down onto a different line so that the opening
and closing tags are each on their own line and the content sits here.
OK, and then right above that answer text, this is where the green check mark would go.
So let's have curly brackets to do something dynamic here and say is correct.
Delayed if that equals true and.
If this is the correct answer, right, we only want to add the green checkmark to the correct answer,
so and if index equals props, correct answer.
Now, again, in case we can't have an if statement, but we can have sort of this cool trick here,
we can say and and once again and then pair of parentheses and then we can drop down inside the parentheses.
And now this will only be included if our condition is true.
So now let's just paste in the SVG for a check mark icon.
So I will once again use the Bootstrap Icons website.
You can search for checkmark.
I'll use this first basic check.
Just select the SVG contents here back in our code, just paste that in.
Let's change the width and height to twenty pixels instead of sixteen.
We don't need the fill and let's also change class to be class name.
Let's give this a save and see what it looks like.
So if I refresh and get the answer right.
Perfect.
You and I never actually saw the checkmark appear, it came into play during the middle of the overlay
animation.
Let's do the same thing, but have a red X for the incorrect answers.
So back in our code, we can actually just duplicate this entire area that I'm selecting right now.
So just sort of the overall curly brackets that's right above answer.
Just duplicate that on the new copy.
Let's just check for the opposite.
So only if the index does not so exclamation equal the correct answer.
And then let's just go find an SVG icon for an X.
So if we go back and search for the word close, I'm just looking for this X icon.
Click on that.
Copy the SVG paste that in instead of this one with change the height and width to twenty.
Once again, let's remove the fill and change class to class name.
Skip the save and test it out.
If I get it correct, as soon as that goes away.
Now the X's are green instead of red, but we're going to fix that right now.
So what we're going to do is give each a list item a class.
So we'll give the incorrect answers, a class that makes them transparent or see through something like
this.
And then we'll give the correct answer a class just so that when you hover over it, it doesn't look
clickable any longer.
So to set that up, let's find the opening list item tag.
Here it is.
And right before the end, click prop here.
Let's give it a class name equals instead of quotes, let's have curly brackets because we're going
to make dynamic decisions.
So let's have a grouping pair of parentheses and use a ternary operator.
So I'll say is correct.
Delayed if that equals true.
And this is the correct answer.
So if index equals props, dot correct answer.
Questionmark.
If that's the case, let's just output a string of text or a class of no dash click if that's not the
case.
So colon just output nothing after the closing parentheses but still in the curly brackets let's say,
plus another grouping pair of parentheses and just have another ternary operator.
So if is correct, delayed equals true and if it's the incorrect answer.
So if index does not equal props, correct answer.
Questionmark.
What do we want.
Output string of text of Faid Dasch incorrect Colen.
If that's not the case, just do nothing.
Just an empty string of text.
Remember, you can always download the reference code at the end of a lesson if you want to copy and
paste or reference my code.
But let's save that.
Give it a try.
So if I get it correct, as soon as that green message fades away, perfect.
The icons are red, the incorrect answers are sort of faded away and when we hover over the correct
answer, it no longer looks clickable.
And that is going to bring this video to a close.
In our next lesson, we're going to add a few finishing details before we close out this block type.
We're actually going to be jumping back into the admin side of things and letting the owner of the site
change the background color for each instance of the block as well as control the text alignment.
So whether it's left, center or right should be a lot of fun to set up.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.