Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to finish this second plug in that we've been working on.
Let's jump into the action.
So at this point, we are successfully saving the user's preference into the database.
So now it's just a matter of writing the actual code that uses that comma separated list of words to
actually start filtering the content.
Now, before we start writing the IP to make that happen, why don't we make sure that we're actually
looking for words that exist in our blog post so we can see if our code is working or not.
So, for example, let me enter a couple of words that are actually in this lorem ipsum placeholders,
lorem comma, SSD, comma Tempur.
OK, let me save that value.
Cool.
Now let's write the P to actually filter our content.
So in our code up in our construct function, let's add a filter for our content.
So just newline add filter semicolon.
The filter name is the content.
Let's use the callable syntax.
So an array with a dollar sign.
This lets make up a name, let's call it filter logic.
OK, and actually we would only need to apply this filter if the user has entered something into this
field.
If this field is completely blank, we don't need to run the filter at all.
So it's up to you.
You can include the F check inside your method or you could just wrap this line of code in an IF statement.
So, for example, you can just cut this line temporarily, say if parentheses curly brackets.
Actually, if you just have one single statement, you don't even need the curly brackets.
So just if parentheses for the condition would just be if get option call that we named that option
the database, plug in words to filter.
So only if that exists then just paste in that code again.
Cool.
Let's go create our method with this name.
So filter logic function filter logic.
Let's be sure to include a parameter to receive the incoming starter contents.
You could call it whatever you want, but how about dollar sign content.
OK, in the first thing I want to do is convert that string of comma separated text.
I want to convert it into an array.
So why don't we make up a variable name, I'll call it bad words and set it to equal and then there's
a function named explode.
So we give it to arguments.
Let's actually start with the second argument.
So it's the string of text that you want to work with.
So we would just say get option.
Remember, the name is plug in words to filter.
The first argument is the separator.
So what in the string of text do you want to be the divider of where it should be split into different
pieces in an array?
So for us that would just be a comma, right?
We're working with a comma separated list.
OK, so now we have this array of the words that we want to filter out or replace.
However, they might have all sorts of space around them because remember, someone might add a comma
and then add three or four spaces and then a new word and then they might have a space on accident before
they have a comma.
So we just want consistency in terms of the empty space before and after each word.
So we want to trim the white space.
So let's create a new variable.
I'll call it bad words trimmed.
You could make up any name and let's set it to equal.
And then we're going to use a function called Array Map.
Let's give it to arguments.
The first argument will just be Trem.
We're telling it what to do to each item in the array and then it's going to return a new array.
And then the second argument is just the original array that you want to work with.
So bad words.
OK, now we simply want to look through our content and replace any instance of a word that exists in
this array.
So in B, there's a function called estar underscore.
I replace semicolon and we're going to give this three arguments.
The first argument is an array of words that you want to replace.
So that's just bad words trimmed.
The second argument is what you want to replace them with.
So for now, just as a quick test, let's replace them with maybe three or four asterisks.
OK, and then the final argument is the text that you're performing this replacement operation on.
So that would just be dollar sign content, right?
The WordPress blog post or page content.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And test it out, so if I refresh my front end blog, woops, you can see the content totally went away.
This is because I forgot to return anything.
So right now, this line is just sort of floating in outer space.
We didn't save it to a variable.
We didn't return it.
But really the ultimate job of a filter function, we just want to return the new content.
So the start of this line, we just want to be sure to return this value that we worked on.
Let's give that save reload.
Cool.
You can see Lorem is being filtered out.
Tempur said perfect.
Now we temporarily set the replacement text to just four asterisks, but ultimately we want to give
the site owner control so that they can type in whatever they want the replacement to be.
Now, we absolutely could just add a second TextField to this page.
However, remember, we already set up a sub page in our menu called Options.
So let's visit options.
And just to practice having multiple pages, why don't we have a form on this page with a field where
they can type in the replacement text?
Now, at this point in the course, you have learned two different ways of how to create an admin form
page.
So it's up to you which approach you want to use.
But right now I want to show you that you can mix and match.
So, yes, we created that first page, this page.
We created this using our own custom PHP handling, but we don't have to use that same approach for
the options sub page.
So just for an example, I'm going to use the WordPress form builder for the options page.
So to get started, let's go find the function that's outputting this hello world from the options page
text.
So down towards the bottom.
Here we see options, sub page, let's get rid of this placeholder text and instead have a div with
a class of wrap inside that, let's have a heading level, one that says word filter options.
After that, let's have a form to just hit tab after form.
Now, if I'm going to create a WordPress generated form where it sort of outputs the fields for me,
we want to be sure that the action is pointing towards options.
Dot BHP.
Let's also go ahead and set the method to equal post inside the form.
We just want to drop in to be Miklós out of it right here inside the P.
This is where we would output our sections and our setting fields, but we haven't registered any of
those yet.
So for now, let's just output the submit button and then we can circle back to this area a little bit
later.
So submit button, that's a WordPress function.
Let's go ahead and save this and see what it looks like perfect at this point.
Let's just register a new setting that WordPress can save for us that will be responsible for letting
the user type a replacement text, and then that's what we'll get stored in the database.
So to set that up back up at the very top of our file, we want to add an action in our constructor
that is added to the admin init action hook.
So I'm just going to create a new line in the constructor.
Let's say add action semicolon.
The hook name is admin underscore init comma.
Let's give it a method.
So every dollar sign this lets make up a method name.
You could call it anything.
I'll call it our settings.
Let's go create a method with this name of our settings.
So function our settings.
First, let's register a section.
We only need one section on our page so we don't need multiple sections, but we do need one section
that we can assign fields to.
So inside our new function we'll just say add settings section.
So my colon, we're going to give this for arguments.
The first is the name of our section.
We get to make up a name, let's call it replacement text section for the second and third arguments.
I don't want any labeled text or description text for this section.
I just want it to be blank other than the actual field that we're outputting.
So for the second and third arguments, I'm just going to say null.
OK, and then the fourth argument is the slug name of the admin page that you want to display this section
on so you can just look in your Eurail address bar.
You can see we chose word filter options, so I'll just copy that.
And that will be the value for this fourth argument.
Cool.
Now that we have a section, we can actually register and add a setting in field.
So let's register our setting first register setting call that we give it to arguments.
The first argument is the option group.
We only have one field here, but we just need to make up a name.
How about replacement fields?
And then the second argument is the option name for this specific option that we're creating.
How about replacement text?
OK, now that we've registered the setting, let's just add a field to our section.
So we just use the ADD settings, field function.
We give this five arguments.
The first argument will be used as the IDE attribute for the actual element.
So why don't we just say replacement dash text?
The second argument is the text that the user will actually see on the form as the label for the field.
So why don't we say filtered text?
The third argument is a function that will output the HTML for our field.
So array for argument is dollar.
Sign this.
Let's just make up a method name.
How about replacement field HTML?
We'll create that method in just a moment.
The fourth argument is the slug of the page that you want to show this on.
So again, that's word filter options.
And then the fifth argument is the section that you want to output the field too.
We only created the one section and we named it replacement text section.
So we can use that as our fifth argument value.
OK, now let's go create the method that we named replacement field HTML.
I'll just say new function, replacement field HTML.
Now I want to include HTML right here inside the body of the function, so let's exit here and then
we can enter back into PHP here inside the function.
Let's just type input and then hit tab.
We do want it to be a type of text.
Let's also give it an attribute of name and set that to the name that we chose for the actual option.
So this is the option name that will get saved in the database.
So we want that to match perfectly replacement text.
And while we're here, let's go ahead and also give it a value attribute.
And we would just want to load the existing value from the database.
So that way, when you refresh this page, the field is already populated with your previous value.
So inside these value quotes, we would just go into HTTP.
We want to echo something.
Let's begin by escaping an attribute, right?
Any time a value is dynamically coming from the database, we want our front end to escape it.
OK, and then what do we actually want to work with?
We just want to get an option that has this name of replacement text so it quotes replacement text.
If a value doesn't already exist in the database, we can provide a fallback options.
We could say comma and then we could just give it maybe three asterisks.
OK, right below this line, why don't we include a paragraph and say leave blank to simply remove the
filtered words for a bit of WordPress styling.
We can give that paragraph a class of description.
OK, and at this point, before we save, be sure to go down to the very bottom and within the HTML
for the new form we're building right above submit button.
We just now want to output our section in our fields.
Let's start with our fields.
So we use a function called Settings, Fields, semicolon.
We give it the group name.
If you can't remember what you chose a little bit ago when we registered our setting, remember, the
first argument was the group name that we chose.
So replacement fields.
OK, next, we also want to output our sections, we only have one section, what we call a function,
do settings, sections, parentheses, semicolon, and this is the slug name for the page that we're
on.
So that's word filter options.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So if we reload, cool, let's provide a custom value instead of the placeholder.
Three asterisks, maybe hashtag hash tag to exclamations.
Let's try to save that cool.
You can see, even if we reload, that value is saved in the database.
It's persisting.
If you open up your ATM and go to the options table and click on to the final page, you should see
replacement text with whatever value you just entered.
So now that we're actually saving this in the database, we can just go adjust the function that actually
performs the replacement's to use this instead of the four asterisks.
Let me show you what I mean.
So back on our blog, right.
Instead of this default for asterisks, let's just go adjust that back in our code.
We just want to find our function.
We gave it a name of filter logic.
Here it is now where we have the four asterisks.
Well, let's just get rid of that instead.
Let's use Escape HTML.
Right.
We're pulling something dynamic from the database.
We want to escape it inside here.
We would just want to say get option.
Right.
We want to load that from the database.
It had a name of replacement text and then if you wanted to, you can use the four asterisks as a fallback
if we can't find anything in the database.
So you could say string and then four asterisks.
Let's save this and give it a try.
So if we refresh the front end, perfect.
It's using the user's preference for the replacement.
Before we bring this lesson to a close, there's one more detail I want to take care of.
So back on this options page, I noticed that when you save a change to the form, we don't receive
any sort of green success message right about here to make sure we have that in place.
All you need to do back down towards the bottom in our options sub page function within this area.
Let's just add a new line and say settings underscore errors.
Call that semicolon.
Now, back when we were creating our first plug in, we did not need this line.
And that's because the WordPress Settings API will call this for you when you're on a settings page.
And remember our first plug in, it was registered as a settings page under the WordPress settings menu,
whereas this page that we're building right now, this is just a generic admin page.
So it's not officially part of the Settings or Options API.
So we do need to call this function if we save that reload now, if we make a change to this and save
it, perfect settings saved.
And that's going to bring not only this lesson, but also this chapter to a close.
In our very next lesson, we're going to start a new chapter.
It's still all about plugin development, but now the focus is going to be on JavaScript, in particular,
how we can use JavaScript to work with the WordPress block editor.
In my opinion, out of the three plugin development chapters, the JavaScript chapter should definitely
be the most exciting.
So let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.