Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to jump back into the admin side of things and learn how to add custom
options to our block type.
Let me explain what I'm referring to.
So right now, we're looking at the finished product version of the block type.
And you'll notice that as soon as I click onto the block.
Well, in the right hand column, we now have this tool that lets us choose the background color.
And thanks to the real time nature of the React library, you can see as you choose that color, the
block gets updated.
And then obviously, if I choose this color and view it on the front end.
Perfect.
So in this lesson, we're going to learn how to set up this right hand inspector or customize panel
for our block type.
Let me jump back to the tab that you and I are working on together.
And let's move forward from here.
So in our text, Ed, for the last several lessons we've been working in front end.
Yes.
But right now we want to make sure that we're back in Index J.S..
Right, because this is the copy that controls the ED or admin side for our block type to get started
up at the very top.
We want to import something new from WordPress that will make this process very easy for us only instead
of adding it to this line where we're importing from WordPress components, we actually want a brand
new line, maybe right below that one, where we say import curly brackets from quotes at WordPress
slash block dash editor.
And again, just like with this line of code, it doesn't matter that you and I didn't actually install
this package from NPM.
The Web pack configuration that our automated JavaScript package is using is smart enough to look for
this in the browsers global scope.
Anyways, in these curly brackets, we're trying to import something called inspector controls.
OK, now that we have this line of code in place, there are two more things I want to load within this
line of code, this line where we're pulling from the components.
So just add on comma, panel, body, comma, panel, row.
So with panel body and panel row from components and inspector controls from the block.
Ed, we have everything we need to create a right hand options area at this point.
Let's go down into our X..
So here we are returning our multiline JSC X and right within the opening div tag.
So right inside it right here.
This might seem unintuitive at first, but right here we're just going to include inspector controls
and hit tab inside the opening and closing tags.
We can drop down and now let's say panel body hit tab on the opening tag.
Let's give it a title.
Propp So title equals we could call it anything but maybe background color inside the opening and closing
tags.
Let's drop down and finally let's have something called Panel Row It tab.
And inside here just for a quick test, we can say hello, let's give this a save and test it out.
So back in the admin dashboard, if I refresh the edit screen.
Now, you do have to actually select or click on your block type instance, but as soon as I do here
we see background color.
Hello.
Yours might not be opened by default, so you can just click this arrow to open it.
Or better yet, on the panel body opening tag, we can give it a prop of initial open equals curly brackets
and then just give it either true or false.
So if you said it's true, then it should be open by default.
So I don't know about you, but the first time I saw this in action, I was pleasantly surprised.
I thought it would be a lot more involved or complicated to create sort of a right hand area.
So we just include inspector controls within the four hour block type.
And WordPress will know what to do with this.
Right.
It's not going to render it on the main left hand column.
It knows exactly where to place this.
Now, we don't actually want the word hello instead right here.
We want the color picker component.
Luckily for us, we don't need to program a color picker from scratch.
So check this out up at the very top of our code on this line where we're importing a bunch of different
components from WordPress.
Let's add one more.
So maybe after panel row, I'll say comma, color picker.
And now let's go leverage color picker, so back down in our J.C. Watts instead of hello exclamation,
this is where we could just have a self-closing color picker tag just like this.
Now, before we truly learn how to work with the color picker component, let's make sure that we have
an attribute or something that's going to save the value that the user chooses into the database.
Let me explain.
So if we scroll up just a bit, when we're using WP blocks, register, block type, remember, we spelled
out the attributes that this block has right now.
We have question answers and correct answer.
So let's just add a comma at the end of this line and add on another attribute.
You could name it anything, but I'll call it BGI color, colon, curly brackets.
Let's say that it's type should be a string and let's give it a default value of string text, hash
tag, Ebbe.
So just a light gray by default.
OK, now with this attribute in place, it's very easy to bring the color picker component to life.
So if we scroll back down on the color picker component, we just say color equals curly brackets and
then just give it that attribute.
So props, dot attributes dot big color.
So that will populated with the value initially when you first load the page.
But we also want to tell it what it should do every time the user selects a new color in real time.
So every time it changes its value.
So we just give it something called on change comp..
So this prop name is different than the usual on change.
So that is something to keep in mind when you're using the color picker component, it's on change comp.
But we just set it to equal curly brackets and give it a function instead of giving it a separate named
function.
Let's just write out an Essex arrow function right here.
So I'll include X as my one parameter that includes information about what just happened and then arrow
symbol.
If we just have one statement, we don't even need curly brackets and let's just use the WordPress set
attributes function.
So that's props, dot set attributes, parentheses to call it in those parentheses we give it an object
so curly brackets and then this will get merged into the other attributes.
So the attribute we want to change is BGI, color, colon and then X.
Right.
That contains information about what just happened.
And then we're going to look inside that.
So X dot and then I want the hexadecimal color code and the WordPress color picker component is going
to offer something just called hex.
So X hex, let's give this a save and test it out.
So if I refresh and click on the block type and if I choose maybe a light blue or teal.
And click update, so nothing changed over here yet, that's OK, we'll get to that in just a moment.
But if I refresh this page.
And click back on the blog type, cool, you can see that it remembered or stored that value.
So it's persisting now at this point, it's very easy.
Let's just go back to our actual blog type here and make it use that color.
So let's find the overall opening div tag.
Right.
So at the very start of the gests that we're returning, we have this div maybe after class name, let's
give it a prop of style equals one set of curly brackets for a dynamic value or just something other
than a literal string of text and then another set of curly brackets for an object of styles.
So background uppercase C for color.
Right.
Normally insists it would be background dash color, but this is JavaScript sort of pretending to be
fixed.
So it's background, color, Kohlman, and then we would just pull it from our attribute.
So props, dot attributes, dot BGU color.
Let's give that to save and test it out.
So now as soon as I refresh.
Awesome.
It's using our custom value.
Let me tone that down a bit.
Now, before we adjust the front end of our blacktip to also use the custom background color, I first
want to address a little styling detail on the admin side of things.
I'm getting this awkward horizontal scroll bar in the right hand toolbar and the color picker is what's
causing that awkward scrollbar.
Also, you'll notice there's not enough room or space for this icon right here.
And if you click on it, well, I just think it looks like it should be sitting here instead of down
below.
So all in all, I'm not very happy with the way that the default WordPress color picker is sort of squishing
down to fit in this area.
And there's nothing wrong with using the default color picker.
Maybe you could even adjust it so that it does properly fit in this area.
But instead, I want to use sort of a third party react component, not just for this tiny horizontal
scrollbar detail, but really just to show you how easy it is to use third party community react packages
inside of WordPress here.
So, for example, there is a package in the react community called React Color, and this has nothing
to do with WordPress.
However, we can see that it offers many different types or styles of color pickers.
So this one looks like Photoshop.
This one looks like sketch, GitHub, Twitter.
This one looks like the default Chrome browser color picker.
You get the idea.
So right now, I want to show you how you can use this package that has nothing to do with WordPress
within our block type in particular.
I want to use this version of the color picker and I want this to be placed right here.
So do this with me.
Voice code.
Let's open up our command line and press control.
See to stop the current task.
Or you could leave it running and open up a secondary command line.
But just for simplicity, let's stop that task so we can stay in this one single command line and run
this command with me.
So we're just going to install that react color package from NPM.
So we just say NPM install in the name was React Dasch, color press, enter.
OK, then we can start our task up again that watches us so that npm run, start cool.
So now back in our code, up at the very top, let's import that package.
So on a new line towards the top, I'll say import curly brackets from string of text.
And the package name was react dash color.
Now, inside the curly brackets, what do we want to import?
Well, that package has many, many different color pictures, right?
There's the Photoshop version.
There's the sketch version, so on and so forth.
In particular, I want the one that's called chrome picker.
OK, now let's go use or leverage this.
So back down in our JSA X.
Instead of color picker.
Let's just change this to chrome picker, we can leave the exact same color prop and unchanged complete
prop, but maybe at the end.
So right before the end of the self-closing tag, let's have one more prop and just say disable alpha
equals curly brackets.
True.
So I don't want to let the admin users change the alpha transparency.
Let's go ahead and save that.
And if we refresh and then click on the block, perfect.
So we no longer have the awkward horizontal scroll bar.
And I just think this color picker looks a bit cleaner, a bit more minimal and it works just the same.
So if I pick sort of a maybe light purple value and click update, I can go ahead and refresh the page
just to prove that it is persisting or storing that data perfect at this point.
Let's change gears and work on displaying the custom background color on the actual front end.
So if we view this on the front end of our site.
Currently, it's still displaying as just the default grey.
This is super easy to fix, so actually to save a bit of typing, we can just take on the opening div
that we just were working with.
Just take this style equals curly brackets, so we don't have to type that out again.
So just copy that into your clipboard.
And then in our file Explorer sidebar, just jump into front end, James.
OK, let's go down into the JSE, towards the bottom.
Here's the overall opening div tag and just paste in your clipboard right about here.
So we have style equals because that exact same attribute will be available to this component.
So if we save that and then refresh the front end.
Woops, you can see that didn't work, I know what the issue here is.
So instead of props attributes, big color now it would just be props, big color, because on the front
end version of our component, there is no attributes object.
We just directly destruction of the properties and pass them in as props.
So just props dot big color for the front end.
If we give that a save refresh perfect.
And that is going to bring this video to a close.
In our next lesson, we'll learn how to change the text alignment.
So, for example, when you click on this block type, we see this menu up here, right about here.
Well, wouldn't it be nice if there was a text alignment icon and you could just click on it and easily
say that the text for our block type should be perhaps center aligned or right aligned, should be a
lot of fun to set up.
And this will be the final lesson for this block type.
Before we change gears, let's keep the momentum rolling and I'll see you then.