Let's choose generic button.
So then you can just start typing, click me right away.
I'm noticing that the button background color is transparent.
That's not what we want.
We would want it to be the fictional university blue or fictional university orange.
Now, in our next lesson, we can actually build the dynamic color picker tool for this lesson.
Let's just hard code it to be blue by default and we can circle back to that later.
So in other words, in the edit component, right on the rich text in the class name after the button
dash, dash, curly bracket, but before the back tick closing curly brackets are right here.
You could just say BTN dashed dashed blue and then do the same thing.
If you scroll down just a tiny bit on the opening tag here we see class name again right before the
closing back tick and curly bracket.
You can just say BTN dashed, dashed blue.
So we'll hollow this out and make it actually dynamic and choose a bowl a bit later on.
But for now we can save that.
And let's go ahead and refresh the template editor.
Insert that again.
Click the plus symbol generic button.
Learn more.
Cool.
And it's actually blue now.
In our next lesson, we'll set up the color choosing ability for the remainder of this lesson, let's
work on the actual link value, the ref value, right?
So when someone clicks on this button, where should they go?
So here's what I have in mind.
Once you click on this in the editor admin screen, this toolbar appears right and you can use this
to change if it's large, medium or small.
Cool.
Well, I think maybe just right about here, we can have the link icon.
When you click that a little pop up window will appear and you can start searching for any pages or
posts on your website or just a you are URL in general.
Right?
And then that URL will be used for the ref value.
So how would we set that up?
Well, let's go look at our edit component.
So up here there's the rich text for the edit component.
But notice we already have block controls and a toolbar group for the large, medium and small buttons.
So what I would do right above this toolbar group, I would just create another toolbar group, toolbar
group opening and closing.
So this toolbar group will be for the small, medium and large, but this group can have the link icon
that you click.
So inside this group we just need one tool bar button can be self-closing.
Let's give it a prop of on click equals curly brackets and another prop of icon equals curly brackets.
Four on click.
Let's just point towards a function.
We can name it maybe button handler.
Let's go actually create a function with this name.
So within our edit component function, but above our return line, I can just say function button handler,
parentheses, curly brackets in terms of what we actually do in this function.
We can circle back to that in just a moment.
First, let's just make sure that the button is actually appearing on screen.
So let's fill in this icon value, just point towards a variable called link.
Now up at the very top of our file, let's import the official WordPress link icon and make it available
from this name.
So up at the very top, a brand new line of code will say import curly brackets link and we're importing
it from a package called at symbol WordPress slash icons.
Now this appears to be an exception to the rule.
For whatever reason, the official WordPress Scripts package will not be able to locate this and alias
this for us.
So even though we didn't need to manually install, you know, components or block editor or blocks
from NPM, we do need to go at least as of today, as of this recording.
We do need to go to NPM and install this package.
So hit save on your keyboard, open up your command line.
We can press control C to stop the current task and then just run this with me.
NPM install at symbol WordPress slash icons.
Go ahead and press enter.
As soon as that installation finishes, we're just going to restart up our script.
So let me run clear.
I'm only running clear.
So it's not falling off the bottom of the screen so you can actually see it in the recording.
You don't need to worry about ever typing clear if you see me do that anyways.
Now we just start up our task again.
So npm run start.
Okay.
And then back in the browser if we've refreshed the template editor and again, just a reminder, you
might want to save your template editor before refreshing so you don't have to keep inserting the button
block again and again and again.
But with that saved if I refresh.
And click on the block.
Perfect.
There is the link icon.
So now it's just a matter of when you click on that, something should actually happen.
What specifically do we think should happen?
Well, let's set things up so that when you click this, it toggles whether the link chooser tool is
visible or not.
So we're going to have a piece of data that will just be true or false.
And it's essentially saying, is the link chooser visible?
True or false?
Now, where should we save that data?
Well, I'm actually not going to store it in attributes.
I'm going to use React State itself.
My reasoning for this is because we don't ever, ever need to store something like that in the database.
Right.
It's just a super temporary UI detail of whether you've toggled it to be visible or not.
So there's no sense in treating it like a meaningful block attribute.
So how do you use React State within the context of WordPress?
Well, up at the top here, let's say import curly brackets, import something called use state.
From now outside of the WordPress world, you would import React.
But in WordPress we would import this from at some more quotes, WordPress slash element.
So WordPress makes React available sort of as an alias on element.
I believe WordPress does this.
So if in the future they ever wanted to get rid of React and replace it with another JavaScript library,
they have this abstraction layer right instead of having you and I as the developer directly depend
on and call react directly.
Anyways, now that we have use state, let's go use it in our edit component.
So at the very start of the body of our edit component function right here, let's say const square
brackets.
So have a comma B for the first value we get to make up a name for our piece of state.
We can name it anything, but why don't we call it is link picker visible?
And then for B it would be set.
Is link picker visible?
All of that should equal use state and give it a default value of false.
In other words, when you first load the block of the page, we wouldn't want the link chooser to already
be visible.
So false.
Now we can just set things up so that when you click on this link icon, we manipulate that value to
be true.
So let's do this in our button handler function within the curly brackets we would just call set is
link picker visible and instead of just setting it to always be true, let's set it to the opposite
of whatever it currently is.
So that way this button can actually act as a toggle, right?
If the link picker tool is visible and you click this link again, it should hide it.
So to do that, we would just say start with the previous value pass.
I didn't do an arrow function.
And what do we want to return?
Just the opposite of the previous value.
So exclamation prev.
Cool.
Now before we go use that value is link picker visible in our gsx.
Let's first import a component from WordPress that makes it very easy to display sort of an inline pop
up bit of content.
So up at the very top of our file on this line where we're importing from WordPress components, let's
import something else.
So comma, the thing we're interested in is pop over.
This makes it really easy to create sort of pop ups or popovers.
So here's what I would do down in our edit component gsx maybe right below our rich text field.
So right before the closing of the fragment right about here, let's have curly brackets and let's say
is link picker visible?
So that's going to be true or false and ingest X, we can just say and end parentheses, you can drop
down in the parentheses and now whatever we include here will only be included if this is true.
So what do we want to include in here?
Let's just have a pop over for now.
In the pop over, let's just have the word hello.
And then three exclamations.
In a minute we can have the actual link picker live here, but let's give this a test.
So save that.
So refresh our template editor.
So if we click on our button and then click on the link icon.
Cool.
Notice this just popped up sort of animated in The View.
And if we click on the link icon again, it goes away.
Perfect.
So now, instead of just the word hello and three exclamations, let's have an actual link chooser tool.
Luckily we don't need to reinvent the wheel.
WordPress already has a link chooser that we can just leverage.
So back up at the very top of our code when we are importing items from WordPress slash block editor,
let's add a comma.
And trust me, I realize the name of this looks really weird, but as of today, this is what it is.
It's underscore, underscore, experimental, uppercase link, uppercase control.
Now, I don't know about you, but I don't want to have to type that in down below in our gsx.
So what we can do is say import that as just link control.
So then this is sort of an alias or a shortcut.
This is what we can actually use down below before we go down into our JS acts and actually leverage
link control.
Let's update our attributes.
So we have the text that you type in that you click on.
We have the size without a comma and let's have something called I mean, we can make up any name we
want, but just so you and I are on the same page.
Let's call it maybe link object.
Call in curly brackets.
It's a type of object.
So in the WordPress link control link picker tool, when you select a link, it's going to store multiple
pieces of data about that link.
So for example, if you clicked on a blog post that you wanted to link towards, it's going to store
the ID number of that blog post in addition to the title of the blog post and then the actual URL for
the blog post.
So we've got multiple pieces of information that will live inside of link object.
Cool.
So now that that's in place, there's just one more detail before we set up the actual gsx on the line
where we're importing from components.
In addition to pop over, let's say comma, let's also import something called button.
Cool.
Now we should have all the pieces we need to build something meaningful.
So if we scroll down into the pop over Gsx area, let's get the parentheses back.
So opening parentheses before pop over.
Closing parentheses there.
So now we can drop down to multiple lines like this.
And now we don't just want the word hello inside the pop over.
What we truly want is a link control.
Oops, I didn't mean to have the closing tag.
We want a self-closing link control tag just like this.
Let's give it a few props so we can have one called settings and let's just set that to an empty array.
We don't need any custom settings for its value, so value equals curly brackets.
That would just be that link object that we set up a moment ago.
So props dot attributes dot link object.
Okay, finally, let's give it a prop of on change equals curly brackets and let's make up a function
name.
We can create it in 10 seconds from now.
How about handle link change.
Finally below that link control but still within our popover.
Let's add a button that you can click that will close the popover.
So button upper case button component.
The actual text that you would click on says maybe confirmed link.
So I'm just making this up.
Let's give the opening tag a few props.
So variant equals primary.
Let's say what should happen if you click the button.
So on click equals curly brackets.
Let's just write an anonymous function or an arrow function that just sets the popover to be invisible
again.
Or in other words, we can just set this piece of state to be false.
So just empty parentheses.
Arrow symbol set is link picker visible.
And just set it to false.
Finally, on this opening button tag, let's give it a style.
Props.
A style equals curly brackets.
Another set of curly brackets for a style object and let's say display should be block comma and width
should be quotes 100%.
Cool.
Now, before we save this, let's go create the function named handle link change.
So if we scroll up right above all of our jazz acts, we already have these functions, maybe right
below those.
So right before the return line we can just say function, handle, length, change, parentheses,
curly brackets.
In these parentheses be sure to include a parameter.
You can name it X or let's name it maybe new link.
The idea is that that component is going to pass into this function, the new link object, whatever
link the user has chosen.
So what we would want to do is call props dot set attributes.
Remember, we give that an object and then we would just want to change the attribute, the block attribute
that we named the link object and set it to be whatever was passed into this function.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So.
Can the editor if we refresh.
If I click on the button, click the link icon.
Cool.
However, I think it would look better if it was centered horizontally below our button.
So let me show you what we can do down when we use the Popover component on the opening pop tag.
You can just say position equals and let's say middle center just like this.
Cool.
Let's give that a save and test it out again.
So if we refresh, click on the button, click the link icon.
Cool.
So imagine we wanted to link this to our About US page.
So if I just start to search for the word about perfect, there is our about us page.
I can click on that.
I can click confirm link.
We can go ahead and save this template.
And now to really understand what sort of data that saved, let's go look at our database and then we
can talk about how we're going to use that link object.
So if we dig in to the post table, click select data, go to the last page, scroll down to the bottom
and click edit on the very last item.
Cool.
This is the page template we just saved and if you scroll down towards the bottom of this banner block
code.
We're looking for this.
So this is our generic button.
So there's the text attribute, right?
That's what we typed in.
Learn more.
And then we had the attribute called Link Object.
And now this is what I'm trying to draw attention to.
So this is the object that WordPress created for us that represents the link that we chose.
So you can see it includes, you know, the I.D. of that post, the URL for the post, the title, the
post type, so on and so forth.
So there are a million different ways that you could leverage this.
For example, if you wanted to build something really resilient, you could use the post ID.
So that way, even if the permalink was ever changed in the future, you could write a bit of code using
the rest API or a callback to use the post ID to look up the current URL on the fly.
In this moment right now, I don't think we need to build something that resilient or that custom.
So realistically, the only property were truly interested in right now is the URL value, right?
The actual HTTP value that we want to use for our ref value.
So here's what I would do in our code.
Let's go find our save component.
So down towards the bottom or save component.
All we really need to do is set the ref to equal instead of quotes and hash tag.
It would be equals curly brackets and then just say props dot attributes, dot link, object, dot URL.
Let's give this a save.
And now unfortunately, because this is a JavaScript function for the save output, you know, the actual
HTML value, we do need to go back into the template editor refresh.
Klick attempt block recovery just to be safe.
Click on the link option again.
Click Confirm Link and click Save.
Now in the future, when we finish the ban or block an ad, the ability to upload a new image for the
background image, we will learn how to have a dynamic render callback function instead of a JavaScript
save function, and that will alleviate a lot of this sort of static, manually clicking update behavior
that I am not a fan of at all.
But I didn't want to dogmatically force that render callback opinion on you.
So that's why for these first few blocks that we've been building, we're using this JavaScript save
approach anyways.
Now that we've saved our template, let's go to the front end of our website.
So just visit the home page URL and refresh.
Cool, there's our button.
But more importantly, if you hover over it and actually click on it, perfect.
The page didn't change because we haven't built out our templates yet.
But the important thing is if you look in the URL of address bar of your browser, it successfully took
us to slash about us.
That's going to bring this video to a close.
In our next lesson, we're going to add the ability to choose whether you want this button to be blue,
orange or dark orange should be a lot of fun to set up.
Let's keep our momentum rolling and I'll see you then.