Hello, everyone.
This is a quick note that I'm filming in June of 2020.
So we just completed the JavaScript for the My Notes feature.
However, we used J.
Query to accomplish this.
And right now, I want to provide you with an alternative or G query free version of our code.
I didn't think it made sense to re film the entire previous chapter for just minor syntax differences
and slightly different approaches here and there.
So all of the same overall big picture concepts stay the same.
I'm just approaching things slightly differently.
So in this window, this is the code that we wrote together.
But in this window, this is the same my notes module, but I coded it without using J.
Query.
So you can find this file available for download in the associated resources for this lesson.
And this is a completely compatible drop in replacement for our existing my notes J.
S file.
So I can just copy the entire contents into my clipboard back in our existing file, delete everything
pasted in, hit save.
And if you have your npm run dev task running in the command line, that will rebundle everything up.
I will refresh in the browser to make sure that my event handlers aren't doubling up.
But if I try to create a new note, I already have five notes.
So we see the note limit reached.
If I delete one of my existing notes, the message goes away.
And now I can successfully create another note.
So it works exactly the same.
Now, right now, I want to jump through the code.
Sort of from a bird's eye view and walk through the different approaches that I took without having
J query in my tool box.
So up at the top, I'm using Axios once again to make H.
TTP requests to our WordPress rest API in the constructor.
I wrapped things within an IF statement because I only want to run basic code for this module.
If the my notes parent div exists on the current page.
Right.
Because it's not like every page on our Web site needs to run this JavaScript.
Also when it comes to the nonce code that WordPress provides so that it can trust, we are who we say
we are.
Well, instead of including that in each individual request, I'm just setting it once globally up here.
OK.
Everything's fairly standard here for my event listening.
I do have a function named Find Nearest Parent Ally.
Essentially I coded this because the user can click on the delete or edit button the button itself.
Right.
Or they can click on the little icon.
And those are separate DOM elements.
So the whole point of this function is regardless of which specific element you click on.
It just loops up the parent dom tree to find the nearest list item element.
Right.
Because that's what contains information about the current note, like the note I.D. scrolling down.
Everything else is fairly standard instead of J query methods to remove attributes or add attributes
to an element.
I'm just using web browser native methods like remove attribute and to add or remove CSF classes.
I'm just using class list, dot, add or class list at all remove.
Here you can see I'm setting an attribute.
This is how you do it without J.
Query.
If we scroll down a bit.
A lot of the same things going on in this function.
Scroll down even further.
Here you can see I'm using axios to send a request to the WordPress.
Rest API Axios is going to return a promise.
So then I'm awaiting that promise.
So JavaScript will not move on to the next line of code until this promise actually completes or returns.
If I keep scrolling down, there's really not a whole lot else to review here.
We can see when I'm adding a bit of HDMI oil instead of using the J.
Query HTC Malfunction.
I'm using the Web browser native insert adjacent HDMI oil.
The first argument is where in relation to that element do you want to insert this?
So after the beginning div tag and then the second argument is just the string of HDMI MLT.
You want to add.
If I scroll down, the only other interesting thing going on in this file is this code down here.
So J Query has really convenient methods named slide down and slide up.
So for example, if I delete one of my notes.
Notice how it animates up.
Well, since I coded this without using J query, I needed to sort of code my own slide up or slide
down functionality.
So I'm using CSF for the transition or the animation.
But I do need to use JavaScript to sort of babysit the hight values in the classes.
Essentially, this is because in CSX, you can't intimate to a height of auto in CSX if you want to
animate or transition to height value.
You need to actually provide a real value.
You can't just say auto.
You can't let an element.
It's natural height.
So behind the scenes, I'm doing a bit of trickery here.
I'm inserting an element.
But having it be invisible for just a split second, I'm measuring its height.
I'm keeping track of that.
And then I'm sort of babysitting the process of adding it or removing it to the DOM.
So you'll notice that if I add an element or a note, I should say it also gradually fades or animates
in.
OK.
That about does it for this new JavaScript file.
I encourage you to use this drop in replacement for my notes dot j.
Yes.
One other thing I do want to cover.
If you jump into the CSX folder and then modules and then the my notes dot CSX file down at the bottom,
you'll see this comment reveal and hide fade transition.
So just make sure that this code exists and that it's not commented out.
I believe in an earlier lesson, the course I instructed you to comment out this code if you wanted
your J query animations to look smooth.
But now that we're not using J.
Query, you do definitely want to have these custom CSX rules here in place.
OK, that brings this video to a close.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see in the next one.