Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, I want to talk about a file named BLOCK JSON which can make loading our blocks, JavaScript
and CC files a little bit simpler.
Let's jump into the action.
So here I am in our Are You paying attention folder?
And just in the route of this plugins folder, let's create a brand new file and name it block dot JSON.
It needs to be this exact name, block dot.
Jason okay.
Now the question becomes, what do we do inside this file?
Well, first, let's talk a little bit about what in the world this file is supposed to be.
So if we look at the official WordPress documentation, you can find this, by the way, by Googling
for WordPress block dot.
Jason, this should be the first result.
But here we can see that starting in WordPress version 5.8, which was the summer of 2021, WordPress
officially started recommending using this file as the canonical way to register block types.
And then right here you'll see a bit of example code that we're just going to copy and paste.
If you don't want to visit this WordPress documentation page in your browser, you can always find the
completed files as a downloadable zip associated with this lesson, but I'm just going to select everything
in this example.
Bit of code, copy that into my clipboard and then back in our empty block JSON pasted in.
Now we don't need every single property here.
Let's start at the top and we can sort of work our way through.
So this dollar sign schema, this just defines which properties this file should and should not contain.
API version two that will come into play a little bit later on in the video.
For now, we can skip over that.
Let's definitely change the name value, right?
So it has the namespace and then the name of our block.
So if you jump into index dot B and for me it's around line number 21.
But you might remember that this is the name of our block type, our plug in slash.
Are you paying attention?
So I would just use that as my name value here.
The human readable title is Are You Paying Attention?
And now the idea here is that if you define one of these properties in this blocked out JSON file,
you don't need to define it in your JavaScript file.
So in other words, you could now go into your JavaScript file and remove the title property.
I won't bore you with most of these properties because they're the exact same thing that you would include
in your JavaScript file.
So there's really nothing too exciting here.
I would actually just delete category parent icon description.
I'm going to delete all of these.
All the way down to these lines, down at the bottom of editor, script, script, view, script, editor,
style and style.
These properties are the entire reason I wanted to make this video.
So as you saw all those properties we deleted.
Yes.
BLOCK dot JSON can be used for many different things.
But ultimately the thing I find most interesting is that we can point towards our assets, our JavaScript
and CC files from within this file.
And then you and I don't need to manually load in and queue them within PHP.
We can cover all five of these properties in the video.
But first let's begin with editor, script and editor style.
So I'll actually move Ed style up so that they're sitting together.
So these are the JavaScript and CC assets that will only be loaded in the admin editor screen, not
the front end of our website.
So let's go ahead and save this file.
And just to prove that it's actually working and going to load our assets, let's go into our index
dot AP file because actually before WordPress will truly make use of block dot.
Jason, we need to adjust something in PHP when we're calling register block type.
So previously, remember when we used register block type, the first argument is the name of our block.
Well, if you're using block dot JSON, you instead want this first argument to just point towards the
folder or directory that contains the block dot JSON file.
So that's the current folder that we're in right now.
So really this first argument would instead just be underscore, underscore, die, r underscore, underscore.
Cool.
Also because we're using block dot Jason.
Now, we don't need to manually spell out our editor script or our editor style so we can get rid of
that within this array.
And also, we don't need to register them as files on these two lines so we can get rid of this line
of code and get rid of this line of code.
So now literally all we're doing is just saying, hey, use this directory that has a blocked JSON file
and we are still pointing towards our PHP render callback.
But with this in place, we can save this file, make sure you have your block dot JSON file saved.
And to test it out, let's just go edit a post.
So I'll edit this yet another post which contains a copy of our quiz block.
There it is.
You can even perform a hard refresh if you want to.
Just to prove the point.
You can hold down the shift key and click the reload icon.
Cool.
So it's actually loading our assets.
However, if I zoom out a little bit, you'll notice that the quiz block is taking up the full available
width instead of previously.
It knew that it should only take up about this much horizontal space.
Also, currently, I can't just click on the block and have it change the right hand sidebar so that
you can change the color of the block.
In other words, if I use this list view icon right about here, then yes, I can click on Are You Paying
Attention?
And notice as soon as I click on that you can indeed have the block menu on the right hand sidebar.
So in other words, why are we not able to see that any more by just actually clicking on the block
here?
Well, this is where if we go back in the block that JSON, this is where this API version two comes
into play.
Essentially, if you opt into this newest version, version two, that means that you now need to micro-manage
or babysit the wrapper element for the block itself in the editor.
So previously, when we had not yet opted in to this version two, WordPress would add its own generic
wrapper element around our block here in the editor, and it would handle all the programming and logic
so that when you click on that area, it knows to treat it as selected in the editor screen as a whole.
So the question becomes, well, how do we take that into our own hands, or how do we make that happen
now that we're using this new version?
Well, luckily, it's not too difficult, so we just need to jump into our JavaScript file for our block.
So in the sassy folder, jump in to index dot.
Jess Up at the top of this file, we're looking for the line where we're importing items from slash
block editor.
So then in the curly brackets where we're importing or structuring from block editor, we would just
add a comma, pull in one more item called use block props.
So we just use this.
And then you and I don't need to program any of the logic that WordPress uses to know that a block is
selected, so on and so forth.
So we just need to go use this on our wrapper element.
Let me show you how we use it.
So let's scroll down and find our edit component function.
Here it is now, right within the body of this function.
So as soon as it starts right here, let's add a brand new line and let's just create a constant called
block props.
You could name it anything.
So there's nothing special about this name.
I just made it up but set that to equal and then use block props parentheses to actually call that.
And now you would just make sure that you give this to your wrapper element and then WordPress will
take care of the rest, right?
So it will have the on click events, any sort of subtle styling to show that the block is selected,
so on and so forth.
So then we would just go down into the sex that we're returning.
So for us, it's this div and right after the V and div, but before class name, I would just say curly
brackets, dot, dot, dot, block props.
So the three dots like this, we would refer to this as the spread syntax.
Essentially whatever properties live inside of block props.
Each one will be applied to this wrapper element.
So this way we don't need to spell each property out one by one.
Now, if you and I were not already parsing class name and style onto this div, we'd be done.
But because we do have these props of class, name and style, let me show you what we need to do.
Let's actually cut these into our clipboard so I would begin selecting from class name and just select
all the way to these closing two curly brackets for the style prop as well.
So just cut that into your clipboard.
So now literally the only thing on this opening wrapper element is just block props.
Okay.
And now I want you to scroll back up to when we called use block props essentially in these parentheses.
When we're calling use block props, we can give it an object and now anything we give it, WordPress
will know to sort of merge that into any of its properties.
Right.
That it's using for basic behaviors like knowing when the element is selected or not.
So this is where we would just paste in our clipboard.
Only these shouldn't be phrased as props.
This should be phrased it just properties and values.
So instead of class name equals, it would be class name, colon, and then a string of text.
After the string we add a comma we could drop down.
It wouldn't be style equals, it would be style colon.
And then we don't need the double opening curly brackets.
We just need one.
We don't need double closing curly brackets.
Just one.
Cool.
So just like this, we can give that a save and actually make sure that your NPM task is running.
So NPM run start.
Cool.
And let's go test this out.
So back in the editor screen, when I refresh, we're hoping that we can actually click on that block
now.
Cool.
So now it knows to not take up the full width.
Also, as soon as I click on it perfect, it actually shows the appropriate menu in the right hand side.
Also notice that WordPress knew to give it the slight blue border because it's selected or active.
So that takes care of our editor success in JavaScript.
Now let's change gears and talk about the front end assets.
So really quick, let me just change this color click update.
So that gives me this link to view the post on the front end.
Perfect.
Now let's talk about making sure we're loading the access and JavaScript for our block on the front
end.
Let's start with the CCed because it's a lot simpler than the JavaScript.
So essentially back in our blocked JSON file.
So you'll notice there's style, but there is no view style.
Let me explain what's going on here.
So when you see editor and then scripter style, that means it will only be loaded in the editor if
there's no word in front of it.
So if it's just script or just style, it's going to be loaded on both the editor and the front end.
And if you see the word view, that means it's only for the front end.
Unfortunately, there is no view style, so there is no way to load a CSV file just for the front end.
Well, there is a way if you take matters into your own hands.
We already did that in our index dot ap file but using blocked dot Jason, you would just provide your
front end CSV file here and hopefully.
Right, see selectors that don't select anything on the admin side.
So in other words, here's what I would do.
Our file is not named style boxes if you look in the build folder.
Right.
Ours is named front end dot CST.
So for this style property I would just change this file name to front end next.
Go ahead and give that a save.
To prove that it's working, we need to go remove our manual CST that we load it index dot up.
So in our AP file around line number 24, we have our HTML render callback function.
And remember we wrote this if statement, we said if you are not in the admin.
So in other words, if you're on the front end load our CSC in JavaScript assets.
So we would just delete this on queue style line, completely delete that line.
So this way we can prove that our access is being loaded.
So I'll give that a save.
Make sure you're blocked out, JSON is saved.
And now if we refresh the front end, perfect.
We still have these styles.
You can really prove that it's working by, you know, getting an answer wrong or correct or to really
prove that it's working.
You could just provide a wrong path here on purpose.
So if I point towards a file that doesn't exist, refresh.
You get the idea.
We put that back.
Perfect.
So that takes care of the cost.
At this point, the only detail remaining is the client side JavaScript for the front end.
The reason I saved this for last is because it's not perfect in my opinion.
So WordPress gives us editors script, which is just for the editor.
It gives us a script which would load in both environments, the editor and the front end.
And finally, it gives us Vue script, which is just for the front end.
So you would think this is perfect.
However, WordPress will not load the view script for you if your block uses a PHP render callback function.
And because every block that I ever create is most likely going to use a b render callback function.
That means we can't rely on this.
So to be clear, if our block type did not use a pre render callback, then this would work.
WordPress would indeed load this for us just on the front end because we are using a callback function.
The question becomes what are our options?
Well, let me go ahead and delete view script because it's not going to work for us.
So you have two options.
A, you could just leave this code that we've already written in place.
The WordPress documentation will tell you that you're going to have to load the file yourself like this
if you're using a render callback function.
So that's option number one.
Just continue to load the JavaScript yourself or let me show you what another option is.
You could get rid of this, you could delete this if statement where we're loading JavaScript.
So now literally all our callback function is doing is just rendering this HD HTML.
You could save that, right?
Obviously now no client side JavaScript will load and what you could do is just take advantage of this
script property.
So this file will load for both environments, both the editor and the front end.
So I can just point towards my front end js file.
Oops.
I mean spell it correctly.
Give that a save as soon as I refresh.
Woops.
You can see it doesn't work.
And this is because WordPress is loading it in the head instead of down in the foot.
So in other words, the dorm hasn't loaded in been processed by the time our JavaScript runs, so it
can't see the content that is looking for.
This is a bit frustrating because when you load a JavaScript asset and PHP in WordPress you can tell
it to be true or false, right?
Whether you want it to load in the footer or not.
As of today, there doesn't appear to be a way to do that when you're loading a file from JavaScript
like this or JSON.
So what you could do is go into our front end JavaScript.
So in the CRC folder, front end.
Yes.
And you could just wrap all of our code so that it only runs after the DOM has been passed.
So in other words, you would select everything in this file except for these three import lines at
the top.
So just select from this constant divs line down to the very, very bottom.
Cut that into your clipboard, wrap it inside document dot add event listener.
That takes two arguments for the first argument.
The event we're listening for is Dom content loaded.
Second argument is just a function in that function.
Just paste back in your clipboard so you can give that a save.
Now when you refresh perfect.
The DOM has actually been passed.
It's almost as if we're loading the JavaScript in the footer instead of in the header.
So that is an option.
Personally, I probably wouldn't want to do that.
Also, this JavaScript is now going to be loaded on the editor side as well.
Now, if you wrote your JavaScript in a flexible way so that it's not going to throw any errors if it
loads here.
Cool.
But remember, you can always use the option that we already had previous to this lesson, right?
Where you load the JavaScript, file yourself, you on, queue it yourself from within your PHP render
callback that is going to bring this lesson to a close.
To summarize, the block dart JSON file is the official way that WordPress recommends we register our
block types and in my opinion, it can make loading our assets a lot simpler.
For a working example that you can reference.
Remember, you can always download the associated zip file for this lesson with my finished product
code.
Let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.