So just a fair warning.
The remainder of this video lesson is now just all of my own personal preference and my own personal
philosophy.
Essentially, I don't want to store the hexadecimal color code.
I want an extra layer of abstraction.
Let me explain what I mean.
So if we go look at the edges for our button, right, we've hardcoded down our save component, BTN
dash, dash blue.
So I only have 60 classes for blue, orange and dark orange.
That's it.
And those are the only classes and colors that I want to use.
In other words, I don't care about the hexadecimal color codes.
The only reason let me scroll up a little bit.
The only reason we've even listed our colors here with these color code values is so the user can visually
see a little circle of what color they're choosing.
Right?
In other words, the only reason these codes even exist in this JavaScript file is just to provide a
preview to the end user, to have something to see and click on.
In terms of the data we're storing and the system that we're going to output, I don't want to rely
on these color code values.
I want an abstraction layer.
So I would want the data in the database to actually say color, name, colon, and then literally a
string of text that says blue or orange.
Or if you wanted to use more abstract names like, you know, primary color or secondary color, that's
the approach I would want to take.
So then it's up to me, you know, let's say a year from now, the fictional University Blue, the design
team decides that it should be a different shade of blue.
Well, in that case, I don't want to have to worry that hexadecimal color codes spread out through
my data like this are outdated.
I would just want to be able to update my CC class.
So let me show you how I would set this up.
And remember, the end goal here is that I want this data to just literally say, you know, a string
of text of blue.
So back in our code, let's begin up at the top in our attributes.
So on color name, let's just go ahead and give it a default value of blue.
Okay.
Next, let's go find the function that we created called handle color change within the body of this
function.
You can even write a comment to ourselves.
We can say from the hex value that the color palette gives us, we need to find its color name.
So in other words, if the palette component gives us this hexadecimal color code, when the user clicks
on it, we need to write a little bit of code that looks in our colors array for that value, and then
we want to return the name that matches that value.
There are multiple ways to do that in JavaScript.
Every array has access to a filter method.
You could use that.
However, WordPress actually has a function specifically for this use case.
So check this out.
Up at the very top on the line where we're importing items from block editor, we can just add a comma.
And there is an official WordPress tool name to get color object by color value get color object by
color value.
Let's go use it.
So down in our function.
Right handle color change.
Right above this line where we say props, stat set attributes.
Let's write a new line and say get color object by color value.
We give it two things.
A acorn would be the first thing we give it is the array of colors.
So our colors, the second thing we give it is the color code.
So color code.
So this function, when we're calling it, it's going to return this object, right?
It's going to see that this is the value we provided.
So it's going to return this entire blue object.
So at the start of this line, let's just de structure things we can say contrast curly brackets to
de structure equals.
And then in the curly brackets we just want to pull out the property of name.
So in other words, this line of code will now give us blue.
Or if the color code you passed into it was something else, it would give us orange or dark orange.
Cool.
So then that's what we want to use on this line when we're setting our attribute.
So instead of color code, this would just be this name variable that we made up.
Cool.
So that's step one to working with the color name instead of the color code value.
Finally, we need to go back down to our color palette component.
Here it is.
And when we're saying value equals, we do indeed need to give this component a color code value.
So we can't say value equals blue, so it doesn't make sense to give it the color name.
So let's hollow this out.
Value equals curly brackets.
Let's make up a variable name.
Let's call it maybe current color value.
Now let's just go create a variable with this matching name.
So back up if you scroll up a little bit, maybe right above our handle color change function, we can
just say.
Konst Current color value equals.
Now we are starting with the color name and we need to retrieve the actual color code.
Now I've looked through the WordPress documentation.
I don't believe they have the opposite of this function.
So we can just get creative and write the code ourselves.
So this should equal and then let's just start working with our array of colors so our colors and we'll
use the array method called filter.
Let's write an arrow function.
So color arrow function, curly brackets.
So filter is going to build a new array in the body of this function.
Here you just return true or false.
So each item in the array that gets looped through, if you say true, it'll be included in the new
array.
So I'm just going to say return and then you know, it would be true or false, but the condition would
be if color dot name.
So the current color we've looped to if it's name, if that equals whatever color name we've stored
in our block attributes or props, dot attributes, dot color name.
So if that's true, include that in the new array.
So now this new array will only have one item in it.
So at the end of this code we can just say square brackets, the first item in the array and then at
the end dot color, right, which will give us the actual color property value.
Cool.
So when you have a fresh, empty block, we've said that the default color should be blue.
And just from that string of text now our color palette and all of our code will realize that this is
the color that should be selected.
Let's give it a test.
So if we save that and we go refresh, we'll probably get an error.
Yep.
That's just because what was already in the database is a hexadecimal color code.
So obviously we can't look it up based on the color name because we don't have a color name right here.
So to really test this out with our new code in mind, just delete this block instance.
So remove generic button and insert a fresh copy.
So generic button, say learn more, offset the color to light orange, I'll click save.
I can refresh to prove that it's remembering that choice.
If I click on the button.
Perfect.
It remembered that that's the selected choice.
And now if we go back to our database.
So if we just go back to our post table, go to the last item, click on the last item.
Perfect generic button.
The color name is actually just a string of text that says Orange.
Beautiful.
So now we can just go use that in our success classes that we're outputting.
Let me show you what I have in mind.
Let's start with our edit component so that as you're clicking these choices, this button is actually
changing its color.
So in our edit component X, we are looking for the rich text component.
We already have class name and the size is dynamic.
Now we just want to make the color part dynamic to save a bit of typing.
I'm just going to copy this dollar sign prop stock attribute size.
Just copy that.
Hollow out the hardcoded blue.
Paste that in and just change dot size to dot color name.
Cool.
And then just go do the same thing as well in our save component.
So save component we already have the class name.
The size part is dynamic.
So just again, get rid of the hardcoded blue paste in your clipboard.
Change dot size to dark color name.
Let's give that a save and test it out.
Now, I have to warn you, when we refresh, we're going to have to click the, you know, update block
because we modified the save value.
So attempt block recovery.
But now as I'm clicking these different colors, notice our button is actually getting updated.
More importantly, if I choose this dark orange click save and we actually go refresh the front end,
whoops, it's still blue.
If you look at your inspector, you can see that.
Oddly enough, it has beaten dark orange and beaten blue.
I think this is just a weird side effect of us modifying the save value while we've already had an instance
of the block inserted.
For example, if you click on to the block and click Advanced here, you can see WordPress for whatever
reason has tried to manually add BTN Dash Dash blue.
So now that our JavaScript save output code is actually complete right now that we've actually set this
up so that this part is dynamic.
Let's give ourselves a fresh slate.
Delete this instance of the block and insert a totally fresh new copy now that our JavaScript is finalized.
So generic button learn more.
Let's tell it to be light orange.
Click Save.
Now if we refresh the front end.
Perfect.
So that example we just ran into where you have to click that awkward attempt block recovery button.
As you can see throughout this chapter, I'm not a fan of that behavior in any way, shape or form.
Don't worry.
We are getting very, very close to showing you my preferred render callback approach, and that can
solve all of those awkward issues.
The reason I didn't build this in chapter entirely using that personal approach of mine is because I
really don't want to force that opinion on you.
Anyways, back to the task at hand of our color picker.
Let's finish things up in this lesson.
So, number one, I want to show you how you can restrict a few of these custom options here.
So I don't want the user to be able to click clear.
And I absolutely 100% do not want the user to be able to click on the color preview here and provide
a totally custom color value.
In fact, being able to disable the custom color chooser here is the entire reason why I built this
custom color approach instead of just using a theme palette from themed JSON.
From my experience, any value you provide in themed JSON can be overridden by the end user, and I
don't like that if I'm using WordPress as a content management system, I only want to give the user
a few choices that they can pick from a few curated and wisely chosen choices.
So to finish things off, to disable this ability to pick a totally custom color.
All we need to do in our edit component is find the color palette.
Here it is and just give it a few additional props.
So number one, let's say disable custom colors equals curly brackets.
True.
We want to enable that.
And then let's say colorable equals curly brackets.
False.
If we give that a save and we refresh.
Now when we click on the button.
Perfect.
The end user doesn't have any ability to choose a custom value.
They literally can just pick between our branded, highly curated selection of colors.
This is exactly what I want.
Cool.
Now, one last detail before we bring this lesson to a close.
You might have been screaming at the screen saying, Brad, do we really want a hard code, our list
of colors in one single file like this?
What if you want to use this array of colors across ten different custom blocks?
Well, that's easy.
I would just split this array into a separate file and then just import it anywhere I need to use it.
So let's do that together really quick in our themes in C or includes folder or really you could do
this anywhere.
I just think this would make sense.
In the includes folder, you could create a new file and maybe name it colors.
Or better yet, let's call it our colors.
Dot JS.
Okay.
In that brand new empty file, just cut and paste our constant variable of our colors.
Right.
Our array.
Just copy that pasted into here at the very bottom.
Say export default.
Our colors give that a save.
And now back in the file we've been working on, you can delete that array of colors.
Cool.
And then up at the very top you can just say import our colors from quotes, dot, dot, slash to go
up out of the our blocks folder and then dig into the iron folder and grab the file called Our Colors.
If you wanted to, you could say yes, but you don't need to.
You can give that file to save refresh.
And as you can see, everything still works perfectly.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our very next lesson, we're going to work on our banner block.
We're going to revisit the banner block and set things up so that you can actually upload and choose
a different background image.
We're also going to learn about my preferred way of handling things with PHP render callbacks.
I think there's going to be a ton of fun.
I think it should be an aha moment.
So let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.