Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to actually start working on the background image choosing functionality
for our banner block.
Let's jump into the action.
So right away the question becomes from the template editor screen.
If you have the overall banner block selected.
So if I click right about here, well then over in this right hand menu for that block, maybe right
about here, we would want a button that lets you choose the background image.
So how do we set that up?
Well, let's begin by importing all of the ingredients that will need.
So in our text editor in the our blocks folder, jump into banner.
Gorgeous.
And let's pull in all of the ingredients we'll need.
So up at the top here on this line where we're importing from block editor, let's add a comma here
and also import something called inspector controls comma.
We also want media upload comma.
We also want media upload check.
Okay then we need to import on an entirely new line because we need to pull something in from components.
So import curly brackets from quotes at WordPress slash components.
Now in the curly brackets, what we want to pull in is button comma, panel, body, comma, panel row.
Okay, now let's go actually leverage and use all of these new ingredients.
So we're interested in our edit component.
So within our edit component, we're just looking for the sex that we're returning.
Now, remember in G6, you can only have one top level element.
So here's what I'm going to do.
Cut all of this current G6 into your clipboard.
So the entire wrapper of all of its contents, everything just cut it in its place.
Let's have a react fragment.
Now, in that fragment, sure, we can paste in our clipboard, but then inside the fragment right above
what we just paste it in, let's have an inspector controls component.
So in Spectre controls, we do indeed want the actual closing tag.
Inside of that we want a panel body, panel body on the opening tag.
Let's give it a prop of title.
You could make up anything, but let's call it background and let's set initial open two equals curly
brackets true within the panel body.
Let's have a panel row within that.
Let's have a media upload check.
So this is a component that WordPress makes available to us and it's going to check to make sure that
the current logged in user actually has permissions to upload media.
So it'll take care of that for us.
Nested inside of that, let's have a component finally called media upload and this can be a self-closing
component just like this.
We don't need the actual closing tag now.
We just give media, upload a few props, so let's spell out all of them on select equals curly brackets,
value equals curly brackets and finally render equals curly brackets.
So we'll walk through all three of these, but let's start with render.
So in these curly brackets, we just give it a function that returns a bit of JS X and that JSF will
actually appear here.
So what do we want to live here?
Let's just have a button that says Choose Image.
So here's what we would do in these render curly brackets.
Let's give it an arrow function.
So parentheses, arrow, symbol, curly brackets we can drop down.
Let's just return a bit of JSF.
That's simply a button.
And let's say choose image.
Now when you click on this button, what should happen?
Well, we would say on click equals curly brackets.
And now this is why we're giving render a function, because render is going to give us something that
we can use for on click here.
I'm not sure why, but the media upload block actually gives us an object, so we would need to structure
it.
So in these parentheses it's going to give us an object so curly brackets to structure it and the property
that we're interested in, the only properties called open.
So now in the body of our function here, we can use that.
So when you click on this button, the on click would just be open.
In other words, the WordPress team has already coded this block for us and this will open the standard
traditional WordPress media upload or media choose window.
Okay, so that takes care of the render prop.
Let's work through these other two props for value.
This is just the image ID.
So you know in WordPress every.
Post and page as an ID.
Well, every piece of media also has an ID number.
We'll circle back to this later in the video.
For now, let's just hard code it to the number one.
Don't worry, we will actually make this dynamic.
Let's move on to on select.
So this is a function we give it a function in WordPress will call that function whenever the user actually
selects which image they want to use.
Now, you absolutely could write an arrow function directly in these curly brackets, but to stay organized,
why don't we point towards a function?
So let's make up a name and call it on file select and let's just go create a function with that name.
So right above our return here, we can just say function on file, select parentheses, curly brackets.
And now anytime WordPress is going to call a function for me, here's what I like to do because I'm
not exactly sure what it's going to give back to me.
I just like to log it to the console so I can get my own feel for what WordPress is giving us.
So for the parameter, let's just make up a name of X and then in our function let's just log that to
the console.
So console that log x, we can take a look.
And once we have an idea of what WordPress is giving us based on the image file that the user chose,
then we can make something actually useful happen.
But let's not get too many steps ahead of ourselves.
Let's save this and make sure that you have your NPM run start task up and running because we just saved
a JavaScript file and then back in the browser we can refresh.
So if you click on the empty background area, you've selected the banner block as a whole.
Here we see.
Choose Image.
Now, before I click on that, open up your inspector and open up your console so we can get a feel
for what WordPress is going to give us.
These are all of the default things that WordPress logs to the console.
You can actually click this icon right about here to clear the console.
So now it will be obvious when something new gets logged here, but let's just go back in and actually
try to choose or upload a background image.
So choose image.
You can choose one of your existing images or you can upload a new file.
I'll do that.
I'll choose this image of this dog and me upload that.
Now, here is where the functionality comes full circle.
As soon as you click this select button down here in the bottom right corner, that's what's going to
trigger the on select function call.
So as soon as we actually click that little select blue button, WordPress will call our function for
us so we can check that out.
If I click select.
And then we check our console.
You can see WordPress logged this to the console.
So now let's just take a look at what it's giving us and what we might find useful.
Right away, I want to draw your attention to this ID property.
Personally, that's what I'm interested in.
But let's not get too far ahead of ourselves.
So what we're ultimately trying to get is a huge URL for the image, but not just any URL.
We want one for the cropped or sized version of the image that makes sense for our use case.
In other words, if someone uploaded a 6000 pixel white image, we don't want the original and we don't
want a tiny square thumbnail.
We want a reasonable size for the task at hand, right?
We want a reasonable size for a banner background area like this.
So depending on the website and block that you're building, you might be able to just look in this
property called sizes.
If you expand that, you'll see that there's full, large, medium and thumbnail, right with the URLs
to the JPEG.
That might be what you're looking for.
But personally, I'm not interested in those.
I specifically want our image size that we created back in our theme chapter called Page Banner.
And unfortunately, this data that WordPress is giving us by default, it does not include custom image
sizes.
To refresh your memory, if you jump into our theme folder and open up functions, dot up and then press
control F or command F and search for add underscore image, underscore size.
Right?
We added these custom aspect ratios called Professor Landscape, Professor Portrait, and another one
called Page Banner.
So this is the size, this page banner aspect ratio.
That is the size that I want to use.
That's the URL for the selected image that I really want.
Now again, unfortunately, this data that WordPress provides does not include custom sizes and aspect
ratios.
But here's what we can do.
We can just use the idea of the selected piece of media, and we can use that value, whatever it may
be, to take matters into our own hands.
Now, before we actually go look up the aspect ratio based on this ID value.
Let's take things one step at a time.
First, let's just make sure that we're holding on to this ID value in a block attribute.