Now before we actually go look up the aspect ratio based on this ID value.
Let's take things one step at a time.
First, let's just make sure that we're holding on to this ID value in a block attribute.
So do this with me back in our banner.
Gorgeous file up at the top.
Let's work on our attributes.
So we have this one attribute called the line.
At the end of that, let's add a comma and let's have a brand new attribute.
We could make up any name we want, but just so it makes sense, why don't we call it maybe image ID
and I'm capitalizing the eye and the D colon.
Curly brackets.
It's type would be a number.
Now, before we worry about looking up a specific aspect ratio version of an image, let's first just
make sure that we're saving and loading the image ID.
So essentially if we scroll down, we're looking for the function we created just a moment ago called
On File Select.
So in this function, we don't need to log it to the console anymore.
Technically, you could leave this if you wanted to, but I'm going to get rid of that.
And what we would actually want to do here is just update our block attribute.
Right?
We know that we can look on this parameter.
So it would be export ID.
We just want to set that and update our block attribute now to update our attributes.
We want to say props dot set attributes.
So within our edit component function, you need to be sure to include props in these parentheses.
So props.
Then back down in our function we can say props, dot set attributes, parentheses to call it, give
it an object.
We want to change the image idea and set it to x dot.
Okay.
Finally down in our JS acts when we added media upload, let's get rid of this hardcoded value of one.
So instead of one it would be props dot attributes, dot image id.
If you're wondering what this is used for, let's say you choose a custom background image and then
a week later you refresh that editor screen.
Well, this lets WordPress know which values should look preselected or highlighted to indicate that
that's what you've already chosen.
See this in action.
So if we save this and then refresh the template editor screen.
Click on the banner block as a hole.
Click Choose Image.
And also like this image of the dog.
Click Select.
Click Save.
Now we haven't connected the dots to actually display the image yet.
However, because I saved that, if I refresh the page just to prove that we're saving and loading that
attribute, if I click on the banner again and click Choose Image.
Notice that word knew to select the right image.
So in the database it's saved that block attribute of image ID.
So whatever the ID number is for this image.
But that just means it being properly saved and loaded to and from the database.
So now we just need to use that image ID number, whatever it may be.
Use it to look up the exact aspect, ratio version, the URL for that.
Then we can actually use that to display the image both in the back end and the front end.
So there's a million ways you could handle that.
But here's what I'm going to do.
Up at the very, very top of our file, let's add a new import line and say import API fetch from quotes
at symbol wordpress slash API dash fetch.
We're going to use this API fetch tool to retrieve data from a you are that looks something like this
and you do not need to type this in the next 30 seconds is just a demonstration, but it's going to
be the base of our URL slash WP, dash JSON, WP slash v2, slash media.
And then it would just be whatever the ID for your image in question is.
So this is the URL for that dog image I uploaded just a moment ago.
Anyways, this is going to give us back a lot of JSON, but if we search for something called page banner,
there it is.
You can see we're going to get a property nested in its source URL with the exact u URL for that aspect
ratio for the correct image.
So I can copy and paste that into a new tab.
Perfect.
Now obviously the vertical cropping is off a little bit.
That's not the point of this lesson.
We've already learned how you can crop the different aspect ratios with a plug in that we are a big
fan of back in our theme chapter.
For now, the idea is how do we want to find this URL from within our client side JavaScript in the
admin editor.
So let's put all of this together back in our code.
We're going to use API fetch to find that you are URL.
Any time that this image ID attribute changes.
You might think, well, why don't we just perform the JSON lookup within our on file select function?
My answer to that is because what if you reloaded the page right before you actually would trigger this
function?
We'd still want to perform that lookup.
So as with almost anything we do in block development because it's so complex, there's 100 different
ways you could set it up.
But here's what I would do.
I'm just going to use Reax feature called Use Effect.
So to import that, we would say import curly brackets, use effect from and it's from React.
But the WordPress way of doing that is at simple WordPress slash element.
So WordPress has sort of this react abstraction layer that we can reference.
Now let's go actually use that.
So in our edit component function, let's go ahead and get rid of this constant called use me later.
We don't need that any longer.
So right at the beginning of our function, we would just say use a fact parentheses to call it.
We're going to give it two things a comma b.
Let's actually start with the B placeholder.
So you give it an array of things that you're watching for changes.
So we just want to watch props, dot attributes, image ID.
So the idea is any time that this changes, react will call whatever function we give it here.
So now instead of this a placeholder, let's just provide an anonymous function.
So function parentheses, curly brackets.
And now I want to use the async await syntax, but you can't directly give use effect in asynchronous
function.
So I have sort of this wrapper function.
Now inside that function, let's make up a new function.
So async function, let's name it.
Just go or something.
Generic parentheses, curly brackets right below the definition, just immediately call it.
But the idea is that now in this function we can use the a weight keyword.
So what do we want to do?
Well, we want to use API fetch to look up the URL for a very specific image in size.
So let's say Konst and I'm just making up a name of response.
The idea is this is what the WordPress rest API will give back to us.
So response equals a weight API fetch parentheses to call it.
Before we worry about what should go in these parentheses, let's just drop down.
And immediately after we have this new data, let's just set a new block attribute called and we.
Make up any name, but let's call it image URL.
So props, dot set attributes, parentheses, curly brackets and just to do things in a logical order.
Why don't we actually go spell out that up at the very top in our attributes?
So let's just add a new property.
Let's name it.
Image url l.
I'm just making up this name, but it would be a type of a string.
Technically, you could get away without storing this as a block attribute.
You could just look it up on the fly with JavaScript.
However, remember that we're going to need to sort of recreate things from a aspect as well.
So we could get by with just the image ID and then use that image ID and P.
But I don't want to have to write up the lookup code again in PHP.
So if we just actually store the image URL as well, then we can just leverage this value instead of
performing another lookup.
But there's no right or wrong way of setting this up.
Anyways, back down in that code we were just writing set attributes.
We would just want to set image URL colon and now we would just use our response from the server.
So I won't bore you with this, but if you looked through all of this JSON that this type of a URL is
going to give back to you, essentially the way that you would dig down to the exact property that we're
interested in would be this the response dot media underscore details, dot sizes, dot and then whatever
the name of your aspect ratio is.
So we named it Page Banner back in the theme chapter.
Dot source underscore you are now cool.
Now we just need to fill out what goes in these parentheses here.
So we give it an object.
Inside the curly brackets, you can drop down, let's say path.
Just give it a placeholder string of x comma method.
So this would be quotes.
We're performing a request.
Now let's actually fill out the path.
So this is a string of text, but I'm going to want to do something dynamic.
So let's actually give it to back text.
And now the nice thing about using API fetch, you don't need to worry about providing the base part
of your domain and you also don't have to manually include the WP dash JSON.
You just have to include from this point forward.
So the slash WP part forward.
So essentially the path would be slash WP, slash, v2, slash, media slash and then whatever number
only we don't want to hard code the number.
So it would be dollar sign curly brackets and then just props, short attributes, dot image I.D..
Now before we save this to make things come full circle, we would just want to actually use that desired
HTP image URL.
We just want to use that as the background image here in the template editor screen.
So back down in our JS acts towards the very bottom of the G6 that we're returning.
We have a deal with the class of page banner and we have this in a wrapper.
Dave And its style is set to background image and then this hardcoded string value.
So leave style equals background image URL open parentheses, even leave this single quote here, but
everything inside the single quotes, let's get rid of that.
So essentially from there to the end of dot jpeg.
Okay, right there, I'm just going to put a placeholder X and then I'm going to swap out the overall
double quotes here to instead be back ticks.
So opening back, tick, closing back, tick, instead of the closing double quote.
And then instead of the X, we can just say dollar sign.
Curly Brackets.
Props dot attributes.
Dot Image URL.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So back in the template editor screen if we refresh.
Cool.
Let me zoom out a little bit, but there you can see there is the dog image being used.
And if I click on that overall area and choose a different image.
So if I choose this frog, click select, you get the idea.
Now for the very final step.
We just need to set things up.
If I save that so that on the actual front end, we use that image as well.
Now remember, this is using P, so it's totally up to you.
If you wanted to perform the image URL, look up and you could again.
There's a million different ways you could set this up, but essentially let's just go use P and let's
just look up the image URL value instead of using the ID inside of P.
So in our our block folder just jump into banner p up at the very, very top.
Let's drop into P, we can exit page B and let's write an if statement.
And basically we're just going to check to see if there is an incoming image URL attribute.
If there isn't, let's set a fallback.
Right?
We can just point towards the generic library here.
Okay.
JB So this is what I would do, let's say for the condition if the opposite.
So if dollar sign attributes, square brackets, quotes, image URL and the exclamation means.
So if this is false, if this is not true, well then let's just sort of override this value with the
fallback.
So it would be dollar sign attributes, square brackets, image url now it should equal get the m file
u.
R i.
Quotes.
Slash images.
Slash library.
Dash zero dot jpg.
Cool.
So now in our code, we know that this property of image URL.
It's good to go.
It's either going to be the fallback or the correct custom value.
So now down in this code, this would just be echo.
We can get rid of this git theme file, you'll recall.
Instead it would just be echo dollar sign attributes, square brackets.
Look inside it for quotes image URL.
If we give that a save, refresh the front end.
I'm not surprised.
Looks like I forgot a semicolon.
Yep.
So on line number four, end your line with a semicolon, obviously.
Refresh again.
There's the frog that's going to bring this video to a close.
In our next lesson, we're going to take care of a super small detail related to our banner block.
Essentially, we want to set up a really resilient and robust way of setting the default placeholder
value for the background image here on the admin editor side, because we don't want to have to hardcoded
a value to a theme JPEG that makes any assumptions about where you've installed WordPress.
Right.
If someone installed WordPress in a subfolder on their domain, we don't want our path to break.
So it should be a very quick lesson.
I'll show you the way that I would handle that situation.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.