Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to work on a couple small, quick details to truly finish our banner block.
Let's jump into the action.
So to explain the first issue that we're going to fix, if I insert a new fresh copy of our banner block
banner notice it cannot locate a default background image on the editor side.
But if I save this and refresh on the front end, well, because we wrote the P code to have a fallback
image, it works without a problem.
So really quick, let's set things up in a way so that our client side, JavaScript admin side, it
also has a default or fallback image when you first insert the block.
So in our text editor inside of banner tags in our attributes, what we could really do is just give
this image URL attribute, just give it a default tag like this and just give it a value that makes
sense.
However, I've dug through the WordPress documentation and I can't seem to find an easy way from within
JavaScript to point towards the currently installed theme folder.
Now yes, you could make some assumptions and hard coded, so you could begin the path to your hardcoded
fallback image with a forward slash to mean the root of your domain.
But what if someone installed WordPress in a subfolder on their domain?
Or what if they renamed their WP content folder?
Right.
So we want some sort of robust or dynamic way to have WordPress itself give us a URL path to the currently
installed theme.
If you are aware of a simple way of doing that with JavaScript, please let me know.
But I'm going to resort to using PHP.
We can have PHP output a little bit of JSON and then it will be very easy for our JavaScript to just
access that value.
So let me show you what I have in mind in our functions dot AP file, scroll down to the very bottom.
So when we're using the Gsx block and we're calling it here for a new instance and we're seeing that
it's named Banner and we're saying that it's true, meaning it should have a callback.
Let's just provide a third argument here.
So comma, let's give it a IP array, so square brackets and we can make up a property name quotes.
Let's make up a name of fallback image and then arrow symbol and then we just give it whatever URL value
we want.
So how about we just say get theme file?
You are I parentheses to call that quotes slash images slash library hero dot jpeg.
Cool.
So we're giving this IP array of data into our class.
Now let's just adjust our class so that if there is a third argument, we handle this in a way where
we output it as a JSON object using something called localized script.
So here's what I would do.
Let's go find the class, the opening class for JS block on the construct function, let's add a comma,
let's have a third argument or a third parameter.
Let's call it dollar sign.
Just data equals null.
So that way, if I instance doesn't provide this, we don't run into a problem.
Let's be sure to hold on to that incoming value.
So I'll say dollar sign this dash greater than data equals dollar sign data semicolon.
Now here's what I would do to actually use it on our on init function.
We're going to write a line of code and it just needs to be below the line of code where we say WP register
script.
So whether you place it here or here or here doesn't matter.
But it does need to come after we've already registered this script with this name, so maybe right
below that line I'm just going to have an if statement.
So if parentheses, curly brackets for the condition, let's just say dollar sign this dash greater
than data.
So essentially when you're instantiating your new object, only if you actually provided data do we
want to then just call WP localize script semicolon.
Now in these parentheses we give it three things.
So a comma, B, comma, c, the first thing you give it is the script that you're trying to hook on
to.
Essentially, when word press outputs this script to the page, it's going to let us output a little
bit of JSON along with it.
So this first value would just be dollar sign this dash greater than name.
The second argument is where we get to make up the name for this JavaScript variable that'll be output
into the HTML.
So again, let's just use the name values of dollar sign this dash greater that name.
The third value is the actual data that you want to output.
So that would just be dollar sign this dash greater than data.
Let's go ahead and give that a save and now I'll show you where you can find this.
So if you refresh your template editor.
And then right click somewhere up in this empty area and choose view page source.
Then press control F or command F to search or find something.
And let's just look for fallback image, right?
Because that's what we named our property.
We zoom in a little bit here.
Cool.
So WordPress output, this little bit of JavaScript, there's our variable name banner and it equals
this JSON object.
So now we can just use this value in our client side JavaScript.
So to bring this full circle, just go back into banner dot Jess in our attributes area and image URL,
just say comma default value should be.
Banner.
If you really wanted to make it obvious, you could even spell out the word windows.
You could say window, dot banner, dot, fallback image.
But in JavaScript, in a web browser, the window is just sort of implied.
The point is we're just pulling it from sort of the global browser scope, but we can go ahead and give
that a save.
Make sure that you're running NPM run start.
Now back in our template editor if we refresh.
Let me zoom out a little bit and then let me delete this old copy and insert a totally brand new fresh
copy.
Cool.
Just to prove that it's working.
There is our fallback image URL.
Perfect.
And just to prove that our other features are still working, you can click on it.
Click, Choose, image.
Choose any image you want.
Perfect.
Let's take care of a couple more tiny details.
So in our code, I want you to find the area where we're calling use effect in this function.
So from async down to when we actually call go.
I want you to copy that into your clipboard.
We're going to need it in about 10 seconds from now.
And I want to wrap that in an if statement.
So if parentheses, curly brackets for the condition, I want to say only perform that API lookup if
props attributes image ID if that evaluates to true.
So in other words, if the user hasn't even provided an image ID value yet, we don't need to bother
looking up that API data.
So then in the curly brackets for if just paste in your clipboard again.
Cool.
Let's give that save and test everything out to make sure it's still working so I can refresh.
Let me insert a fresh copy.
So, Banner, let me choose a new image.
I'll choose this cat.
Cool.
And if I look in my console, perfect.
At no point do we see a red error message saying, Hey, you're hitting up the API for an image media
ID value that doesn't even exist.
Perfect.
Now for one tiny CC fix.
If you refresh on the front end, I think it would be better if the images were centered horizontally.
For example, I know that the original image of this frog, I know that the frog is centered horizontally.
So we can adjust our CSS a little bit just to make sure that our images appear that way.
So this has nothing to do with WordPress, but it's just a quick fix.
If you go into the CC folder and then go into modules, then go into page banner.
Scroll down a little bit.
We're looking for this BG image area right after background size.
You can just say background dash position and just set it to center, center, give that a save and
then refresh the front end.
Perfect.
That's going to bring this video to a close.
And we have now officially completed the banner block.
In our next lesson, we're going to change gears.
So I just switched to a tab where I'm looking at the finished product of what we're going to build.
And up next, we're going to work on this area.
So this is on the homepage.
We pull in the two most rapidly approaching events and we pull in the two newest blog posts.
So we're just going to move this over or implement this within the new theme that we're building together
should be a lot of fun.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.