Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to set up the header and footer for our block theme.
Let's jump into the action.
So right away, if we look at the finished product of what we're trying to build, we see that, yes,
this is our page banner.
But up here, this content that doesn't exist in page banner, this is sort of the global header for
the entire website.
So it has the logo or the link back to the home page and then it has the navigation and then our, our
custom buttons and our custom search overlay icon.
So in this video, we're going to leverage the IP class that we set up in our previous lesson to set
up this global header.
And down at the very bottom, the global footer, we're going to set them up as blocks that you can
include in any template you want, so on and so forth.
So to get started implementing those in this copy of our website or this theme that we're building,
let's jump into our functions.
TCP IP file.
So functions TCP IP.
Here we have that new placeholder block instance.
Let's just set up another one.
So new placeholder block semicolon, let's give it a name of header.
We can save that in our our blocks folder.
Let's just copy and paste in duplicate the contents of events and blogs dot js write that placeholder
block.
So I'll just copy everything in that file, create a brand new file and name it heterogeneous paste
in those contents.
Let's change the name of the block to header.
Let's change the title so the human readable and just be uppercase header.
And then all we need to change is the placeholder text.
So on this line, let's just change this to say a header placeholder.
Let's give that a save.
And now we just need to create a matching file.
So in the our blocks folder, new file header, TCP IP.
In this new file, there's no sense in reinventing the wheel.
So right now, I want you to dig in to the theme we created in the earlier chapter.
The original fictional university theme.
And in that theme folder, we're just going to open up, header, dot up.
Now, we don't want to just copy the entire file.
Let's start selecting from the opening header tag that has a class of site header and then just scroll
down and just select until the header element closes.
So essentially that is the entire file, but we don't need any of the dock type or the head or the body
tag.
So just the header element.
Copy that.
Back in our empty header, not be file.
Just paste in your clipboard.
Let's give it a save.
Now, back in our template editor.
We can refresh and above our banner block.
You can see I currently have this hello paragraph.
Let me delete that paragraph block and then I can use maybe this icon to insert a new block up in the
top left the blue plus symbol and let's search for header.
There's actually already a default WordPress block called header, so you could rename our title to
our header, but really you'll know that it's ours because it has the generic icon.
Why don't we just go ahead and change that to our header?
So back in Heterodox, you could change this to our header or you know, fictional university header
refresh in the template editor one more time.
I mean delete that paragraph again, insert and I can search for header and there it is fictional university
header.
So just click that.
Woops, because I didn't place my cursor before I used this button, it placed it at the very bottom.
That's okay.
We can just use this toolbar that appears when you hover over a block and just use the up arrow.
So click that a few times.
Or don't forget, you can always use this tool as well.
This list view icon that I'm highlighting right now, you can use that.
There's our fictional university header and then you can just click and drag it to be up at the very,
very top.
Perfect.
Cool.
So we've got our placeholder, then our banner.
Let's go ahead and save that and then refresh the front end of our website.
Perfect.
Now, before we move on and set up the block for our global footer, let's first talk about the quote
unquote, official way that you might have handled this header and footer block situation.
Because I want to make it abundantly clear, this approach that we're taking, this is my own personal
philosophy approach.
This is definitely not the standard approach.
The reason I'm taking my own approach is because I don't want to create a theme that is literally nothing
but WordPress core default block types.
Right?
I want to create my own custom bespoke theme with my own HTML, my own CSS asked, my own custom queries,
so on and so forth.
Right.
We've already talked about that topic several times.
However, I do want you to be aware of the way that you would handle sort of a global header and a global
footer if you were building a theme that was more like the 2022 default theme.
So let me show you something.
If you open up the 2022 default theme.
Here it is.
I just want you to be aware that you can have a folder in your theme called Parts.
So inside of the 2022 theme, you'll see that in that folder they have something called, for example,
header on each html footer dot HTML.
Let's look at header.
So there's nothing new here.
This is literally the exact same thing that you would find in a template file.
Right.
It's the HTML comments that represent Gutenberg block types.
These are all just default WordPress block types.
The idea is that you can have a combination of all of them in this part file and then you can include
one of these parts files in one of your main template files.
So for example, if you look in the templates folder and open up any of these, for example, archive
that HTML, you'll notice that the very first comment is just saying, hey, pull in the global header.
It's called a template part.
Pull in the one called header.
So that's going to pull in this file header on HTML.
So anyways, I just want you to be aware of this sort of quote unquote standard or official way of setting
up sort of a global header and footer.
Personally, with my own philosophy in the way that I use WordPress and the way that my clients want
to use WordPress.
I don't see much use at all in setting up template parts because at the end of the day it's still nothing
but just default block types.
Right.
If I'm going to be creating my own custom bespoke HTML and C SS, then I'm not going to have, you know,
tons of different blocks all laid out in my global header file.
I'm probably just going to have that one header block that you and I just set up.
Anyways, big picture, there's a hundred different ways that you could organize your code.
This was just something I want you to be aware of at this point.
Let's switch gears back to our block theme that we're building and let's go set up a block for our global
footer.
So if we look at the finished product of what we're trying to set up, it'll look something like this.
So let's just go into our functions dot AP file.
And I'm just to be clear, I'm back in our block theme that we're building in this chapter.
And let's just set up a new instance of our new class, you know, new placeholder block.
So my call and give it a string of text of just footer.
Now we can just to save a lot of typing, just duplicate everything in header dogs into your clipboard,
create a new file in our blocks.
Let's name it.
Footer Dot.
Jess.
Paste in your clipboard.
Just change this block name to footer.
Let's change the human readable name to fictional university footer.
Finally, just change the placeholder value to say footer placeholder.
Give that a save.
We do want to create a new file named Footer TCP IP.
Now, in this file, we don't need to reinvent the wheel.
Just jump into the original fictional university theme.
Open up footer TCP IP and in this file, just select the entire footer element that has a class of site
footer.
So from this opening footer tag down to right here when it closes, we absolutely do not need the IP
tag or the body tag or the HTML tag, just the HTML footer element.
So copy all of that into our clipboard.
Back in our block theme footer, TCP IP paste in your clipboard, give it a save and we're ready to
test it out.
So in our template editor refresh.
Down at the very bottom here.
Let me insert a new block.
Let's search for the word footer.
There it is.
Fictional university footer.
There's the placeholder.
Let's give this a save.
And if we go, refresh our front end and then scroll down to the bottom.
Perfect.
And for the final step in this video, and this has nothing to do with WordPress or programming, but
I'm going to take a minute or two to set up the original headline text values for the banner.
So back in the editor, this first large headline would be welcome.
And then we'd want a medium sized headline that says, We think you'll like it here.
Then I want a generic heading of the small size.
Let me push that up to right there.
And it should say, why don't you check out the major you're interested in?
Maybe I'll make the word major.
Bold.
And then the button should say, find your major.
Let's save this.
And if we refresh the front end.
Cool.
Let's choose a different background image really quick.
And let's make sure that this button actually points where we want it to.
So we want it to go to slash programs.
If you actually tried to visit our programs page right now, you wouldn't see the content.
And that's just because we haven't set up, you know, the equivalent page dot template in our case,
because we're building a block theme that would be page dot HTML.
We haven't set that up.
We will in just about a lesson or two.
But that doesn't change the fact that we would absolutely want this button to point towards slash programs.
So how would we set that up?
Well, you can just click on the button, use this link icon right here.
Now, typically, you'd search for a page or post, right?
So, for example, if you search for the word about us, we have a page called About US.
And as soon as you clicked on that, well, that'll give you a value.
That will absolutely work.
In our case, there is no page or post named programs.
That's just the slug for our custom post type.
So I'm just going to type in slash programs.
And then this was the confusing part.
You actually have to push enter on your keyboard to actually use that as the value.
Now, if your WordPress installation doesn't live at the root of your domain, you could just include
the full HTP domain address here instead of just slash.
Either way, I'll click confirm.
We can save that I refresh in the bottom left corner when I hover over this button.
Perfect.
It's going to take me to slash programs.
Now let's talk about what we're going to do in our next lesson before we use this PHP placeholder block
approach that we used for our header and footer.
So before we use that on the remaining portions of our block theme, I first want to set up one last
piece of interactive Gsx block functionality.
And what I'm referring to is our slideshow.
So if we look at the finished product in this tab, I want our end users of this block theme to be able
to add a slideshow like this to any page, any post in any template, wherever they see fit, and they
could even have multiple slideshows per page.
The good news is we can recycle our generic heading and our generic button blocks.
Whoops.
In the finished product that I was just showing you, I had forgot to add the button to each slideshow.
But you get the idea.
So we can reuse our heading and button blocks.
And in terms of the background image area, well, we can reuse at least 80 to 90% of our banner block.
I think this will be a fun feature to build.
So let's keep our momentum rolling and I'll see you then.