Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to build our slideshow.
BLOCK Let's jump right into the action.
So there are a million different ways that you could set this up.
But let me explain my thought process.
So looking at the finished product of what we're going to build, here is the slideshow and I'm going
to set things up so that there are three layers of blocks.
So the overall outermost, you know, overall parent block will be called slideshow.
And it can have in this case, for example, there's three slides nested inside the slideshow.
Then each slide is essentially just a banner block, right?
And it can have text and buttons, in other words, those blocks nested inside of it.
So there will be generic headlines and generic button blocks nested inside a slide block, and then
all of the slides are nested in the slideshow.
If that doesn't make perfect sense yet, that's okay.
I think once we set up sort of the basic skeleton, it'll start to be clear.
So where do we begin?
Well, let's start with the outermost parent block, which is the overall slide show block.
So to get started, as always, let's jump into our functions dot, AP, file towards the bottom.
We do not want a placeholder block for this lesson.
We absolutely want a JS block because there's going to be interactivity, you know, from the admin
editor Gutenberg side, technically you could write plain JavaScript instead of gsx, but I think you'll
find that when your blocks have any sort of complexity or any amount of HTML, aside from just one element,
like our placeholders, you're going to want the convenience of JS processing anyways down here at the
bottom.
Let's just set up a new instance of JS X block.
So new j x block, parentheses semicolon.
Let's make up a name of slideshow and then let's give it a second argument.
So comma of true this means we do indeed want a render callback so we can give this file a save.
And now in the our blocks folder, create a new file and name it slide show dot js to save a little
bit of typing.
And because I don't believe in ever truly memorizing all of this, let's just borrow or copy and paste
from our banner dot js file.
So if we jump into that file, we don't need to copy the entirety of this file, but I would just grab
all of the import lines and then this very first register block type call.
So just down to about line 19.
So I'd copy that piece into our new empty JavaScript file.
Let's change the name.
So around line seven, register, block type instead of banner, it would be slide show.
Let's change the title to uppercase.
Slideshow.
Our slideshow does not need image I.D. or image URL.
That makes sense for the individual slides, but not the overall parent slideshow so we can get rid
of those attributes.
Okay, now below this, let's add a function for edit component and save component.
So let's start with save components.
So function save component, parentheses, curly brackets.
The only thing we would need to save into the database is just any nested content.
So whether you add two slides to your slideshow or ten slides to your slideshow, the nested slides
are the only thing we need to return from within our save function here.
So we would just return.
And then they self-closing inner blocks dot content just like this.
Okay, next, let's set up the edit component functions, function edit, component, parentheses,
curly brackets.
Let's have an overall div.
So first of all, return parentheses so we can have multiple lines of gsx.
And now I want to div so I'll just type div and then hit tab on my keyboard.
So now this is the UI that you'll actually see in the block editor screen.
So let's have two things inside our div.
First, let's have a paragraph sort of a label and it can say slideshow.
And then right below that we'll just have the actual nested slides.
So an inner blocks component, self-closing and let's give it a prop of allowed blocks equals curly
brackets, an array, so square brackets and then quotes.
The namespace for all of our blocks is our block theme and then slash.
And now we haven't created this new block yet, but essentially the only block type that I want to allow
in the slideshow is a slide.
So let's make up a name here, a slide in just a moment.
We can go create the block type named slide first.
Let's add a little bit of styling to our overall div just to avoid confusion.
So for example, when you're in the editor screen and you've inserted a slideshow, I think it would
be nice if the overall parent block had a bit of padding so that you could see maybe a gray background
color so that you could tell the banners that you were inserting were sort of nested in that parent
slideshow.
BLOCK You don't have to add this, but I think the user interface would get fairly confusing without
this.
So here's what I would do on the opening div tag.
I would just say style equals curly brackets, another pair of curly brackets for the actual style object
and then the DJ's version of background dash color is background, just uppercase C color, all one
word call and let's set that to a string of text of hashtag three, three, three.
Com.
Let's give it a nice amount of padding.
So padding string of text 35 pixels.
Okay next let's style are sort of label paragraph a little bit.
So style equals curly brackets, double pair of curly brackets.
So text a line, string a text center.
Come on, let's bump up the font size, font size, maybe 20 pixels, comma, color string a text just
hashtag f, f, f.
Okay.
Before we save this file back up at the top, let's get rid of some of these imports that we don't actually
need.
So we didn't use API fetch.
We can get rid of that.
We didn't use any of these components.
We can get rid of that on this line.
The only thing we're using is inner blocks.
So you can get rid of these three items here.
And finally, we did not use use effects so you can get rid of that line as well.
Cool.
Let's save this.
But before we go, add it to our package dot JSON file and actually, you know, bundle it up and expect
to see it in the admin.
Let's first go create our second custom block in this lesson because remember we've said the only block
type that's allowed is slide.
So let's go actually create a block type named slide.
So back in functions, drop down at the very bottom, you could just duplicate this line we wrote a
few moments ago, changed the name from slideshow to slide.
Let's give that a save back in the sidebar.
In our blocks, create a brand new file named Slide dot Jess.
Now Slide is absolutely a copycat of banner JS Even more so than slideshow because think about it,
slide is the element that's going to have a background image.
And also it's the block where you're allowed to insert only headlines and buttons.
So it's very much just a duplication of banner.
JS In a perfect world, you could spend the time to create sort of an abstract ad class that both slide
JS and banner dot JS inherit from.
In this course, we're not going to worry about staying 110% organize like that.
So I'm just going to jump into Banner Dot JS this time.
I am indeed going to select the entire file.
So yes, that includes the edit component save component functions just absolutely the entire file.
Copy that pasted into our new empty slide that JS up at the very top.
We really only need to change the name of the block.
So our block theme instead of banner, let's call this slide.
Let's change the title to Uppercase Slide and that's really all we need to change.
So let's go ahead and give that a save because remember, it's already programmed to only allow the
block types of heading and button.
Cool.
So be sure to save this file.
And now we can just go into our package dot JSON file and add those two new blocks.
So at the end of this start line, the very end here, I would just say space, our dash blocks look
for slideshow and then a space our dash blocks slash look for slide.
Let's give that a save.
And then in your command line be sure to start up npm run start.
So now back in the browser in the block editor screen, if I refresh and scroll down a little bit,
maybe right below events and blogs, if I want a slideshow here, I'll start searching for slide.
There it is.
Slide show.
So I insert that.
Cool.
There's sort of the outer wrapper to signify that this is a slideshow.
And then there's the symbol to add.
You click on that.
The only option is a slide.
So it didn't even bother to ask us which type of block type you want.
The only allowed type is slide, so it can make that assumption.
Now, inside this slide, click the icon.
You can add headings and buttons.
So let's add a heading of the medium size and say.
Slide number one example text.
And then I'll click off of that on this overall slide.
Click the symbol here to add a button, let's say learn more and I'll make that a medium sized button.
Click on it.
Maybe I'll make it dark orange.
Cool.
Let's add at least one more slide.
So now you would click on the overall gray background area for the slideshow as a whole.
There's a plus symbol right about here.
The bottom right corner, we can click that.
Now we've got two slides.
Let's add a headline here.
So I'll see slide number two, example, text.
Make that medium sized.
Let's add a button, learn more exclamation, and I'll make that medium and I'll leave this as blue.
Let's not forget the actual background images.
So if I click on the background image for this one and then open up the sidebar, I can click Choose
Image.
Let's imagine I want this second one to use the frog and let's imagine I want the first slides.
If I click on the background image, choose, choose, image, maybe I want this building.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now I don't expect anything to appear on the front end yet because we haven't written any callback
functions.
In fact, I believe if you refresh the front end right now, you'd see an error message.
Yep.
Don't worry.
We'll write the callbacks in just a moment.
But to prove that we're saving all of this data and loading it successfully from the database, we can
refresh this edit screen.
Scroll back down.
Perfect.
It saved our text, our colours, our background images, everything.
So now all we need to do is maybe fine tune this HTML a little bit to have sort of the dark gray background
that sits right about here.
Remember, if you look at the finished product, the slideshow has sort of this transparent background
color box.
So we'll add that.
And we also need to adjust the output each HTML which can live in our app to have these three dots here
as the slideshow navigation.
Right.
They signify which slide you've currently navigated to.
So back to the copy that we're working on together.
We're currently getting this error message on our home page.
So let's go work on the PHP, render callbacks and let's begin with the outer parent element, which
is the overall slideshow.
So back in our text editor in the Our Blocks folder, just create a new file named slideshow dot page
P.
So in this file we would include the wrapper HTML output for the slideshow as a whole.
Now this HTML structure that the slideshow JavaScript hooks on to or looks for that has nothing to do
with WordPress.
But the overall idea here is you could imagine if you wanted to use Bootstrap and some of the bootstrap
JavaScript like their slideshow or a similar feature.
The idea is you need to output each HTML with a specific pattern or using certain classes.
Now we've already written that structure and pattern of that each HTML, so there's no sense in reinventing
the wheel.
So right now I'm going to open up my text editor for the original fictional university theme from an
earlier chapter in the course.
And we need to jump in to front page dot P in that file.
If you scroll down around line number 81, we're looking for this div with the class of hero slider.
So this is the HTML structure, the pattern, the class names that are going to give us the JavaScript
slideshow, right?
We're using a JavaScript package called Glide to Power the slideshow.
So there's a million different ways you could do this.
But here's what I'm going to do.
Begin selecting from the start of this hero slider div.
So right here.
And then let's scroll down.
It ends right before the get footer.
So I'm going to select everything down to this chunk of HTML with copy that into our clipboard and then
back in our empty slide showed up AP file that we just created, paste it in and now let's just hollow
it out a bit.
So essentially we only want sort of the outer wrapper and any interior content that you see repeating
more than once.
Let's hollow that out.
So I'll give you a hint around line number four, we see this class of hero slider underscore, underscore,
slide.
Now because the slide show previously had been hardcoded to have those exact three slides, you'll see
there are three instances of that.
So just delete all of those.
So I'm going to begin deleting from the first one.
The indentation is not perfect, so this can actually get a bit confusing, but I'm going to delete
from line four and then where you see the three closing divs in a row, just delete all of that.
So that's the first hero slide out of three and then just delete the other two as well.
So from here and then three closing divs in a row and then this one with the three closing divs in a
row.
So now the idea is this remaining closing div.
This is for this glide slides.
So all of our slides will live inside of that.
Then there's this div that has the navigation circles.
So if you have three slides, there's going to be three dots.
If you have ten slides, there'd be ten.
So this is the closing div for the slider bullets.
This is the closing div for this glide track.
And then this is the overall closing div cool.
This looks good to me.
So the idea though is that inside here, glide slides, that's where we would output the nested content.
So just drop into P here and just say echo dollar sign content semicolon.
Let's give that a save.
Now if we refreshed the front end, we'd still see an error message and that's because we need to provide
a callback file for slide itself.
So in the our blocks folder, just new file, name it, slide dot up.
Now just for a quick test, let's just have maybe a heading level one that says hello from slide.
If we save that, we should see that repeated three times.
So if we refresh the homepage and scroll down.
Perfect.
Hello from slide.
Hello from Slide.
Now we just need to adjust this output to actually look like a slide.