Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to actually finalize our first block themed template file that users can
revert back to.
So we already learned about that concept earlier in the chapter.
Only now it's actually using the desired blocks that we built ourselves.
Let me explain.
So currently this is what our homepage looks like.
We've successfully added the header, the banner block, the events and blogs, block slideshow, and
then the footer.
So this exact combination and layout of blocks, this is spelled out in the database.
Let's just go find that and then actually use it in our text editor copy of the file so that the user
can always revert back to this.
So just to be clear, if you look in your theme folder and go into the templates folder and dig into
indexed HTML, currently all we had hardcoded in this is just a paragraph and heading as an example.
So the idea is we want to have the Gutenberg comments right that look just like this, only they're
using our block types.
We want this type of code that spells out this exact combination of our blocks.
So remember, there are two ways to find that.
So let me show you in your admin interface under appearance if you click into editor.
One way to find that code is from this editor screen in the top right, you see the three dots and this
needs to be in the full site editing, not the blog post or page editing screen, but you can click
those three dots and choose export.
So that'll download a zip file.
You can look in the contents of that zip file for the template files.
You can totally do that.
But I like to just go look in the database oftentimes.
So, for example, here's the database for my local WordPress website.
If you dig in to the post table, click Select Data.
Just go to the very last page.
I scroll down to the very bottom.
Well, this is assuming that you haven't created any pages or posts since you last saved a change to
this template.
But if you go into the very last item and look under post content.
There you have it.
So it starts with our header block and then our banner block.
Perfect.
If you scroll down to the bottom, there's our footer block.
So I would just click into this field and just control or command a select everything in there, copy
it into your clipboard and then back in this index dot HTML template file.
Just empty it out and paste in your clipboard.
Let's give that a save.
And now I want to show you why this is so useful.
Now, don't worry.
We're going to make a few improvements to this to make it a bit more robust or resilient to different
WordPress installation configurations.
But for now, let's see why this file is useful.
Just a quick reminder.
So now if the user of the website makes a change, let's say they change this headline to just be something
that doesn't even make sense.
And they click Save.
And imagine they accidentally deleted, you know, the header placeholder and maybe they accidentally
deleted the slideshow.
And they saved that as well.
Cool.
So they've totally changed their website.
Now, I imagine they want it to revert back to the original default version that the theme provides.
Well, that's the whole point of that text file that we just created.
So the user would just go into this templates menu here.
Oftentimes you will need to manually refresh this page.
But the idea is for index, you'll see a blue dot and that means that there are user customizations.
So the user could just click these three dots here and click clear customizations.
And as soon as they do that, that's going to revert things back to this hard drive copy version of
the file, the template.
So now if we go back to the front end and refresh, everything is perfectly restored.
Right.
This is back to normal.
We've got the header.
We've got the slideshow.
Perfect.
At this point, I want to talk about something that may seem like a tiny detail, but it's fairly important
to me.
Let me explain.
So I want you to dig into our file that we just created, indexed on each HTML.
And I want you to scroll down and find the slide show area.
So for me, it's around line number 23.
Here's the first slide and I want you to pay attention to the image URL value.
In other words, off camera.
In the previous video, I actually uploaded the images for the slide show, you know, the apples,
the bread and the bus.
However, let's think about this for a moment.
We want this default version of the theme that we ship out to our users.
We want it to make sense right away.
And when someone has their own installation of WordPress, they're not going to have a media uploaded
file for the bus and the apples in the bread.
Right.
That user is going to have their own totally unique media library.
They're not going to have the same images that we've uploaded, so this file reference wouldn't exist
for them.
So we need to set things up in some sort of robust, resilient way where we can somehow point towards
our theme folder.
Right.
So if we're distributing our fictional block theme folder.
Yes.
Inside that folder, we will indeed be shipping this images folder.
And that has the real copies of bread, apples and bus that we want to point towards.
Right.
So that way, anyone who uses our theme would actually have the JPEGs in question.
Now, if you wanted this to work for maybe 70 to 80 to 90% of your potential users, but not 100% of
them, you could take the easy route and just hard code this.
So for example, you could get rid of the HTTP and just begin with, you know, slash for the root of
the domain WP content and then change this to be, you know, the themes folder.
And then I won't spell it out but your theme name and you know images bust dot jpeg you could do that
and that would work for most but not all users because not everyone is going to install WordPress at
the root of their domain.
And some users might, you know, change the name of the WP content folder, so on and so forth.
So how would we set this up in a flexible, resilient way?
Well, there's probably a hundred different ways you could set this up.
But let me show you what I have in mind.
And actually, first, just to make sure that the issue at hand is crystal clear, we can actually scroll
up to the very, very top of this file.
And before we worry about the slideshow, let's first worry about the banner block.
So around line number three on this opening banner block tag, I would just completely remove image
ID and especially image URL from this template file all together.
So I would just delete both of those attributes or values.
You don't even need these empty curly brackets then.
So the opening tag would just look like this.
We can save that and test it out in just a minute, but we're able to do that because we already built
the banner block in such a way that it knows what to use as a fallback, right.
A default placeholder value for the image.
Remember we told it to use the library hero image as a fallback.
So if we go to the homepage and refresh.
Right.
Perfect.
It knows to use that as the fallback image that works for us in this banner block, because this fallback
image can sort of be the singular fallback.
But when it comes to our slideshow, we want to ship our theme in a way where this is already spelled
out for the user, right?
Where there's these three slides that start out with these text values and these images.
So we can't just provide sort of a singular default fallback image for a slide in general.
We need to actually provide specific instances, you know, of bread, dot jpeg and bus dot jpeg and
apples dot jpeg.
Now again, if you asked 100 different program.
To set up a solution for this, you'd probably get 100 different answers of how to do it.
But let me show you what I would do.