Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to work on building the remaining templates for our block theme.
Let's jump into the action and let's start by just navigating through the website and we'll build whichever
template would be needed to actually visit that URL.
So for example, from the homepage, we have this from our blogs area.
And if you clicked on one of the links to a blog post, well, this URL would be powered by the single
template.
So with a traditional theme that singled out PHP in our case with the block theme, it would be in our
theme folder, in the templates folder, the file named single lot HTML.
So in other words, in single that HTML currently we just have the hard coded, you know, paragraph
block.
But remember we used the full site editor to add the post title and the post content.
It's okay if you don't remember us doing that.
That was many, many lessons ago.
So to refresh your memory, if we go to the full site editor, appearance editor and we don't want to
edit the index or the homepage template, we want the single template so you can use this menu and then
click browse all templates.
Or what I have been doing throughout the chapter is I use the top left WordPress logo, click templates.
Either way, we just want to edit single post.
Cool.
So there is post title post content.
So that's what's giving us this dynamic content.
That's great.
If you wanted to build a theme where you use these WordPress default blocks, you know, to display
basic things like the title and the content, and you don't need to do anything custom and you don't
need to be in control of the wrapping HTML around it, then that's fine.
This approach will work wonderfully for you, but if you need to write your own custom queries on the
page, or if you need to be in control of the HTML or just really anything that the core default blocks
can't handle, well then the question becomes, what are you supposed to do?
Well, I'm well aware that my own personal philosophy or my own personal approach is definitely not
the, quote, standard way of doing things in a block theme.
This that we have right here, this would be the, quote, standard way of doing things.
But there's really not a whole lot to explain here, right?
It's just clicking and dragging and inserting default blocks and arranging them in a way that you like.
You don't need a video lesson walking you through that, but to set up your own custom solution, well,
let me show you what I would do.
So let's just delete everything that we have so far.
So we just want a completely blank template and let's begin by having the overall header.
BLOCK So what kind of block do we want to add?
First, you can just type slash and then I want the fictional university header.
Cool.
We know that at the bottom we want a fictional university footer.
So if I search for footer?
Yep.
Fictional university footer.
Cool.
Now, in between the header and the footer, what do we want?
Well, off camera, I just switched to the finished product theme, and this is what an individual blogpost
screen should look like.
So yes, it has the global header and the global footer, but then right below the header, we want
sort of just this basic formatting.
So this is how the blog post title should appear.
And then we have this sort of breadcrumb navigation area and then we have the actual, you know, content
for the blog post itself.
Now it's just my opinion, but I don't want this to be set up in a way that the end user, you know,
can rearrange things like, I wouldn't want the end user to be able to move the breadcrumb navigation
to sit below the blog content.
Or I wouldn't want the user to be able to drag and drop the content to live above the blog title.
In other words, I don't really believe there's any value in the user customizing something like the
interior blog post view, but that is 100% my own personal view.
So from here you really have two options.
If you did indeed want this area to be customizable for the end user and you wanted them to be able
to drag and drop and change the options for different pieces of content, you could use the default
WordPress core blocks, or you could use all of the concepts that we've learned in this chapter to build
your own custom blocks and just add different attributes and options to let the user choose.
For example, you know, does the user want the title to be a certain font size?
And then remember how we had the small, medium, large, or if you wanted them to be able to choose
the color for the breadcrumb navigation, right?
We had our blue orange and dark orange, so on and so forth.
So you could apply those same principles if you wanted to to allow customization here.
But personally, I'm not going to go that route.
I don't really think there's anything here, a value worth customizing.
So let me show you what I'm going to do.
We've already added our header and footer placeholder blocks, so really in between those two, we just
want sort of the static template, right, that's going to output all of this other basic content.
So I'm just going to create a placeholder block and we can call it, you know, instead of header or
footer placeholder, maybe single post placeholder.
So do this with me in our functions dot AP file down at the bottom.
We don't need a G block, we don't need any advanced, you know, client side interactions or HTML.
If you scroll up a little bit for me, it's around line 200.
We have placeholder blocks, so just duplicate one of those lines.
We just want to set up a new placeholder block and the name for it would be maybe how about just single?
Or just to be clear, I'll call it single post.
Cool.
Let's give that a save.
And now we just need to go into the our blocks folder, create a brand new file and name it single post
dot Jess To save a bunch of typing, just go into your header, not just file.
Copy that into your clipboard, paste it into a single post.
Let's change the name here instead of header.
It would be single post.
Change the title to maybe just fictional university single post and then change the placeholder content
that you'll actually see.
To maybe be single post placeholder.
Let's give that a save.
And now we just need the render callback with the matching name.
So in the our blocks folder new file all name it single post-op AP.
Now in this file, we don't need to reinvent the wheel.
We've already written the AP for this custom content, right?
We wrote the logic in the code, the HTML, the PHP for this breadcrumb navigation.
And along the way, if you added any other queries for related content or whatever sort of custom advanced
features you've built into this template, well, you can just include that in this file now.
So let's just go borrow that code from the original theme that we built earlier in the course.
So if I switch to this window of VS code, this is our traditional theme.
I would just jump in to single that up and we definitely do not need this header code, but I would
just start copying from the wild loop.
So from the wild down to and then down at the very bottom, this closing tag and the closing curly bracket,
we do not need the footer.
So just sort of the middle content on the page, I would just copy that into my clipboard back in our
new empty single post op.
Just paste that in, give it a save and let's go use it and test it out.
So in this screen where we're editing the single post, you can save what you have so far with the header
and footer placeholders and then we need to refresh so the new block type will appear.
And then right about here I would just want to insert I start to type single post.
Yep.
Fictional university, single post.
Perfect.
So we can save that.
Now, if we go to our front end, this is a URL for an individual single blog post.
I refresh.
Woops.
Looks like we've got a really obvious error at the very top of this file that we pasted into obviously
at the top or in PHP.
So have an opening question mark.
P tag just like this.
Give that a save.
Try one more time to refresh.
Perfect.
So this is the approach I like to take when there's custom content that doesn't really need to have
any interaction or doesn't need to have any user customizations.
Now, you might be wondering, well, what's the point of even having this as a block theme then?
And my answer to that would be because now the user can add whether they want a slide show or the events
and blogs, right?
So we have this template for all single blog posts.
And what if right before the footer, what if the end user decides, hey, you know, I think it would
be nice if the upcoming events and blogs block was right here or I think it would be nice if we had
a slideshow before the footer.
So the point is, even if this specific content isn't editable or customizable, the page as a whole
still is.
And through the power of composition and choosing whichever blocks you want, the possibilities are
still infinite at this point.
Let's get back to the actual task at hand or the goal for this lesson.
So in verse code, in our block theme, in our templates folder, let's go back in to single that HTML.
So remember, we want this to now have the code that represents this, right?
These placeholder blocks instead of just a paragraph.
So to find the code that WordPress has generated from this full slide editor, I just like to go look
in the database.
So assuming that you've saved a recent change to this template, it will be the most recent post in
your post table.
So you know the drill by now.
I just found that post template in my database and there you have it.
It's nothing but our block theme and then header single post and footer.
So I would just copy that back in our text editor, just paste it in and that is all we need for this
single template.
The end user is still free to add in anything they want in between the blocks.
So if they want a slideshow, if they want events and blogs, so on and so forth.
Also, if they do make changes, they can always revert back to this as a starting place.
Let's change gears and now let's set up similar behavior for an individual page.
So, for example, if I try to visit my About US page.
Well, because we don't have a page template yet.
It's just using the index template.
But you could imagine that this URL should use an individual page template.
So let's go create that right now.
So in our templates folder, just create a new file and name it page dot HTML within this new empty
file.
You can just copy and paste and move over the contents from single that HTML.
So just duplicate paste those over.
And really we would just need to use a different block here in the middle.
So instead of single post, let's go create a new block type and we can call it something like single
page or just page.
So in functions dot p, I would just use a new instance of placeholder block.
So new place holder block semicolon quote value is let's just call it page.
Give that a save.
And then in the our blocks folder, just create a new file.
Name it.
Page dot JS to save a bunch of typing, just jump into single post dot js, copy everything in there,
paste it back into pages, change the block type name here to maybe just page.
Let's change the title to fictional university page.
And then change this placeholder line at the end here to be just single page placeholder so we can give
that a save.
And then finally, we just need to create a new file in our blocks and name it page TCP IP.
Now, in this file, we do not need to reinvent the wheel.
Let's just go borrow a bit of code from our original fictional university theme.
So let me switch back to that folder and I would just open up page TCP IP.
Now we do not need the header, right?
We already have a block specifically for the header.
So I would just start selecting from this while.
And then down at the bottom we do not need the footer.
So I would just select until this closing curly bracket here.
So copy that.
Back in this empty page up.
Copy paste in your clipboard.
Up at the very top.
Be sure to add the opening IP tag like this.
Cool.
So we can save this file and then we just need to jump into page or html and just change the block type
that we're using here.
So instead of single post, this would be page.
Let's give that a save.
And now if we refresh on the about us URL, perfect.
And we can click these links to view the children pages of the about us page.
Excellent.
At this point, let's change gears and let's actually go back to our blog or actually to illustrate
the point I'm trying to make.
If I try to visit the blog up in the navigation, well, that index template for that doesn't make sense.
So let's set things up so that our home page is powered by a template called front page dot HTML, but
then our blog listing.
So that should just sort of be the fallback index template that can actually be indexed on each HTML,
right?
And this URL would then show you the ten most recent blog posts.
If that doesn't make perfect sense, that's okay, but let's walk through it.
So first of all, in our block theme, in our templates folder, let's just duplicate index that HTML
and name the new copy front page.
So I would just jump into index, select everything in this file, copy it, create a brand new file
in the templates folder and name it front dash page dot HTML.
In this file, just paste in your clipboard, give it a save and then back in index dot html.
Well, we can delete everything in that file and to save a bit of typing, just go borrow these three
blocks from page or single that html.
So I would just copy those paste that into indexed on each html only we'd want to do something different
here in the middle in between the header and footer.
Right.
We'd want the blog listing.
So let's actually just change this block type name right now, even though we haven't created the new
block type right now, we're already in this file, so we might as well change it.
Let's name it.
Blog index.
Just one word.
Just like this blog index.
So we can save that jump into functions.
Dot B Just create a new placeholder block with a name of blog index semicolon.
Save that.
Then in the our blocks folder, create a new file, name it blog index dot Jess.
To save typing, you could just jump into a simple file like footer dot J.S. Just copy all of that content,
paste it into blog index.
Just change the block type name here to blog index.
Change the title to maybe fictional university blog index.
Change the placeholder, maybe just blog index placeholder.
We can give that a save.
Create another new file in our blocks and name it.
Blog Index Dot AP.
This is the file where we do not need to reinvent the wheel.
So back in our original theme that we built together, I would just jump into index dot AP.
We do not need the header, but I do want this page banner.
So I would just start selecting from page banner.
All the way down at the bottom until this closing day.
So we do not need the footer, just the closing div like this.
I would select that into my clipboard back in our empty new AP file.
Just paste it in at the very top.
Make sure you add an opening IP tag.
Let's give that a save.
And now if you refresh this blog listing URL, woops, it's still our homepage template.
I believe this is because WordPress stored a customized version of our template in the database instead
of actually using those newest files, you know, they actually live on the hard drive.
So I would just go into the full site editor and click on the templates area.
Might need to refresh this and yep, you can see for index the blue dot.
So just restore that click on these three dots, click clear customizations.
So it will actually use our text file.
So now if we refresh the blog URL, perfect.
But if we click back to our homepage, cool, that uses the front page template to refresh your memory
on how I set up my blog listing page to be different from my homepage URL.
Well, remember back in WordPress?
Under settings.
If you click into reading instead of this default option of your home page displays related posts.
I just clicked this a static page and then I created two pages, one called home and one called blog.
And those pages can be completely empty.
They really just need to exist for a sluggish URL perspective.
But essentially now WordPress will use the index template for your blogs and front page template for
your home page.
Cool.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our next video, we're going to create a few more page templates together.
Now, don't worry, I'm not going to bore you and make you walk through creating every single page template
with me, because as you can see, it's getting a bit repetitive.
But I do want to walk through the process with you at least another three or four times just to show
you how I would handle certain post type archive screens, so on and so forth.
Let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.