Hello, everyone.
In this quick lesson, we're going to learn how to restrict different block types in the page in post
editor versus what's allowed in the full site editor.
Now, obviously, by default, WordPress allows any block type in either of those environments, but
if you're using WordPress as more of a content management system, I think it's very likely that there
may come a time where you want to restrict which blocks are allowed.
Let's jump into the action and I'll explain.
So imagine you are editing a blog post or page, or maybe your client is.
And in this editor screen you do indeed want to let your user add any block type that they want, right?
So all of the default core blocks, all of our custom blocks, so on and so forth.
But let me switch tabs.
If they're using the full site editor screen to edit a template, maybe you want to restrict which blocks
are allowed.
Maybe you only want to allow the custom block types that we have created.
So in other words, you wouldn't want to let the user just add a random paragraph here.
Now, these were just my examples, but the idea is what if you want to restrict a different set of
block types for the page in Post Editor versus the full site template editor?
That's what I'm going to show you how to set up.
Right now, there are a million different useful ways that you could implement this.
That's up to you.
But here's the concept.
We just dig in to our themes, functions, TCP IP file all scroll down to the very, very bottom and
let's write a brand new line.
And we're going to say add filter semicolon in the parentheses.
We give it four arguments.
So A comma, B comma, C comedy, let's fill in the C and D first.
So C is just a priority, let's say ten.
So it gets called last for the D placeholder, let's say two.
This is how many arguments the function will use.
Okay?
And then we know what to do with A and B.
So A is the name of a word press filter hook that we want to hook on to.
So this would be allowed block types all and then the B value.
This would just be a function that we make up.
So quotes all.
Name it.
Make up a name of maybe my allowed blocks.
Cool.
Let's just go create a function now with that name.
So function my allowed blocks.
Now we included a two here saying that the function will have two arguments.
So let's have two parameters here in these parentheses.
Dollar sign allowed block types comma dollar sign editor context.
Now within the body of our function, what do we do?
We're just going to return.
Allow to block types.
Now, if we just did this.
Right without modifying it or changing it in any way, we would essentially be doing nothing.
In other words, the default allowed block types that WordPress is already allowing.
We're just passing that through.
However, within this function, we're free to modify it if we want to.
So if you wanted to allow the exact same set of restricted block types in all environments, right?
In both the Page and Post Editor and the full site editor, you would just return an array here.
So you could say return array and then you would just list out your block types.
So quotes.
Our block theme is the namespace, you know, slash header and then comma our block theme slash footer.
You would list out any and all blocks that you want to allow.
However, what if you wanted to allow one set in the page in post environment and one set in the full
site editor?
Well, we would just write an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets for the condition.
I would say if PHP has a function called empty that I'm going to call in the empty parentheses.
I'm going to look at dollar sign editor, underscore context, look inside that.
So dash greater than four post at the very start of this condition right before the word empty.
In the parentheses I'll add an exclamation just because I want to check for the opposite.
So altogether, I'm basically saying if there is a post, that means you're working with a page or a
post.
So in here, if you didn't want to restrict which block types are allowed on pages and post, you could
just return allowed block types without modifying it.
So return allowed block types.
Okay.
Then after this, if statements are right about here due to the nature of, you know, programming,
when you return something further execution of the function ends.
So we don't even need to write an else block.
We can just return something else here if this is not true.
You could also write comments to yourself.
So right here you could say if you are on a page or post editor screen and then down here you could
say if you are on the full site editor screen.
So then here you can just return a different array.
So return array, semicolon.
I won't bore you by typing out a bunch of different blog types, but imagine I'll just say it.
Maybe our header and footer blocks.
So our block theme slash header comma our block theme slash footer.
Let's give that a save and test it out.
So in the page in Post Editor, I should still be allowed to insert any block type I want.
So if I click the plus symbol here, cool.
I still see all of the choices that you would imagine.
However, back in the full site editor, if I refresh and I try to add a new block here.
Yup.
You can see my only choices are those two that we spelled out the header and footer.
And even if you click this browse all button right here, nothing else shows up.
That's it.
There are an infinite number of ways that you can use this logic and this feature that we just set up.
It's up to you to get creative or use it in a way that makes sense for your projects.
But I definitely wanted to show this to you because I think it's a very common feature that you're going
to want to set up.
And just a quick edit here at the end of the video, I want to give you sort of an extra credit idea.
So if you were working on a project and you found yourself wanting to restrict the block types based
on the current post type, you could write a condition like this, you know, if parentheses, curly
brackets for the condition.
And imagine if you only wanted to set up a custom block type list for the professor post type.
You could say dollar sign editor context.
Look inside that for post, look inside that for post type and only if that equals professor.
Well then you could return a different array of allowed block types.
Also, just to be clear.
It's not as if you can only spell out your block types.
You can spell out core block types.
So for example, you could return an array where you only allow, you know, core dash, paragraph comma,
you know, core dash and list or core dash heading.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our next quick lesson, I want to show you how to set up a completely blank template.
In addition to how to set that up, I want to show you why you would set it up.
I'll give you a hint.
I think it can be very useful for creating landing pages or just any sort of really custom page.
I think it'll be fun to set up.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.