Whether you're working with standard web applications or
microserviced‑out serverless applications,
basic log‑level monitoring usually leaves a lot to be desired.
In surplus applications,
you have the added task of having to find which
services are calling which services.
As you get more distributed with your architecture,
monitoring only becomes more difficult.
One solution to make things easier is to aggregate all your
logs from each service to a common location.
While this is always recommended,
now with AWS X‑Ray, you have a new way to monitor your applications.
X‑Ray collects data from your application as requests are handled and
replied to. As a service or an application sends this data, X‑Ray uses a
trace ID to build a picture of what requests are doing as a pass through
different parts of your architecture. Because each request is using the same
trace ID, X‑Ray can draw a map of how things are processed in your
application and provide very specific data at each step. The data available
are things like how often the step resulted in a success or failure, the
total length of execution including a breakdown into child calls, and how
many similar requests were made. When your code sends this data to X‑Ray,
it doesn't send it directly to the service, but instead sends the
data to an X‑Ray daemon process that buffers the data before
uploading it to the actual X‑Ray service.
This daemon comes preinstalled on Lambda and Elastic Beanstalk, but you
will need to download it from AWS and run it if your application is
running on a different service like EC2 or ECS.
X‑Ray doesn't use every single request,
but instead applies a sampling algorithm to only take a sample of the
requests that are coming. By default, it includes one request per
second and then 5% of the subsequent requests.
This keeps costs low and has a good likelihood of accurately
reflecting what's going on in your application as a whole.
You can edit these sampling rules in the X‑Ray dashboard and even
set different rules according to the service type.
You might not ever need to change this configuration,
but it's nice to have control at that level. Tracing is an
important concept to understand in X‑Ray, so let's take a look at that in the next video.