Oftentimes, when certain terms and technology become what I might call buzzwords,
it can often become difficult to get to the bottom of what
they truly mean and how it can impact you.
Cloud is definitely one of those words that dominated the
technology conscious for many years as companies looked at what
migrating to the cloud could do for them.
It became so prevalent that memes developed around the
cloud solving all the world's woes.
Well, the term serverless has reached that same level of notoriety now,
and I feel the need to really pull apart the facts from anything you
may have heard that doesn't really jive with reality.
So let's start by putting the emergence of serverless into perspective.
In the early days of the web,
companies would need to purchase their own infrastructure,
such as servers and networking appliances,
in order to properly maintain a web application.
Then the cloud came along and disrupted that entire practice by
relieving businesses of the burden of owning hardware.
Platforms like AWS virtualized the hardware required to run applications and
let users control infrastructure through GUIs and APIs.
That change from on‑premises to the cloud was world‑changing,
and many businesses are still going through extensive
migrations to make the most of the cloud.
When AWS introduced its Lambda service in late‑2014,
it inadvertently created the final piece of the serverless puzzle.
While there were some services that AWS offered before
Lambda that fit the serverless model,
Lambda made true serverless applications a reality in AWS. The
advent of serverless meant that not only did businesses not
have to manage physical servers,
they didn't even have to manage virtual servers anymore either.
In addition,
the cost model that had been flipped on its head with cloud
billing was once again revolutionized with serverless's
pay‑only‑for‑what‑you‑use model.
I think the serverless revolution could be as big as the cloud
revolution, and it really has only just begun.
So let's get into some specifics about serverless. The key
aspects of serverless are the following. A completely
abstracted infrastructure. With serverless, you don't know what
instances your code is running on,
how it's scaling, or any of the other multitude of concerns you have to keep
track of with server management. Pay for what you use.
Since you're not managing the infrastructure,
you don't need to pay for it when your application isn't using it.
Say goodbye to idling servers eating up your wallet.
Stateless. With any serverless service,
you won't be storing state and your compute layer. You would
have to rely on explicit persistence like a cache or a
database to preserve your state.
Event based. The way that things happen in a
serverless application are from events,
whether it's HTTP events or scheduler events or messaging events.
Things happen from explicit events, and you'll need to think about
your architecture with that communication model in mind. These
aspects will play a large role in how you will architect and write
code for your application.
A serverless application is quite different than a regular
web application running on a server.
In the next video, let's take a look at how to architect a serverless application.