We only have one lambda in our demo application that
connects to a non‑VPC service.
But let's use that as an example for setting up a
secure connection using VPC endpoints.
As stated in the last module,
VPC endpoints are configured per service per region.
So if you had resources in a VPC that was going to connect to a
lot of different services through VPC endpoints,
you will have to set up a lot of VPC endpoints.
One thing to be aware of, unlike most networking services such as VPC and AWS,
VPC endpoints do have a cost associated to them.
The cost depends on the region you're working in,
but the lowest is 1 cent an hour.
This amounts to roughly $8 a month.
That's not really that cheap.
Pretty close to the cost of running a small EC2 instance.
So, make sure to be conservative with these connections.
They provide a lot of value in creating a secure
infrastructure for your resources, so use them as needed.
For our purposes,
we want to connect to a Kinesis Stream without going to the internet,
so let's get a VPC endpoint set up to connect to Kinesis.
In the AWS console, navigate to the VPC dashboard.
In the menu, select Endpoints.
Your endpoints will appear here, specific to the region you're working in.
Now is a good time to double check the Region drop‑down in
the upper right to make sure you're in the same region you
deployed the demo application to.
Now, click on the Create Endpoint button.
Leave the AWS services radio button selected in the Service category section.
In the Service Name list below, look for an entry
that ends with kinesis‑streams.
The exact service name will be different depending on your current region.
In the VPC drop‑down, select the VPC with the name trash‑panda‑buffet next to it.
It should then change the subnet options to the only
two that were created in that VPC.
Leave the checkbox for Enable DNS name checked.
This sets up a private DNS record for the VPC
endpoint that resolves for your VPC.
We can also leave the Security group option alone.
It's already got the default group ID for the VPC entered. This
policy section allows you more specific control over how this
endpoint can be accessed and what it accesses.
We'll leave this at full access. Now click the Create endpoint button.
The VPC endpoint will be created, and any calls to Kinesis will
automatically resolve to this endpoint and will go to Kinesis without going
through the outside internet. You can see this DNS names section has the
main Kinesis endpoint for whatever region you're in. This is how our lambda
will connect to Kinesis via a VPC endpoint. In the next video, let's look at
what kinds of events sources we can use to invoke lambda functions in a serverless application.