When AWS launched the X‑Ray service,
they made it very easy to get it running for serverless applications.
There are two sides to configuring X‑Ray for your application.
The first is the service configuration done in AWS,
enabling X‑Ray tracing for services that you use.
The second is instrumenting in your application code
with the X‑Ray‑enabled AWS SDK.
We'll start with the first part, configuring our application services.
API Gateway is the easiest as you can enable it for an entire API.
In your AWS console,
go to the API Gateway dashboard and select our dev‑trash‑panda‑buffet API.
Now select Stages and then the dev stage.
Here are all the configuration options for this particular deployed API.
On the Logs/Tracing tab,
you'll see a specific section for X‑Ray with one
checkbox for enabling X‑Ray tracing.
Check the checkbox and then click Save changes.
If we only did this step,
we would already have added a lot of monitoring to our application.
Now you'll be able to see metrics on what lambda functions your API
is invoking and how long they took to complete.
Once the request hits your lambda,
the functions aren't set up to pass on that tracing ID and
gather more data on what happens after.
So, we'll configure that next.
I've set up one of our functions to give us more data.
So, let me show you that in the code.
Open your code editor and look for the actions.js
file and the src/lambda directory.
On line 6,
we have the save handler function that is invoked by an API
Gateway POST call to the action endpoint.
Inside the function,
I import the AWS X‑Ray SDK first and then import the regular AWS SDK
inside a captureAWS function call from the X‑Ray SDK.
This is going to allow me to use the AWS SDK as I normally would,
but any relevant calls to other AWS services would send along the X‑Ray
header information and create and close segments for better tracing.
Beyond these two lines, I write my code as usual.
It's really quite trivial to get X‑Ray working in your application.
Now you may notice that in this particular function, I'm using the
callback pattern, which is different from the async/await pattern used in
all the other handler functions in the application.
There is currently an open issue with the X‑Ray SDK where it doesn't work
with promises. And since async/await uses promises under the hood, that
means it also doesn't work with async/await.
Unfortunately,
this means if you use promises on any of your code or any of your
dependencies use promises, it can cause issues with the current
implementation of the X‑Ray SDK. For this reason, this function is the
only place I'll show you how to use the X‑Ray SDK.
Hopefully, once this video is published,
the issue will be resolved. With our code instrumented to send trace
data to X‑Ray, we just need to configure the lambda in the AWS
console. So, switch over to your browser and go to the saveAction
lambda function. In the Configuration tab,
select the Monitoring and operations tools option. Then
click the Edit button. In the AWS X‑Ray box,
click the Active tracing selector.
There will be an info alert that appears because we haven't added the right
permissions to the lambda function's role yet, but AWS will try to add them
automatically for us. And that's all there is to it.
So go ahead and click the Save button. Now that this function
is saved, you can go into the demo application and play around
with it to generate some traces.
Once you've clicked through several actions, pull up the X‑Ray dashboard.
If it isn't already active,
click on the Service map menu option, and you should see a
visualization similar to what I'm showing here.
This is the service map for your serverless application.
Each node is for a specific segment, whether it's the Lambda service running a
lambda function being invoked, or a Kinesis record being put.
You can click on any of them to get more information. With X‑Ray enabled,
you can now use it to monitor the progress of requests in
your application, look for bottlenecks that may be causing
latency, and troubleshoot issues.
In the next clip, we're going to see how CloudWatch can add to our ability to monitor our application.