Besides permissions,
another important security concern with Lambda is the storing
of credentials and sensitive information.
While IAM permissions are often enough to access most services in AWS,
occasionally there are credentials you need to store for accessing things
like databases or external services There are a few different approaches to
this ranging from least secure to most.
The first approach is to put the credentials in your application code.
Bottom line,
do not do this. There are plenty of better ways, and this is
the most insecure and hardest to update.
A better approach is to store the credentials as
environment variables in your lambda.
As you can see in the lambda details for one of our functions,
that's what we're doing in our demo application.
This makes it easier to update and more secure.
The environment variables are encrypted at rest by
AWS, and using IAM permissions,
you can lock down access to your lambda configuration in the AWS console.
The only step where these environment variables aren't encrypted is
in transit, such as when deploying to your lambda.
The best approach is to store these credentials in
one of AWS's secret solutions.
One that has been available for a while is the EC2 Systems Manager
Parameter Store. This gives you command‑line access to set and
retrieve secrets, such as credentials.
Your lambda would then call the parameter store
anytime it needs those credentials.
This adds a little latency to your lambdas that need those
credentials, but greatly improves security.
A newer service that follows the same model is AWS Secrets
Manager. With a similar process, you store secrets and then
retrieve them in your code with the SDK.
What Secrets Manager adds is the ability to automatically connect to
RDS databases and rotate credentials regularly.
This means that your credentials for the database are ultra secure,
rotated regularly, and available anytime your lambda needs them. Reducing the
permissions of your lambdas and securely storing credentials will ensure your
serverless application is as secure as possible.
In the next video,
we're going to look at what it takes to increase the stability of your lambda functions.