Every great course needs a great demo application,
and this course is no different.
So let me introduce you to Trash Panda Buffet,
a completely serverless game about feeding trash pandas,
also known as raccoons, their favorite kinds of food,
also known as trash.
The game itself is simple and a little random.
You select a food for a given raccoon.
Each raccoon has certain likes and dislikes,
which contribute or subtract from a total score.
After the accumulation of four tries for five trash pandas,
you have a final high score.
You can store your score to gain serious street
cred in the persisted high scores.
And that's about it.
Under the hood, the serverless architecture looks kind of like this.
A lambda is responsible for serving up the initial index page,
and then assets are loaded from a CloudFront distribution.
There are several API endpoints for things like getting a game ID,
retrieving trash panda and food information,
sending the user actions, and saving the scores.
The application uses Amazon Aurora and RDS to store all
the user data and Kinesis to communicate between lambdas,
just for a little extra spice.
While this is the finished application,
you'll be responsible for implementing a lot of the pieces of this application throughout the rest of this course.