Hi, my name is Kevin Jones,
and this is The Basics of Classloading module from the Java
Virtual Machine: Class Learning and Reflection course from
Pluralsight. So in this module,
we're going to take a look at class loading, and we're
going to cover a few things. We want to take a look at how
class loading works in Java 8,
including something called a delegation model and how that works in Java 8.
And then we're going to take a look at how class
loading works in Java 11, in fact,
from Java 9 onwards, and how delegation works in Java 11.
So for Java 8, we want to take a look at a number of things.
We want to take a look at what are known as core classes.
So these are the classes that are loaded as part of the standard Java Runtime,
if you like, so things like the String class. We are then going to take a
look at extension classes and the extensions directory.
These classes don't necessarily ship along with the Runtime,
but that may be used as if they were Runtime classes.
And examples of these are things like the cryptography classes in Java. Once
we've done this, we want to take a look at delegation.
So delegation is how class loading works in Java.
You have a hierarchy of class loaders, and each class loader in that
hierarchy delegates to his parents. My parent could try and load extension
classes, or it could try and load the core classes.
I'm going to take a look at how this works in Java 8 in a
moment. And we can also display this delegation. So we can walk
this hierarchy of class loaders in Java 8 and display
information about those class loaders,
such as the name of the class loader and where they're
trying to load their classes from. So let's see some demos and see how we do this.