We've seen that we can create instances by doing cls.newInstance,
and that's fine so long as the class has a default constructor.
If the class doesn't have a default constructor,
instead we can use the constructor properties of the class.
So I can say Constructor, array, ctors = cls.getDeclaredConstructors.
Then from here, we know in this case the class has two constructors,
as we've seen this previously.
We know we have the default constructor and one that
takes an int as the parameter.
So in my code, I can say ctors [1], so take the first constructor,
which will be the one with a single parameter,
and then call newInstance.
And to newInstance, this is a variadic method,
so I can just pass in the arguments that we need for that constructor.
So in this case,
let's just pass in the value 6, let's say, and we know
this will give me back a Car object.
Now this obviously defeats the purpose slightly,
as I'm using reflection to create an instance of a car when I already
have the Car type actually in my code. Instead,
we again do something like code against an interface, if we
were doing this in a real‑world example.
This is just to show that we can actually do a constructor using
reflection, and we don't get any exceptions.
If I try and call this with too many parameters and run the code,
we end up with an IllegalArgumentException, wrong number of
arguments. And if I try and call it with an invalid argument,
passing the string string, again, we end up with an IllegalArgumentException,
this time with an argument type mismatch.
So we're definitely doing something right by passing in a single integer
parameter to this. We are calling that constructor.
So now that we have the Car,
how about calling a method on that Car using reflection?
So to do that, we'd say Method method = cls.getDeclaredMethod.
So just like getDeclaredField,
we give this thing the name of the method, so that's going to be drive.
However, for getDeclaredMethod, methods could be overloaded,
so we also have to specify an array of the types that identify the
parameters this particular method will take.
So if I look in Car here, our drive method takes a char and an int,
but let's say we had an overloaded version of this that just took an int.
We'd need to tell reflection which version of the drive
method we'd like to use, the one that just took an int, or
the one that took a char and an int.
So putting this back as it was,
if we go back into Main, so here we have to tell this which method we want
to use, and we do that by passing an array of classes. So we can say
char.class that identifies the first variable, and int.class, and that
identifies the type of the second variable.
Once we have the method we can then invoke it, so we do method.invoke.
When you call invoke,
you have to pass both the parameters to the method you're trying to invoke.
But you also have to pass the instance on which you'd like this method invoked.
So we say car, and then we have a char, so let's say D, and
the speed we'd like the car to get to,
let's say 6. And if I go in, if I put a breakpoint on the invoke call,
go into Car and put a breakpoint on the drive call,
then go to the debugger and debug this application, then we break at
invoke. If I just leave this guy to run, then we're now inside the
drive call. And inside here if we look at drive, we see that's been
set to the value of D and desired speed that we pass here is set to
the value of 6.
A couple more things to think about when invoking methods.
Firstly, what about static methods?
So on Car, I have a little a static void method called
print, and that just prints out Hello World.
We can invoke this in a very similar way.
So again I can say method = cls.getDeclaredMethod
and pass the name of the method,
which in this case is print. Print takes no arguments,
so we don't need to pass anything extra to getDeclaredMethod.
I have the method object back, I can say method.invoke,
but now we're invoking the method,
and we don't have to use an instance, as it's as it a static method.
So to this, I can just pass null.
So null here says treat whichever method is being referenced
by the method type here as a static method.
And if I run this code, it prints out Hello World.
So how about invoking a private method?
Let's say I do method = cls.getDeclaredMethod.
And in the Car class we have a couple of private methods.
Let's use accelerate that takes no parameters. So we can say
method.accelerate and then try and do method.invoke.
I will invoke it again on the Car object, and accelerate
doesn't take any parameters either.
So if I run this code,
the code explodes, and it throws an exception. It throws
an IllegalAccessException. So by default we're not allowed
to execute private methods.
However, there's a simple way to get around that.
We can say method.setAccessible to be true. So by default
setAccessible is false, and you can't access private methods.
But by setting the flag to true,
then we're allowed to do this. Again, if I run the code,
the method executes. Now be aware, this is not a free lunch.
We can't simply go ahead and access private methods.
It's possible that a security manager might be involved, and the security manager can prevent this behavior.