let's now turn our attention to the manipulation of text.
Let's take a look at some of the typical function combinations that you use when working
with text,
so we're currently in zero for manipulating text on Let's start with number one combining
left search from the look up.
Then this workbook We have to work feeds.
The first has a record off all the highest of taking place,
the second as the names off into the items that can be hired,
saying the highest work seat.
We have a high of ref column,
but the higher ref has three components,
and it's only the first of these three components that matches the items.
So we need to have a formula which will extract all the text before the first hyphen.
On this occasion,
we can't simply use the left function because when you use left on its own,
you need to specify the number of characters to extract started from the left.
And as you can see that number very sometimes it's four on sometimes is free.
There is,
of course,
in the data tab,
this very useful feature text to columns.
But remember,
this is an operation.
What we're trying to do here is to create a formula so that,
given any higher up with these three components,
we can extract the first component and then use the V look up function to find out the name
of the correspondent item so that the name of the Iceman's probably all with me.
Let's start by simply extract in the code so that we can look at using the to text
functions in conjunction.
So here what we're interested in doing,
extracting all of the characters that precede the first hyphen so we can use the left
function,
which takes two parameters.
First of all,
the text from which you want to extract some characters on this,
of course,
is the text in the cell.
Eight to the second argument is the number of characters,
and for this we can't give a literal number.
We can't say three or all because the number varies,
so instead,
use the search function,
so the search function becomes the second argument of the left function.
The search function,
in turn,
takes two arguments.
The fine text,
the text that you're looking for,
which is we know,
is the hyphen and then within text the selling which you're looking for that text.
And as we've seen that stay,
too,
the search function returns a number,
which is the character position of the stream that your searching for so in this case in
selling to the hyphen is in character position.
Fine.
But of course,
we don't want to extract five characters we want to extract.
Or,
in other words,
we always want to extract one character fewer than the character position of the hyphen.
So after the closing parenthesis for the search function,
we need to put minus one so there is a lesson going on.
So we'll split this onto several lines and for that will increase the size of the formula
bar.
So it's equals left then all enter to go to a new line,
and the first parameter is the text.
Which is,
you can see is the text in the adjacent column in a two that's our first parameter old
enter again and then for the second parameter,
we now need to use a function which will identify the character position of the first
hyphen.
And there two candidates search and find find is case sensitive,
and search is not.
And for that reason it's probably best to think of searches,
the standard function and then only use.
Find on those occasions where you definitely need to take the case into account so he will
use such the fine text has to go in double quotes,
and it's the hyphen.
Within text is the cell that we're searching in,
which is a two.
If we admit the third parameter,
which is you can see,
is optional.
That's the starting.
Um,
we know it's optional because it's in square brackets.
Excel will simply start the search on character Position one.
What is fine.
So he closed when we found the position of the hyphen.
We then need to subtract one.
As you can see in this first example,
the hyphen is in position.
Five.
We don't want the 1st 5 characters.
We want the 1st 4 so we now need minus one,
and that completes our left function.
So just press old enter and put the clothes in parenthesis on a separate line.
So when we press center,
we'll see we have all the characters before the hype in.
If I copied down that it works both for three letters on four letters.
In reality,
we probably wouldn't bother to have a separate column just for the item code.
What we really need to know is the name of the item.
But in a learning scenario is always useful to have a look at these things in isolation on
Just look at the components that go together to make up the whole.
So what we can do now is to highlight all of this and copy it Amanda's press escape to come
out of formula editing.
And now we can use to be look up function to look up the item code that we've extracted in
columns A and B,
all the adjacent work she called items.
So here we using the V look up function to retrieve the name of the item that was hired
that we look up function takes four parameters.
First of all,
the look at value,
this is the information that you already have.
So in the case of Sally to,
we would want to look up as MTBE.
Next we have the table of Ray where you looking all that value.
So we'll be looking in the adjacent work feed cool items in Collins A and B,
and the third argument is the column index number within the look up table.
Which column contains the answer,
and it's always the Americ.
So we put two and not be.
And then the final parameter range look up specifies whether you're looking for an exact
match or an approximate one because we're looking for an exact match.
We put the word falls so the lost three arguments is straight forward.
But first we need to use a function which will extract the characters that we want to look
up on.
The function use is,
of course,
the left so equals the look up old mentor and paste.
I mean,
losses press the space,
but it's have everything in So all of this becomes the first argument of the look up,
which is,
you can see is look up value.
So we put a comma all 10 and then on to the second argument would be look up,
which is the table of Ray.
This,
of course,
is in the adjacent worksheet items.
We want the 1st 2 columns A and B calmer Walt enter,
and then we simply specify which column in that table contains the answer and this is
always numeric.
So it's not be it's too calmer or center.
And then in the final parameter that the look up we use false to indicate that we want an
exact match Old and,
uh and in the closing parenthesis for me Look up.
So when we press center waken see,
that s nbt refers to a Samsung tablet and we can then just copy the formula down.
So there we have a very typical combination Well manipulating text,
namely left and such.
In the next video,
we'll move on to look at combine in mid and search No.