Let's move on to look at another very typical combination when you're working with text at
last,
the use of the mid and search functions.
Zero for manipulating text.
Let's open up zero to combining mid search.
And if what we want to do in this video is to find out the type of usage,
whether it was internal or external,
and we can do that by examining the letters in the middle of the higher reference,
they'll either be i,
N T or E X T.
And again because the letters that precede the hyphen very sometimes for sometimes three
we'll need to use the search function.
But this time we use in in combination with mid rather than left because obviously we
started in the middle of the string,
not starting from the left.
So again,
what we really want to have is usage.
We want either internal or external in the usage column,
but just doesn't learning mechanism.
That's first of all,
extract the i m.
T.
Using a combination of minute and such.
The mid function takes three parameters Festival.
We have text,
and this is simply the cell that contains the text you're examining second we have to start
number the character position from which you want to start extracting text and thirdly,
the number of characters that you want to extract.
So,
in our example,
texted,
straightforward,
we're looking in Cell eight to,
and the number of characters is straightforward.
It's always three because the letters are either i nt for internal or txt for external.
So the thing that's not straightforward is the start number.
Which character position do we start from when we're extracting text?
So because of that,
we use the search function to supply that parameter.
The search function takes two parameters.
The fine text is what we're looking for.
It is a hyphen,
and within text is the cell that you're examining,
which is self a two that will tell us the character position off that first hyphen.
But what we then need to do is to live one character position to the right.
So after we close that parentheses for the search function,
we need to put plus one so that we don't include the hyphen in the text that were extracted
.
So that's right.
Our function un.
Expand the formula virus per usual,
so we want equals mid and then I'll press fold enter because we'll be less than another
function inside made.
So the first parameter is text.
That's the cell that we're examining,
which is 82 coma,
all tender.
And then we,
specifying a start position my nest in the search function,
have a search function as its two parameters that find text,
which,
of course,
has to go in double quotes.
That's the hyphen.
Call me within text the cell that you looking in,
which is a two.
But then the start number will omit because we want to start from character Position one.
But then we add one plus one to make sure that we don't include the hyphen itself.
We want the character that follows the hyphen.
Come on.
So all of that is the second parameter about made function.
All 10 and in the third parameter is the number of characters which is fixed at three and
then old Enter on the closing for emphasis.
So when we press end,
so we should get I in t.
And then as we caught me down alive that I nt or the X t each time,
so that gives you a bit of practice on using mid and search in combination.
There are very common combination in a similar way to the use of left and search which we
saw in the previous video.
So now let's copy the formula that we've got so far excluding,
of course,
the equal sign in his press escape once you've copied and then we can use this as one of
the parameters for the if statement that we now need.
So what we want to say basically,
is that if the mid function gives us,
i n t put the word internal into Sally too.
Otherwise for the word external.
So the it function becomes the outer function and the function takes three arguments.
First a logical test,
then evaluate true and then a value the false.
So for a logical test,
well,
basically nest the mid formula that we created so far.
So we've got the text that start number,
number of characters.
And then,
as we saw,
this start number is being supplied by the search function which has iPhone is it's fine
text and so a two as the within text.
But then we and one to the result in character position now because we want this to be a
logical test.
What we then have to do is to use a logical operator.
And obviously equality is the thing that we're testing all.
Does the result produced by the mid function equal the letters I NT?
So that would be a logical test.
I test that can only be true or false value of truth.
We put the string internal into the cell,
value it false.
Who put the string external.
So let's right now,
function equals if Walt enter and then I'll just paste in before Mueller that copy.
Remember to use the space Barton s this so that was the formula we had before.
But as it stands,
it's not a logical test.
And since it's acting is the first parameter of an if statement,
it needs to be converted into a logical test.
And we do that simply by Adan equals and then,
of course,
in quotes,
because it's a string e x t.
So now we have a logical test.
If the result produced,
my maid equals txt coma,
old enter and then the second parameter which were align in underneath mid,
which was the first prime Minister If is the body is true,
which is a string.
It is the word internal Homa or cancer Valley falls external Walt,
enter on the clothes in parenthesis for the if statement And I just noticed that I've got
this the wrong way around I should be testing for I N t And then the positive values
internal the negative values next time.
So let's ends around formula class the full huh?
And called me down Whenever we have I nt we get internal on Whenever we have txt,
we get X double.