Let's continue our local techniques for extracting one string from another by examining the
combined use of right Len and Search zero for manipulating tax that's open up 03 So we're
working with the same example as in the previous two videos on What we want to do this time
is to extract the higher code from eight to on.
The high coat is basically either all five numbers at the end off the string.
So the fact that we have a variable number of characters,
which we're extracting starting from the right,
is that we need to nest a function or,
in this case,
two functions in order to calculate the number of characters to be extracted.
So let's have a look at how we combine,
right Len in search How else a function will be the right function.
This takes two arguments.
First of all,
we have the text,
which is the cell eight to,
and then we have the number of characters on.
Because this varies,
we need to use another couple of functions that calculated So the technique will use is
first of all to use the land barge in the target.
The final character within the string.
So the length of the string is 13 which is the case with the string in A to Len.
A two will target the 13 or last character,
and then from that we subtract the character position,
all that final hyphen.
And as we've seen in previous videos to calculate the position of the hyphen,
use the search function that takes two arguments.
The thing you looking for but find text is the thing you're looking for,
which will be our hyphen.
And the within text is the cell within which your surgeon,
which is sell eight to So given the current contents of a to then a two,
will take us to Position 13 whereas search for the hyphen in a two will either take us to
position five or to position nine in order to make sure that we end up on the second hyphen
,
which is character nine.
Within the string,
we need to use the certain parameter the optional parameter of the search function,
and that is starting.
Um,
in the previous examples,
we've admitted starting them since it defaults toe one,
which means that the function will start searching on the first character if we sent start
numb to six.
This means that we're always starting the search beyond the position of the first hype in,
since the number of characters that precedes it is a maximum of four,
the maximum character position of the first hype and is five.
Therefore,
by specifying that are starting on the six,
we ensure that we miss out the first hype in,
which means that the first high phone will find will be hyphen number two.
So let's write our function.
I expand the formula.
Buyers per usual equals right,
and since we'll be nest in another function inside it,
that's useful.
Enter to put the arguments on separate lines.
The first argument is the text just simply eight to comma or center,
and the second argument is the number of characters.
So for this we start with Len as in length,
and we want the length of a to And then from that,
we want to subtract the character position off the second hyphen.
So this is where we use our search.
Find text has to go in double quotes,
and it's a hyphen comma found within tax where own searching is sell a to comma and then
are optional.
Start Numb is six because we want to start searching from character Position six.
So that calculation is the second argument off our right function on.
We finish with Walt enter and then the closing bracket.
So now we can answer the formula and let me call me down Begin.
Siano too.
We have four numbers at the end,
which we've extracted,
but on Road five,
where we have five digits following the hyphen,
we've successfully extracted those.
And if you're thinking,
could we have done that using the mid function?
Yes,
we could,
but I wanted to practice this combination of right Len and Search,
since it's a classic example,
or a complex formula which uses a classic combination or excel functions.