in this video,
we'll get some more practice on using the brute pool substitution technique that we saw in
the last video.
So zero for manipulating text that's going to number seven,
creating a title case formula.
But what we want to do in this example,
is to come up with a formula which will transform the text in this color into dramatically
correct titles.
Now,
as you probably know,
Excel has a function called proper,
which will capitalize the first letter image word.
This doesn't always give a viable title.
Let's put it to the test.
Let's begin by inside in the colon.
And then we could copy the title,
had her across and then just use equals proper.
Press the left.
Arum to reference the adjacent a two and enter on the first couple of titles.
We have no problems.
When we get to titles three and four.
We can see that a off and should all be in lower case If I move across to the other
worksheet that we have here in lower case list.
I've got a list of other words and phrases that should always be in lower case when they
occur in the title,
and I should add that I've made no great efforts to make this list complete.
So you are using this technique in a real life situation.
The onus is on you to actually come up with a list they to improve on the proper function.
What we can do is having applied the proper function to a to We can then use our fruitful
substitution 10 week to replace all of these words with their lower case equivalents
whenever they occur in its idle.
So let's just undo all of that.
But leave the new column in place,
and it's now open up our template so that a second template 07 substitution template it is
currently blank.
Here's the formula that we put together in the last video,
so we just need to copy all of those words into the old text column.
However,
we can't copy the words as they are.
For example,
if we change every occurrence of a the indefinite article to its lower case equivalent,
all words beginning with a would also become lower case and hear the word Andes would also
become low case because it starts with a nd so what we need to do is to make sure that we
have in place these words when they are recognized as words.
Nicole's what makes them recognize the buzzwords is where they're preceded by a space
notice I say preceded rather than followed.
Because,
of course,
if one of these words is the first word within a title,
it shouldn't be converted to lower case on.
The formula for doing this is fairly straightforward because and then the space has to go
double quotes and percent.
I'll just press the left arrow to reference they won and that sound formula.
And then we just company that down So you can see by the slight in dende at the start of
each of these entries.
We've now been a space inserted before each of these words and phrases.
So this is what we copy into our time place.
And of course,
we don't want to pace the formula.
We want to paste values then for the new text.
In other words,
detects that we want to convert this into we simply use equals lower press the left an
arrow to pick up you,
Jason itself on enter and then we can copy to fool me that down and then to build our final
formula,
we just need to specify the cell that were initially applying the substitute to.
So we go back into the worksheet titles.
That cell,
of course,
is a to,
but what we want a blind,
too,
is the proper version of A to and I'll template.
We need to type proper brackets.
A.
To that sounds starting formula was certainly a space,
followed by other case,
a changing into space,
followed by love in case A.
Then,
as I copy that down uses,
the Saleh bothers the input,
the men does the second substitution the third and so forth.
So we simply copy these all the way to the bottom.
All of these values then get substituted with the values in column C on the final or villa
contains all of their substitution Sylvester one that we copy.
And of course,
the reason I have to paste this into the text editor that he copious several in excel.
You can only paste it into another cell,
so we need to get it onto the general clipboard,
pasting it into a text.
Eggs are like night pad will do the drink.
So here's our formula.
Unlisted selected all on Copy it.
Now we're ready to build our final formula.
That's just expand the formula bar.
So this time what we have on the clipboard is literally all they'll need.
So we just begin with an equal sign and then we based everything.
And that's our completed formula.
So let's copy it down so we can see it's working off the A etcetera.
All of these words are now in lower case.
But when they care at the start of the title,
such as The Lord of the Rings,
you'll see that the upper case initial letter is retained.
The only problem I can see is on this line.
Gulliver's Travels,
where we have Apostrophe s Excel is treated the apostrophe as being the end of one word and
therefore s is the beginning of another word.
So we obviously need to modify our template to take this into account.
Now,
this is not to say that every time we have an apostrophe,
we now have to look at the following letter and make sure it's lower case.
If you think about it,
Apostrophe s is the only problem,
say,
for example,
it Swift had called his hero Ohara instead of Gulliver.
So the book title was actually Oh,
Horace travels.
We wouldn't want the age to become lower case.
We would want it to stay uppercase.
So apostrophe s is really the only thing that we need to change the lower case and the
logical way of doing that just to bring back out templates,
add it to the bottom and put the lower case substitution.
Now,
apostrophe has a special meaning in excel,
so we can't simply type apostrophe uppercase s.
Instead,
what we'll have to do is to use a formula to generate that string equals quotes.
And then inside the quotes,
we put apostrophe uppercase s and then replace that with the equivalent lower case formula
equals quotes,
apostrophes low case s close quotes.
So by doing that with Force in Excel,
to treat the apostrophe is a literal string instead of assuming that it has a special
function,
as it normally does.
And of course,
that special function is to indicate that we have a number stores text,
so we just need to add that into a formula.
And we do that by copying the formula down and then we'll just copy that new version.
So,
really,
this one,
Just paste it here for safekeeping.
A man just copy it into our solution.
So what goes?
No place is the new fashion,
so we can see that we've killed the problem you've now put on Horace travels.
Better change that back to Gulliver's Travels.
So if you try this in a real scenario,
I'm sure you'll also come up with other anomalies.
This will be especially true.
Perhaps if you're not working in English,
you're working with languages that have accents and so forth.
You may find that there are anomalies that you need Teoh take into account.
But hopefully simply by using this technique of brutal substitution,
you could just come up with substitution strings which will solve all of these problems for
you.