We've already seen seven examples of concatenation using the ampersand operator in this
video,
we'll have a look at making concatenation conditional zero for manipulating text that's
open up 08 conditional concatenation on What we want to do in this solution is to have the
user choose a company name and have the address of that company each line automatically
inserted.
To do that,
we use be look up and I'll look up Table will be in the customer's worksheet.
This will be the look up column,
and then we'll call back each of the four lines of the address three of the lines and never
empty.
But the second line of the address it's sometimes blank,
and this is the one that will need to make conditional.
So let's begin our formula by pulling across the first line.
So equals V.
Look up.
The thing we're looking up is the cell above 85 comma and the look up table is in customers
.
Columns 80 e Comma.
The column that we need is column,
too Coma,
then zero or calls for an exact match.
So no problems so far.
If we change the company name the corresponding first line comes across.
So let's now have a think about how we need to approach it when we come to this column.
So we'll need an if statement and for the logical test.
Well,
testes.
See whether V look up,
returns a blank.
So we use exactly the same view the cup that we've just done.
And then to make it into a logical test,
I will simply say not equal to nothing but the value of true.
We don't just want the address.
We want the address on a new line so we can use excels,
character function or char with the number 10 to achieve that.
And then after the new line,
we would put the results off.
I'll be look up off column three of the look up table on the value of false will only kick
in when the villa camp produces a blank value.
And in that case we simply insert nothing.
And,
of course,
when I say nothing,
I'm repairing to to double quotes,
but nothing between land the null string.
So let's go back to the invoice form and continue our formula so conditional concatenation
.
We still use the regular M percent all then toe.
And then we deserve our if statement all cancer.
Since we're now gonna nest,
be look up,
which will be essentially the same as the first.
So let's just copy the rest of it.
And,
of course,
we now on color three.
Then to convert that into a logical test,
Use Matti call to been old string quote squints.
That's a logical test.
Coma old Enter,
I meant value.
True,
We need this preceded by current to 10.
So character 10 ampersand we look up that will insert a new line and then put the result of
our be look up coma goaltender.
And then finally we put the value of false,
which is close quotes,
a little string,
well,
Vento and then the clothes in parenthesis to finish the if statement,
Let's check with that.
All works so back.
So leisure do have something in that column.
Let's find a customer that doesn't have a day of manufacturing,
for example,
and we can see that nothing is inserted and we don't get a narrow.
So let's just finish out formula.
So we've used conditional Comcast a nation to take care of the column,
which is sometimes blank the last two columns never blank,
so we could just copy this line and then using to put across the last two columns.
I m percent and I'll just split.
It's on to another line.
This one will be calling for ampersand,
old enter and column five,
and that completes our formula.
So the company up it their manufacturing have three lines of address.
Where is the backs of leisure?
Have all lines?
And by using conditional concatenation,
we've eliminated the possibility have in blank lines.