that's.
And now look a text manipulation formulas by creating a formula which test to see whether
the contents of ourselves start with a number.
So zero for manipulating text that's taken 09 So in this example we have a series of topic
headings,
and then we've got some paragraphs below each headed,
and what we want to do,
basically,
in the Topic Level column,
is to assign a level based on whether the text starts with a number or not.
You'll see that each of the topic Allen's begins with a number,
and in this example,
we want to end up with the appropriate HTML tanks placed around the original entries.
So the training folder,
if you open up the HTML file what we want to do is to paste our topics below the
appropriate headed excellent production for Excel Intermediate.
So the level column will tell us which is which.
That's the last topic related to Excel introduction.
And as I said,
the number will tell us whether this is a heading or whether it should be body text.
Let's look at the functions that will need to achieve this so naturally the first function
we're going to use is if and as we've seen,
it has three arguments,
the first being logical test a test which has to produce the value,
true or false,
the test.
Whether something America we can use the is number function and this is inherently
1,000,000,000.
It can only produce the result true or holes.
It takes a single argument which excel calls value and to supply that argument.
The logical thing is to assume that we would use the left function,
which we've seen several times first thrown into text the cell that you want to operate on
,
which is due to second parameter number of characters.
We want the first character only.
However,
there's a slight problem in this approach,
which is that all text functions,
including left,
will always produce a text result.
So even though the character we're extracting may look like a number by virtue of the fact
that that number has been produced,
uses a text function.
That character will always be treated as a textual character,
never numeric.
So the value being processed by these number function is supplied by the left function.
The result will always be false.
We will never have a number.
So before evaluating the character that we've extracted,
we need to use the value function in order to attend,
to convert that character to a number.
And if it is a number,
that attempt will be successful and the is number.
Function will then produce true.
So I heard the fact that we've got value value in a diagram hasn't confused you.
His number takes a single argument,
which excel calls value and then we use in the value function.
Just apply that argument.
So we have our true or false.
And then the second argument idiot is valued true.
If the first character is numeric,
we want to change Selby to into ahead in three.
And if the value is false,
In other words,
if the first character is not the America,
we want to change selfie to into a paragraph.
And if you haven't done much with Web development,
just a point out that HTML has six headings.
The pace that we use in this is headed one h one these ahead in twos.
So back in Excel,
we want this to be head in three.
So let's write our function office expound the formula bar so we start with equals If and
then we nest in.
So old mentor is number.
And again we're next in so old mentor value.
And then we lest in left inside values overall,
enter left.
First argument.
What's the text that you're operating on?
Its D to coma?
A second argument.
Number of characters.
How many characters are you extracting from B to one character?
So that's our left.
And that's the only argument off the value function.
So all cantor on the clothes in parenthesis.
So the value function all cancer on the clothes in parenthesis for his number function.
So that is number Statement is the first argument biological test argument off our if
function.
So no need a coma.
And on to the second argument,
your true so for value True.
Want to convert D to into an HTML age three statement.
So to do that in quotes,
we put the opening tag age three close quotes and then we use the concatenation operator
and percent tag on de too.
And then we need the close in time and percent quotation marks because we're doing a
literal string and then we put the clothes in H three tag,
which in Html looks like this coma.
So that completes the value of true on value.
False is very similar.
So I'm going to copy it all center and then just paste that in.
And instead of age three,
you know what a paragraph,
which is simply he and that completes our if statement on our regular So all mentor and
then we close in parenthesis.
Is that the if statement?
So when we price center D two should be converted into 83 because it starts with a number,
so that's working.
We can learn,
just collapse up on the bar computer formula down.
So what Excel has done for us?
It's the generate the HTML marca that we need for our page.
So we can now open up the HTML page in an editor.
So you probably need to right click and choose open with,
you know,
Pat or similar editor isn't available.
You can obviously just shoot another out something.
Open it with night pack,
so we want the markup for excellent reduction Here.
Got a couple of that festival introduction ends here,
so we can't be that on a student off page scroll down for the immediate Malcolm,
which goes all the way to the bottom.
So it's close and same.
And then let's open the HTML page,
my double quick in and then we can see we have our head in threes.
That's the end of the first section and then excellent,
and they get it.
So complete sound.
Look at manipulating text.
Hopefully,
you're getting used to the use or multiple functions to produce the result that you need,
and hopefully you can see why.
I prefer to split complex formulas onto several lines using all enter in our next section,
we want to look at formulas which used look up in reference functions.