Once you've downloaded and unzipped the exercise files for this course,
it's probably a good idea to delete the ZIP file just to avoid confusion.
Amanda is going to the exercise folder on here.
You'll find everything that you need to complete the course.
The 1st 2 sections are preparatory,
so there are no real work files here.
You'll see in the Welcome folder there.
No work files,
a tall on.
Then we've just got one work file and getting started.
The course proper starts with 03 logical functions,
and there are three components inside each of the sub folders.
First of all,
we have the start files.
These are the files that I'll be using as I demonstrate.
So when we talk about the first topic,
which is if statements you'll need to open this file,
which is what I'll be doing on screen and then follow along on what I'd recommend that you
do,
it's to start from scratch each time and then type the formulas as you watch the
demonstration.
However,
I realize it's not always convenient for people to do this,
so if for any reason you find it inconvenient to work in this way,
simply go into the folder called Completed,
and here you'll find the completed exercise.
And here's the formula that will be built in in the very first you tool riel.
But that's not the recommended method.
Recommended method is to start with a blank each time,
and that's what's the tutorial and to the formula.
And,
of course,
if you feel confident that you can solve some of these problems yourself,
go ahead and pause the video and have a crack at entering the formula yourself.
So those are the tutorial files start in and completed,
and then the other sub folder that we have here is a little diagrams.
So as you're watching the tutorials,
if I use any diagrams,
you'll find your copy of that same diagram in this folder.
And obviously the names match the tutorials that we do.
They're all in PdF format,
so when I double quick on a pdf,
it opens in Acrobat.
But any pdf Rita will be fine.
If you are used,
an acrobat will record that reader,
and remember,
you can just go to view full screen mode,
but which the short cut is.
Control L and then remember that some of these PdF's have multiple pages,
So if you are in full screen mode,
just use the forward and backward arrows to switch between pages.
And,
of course,
to come out at full screen mode.
Just press the escape key or type control L one small.
So those are the three areas to look for when you go into each folder,
completed diagrams,
and then these are the ones that you need to focus on but start in file for each tutorial.