the V look up function is very useful.
However,
it does have limitations.
So this video will move on to look at a couple of functions,
which provide a much more flexible alternative.
When you're performing,
look up operations 05 look up reference that's open up 03 using matched an index.
So festival.
Let's discuss the key limitation off the bill a cup function.
In this example,
we have to work seeds,
hires and damaged items,
items which will return from higher but were damaged.
And we simply want to find out the name of the person who hired each of these items.
So we have a higher ranch,
and in our highest table,
we have a higher ref column.
However,
the simple fact that the column saying in the name of the person who hired is on the left
of the column,
which contains the hiring,
means that we can't use the look up now.
A simple solution would be to cut the higher F column and paste it on the left of the
higher A column that would solve the problem.
But clearly this is not always gonna be feasible.
There are going to be situations where you're simply not able to make that kind of change
without perhaps messing up part of a solution.
Accident.
Have the authority is not your workbook.
He don't have the authority to sort of cut and paste Collins,
so sooner or later you'll find situations where we look up simply can't be used.
And in these situations,
the best solution is to use a combination of match and index In each of these two.
Before was one part of the look up operation.
So we started with a particular higher ref.
And if we look at our hires data,
the higher ed column is calling me.
What the match function will do is to identify which row a particular higher F occurs in.
Once you've identified that road,
the index function could be used on any other column toe.
Identify the entry in that column On that road,
the index function will be the outer function,
and the index function takes three arguments.
First we have to you,
Ray,
which in this case will be calling a of the highest worksheet into the second argument.
The road number.
We used a match function that match function,
in turn,
takes three arguments.
First of all,
the look up value,
which is the higher reference in Cell A to the damaged items.
Work,
please.
Then we have to look up array,
and this is column e of the highest work feet,
the column that contains all the higher references.
Finally,
we have the match type,
which is very similar to the final argument of the V look up option.
And as with that argument,
we can either use zero or falls to indicate that we want an exact match.
So all of that supplied by the match function becomes the second Argument row number,
and then index has 1/3 optional argument,
which is the column number.
In this example.
We're working with a single column,
said the depo column number,
which is one is fine.
For that reason,
we can omit back there.
Optional arguments.
Let's write out formula.
We start with equals index all tender since we're going to be nest in match inside it First
argument is Thean Ray,
within which we're looking and that's going to be hires.
Call him a calmer all cantor,
and then the second parameter is the road number,
and this is where we need our match.
The match starts with a look up value,
which is back in damaged items,
and it's eight to since damaged items is the work.
See that contains the formula well,
believe the name of the work street coma.
Now the look up array is back in hires,
and it's calling E,
which is quite difficult to click on that you can just about manage it coma.
And then we specify the match type as zero waffles,
although enter on the clothes in parenthesis to finish index,
and then we can help you on formula down.
So I see you can see use an index in combination with Match gives you much more flexibility
than using,
be look up and then require in a look up table.
You could use match on any column to identify a row number.
Then,
once you targeted that road,
you can use index on any other column to pull back any value on that road.
So they're very much partners in crime not last powerful on their own.
But when used in combination,
they provide a very flexible method of performing look up operations