Let's now move on to look at a more advanced use of the match in index combination,
the one in which you need to.
Unless the match function twice inside the index function 05 Look up in reference.
That's open up zero for that Burns Majin index.
And in this example,
we have an order for and then in the adjacent work seat,
we've got the number of items in stock of each of our products at each of all branches.
So on the order form,
if we put in the quantity and then choose a particular product,
I'm gonna go for this one y a l 50 80 on entry unit price of 75.
We want tohave a formula in this stock column which,
given the product code and also a branch.
So let's choose London will automatically display the number of items in stock.
So we've got an idea of whether we can actually supply the items being ordered.
So we've seen how we can use the match function so identify which road contains a
particular item.
But in this example,
additionally,
we can use mass to identify which Kahlan we should be working in so We want the
intersection off this road on this column,
and that's what we need are formula to do for us.
So we'll have a similar nest into the one that we saw in the previous video index will be
out out of function,
but this time we'll use all three arguments.
The first argument is the ray The last time we had a single column array.
This time we'll need a multi call in the rain,
so we reference all of the columns in the stock worksheet.
Then,
for a second argument,
the row number.
We used a match function and has the look of value.
We used the product reference that we've entered on the look up array will be column A of
the stock table.
That's the column that contains the references on the match type zero for an exact match,
then on to the third argument of index the optional one.
And that's the colon number.
And in our arrangement,
what we need to do is identifying the branch that we're actually working at,
so we nest the match function a second time.
This time to look at value is sell F 10 which contains the branch and for the look up array
will then specify Row one of our stock work feet and again,
we've got a match type of zero for an exact match.
So now let's write out formula Well,
just collapsed the ribbon to get a bit more space.
So equals index all kinds of since we're gonna be nest in the match function inside it when
the first argument is theory A that we're looking inside.
This time we need to have a multi column array,
so we go away from a across the end,
so reference in all of those columns,
comma or center lead to calculate the room number,
we make our first use of the match function.
So for the road,
we're taking the product code from the 15.
It's into a reference in a cell in the same worksheet is the one that contains the formula
.
We don't need the name of the worksheet comma,
and then the look up array is simply the first column of the stock worksheets,
then comma zero to specify that we want an exact match.
So this back statement constitutes the second argument of the index function comma all 10
and then we use match a second time to supply the third optional argument.
The column number.
So this time the thing that we're looking for is the branch,
which is in F 10 and again.
We don't need to include the name of the worksheets.
However,
we do need dollar signs,
because when we copy this formula down,
we don't want F 10 to change.
So I'll just press that four to convert this from a relative reference into an absolute
reference comma.
Now the look up array,
Where we gonna find the brunch?
Then I stopped.
Work Seat will find the Browns on the first row and again when we copy before me that down
.
We don't want this reference to change so a lot to insert dollar signs and to finish the
match.
Com a zero for an exact match,
and that completes our formula all tender and the closing parentheses to complete the index
function and to complete the formula.
So when we press enter,
we'll just need to choose a branch back to London.
We can see the quantity in stock in London,
and of course,
it would be a good idea to suppress the errors So,
for example,
we copy this down at the moment until we supply a product code.
We will get this error so we can simply use the if era function to suppress that error.
So enter,
let's put out if error here.
So this now becomes the first argument that if our comma or enter so here we need the
replacement value,
which is double quotes twice,
or the null string on the closing parenthesis to finish off.
If era now,
we don't have a branch recently have nothing until we choose a branch.
And then if we copy the formula down,
we shouldn't now have any errors.
But women choose a product.
The quantity and stock is calculated for us.
So that's the slightly more advanced use off the index function where the match function is
nested twice wants to specify the road and wants to specify the Colin