in this video,
we'll look at two techniques which you can use to optimize and speed up your look up
operations.
05 Look up in reference.
Let's open 05 optimizing.
Look up operations.
Now there are lots of minor changes that you can make,
which will moderately speed up your look up operations.
What we're gonna discuss in this video that the two techniques that you can use to make
dramatic speed improvements in any look up operations that you're doing on the first
technique will look at his use of the approximate match type as opposed to the exact match
time.
Let me begin by reminding you the difference.
First of all,
we've got a serious of job candidates and we're looking to complete these three columns
based on information in the applications worksheets on the application work seat as an
entry of road for every stage reached by each of the candidates.
And then the stages work feats as details of what those stages are.
So as you can see,
there are six of them,
starting with having an interest in C V all the way to being hired.
So if in our applications work seeds we want to display not just the stage number that the
stage description,
we can use it be,
look up or we could use a combination of index and match.
Let's go ahead and do that.
We'll call the new column stage description.
And since the data were looking up is so insignificant,
it doesn't matter whether we use we look up all index and match.
But what we really interested in discussing is the use of approximate match.
So let's use V look,
huh?
Equals we look up.
The lookout value is the stage number,
which isn't too coma.
Look up.
A raise in the state is worksheets and its columns A and B coma.
The result were looking boys in column two of that look up table comma.
And it's this final optional argument,
which specifies whether we have an approximate match or an exact match.
And the first technique,
which has a big impact on the performance.
The speed of your look up operations is that wherever possible,
you should use approximate mash.
Let's just insert true one is the alternative both mean the same thing,
and then when we end to that,
you can see that stage to correspondence to phone screen on we human copy that down.
So what makes the approximate match type so much faster than the exact match die?
Basically,
with an exact match,
Excel has to search every single road of the look up table.
So,
in this example,
will again for F two,
which contains one with the exact match.
Excel goes to the first row of the specified range to look up range and compares it to to
the value in that cell,
in this case with the element numbers so text evaluates to zero does that to equal zero.
No,
it doesn't say it moves on to the next cell.
Does that to equal one?
Yes,
it does.
So Excel stops and then pulls back the value from Colin,
too.
So that's no problem.
It's all in such a small table.
But what if we had half a 1,000,000 entries?
Excel would basically have to evaluate all of these rows until it finds something that's
equal to what it's looking for.
And it's this repeated testing for equality that makes the exact match so slow Excel is
forced to perform what's called a linear search going from row to row testing for equality
.
By contrast,
when you specify an approximate match time,
Excel perform what's called a binary search.
This is far more efficient.
The way it works is that Excel goes to the middle value halfway down the date of range and
compares that to the look of value.
Listen,
Ari,
we have seven rows Excel goes to road for and compares F two to the value on road full.
If that,
too,
is equal to that value job done,
it's found what it's looking for.
If it's greater than that value,
then itself simply ignores all the roads a bubble and focuses on the roads below.
In this case,
F two is less than the road that we've evaluated.
So excel this guns the bottom half and focuses on the top half.
It goes to the middle row of what's remaining.
So in this case,
we've got three road meaning.
It goes to the middle road and compares F two to the value in macro,
which happens to be what it's looking for.
So at this stage it would stop.
So if we had half a 1,000,000 roasted process,
you can see how using a binary search is gonna be so much more efficient because with each
pass,
the number of rows being process is hard and it doesn't take very long for Excel to start
whittling down the number of rows,
starting with half a 1,000,000 within 20 passes.
We're down to one road,
and this is what makes approximate match so dramatically faster than exact match.
So when you work in with large data sets,
you should always try and use the proximate match on.
Obviously,
you've got to make sure that the data is sorted on the look up Colin sorted in ascending
order.
However,
there is one problem with using approximate match,
and that is that it doesn't give you errors.
So if I put a stage number that doesn't exist like nine,
I really want this to say not available.
But instead it simply gives me the highest value.
It's where I have an invalid member in stage number.
I'm simply going to get any erroneous results instead of getting an error,
which I can then pick up on.
So whenever you're using approximate match,
you need to do a bit of error handling.
So the solution is to use an if statement and then for the logical test,
we use the look up set in the column in next to No.
One and then converting the V look up into a logical test I put in equals.
Whatever the look of value is,
so we're looking for F two in column one.
So,
in other words,
we're testing to see whether somewhere within that first column the value that we're using
to pull back the state description does actually exist.
As long as it does.
Our family,
true,
becomes to be look up.
But if it doesn't exist,
our value of false becomes the function in a on the end,
a function is a special era handle in function,
which Excel has,
which simply generates the n a error value.
So let's update our be look up statement algo centre.
Now Delta function now becomes if Ben Theological Test.
We want Help me look up,
John Copy using column one.
And then we test whether it's equal to two comma.
That's a logical test,
all center and for value.
True Wilder's paste in When I copied.
And this,
of course,
is column to which is a column we're pulling back from the look up table,
comma old enter and then the special function in a And,
of course it's a function that takes no arguments.
Its sole purpose in life is to generate the end.
A caravan on the closing parenthesis,
determinate the if so,
let's into them.
It was fine,
but what we've now put in place it's a way of picking up values that don't exist.
So if I put that mine back in,
there is no nine,
so it generates the end.
A era value.
That's how you use approximate match with the look up.
And as I've said,
the only provider is you've got to make sure we put some error handling to pick up illegal
entries.
Let's now move across the outcomes and look at the second major tech me or improving the
speed of your look up operations.