Let's now move across the outcomes and look at the second major tech me or improving the
speed of your look up operations.
Everything we've discussed so far applies both to be look up and to the index and match
combination.
Both of them have the option to send the match type to truth.
The second technique,
however,
applies specifically to the match and index combination,
and you'll use this technique where you're use in one match operation to pull back several
different pieces of information from your data set.
And the trick,
basically,
is that you separate the two functions.
So instead of using them repeatedly in combination,
you use the match function once in a helper column and then all your index functions refer
to that one match function.
So it's not untypical that you'll be pulling back,
say,
10 or 20 bits of information on the same I d.
Number the same stuff I D.
Number,
same national insurance number,
and you're just pulling back lots of columns using that one piece of information.
So whenever that's the case,
if you use this technique,
you split in the two functions,
so you've got matched only once and then,
using Index,
you'll see great improvements in speed.
So let's have a look at how it works here.
We've got our candidates summary.
So in this work feet,
each name will occur just once.
And we want to move across to the applications.
Work feeds by the well,
just put that back.
So one.
And we want to move across to the applications worksheet and find out three bits of
information.
Firstly,
how far did each candidate get?
What stage off the possible six did they reach?
Secondly,
what was the first contact date?
And thirdly,
what was the last contact date on the key to get in a long This information is to sort the
data using the candidate I d.
On the stage date the men using the approximate match with the match function.
So let's begin by sort in,
they will need a custom of salt.
First of all,
by candidates,
I d.
That level.
And secondly,
by stage dates on the candidate ideas,
you can see it's a number stored is text.
So all sorted numerically.
So now we have all the roads related to each candidate's sorted next to each other,
and I think I must have accidentally placed a nine in here protesting purposes earlier.
That should be a two soldiers Revert wanted to.
So the first thing we want to do it's to pick up the last entry for each individual.
So this person got as far as ST to own screen,
and we scroll down to see if someone who got a bit further we've got to Sarah.
Hansel,
we've got as far as stage.
Fine the reference check.
So let me do I look up.
We're interested in three things.
The final stage,
the first dates and the last eight.
And for all of them,
we're going to start by using the match function to match the candidates.
So we perform in three operations,
all using the same match.
So this is an example where we can use this technique of split in the match in the index.
So the match is only evaluated once,
and then the index operations or we use the same match.
So let's begin with the MASH.
I'll insert a column which typically you would then hide once you got your formulas in
place and let's just call it match row and of course we'll need the same error handling
that we put in place for the B Look up.
Let's do the basic function first,
and then we'll put in the air handling afterwards.
Everyone equals match.
Look at values.
The candidate I d in a to coma on the look up array is in applications,
and it's calling a comma and then important and then importantly,
the match type.
True or false?
One or zero,
we want one.
True,
you'll also notice that we have minus one as an option,
which we don't have would be.
Look up,
and this applies if it's more convenient for you to sort your data in descending order.
And then if you have repetitions of the look of value,
Excel will take the first entry rather than the last.
So in our case,
we want Excel to take the last.
So you true one on when we enter?
I've got this format.
It is a dates on things.
A format.
It's a number on remained the decimals safer James Woody within the specified range.
The last row is Road three,
so no one road to run three.
So we still have this potential problem that we can put erroneous values in here which
aren't picked up his errors and simply give us wrong results.
We'll need to add some era Handley,
since the match function simply gives us of row rather than retrieving a value to do our
test in,
we'll need to use the index function.
So again we've got an if statement and for a logical test,
we use index.
The array is the first column of the applications work treat,
and then for row number we use match the same match function that we intend to use.
So the look up valuing too Array Applications column A and match type one approximate.
And then we convert that whole index match combination into a logical test by put in equals
to a to So we're testing to see whether the value looking for does actually exist.
If it does,
value attributed statement becomes the mass function.
And if it doesn't as we saw in the last example,
we used the n A function to generate the A era body.
So let's put that in place.
Bolt,
enter Hey,
we need if Old Santa and we invest in index now a raise applications call him a comma in a
row.
Number is supplied by match The Chargers copy all hands,
sir.
Closing next and then make it into a logical test by saying equal to hey soon,
comma.
So all of that is the logical test from,
if statement or cancer.
True,
is our manager coma on value?
It false is the n a function,
and that completes our formula,
so that now makes it a bit more robust and ensures it's gonna pick up all those candidate
ideas that don't actually exist.
So now we can copy this more robust formula down.
Are we ready to use the index function to pick up the three bits of information that we
need?
So first of all,
we want the outcome,
which is in column G because we've got our data sorted and we'll be using approximate mash
for each tender that i d.
It goes through all the repetitions and always picks up the last one so we can collapse the
formula bar because we're now gonna do a single function with no nesting equals index.
The array is Colin G.
Coma And then I wrote Number is supplied by the match function,
which we've got in C two.
And because our formulas and outcomes we don't need to specify outcomes as the lane of the
work it that's our outcome on it.
We coming down and just tested.
Remember Sarah Hutzell got us faras reference check.
Let's leave first day till last.
That's the most complex Let's now do last state.
So last state is in column h.
We want exactly the same formula,
but we want to use H instead of G.
Everything else is the same.
The First States is slightly more tricky.
We can start by using what we've got here for the last eight.
So that takes us here and then we need to move up.
But how many rows do we need to live up?
And the answer is basically we can use the stage number.
So we've move up by this number of rows.
So in this case,
too,
we went on the cell above the first road.
So we then just need to down one.
Let's try that with Sarah Hustles Road five stages.
Move up.
512345 and we're on the cell above her first road.
We then lived down one,
So let's build out logic into our formula.
We'll start with this one,
but we're now gonna be nest in an index inside an index.
So all kinds of and I'll just lose the closing parenthesis for a moment.
We now want to subtract from sea to all hands up index on our array is column F.
That's where the stage number is.
Coma on our row number is the value supplied by sea to and the closing parenthesis for
index.
And then we have to remember to add on one so that we moved down one road to put us on the
first row.
That matches that candidate I be and Walt enter on the closing around consists for the
index function.
Let's test it that we coming down.
So for James Woody,
we have a society faster The AIDS um em for Maduro.
Yeah,
the 29th of this six.
Let's just do one more So Hansel 30 that the eighth.
No,
she is the But those are the two key techniques to take into account.
Firstly,
when used in either natural,
look up.
Always said your match time to approximate by using one.
What true?
And secondly,
if you're retrieve in several pieces of information using the same match.
Always use the index and match combination.
But the match in one Kahlan and then for all the other columns,
you can simply use index on its own and refer back to that one match,
Colin.
So those are the two things to bear in mind if you want to make your lookups as fast as
possible.