in this video,
we'll take a look of the use of excels offset function,
which could be used to isolate a range of data within a larger range.
The 05 look up reference Let's open up 06 offset function.
So here we have to work sheets.
First of all,
we have call centre averages has information every day of the week.
But those are the seven days of week one,
and we've just got some summaries,
average time,
things of answer,
call,
duration,
etcetera.
And in the summary worksheet,
what we're looking to do is to get the weekly averages.
So we want to take each of those seven rows and just get the average figure.
But in each of the columns,
so naturally,
for this to work,
we have to have the data sorted chronologically.
So we've got all the Week one information or the week to information,
etcetera.
But in this case,
I think you'll agree that is the logical way to lay out this information.
So it's logical that it would be sorted in this fashion.
The way that the offset function works is that you specify a reference cell,
which is the starting point So in the case of column see the time taken to answer a logical
reference.
Elwood BC to the first cell in week one.
Then we specify the robe offset and column offset How many rows down?
How many Collins across Solwezi?
In this case,
we don't want any columns across,
and the number of rows down depends on the week saying We won.
We want an offset a zero rose because we're in the right cell in Week two.
We want an offset of seven.
So it's starting from here.
1234567 And that takes us to Monday of the following week.
So the relationship between the week number on the offset is that we need to subtract one
from the week number and then multiply the result by seven saying we won,
we subtract one from one,
leaving zero multiplied by seven gives us zero,
so we've got no upset.
Then we to tu minus one,
gives us 11 Time.
Seven gives this seven.
That gives us an offset of seven starting from the initial reference point so that initial
reference point C two will be fixed,
or at least a two will be fixed with a dollar sign.
So we're always started from that point.
And then as the weeks progress,
the road offset just continually increases.
So this is the formula we need to create.
The out of function is average,
and this can take a series of arguments separated by commas.
Refer to his number one number two etcetera.
Each of these is normally a cell reference molders need one block of cells which will be
retrieved by the offset function.
The offset function takes five arguments,
only the 1st 3 or obligatory.
Firstly,
we have the reference.
So for the first piece of information,
we're looking up.
That's gonna be cell C two and we'll have to remember to put a dollar in front of the two
sides.
We copy the formula down,
we stay stuck on that road.
Then we've got the two offsets.
How maney of Rose he wants,
well,
sat down.
How many columns do you want to offset across?
So for the rose,
we use the week number,
subtract one from it,
then multiplied by seven and the columns We haven't all set of zero because we're in the
right column.
And then because We're doing an average for the week.
The height that we want to retreat is seven.
So the offset takes us to Monday.
A man from there.
We have a height of seven,
which encompasses the entire week because we want the with to be one on because one is the
default.
We can venom it.
The fifth argument,
which is the with that we've got a matrix,
which is seven rows high on one Colin wide.
So now let's write out formula.
So the outer function is average old Santa and then inside it me.
Next hour,
offset reference is call centre averages C two and then I'll just press that four until I
got a dollar sign in front of the two but no dollar sign in front of the sea and then for
the number of rows that we want to offset in parentheses.
Well,
first of all,
pick up the week and I'll just deletes the name of the worksheets since the Formula Asian
summary.
And then we just press that for until we've got a dollar sign in front of the A that no
dollar sign in front of the two.
That way,
when we call me to the right reference will remain stuck on the week color,
but when we call you down,
we'll pick up each of the different leaks from that figure.
We need to subtract one before multiplying it by seven.
That's how many rows down we want to offset.
Now we need to specify how many columns we want to offset.
We're in the right column so we don't need or not said it's all.
But we have to put zero because Collins is not an optional argument comma that we specify
the height we want the average of seven days.
So we put a height of seven.
And then for our wits,
we can either put comma one or because,
as you can tell by this,
where brackets it's optional,
we can simply admit the with,
and then we'll have a default of one.
So the upset function is returning.
The matrix of seven rose by one column.
That's our formula.
So all times on the closing practices to him,
the average function.
So because of our strategic use of dollar signs,
we can now call me to the right,
pick up the average reach of you,
Jason Columns and then we could just double click.
So you copy down and pick up the averages for each week.
So that's how the offset function works very useful function or isolated and analyze in
small sections of data within a larger data set.