that's our move on to look at excels in direct function.
05 Let's open up 07 The indirect function enables you to construct a cell reference by
using concatenation.
So in this example,
we have a series of worksheets.
We want to analyze the data in each of those work treats.
We want to come up with a total amount claim total amount reimbursed on the average
percentage reimbursed.
So obviously,
when we come to analyze the Birmingham work,
Treat will be using the word Birmingham.
When we come to analyze,
cardio will be using the word Cardiff and so four on what the indirect function enables you
to do is to incorporate that word into your cell reference.
And a good way to use indirect is to start with a literal reference and then incorporate
indirect within a literal reference.
So for Birmingham,
we would say equal some.
I live across the Birmingham and highlight this cell reference that we want to analyze.
So for amount claim that's column C and then we enter the formula,
and what indirect now enables us to do is to substitute the word Birmingham with a
reference to sell a to that way,
when we copy the formula down will have a reference to sell a three a four,
which will effectively enable us to target a different work feet.
So let's just expand the formula bar because we're nest in indirect inside.
Some are used old enter.
Yeah,
we'll need indirect come in here,
we'll need old enter.
And that will be the clothing parenthesis all the sun.
So the argument that indirect taste,
the obligatory argument is referenced text and the key word here is text.
So in other words,
what goes inside the parentheses is a string.
If I were simply to put what we have already as a string and close parentheses,
we'll get the same results.
But because it's a string,
what we can now do,
it's the use can cast a nation so we can delete the word Birmingham and proceed it with
Cell 82.
So if I put in reference to eat too,
and then use the ampersand African cattle nation,
I'm now saying,
Take the word in cell a to and then can Katyn ate the rest of this string to produce the
spinal cell reference and when I enter,
get exactly the same result,
but I now have a flexibility,
a copy in this formula down and then the total reimbursed will be exactly the same as this
formula.
But with colon be instead,
that's just verify that so that we could see amount playing see amount.
We invest the so if instantly copy the original press escape and then paste it in and
changer C's two D's was coming that one down,
and then finally,
or the amount reimbursed.
We analyze column E,
but we use the average function again.
I'll just paste in change something average on chain C T E.
On.
I've already formatted this column as a percentage.
So that's the basic usage off the indirect function.
It provides a great deal of power,
a great deal of flexibility.
We'll get some further practice on using it in the next video.