in this section will take some examples of working with numeric values.
Let's begin by looking at rounded 06 manipulated numbers.
Let's open 01 Controlling round insensitivity Excel has a number of functions which will
perform round in operations on the American bodies,
but these are not to be confused with all matin.
So,
for example,
here I've got a recommended retail price.
Colin,
if I highlight it and use the increase or decrease decimal buttons,
I'm in no way changing the number.
So simply by changing the corner so that the decimals aren't displayed doesn't imply that
the number has changed.
When I click on the cells,
we'll see that any decibels that were there are still there.
By contrast,
when we use around in function,
we're actually changing the number in some way.
So the most basic round in functions will change the number of decimals,
which displayed perhaps the most useful round in functions of those which round the number
in more sophisticated ways.
These are the functions will look at in this video and round,
ceiling and floor.
All three of these have the ability to around the number to whatever significant digits you
desire in this example.
Well,
look at calculating discounted prices,
but since they on prices,
we want them to be fairly user friendly and easy to remember.
We've got all out discounts set up in columns.
I threw a hammer,
and here we have a couple of drop downs,
but which the user can choose the significance or sensitivity.
So,
for example,
if they choose five,
we'll be round in the number to the nearest five to the nearest 2.5,
right down to decimals,
to the nearest nor going to five,
and then the user can specify the direction.
Do you want to do normal rounding up with no 0.5 and above,
down for anything below,
nor point fine?
Or do we always,
once around,
up all always round down?
So let's begin by putting our basic formula in place.
One which calculates the prices based on these discounts so we would want equals
recommended retail in the three minus because with this county the recommended retail
multiplied by the discount so that will take care of this count.
A Now who wants to copy this formula?
We'll have to think about dollar signs.
First of all the to be threes.
When we copy to the right,
we won't want the beater change,
but when we copy down,
we will want the three to change.
So we press at all.
And so we've got a dollar in front of the bees,
but no dollar in front of the three.
And then for I three,
we have the reverse when we copy.
So the right we do want the I to change to a J.
K etcetera.
So it picks up all the other discounts.
But when we copy down,
we go with the three to change.
So this time we use that for to get toe I dollar through.
That's our basic formula.
Now let's make out solution a bit more flexible By taking the significance on the direction
into account.
Let's start by name in these two cells also alone,
this one to the right.
I think he looks a lot better that way.
And then to name the cells,
we could just highlight this matrix,
which has potential names on the left,
have an automatically generated the names by using formulas create from selection and left
colon,
so the name significance will apply to J by on the name direction well,
applying to J six and then our created names available here with my choose direction,
even see Stay six and significance is j fine.
I believe the next statement.
Test the direction that's chosen and use the appropriate function based on the current
selection.
So the outer function will be if and then a logical test.
Well,
we weather direction equals around and then for value is true.
We would use the M around function,
which is normal.
Rounding the number that we want around is the formula that we have so far that simple
calculation.
And then we specify in the case of em around the second row mentor call multiple.
And this will basically be our significance.
And that's a number between North 0.25 and five.
That's what we do in a logical test proves to be true.
And when the logical test is false,
value it falls is a nested if statement.
A logical test here is for the second puzzle of their action direction.
People's ground up.
If it does,
value true is to use instead of the M around function,
the ceiling function,
which always rounds up and like em around seeing it has two arguments.
The number two which it applies.
It is our calculation,
and then the second perimeter.
Instead of the import multiple.
It's called significance,
and that will be this cell that we've called signage because which has to drop down with
the different numerical values between 4.5 and fine,
having tested but two possible directions.
It neither of those is true catchall value,
if all still kicking.
And in that scenario,
we know that we must be around it down.
So we'll be using law and then the first parameter,
which should say number like so present calculation and then ask before the significance is
the choice that's currently in play in the cell that we've made its significance.
So now let's create our final formula.
Let's expand the formula bar.
Let's also collapsed the ribbon to get ourselves a bit more room,
so we'll need this So this press old into a couple of times and leave it in place.
But to start the final formula,
we need if all hands a neurological test and we test in the direction,
so you'll notice that when I click on J six.
Because it has a name,
the name is automatically picked up.
Direction equals ground.
That sound test,
all hands are and the value true used the M around function,
and then the number that we around in is the calculation that we did earlier.
Coma.
And then the second argument,
which Excel holds more people will be the cell that we've called significance.
So when I click on it,
the name of the sound is automatically inserted.
Close friend persist in the M round and comma to end the second on Vince the value true or
our if statement,
and to supply the third argument on its walls,
we put in a nest it if or enter at this time,
we're testing to see if the direction equals round up calmer.
I meant to supply the value of true arguments of this nest.
It is.
You would use ceiling.
We can ignore sealing off man for two reasons.
First reason.
It's only available in Excel 2013 and 2060.
So not everyone doing this tools for actually have it available,
and secondly,
the promise of it it offers which ceiling doesn't.
Pam is to specify the direction or around in negative numbers.
So since we're not dealing with negative numbers,
we can ignore seeing that man,
you just insert ceiling.
And then,
of course,
the number that we're analyzing is the one supplied by our initial calculation.
Common and then significance is this cell that called significance.
Let's just call Colmer and then for the value of false not just of the nested.
If,
but they're both ISS will become floor and then we just paste in rest off the function.
So it has to see the user has specified that we want around all round up.
If they want around,
we use them around if they want to round up when you see them.
Neither of those two is true when you small old enter closing parenthesis for the nested it
on the closing parenthesis for the outer.
And when I pasted,
I managed to end up with two open parentheses.
There sort of lose that one.
That's our basic formula,
which because of our strategic use of dollar signs,
we can come across on coming down.
So with the significant sets of five,
you can see that all our prices are multiples of five and Then,
as we re buying this significance,
we get more granular prices all the way down to 4.25 where we had personal accuracy to our
prices.
And if you want the user to see the consequence of the choice of around in this chosen,
you can just insert a formula here to calculate the average vehicles,
average all these cells on.
Then we can copy that across and then to see the most dramatic difference,
we can set the significance toe fine.
If it is candidate,
we have a price of about 48.
If we round up,
that becomes 50.
I think we round down.
That becomes fully fine.
So as you can see,
rounding in Excel is not just a case off the decimals.
It can apply to the significant digits as well,
using one of these three very useful functions em around ceiling or law