Let's now move on to look at a very simple but very useful function.
Sub Total.
06 Manipulating numbers.
Let's open zero fall sub total gumption.
The sub total function is used automatically by Microsoft.
Excel whenever you use the sum total command.
However,
Additionally,
you can use the sub total function in your own formulas and solutions,
and thats we'll see it provides a couple of very unique attributes,
which you can take advantage of.
Let's begin by reviewing the sub total command,
so we'll switch across to the sub total command work feet and here we have some sales data
.
The subtitle Command is basically a poor man's pivot table.
It allows you to group data and to insert subtitles either before each group or after each
group.
So,
for example,
if we wanted to show stop totals by sales person,
our first step would be to sort the data by the salesperson column.
I mean,
it's just a case of going across to the data time and on the right hand side here,
we've got sub total,
so each changing sales person we use the some function on the sales.
Kahlan.
When we click OK,
excel automatically inserts extra rose after each group,
and it uses the sock total function to generate the subtitles.
We'll discuss the syntax of the sub total function shortly,
but for the moment,
I just like to point out to very useful and unique attributes possessed by the subtitle
function.
The first is that the sub total function ignores any cells that contain sub totals.
So,
for example,
at the bottom of our data,
Excel has automatically generated a grand total road,
and it's using the sub total function to calculate the grand total along the data.
In doing so,
it creates a reference to the entire column,
starting from road to the first data road and ending on 1000 and 84 the last state of Rhode
between those two cells.
There are lots of cells that contain sub total formulas,
but these are automatically ignored,
and that wouldn't be the case if we were using this some function,
for example,
the total is generated by all these analysis cells would be included in the calculation if
we use the sun function instead of the sub Total function on the second key attributes is
that when you filter data the subtitle will analyze only the currently visible cells.
So,
for example,
if I activate Filter In and let's say I only want to see sales greater than or equal to
75,000 So if I make a selection,
we can see that the total in the status bar matches the total generated by the sub total
function,
and this is the attributes that will be taken advantage off in our solution.
So let's clear our filter and let's remove our subtitles by using the subtitle Command
Again and clicking on removed or on before we create our formulas.
Let's have a look at the syntax off the subtitle function.
The subtitle function is basically a wrapper function,
which allows you to perform a variety of different calculations,
depending on the first argument.
But function argument is used to specify whether you want sub total to give you the average
count.
Count a max etcetera,
and the argument is numeric.
You'll notice that each of these possible values occurs twice.
This allows you to specify how you want the sub total function toe handle manually.
Hidden rose if you choose a single digit valley,
manually hitting rose are included in the final calculation.
If you choose one of those three digit equivalence,
manually hitting Rose are excluded,
and it's important to remember that we are talking about manually hidden rose.
Only any rooms which are hidden as a result of film three I never included on the second
arguments of the subtitle function is the reference that you want to apply this function,
too.
So,
in our case will be working on the sales.
Told him.
Ask the name of the arguments implies Breath one.
You can either have a single reference or a series of comma separated references.
So in our case,
we just want one column,
which is the sales column.
So now let's create our formulas.
It's a very simple formula with no nesting,
so we don't need to expand our formula bar.
You just need equals sub total,
and then excel very obligingly displays all of the available functions on For our purposes
.
We can either use nine.
A one on nine is the user will be filtering data rather than manually high in rows.
And of course,
both nine and 109 will only analyze visible cells when filtering is used as opposed to
manually hiding Rose.
Someone used nine coma.
And then the only reference that we need to specify is rep one,
which will be the sales column.
So I'll reference the entire column by clicking on the column heading If I could just about
reach and that's our formula.
So we enter,
and we can then copy this formula to save a bit of time when we created the others.
So we simply need to paste each one in and replace the number.
And to get Excel to duel the work.
We just reinsert the opening parenthesis to bring on the list.
So everyone number one everyone number full.
And here we want under five.
So using the simple formulas yuk unbilled solutions,
which are very similar to the ones that you build using functions like some if averages.
But the difference is that you have far more flexibility and interactivity.
You're leaving it to the user to decide how they want to filter the data,
and then your formulas give them a result for the currently visible cells.
So let's test that it's working if we filter the bronze Colin.
So we're only viewing the figures for the Cardiff branch.
And then let's reduce the quarter down to court a one only if we now select all of the
sales figures by clicking on the first and press in control ship Down Arrow,
we can see from the figures displayed in the status bar without total.
On average,
figures have been updated to reflect only the currently visible rose.