Let's end.
I'll look at manipulating numbers by looking at XL's large and small functions.
06 manipulating numbers that's open 06 using large,
small and count A.
In this example,
we have a series of sales figures,
ruled out claims and,
in our summary work leads,
were interested in displaying the top 10 spenders on the bottom 10 spenders.
And this is exactly what XL's large and small functions will enable you to do and for a bit
of further practice will do three versions about summary and with each new version,
will introduce another level of complexity.
Begin with you had a bit of charity to the formulas will create.
Let's create some named Ranges,
since we've only got whole columns,
I'll see next hole and then go across to the Formulas tab and in the defined names group,
click on Create From Selection.
Yeah,
especially find that the names to be used in the top row only now let me kick Okay,
Excel creates our names,
and we can then use these names in our formulas in preference to the rule cell references.
So let's begin by having a look at the syntax of the large and small functions.
The syntax for both functions is identical.
Each function takes two arguments.
Festival.
You have the array,
and this is normally a single column containing numbers or sometimes dates within which you
want to find the largest second largest,
etcetera.
So in our case,
it's going to be the total.
Spend a column.
The second argument K allows you to specify the nature of the value that you want to
retreat.
How close to being the largely shouldn't be second,
largest,
third largest or if you were using the small function second,
smallest third smallest,
etcetera.
So let's complete summary version one the simplest of the three.
And to make this one really simple,
what we've done is to insert a new married column,
which essentially has the K number.
The second argument of the large ins all functions.
So the large will be working in ascending order,
iced first and then for small will work in descending order 10 from smallest at the top on
the very smallest at the bottom,
so the large function will be used to calculate the total,
and then once we've got that total,
we can use index and match to find out the client you spend that amount formula is going to
be equals large and for our Arabian Goto formulas using formula on,
pick up total spend coma and then for the K argument,
you just click on Self a two and then we can just copy that down on the K argument is
always being picked up from the first column.
So we get largest,
second largest,
etcetera,
and we can copy this formula to save a bit of time for the small equivalent on.
Firstly,
changed,
the function names a small and secondly,
we change the K reference to call in half.
And then we can call me this one down,
10 smallest all the way down to smallest.
So now that we've extracted these figures,
we can simply look in sales.
Find the client who spent that month,
and then we can use index and match to pull back the name of the client.
Let's just have a quick review of how in Nexen match work when index and matter used
together to look up.
A value index is always the outer function,
and it takes two arguments.
First of all,
we have the array within which you're looking for.
A particular value in our case is going to be the client column,
and secondly,
you have the road number.
This is supplied by Ness in the match function.
The match function needs a look up value.
In this case,
it's going to be D to That's the total Spend column in our summary worksheet,
and we specially find the look up Ray.
And that will be the total Spend column within our sales work.
She's and then finally,
we have the optional argument match type,
and we wouldn't want zero for an exact match.
So let's expand the formula.
So any equals,
index enter.
And the first argument the array will be the client Cullen,
which we have named the client coma.
All enter and then for the road number.
The second argument we nest,
the match function Look up.
Value will be D to coma and the look up array within which we certain for D to will be the
total Spend column coma.
We're looking for an exact match.
Closed parenthesis to end match old enter on the closing premises to end index and then we
can just double quick to copy this down and copy the formula to the bottom 10 spenders.
And all we have to change is D two,
which now becomes I to.
So when we test it,
we should see Kobe at the top on Ashton Western at the very bottom.
Then they all the high spenders on the list.
So that's the basic version of how summary.
In the next video,
we'll do a slightly more complex example where we haven't got that convenient column with
number,
which can then be referenced by the large and small functions.