in the last video,
we created our first version of our summary,
and we allow ourselves the luxury of having an extra column.
It contained numbers.
These numbers could then be referenced by the large and small functions as the second or K
argument.
When you're building a model that uses the large function,
it's not always convenient to have an extra column containing the number,
which you can men reference,
and it's usually preferable if you could come up with a calculation that will generate the
number automatically.
Naturally,
you could put the number and literally,
there's nothing to stop us type in a one in here,
then on the second road to and so full.
But what if you wanted a top 100 on the bottom 100?
It will be far preferable to come up with a calculation that generates the number
automatically as we copy the formula down.
So that's what we'll be doing in version two of our summary.
Let's move across the summary B two.
Let's first of all,
look a technique for generating the number that we need.
We can use account a function,
and the trick that we use is as follows equals counting,
and we now need to reference his cell close to the cell containing the formula.
You obviously don't want to reference the cell that contains the formula itself.
That would be a circular reference.
So we referenced this celeb.
Um,
if we left the formula like that,
it would always return one.
But if we now put Colon,
we now have C one colon.
See one.
If we count the number of cells in that reference,
we still have a one.
But the trick that we use is to make the first part of the reference absolute.
I can do that by pressing that fall on the keyboard.
So now we have Dolisie one fixed and C one not fixed.
So obviously,
on this first cell,
the count will be one.
But when we copy it down because the first part of the reference days fixed will be going
from C one to C two.
So the count will be two and three,
then four.
And so?
So that's the trick.
If we enter the formula as we copy down,
you'll see that the number increases by one each time.
So all we have to do is to use exactly the same formula that we use last time.
But instead of reference in a cell that contains the number,
we used this count a technique to generate the number.
So this is what the new version about formula will look like again we use in the large
function on the array that we're looking inside is the Total Spend Column.
But for the K argument,
that is the number.
How large,
largest,
second largest,
etcetera.
We messed in the count a function,
and this takes either a single argument.
Refer to his value one or a comma separated list of arguments.
So which was used in one.
Then we using this trick of having the original formula going from C one to C one,
thereby generating one.
But because we have a dollar sign in front of the first part of that reference,
as we copy it down,
the first part stays fixed on the second part increases.
And as the second part increases,
so does the range.
Being referenced on would generate the numbers that we want.
So by using the county function with about this little engine inside the former there
itself,
which generates a number that increases by one as the formula is copied down from row to
row.
And now let's use another trick that you should have in your armory,
which is a trick that you use whenever you want to create a formula,
which is similar to an existing one.
So here's the trick.
Will copy this live across the summary version one,
and we know that what we want to do is to replace this A to with our account A.
So we actually build the new formula in our be one cell.
And the simple trick is,
when we've got the formula,
we copy it and then we just cancel.
So in other words,
we don't commit the changes that we've made to this.
So we're using this cell for convenience.
So here we wrestled,
enter I live across so that we could nest on account,
a function we paste that in.
I'll just put another all tensor in here just to be consistent.
That's the way we've been doing it so far.
On all 10 to here is well and of course,
under in this purely irritability.
Everything's nice needs untidy.
That's it.
So that's the new version of the formula that we need for our B two,
but we're building it here for convenience.
And now all we have to do is to copy the final formula and make sure that we don't press
enter because press escape or click on the cancel button on the left of the formula bar.
Then we can live across,
get rid of all these on pay star formula into C two,
and that's it.
So we copy that down.
You get exactly the same results as we had before,
but we don't need to have this extra column just that that we have somewhere to pick up the
number.
The number is now being generated automatically that in our corner.
So it's much more efficient.
And just to finish off some reversion to,
let's copy this formula to generate the small formula.
So the changes that we need to make our,
of course the function itself that becomes small and then the references.
So now we're referencing column G type colon,
so you have G one DRI one,
and then we put dollar signs on the 1st 1 and I was just about to copy that down on then.
I've remembered that we actually want this to be in descending order,
so we leave it as it is.
We'll have ascending order.
We'll go from 1 to 10.
We want to go down from 10 to 1 on.
The simple answer to this is that we prefix the count A with 11 minus.
So if you think about it,
11 minus one,
which is what this county generates will give us the 10 when we copy it down.
Account increases to two.
So we have 11 minus two,
which is nine copy down again.
The count increases to 3 11 Minus three is eight and salt.
So we enter that and as we call me down the K argument of small,
which determines how small sounds a 10 on ends on one.
So we should have exactly the same numbers as we had last time.
And finally,
let's copy across our second formula.
And the only difference is we no longer have column A containing numbers that we've got one
column fewer,
so be too needs to be changed to see to Yeah,
we can copy this down,
then do the same thing for the bottom 10 on again.
D two needs to be updated this time to G two.
So that sound,
new,
improved version of the summary and the improvement is that we don't have to have this
extra column with the numbers we used in the count a function to generate the required
numbers within the formula itself.