in the last video,
we improved our summary by incorporating the count function to automatically generate the K
number required by the large and small functions.
Let's move on to version three of our summary and introduce a bit more sophistication in
this version.
We want the user to be able to choose whether they want to focus on total spend or total
units.
So,
so far are formulas have unconditionally been analyzing the Total Spend column.
We now want the user to be able to choose between total spend and total units.
And of course,
we've named both of these columns.
So we've got total underscore spend and total underscored units as the automatically
generated names for these columns.
So the first thing we'll do is to name the choice Cell a one instead of reference in a one
.
Let's call this cell total choice to manually name a cell.
We go to the name box in the top,
left here on type the name Total under school choice,
and always remember to press enter.
Otherwise,
the name doesn't actually register.
So now we want to move from this formula,
which unconditionally uses the total Spend column as the array argument of the large
function to a conditional structure.
And that,
of course,
means an if statement so logical test will check to see the value that's currently in place
in the cell that we've now called total choice.
So we can say the total choice equals total spend Been.
The value of true is the large formula that we had in version two of our summary on the
value of falls.
It's the same large formula,
but for the array argument instead of total spend,
we have total units.
So let's create our formula,
and the first thing we can do is to copy that formula that we have already.
So let's copy the large formula.
Let's just make this a bit bigger,
and we can also collapse the ribbon to give ourselves a bit more room.
So we need equals.
If,
well,
Penta and then our logical tests is going to test the value that's been chosen in cell a
one.
So total choice equals double quotes,
total spend,
comma Walt enter,
and then the value of true.
He paced in the formula from version two of our summary,
and I'll just put a few spaces into invented a bit further coma.
And then we just need to modify this cell reference This version of the summary we've
introduced two new rose.
So the rose reference by the count a function have also increased by two instead of C one.
We simply need C three on.
Then we can copy a lot of this and paste it as the third argument about it function.
So all tender on based.
And the only change we need to make is that this now becomes total units and that completes
our if statement so old enter and the clothes in parenthesis.
So you can copy this down and then use it to generate this small version.
So first large become small.
Then we modify the cell reference.
So all our seas replaced by G's and finally so that we can have descending order we prefix
the count A function with 11 minus 11 minus one equals 10.
You copy it down.
You haven't minus two equals nine on so forth and we do that here as well and that's it.
We can then answer on copy this one down as well.
And now we need to use index and match to pick up the names of the clients,
so we need a very similar if structure to the one that we've just used.
We'll need exactly the same logical test,
checking to see what they use is chosen in cell a one which we've called total choice.
If they've chosen total spend,
then for value is true.
We use index and match in.
Next be in the outer function on our array is the clients.
That's what we're trying to look for to calculate the room number used match.
Look out.
Value is now in C four because we've got expert rows of the top.
So all is our first data road within our summary data on because the user has chosen total
spend,
I'll Look up Array is the total Spend Column,
and the match type is zero Bren exact MASH.
Let the user hasn't chosen total spend.
That means they've chosen total units,
so the value false.
We use index pulling back a client we met in the value in seed for,
but we're matching it in the Total Units column because as a result of the user's choice,
the formula in column hall will now be Eritrean units sold rather than total spend.
So to get the company name,
we can start my copying the first part of our if statement,
it's gonna be exactly the same.
There we go back into our summary version two.
You can use this convenient trick of building the formula in a convenient location,
copying our final version,
pressing the cancel button on,
then move in that code to its destination.
So here we need a lot Kenta on here,
we paste in the start about it.
This is the logical test part of the if statement and index becomes the value of truth.
So let's just invent it and then terminated with a comma.
Then we can copy the second arguments old enter and paste it as the third argument.
And of course,
the enemy changes.
If total sorties doesn't equal total spend,
it will equal total units.
And then the only other change is that si two will become C four.
Because,
of course,
on summary version three,
we've introduced two new rose at the top so that the user can make that choice so seem to
now becomes a sea pool on to finish out of statement.
Let's just do old enter and put the clothes in parentheses,
and when I pasted,
I managed to end up with two equal signs of Let's get rid of this extra one so we can can't
be all events.
So we built it here for convenience because it handsome,
useful code that we could use as a starting point.
But we've only been using it as a work area.
We don't actually want to change this cell.
So once we sure we've got that on the clipboard,
we can just press cancel.
No harm has been done to this cell,
but we now have on the clipboard the formula that we need for this cell.
So we just paste it in and it's good to go.
We can then copy that down and then paste another version in the bottom 10 section on.
The only change that we need to make here is that instead of reference in column C,
we now reference in column G so that to see falls need to be changed to G fools.
That's the only change I can see.
That's just test it on.
Help me down.
That completes version three of our summary this is the version that really had in mind or
this section.
I thought it might be useful to us to do it in three stages and introduce a bit more
complexity at each stage.