in this video will extend the basic array formula that we created in the last video by
making it conditional 07 right formulas that's open zero to using condition ALS in array
formulas.
So this is a far as we called in the last video.
We have an array formula which multiplies quantity by unit price and then returns the total
rural rose.
What we now want to do is to split this by both branch and product range.
So we want a matrix of conditional co tal's and each time we want to conditions satisfied,
the branch name and the product range name be to the branch name has to be Aberdeen on the
entry in product range has to be Jamia and so forth on the normal circumstances,
we would use some ifs,
but the problem here is that some ifs requires a reference to two ranges.
But some range on the criteria range,
and what we need to do is not to supply.
Arrange to supply a calculation which multiplies one array by another.
And that calculation is not an acceptable argument for the summits function.
So what we have to do instead is to find a way of using the calculation that we've
currently got,
but making it conditional so that as we go from row to row quantity,
times unit price will only apply when the two conditions are met.
When the bronze is what it should be on the product range is what it simply before we move
on to look at our formula,
let's create two more named Ranges.
We go across the formulas and click on name manager.
We can see the two names that we created in the last video quantity in unit price.
Let's go across the item sales,
and it's now adding the two criteria ranges that were interested in branch and range.
Now you remember we can't reference the entire column when we working with the Wraith
formulas,
we have to reference the individual cells.
So click on the one press control shit down,
and then we can use this convenient create from selection and use top row.
Then let's do the same range.
Cleveland.
I won control ship down,
create from selection,
so we now have four names that we can reference in our regular.
So we look into creative formula in Selby,
too,
which we can then copy to the right or all the other product ranges and copy down for all
the other branches on the bronze that applies to Selby to Is Aberdeen on the product range
is called Jamia,
so we want to have a formula which performs a logical test,
and we can do this by nest in an if statement,
the first parameter if is a course,
a logical test,
and we need to combine two tests.
We want to test every row in the brown Colin the branch array to see whether it matters the
value in cell eight to,
and we then want to perform a similar test on every road in the Range column to see whether
it matches the value and sell be one.
The normal way of combining two logical tests is to use the and function,
and then we have a logical test one a logical test,
too.
But unfortunately,
with our array formula,
this one work,
the problem is that the and function only returns true or holes,
and what we need to have is a logical test but returns an array of true or false values.
Se ro one is true.
We go ahead and multiply the quantity by the unit price.
Otherwise,
we put a zero.
And of course,
we know that the cell B two,
if we compare the branch and the range,
none of the 1st 4 items will return.
True because we don't have Aberdeen and Jamia as the combination.
And it's only when both of these are in play that we get a true So the formula in Selby,
too,
will return zero for the 1st 4 rows of the virtual array.
So the solution is to use exactly the same approach for the logical test that we used in
the last example,
multiplying one matrix by another.
The first Matrix is created by using the statement.
Brown equals a two.
Ron's applies to the entire Bronze column,
which is an array.
So if we compare an array to a single value and Excel will simply go through the array and
compare every row to that single value,
it will then create a virtual array in which every road contains either true or holes.
True,
of course,
equates to one and false equates to zero.
So we have one array with exactly the same size as the branch array the quantity array unit
price containing either true or false on every single run.
And then we do the same for the other evaluation we have.
The statement range equals B one on Excel will then compare value and be one to the value
in every row of the range column.
Wherever it finds a match,
it puts one wherever it doesn't put zero.
So we end up with two virtual tables,
all containing true or holes on every road,
and we simply multiply boasts to virtual arrays.
That gives us the final virtual array,
which itself would likely contain one or zero on every road.
Because,
of course,
only one multiplied by one true multiplied by true will give us the output one or true.
Any other combination will give us false.
So by taking this approach,
we end up with exactly what we need,
which is an array of true or false values.
And then Excel evaluates every road that array wherever it finds a one.
It goes ahead on that road to multiply the quantity by the unit price.
Wherever it finds a zero,
it simply puts zero in the result in a rain does he said.
The formula in Selby,
too,
will produce all zeros as the 1st 4 items in the result in virtual array.
And of course,
the final part of the puzzle is that the sum function returns the total of all the items in
our virtual array.
So that's the approach.
Let's now Bryant out formula.
So we want to write a formula,
and Selby,
too,
which we can then copy across and copy down.
So we'll need to think about the placement of dollar signs.
Let's begin by expanding on a formula bar.
So we doing equal some all kinds of and then we missed in the bunker.
And even though there's no further nesting,
I split the parameters on two separate lines for readability.
So old enter first argument is our logical test.
I say we want brunch equals Have a dean,
which is in a to on when we copy the formula across.
We don't want the A to change to a B to A C etcetera.
We wanted to stay as a but when we copy down,
we do want the to to change to a 34 etcetera.
So we just press at all until we have a dollar in front of the A and then we'll multiply in
that test by the test range equals 31 And this time it's the reverse.
When we copy across,
we do want the letters that change when we copy down.
We don't want the road number to change,
so we need B dollar one.
Then we've got to think about operator precedence.
So what Excel will do is to evaluate this multiplication first.
And of course,
what we wanted to do is to evaluate branch equals a two evaluates range,
equals B one and then multiply the to result in the rays.
So we'll need parentheses around both of these tests.
Comma to end The first argument value it true will be the calculation that we saw in the
previous video Bold enter,
which was,
of course,
quantity multiplied by unit price,
coma or pencil on the value false is simply zero or cancer.
The closing parenthesis to the if old answer on the closing parenthesis for some and then
very importantly,
we don't presenter.
We press CSE control shift enter.
So now,
because of our strategic placement of dollar signs,
we can go ahead and call me to the right and then double click to Kobe down