So far in this section,
we've looked at a rate formulas which perform operations on the raise,
such a multiplication and concatenation.
Let's now move on to look at another type of every Formula One that uses an array function
.
We'll start by looking at the table function 07 or eight formulas that's open 04 ray
formulas and data tables.
A data table is a special Excel construct,
not to be confused with pivot tables or Excel tables,
which live in the insert tam.
There's nothing to do with pivots,
nothing to do with tables,
data tables he used in what if analysis.
They allow you to create a matrix of possible values when you're doing projections or
looking at best and worst case scenarios.
So in this example,
we're doing that projection to calculate gross profit for the year,
and we've got 3/4 of actual information,
and then we have some budget information or quarter for,
and we want to use our data table to give us a bit more flexibility to look at a range of
possible profit values.
The way that the data table works is that you have to follow a certain structure in the top
left of the table.
You must have a formula and then below the cells that contain the formula.
You can put a range of substitute values.
These values can be substituted for any cell referenced by the formula,
either directly or indirectly have very birth to as the road input values and then
optionally on the right of the cell that contains the formula.
You can put a second set of substitute values,
and these refer to as the column input values.
And again they can act as substitutes that any single fell referenced directly or
indirectly buying the formula.
So in this example,
the two variables that we're using is the number of days boot for our banquet.
Swedes and the number of days boot her out conference weeds the really input values with
actor substitutes for the banquet.
Sweet Days on the column.
Input values well,
actor substitutes for the conference suite bookings.
And to add a bit of flexibility to the model,
we allow the user to change the stunt in value for both the column and road input values.
So if we want to be pessimistic,
we could say go from 60 for the conference suite.
Bookings on.
We've simply got a formula in here which says on one,
as you go to the rights and again,
if we being very pessimistic,
we can say what he found.
Banquet suite bookings are also quite low,
and if you want to be optimistic,
weaken started 70 80.
So those are the variables that we're working with.
Let's now look at now.
Excel implements the rape formula.
First of all,
you select the entire matrix.
The top left of your selection will always be the cell that contains the formula.
If you're using row input,
only,
then you'll have a matrix of cells,
which is one column white.
And obviously,
in our case,
we use in both row input values and Colin input values.
So in selecting the entire Matrix and then you don't actually type any formulas the command
that you need lives in the data town and it's in the forecast group.
You click on what if analysis and shoes data table and then all you need to specify is
which cells are being substituted begin by special.
If I in this cell,
which your row input values the values arranged in rows are going to be substitutes for.
So,
as we've said there substitutes for our banquet suite bookings if he's on road to and cause
a ball so e to And then we specify the cell for which the values we've got arranged in
Collins with actors a substitute.
And in this case,
it's the conference suite Bookings.
I'm not saying 85 and that's all that Excel needs to know when you click.
OK,
it populates the table,
and it does so by using a single formula.
So when you click on any cell within that matrix,
you'll see exactly the same formula displayed,
and it uses the table function.
So here we've got an optimistic matrix,
and then we could go in change the start in values two medium figure out or to a
pessimistic figure,
and that single array formula updates the entire table