Let's move on to look at another array function this time one that you can use yourself
rather than one that's created automatically for you.
07 Array formulas.
That's 705 transpose function.
The transpose operation simply means to change the orientation of your data.
So,
for example,
if we have the days of the week in this orientation,
we can can't be.
And when we paste,
we can transpose.
So that's the transposed operation.
The transpose function,
by contrast,
enables you to achieve this switch in orientation in a dynamic fashion.
And it's particularly useful when you're summarising data,
and it's more convenient to see the summarized data in the opposite orientation to the
original data.
So in this example,
we look at daily sales.
Let's say in our summary work seat,
we simply want to keep track of the total for each branch,
and that's displayed at the bottom of the table using the total row.
So if you haven't used this before in table tools design,
we'll see there's an option here for Total Road.
When that switched on,
Excel allows you to automatically aggregate each of the columns so all we want in our
summary is the headings and the total road,
but the convenience.
We want them in columns.
So the first thing we need to do is to measure the Matrix so you don't highlight from a one
t.
J.
One very conveniently in the name box.
Excel is blazed by mentions of my current selection so we can see it one row by 10 Collins
.
And to use the transpose function,
you simply select the Matrix,
which has the opposite.
I mention in this case,
let's do headings.
First you need to select the Matrix,
which is 10 rose by one column.
So,
as you can see,
like the table function,
which we saw in the last video,
the transpose function is a function that populates multiple cells simultaneously that this
function you enter manually.
There's no command which generates it.
As we saw in the table function,
they simply equals transpose.
And then you specify the array,
which you want to transpose within the currently selected cells.
So you go across the daily sales and we selectable that the head is,
and you probably know that you don't need to put a close in parenthesis when you only have
a single function in your formula.
But what we need to do is to make sure that we press CSE control,
shift and enter.
So we now have a dynamically transposed version off the original data.
So let's say for some reason we wanted to abbreviate the headings,
it would change Birmingham to be apostrophe.
Um,
when we go back to the summary,
of course,
we'll see the updated version there.
But now let's do the same for the totals.
So I'm including the heading in.
My selection equals transfers,
and we strolled bottom and drank across all of the total cells.
So you always have to make sure that the range that you specify is the exact opposite.
In terms of rows and columns or the selected range,
you're transposed formula and then ask before we make sure that we press control ship enter
.
So we've got a summarized version off the table,
and just to emphasize that it's dynamic,
we go across the more data.
Select all the data here,
missing out the headings,
of course,
so controls it writes.
Control it down,
copy all of that data and paste it into the table.
We just need to click in the bottom.
Later sell just about the total road press the tab key,
and that creates a blank grow into which we can then paste.
And I should have done that before the copy because I've now canceled the copy.
Soccer go back could be again and then based into my blank right.
Of course,
when we come back to our summary,
we have the new updated total.
That's all there is to the transposed function.
Very simple,
but sometimes very convenient feature.