Microsoft excels.
Web service function is used to get an external response from a Web service.
A Web service is an application designed to deliver a particular type of information to any
client who requested when the request is made.
Parameter values are normally supply,
which determine the result generated.
It's very similar to simply visit in a Web U R L and having a Web application which
supplies content to you.
The big difference is that a Web service is designed to supply content not to humans,
but to another application.
So in this case,
that other application is excel on.
The mechanism that we're using is the Web service function.
We specify the Earl of the Web service application,
and normally that girl has embedded in it.
One mobile parameters on the Web service as a result of the request,
produces an XML response and then delivers that into the cell,
which contains the Web service function.
Web services can deliver other types of content apart from XML.
But in the case of Microsoft Excel,
XML is the only response which is understood.
So in using excels Web service function,
you can only work with Web services capable of producing an XML response.
So let's take an example in the training folder will now working in zero for Web service
filled,
exhale exposed.
And that's going to fold one using the Web service function.
Now let's examine our example international pricing that's open that.
And in this example,
we have a series of prices using GDP as the base currency.
We want to be able to translate those prices into all of these different currencies,
using up to date conversion rates.
So what we want to do with the Web service function is defined a Web service which will
give us the conversion rate from GBP.
$2 euros,
Canadian dollars,
etcetera.
So let's now return to the training folder.
And if you open up the text vocal Wandell software for this demonstration,
we're going to use Mondor dot walk as our Web service supplier.
And the reason to do in this is that they have a 14 day triable service,
which allows you to make a limited number of requests to their Web service.
So the first thing we'll need to do is to sign up,
so just copy this sign up.
You are L and Paste it into your browser using paste and go and then just fill out the
information and click on request demo key now.
And if all is well,
within a few minutes,
you should receive an email like this one which contains an A p I key.
So I'm just gonna copy this a p i and paste it into note pad so that would just need to
know the u r L that we need to access when we use in Excels Web service function.
So we go across to the website,
click on the link on the left here,
currency exchange rates,
XML Web service and then just click on this web ap I access link on the first.
You are role that we see here gives us all the information that we need and it gives us a
breakdown of the six components to that You are l on.
What we have to remember basically is that the base currency comes first.
So in our example,
obviously the base currency will be UK price.
Then comes the target currency and then components five and six.
You'll notice that both optional So in our case it will simply omit them the amount of
convert defaults toe one and the date of conversion defaults to the current date.
So that's exactly what we want.
So we can just copy the first part of the URL admitting the last two sections.
I'll just face that here as well.
That and save my changes.
So now we're ready to use the Web service function in Excel.
Let's start with USD.
I have the u.
R l still on the clipboard,
so I can just tie equals Web service and the girl is a string.
So it has to go in double quotes,
double quotes,
and I can just paste it in close quotes,
close brackets and presenter.
And of course,
the thing that I forgot to do was to put in my keys.
I left this sort of default key in there.
I obviously need to replace that with the A p I key that they supply to me.
So let's just go back on,
grab that,
just paste it in here.
It's now we should be good to go and we have a price.
Let me just widen this soul so that we can see the result on then see what we need to do
before we can actually use this value so we can see that in this case the Web service
actually returns the value that we want.
The only problem is that the value is quoted.
So all we need to do to get our calculations to work is to remove the quotation marks on.
We can do that using excels,
substitute function.
So around our Web service,
let's put the substitute function and use that to remove the double quotes so equal
substitute.
The Web service function is the first argument.
In other words,
the text.
We put a comma at the end.
Now we supply the old text in other words,
the text we want to remove and that text has to go in double quotes.
Which raises the question.
How do you put double quotes inside double quotes?
I don't know if you've ever had to do this,
but basically you double up.
So you put two double quotes to represent double close.
Hence we put open quotation marks,
two double quotes,
close quotation marks,
so four double quotes in total coma.
What do we want to replace them with?
Nothing.
So we simply put open and close double quotes to indicate the mold stream close brackets.
And,
as you can see once the quotation marks have gone even though,
strictly speaking,
we still have a text value because the text value consists of numbers only Excel
automatically converted to a numeric value and uses it to perform the calculation.
So I'm just gonna reinstate the Marrow column with so you can see all the different
currency rates.
And then the final thing we need to do is to modify the default formula.
So it's not using euro and us deep,
but it's using G V P as the source and then picking up the conversion currency from the
cell above the cell containing the formula.
Simple way of doing that is to festival,
delete euro and replace it with GBP.
Then we delete USD.
But this time we need to replace USD with the contents of this cell above the cell
containing the formula.
So to do that,
we close quotation marks,
then put an empress end but can cast a nation and click on the cell above which in this
case is J two,
so that picks up the currency in that cell Then we put another empress end and then open
quotation marks.
So you just insert in that variable string into the URL.
So when we press enter,
our calculation should now actually be the correct one.
And what we now do is just to copy that formula.
It's of the rights,
and because there are no dollar signs were always picking up whatever currency is in the
cell above the cell that contains our formula.
So that's an example of using excels Web service function.
And on this occasion,
the result that was produced was,
in fact,
the result that we needed.
In most cases,
however,
the Web service function returns an XML document containing a hierarchy of elements and
attributes,
and you then need to use a second function,
filter XML to navigate within that structure and extract the data that you need.
So in the next video,
we'll move on to look at working with the Filter XML function