in this video will move on to look at the other two functions,
which are available when you're working with acceptable in Excel,
filter XML and encode U R L So in zero fall Web service Filter XML the next part that's now
going to number three years in built XML and encode u R l To see how these two functions
work,
we're going to be using a Web service from a free website called Geo Names or Award.
Let's begin by opening up geo names dot txt And here we've got all the information that we
need to work with this free site,
and the first thing that you'll need to do is to sign up for a free account.
Has the U.
R L,
which you can do this.
So let's just copy that you are.
L just move into your favorite browser and use the paste and go feature to get to that you
are l.
So the first time you visit the website,
we'll need to create a new user account.
Just choose a user name.
No space is allowed,
and then just put your email,
confirm your email,
choose a password and confirm your password and then go ahead and create an account,
and the confirmation email will be sent through to the email address that you supplied.
The email will look something like this,
and it will include an activation link so you simply click on the activation link to
activate your account.
Once he validated,
your account will automatically be logged in and thereafter.
Future.
You obviously can just click on the log in button,
put in your credentials and log in.
And then there's just one final step you need to perform on.
That is to going to manage account,
and you get to that by clicking on your user name in the top,
right,
you'll see you've got the two wings there.
Want the logging out on the other,
which consists off your user name is the managed account link.
So you click on that,
and here you have the opportunity to change your user email and to change your password.
The thing that's most important for our purposes is to be able to use the free Web services
,
and to do that,
you have to click on this link at the bottom,
says you can see it,
says the account is not yet enabled to use three Web services.
Click here to enable,
So we click on that and then we good to go.
So from now on,
we can use that free Web services.
There is a limit as to how many requests you can send that day,
but beyond that,
it's all free.
So we now click on Web service.
A Van Web service overview.
These were all the different Web services.
And of course,
the XML column is the one that we're interested in.
Because Excel doesn't offer an option to use Jason,
it only uses XML using the Web service function that we've seen.
So the Web service that we're interested in using it's postal code search,
which is you can see,
is available in both XML and Jason.
So let's click on that.
And here we have all the possible parameters that you can use with this Web service,
and if we go to the bottom,
we can find an example which we can use in Excel with the Web service function.
So that's just coping that,
and I'll add that to the text file.
And,
of course,
when using this girl,
you simply need to replace that user name demo with the user name that you chose when you
signed up to this service.
And,
of course,
the other thing will need to change is this.
We want to have different postal codes when we actually use this facility.
So let's leave the text file.
It's no open up the Excel file.
We're working with postal codes.
Example,
and inside it you'll find hotel information.
So you've got the address of each hotel and then the rating,
the average rating given by our start members.
And let's say to completely solution,
we need tohave the latitude and longitude off each of these hotels,
and we're going to use a Web service to obtain this information.
Select at three new columns.
The first will contain the XML that we retreat from the Web service.
Then we want the latitude,
longitude and it's copied formats.
The logic of having a separate column for the XML is that both the latitude and longitude
can then be extracted from that one cell instead of embedding to Web service calls in each
of these two columns,
and this way of working becomes quite important.
If you're paying for every single call that you make to a given Web service.
So now let's put the Web service function equals Web service.
And as he saw in a previous video,
the only parameter is the URL,
which is a string on which we can just can't be from text file.
And before we do that,
I'm just gonna change the maximum number of rows toe one.
We don't really need that much detail,
since we're only interested in the latitude and longitude.
So we called you all of that,
paste it in,
and then we need to make a couple of changes.
First of all,
the postal code that we're looking up is the postal code from cell F two.
So we need to tag on to.
And this is where we use encode.
U R l What it does,
basically,
is to take your data on converted into a format which is Earl Legal.
In other words,
any characters which were illegal in a URL will be converted to their equivalents.
So,
for example,
spaces will be converted to percentage 20 so just not enough to we closed quotes,
then use ampersand.
Then we use encode u R L click on it to close parentheses to end the function.
Now we need another ampersand on.
We reopen the quotation marks,
So the whole thing looks rather strange because,
of course,
we can an M percent inside this string.
But as you probably know,
1% a very common in you RL's where you're supplying parameter values.
Then,
of course,
the other change we need to make is to replace Demo with our user name.
Let me close quotes,
close parentheses and we're done.
We can then copy that formula down and each of the cells in column h will now contain a
slightly different XML document.
What I always like to do at this point is to copy one of these XML documents into a text
file so we can take a good look at the external structure.
So let's go back into the folder and create a text document,
and it's just rename it results dot xml.
Yes,
we do want to change the fine extension,
and then we can just open it and paste in our XML.
So here's our X terminal document.
We can lose the double quotes so you can see we have a Roose element of geo names.
And then it's got to child elements,
total result,
count and code.
So let's just select all of these and tap them in,
and then code has child elements that contain the data that we actually want.
So again,
let's just tap those in on the two bits of information we want their Agassi lacked on LNG.
So in terms of our experts statement,
we're gonna have three locations steps g,
other names code and then l a T or L N dri.
And in each case,
we maybe along the default child access so they can from parent to child each time.
So that's saved this document.
And now let's get back to excel so we can hide column H That's Desprez escaped to coming
out a copy mode and then create a formula.
So we've got equals Filter XML.
The first parameter is the XML,
which is in our hidden cell H two on the second parameter is our expert statement which
goes inside double quotes.
For an absolute experts statement,
you always start with a forward slash,
which represents the root of the XML file and then you put your location steps so first,
as we said,
was geo names.
Then we had code and then the latitude is L.
A T close quotes clothes for embassies on.
We can just copy this entire formula because the longitude is virtually the same.
So let's just paste it in for longitude a man change L A t soup LNG and we could to get So
we can now coffee this formula down for every road on because basically,
you know,
hidden call him.
We return in a slightly different XML result on each road,
the experts statement is retrieving a different value each time.
So that's our first look at using expert statements with the filter XML function on.
Just remind you,
we have these three locations steps in each case we use in two off the three possible
components we use in the access on the no test.
We're not using the optional predicated.
It will come to that later.
And as I said,
because the child access is the default,
it's normally admitted.
So if you did want to write it in,
it would be child colon,
colon in each of these three cases,
so we'll see you get exactly the same result.
But if course because child is the default axis,
it's always omitted.
So let's just undo.
Although the Filter XML function is normally used in conjunction with the Web service
function,
it's also possible to use it on local XML files.
I will take a look at doing just that in the next video.