let's now move on to look at nested.
If statements what would be doing in this example?
It's a sign in a status to each of the accounts listed in this worksheet,
and these are the criteria that will be using.
I should just explain one quirk that you'll notice in this streak.
The days overdue column contains static values on the date.
Do Kahlan contains a calculation to display that they do.
And obviously,
in a really scenario,
the reverse would be true.
We would have static values here,
which indicated when the account was due and then would have a calculation here to work out
how many days do each account waas.
So just to explain,
I've done that for training purposes so that we can both have exactly the same thing on our
screens.
So to calculate the status we're going to use these criteria 120 days or greater status is
bad.
Mind your greater aged on DSO four.
When you use invested of statements to test numerical values,
it's always best to start with the highest value.
Work your way down to the low study.
This means that you don't need compound testing.
Don't need to say between 1920 between 60 and 90 etcetera.
The reason for this is the way that Excel will evaluate the X statements.
So we take the first road as an example.
We've got days over.
You have 20 by eliminating the highest value with our first test,
what we come to do our second test.
We know that the value is less than 120 because if it weren't,
the second test would never even take place.
That we need to test for each time is the next one down.
Our test will simply to say great to them.
Regal to it will never need to say both.
Greater panel recall two and less than so before we go ahead and write the formula,
let's have a brief discussion of how invested its work in Excel when they hear the term
nice two days,
a lot of people will visualize a structure whereby you have one if statement with several.
If statements nested inside that one if and this is not actually the case,
this isn't how it works.
A better way of visualize invested ifs is to think of a Russian doll arrangement whereby
each if statement is nested inside the previous one.
So going back to our days overdue example.
Let's say that we have a cell that contains 20 days overdue.
Let's just run that career unless they've structure.
So we start without outta if the one that contains all the others.
And like all if statements,
it has its street reminisces for the logical test for the outer if is gonna be days overdue
,
greater than or equal to 120 on the value of true will be the word bad that clearly our
cell contains 20 so that's gonna be evaluated to falls.
But instead of having a literal value,
people's we need to do some further testing.
So the value of falls is supplied by another,
if statement.
And so we have a statement to nested inside if statement one via the value of false
parameter.
So if statement to becomes the value of false parameter off if statement one.
And that's how the structure works on our second if statement were tested to see if the
days overdue is greater than or equal to 90 and if it were,
we put the word aged into the cell since 20 isn't greater than or equal to 90.
We need the value it false and again that is supplied by another,
if statement.
So we move on to its statement.
Number three,
which test to see the value of you is greater than or equal to 60.
If it were,
it would put the word of the do that.
Since it's not,
we go to Value Falls,
which is supplied by the final if statement on the final or innermost.
If statement,
we test to see what these over here is greater than or equal to 30.
If it were,
we would supply the man do.
But since it's not,
and since we've done along the testing that we want,
we supply the value,
not do the literal value,
so you can see that it's only the in the most.
If that has a literal value for value falls.
In the case of all of the other ifs,
the value of falls is being calculated by another nested it statement.
So now let's move back to excel and create the formula.
So we're in the status column e to let's increase the size on hold,
and then we'll split the formula into multiple lines.
We start with the outer if statement,
and we're testing the highest value.
The Selva testing is D to on the highest value is 120 the greater than or equal to 120 coma
.
And then,
as Excel is prompting us here we're onto the value is true.
If true,
we want the word bad to appear in the self on because that's text.
It does,
of course,
have to go in double quotes.
So now we come to 1/3 parameter value in bowls,
and this is where we implement our nested if structure,
instead of putting a literal value for the value false.
We put another it function.
Let's put that on a new line.
Old enter for a new line Tremendous hit the space bar to move along underneath the first
argument.
So now we need another If and again we're testing D to.
So what I'll do is to just copy this first test and then we can use that as our starting
point.
Each time I'll do all my paste in now old enter on old enter.
So just explain why I've done that.
We're testing or values 1 2090 60 on 30.
So we're now need to do is to train these values and then change the status associated with
each one so aged.
What do you and not do?
So,
Having eliminated 1 2090 60 and 30 we now know that if none of these proved to be true,
the status needs to be not do so.
We don't need any further test in.
We can finally supply a literal value.
The value balls value falls has been supplied each time that it's been supplied by another
,
if statement.
So within this structure,
each of the statements has as its third argument,
value it false.
Another if statement.
And it's only the innermost statement that has a literal value as it's patently false.
So let's put this on the new line as well.
Or Cantor space bar across men in double quotes you need not do.
Let's have finished the formula.
We've used four if statements and put in opening parenthesis after each one.
We therefore now need all match in closing parentheses to finish the Formula 1234 and we
don't let's restore the normal height.
That formula bar and just copy before then.
They're down by move into the also feel handle and double click in.
That's how nested ifs work.
If you're struggling to understand them,
just think of Russian dolls.
Lester.
That's can be quite complex and convoluted.
So in the next two videos,
what discuss alternatives to use in the next city of structure?