in the interest of security.
Microsoft Excel regards any file in which you placed BB a code as a potential security risk
.
So,
for example,
or we're going to fold in nine and then open up the workbook that we used in the last video
.
03 Excel automatically displays a security warning and disables the content.
Naturally,
you can click on enable content and everything works fine.
This feature is obviously quite useful,
and it's in our best interests.
But when you're doing any kind of BB a development,
you don't really need tohave files that you've created.
Treated with any suspicion,
A good way of achieving the right balance is toe.
Add the folders in which you're doing development to your trusted locations.
As always,
everything related to the B B A is in the developer town and in the code section.
On the left,
you'll find the macro security button,
and this command takes you into the trust center settings on these settings for part of
Excel options.
So we cancel.
We can get to the same location simply by going to file options.
Then,
on the left,
we click on trust center and on the right you'll see a button marked trust center settings
,
so clicking on that button is exactly the same as clicking on the macro security button in
the developer tab.
While it's possible you can see to set global settings,
it's more convenient to use trusted locations because this allows you to be more selective
.
So on the left we choose trusted locations,
and then we add any older locations in which we do in VB a development to our trusted
locations.
It's on the right.
You'll see a button marked at a new location,
and this enables you to browse to any location that contains the B A that your develop it
that's going to the desktop.
And here I've got the training folder.
I opened the outer folder and add that to my trusted locations.
And then,
very importantly,
before clicking OK,
I also activate the option.
Sub folds of this location are also trusted.
Then I click OK,
and from now on,
any code files within that folder that I open won't trigger excels normal security warning
message.
I can click.
OK,
okay,
again close without saving.
And then when I reopened the file because the file is in my trusted locations,
it doesn't trigger the security warning message