we've now reached section 10 of the course,
so let's go into this section 10 older on what would be doing in this section is to look
more closely at the key aspects of right in the B A code.
Let's begin by discussing the first thing that you're gonna need to get to grips with,
which is B B A syntax.
So let's open up 01 BBs in tax,
which is a Pdf file.
And if lightly your PdF so open with Adobe Acrobat,
you can just catch a view Bull Street mode.
Well,
press control L.
BB is a fully fledged programming language,
and it has a series of features which are common to all programming languages.
This table is the key syntactical elements of B B A.
And as we encounter these elements in our code,
I'll keep referring back to this chart.
I'll recommend that you do is saying each line of code that you write in B B A will fall
into one of these categories.
Now we've obviously just stomach did so we haven't really done very much,
but let's look at the features that we have encountered so far.
Festival.
We've encountered procedure declaration that's just come out of full screen mode for a
moment by pressing Escape and go back into the train in Boulder.
Hold on nine and 03 We wrote our first user defined function that we're going to The
developments happened.
Click on visual Basic.
This basically is a procedure declaration,
and it remember we went insert procedure and then chose the type of procedure which was
function.
So the two lines of code relating to procedure declaration that we've encountered and which
,
applying to the creation of user defined functions,
this line,
public function,
name of function,
her embassies containing optional arguments and then a declaration of the type of value
produced by the function using the ask he were.
And then the other line that relates to procedure Declaration is,
of course,
the end function,
which indicates the termination of that particular function.
Because,
of course,
there's nothing to stop you put in other macros and other functions within this same model
.
We also encountered comments,
comments or simply lines of code,
which you insert a clarification both for your own benefits and for the benefit of anyone
else looking at your code as well as placing comments on their own line.
You can also place a comment at the end of the line.
So here,
for example,
I can just hit the space bar.
But in apostrophe,
which remember,
is the signal for a comment.
And then I can simply say procedure declaration.
When I move away from the line,
Excel will change the color of the comment,
which is quite useful.
It makes them stand out another nice feature,
by the ways,
when you've got toe a lot of code,
and when you're debugging when something's not working,
you can simply highlight a line of code.
If you remember,
these two lines are treated as one line because they got the space.
Underscore the continuation character At the end of the first line,
I can highlight any line or lines of code on.
Then,
in the editing toolbar,
which is here,
I just remind you,
the old school method.
If the editing toolbar weren't visible,
just right click into edit to make it visible.
Well,
that's a view to bars on Giuseppe from there.
So on the Edit toolbar has this feature called a comment look.
So if I highlight some lines of code and click on comment block that effectively disables
those lines of code so I can focus on something else.
And then when I want them back again,
obviously next door has the uncommon command.
The other thing we've seen is assignment off data value,
and that's indicated by the keyword less.
As I've said,
Let is actually optional so most people admitted.
But it's useful when you'll learn inmediato.
Always use it so that you remind yourself off what's taken place on that particular line of
code.
So the assignment of a data value means that on objects,
which is essentially a container for ordinary data which means text or string base numbers
,
these are ordinary pieces of data as opposed to excel objects such as worksheets,
cell ranges,
etcetera.
So the ASIC nation of a data value involves place in the appropriate type of value into
that container.
So in this case,
the container is the function itself.
But the function is essentially a string simply by sane after the function name as a string
.
We're saying that the sole purpose in life of this function is to produce a piece of text,
a string.
So what we did on this line is a signing the string,
which is on the right hand side of the equal sign to the object or container,
which is on the left of the equal side.
And that's the way that the assignments operation always works.
Whatever is on the right of the hole is being placed inside whatever is on the left of the
equal sign.
So let's put one more comment into that effect.
Apostrophe assignment or days of value and then in print diseases weaken,
say string.
So the key thing to remember is what I mean by data is the kind of thing that can actually
go inside and excel Cell a date number piece of text on the big contrast that you've got to
get used to when your programming in B B.
A is the distinction between these ordinary pieces of data on references to excel objects.
So whenever you're working with ordinary pieces of data used,
the key word let and as we'll see later,
when you come to work with references to excel objects such as worksheets and workbooks,
you use the opposite keyword set.
That's a far as we've got without look at B B A syntax.
We've just started to scratch the surface,
but as I said,
I will keep coming back to this chart so that we can just keep track off the different
syntactical elements that you need to get used to.