as you write your BB a functions you'll need to manipulate different aspects of Excel on
Excel elements.
The Excel Object model is the term or the hierarchy that Microsoft have created,
which represents Excel and all things excel.
So key aspect of this Intacs that you'll need to learn is how to reference different parts
of the Microsoft Excel structure.
This diagram is far from complete.
It represents only the key aspects.
The key elements within the Excel hierarchy on also bear in mind that there are certain
elements which you can't access when you're right in user defined functions,
these elements can only be automated,
so when you write macros,
you can refer to them.
You can't,
for example,
right.
A user defined function,
which uses excels speech capability to talk to the user.
That can only be done by writing a macro as we manipulate Excel elements or come back to
this diagram and just point out different aspects of the hierarchy that were actually
manipulated.
So in order to get used to the syntax that you use when you work with the Excel object
model,
let's just briefly discuss four of the elements in this diagram complication Workbooks This
workbook Onda workbook.
As you can imagine,
application represents Microsoft Excel itself.
It's whenever you're working with settings,
which are essentially excel settings rather than attributes pertaining to a particular
workbook or a particular work seat.
We'll be working with the application object.
Let's have a look at some of the syntax that applies to the application object.
Let's go to the developer tab on visual.
Basic visual.
Basic Editor includes a very detailed reference to excel,
maybe a.
But you can access my feelings of you in choosing Object browser.
And here you can find a list of all the components that make up the Excel object model in
the top left.
Prince has all libraries.
We can restrict our list into excel and let's find application.
But I highlight application the members off the application object displayed on the right.
That basically means all the other elements within the Excel object model that apart off
the application object and there are two key types of elements.
But first,
let's have the green icon our methods,
which are essentially functions,
and for the most part,
when you're writing user defined functions,
you don't really access them these operations.
So if you're right in Mac Rose,
you want to close files,
open files,
print documents and so forth.
These are all methods or actions that you can perform on these objects.
The type of member that you focus on when you're writing user defined functions is really
properties.
These are the attributes off the elements.
So,
for example,
if we scroll down,
we have calculation.
That's the current set in within Excel As to whether calculation is manual or automatic.
When I click on calculation on the bottom of the screen,
you'll see a brief description is displayed.
If I want a more detailed description,
I just click on the help button.
And here you're given a description of the calculate property,
handsome examples of its usage and at the bottom of the screen.
We have a brief description on also useful links if we click on the link that says Excel
calculation were taken to a list of all the permissible values.
So this is a constant.
So we used to represent the settings that air access to the interface,
automatic manual or semi automatic,
another tool that's quite useful when you're experimenting with the Excel object model is
the immediate window.
To get to this,
you get a new choose immediate window on in this window,
you can type a line of code and their two styles in line that you can write.
One is where you simply want to get an answer to a question.
So,
for example,
we might want to check What is the current calculation set in within Microsoft Excel.
But that style of line You start with a question mark,
and then you just write a line of code and presente so we would write application,
not calculation.
Now,
when we present,
we get a constant and if I close this window for a moment,
but I click on these.
If you look at the bottom of the screen,
you'll see the actual constant that's represented by each of these.
So the minus 4105 If we can see represents automatic,
it would move onto wet books.
Workbooks simply represents the collection of files,
which you currently have open in Excel.
As soon as you close a file its top speed in the workbooks collection on when you open a
file.
The workbooks collection increases by one so if we type application,
don't work.
Bookstop count.
When I press enter,
I have to the file that was created automatically for me when I open Excel and the personal
workbook,
which is currently open.
And that kind of says one,
if I want to reference a particular workbook in parentheses after the word workbooks,
I can either put the name of the workbook or it's positional number.
So the personal workbook,
because it's integral to excel if it's open,
it will always have a number of one say bye,
puts one in parentheses and then use the property.
Don't name.
When I press enter,
the name of the personal work is displayed.
So when we reference a workbook in this way by place in either a name or a number in the
parentheses,
we are referencing a workbook object.
So to get to a workbook object,
you dive into the workbooks collection and pick out a single one that gives you the
workbook object as well as reference in individual workbooks.
You can also use application,
not this workbook on what this means is the workbook that contains your BB,
a code so here,
instead of access in a particular workbook.
Weaken,
say dot this workbook Full name on.
When we press enter,
we can see it's called Book one,
which is the default name of the workbook that Excel creates when you first want to the
program and will be used in this workbook very shortly in our code.
So those are the two tools in Excel that you can use to just navigate on.
Learn about the Excel object model.
Let's just close these down for the moment.
And as I said,
we'll come back to this diagram as we encounter different aspects of the Excel object model
.