as well as the Excel object.
Model B B A itself provides a lot of syntax.
Buyer The BB A object model,
The V B A object model consists of a series of useful functions divided into different
classifications.
A lot of these functions relate to the manipulation of data,
and they directly equivalent to some of excels.
Work three functions.
So,
for example,
most of the functions in the strings classification are equivalent to excel text functions
,
and similarly,
we have data time,
miss information.
So these are all useful things that you conduce to manipulate data,
many of which are equivalent to the familiar territory of using Excel functions.
So let's take just one example off using a BB A function.
Let's go back into the previous folder,
number nine,
and open up the first user defined function that we rose.
And if you remember this,
simply insert a piece of text.
Let's say that we prefer to split this text onto two lines so it's displayed in a large
cell.
Let's make this a larger,
and the cell has wrapped text activated.
So let's say we want copyright City smart limited,
then a return,
and the rest of the statement.
So that's going to developer on visual basic on before we actually modify the function.
Let me just point out that the Object browser,
which we saw earlier,
can also be used to check BB a syntax.
So let's go back into view object browser and then choose the V B A library.
So here we've got the different classes that we saw earlier on the one we're going to use
his constants.
Now we've got the VCR,
carrot return,
BBC RLF carriage return line feed on VB LF line feed.
And obviously,
in the context of a cell,
there's no difference.
If you exported the text and opened it in a word processor,
then carried return line feed will always to give you a paragraph.
Where's the other two will give you a line break.
So all we want to do here is to split this text,
so I'm gonna speak it now onto three lines.
So let's terminate the string here,
put an ampersand space on the school to split the line,
create a new line and then reopen the quotation marks.
So although we've got three physical lines,
we have one logical line of code on what we now want to do is after this statement to
insert a line feed so we can just click here until I m percent.
And when you type in BB A functions,
a useful thing is to type the function longhand.
So it stands out,
becomes very conspicuous whenever you look at it.
You know that V be a function has been used at that point.
So we would type B B a dots and then the intel a sense this auto completion pops up and
gives us a lot of different baby A functions if you remember when looking inside the
constants class and when we took the second dot we get all the different options.
So I'm just gonna use V b l f A line feed,
and that's it.
So,
having updated out function,
if I just add in the cell and you'll see our line feed character kicks in and splits the
string onto two lives.
So he now looked at the three different parts of the V B.
A syntax puzzle.
We have BB a syntax structures such as if statements,
loops,
etcetera.
Then we have the Excel object mobile,
and then we have the V b a object model.
So as we go through the course,
I'll just keep coming back to those three themes,
so hopefully you'll have a good idea of what's being contributed by each of these three
aspects.