Let's get some more practice on writing user defined functions.
So we're working in number 10.
Unless in open up number four displaying the user name in this example,
we want to create a kind of welcome page,
similar to what you see when you're logged in on a particular website.
We want to display and sell a one a message to the effect.
Use the name logged in as log in name,
for example.
John Smith logged in as Jay Don't Smith on For this.
We're going to use two pieces of information.
The Excel Log in name on the windows,
looking they to get the Excel log in name manually.
We can goes a file options and in the general category,
the first category.
Whatever entry is in,
user name becomes your Excel user name in terms of syntax.
Anything Excel related is part of the Excel Object model and anything that refers to excel
itself.
It's part of the application object,
so we know it's going to be application docked something on.
There are no prizes for guessing that it's actually application.
Don't use the name to pick up the windows log in name.
We use the V B,
a object model and in the interaction class we can use in Vyron,
which obviously sure for environment.
This provides a number of different insights into the user system and environment.
User name will give us the windows Look on me.
That's right.
Our function in developer.
We've taken visual basic to bring up the visual basic editor.
And if,
like me,
your personal workbook is visible,
just ignore it because we'll be right in this function in the workbook itself.
So it was right.
Click on the workbook and choose insert module.
And then let's bring up the properties window View Properties Window and renamed the new
model and then call it and use that interaction bends right.
The function.
Obviously we've got a click in the code window.
Man inserts procedure,
time function name that's called it.
Use a greeting,
but we see no space is allowed.
That's the Selivanov function.
It doesn't need any parameters,
but we do need to specify the type of data that the function will produce,
and this is going to be string,
so we put as string after the parentheses.
Now let's look at another feature of V B a and a programming in general,
which is the use of variables.
Use variables wherever you want to capture and track a piece of data,
or create a reference to an Excel object,
which you can then manipulated in your will.
So in this function we want to capture the person's Excel user name and their log on name
into separate variables.
The variables are simply named areas of memory,
which store either data well references to excel objects.
So in terms of syntax,
we're now going to discuss variable declaration to declare a variable used the key word dim
,
which is short that I mentioned.
You then create a name for the variable,
which describes its use.
Additionally,
it's a good idea to use a prefix to the variable name,
which indicates the type of data that it will contain.
If we go back into excel by closing the visual basic editor,
we'll see.
How about another work seat here called prefixes?
This gives examples of prefixes that you can use whenever you're crazy,
variable to indicate the type of data that it contains,
and this applies both to data and to excel objects.
So if you're creating a reference to an Excel object you can.
All that references are variable,
and again it's useful just to use the prefix.
So these prefixes that I will be using,
but the main thing is to be consistent,
and that's particularly useful if you're working this part of the team.
So we're gonna create to string variables because we've got two pieces of text the Excel
user name on the windows local name.
So both of these will be str variables so dim as in dimension and let's have str excel name
.
Obviously,
as you can anticipate,
those spaces are allowed in a variable name and then we used as to specify the data type.
So this is obviously as string a man dim str loving name also a string.
So that's variable declaration.
The next thing is to populate the variables to put something inside them,
and this is where we can see why they call variables.
We,
as programmers don't know what they will contain.
We simply know where the data is going to be captured from,
and if this function is used in 10 different locations on 10 different machines,
it could produce 10 different results.
So in terms of syntax.
Populating the data variable comes under the classification off assignment of data value.
Your place in a piece of data be is a string a date or number into a data container
whenever that's the case,
As we've said,
you used the key word.
Let let my container equals my data.
So let's my variable,
which is str excel name bqool my string value and we're grabbing the string value from
Excel.
The key word Frank's cell as an object is application knows on.
Then we make our best guess,
and obviously the best guess we use the name is user name.
Then we do the same for the windows.
Log on Let's str log in name equal and this time we're digging insight.
BB A so b b A.
Don't interaction don't environment on the syntax that you need to use is to put
parentheses and then a quoted reference so again use the name.
But this time it has to go in as a string.
Having populated those two variables we can now compose are simple message,
and that message will be the output of the function itself.
So again we're signing a data value,
but this time we're doing it to the function itself.
So let because its data user greets in equal STL.
Excel name.
Empress End Colon space loved in as a space close close.
And then we can Katyn ate the str long in name.
And if you want a full stop after that and percent full stop,
and that's our function.
Since we broach the topic off variables,
this is a good point to explain.
Option explicit.
You probably noticed that every time we create a module when the code window opens,
it has the words option explicit and what this means.
Basically,
let's just get rid of this unwanted in audio way.
Need to expose it.
No,
we don't know what the option explicit does basically is.
It requires you to declare your variables.
This is how he declared variables that this,
strictly speaking,
is optional.
If you use option explicit at the top of your model instead of being optional,
variable declaration becomes obligatory.
So if I were to take out option explicit if you remember,
you can take a line out simply by comments in the line out.
So click on comment.
Look,
that puts an apostrophe at the start of the line,
turning it into a comment,
so it's no longer functional.
And now let's say that in type in the let's statements,
I made an error,
so I just did a typo,
I m A instead of a M,
and I didn't notice.
If I now go to debug in twos,
compile,
you'll see that the code compiles with no problems.
But of course it's going to be wrong,
because Excel name hasn't been populated.
Another non existent variable.
An accidental variable,
if you like,
has been populated.
When I don't put my greeting,
I'll get nothing at that point.
That's now reactivate option explicit by Uncommon Tin it.
Now let's try debug,
compile and you'll see very usefully.
It picks something the error or me so I can immediately see.
Oh,
that's a typo on,
then I can just correct it.
The automatic inclusion of Option Express it is controlled by going to tools options and
ensuring that this check box is activated require variable declaration,
so if this is not activated,
often explicit will not automatically be inserted when you do a new module.
But there's nothing to stop you from type in the words anyway.
OK,
so that's our function completed.
Let's now check that it works.
So we wanted in this cell.
So they called it.
Use a greeting equals use a greet in.
No arguments required and let me enter Excel named Gamble Log in name Train in seven.