Let's now move on to look at two types of VB,
a statement which are essential in order to land more complexity to your VB a functions
condition.
ALS Looping folder 11.
Using conditional czar Looping,
let's open the first example using if statements adding conditional logic to your excel.
Formless can often seem quite complex because,
of course,
in a formula,
everything has to be a function.
But in BB eight,
we don't have this restriction,
so you'll often find that right in logical structures is much easier in V A.
Than it is in Excel or analysts.
In this example,
we want to create a V be a function which will display the version of Excel that's being
used.
Let's say,
for example,
we're tracking printing problems and finding out whether certain versions of Excel are less
compatible without princes.
So this message,
which is currently static we want to make dynamic and instead of heart code in the version
,
we want the version automatically picked up and displayed at the end of this message.
So let's rise our function,
go to developer like visual basic,
and then let's insert a module in this workbook,
as opposed to the personal macro workbook.
Let's go straight into our function.
So insert procedure procedure time function on Let's call it Excel version.
Since the information being used by the function will come from the system,
we don't need any arguments specified.
It's with parentheses.
However,
we do need to specify the type of data reviews by the ocean itself.
And this,
of course,
will be a string confirming the version of Excel being used.
So after the closing parenthesis we put as string the two pieces of information that were
interested in are the platform Windows or Mac and the Excel version,
and we can find out both of those by looking at the properties of the application object.
So we dip into the object,
browse a few object browser on look inside the application object.
Here we have operating system,
which is you can see is a string,
and then we have version,
which,
although it appears to be a number,
is actually a string.
So let's create a couple of variables to keep track of this information.
You First of all,
let's create str version as string,
and that will hold the actual text that we intend to display to the user confirming the
version of Excel because the version returned by application dot version is inherently
numeric will be useful to convert it into a proper number.
So let's all said them l m G version as long,
I just remind you,
long,
short or long integer.
And then finally,
let's create our 1st 1,000,000,000 variable on will use this to keep track of whether the
user is on a Windows machine,
So call it him bln win as Julian.
And now let's construct our if statement.
Let's begin by looking at the generic structure oven.
Xlv a.
If statement we have the key would.
If we have a logical test,
let's call it test one and then we have the key.
But then then we have the statements if test one is true and then we contest for
alternative possibilities.
But this time we use else if and then we have statements which will kick in if test to is
true on.
We continue in this way with us many tests as we need when we finished all the test.
We can then have a cattle statement,
which will only apply if all the tests have been false and to do that we use else and then
to terminate the if statement we used end.
If so,
let's begin our testing by checking for all the Windows versions of Excel.
So it would be a good idea to populate our bln wind variable before we do the testing.
So we can say let bln win bqool.
And then,
rather than testing to see whether application operating system is equal to a certain
string,
it's more useful to test whether it contains the word windows.
And we can do that by using the in string function,
which is supplied by the V B.
A object model.
So we start with B B A and then we drill down into the strings close on.
We find in string.
When we talked,
you have in parenthesis.
Excel reminds us of all the arguments that we need and best practice is to supply the name
of the argument followed by colon equals bullet by the value.
So start specifies the character from which you want to start searching,
which in our case,
is one the first character coma space underscore so we can end the line.
I mean,
let's just align.
The second argument under the first on the second argument we need is String one Colon
equals on This is the text string that you're evaluated.
And of course,
in our case it's application got operating system comma under school on the final argument
that we need extreme to,
which is the string that we're certain for within String one.
And that,
of course,
is the word windows and then the closing to emphasise to end the in string function.
Um,
in the second thing we need to evaluate is the version.
So let's use LNG version for that.
Let LNG version equal,
and what we need to do here is to convert a string value into a long indigent and again,
v B A has a function that does that forest.
So this time it's vb a got conversion and then we won't see l injury as in converted alone
,
and we need a single argument,
which is called expression.
The expression come on equals and then we simply use application.
No version.
So now we have the two bits of information that we need to evaluate.
We can specify out tests,
so let's go back as far as 2010 Excel 2010 was version 14.
So test will be if LNG version equals 14 and the Ln win People's Truth on our statement is
true will be let str version Equal Excel for Windows 2010 and then we can copy this test,
just paste it here and make the necessary changes.
So let's meet up.
Version 1015 was Excel for Windows 2013 on.
Then let's just do one more version 16.
If Yellen,
when it's true,
is Excel for Windows 2016 then let's move on to the Mac versions.
So if the version is 14 but bln win is false,
then the user is on Mac 2011 on,
then let's copy that.
And finally,
if the version is 15 on bln Winnie's Falls,
for some reason,
the user is on Excel for Mac.
If you're on a Mac,
use in 2016 the version comes up,
it's 15.
If you're on Windows,
it comes up a 60.
So that's the technique.
And obviously,
if you need to do this,
you may need to sort of a test for some of the earlier versions that this is just to
illustrate how,
if else if it works So these are all the tests we want to do and then the else becomes our
cattle Is none of the other truth.
What value do we want to place inside?
Str version So let's simply say Let's str version cool and then we'll put a fixed piece of
text for example,
a pre 2010 version.
I think so.
So having the else clause within your structure allows you to cater for pretty much every
eventuality chest or all the things you're interested in testing ball and then the Els will
apply to all other possibilities.
So what we've achieved with the if statement is to have the variable str version contain
the version that excel and now we simply need a function to return.
Str version.
So after the statement,
we simply need to say Let's excel version equal.
Str on Then let's just coated,
debunk and compiled to make sure there are no errors.
And now let's give XXL and use on function.
So this static message we can now convert into a dynamic one.
So make the whole thing.
Is your formula equal sign at the beginning and converting out text into a string by
enclosing it in quotation marks.
And then instead of this static 20 tainment,
we now can Katyn eight using ampersand.
How do you function?
Excel version Closing Apprentices on memory Presenter I'm using Excel for Windows 2016.
Onda function just picks that up.