if you've upgraded to Excel 2016 When working with multiple conditions as well as using
nested ifs,
you now have the option of using a function called ifs.
Let's have a look at how it works that's open 03 the dysfunction.
And here we have the same example of unsold in the previous exercise.
So before creating our formula that's have a look at the mechanism of the dysfunction.
Now it differs from a regular if and nested ifs.
This diagram shows the basic structure.
Seven.
It's formula.
The first thing to notice is that there is only one ifs,
and this single function takes as its arguments multiple logical test and value it true
pairs.
So we proceed exactly as we did in the last video.
You start with the highest value,
so our test is overdue,
greater than or equal to 1 20 which is we saw before is false,
and then the value true would be bad.
It's in states over deuce.
This first test proved to be false,
so we go into the next one testing for 90 intestine for 60 then testing for 30 now when we
were working with nested ifs that was the last test that we needed to do,
because when you nest YPF's the third argument of the final statement becomes a cattle.
So you simply put the value that you want to appear.
If none of your previous tests proved to be true,
and it's very important to note that this is not the case with the dysfunction,
there is no cattle.
You simply continue with that structure up to 127 times.
So in this example,
we will need to do a final and fifth test to cater for that circumstance.
When the days overdue is less than 30 we need to explicitly put a test to cater for it.
And this is what you might call the Achilles heel of the dysfunction.
If there were a casual,
it will be exactly equivalent to invest it if and we could stop using nested lives and use
its instead.
But because there is no cattle and you have to manually cater for all eventualities you may
find in some scenarios,
this makes you a little nervous because obviously you have more testing to do just to make
sure that you haven't let anything slip through.
So let's now right,
the function going to need to.
And as usual,
I'm going to increase the size of the formula bar and split the function onto multiple
lines.
They're equals gifts.
So our first test is going to be whether it be to is greater than or equal to on this time
.
Instead of putting the literal values like we did last time,
let's use the values in this table,
so I'll simply click on the cell that contains 1 20 And,
of course,
since we intend to copy,
this formula amounted to press F or hopefully,
you know,
factual cut so that Excel will insert dollar signs.
Hence,
when I copy the formula,
that cell reference won't change.
So that becomes my logical test one.
And I put in a coma we now want to.
Value is true one and value it true is in this table 86 So I click on the cell and once
more press F four and then a comma,
and that's the way the its function is structured.
I simply repeat this parent logical test by the true logical test on drew up to 127 times
So in our case,
we need fire again.
I'll just call me back,
use old enter to move down,
um,
and control the paste.
On this time,
I'll copy the space as well.
So old Enter control the entire control the control the and delete the final comma.
Now all I have to do is to change the number each time.
So we're working up that time.
Thanks All it's a strain.
And finally to on this final test needs a modification,
doesn't it?
So we're test in G three on.
We're making sure that it's less Stan g three and to complete the formula,
we've only used one function this time.
So we just need one close in parenthesis and that completes our formula.
But we present collapse the formula bar back to its normal size and copy down by double
clicking on.
We also feel handle.
But in many ways,
using ifs is a neater and easier alternative to using nested IPs.
But as I said,
it has not this sting in its tail that there is no option for a catch.
Alvar al you.
When you're working with something as straightforward as numeric values,
it's very convenient and it's fairly easy to make sure that you cater for all eventualities
.
But in some other circumstances,
it may need a bit more balls.
So for that reason,
the dysfunction is perhaps not quite as useful as it should be.
I'll just demonstrate the danger to which I'm allude in.
If we increase the size of formula bar again and simply take out this equal sign,
we're now seeing greater than 30 in less than 30 a symbol era we now make.
This found you exactly 30.
Our logic hasn't tater for that number,
so we get the not available error.
Obviously,
with numeric values,
it's fairly easy to avoid making that error.
But just to emphasize that,
that's the danger with the assumption there is no capital that you have to cater for every
possible outcome within the scenario that your evaluation