when you use investor tips to test numeric values.
What alternative is to use the V look up function?
Let's take an example that's open 04 Use envy.
Look up instead of it.
So here we have the same example that we've used in the last two videos and since the
criteria that we want to use are laid out in a table,
we could use this as I will look up table and then simply use the look up as an alternative
to having the If logic on the only provides er is that we've arranged our table in
ascending order.
So we have a numeric values in the first column,
and they've been sorted in ascending order.
So the B look up will automatically take each of the values in column D and compare them to
the values in the first column of the look up table.
So it will start on this column,
and in the case of D two,
it's gonna compare 20 to the cell below on because the number below is greater.
It wouldn't move down.
It will stay on these roads,
and we can then move across the column,
too,
to see what status is appropriate for that value.
So the if logic that we implemented manually is implemented automatically by the V Look up
function.
There's no nesting required on this one,
so we can just write it.
Alarm online equals B.
Look up,
and then we have our four parameters.
Look up values,
of course.
E to.
If it's difficult to click on the selling one,
remember,
you can always press the arrow keys to move to the soul.
So here I'm gonna press the left era comma for second values table array.
We could simply drag across the column.
Headings like this G and H and level,
of course,
include the title,
which being text is just equivalent to zero.
If we wanted to have just the values he could drag cross posed.
But of course we have to remember to press at all to insert the dollar signs so that when
we copy the table values,
they're still being addressed.
My own personal preferences wherever possible to track across the column headings coma.
Then we specify the column within the look up table,
which contains the answer that we want to display.
So it's a two column table and the answer is in the second column off at two column table.
So he put it to on not an H that this third parameter is always knew.
Married.
It's never letter about given column.
And then,
finally,
at Excel promises.
Are we looking for an approximate match or an exact match?
And in this case,
of course,
looking for an approximate match.
We just want to put each of these numeric values into the appropriate band,
and that's it.
We don't even need to put the clothes in parenthesis because there's no nest in so we can
just presenter on Excel will insert it for us.
We can then coming down.
So if you do find yourself using a nest,
if which has lots of possible values or is purely numeric,
as in this case,
and you might consider just constructing a look up table could be on a hidden work feet
even on then using that to implement the logic rather than having what often becomes a very
complex nested.
If structure