Let's end our look at excels,
logical functions by looking at a very simple but very useful function.
If Karen and basically what the if Arab function does is to enable you to substitute
potential era values returned by your formulas with something will use a friendly.
Let's take an example here we want to create a formula to do some basic email validation,
and are we going to do is to test for the presence of the at sign and the dot in each of
our email addresses.
So,
as usual,
let's expand our fold in the bar.
So this,
of course,
will be an if statement.
So as per usual,
we start by specifying a logical test.
And since this will be a compound test,
we have to use all or And and in this case,
we want both the acts and adult to be present.
So we needed,
and both conditions have to be satisfied.
So we have.
And now let's start with the outside.
So we need a function which will test whether the at sign is present in cell F two on for
this weekend.
Use find.
The first argument is the thing you're looking for,
and that has to go in close.
Of course,
it's the outside comma on.
The second argument is to sell that you're examining,
which of course,
is left to the first email address.
Then we can close parentheses,
permitting the final optional argument,
and then we need to finish this off to make it into a test.
If I say,
for example,
greater than one,
this will test ISI that the string contains an ensign and it's not the first character,
and then we can do the same for the dots find Don't enough to.
And this time,
let's say,
greater than four.
That completes out.
And so you put the clothes in parentheses.
Coma.
That's our logical test completed.
Let's press old enter for a new line and move on to the value is true.
If the test is successful,
we want the word valid to appear in the song coma,
cancer and then for value of false.
We want the word invalid that completes our If so,
we can just put the clothes in parenthesis.
So let's presente.
So the email address,
you know,
two is valid.
But when we copy down,
what we find is that all those email addresses,
which are invalid instead of returning the text in value,
as we've asked,
producing an Arab body.
So we know in this example that every time there's an error,
what we actually have is an invalid email address.
What we want to do here is to replace this arrow value with the word in Balad,
and that's exactly what the if error function enables us to do.
So Here's a summary of the logic that we have in place using the and function.
Have an inside it use the find function twice very fine the position of the at sign on the
dots.
So because this email address has no out sign,
the first find operation produces an era value.
Once that happens,
the formula itself produces an error value so the value of true and valuable false parts of
the if statement are processed.
So the solution is to use if era it takes two arguments on the first argument is simply the
entire formula that you want to evaluate.
So the formula that we currently have will become the first argument,
the value argument of the if Eric function and then the second arguments is the value that
you want to appear in the cell whenever an error does a result from your formula.
So in this case,
we want the word invalid to replace the Arab Annie.
So all we need to do is after the equal sign to put if error,
I'll just press walk enter to emphasize that the if statement is the first argument of the
era.
And then that first argument is followed by a comma now completed the value arguments of
the era.
We just need the value,
if error argument again on press Old Enter have in to line up with the if statement and put
the word invalid and then a single close in parenthesis to end the era function.
So let's test it and and then copy down.
So now,
whenever an error occurs,
the word invalid replaces the error of value.