Greetings fellow CDK enthusiasts.
I'm Scott Tate, a cloud architect from blindspot.com, excited
to share a few hours a year time in the exciting world of
Infrastructure as Code with the CDK,
which has interest levels all the way up to the proverbial sky.
It's been a long time since a technology has burst onto the
scene and taken the industry by storm as quickly as these AWS
CDK has. In just a short period of time,
the entire world of IaC has exploded as a result of the new structured
programming language capabilities now available.
Avoiding 100,000 line CloudFormation JSON files, we can now
right a fraction of the code to achieve the same result in
one of the many structured,
higher‑level programming languages and take advantage of
object‑oriented principles along the way.
As this is the next course in the CDK learning path,
I'm going to focus on more advanced topics around building CDK
applications. We'll first take a much need to dive into the critically
important subject of building organized application and stack patterns to
help you ensure sustainable growth in your AWS environments. Complementing
that, we'll then dive into the concept of managing and deploying
multi‑environment applications to AWS.
To ensure we cover the gamut of advanced topics, I'll walk through
intra‑stack communication concepts in the veritable compendium of variable
storage methods we can use in large CDK applications.
We're going to have some fun learning about building custom construct libraries,
and I'll go through the important topics of testing and securing them with
Jest testing and aspects. We touch on many subjects around the CDK that you
likely won't find in any other resources out there.
So I hope you'll stick with me and join the movement to advance IaC to new heights with the AWS CDK, here at Pluralsight.