Now that we have a reasonably clean and well‑organized system to work with,
let's dive into the concept of promoting this application
to multiple environments to start working with Ellen's
requirement to boost reusability.
As with stack patterns,
there are dozens of different ways you can
facilitate the multi‑environment concept,
so let's dive in and look at a few.
So before we jump into the deep end of the proverbial pool here,
I wanted to first define what we mean by environments.
The word environment, like the construct joke I made in the last module,
is used in a variety of contexts.
First, there exists the concept of the physical AWS environment.
We all know this well.
We have an environment or an account in which we have
regions and availability zones.
Unfortunately,
the term environment tends to get watered down and
overlaps the account a little bit.
One might even call the overall entity with multiple
accounts underneath it an environment.
I use Control Tower in my organization,
so I have an AWS organization with dozens of different accounts underneath it.
See how that nomenclature gets a little confusing?
Then,
we as engineers talk about the term environment as a physical
place where we can work on and/or deploy our code.
Sure this may be in a single AWS environment in one region or it
may span multiple accounts in multiple regions.
Since we're teaching in the engineering world,
I'm going to focus on an environment representing a place where you
physically deploy your infrastructure is code.
To that end,
an environment will be a collection of stacks
representing our deployment target.
Taking that concept one level deeper, environments represent a sandbox in which
developers might work independently while they develop code, a dev environment
to which a team of developers might deploy and integrate feature branches or
code changes, higher level pre‑prod environments that more closely represent
production and facilitate a deployment process through to production. and then
lastly a production environment where live code is usually running for users
and clients.
If your organization does use any of these types of code environments,
think about some of the characteristics of each. First, size and capacity of
resources is a huge concept that needs to be controlled to efficiently manage
costs. If you're using EC2 instances, you certainly wouldn't want to ratchet up
production‑grade large AMIs for this purpose.
In most cases,
developers are perfectly happy with t2.micro or nano
instances or even free tier instances.
Think about your load testing environment.
That's always one environment that needs to simulate production,
whereas all other environments usually don't.
And then how about security?
While production should be locked down,
you really don't want to limit what a developer can and can't do
while writing code. While on the topic of security,
you very well might want to ensure that production is
completely isolated from lower environments.
Also, your type and degree of automation may change at different levels.
You may seed dev databases in development environments,
where you might not further down the line.
So in that regard,
doesn't it make the most sense to build environments that can be
reused and deployed with individual meta‑characteristics for these
particular needs without raw duplication?
If you remember my first module,
the boss kept asking me for more environments to the
tune of an environmental eye chart.
In this case,
we're building IaC so as to be able to reuse everything we create, but not
tailor it specifically for the needs of the environment owners.
Then don't you want to be able to duplicate that advantage by automatically
provisioning environments for other teams or projects?
Dynamically controlled environments can be a very powerful asset, and
could promote extremely rapid engineering cycles.
One of the biggest roadblocks in organizations today is a
lack of usable environments, or worse,
having to share environments painstakingly.
And when managed well,
costs can be a fraction of resident hardware virtualized
data center costs. In the next clip, let's dive into exactly what it looks like to begin setting up these concepts.