As we're now a few courses into this learning path,
I'm sure you're anxious to get started.
With that in mind,
I'm going to assume that you're at least a moderately capable
TypeScript developer and have run through the beginning and
intermediate concepts in the AWS CDK universe.
I promise I'll try to keep the teaching slides to a minimum
and focus more on the demos and code that you're most likely
here for in the first place.
So this module is all about beginning to break up monolith CDK stacks.
The first thing I'm going to do is quickly show you the
baseline version of the monolith,
as well as a neat diagramming tool called infviz.io that you
can use to view your deployed infrastructure.
David's done a great job so far on teaching the basics and beyond,
so most of the constructs and patterns should look familiar to you.
In that regard, I'll go over stacks, constructs,
and abstraction levels, only very briefly as they pertain to my code refactoring.
As always, if you're looking for a deeper refresher,
head back to David's first course in the path and look
for the construct and stack overviews.
He's got some great fundamentals in there.
I'll then dive in and talk about the mystery of stack
patterns and why you might not find as much information out
there in the wild about this subject.
Before we start our refactoring deep dive,
I'll take a few moments to consider the direction being taken by
Josh and Ellen on the TechStream acquisition.
Finally,
I'll take a comprehensive approach to refactoring our monolithic application to
fit the needs of Globomantics and the TechStream developers.
And with full disclosure,
I won't really live‑write every line of code or we might be
here for a lot longer than you'd like.
However, I'll stick to some copying and pasting,
as well as some fast forwards that'll help you fully
follow along with the course progress.
As we progress through the refactoring,
you'll quickly see that we get stuck on the need to communicate between stacks.
I'll talk about the handful of ways you can achieve this and then go
forward with building these techniques into our application.
And to summarize,
we'll exit the module by reviewing what Josh and Ellen were looking for and how
our newly refactored code begins to meet these challenges.
By the end of the module,
you should be starting to see the light at the end of the tunnel.
At this point, you've seen the demo application,
and I explained that I, and by I, I mean Josh,
disassembled it with the CDK disassembler from CloudFormation JSON
into one big multi‑thousand line beast file.
As the disassembler generates level 0 constructs,
I'd recommend against using it for anything meaningful in your enterprise.
To that end,
I've essentially rewritten it almost from scratch into level 1 AWS constructs.
Let's take a look.
All right,
so if we go ahead and open Visual Studio Code to the folder that
would be created from the ZIP file in the course materials for the
baseline version of the application,
you should be seeing approximately what I'm seeing.
Now, a couple of things to note.
First and foremost, you'll want to dive down into the cdk directory.
If you remember, this was a fork from the AWS Labs repository,
so all the work that we're going to do is going to be inside the cdk folder.
And then obviously, you're going to want to run an npm install or even better,
an npm update so that you've got all the latest construct libraries.
So really, for this early version of the application,
there's really only a couple of files that you're going to be concerned with.
First and foremost, the dasm file, that's the file that was created when we ran
the disassembler that created all the level 0 constructs.
Now the master‑fullstack‑single‑stack TypeScript file,
that's our main code file.
Obviously, in our bin directory, we have our master‑full‑stack‑single,
which is where our app is going to be instantiated.
But for now,
let's go ahead and open the main TypeScript code file and let's look through it.
As you can see here at the top,
we have a very simple class called MasterFullStackSingleStack,
which has all the constructs inside of it.
Now, if I go ahead and scroll down, you'll see that there is a Dynamo Object,
and if I open that up that is the goalsTable.
We know exactly what that's for, storing all the data from the CRUD operations.
Here are the S3 Objects, the source buckets,
the website bucket, and the assets bucket.
There's also an S3 deployment in here as well.
This is where everything is going to be stored as far
as S3 is concerned for our website.
Below that is the CloudFront Distribution,
which I'll go ahead and skip over for now.
And then the Lambda functions are below that.
Now, I haven't made any changes to the Lambda functions.
And if you remember from the original distribution,
they just perform the CRUD operations and they
still live in the functions folder.
And then we have our Cognito constructs.
Now, there's a lot of code in here, so I'm not going to go through it.
And keep in mind,
this course isn't necessarily intended to teach you how to write CDK constructs.
It's more geared towards teaching how to better organize constructs and stacks.
So I'm not going to dive as deeply on individual constructs and CDK concepts.
After that, we have our API Gateway, which sits in front of our Lambdas,
and then we have all of our CodeBuild objects.
You can see that I output a couple of things.
I output the WebsiteBucketUrl and the CDN URL.
Now I didn't lock the website bucket down itself because the CDN
takes a lot longer to deploy with a CDK deploy,
so you might want to actually comment that out and
literally just hit the WebsiteBucketUrl,
if you're actually following along.
So for our purposes, let's go ahead and compile it with a tsc.
And now that everything's compiled,
let's go ahead and list our stacks with a cdk ls.
And sure enough, there's our stack called FullStackCdkStack,
and it's ready to be deployed at this point.
So I'll go ahead and run a cdk deploy,
hit yes on the question that asks me if I want to create resources,
and what I'll do is pause the video from there because this deployment,
especially including the asset CDN, takes about 8 to 10 minutes,
so I'll be right back.
And sure enough, about 8 or 9 minutes later our deploy is finished.
And you can see some of the outputs that I created.
You can see that you can click on the CloudFrontCDNUrl,
and you can click on the WebsiteBucketUrl,
as well.
so let's go ahead and Ctrl+click that guy and Open,
and our website is running exactly as we expect it to be.
And if I flip over to the CloudFormation console we
can see that this stack is complete.
But what I wanted to show you really quickly is,
I don't necessarily like just an exhaustive view of
resources under the CloudFormation console.
So the wonderful folks that at infviz, which is that
infviz.io, have created a very affordable diagramming tool
that you can connect to your AWS account.
Now they've also created a promo code with the word
Pluralsight, so if you go ahead and type that in,
you can get a discount for a couple of months.
But suffice it to say you, can use the free account, you can connect a
workspace directly to AWS, and then you can have your infrastructure
refreshed every single time you come in here.
So right at the moment we're not looking at any infrastructure.
So let me go ahead and hit CONFIGURATION,
General, and I'm going to hit Reimport Data.
And that takes a half a minute or so, so I'll pause it and move forward.
And it pulled back all the infrastructure that we just deployed.
Now if I go back over to the CONFIGURATION tab and I go to Services,
I can select all, then I can go down and I can clear some of
the control tower‑created objects in the account that aren't
really applicable to this course,
and I can filter them out and update the diagram.
And once it loads,
you can see that we have the exact infrastructure that we just
deployed. Our API gateway is there, our Cognito and buckets are
there, our Lambdas are all there, and our stack is listed there as well.
There's a lot of neat tools in here.
I can click Connectivity,
and it shows the connection paths through all the resources. I can click Report,
and it shows a nice executive summary with estimated costs,
resources, and a node list.
You can click Security, and if you have GuardDuty turned on,
it'll show you some red flags.
And then one of the nicest tools is, you can actually say Edit in draw.io,
and if you have a draw.io account,
it will instantly open this in a console in draw.io that you can actually edit.
It's a really nice tool while you're actually learning CDK or
where you're developing CDK, and it saves a lot of time on having
to create diagrams on infrastructure.
So at this point,
let's move forward and see how we can't start breaking this monolith up into distributed stacks.