At this point in the course,
the SSM Parameter Store shouldn't be a new concept to you.
I waited to refactor our application so as to pair that effort with
the concept of building loosely coupled systems.
One of the greatest choices in recent years on promoting loose coupling
is already built into our application architecture.
That's a serverless design.
Now, again, this isn't using a serverless framework in this course,
but we certainly haven't spent any time yet building complex VPCs,
EC2 instances, or autoscaling groups.
Our application design uses Lambdas with an API Gateway
to perform CRUD operations on Dynamo.
Right out of the box, the design is already very loosely coupled.
These components all communicate to each other
through some semblance of an interface,
all essentially glued together with CodePipeline deployments.
Thanks to our distributed designs with the CDK,
any one of these components can be replaced or
improved independently of the rest.
Now we truly won't be able to set up a fully decoupled and
dynamic platform until we get to the next module where we move
constructs into a construct library.
For now,
we'll build as many dynamic concepts as we can through
context and deploy time SSM parameters.
If you remember this slide from a few modules ago,
we demonstrated how to create and reference SSM parameters.
Just about every aspect of our application can be dynamic,
which is precisely what we want.
I also showed a view of the seven or eight parameters that I
manually created in the Systems Manager as well.
So as to make our deployment self‑contained and immutable,
let's build a new stack that seeds those parameters for our application.
One point of factor that's slightly different from the slide In the last module,
I mentioned that SSM parameters can be acquired at
synthesize or deployment time, depending on your needs.
Note that the fromStringParameterAttributes method exchanges
tokens for real values during deployment.
Since we'll need these values at synthesis time to build properties,
we'll be using the valueFromLookup method instead,
like this.
In this demo we'll create a brand‑new stack that allows us to
seed SSM values with needed parameters.
I'll go ahead and keep the stack in the same distribution so that you
can deploy and destroy it independently as you need.
All right,
so if we roll back over into Visual Studio Code and we open our
little handy‑dandy refactor‑steps text file,
we can see that I've added step 14 and 15.
And what we're going to do is,
we're going to create a seeder stack for SSM parameters to
make our lives a little bit easier here.
So the first thing I'm going to do is,
I'm going to go ahead and create an ssmseeder
directory and then the typescript file.
Now what we're going to do is,
we're going to go ahead and use the SSM Parameter Store,
and we're going to seed all of our demo parameters,
and then we're going to deploy them to the Systems Manager.
So if I go over to the seeder TypeScript file,
you can see again that this is just a very simple CDK stack.
And in this case, we're using the aws‑ssm package.
I don't really have any properties I've injected,
but what I've done inside the class is, I've created an array called envList,
which, for the sake of demo purposes, includes two demo environments,
our Dev‑local environment and our Dev‑integration environment.
Now you may have 20 environments here to create parameters for,
and since all of our parameters have to exist in the form
of a hierarchy to represent an object, my top‑level parent is called CdkEnvs,
for CDK environments.
And what that's going to do is, my top level will be a /CdkEnvs,
and then my environment will be below that,
and my parameter will be below that,
as we'll see in just a second in the Parameter Store.
So first and foremost, the first thing I've done is,
I'm creating the defaultEnv parameter,
and that's going to represent the default environment if no
environment is chosen during the synthesis process.
And as we've learned,
we're going to use the StringParameter command to create the parameter.
Let me go ahead and free up a little more space here.
So we're calling ssm‑StringParameter.
And in this case,
the second parameter as we know in constructs is just the construct ID,
but naturally I can't have forward slashes in that, so
all I've done is create an envParent‑, and then the value.
And if I scroll over just a little bit further and see the rest,
we can see that what I've done is, my parameter name is going to be /envParent,
and in this case, that's going to be CdkEnvs.
And then the parameter name is going to be Default‑env,
and the string value as we know now is going to be Dev‑local.
So that's our default parameter as far as environments is concerned.
And if I go down now what I've done is,
I loop through the envList to create parameters for
both Dev‑local and Dev‑integration.
Now, obviously, that's going to create the exact same parameters for each,
so you may duplicate this.
But remember, this is just a seeder stack.
So in theory,
you could go ahead and seed these into your Systems Manager and
then go in and change values as you see fit.
And just as you would imagine, again,
we're creating the construct ID with the envParent and then the env,
which is our for loop variable.
And in this case, it's going to be Dev‑local and Dev‑integration.
And then our parameters are going to get created with parent,
the name of the environment, and the parameter name and value.
So here is the apiName parameter, and that's going to be set to apiGw.
So this will be CdkEnvs/Dev‑local/apiName, with the value of apiGw.
So now if I go back over to the full stack file,
I've gone ahead already and pulled the seeder stack in at the top.
And then from there I create a version of the seeder stack.
And again,
we didn't have any properties and I don't need to create any
local variables specifically for the stack,
so we can actually go ahead and deploy this independently of the rest.
Now, one thing you'll notice is, I've put a little bit of error handling in here.
So for example,
if you actually go in here and you fail to provide an environment on context,
it's actually going to throw an error.
And one challenge here with using the CDK is,
any one of the CDK commands will actually reveal that error.
So this will still execute even with a cdk ls or a cdk synth.
And as an example, if I just run a cdk ls,
that error handling is basically going to tell me that I didn't
choose one of the two appropriate environment types,
which it did.
And you can see that those two are available right
here at the top in an envList array.
So now if I do a cdk ls using the context flag and I set env to Dev‑local,
we know that this line of code right here is going to
pull that right off of context,
and it's going to jump over to that error handling appropriately,
which it did.
We can see every one of our stacks in the list.
So if I go back up and do exactly the same thing,
but in this case I deploy only the SsmSeederAppStack,
we see that our stack deployed.
And now if we head over to the Parameter Store in the
Systems Manager and I refresh the page,
we can see that all of our parameters have been created and now exist
exactly as we would have expected in the Parameter Store.
And using the simple example we looked at a second ago in code,
here's the apiName, which is set to apiGw.
And we know that we have Dev‑integration versions of the
parameters and Dev‑local versions of the parameters.
So one nice feature of using a stack to seed with is if you
change any parameters in your SSM seeder stack,
it'll do a simple update and change those values for you.
And secondarily, every single time you deploy,
even if you deploy just with a *wildcard,
it's going to simply ignore the seeder stack with no changes.
So you don't have to worry about it overwriting any variables or
parameters unless you intentionally change values.
Now that we have all of our parameters fully
dynamically available in the SSM store,
let's contribute to our goal of loose coupling by building property objects and
required interfaces for each stack using these parameters.
So now that we have all of our parameters in the SSM Parameter Store,
let's take advantage of these.
So I'm back in our refactor‑steps text file here
and I've added a couple of tasks.
First, what we're going to do is,
we're going to go build a set of property objects and then
ultimately interfaces for our SSM parameters.
So properties will be represented by objects in our main application file,
and then interfaces will be designated in each
class file for each physical stack.
So if I go back to our full‑stack application file,
the first thing that we can see is, I take in our projectName on context.
Now,
the projectName itself is the one variable or one piece of data
that I can't store because that's what you're going to use to
create this entire application.
And if you had the chance to deploy the CloudFormation
stack from the AWS Labs distribution,
you saw that the projectName was one primary parameter.
And since almost every other parameter name is
somehow a root of that projectName,
it's required that that only be 12 characters long.
So there's a little bit of error handling here just to make sure
that your projectName is less than 13 characters.
We just saw in the last module how the seeder stack works.
We can ignore that for now.
And now what we have is, we have a new deployment stack.
Now, DeploymentStack has absolutely nothing in it.
It really doesn't do anything.
But SSM parameters have to be retrieved in the context of a stack.
So we have a deployment stack that we could take advantage of in the future if
we need to from which all of our SSM parameters will derive.
Now, I showed this line just a little bit in the last clip.
I set a value of bizEnv, or business environment,
and what I do is, I try to grab that from context,
which you saw briefly in the last module.
And if that is not on context,
I grab it from our new default value of Default‑env from the Parameter Store.
And then as I also briefly explained,
I put a little bit of error handling in here,
nothing fancy,
to require that any environment designation that you
actually pull in is in the list.
So if you type in env=abc123, this will bail out when you run a cdk, anything.
So now what we're doing is, we're expounding on our property pattern.
So what I've done is,
I've created about seven or eight different objects, all
intended to store and be used for property management and
facilitate our interfaces and our class stacks.
So the first thing I've done is, I've created an envProps object,
in which case the only thing I could really think of
environmentally for demo purposes was the useCdn value.
I've created a projProps object,
in which case I store the projectName which was provided at the top,
and then we go through our stack properties.
So the first object here are our API Gateway Properties, or our ApiProps.
And in this case now, I am actually pulling these out of SSM parameters.
So the apiName value itself comes out of the ApiName parameter.
Now, this is a very long line of code,
so I apologize for scrolling back and forth.
But essentially what I've done is,
I've prepended it with the projectName because if you remember,
this value was apiGw in the SSM Parameter Store.
At least we can get the projectName on it to give
it some semblance of uniqueness.
Now you can see what I'm doing is,
I'm simply concatenating the value of the parameter
that comes out of the SSM store,
and I am adding the projectName to the front of it.
And then if we go down a little bit further,
there's a few properties similarly that are created
for the content delivery network.
We have a suite of parameters that are created for the code objects
or the code stack for CodePipeline and CodeBuild.
We have a set of cognitoProps,
which are used for our user pool and our identity pool.
There are properties created specifically for the Dynamo database,
including the name of the table that gets created and the
partition key and the sort key used in the table.
I didn't really have any Lambda props to add, but I included it just for now.
And then we have a suite of properties associated with our S3 buckets.
Now what I've done from there is, I've simply use the spread operator,
and I've combined all the properties together into a props object,
and I pass that into each stack instantiation.
Now, realize you're going to get a lot of extra properties from each stack,
but keep in mind, these objects are not very heavy.
So it's not the worst thing in the world to have access to
each one of these properties in each stack.
And if I go over to one of the stack files,
the database file in this case,
you remember now that we have interfaces in each class.
So the database stack requires the projectName in the tableName.
And in this case, we just talked about the partition key and the sort key,
all now coming in from the SSM Parameter Store,
used right here.
So everything is completely dynamic at this point.
And if I go back to the full‑stack file and I
uncomment the properties themselves,
I'm going to show you a few interesting things associated with SSM parameters,
as far as the CDK lifecycle is concerned.
So let me save that and recompile.
So these SSM parameters will be pulled when the cloud assembly is created,
and that happens during an ls, a synth, or a deploy. And what will happen is,
it will pull the properties out of store and it will
store them locally in the context file.
So now that I've uncommented that line of code that logs all the properties,
let me go ahead and do a cdk ls.
And now, if I go back and look at that output,
you can see that all the properties were synthesized.
Now what's a little strange here is, they were already in my context.json file.
So if I go ahead and open that up,
you can see that all of my properties were
essentially cached and stored locally.
So let's empty that out and start from scratch with a cdk context ‑‑clear flag,
and now you just saw, all of those parameters in the context just disappeared.
So now if I rerun that command, watch what happens.
The cloud assembly creation process goes through a few passes of attempting
to pull those parameters back from the Parameter Store.
And the first time it goes through and says,
hey, I don't know where these parameters are,
you'll notice what it does is, it puts a dummy‑value‑for,
which is a very obscure placeholder,
in place of the value that it hasn't pulled back yet.
And if I scroll down a little bit further,
you can see that there was a second pass here where everything was resolved.
Now that creates a few problems,
because while it's trying to pull those parameters back,
it's substituting their targets with values of dummy‑for,
which causes problems in certain resources like S3
bucket names and CodePipeline objects.
Now as long as you understand exactly what's happening here,
it's not that big of a deal, and just as you would expect,
all my parameters are appropriately listed.
So now if I go back and run a cdk deploy,
everything will deploy exactly as we expect it to
using the Dev‑local set of parameters.
So now we have an application where everything is completely and
dynamically pulled from the SSM Parameter Store.
In theory,
now you could go back to the Dev‑integration set of parameters or create a
production or test set of parameters and completely change the values and
deploy these entirely independently of each other.
In fact,
if I go ahead and go back and change this value and change it
from what deployed just back to an ls for now,
we simulated that exact process.
Now, if I go back to the context.json file and show you those values,
these values are all coming out of the Dev‑integration set of variables.
Pretty neat, huh? You can go in just about any direction you want here, being fully dynamic.