So what about Globomantics?
Did Ellen take the right course for her organization?
Would you have done anything differently than Ellen?
As it stands,
Globomantics has now successfully fully integrated TechStream into its
organization as Ellen intended. They now build applications that run on
mainstream reusable CDK‑driven environments,
and now their development cycles are faster than ever.
As a result of the well‑organized principles in use by the CDK,
many of the TechStream developers are participating in building
IAC as well for their respective teams.
Josh is an architect who gets to evaluate and prescribe
cutting edge processes and technologies that have made his
job as enjoyable as it's ever been.
Instead of having conversations about complex modulus,
discussions center on building more reuse into future projects with the CDK.
And since they've been pressing hard on the CDK best practices,
Globomantics has acquired that new development shop as promised
by the now highly confident CEO. Bring it,
Ellen tells her CEO every day when they talk about potential future acquisition. Would you do anything differently?