So building a construct takes on a slightly different path in building stacks.
Actually, building constructs is much simpler and includes far less overhead.
In this clip,
let's go build out our S3 static website construct and
get it published to our registry.
Now comes the fun part.
Let's go ahead and see what's involved in building out the construct,
publish it and get it ready to be used in the next clip.
So I think you'll find that building out this construct is actually very easy,
and in fact I'm not going to write a lot of code here,
I'm just going to steal a lot of code that we've actually already written.
So if I head back over to our main demo application and I open the
S3 TypeScript file and the cdn TypeScript file,
the first thing I'm going to do is I'm just going to go
ahead and grab the S3 deploying the S3 objects and I'm
going to go ahead and paste those.
I already had those in the package.json, so they're
actually installed and resolving.
So from here,
what we're going to do is I'm going to grab a little sample dummy interface
and paste that in. We're not going to call these S3StackProps anymore,
we'll call them CDKStaticWebsiteConstructProps,
which I understand is a little bit long,
and we'll go ahead and inject those for now.
Now what I'm going to want to grab is I want the websiteBucket,
and I want the S3 deployment object, and I'm not going to use
that entire function in the construct.
What I'm going to do is I'm just going to grab its logic, and I'll go ahead
and just embed its logic in the construct creation itself.
So let's go ahead and fix up a few of the issues that we
have, and we're getting closer here.
We have our deployment working,
everything's resolving and we have our website bucket created and
everything is resolving appropriately as well.
So let's go grab the cdn objects.
So I went ahead and grabbed that package, which was also
already installed from our package.json. Now we've got all
the items we need in our interface.
So let's go ahead and grab the Cloudfront distribution, and
we're actually good to go at this point because it's using the
same website bucket designation.
So if we go back up and make sure that everything looks okay,
we're pretty much good to go at this point.
We know that our construct is going to require some type of project name,
which is perfectly fine.
We're going to need a deployment source,
which is actually going to be a path that we're going to provide.
We need a website index document,
a website error document, which we're going to provide in a properties
object as well, and then for our cdn we're going to reference the same
index document and then for our cdn comment, we're going to go ahead and
fill in some information as well.
So at that point, our construct is ready to be published.
So let me go ahead and save it and compile, and if I go back to our
package.json just for a second, we can see that we're working with version
0.3.0, so let's go ahead and run an npm version and let's up it to 0.4.0,
and now we're actually ready to publish,
provided that we're still logged in and we make sure that it's public on our
access flag, we can see that it published successfully.
So if we head back over to npmjs and take a look, I'll go
ahead and refresh the page, and we can see that version 0.4.0
was published, and sure enough,
if I go in and look at it, version 0.4.0 is there.
So at this point,
our CDK S3 static website package is ready to be used in the creation of another stack.