CI/CD is one of my favorite topics to talk about with all
the new tools available in the CDK.
With full disclosure,
building a fully integrated and dynamic pipeline is
truly a subject for its own course.
Once again, we have several methods available to accomplish this,
which I'll touch on lightly in this clip.
In the CDK's infancy,
building pipelines wasn't quite as easy as it is with the tools available today.
Amazon essentially built a one‑to‑one mapping from the CodeBuild
and CodePipeline resources into CDK constructs,
and you were a bit on your own in the creating of anything multistage.
Now even that necessarily isn't a bad thing.
Level 1 constructs give you full control to build what
you need exactly where you need it.
As a result,
folks began building pipelines with CDK tools that
were a combination of level 1,
constructs together with more sophisticated scripting and build spec files.
Again, this isn't a bad thing either.
I call it advanced, as to build pipelines in this way,
a higher level of scripting knowledge and control is required.
I'll show you one of my favorite examples of this in a bit.
If you want extreme control over what your pipeline
is doing and how it's doing it,
this is a wonderful way to keep full control over your ecosystem.
If that level of intensity isn't what you need in a pipeline,
you're free to use the level 1 constructs to build
CodeBuild and CodePipeline projects.
This technique is just as easy as building any other construct,
as you're using the prepackaged defaults and options to build sources,
stages, and deployments.
There's still a basic element of simple scripting through build specs,
but this is still considered mainstream technology in CodeBuild.
To keep learning as clear as possible, the demo app,
which you remember was originally built by AWS Labs,
includes a basic two‑stage pipeline built with level 1 constructs.
As a new alternative,
Amazon's built a higher‑level construct solution library specifically for
pipelines ,initially called a Solutions Constructs library.
It's now just called the CDK Pipelines module,
which is easily found on the CDK docs.
As with other patterns and solutions,
Amazon's pre‑built many of the defaults and options for you,
making the creation of comprehensive pipelines easier now than it's ever been.
So I won't go through it in deep detail.
However.
A friend of mine who runs serverlessfirst.com,
Paul Swail,
wrote a really awesome article last year on the
nuances of building advanced pipelines.
The link is here,
but it's easy to find if you ever need it at serverlessfirst.com.
Paul,
with his longstanding skills and evangelism in
pushing pure serverless cloud tech,
demonstrates with scripting and level 1 constructs how to
build a 3‑stage dev staging prod pipeline.
He uses a bit of Bash scripting to dynamically assume and release deployment
roles in tandem with environment specific build spec files.
All in all,
he shows a pure method of imparting extreme control over the
creation and execution of your pipelines.
As I said, roles are created and released on the fly within the script,
allowing the pipeline to be region agnostic.
Using traditional methods,
build specs exist independently for each environment or stage.
And as I illustrated earlier, environment variables,
which he uses heavily, are a great way to pass information across boundaries.
In this case,
boundaries represents script shells physically outside of the AWS purview.
With these tools in mind,
you can see how this imbues a great sense of control over your pipeline,
all predominantly built with level 1 constructs/ To get a better understanding
of pipeline creation with fundamental level 1 constructs, let's take another
look at the pipeline that exists for the demo app.
So setting up CodeBuild projects with CodePipeline really
isn't that difficult if you just follow a simple set of
steps for setting everything up.
If we move back over to our code file or code stack,
I'll show how easy this is to do.
The first thing we do is create a couple of roles and policies.
So I create a CodeBuild role,
and then I make sure that the service principle is assumed by CodeBuild.
And then from there we simply add a few things to our CodeBuild policy,
such that we can access the S3 buckets that we need
to deploy to and grab assets from.
And then there's another quick step in here as well to ensure
that all resources can log appropriately.
From here we create a codePipelineRole as well and ensure that that role
can be assumed by the CodePipeline service principle.
And then similarly,
we ensure that CodePipeline can access the S3 buckets as well.
At that point, we simply set up the CodeBuild pipeline project,
which is fairly straightforward.
You can see that in this instance we pass all the environment
variables from the CDK code using environment variable syntax
through what will be used in the build spec.
And the reason this is done is because the build spec itself is
actually going to set the values in the React application.
And if I go over and look at the config.ts that's in the React application,
you can see that this is exactly how it understands what region Cognito's in,
the user pool, the app client, and the identity pool IDs are in,
as well as the API Gateway object.
And then the last thing we do for that CodePipeline rule is,
we need to make sure that it can actually batch and start builds.
So from there, all that's left is to actually create the CodePipeline pipeline,
in which case, all we do is,
we create a couple of outputs with CodePipeline artifacts
and then we can go create our stages.
There's the Source stage right there.
You can see that it comes out of the sourceAssetBucket.
And then there's the Build stage.
You can see that the action called build‑and‑deploy
simply uses the codeBuildProject, the source input,
and then it outputs the buildOutput, and that is really all there is to it.
Pretty simple to create level 1 constructs,
if you simply just follow a few rules.
Now that you've seen a few fundamental and advanced ways to construct pipelines,
let's talk briefly about the new CDK Pipelines module from Amazon.
As I said earlier,
I could go into an entire course on setting up comprehensive pipelines, so
a deep dive here is beyond the scope of this course.
In short,
this is a module built by Amazon representing a high‑level construct library,
including everything you need to easily set up pipelines.
Amazon calls it more opinionated,
which is natural for a higher‑level construct. In that regard,
the module, still in developer preview at the time of this
video, includes all tools needed to represent your pipeline
with all necessary stages and actions,
and as with other constructs, you can add any existing source,
including GitHub, CodeCommit, or S3 buckets. If you're
interested, Rico Huijbers wrote an AWS Developer blog post
that includes a nice sample walk‑through.
It's a great read that just takes about an hour or so to set up and
execute. For the current CDK‑approved documentation, the CDK Pipelines
module is fully defined in the CDK documentation.
Both of these are very easy to find by simply searching for CDK pipelines.
In either case, I'll go ahead and add these links to the course materials for you.