Similar to VPC characteristics,
both subnets and AZs can be retrieved dynamically as well.
Now this is inevitably something you will run into in your CDK career,
so it's worth showing briefly.
The concepts are all similar here, that the goal is to
dynamically assign attributes to the correct VPC with the
correct subnets in the desired availability zones. So we can
take the previous example of it further.
As you know,
we set some VPC values from context using the ternary in
the prior example. We can also retrieve a list of subnets
using this selectSubnets method, in this case,
looking for a public subnet in the VPC.
In addition,
there are a handful of properties we can use as well to
retrieve a list of availability zones in our current target
region for our current stack.
This makes it very easy to evaluate how many AZs are in a region and deploy accordingly.