The concept of testing with the CDK is quite comprehensive.
Once again,
I could dedicate an entire course to the universe of
testing using the Jest framework.
Fortunately,
testing the CDK isn't that much different than unit testing any other
application you may have written. For the most part,
the principles are all the same. In this module, I'll go through some
basic testing concepts, and then we'll use Jest to write a handful of
tests around our custom S3 website bucket construct.
There are a few resources out there that can help you
get set up with general CDK testing.
This is a topic you'll want to prioritize and master as you become
familiar with the basic concepts of the CDK.
First, the AWS CDK Developers Guide is a nice overview on testing topics,
including a nice lead in example of how to get started. Again, don't
feel like you have to write these links down quickly,
as you can come to both topics by simply searching for AWS CDK testing.
I'll also include the links in the course materials as well.
In addition,
CDK Workshop by AWS also has a great walkthrough geared mostly
towards the concepts I'll focus on around fine‑grained
assertions and validation test types.
At the moment, only TypeScript or JavaScript is usable with the Jest framework
to test constructs. The base concepts are extremely simple,
so the potential language barriers shouldn't be too obtrusive,
even if your CDK constructs are all based on Python or another language.
After all, assert is assert and expect is expect in a testing library.
I even follow the basic unit testing standards and set up tests
decorated with given, when, then designations.
Among these test types, Amazon first discusses snapshot tests.
I generally try to keep my opinions out of courses,
but I'm not a huge fan of snapshot tests unless you're simply
refactoring code and you want the end result to behave exactly
in the same way as you started.
Snapshot tests literally test the synthesized Cloud
Formation assembly against a previous version.
It's that simple.
If the two templates don't yield similar results,
the test will fail. If you're interested in more information on
snapshot tests, take a peek through the developers guide.
If you have any testing background at all, fine‑grained assertions
are going to be very familiar to you as with any structured unit
test library in any other coding language.
These are typical tests that use typical assertions through expect statements.
The primary difference you may encounter with CDK testing versus
regular application unit testing is that in general,
we test for expected properties or characteristics of resources
using the toHaveResource method of the Expect class.
Quite simply,
we instantiate a construct, and then we call the method
toHaveResource to assert whether or not a property we expect
has been created on that resource.
Simple in principle, right?
Lastly,
we have the concept of validation tests. Validation tests are used to
validate that a construct in some way does what we expect in various
situations such as a property throwing errors when we reach out of
boundary condition for our property. We once again used the expect
method, but in a case like this,
we use the toThrowError method to validate that the
condition correctly errors as expected.
So the first thing I need to do is help clear up some major
confusion floating around in the CDK Jest world.
There are a few libraries out there, at least as of this course,
that have confused a lot of folks.
First,
if you simply run a CDK init, the scaffolding process will create test files
for you using the @aws‑cdk/assert library as shown here.
And as of just recently,
they've started aliasing expect to expectCDK when
calling these test resource methods.
However, if you open the CDK documentation on the Amazon site,
most of the examples, including the workshops,
still reference the deeper Jest library shown here.
As a result,
you'll find a lot of blog posts asking why folks' test
methods don't function properly.
Now make no mistake.
You can use both of these libraries, and you can use them side by side.
In this example,
the first line of code uses the expect function from the Jest sub library.
The second expectCDK call uses the native expect
call from the base assert library.
That's confusing, isn't it?
Well, as it turns out,
the Jest library creates these functions as
extenders to the base assert library.
I honestly have no idea why Amazon did this,
and I'm not sure where they're going with it.
Just understand what these are and where they come from, and you'll
be okay. After we talk about test types for a bit,
I'll hop over to the demo construct and show you an example of this.
Fine‑grained assertions verify one part of the construct's behavior,
not unlike a simple unit test.
Let's take a simple example of the single behavior principle.
Let's create a test that validates that the construct creates a
simple S3 bucket we could expect. To set this up, I'm simply
calling the test method like this.
Then, in my given statement, I create a new empty stack.
After that, I set up my WHEN section,
referring to when I create a stack with these properties.
And then finally,
my THEN section uses the alias expectCDK method to execute the two assertions.
First,
I simply assert that there's exactly one S3 bucket created by the construct.
I take that a step farther with a second assertion that the bucket
includes the index and error properties as shown, Now in unit testing
CDK constructs, you'll spend a lot of time looking at CloudFormation
properties to build your assertions.
You'll certainly want to bookmark this page for that purpose,
as the property nomenclature in CloudFormation is both difficult
to find and doesn't come up in IntelliSense.
I'll go ahead and add this link to course materials as well.
So let's take a look at that last test type, and that's validation tests.
Validation tests are intended to test that some logical functionality you create
behaves as expected or throws an error when it should.
So before we set up our test,
let's add a few lines of code just below our
constructor in our construct TypeScript file.
I'm simply checking to ensure that the project name
is 12 characters or less here.
And if it's not, I throw an error with that specific error text.
Then, I set up the test again as we did before. And finally,
in this case, I once again call the expect method.
However, as you can see,
I've set the project name to be longer than 12 characters,
and then I simply chain the toThrowError method onto the
end of the expect assertion with the same error referenced
from the construct class file.
And in this case,
the test passes as a result of the forced out of bounds condition.
So hopefully it's clear that creating tests with a combination of fine
grained and validation assertions isn't terribly complicated.
And just like general unit testing,
you can see how testing IAC in this way can ensure a higher
quality standard with much more reliable builds.
So if I flip back over to our demo construct in Visual Studio Code,
let me first show you exactly what I was talking about with the confusion in
the libraries. Right up here you can see that straight out of the gate from
the CDK init, I have the expectCDK alias library from the expect base library
coming out of the cdk/assert library.
And if I go look at that by right‑clicking and saying go to the
definition, and then from inside that library,
I open up expect.js, you can see that here is the root expect library.
The exports here and all of the expect logic is included in this library.
Now remember this was @aws‑cdk/assert.
And if I go ahead and close that and go back and look at the other library,
which is referenced heavily from inside the examples, the jets
is sub library, and I go to that definition,
you can see that there's a namespace in here by which
five extra functions have been created.
And then from there, if I open jest.js,
you can see that here are the extender functions that were created.
So that's what caused a little bit of the confusion.
Now if I go ahead and close that and simply just open one of our sample tests,
for the most part, I used expectCDK because it seems somewhat new from AWS.
And if I had to guess, I'd say this might be the direction they're moving toward.
So let's take a quick look at the test that I've created for this construct.
First, I created a quick out‑of‑the‑box snapshot test,
in which case I set up all the properties, instantiated the object, and now
what we're doing is calling a send utils to CloudFormation,
which takes the stack, and it matches it against a previous
snapshot with the toMatchSnapshot function.
Now I don't have a snapshot created right at the moment,
but if I actually run an npm test,
the first thing it'll do is it'll create a snapshots
folder in my directory listing.
And if you look at it, it'll just be CloudFormation JSON. Now
that's a problem here with the way that we've set up this
construct. We dynamically name S3 buckets.
So every single time I run a snapshot test,
it's going to fail because every single time the CloudFormation JSON is
going to be slightly different with the bucket name.
So for all intents and purposes,
I'm going to go ahead and comment out that snapshot test,
and we'll focus on the fine grained and validation tests.
So the next test that I created is that the construct creates a website bucket.
Now I went ahead and set up the basic properties
again and instantiated the construct.
And now what I'm calling is an expectCDK with a stack,
and I'm using the countResources function to make sure that there is
exactly one AWS S3 bucket created as a result of the test.
Now that's a very simple test, but it's also an obvious one.
If a bucket's not created at all, that test is going to fail.
And there's a lot of reasons why the creation of a bucket could fail.
It could fail because you put special characters in the bucket name or
because your bucket name is simply just too long to be created.
So I took it one step further on the fine‑grained
test and used a few properties.
And in this case,
I used toHaveResource method again looking for an
AWS S3 bucket, but in this case, I dove into the CloudFormation properties,
and I'm actually looking for a bucket that has the error
document and the index documents set to index.html.
So those are two very simple, but very effective fine‑grained tests.
So let me scroll down a little bit further and show you that
I created two validation tests as well.
But before I actually open up that validation test,
let me move back over to our construct and show you that right underneath the
constructor, I created an if statement here that checks to make sure that the
project name is not longer than 12 characters.
Now as you're going to see in the second test,
I also put an if statement in here that checks a regex match to make sure that
the project name doesn't contain any special characters.
Because think about it, I put the project name down
here in the name of the bucket.
So if there are special characters in it or the name is simply just too long,
this bucket's going to fail because it can't take special
characters, and it can't be longer than AWS will allow.
So looking at those two tests,
the first validation test says project name is less than 13 characters.
I set it up in the same way,
and naturally I created the project name to be longer than 12 characters.
And then at that point,
I chain the toThrowError method at the bottom, looking for the project name
must be less than 13 characters error. On the project name containing special
characters, in this case, I named the project with,
you know, my cat walked over my keyboard,
so to speak, and we're looking for the Project name must not contain
special characters error thrown from the construct.
So I'll run an npm run build and an npm run test, keeping in mind, in
this case, that I commented out the snapshot test. And you can see that all three of my tests passed in that case.