Welcome to the
Bootstrap five course
where we're going to show
you how you can quickly
design responsive mobile first
websites using the
Bootstrap framework.
Name is Lauren
said, I'm gonna be
your instructor for this course.
I come to with many years of
web development
experience and I really
enjoy working with
bootstrap because it
allows me to create
websites quickly,
is mobile first websites
that are fully responsive,
adding in the
various classes and
attributes into your HTML
elements in order to
construct and bring
the Bootstrap and
the power of Bootstrap
into your web pages.
There's a lot of really useful
components that you can make use
of in order to create
your websites and really
make them stand out.
We are fully responsive
mobile already,
so it doesn't matter
what size screen
your users are visiting
your website with.
Bootstrap is gonna be
able to take care of it.
This course is going to cover
the commonly used functions and
components and classes
for Bootstrap,
including how to set up
bootstrap containers,
also the Bootstrap grid,
how that works and how you can
set up the different rows.
Columns, structure your webpage
content using text typography,
how to update and
include images,
making them fully responsive,
creating tables and the
various color classes that are
available within
Bootstrap to make
your websites colorful
and really stand out.
There's alert components,
accordion components,
and there's a lot of really
useful components that come
alongside Bootstrap that are
commonly used in order
to create websites.
So the buttons, and that's
one of my favorite
components within
Bootstrap because those buttons
look amazing within
your webpages.
There's the card component,
the navigation in
the navigation bar,
and how you can create a
responsive navigation bar
that resizes,
has the hamburger icon and that
opens up on the mobile
screens vertically,
on the largest sized
screens horizontally.
So this is built-in and really
easy to apply within
your websites,
making them mobile friendly.
And then really
amazing components
like the carousel, the modal,
and other utilities that
you can make use of,
style your website and
really bring it to life.
Bootstrap is the world's most
popular front end
open source toolkit.
It lets you rapidly
create, customize,
and develop websites using
the Bootstrap components.
Bootstrap five is new and
updated version of Bootstrap,
so it doesn't include
jQuery anymore.
A lot of the classes are still
the same as Bootstrap four,
and I'm gonna be covering
classes within the
upcoming lessons of
this course also
includes some of
the older versions of Bootstrap.
The new versions of
Bootstrap come available.
I am gonna be updating
the content source
code is included.
And one of the best
ways to learn is to
try the code out for yourself.
Prior HTML knowledge
is essential,
focused on Bootstrap
and applying
the various classes in order
to make things happen
with Bootstrap,
Let's open up her editors and
start writing some
code with Bootstrap.