We're gonna be exploring
the accordions
and how you can add
accordions to the page.
So it's basically
what an accordion is.
It's a block of content
that can contain a
hidden elements,
so you can select them
and that's going to
open up the accordion items.
Selecting the other
headings within
the accordion are going to
open up those other pieces
of content you can set to start
out by having it visible.
If you do want the
accordion item visible,
you can set that value into
it where it starts out
where it's not collapsed.
So doing adding in show
will have it as opened.
And then the accordion
functionality will still work the
same way if you
remove out the show,
that's gonna start by default
having all of them closed.
And where you need to click
the heading in order to open
up the related content
within the accordion.
This lesson, we're
going to be looking at
the accordion component that
allows you to collapse
content and open content up.
And this is going to
require some attributes.
So let's create the elements.
And this is gonna be the
mean class where we're
going to set the accordion
within this class.
And then we'll add in the
components within here as well.
So this is just using the
accordion class and you
need to give this an ID so
that we can reference it.
So I'm gonna just give
it an ID of a CC1.
Then you can add in the
various accordion items
and set them up as a class.
And these are just listed
as accordion items.
That's gonna be accordion item.
Then within here, we need
to set some headings
for the accordion and
then also buttons so that
we can collapse the
accordion content.
The heading is the
one that the users
are going to be able to see.
Setup another div for that.
This is going to be using
the class accordion header
and give this one also.
And also give this one an ID
for the accordion header.
Then contained within here,
use a button and we'll
set the class of
the button to be the
accordion button.
So this is gonna be the
one that's going to
activate the accordion
to open and close.
You can set it up
as a type button.
And then it uses the attributes.
So data BFS toggle,
which is going to allow
you to toggle open and
closing of the collapse object.
And it's also going to
require an attribute that's
gonna be the data dash bs.
And this is gonna be looking
for the target object.
Wherever you're gonna give
the ID of the target.
I'll just call it open one.
So it's gonna be the first
one that we're going to open.
And this is where that's
going to be targeted towards.
And then within the button,
you can add in some content
within the button object.
And I'll just call
it opened one.
We can save that.
So that's gonna give
us this open one.
Within that same object.
Let's set the
collapsible content.
So we did have the header.
I'm actually going to set
this as an H2 so that
the header object is going to be
separate within the
accordion item.
So open up that and
set that as a header
to that will just update that.
And then just after
the header to
this is where we're going
to set the content.
We need to give this an ID.
The ID has to match with
the ID that we're
setting to open.
Here we had set as head
one is going to be
the collapsible button link
That's going to
open the content.
And the content that's going to
open is going to
be under open one.
Give this and make
sure that this
matches because this is how
it's going to get identified.
Let's set a class.
And the class that we're
setting is going to be
accordion, dash, COH, lops.
This is gonna be a
collapse object.
And then we have an option.
If we want to show
it as not collapsed,
then you can add in the show.
For the data BS
parent attribute.
We want to set it to the parent,
which is gonna be the
accordion one object.
So that's going to
tie it all together
within the same
accordion content.
You can add some content there.
Within the example.
Let's add in another div.
We're going to wrap the content
with accordion body class.
There's quite a few classes
that we need to add in here.
So go to, go over it again.
So for the accordion,
you need to give it an ID.
And then the elements
within the accordion are
gonna get tied to
that mean parent.
So the collapsible content is
gonna get tied to
the mean parent.
Then for the first item,
you need to give it a
class of accordion item
that's going to wrap
the content within
the accordion item.
And then you can set an
element that's gonna show,
that's gonna hide and
close the content.
And then this one
needs to a class of
accordion header and also
assign an ID to it so that we
can reference it if needed.
And then within there,
I've added in a button.
And this button is going to
toggle opening and closing
the accordion content and
using the button class
of accordion button.
And then also setting
a type within
the HTML element has
an attribute button.
And then using the data BS,
toggle is setting
it to collapse.
And then we also need
to set a target.
And this target needs to use
the hash in order to
identify the target.
To open.
It makes sure that
you identify it by
the ID using the
hash and set that.
And then this is the content
that you want to display.
The content that's
hidden is going to
be wrapped within
the Korean collapse.
You have an option to show it.
Or if you don't have the show,
that's going to automatically by
default height the content.
And it just says we're
tying to the other IDs,
the attribute of data bss
parent also needs to have
the hash and that
needs to correspond to
the main parent class for
the accordion itself.
And then for the body contents,
you can add it in
and wrap it within
an element with the
class of accordion body.
Having all of that will
allow you to open and
close toggling the
accordion content.
You can add additional
accordion items using
the same structure
into the elements.
Just give them separate IDs.
So this one will be two,
that will be two.
It's going to open the number
two and actually still
this is number one because
we're still going to the parent.
And then you can add
some different content.
And I still need to update this,
that this should update
and have an ID of two.
So that will distinguish the
two buttons so that whatever
one-year clicking
and it's going to
highlight the active
one, turning that blue.
Let's add one more
so it can create
a third accordion item.
So update this to be had three.
So it's different to open three.
And so this will provide us
another element
within the accordion.
The parent is still the same,
so it's tying it all together.
And then also let's update
the button to say three.
These are all accordion items
that you can open
and close as needed.
This is a really
useful component that
you can use and you will need to
have the JavaScript
library in order
for this to work
fully responsive.
And it will take up
whatever space is
available within the text area,
automatically opening
them, closing the content,
showing it and hiding it.