Let's not like it's
showing you some of
the really cool things that
you can do with buttons,
buttons and Bootstrap, or one
of the most fun components.
As they give you this really
nice colorful buttons
when you hover over them,
they can highlight.
You can also do
buttons as outlines.
You can also add in the
loading spinner options,
set buttons within groups,
set buttons horizontally,
group them together,
and then also how you
can set and add in
a drop-down menu within
the button grouping.
One of the most fun things about
bootstrap are the buttons.
And buttons can be applied to
any element just like any
other class can be done.
So let's turn this
into a button,
will turn the div into a button.
Of course, you can
apply button classes,
two buttons as well.
So this is just a
default button object
and we don't have any colors
or any properties applied to it.
So set this up as
a primary button.
So that gives you this
button type of effect.
Also of course, you can use
the button elements and set
these up as type of button.
And within here,
we'll set up a class.
And using the button class.
Give it a separate button.
By default, if you
just use button,
you're not going to see
any of the borders,
any of the colors.
So you do need to
set a color class.
So you always need to
have a secondary class.
And they do have all
of the primary colors.
We've got secondary as well.
The primary, the secondary.
So all of the typical
color classes
that we've looked at before
in the earlier lessons.
Let's create a few more buttons.
We've got the secondary,
we've got the info button.
We've also got the warning,
the danger, all of the ones
that you might expect.
There's also a success button.
There's the danger button.
You can add all of
these to your page.
They're all nice and colorful
buttons and they're really fun,
interactive components
that you can add in.
And this makes it just
adding in these
buttons really easily.
When you hover over the
buttons, they highlight.
There's also, if you want,
you can do the dark, you
can do the light as well.
So updating the button,
let's get onto dark.
And we can also set a button.
So turn a button into a link.
That will turn that
button actually
into a link like this.
So it's another option that
you have four buttons.
You also have options to do
the outlines of the buttons.
So let's copy the buttons
that we've just created.
And I'll bring those down
into the fluid class.
Instead of using the button,
we're going to set
the button outline
and that's another option
class for buttons.
So adding in the outline
option for the buttons,
what that will do
is essentially it's
going to reverse the button.
So creating a white button,
but using the same color scheme
for the text and for the
border of the button.
This is another
option that you have
four buttons on your setting up
these nice colorful
buttons and Bootstrap,
whatever your preference is.
And there's the eight
different effects.
These also have
the hover effects
where they fill in as
you hover over it.
There's also different buttons
sizes that you can apply.
And so you can do these in
a combination of classes.
There's a button large option,
so that makes the button larger.
There's also a button
small options.
So going into the class again,
and let's set this button.
This button is small,
so it makes it
slightly smaller than
the other buttons.
You can also do a button
that can go full width
across for the button.
Let's go over to here.
We've got the button danger.
And if we want this button
to take up the full block,
you've got an option
called btn block.
What button block does
is this allows us to
take the full block of available
content for the button.
And I'm going to turn this into
a div instead of a button.
By default, it's not taking
the full block as
the component does need
to have the full block.
We'll wrap the button
within another parent.
So that allows us to take
the full block of code.
The parent should be taking
the full available element span.
So let's add in to the
class and set it up as
the D grid that
will allow the button to take
the full available spacing.
That's a full width
button that you can
set using the button block.
You can also set buttons as
active and also
disabled as well.
So if we've got a
button class here,
and let's set this
one to active.
That's going to
highlight that gray one.
And essentially turn it to
similar to what we've
got within here.
But there's no
hover effect on it.
There's also for the button,
we can set the
button to disabled.
If the button is disabled,
then we can't hover over it.
Nothing will happen when
you try to click it.
There's also some new
options for spinner buttons,
where you can set the spinner
elements in the button.
So let's set this up as
a button and give it
a button primary.
The spinner is just going
to be a separate element
that's gonna be sitting
within a parent element.
You can set up the
class for this,
set the various spinner
clauses for it.
This one is just gonna
be using a border.
And let's save that.
So that's going to create
this type of effect.
You can also add in
some text after it.
So if you wanted to do
something like loading,
that will apply that
loading type effect to it.
There's a few different types of
spinner classes
that you can apply.
So this is the primary.
Let's set a few other colors
to make it more colorful.
And then for the spinner,
we can set a spinner border SM.
So that's the spinner
border dash SM.
So it's going to make
a smaller effect
for the spinner or
the smaller border.
There's also the grow.
Let's set that and
set the spinner grow.
And you can also set that as SM.
Let's set up this
says spinner grow.
So instead of spinner border,
we can set it as spinner grill.
You can also group
buttons together.
That's another option.
If you want to group a
bunch of buttons together,
there's an option to set up
a grouping of the buttons.
So let's set up another
set of buttons.
Give this one a parent.
And the parent will
be where we're going
to be grouping the
buttons together,
setup a button group,
and then all of
the buttons within
here are gonna be
grouped automatically.
So setting up some buttons,
you can use the divs
for the button.
Adding in several different
buttons there that group
them altogether within
a separate div chunk.
You can also, for the group,
you can apply button
clauses to the group.
So if you wanted
this to be large,
create a large group of buttons.
Let's create some different
colors for the buttons front.
So you can distinguish
between the buttons.
When you group them, there's
gonna be no spacing between
the buttons where we were
typically adding the buttons.
There is some spacing
between the buttons.
You can also group
them vertically.
So it's another option
for getting buttons.
Create a, another
group of buttons and
set this one as
group and vertical.
That's groups them vertically
like this for the buttons.
You can also have a
drop-down within a button.
So that's another nice option
to have within the button.
So let's convert this info into
a drop-down where we've got
it within a button group.
And then we're going
to wrap another parent
around it and give
this a class of button group.
This is grouping
the buttons that
are contained
within this parent.
Then here we can have
multiple items and
group those together.
So this can be click one,
and this can be clicked two.
And let's add one more
for the dropdown.
So we've got three
click options there.
Right now.
They're just grouped together.
But we can turn them into
a dropdown item that's
using the drop-down menu
in order to convert them
into a dropdown item.
And we might want to keep this,
the first one open there
just as a regular button and
have this to toggle to
open the other buttons.
So let's add that in and
set this up as a class.
That's our secondary button.
And it's gonna be a
dropdown toggle button.
And add in a data BS for
the toggle component.
That will allow us to toggle
the drop-down option
on the button,
set that as dropdown.
Rogers type in open into it.
That's going into
the first item.
And then the rest
of the buttons,
we're grouping these
in another element.
So pulling those altogether
within a, another grouping.
And this is where we're going
to have the drop-down menu.
Set this up as a class
and set up to drop down.
And that should be one word
dropped down, dash menu.
Then for each one of these,
these are not gonna be buttons,
they can be dropdown items and
the toggle should
actually be dropped down.
So click that and
that's going to
open up the drop-down menu.
That's how you can
create a sub menu
using the buttons and
the drop-down option.
Let's try to have some
fun with the buttons.