Cards allow us to provide
some structured content and
display images heading,
footer, and text.
We can also place text and
other components on top of
the image depending on how
we want to structure it.
And it works really well when
it's presented within the grid.
As an example here
where we've got
several different columns within
the grid and then we're
presenting the content.
These are all the same cards.
They're just being
presented nice and
neatly within a unified format.
And the unified
structure all done
with the Bootstrap
classes and using
the cart classes card component
allows us to create some
structured content.
First, we create a
parent for the card
in order to create a
basic card object,
give it a class of card.
And then within the card,
let's add in a body.
So this is gonna be the
contents of the card.
So that's where all of
the card body constants
are going to go.
And of course you can just
like the other components,
you can set them up and
whatever properties you,
whatever class you
apply to the element,
it'll take those
properties of that class.
If we had some content there,
it provides this type
of structured content.
You cannot in a header and a
footer as well to the card.
So again, that gives us more
options For structure of
the content in order to present
the content in different
ways within the card,
setting up a card header.
And this allows us to prevent
that information within
a header type structure
that also we can set in and
set a footer that's
under the card footer.
And that can maybe contain
some contact information
about a person.
You can also set the
various backgrounds of
the cards using
the different background
colors that we've seen.
So if we want to apply,
we can mix and match.
So adding in a background
for primary that we'll
set that to blue,
consent the text to light
so you better see the text.
There's also images that
you can add to the card.
So adding an image to
the top of the card.
So let's add in an image
and give it a class.
This is going to
be card image top.
We need to set the
source for the image.
I do have the logo
for Bootstrap going
to use as the image for
the top of the card.
So that provides
this type of effect.
If you have multiple cards.
So if you have an
element and you've got
a grid structure
for the elements,
and then you've got a couple.
You've got across here.
These are just columns.
And you add in the
cards into the columns.
Select the entire card object.
And then for the column,
let's select a couple of
columns and duplicate those.
That gives us this type of
effects where we've got the
using the grid with
the three columns of
the card content.
You can also overlay text
within the cards as well.
On top of the image,
you can add in some
text over the image.
So that's within the image
just underneath there.
Let's add in another
div and give this one
called or should be
called cloths. Image.
Overlay allows us to place
some text over the image.
And I'll just use the class of
card text that allows us to
have the image over the text,
just like an example.
That's the far
right one that has
that option applied to it.
If you want it to have a button.
You can also add
in a button there.
That button will also
be over the image.
Just have to be
careful that you do
have enough spacing for
the image in order to
apply the card content.
You might want to adjust those
on different sized screens.
Let's keep it responsive,
but we're gonna break
that one on the MD.
That will break
the last column on
MD and provide this type of
effect for the page elements.
So that when that resizes
and it goes larger,
we still have enough
space there for
the text and for the button
that's over the image.
And then on the
smaller size screens,
we're letting it take
the full available
with the parent element.