This lesson we're
gonna be looking at
the carousel component
in Bootstrap.
So bringing in three
different images
that we're going to
apply to the carousel.
The carousel automatically
rotates to the next image.
You have an option to add
in indicators that you can
go to selected images with
the indicators as well.
You can use the icons
on the left for
Previous and Next images to
slide the carousel
over to those images,
you should have images that
have the same dimensions.
Otherwise you end up with
the carousel that's
adjusting in height.
So when you are creating images,
try to cut really large images
and have the same dimensions
for those images,
meaning their width and
height are gonna be
the same so that
the carousel component resizes
and looks really smooth on
different sized screens.
The Bootstrap carousel
allows you to
create a slideshow
component that
allows the Bootstrap to
cycle through images
in the component.
So let's go ahead and
we're going to create
a main parent div.
And this is gonna be the class
that's going to
hold the carousel,
give it an ID or a class of
carousel, and then slide.
And that's going to
create the slideshow.
And it also needs an attribute,
set it up at a data BS.
And right, and that value
should be equal to carousel.
That's the parent
for the carousel.
And then in order to
set up the carousel,
let's add in the images
within the carousel.
So that's gonna be
contained within a class
called carousel image or enter.
And this is where you would
add in all of the items.
So those are as well
contained within
a class called carousel items.
And each one of the items
gives it a class of item,
and you can select one
as the active ones.
So this is the starting one
that's going to start out
at create some images in there.
And I do have the image
that the bootstrap image,
so we'll just load that image
into the Bootstrap image.
Then you can also set a
class for that as well.
So setting it up as d block,
so it takes the full
width across the image.
So there's our image there.
Now the images within
the carousel should be
the same height and width
in order for it
to work properly.
So I do only just have
the one image that
I'm working with.
So I'm going to set
a default width
for the image that's gonna
be hard-coded for the image
itself to be a width of 500.
And of course, when
you are creating the
images for your carousel,
makes sure that the
dimensions are the
same for those images.
So that it looks nice and neat.
Once you construct the
carousel content in
a few other images
into these ones should
just be carousel items.
Don't set them as active.
And now we see that
we already have
the rotation to the next item.
There are some options that
you can set indicators,
and indicators allow us to move
to the next item
within the carousel.
So let's set up a parent for
that and give this a
class, indicators class.
It's the parent for
the indicators.
And you need to create
as many indicators as
you have items
within the carousel.
So that thought matches
up in the user can click
the indicators in order to
move to the next available item.
We need to set a data BS target.
For the indicators to work.
This is gonna be whatever we're
setting for the
parent container.
We didn't set an ID for this.
We'll set it up as car one.
And this is going to be an ID.
So use the hash car one
in order to select it.
Also set the active
class on the button.
That's gonna be the first
representing the first.
And we also need
to set the data BS
slide to let it know
which slide this is
going to connect to.
And these are zero-based.
Starting at 0 would be
the first slide within
the carousel items.
So select that and let's
create three other ones.
And then just update
which image that the
data is going to
slide to elect for
the parent and assign
an ID to the parent.
That's going to match the
ID for the indicators,
again to update the images.
So there are actually going
to be different images using
the placeholder image analysts
at the image size to be 500.
So that way the second image is
going to be different than
the first two images.
And I'll also update
the image source,
so off of the logo to be
different again for this image.
And this allows you to set
the default size for the
image as well as customize.
The colors and the output
for the image as well.
This is coming from
placeholder.com.
There's a number of
sources where you
can get placeholder images.
So this is just one of them.
And that's how you can bring
a placeholder image directly
within your project as you're
developing it with if you
don't have the image,
let's update this
to be times 300.
And I'll also force
this height to be 300.
So all of our images
have the share,
the shared dimensions
and apply some text.
So now we've got distinct
images within the carousel.
And let's just
update this cut in
the wrong place where
it's sliding too,
should be within the opening
button tag. Save that.
And now we can click the
indicators to move through
to the different images that
we have within the carousel.
Let's add in the left
and right controls.
We'll add them in as buttons.
Just below the inner
content for the carousel,
a class called carousel control.
And for the previous,
we're going to give it a class
of carousel control previous,
set the button to be a button.
We need to also link to
the data BS, target value.
And this is gonna be
linking to the main parent,
which is going to be car one.
Once again to the
mean parent element
that's going to contain
the carousel object.
And also we need to add in
another attribute to set it
to where it's gonna slide.
So it's going to simply
move to the previous one.
Once this button is clicked,
set that up as an attribute
within the button tag.
And then for the button,
let's set up an
element within there.
So create the indicator within
the button carousel
control previous icon.
And that could just
be a blank element.
And that gives us
the controller on
the left-hand side
that can move it to
the previous slide
in the carousel.
Let's also add in one.
For the next.
You can copy and paste
the previous structure
is gonna be the same.
Other than we need to change
the class values is to
the previous two next,
and it's still links
out to the same target.
So once you update those,
you should have an icon for the
next and then for the previous,
creating the carousel component.
So let's suggest these images
that once we're expanding,
we'll set the image.
We're not going to fix
the width of the image.
And we can set these to be
width for the image
using a class of fluid.
For the image that it takes
all the available space.
The best practices to get
really large images
for your carousel.
And let's just simply
we'll add up the height.
They're the only one that works
really well is going to
be the Bootstrap one.
As I've adjusted, these
dimensions are different.
So you're going to have
this type of effect where
the carousel is going to
be changing in height.
And so that's again
why you need to
have the same dimension images.
In order to output
the content properly
within the slider.
Go ahead and try it, the
carousel component in Bootstrap,
and it'd be ready to move
on to the next lesson.