Good to be covering
how you can update
the different properties
of the page elements,
adding in padding and margins,
also styling them in
different formats.
So there's giving you some
examples of how we can
take up the horizontal spacing,
the vertical spacing in addition
to how we can select text,
turn it to lowercase,
capitalize, update
the text sizes,
update some of the
properties for the text.
Let's look at some of
the utilities that
are available within Bootstrap.
Setup and create a class.
I'm going to add
in the box class.
And this is coming
from our local CSS
where we've got the box
where we're applying
a border that we can
see the various elements
off from the page.
Just call it element one.
Then apply the different
utilities and properties to
the various elements so that
we can see a difference
in how they're being
displayed on the page.
Let's just over on the
right-hand side there.
And we can add in borders
around the elements.
So if for instance we have an
element with out-of-order,
we can add the border
in to that element.
Element five doesn't
have a border.
So we can set a border class
that's going to
automatically set
a border around the element.
We can specify
whether the border,
if it's just on the top or
the bottom or the start.
Setting the border start adds
the border only in on the
start of the element.
We can actually update
these instead of
the blocks border
so that we can see
the entire element using
the Bootstrap border clauses
can also set a border width.
These are options
here where we can
have border one and
going all the way
to border for changing these
values is going to change
the border width,
making them thicker.
As the increase.
We can also set border colors,
just as we've seen with the
color classes in Bootstrap.
These are also
available for borders.
So there's primary,
there's the secondary,
there's the success, danger.
So all of the typical
ones that we've seen
within the other elements
that we can apply.
These are all also available.
Just selecting some of
them that are available.
And let's set this as
info that can set the
different border.
You can also around elements.
That's another option with
the elements where we
can set them and
around the elements.
So let's create
another container.
And we'll just
simply use that one
as another example of what
we can do with the elements.
We already have the border here.
Let's get rid of that.
And we're going to
set the rounded,
the rounded we saw
already within
the images that we have the
rounded option for the image.
It's slightly
rounds the borders.
You can do a rounded
circle as well.
So that's another option
where that's going
to turn it all
into a circle, rounded circle.
It's going to create a so-called
circle within the element.
Let's set the background
of this to be primary.
And we'll also set a
background of this one to be
dangerous so that we can
see what we've got
for the element.
So the circle is going to have
only the contained contents.
So if you have multiple elements
here and just add in
some line breaks,
the bigger the higher
the more height that you
have for the element,
the larger it's going to appear.
There's also a rounded
pill option that one
is going to be more of
a flat type Circle.
And actually that's
rounded pill not pull.
Let's update that. And again,
it's looks better if you
update the size of it.
So that's the pill effect there.
And notice that the text
is always still going
to be aligning up
at the top left.
You can also set the
width of an element.
So if we want it to be
twenty-five percent of the width,
we can do a W 25,
that's going to make
the parent element 25.
We can also set to 50 to 75200.
So taking it to 50,
that's going to set
that element to be 50.
Let's update and add in a
background color so that
we can see the entire
contents of the element.
In addition to the width,
we can also set a height
for the elements.
So that way we don't have
to use the line breaks.
We can use the Bootstrap
classes in order to set
a height that's gonna
be using the H dash.
If we want it to be set to 50%,
that's gonna take
50% of the parent.
So let's hide a style to
the parent and set a
height for this parent.
So now we can see that.
What it's doing is
it's automatically
taking 50% of the height.
That's off of the
parent element.
So you do need to have a
height set for the parent in
order to be able to see it
on auto height as well.
So apply the auto height and
that's using the MH auto.
And that will
automatically include
the height to take this
to be an height value,
you can also take 25 of
the Ville percentage
of the height that's
available from the
parent element sizing.
There's also margins and
padding that you can set for
the elements that's using
the different sizes.
You can set the
margin and padding.
Top, bottom left, right,
just as it normally
would do with CSS.
You can also set
the padding across
the x-axis or across the y-axis.
And that's for both the
padding and for the margin.
So in order to set that,
let's say for this element,
we want to add in some padding.
I want to add in
padding at the top.
And the size of the padding
that we want to add.
We can set from 0 to five,
or we can also use an auto
for automatic padding.
So setting this element
up for padding,
and let's set it to be for,
for padding at the top.
That's going to
provide that padding
near the top of the element.
You can also center elements.
So we've got the pill elements.
We can use the margin on the
x-axis and set that to auto.
So that will center an
element on the x-axis.
So auto is the same
as if we're setting
the automatic whenever we're
applying the styling to it,
let's add in some more.
Or if we want a margin,
we want a margin of
five to that element.
That's going to apply
that in margin around
the element for
the size of five,
for the elements as well,
you can add in and have shadow
effects for the element.
I'm going to make this bigger.
That's just setting the height.
So that gives us more space to
work with within the element
as we're setting some that
are gonna be the different
heights and widths.
And when we're adjusting it,
we're actually running out of
space there on the pixels.
Let's update that.
And for the element number four,
let's apply shadow
effect for that element.
So apply some padding.
We'll do a padding of four,
adding in the shadow got a
small shadow fault saddle or
a large shadow side in
the large shadow
effect, default shadow.
So in this case it's by default,
it's just taking the
default property.
If we want to align all
of the texts within
the children text and we
can center align the text.
So that's gonna take for
all of the children,
you can select the
elements independently,
the alignment for those could
also do a text transform,
applying and it
transforming the text.
I think we already
have it capitalized.
So let's change
it to upper case,
and that's updating the
text to be uppercase.
There's also a text lowercase,
but converts the text all into
lowercase and apply
to this element.
Let's capitalize the text.
It capitalized the text.
Notice if you already have
the text as uppercase,
it's not going to apply
any changes to it.
So these all have
to be lowercase,
as it is case-sensitive in
order to capitalize it.
If you do have any letters
that are already uppercase,
it's not going to change
the letters that are
within the text.
It's only going to be updating
the first character
within the string values.
We can also update
the font size.
So setting the font size,
we can go from one,
fs dash one, which is
gonna be the largest size.
And then going all the
way down to FSC six,
which is gonna be the
smallest size for the texts.
So F0, F6. So you've got
some sizing options in
order to update the
sizing of the text.
And that's just going to
make the text smaller.
You can also make
the text larger.
It can also apply
bold to the text.
So let's go back up to here to
this example and
make this text bold.
And that's using the FW.
Fw bold is going to
bold the elements.
You can make it italic
using the class.
So taking element number three,
and we'll apply the
FST italic class.
So that makes the
element Italic also
adjust the line height
for the elements.
So let's update the line height.
And that's LH, the
line-height large.
So it gives us more spacing.
There's also a text
decoration that we can set to
underline text content that
the text decoration underline.
If it is already underlined,
you can remove that
underlining by doing
text-decoration, none.
You can also do a
strikethrough by
doing a line through it.
So those are some
of the options that
are available within
the utilities
in order to update
the way that the text
is being handled,
as well as how the
elements are going to be
appearing on the page. So
go ahead and try it out.