hi and welcome to our bootstrap introduction course where we're going to be building out a
website project from scratch using bootstrap.
And if you've never used boots dropped before,
you're gonna be amazed at how easy it is to construct websites quickly and easily.
And these websites are all fully responsive.
As you're going to see an upcoming lessons,
there's a number of amazing components that you can really easily add to your project.
My name is Lawrence.
I'm gonna be instructor for this course.
I come to you with many years of Web developer experience.
And using bootstrap is one of my favorite front end frameworks to develop websites really
quickly and rapidly and that are fully responsive.
Takes all of the tweaking of styling out of the picture and allows you to focus on the
design of the site and out of the box.
There's some really amazing things you can do with bootstrap.
There's a guy be a step by step course,
introducing you to how boots drop works,
the concepts of bootstrap and why you should be using bootstrap in order to create websites
.
So I'm gonna be walking you through some of those in the upcoming lessons.
We're also gonna be developing a website from scratch as we progress through the lessons
and I show you more and more about bootstrap.
This is an example of the website that we are going to be creating and notice that it's got
a number of bootstrap components and silly structured website fully functional.
It can also be adjusted and fully responsive.
So the navigation bar as we shrink it down,
it collapses and we can click and un collapse,
that the coating is going to be done on the left hand side and the editor,
and on the right hand side,
I'll have the window open,
that you can view the adjustments and how it's being presented within the content.
And what effect adding the various classes is gonna have on the project that you don't need
to know.
CSS JavaScript.
You do need to know HTML.
So you do need to have some basic understanding of HTML and start during the content of
your HTML elements and how to apply attributes because mainly with bootstrap it supplying
the right classes.
And then,
of course,
there are some attributes that needed to be applied in order to introduce the JavaScript
functionality.
I'm gonna walk you through how to get boots drop how to get set up with bootstrap,
creating a basic bootstrap template,
and then how you can apply some customized styling if you wish to your website project.
Also the different compatibility for bootstrap and why we use bootstrap.
It's a lot of good reasons why we use bootstrap.
I'm also gonna be encouraging you throughout the lessons to try out some of the code and to
challenge yourself and write the code.
And then I'll show you walk through the exercise in the latter part of the lessons he.
There's a lot of really cool classes that you can add that update the typography,
visibility and,
of course,
images and how images air handled and even tables and then Scott,
these components that are customized that help you lay out content in a nicely formatted
fashion.
You can use lists,
which we commonly do in website development,
how you can group those together and display them nascent neatly and then,
of course,
the navigation bar.
So often times developers air just looking for a bootstrap in order to use navigation bar
because it makes the knave bar responsiveness really easy where you can collapse the
navigation bar and still have access to all of the links and then adding in various colors
.
So making your website nice and colorful really stand out and with some stunning colors,
and then you can,
of course,
update thes default color schemes really easily,
and that updates the whole look and feel of your website.
If you have any questions or comments,
I'm always happy to help within the Q and a section of the course,
and I always love to hear from you.
Let's get started.