Hey,
what if I told you there was a way to create websites really quickly by linking to a style
library in a JavaScript library?
And then you can bring the power of those libraries into your projects to develop your
website.
Just by applying different classes to your elements on the page,
you can make them look completely different.
Well,
this is bootstrap,
and this is what bootstrapped does.
It's a front end framework,
so that means that it's based on HTML,
CSS and JavaScript.
It's an open source,
and it's the most popular front end framework.
On line today is a responsive grid type system that has a lot of pre built components that
you can easily bring into your projects,
saving you a lot of time from styling and also applying the JavaScript in order to produce
that type of functionality.
This is rapid website development where you could build fast responsive sites all using
bootstrap,
so using the different components in bootstrap,
you could bring a lot of power quickly and easily to your projects.
They've got a number of examples of the main website is get bootstrap dot com,
and if you click the examples button.
You can check out some of the really cool things that you can do with bootstrap by adding
in components and these air.
Also,
some of them are commonly used Web development and design components that you might be
using,
and it's all already done with bootstrap.
And in order to bring bootstrap into your project,
there's a number of ways to do that.
So if you're using the terminal,
you can do an install.
If you've got the node package manager,
there's also the boots dropped CD ends.
So what CD ends are their content delivery networks.
So these are libraries that you can link to so that you can add the source files to your
project directly without having to download them.
So if you want to bring the CSS in and there is also JavaScript libraries,
it is based on J Query the JavaScript.
So some of the functionality is based on JavaScript for the components.
So if you do need to make use of the components,
you need to bring in first the J Coury Library than the Popper Library and then,
lastly,
the bootstrap Js library.
So,
in order to get bootstrap onto your Web project.
You can copy the CSS link and then also the JavaScript and J query links.
And,
of course,
there's more information available if you explore the docks.
There's also a number of icons for bootstrap,
so this gives you the option to bring ah,
whole library of icons that you can utilize within your Web pages.
So going over to explore the documentation and give you an overview of how to set that up
and this is designed within a grid like format.
So for now,
when gonna hit the getting started,
and once again it's got the cdn for the C.
S s library,
so you can copy the CSS library and then bring it into your project.
So just put it within the head off your project.
And there's also an option to download the CSS file directly on your computer.
And then,
of course,
you could link to it,
just as you would with any other style sheet that you're producing on your system.
So now when I go over to the Web page and I refresh it,
we noticed already immediately that as I refresh that there are some styling changes now we
can bring bootstrap into our project by applying different classes.
So I'm gonna It's that a class class of Jumbotron And of course,
I am gonna be going through all of these throughout the upcoming lessons it's going.
Apply all of the styling directly to that element that have applied the class to the pre
defined classes have a Siris of properties and values for each one already in the library,
So go ahead and try it It bring the style sheet into your project using the cdn,
and then the next lesson.
I'll show you how you can download it,
and you can also bring the power of bootstrap.
Have the library directly on your computer,
and then you get access and you can look through the CSS file in order to get more familiar
with what's possible with bootstrap and all the various classes available and see what the
output is for the styling.
Try and you could be ready to move on to the next lesson