Hey,
in this lesson,
I'm going to demonstrate how rapidly we can design a website.
So we're starting out with an index dot html file.
So it's just got a basic HTML structure where we've got a title.
I've also added in the meta the View Port eso This will allow it to fit on mobile devices.
And because bootstrap is responsive and built mobile first,
it's always a good idea to include this meta information as well as the utf eight and the
language that you're gonna be using on your Web page.
Then I've got ahead section So this is our heading area for the websites have got a div
with potentially three different columns off content that we can add within the diff and
then a footer area where I've got some copyright information.
So taking all of this just regular HTML code,
we're going apply bootstrap to it to quickly transform it into a bootstrap website.
So there's a number of options that you have with starting with bootstrap so over at the
getting started introduction page,
it gives you the links to bring the CD ends.
And there's also the JavaScript files you can copy these and simply bring them into your
project.
And that will link to the online libraries of the bootstrap CSS File and the JavaScript,
the J Query file,
the JavaScript file and also the bootstrap JavaScript file.
So the boots the J quarry for those that are familiar with Jake Worry,
this is a slim version of J.
Corey.
So if you are looking to bring Jake weary and develop with Jay Query,
then it's advice that you do get the full J.
Corey Library because this is a slim,
trimmed down version of the J.
Coury Library and the M I end within.
All of these file names means that it's men ified,
and what men ified means is that all of the white space has been removed.
But there's also a starter.
Templates Seacon Select the starter template,
and you can copy this.
And this is a great place to start because it has all of the CD ends and all of the
JavaScript libraries that you need in order to run Bootstrap.
It's already in place,
so if you want to dive right in and just without any download right on your system and
start working with it.
You can do it this way as well.
There's also another option,
so there's actually a bunch of options.
You can get it on,
get hub.
So this gives you a link to the get hub repository where they've got boots drop and see.
It's a super popular to bring boots drop in from get Hub.
There's also just different ways that you can,
uh,
access it using the terminal.
So they've got all of the different commands that you can bring bootstrap into your
projects.
And then also,
lastly,
of course,
there's a way to download the source files,
So if you click the download,
it's gonna bring you over to the download file,
where you can select the type of download that you want.
So there's the compiled CSS and Js files,
so this is typically the one that you want to use where you can just download the CSS and
JavaScript files,
and then you can link to those directly from your project.
And then,
of course,
don't forget.
You need to upload thes as well onto your website.
For them to be able to work properly.
There's the whole source files with the S,
a S s compiler.
Eso If you want to go that route,
this is also on option.
It was going to download a ton of files and there's gonna be a ton more information here
downloaded.
And there's also one where we've got pre built examples so you can select those and
download via the pre built examples.
And,
of course,
again,
boots drops cdn You can bring it in through the node package managers,
though,
doing an NPM install boot boots drop There's bring it in with yard Ruby composer and just a
ton of options to bring it in.
So let's download the file,
and this is just gonna download CSS folder and A.
J s folder.
So when you download that within the CSS,
you're going to find that you've got the bootstrap grid.
You've got all of the bootstrap files,
and this is the main one here.
The boots drop CSS.
So if you are to open this and I'm gonna open it within brackets,
they can take a quick look at it.
Eso within the bootstrap file,
you're going to see all the different classes that we're gonna be using,
and the non unified one is the one toe look at if you just want to look at all the
different properties and values that are being set because this is the one with where it's
nice and neatly laid out where you can see what the H r does were displayed for,
and we are gonna be going over what the's classes do and how we're going to bring them into
the project.
So that's another way to bring bootstrap in and then also within the Js file.
If you open up the Js folder so it's gonna download two different folders,
and then this is the bootstrap Js file so we can open that as well within brackets,
the various JavaScript functions that are built in to boots drop and that provide the
components all of the capabilities that they're able to do.
So just says she would any other style sheet you can link to it,
specifying that this is gonna be a style sheet and then specifying the location of the
style sheet.
So it's located within the CSS directory and then select the bootstrap CSS file,
and that's going to allow you to bring Bootstrap into the project and then also for the
JavaScript.
So the JavaScript files.
They're gonna be a little bit more complicated because you need to specify the source of
the files,
and they're all located within the JavaScript file.
So the 1st 1 that you need to bring in is the J.
Corey and then the popper,
and then,
lastly,
the bootstrap Js.
So without the other two,
it's not gonna work properly for all of the components.
So I'm gonna just copy and paste so that we've got a sampling of the CD ends as well as the
CD at the direct link for the style sheet.
So now that we've bought Bootstrap into the projects,
let's save it and go back out to our project and refresh it.
So right away we get the bootstrap styling being applied.
So now let's go through and add some classes.
I'm gonna add in some of the common classes from bootstrap.
And,
of course,
we're gonna be covering these in more detail in the upcoming lessons.
I'll also add it to the footer when we refresh.
So you can also wrap the parent in a container and then set up a grid with class and rope
and then each one of these can function as a column.
So you do have some options for column.
If you just do seal l to indicate column and put it on all the same level Dibs.
What's gonna happen when you go out here?
You're gonna have are three column website already built there.
There are a few options with the container so you can do a container fluid and that will
spread that container all the way across.
And this is fully responsive website.
So when you do a resize of the space that you have for the website,
I'll move this over to the right hand side so that I can shrink and expand the website
content and then also if want to align the text and its text center.
So what that will do is that will center any text that we have.
And we also did this see that we had some larger text size using the display for a class.
So going back into the bootstrap CSS,
we've got all of the classes listed here so we can see what size display four is.
The font weight.
The line height display three display to display one.
Let's go back in here and refresh it.
And now we've got that heading.
It looks a lot bigger,
lot better,
so spreading it out that maybe this is called to call,
too,
and I'm going to be covering how the grid works in the upcoming lessons.
So this assist a brief example of how he can split up the columns into different sizes.
Essentially,
there's 12 columns across,
and the way that the grid works is it structures each one of these to take up the
appropriate space.
So if we've got eight than that's taking up 66% of the available space,
and the rest of the four out of 12 is shared by the other two.
So this is taking up 2/3 and the other two are just taking up 1/3.
So they end up being 1/6 of the available spacing for that parent element role,
and basing it off of 12 makes it really easy to divide the columns.
To try it out,
bring Bootstrap into the project,
apply some of the classes that we've covered,
and you can also go through the CSS and check it the different classes that are available
and apply.
Some of them and I were walking you through them as we go through the upcoming lessons.