this lesson,
we're gonna be covering the bootstrap versions.
So you might have noticed that currently were using version 4.5 and before that was 4.44
point three and all of the way down.
So there have been four major version updates with boots drop.
Originally,
Bootstraps started it with obviously version one,
and it went all the way to 1.4.
Then it was updated to two,
and there was all the way through.
And then with three,
that's where some of the major releases and the release changes were done.
So going between two and three was a major update and as well.
Going between three and four has been a major update as well.
So the upcoming lessons there gonna be a combination of the new version and on the
bootstrap site itself.
So if you go to Doc's for it slash versions,
you can select and switch to any of the versions that you want.
All of the documentation is still updated and still online,
and you can also switch through the different versions by selecting here at the top right
hand corner on the website,
and that will allow you to go through the different versions that are available for boots.
Drop also if you go to the home.
If you go to get bootstrap,
this is always gonna bring you to the most current version.
So if you are looking for previous versions of Bootstrap and if you are looking for a
particular themes,
some of them will be using older versions of Bootstrap as well.
So just keep that in mind that the version is important.
For the most part,
a lot of the components are the same for the major version changes from 3 to 4.
Then there's gonna be a huge difference between the components and how they function.
So if you do find that your code is not working exactly the same as the code that's being
displayed,
check the version and make sure that you are using the same version that we are using
within the lesson.
In many of the upcoming lessons,
we are going to be using either 4.44 point five as those are the most current versions.
As of the time when we are creating this lessons and there will be updates if there are
some major changes for the components and the classes within the components.
And also,
if you are looking for themes or templates online as well,
pay attention to the version numbers because they will differ.
And there's a lot of different versions of bootstrap that have been covered over the past
few years.