badges and boots drop.
Allow us a way to do counts label and also apply attention to specific numbers and this
number of a different examples.
We can also use the default colors.
So the primary secondary success stager warning in fault,
light and dark.
So all of that corresponds.
You can also have them as pills.
So pills air slightly more round.
They've got the border radius being applied border radius property from CSS.
They can also be within a link format.
So the links actually gonna look the same way as the regular badges and this number of
options had to present this content.
So let's try that out in we're you just using the content contained within the mean
container and build out all the different options for badges,
so badges are typically within additional content.
So if you have a class of H four and then some content and maybe over here we want to have
a distinguished part of the content,
see that in a span and then within the span,
you could specify the content number.
So to turn that into a badge and we see that it takes the full H four because that's part
of the parent.
And let's add in a class,
and the class that we're adding in is a badge so right away when we add in badge,
there is some styling that's being applied to that element,
and now we can specify the color of the badge.
So let's use badge warning.
And there's all those default color options for the bootstrap,
so warning always is yellow on the default.
You can also do a badge light as well.
So light,
dark,
and this will update depending on what the surrounding content is so light.
And then there's also Dirk,
so that will have it as a dark background in light text.
And there are some stylings.
Well,
there's one styling option for them,
and you could change it to badge pill,
which will apply the border radius to it,
so that will round it.
And this is something that keep in mind,
depending on what size of a number.
So when I only had just the one number,
it was completely round.
So why not want that effect?
And this is all dependent on how you want to output in what you want to look like.
It So I got a copy and paste this and we'll have a few different examples of the badge.
So maybe this one is badge success,
and this one might not be a pill.
This will just be a regular badge success.
And that's how the differences off the layouts so you can use thes as needed within your
Web pages.