breadcrumbs in bootstrap as well Azzan websites.
They provide us away back of navigational hierarchy.
So you'll see these,
typically at the top of the page,
where you've got your navigation.
And if you've gone in several folders deep,
you might see something with the bootstrap breadcrumbs being presented.
All the different folders that you are in so you'd be in home and then home is parent to
library and libraries,
parent to data and then within data.
You might have some additional options as well,
and the breadcrumbs are done within an a nordeste in providing within the navigation.
You can also do separators within the BET breadcrumbs so you can do this kind of quote
separator,
and that provides all the different options for separating the breadcrumbs.
So this is a relatively easy one.
It would be just a quick lesson on how to use those and how to implement it.
So let's set up for breadcrumb,
and it'll be three layers deep,
so contained within the knave,
and you should also always include the area labels.
I'm not gonna do that within this lesson,
but adding in the area labels air good for accessibility,
so that main container is the bread from class and that's an ordered list.
And then within the ordered list,
you're gonna have a set of list items,
and each one of these list items can have a class of breadcrumb item.
And then these air usually typically hyperlinks.
So this would allow that user to easily navigate back to whatever page that came from.
Let's do home as well.
Maybe this is main,
and this could be multiple levels deep,
depending on how complex your website is.
Of course,
in the last one,
we're just gonna ply active to it so that we know that this is the active breadcrumb.
So it's still breadcrumb item,
but it's got the active class to it and also add in the area label and give this a label of
breadcrumb because this is part of the navigation,
so it should be included