Hey,
welcome back.
This lesson is going to be a fun one because it's buttons and buttons air.
Also colorful in bootstrap.
They allow us a way to provide user interaction and really entice the user to click these
nice and colorful buttons.
So buttons by default.
Whenever you hover over them,
they get this kind of active state so it does look like that you can take action.
You can click thumb.
That's really nice thing about buttons.
And I've always thought that bootstrapped his really nice buttons.
So there are options within buttons and buttons can be applied to any different element.
So they've got them inputs,
buttons,
hyperlinks as well,
and you can do it to devise.
You could do it to spans.
To do.
You could do it to any element.
Apply the button class with the boots dropped.
Four.
We've also got the outline buttons.
So these air kind of that reversed option where the buttons themselves,
they're colored in with the light font.
Well,
this is just a white button with the colored in part whenever you hover over it.
So these air really more appealing because you can see that there's some type of action
that needs to be taken.
Whatever you hover over these,
there's also button size is so large buttons,
small buttons,
block level buttons.
If you want your button to go all the way across,
you can do that.
There's also different active states that you can set on the button,
so adding in the active class will by default already add in an active state to the button
and generally with the buttons.
The active state is the one where you're clicking on it,
so whenever you hover over the active ones,
you don't see any difference.
And there's also disabled buttons,
So that's a disabled state.
So various states that are available with the buttons there's also nice buttons they can do
with your forms.
If you got some checked boxes,
radio buttons and these are just a nicer way to present the radio buttons that are on and
off.
That's another really good option to use buttons within the form,
and they take a completely Duke different look and feel.
Let's try out some of the buttons in our editor.
So going into the editor,
we're gonna be containing everything within that main class,
just as we have in the earlier lessons and creating some hyperlinks that air buttons and
then also applying the class.
So class of Bt end buttons.
Everyone always wants to press buttons,
so when you applied Bt and class to it,
it already has a little bit of styling.
But the real styling comes in when you apply the colored class to it.
So if you do a button primary,
it pops out and it's blue,
and there's all the typical colors that you'd expect.
So the warning is there the danger.
They also have the light,
the dark,
so those ones are all available for buttons.
And these are all of the nice options for buttons.
There's also waste to have the outline,
as we saw with the outline,
that provides another cool way to add button so just could be duplicating these instead of
button B t N Dash.
Whatever that color value is,
there's another dash in there between,
and that one is just outline so that provides that outlined format.
And you can really easily update your buttons with this outline format,
so instead make some updates to them and update the way that they look and feel on your
website.
There's also the button sizes,
so if you wanted these two,
you can combine the various button values so Button L G.
Is for large buttons.
And then there's also for the small buttons.
There's the button sm option,
which shrinks the buttons down to a smaller size and with the still the same behaviors.
There's also button block and that will just turn it into ah block,
which means that it's going all the way across the available space so it takes the full
with.
You could also do a button large and a blood in block if you want it really super massive
buttons make them large and then also update any of the other classes that we have.
And then also adding in active,
I'm gonna just duplicate this and add active to put in a They're so active.
That's the same as whenever we've hovered over it.
It's going to provide that same color when you add in active.
There's also the disabled option so you can update the states so disabled,
and that will make the button so that it's not clickable.
So when you re hover over,
nothing's gonna happen you don't have the little hand that's typical for buttons.
Now let's look at radio buttons and these air great for forms.
So if you've got a form where you've got a button group that you want a group together,
this is a great place to to use buttons as well,
to have really nice for type effects and allowed the radio button so that we can see the
difference.
So type radio options.
So maybe this one is the active one.
There's also label,
So if you wanna apply a label to,
it could add a label around the button,
so that just moves it up slightly.
And that's just regular HTML,
so we don't have any of the bootstrap quite yet.
And as you can see,
the buttons air rather small there.
And obviously they're not all going to say the same thing that are not going to see active
.
So update the's just to be one,
too.
Yeah,
rather small,
not very appealing,
not very clickable in a form and not great for mobile either.
So Bootstrap does provide us a way to update the buttons,
so using the button group and button group toggle provides us the toggle option and when
you need to have an attributes.
So this is the data toggle,
and we need to specify that these air,
button and save and now within the label.
This is where you apply the button class.
So whatever button class you want to apply to it,
and the 1st 1 is the active one.
And with radio buttons,
it's important that you do include that active part because that's the only way that the
user is gonna be able to distinguish which button is actually clicked.
And so by default.
If you have an active one,
then you want to make sure that user knows that it's clicked.
You don't have to start with an active once.
You don't have to have out as a default.
And generally this looks best if you keep them all the same color classes.
And now when you click thes,
you see the active one is gonna update you want to.
You can update to the different default colors,
although it doesn't look as appealing.
If you have different colors,
just keep that in mind,
but it is an option,
and you can always apply any class at any point within your elements,
using bootstrap