cards and bootstrap provide us Ah,
great way to combine content together in a particular container.
They used to be called panels and the older forms of bootstraps.
And now,
with the new form of Bootstrap,
it replaced the panels and wells and thumbnails all for this card structure that's new with
boots dropped.
Four.
So in order to bring a card,
you have a number of options.
You can have images on top titles,
the card body content,
and they help you create and duplicate.
And they're perfect for content that you might be repeating different types of templates
within,
such as products.
We've got product images.
You've got a title of the project product.
Some information about the product and purchase link,
as they do have a nice formatting for the images.
You don't have to apply in the additional image styles.
It just gets brought in with the card image top.
You can also include the list groups within the cards,
and they provide a nice,
handy container for the list groups,
and you can Mitch mix and match the various content types to create the cards that you need
in order to output the content.
The way you need it.
So with headers and footers to distinguish the top head area from the body and so much more
.
There's also variations with the sizing,
and they're probably one of those most flexible components within bootstrap and combining
it with the other classes that are available.
You can align to various text alignments as needed,
and also adding in navigation into the cards to display it within a navigation type format
.
You could also have image over Lee's so having the image in the background of the card and
content on top,
and providing this with the typical bootstrap background colors and text colors provides
you almost endless possibilities.
The cards can also be laid out horizontally,
where you've got the image to the left,
the court title and the card content on the right hand side.
And you can use the typical background colors and text colors in the utilities to update
the appearance of the cards.
There's also options for the various borders of the cards,
and you can also group cards together in a card group.
And if you want to use the card decks and setting them of equal width and height so that
they're not attached to one another.
And there laid out in more than a grid like format that's also available within the card
deck.
There's the card group,
which groups them all together without the spacing.
And there's also a grid option for the cards as well,
which is similar to what we saw with the boots regular bootstrap grid.
And this could be applied within the cards where you've got the boots drop of grid classes
applied within the card structure by using the rows and columns toe output,
the card content.
So yes,
quite a bit to go over with cards,
let's get started.
So start by creating a div,
giving it a class of card and then within the card,
create a nested div,
and this one is gonna be card body.
And this is where the contents of the card are going to be contained so they could be
contained within a paragraph.
If you want to add some other styling to it,
you can also add in titles.
So let's give this one a class of card title and also H three and all space started so that
we have our card content as a title before Matt.
And of course,
you can add in buttons and mix and match the various bootstrap classes together to get the
layout that you want.
And the way that I usually create cards is I'll create the basic card structure and then
I'll copy and paste it to have additional card elements.
So either using the boots,
drop grid or the card grid.
There's also options for the links to have it as a card linked.
That's going to provide more structure with how it's gonna be output.
And then within the card body,
you can have content as card text and images can also be added in.
So I'm gonna add the image above the card body just as an image,
and we'll do the source,
and I'm going to use the same sources we had before with the placeholder image.
And let's apply the class because that image just doesn't look great like that.
So Kharj image,
top class and with Bootstrap to illustrate this a little bit better weaken set default wits
.
So we've got a number of default wits that we can use,
and this way you can see what the card image class is going to do more,
and it keeps the dimensions of the image instead of stretching it out and you don't want to
,
just you can have more than one card body.
You might have a requirement to have two different card bodies,
so you can do that as well and also have ah,
card header.
Notice that it's slightly dark grade there,
as this is what a default header might look like.
And you might also want to make this bigger.
So looking at the various options that you have with the different styling in bootstrap,
there's also an option for card footer as well,
and that will also update the background color.
So it's slightly off.
And if you did have cards,
I'm going to get rid of the card body there.
My difficult way of using card says that I'd create my default template for the card,
and if I want to be able to reuse it,
that I create a grid in bootstrap and I just simply copy and duplicate the content and then
duplicated as many times as necessary,
also going to get rid of the 50 white so that presents the content in tonight's format and
notices well that it's all responsive because we're using the bootstrap grid and you can
have images and multiple spots within the card.
It doesn't always have to sip their the top wherever you place the image.
You could also do it just before the footer as well.
So it's another option.
So wherever you put the image tag,
that's where the image is gonna go.
And typically you will see them near to the top of the element.
You could also have an image overly as well.
Let's create that and give it a class of card.
I m g overly and what this does is this creates text on top of the image,
and I'll just take the header off.
So we just got the text on top is by default.
It takes whatever the size of the card is,
and it positions the image overly on top of the card as a whole.
That's why you got to be careful when you have the header that you didn't wanna have text
on top of the header,
so text on top hat text doesn't look great.
So that's how you can overlay text on top of your image.
And then,
of course,
use the text white to indicate whatever color of text you want.
And that's again within the utilities of Bootstrap and then the card as a whole.
You can always update the background colors,
using the utilities to make them stand out and make them different and again applying text
.
Wait,
if the need is there and I'm gonna just do background dark,
you can also set border colors,
so border.
So if you wanted a green border and you can see there's a slate border around,
the content could get rid of the dark.
We could just see that green border there.
You have options to set the different border colors.
There's also options for the card group That's just a rapper Element was the class of card
group,
and then you would place all of your cards within the card group element,
and that would group all of the cards.
So just select the card and place them within the car group.
I'm gonna get rid of that default with,
and for now,
we're just going to do two different cards within the car group,
and you could do as many as you want.
I'll make this bigger so that we can see there is a difference between the card group and
the grid structure,
so the grid automatically has.
The spacing between the card group doesn't have any spacing between,
but it's also a nice way to lay out the card structure.
And you can always update the card Group two card deck if you do want to have that spacing
in between.
So it looks a lot similar to what we saw with the grid.
And again,
it's an option to use whichever one makes the most sense to you.
And if you add in another card into it,
it will literally look just like the grid below.
The structure will literally look very similar,
so the card group is the one that looks different than the grid.
So if you want to have a different type of effect grouping a bunch of cards together than
use the card group as the card grid,
you might as well just use the bootstrap grid.
But again,
it's up to you how you wanna structure.
There's also card columns,
so if you're using the different a bunch of cards together,
that might not necessarily have the same dimensions,
and I'm gonna update some of this.
You could see it takes on more of a Mason type format where it groups them together as
needed.
But it also is smart enough to know how to structure.
It sits in a more readable format that's taking into consideration the various heights,
and that's card call.
Um,
so it's a lot different than the card group,
whereas the group would automatically just group it as columns.
And the card columns is the one that structures that better in a more presentable format.
So it comes to cards quite a lot of options,
different ways to output the content.
And overall,
it's a nice way to percent content that you're grouping together within containers that you
can vary as needed.
With the Darius Bootstrap classes