Exploring containers.
So there's two types
of containers that you
can use for Bootstrap.
And one of them is
just container,
which is going to have
gutters on the side.
And it's going to
adjust depending
on what the screen sizes.
If you go on a really
small screen size,
then they're both going
to look the same.
The second one is the
container fluid class.
And what this does
is this allows us
to have the container
full width across.
That element is always going
to be full width across.
So it doesn't matter
what the screen size is,
it's going to be taking
up the full width
without any gutters or
any padding or margins around
the size of sides
of the element.
And these are both
added in as in
classes within your HTML
elements where you want to
apply that styling
into were linked
to the Bootstrap CSS and
the Bootstrap JavaScript.
So let's do a quick
overview of the page
we've got the
doctype has HTML and
Bootstrap five does use
the HTML elements and
CSS properties that
require the HTML5 doctype.
If you don't define this,
it's going to revert back to,
or it may revert back to
an older HTML format
so your pages might
not show up properly.
So do include the doctype,
as well as include
the character set.
So the UTF character set is
gonna be the character
set that's gonna be used.
And as well as the
language attribute
within the attributes of
the HTML tag and within
the meta bootstrap
five is mobile first,
and it's designed to be
responsive on mobile devices or
the proper rendering of
your content include
within the meta tag,
the viewport settings
faults are to
set the width to whatever
the device width.
This, and this sets the page to
the following screen
width of the device.
So that's going to
vary depending on
the device that's being used.
Also the initial scale
to set to equal one,
and that sets the
initial zoom level
when the page is first
loaded into the browser.
For Bootstrap, the main pieces
of bootstrap are gonna
be the containers.
There's two different types of
containers that you can set
within the HTML elements as
attributes with the class.
So the first-class that we're
gonna look at is container.
And you can just
create a div and
have the word
container in there.
And the second-class that we're
gonna look at is gonna be
the fluid container fluid class,
which provides a full
width container,
whereas the container
is going to be limited.
This one is going to
be container dash
fluid for the class.
Also within our CSS.
I'm going to add in
a class called box.
So this is gonna be our
custom class that we're
gonna be adding borders
around the elements,
around the HTML elements
that we can actually
identify them on the page
simply by adding in
the box class to both of
those containers
will allow us to see
the pitch elements and we also
still need to link out to
the local style CSS file.
It's going to be using the H ref
and linking to style CSS.
And I'm placing that
after the link to
the Bootstrap source code
file as style sheet
and save that.
And that will add the borders
around both of the containers.
We'll set this up as
container one and
then container to save that,
expand the containers.
There's gonna be a difference
between the two containers.
On the small screen,
they're going to
both look the same.
But on the larger screens,
the container one is going
to have gutters around it,
whereas container two
is always gonna be
taking the whatever
the full width is.
Got it zoomed to 200%.
If we go back down to 100%,
we can see that the breakpoints
that the containers
do constantly adjust as
we're shrinking
down the page size.
And then once we get to a
really small page size,
both of the containers are
actually going to look the same.
So depending on what type of
properties you want
to the containers,
you can either use the container
or the container fluid,
which goes across the full page.
And that will affect how the
content is being displayed.
Typically, when you are
creating bootstrap,
you would wrap the
entire document
within a main container,
whether it be a fluid container
or just a regular
main container.
And then as you add in
different elements on the page,
you can set them as
separate divs and
then separate them as separate
containers on the page.
I'm just copying that
one and I'll update
the wording for
container to afterwards.
This way we've got two
different containers.
And we can see the difference
between the two containers.
One is going to be the top
container is going to be
just the regular container
with the gutters at the side,
which are going to
adjust depending on
the screen size and container.
Full fluid goes across
the full width of the
available page screen.
So go ahead and try that out
and add in some containers,
and then add some
regular HTML content
into those containers.
And you'll get ready to
move on to the next lesson.