Welcome to the Jumbotron.
This lesson is going to be about how we can create a Jumbotron and adding this component
onto our Web pages.
This is a common way to have some content that really stands out to highlight some content
.
And it's a hero unit style content.
So number a few different options.
And really,
it is just having a parent rapper called Jumbotron.
And then this is just regular bootstrap stuff within.
There's also a Jumbotron fluid and that occupies the entire horizontal space of the parent
.
There's not a whole lot of difference.
That depends on how you're using it and where you're using it.
A number of differences that you're going to see.
Let's go back into our project and we're gonna add in a jumbotron so creating a diff that's
going to contain a bunch of elements.
And then these are gonna be what's going to be contained within the Jumbotron.
So the Jumbotron is gonna have a default background kind of agree area.
It's also got some padding around it.
Let's create another div here,
and I'm gonna add a class of display three.
So this is something that you might typically encounter in a Jumbotron and will center the
text so text is centered.
Or maybe you want to do the text centered on the entire Jumbotron.
So it's up to you again.
However you want to display it.
There's also maybe you wanna have a paragraph with a class of text muted.
So this could be like subtitle more in full.
Whatever.
That's a typical Jumbotron.
A lot of times you might also find buttons in there.
There's more information for the users,
and I'll show you the difference between the fluid one.
So there was an option for Jumbotron fluid,
and in this case,
because it's taken up the full container,
we don't really see my name.
Much of a difference here between the Jumbotron fluid and just the regular Jumbotron.
We'll get rid of the text center in order to see the difference,
and the fluid is just taking up the full width bits because we had the text centered,
so we didn't see a difference.
But there is some padding here by default on the regular Jumbotron,
and the fluid doesn't have that padding.
So it's just taking up that full available space that's available within the parent.
That's what the difference there is.