this lesson,
we're gonna be looking at list groups,
and what list groups do is they allow us to contain a series of content that belongs
together.
So,
just as we would with each to Mel lists same idea.
And it just applies the boots.
Drop styling,
using the risk group class for the main container and then for the list items.
It's the list group item so that provides that bootstrap styling.
You can also update and add the active class and just says we've seen before.
The active class will highlight that particular element that has the active applied to it.
There's also an option to disable it.
You can also add in the links,
so there's what's called the list group item action and that creates this hover effect
Wherever you hover over it.
It darkens slightly,
so it provides a clickable link area that's active whenever the users hovering over it.
There's a number of options,
and you can also list your group.
You can do a list group horizontal as well.
And then there's various sizes for the list groups that you can add in and to really
customize the way you want your list being displayed.
So I'm just gonna be using the main container,
and I'm going to give this container a particular with.
So we create another element.
And with inside here,
as normally,
you don't have the list going all the way across,
So this will give it a width of 50%.
So using the bootstrap utility class of W dash,
whatever percentage you wanna go across,
this is how you can contain a list and most the time.
If you do have a list,
you're not gonna have it going all the way across anyway.
So it's create the A Norden list and add in the list group class.
So this will indicate that we want the boots drop,
styling applied,
and then the list items and each one of the list items would have a list dash group stash
item class.
So that will turn it into a list item.
And then you might have some content here.
So whatever you've got contained within the list group,
so that's the list group and displays it as ah list.
You can also update this toe on ordered list or ordered list,
so it actually doesn't matter because the bootstrap is taken care of,
the way it's being styled.
This can also be a div wrapped with a bunch of dips in sight and still going to display it
the same way,
so it doesn't actually have to be list items.
But for consistency sake,
and especially when you're looking through your source code,
it makes a lot more sense when you grouping content structurally within your bootstrap as a
list when you're using the list group.
So it just makes sense to do it as a list group,
although you don't have to.
So let's update this and add in the active class to it and you can see it defaults it.
So it's the blue highlight.
By default,
I'm gonna duplicate,
thes and add in the links as well.
So go all the Web sites all the way up to 78 so that should give us a good sampling of a
number of different list items.
So we wanted to add in ah hyperlink.
So let's add in hyperlink here and then the content of this link will contain the website
for so by default had already has some styling being applied to it with just bootstrap in
general.
So we do see that this is a hyperlink.
But it would be nice if if we go over the hyperlink and it updates so we can update this as
a list group item action and that will create the hover effect you don't even have to.
You can do it as a list group item action as well,
and this can apply to ones that aren't links.
But typically you would use this type of class for links.
So let's take that and will apply it to the hyperlink eso this creates that has a list
group item.
And if you just want the action on it,
you need to also have the list group item within it so you can do it this way where you
take the list group and apply it to the parent.
And that way it will highlight just as the other one,
just below it highlights whenever the users hovering over it.
So you also have the option to disable these What?
May I got a duplicate thes with number six,
so that would do have the list group item actions number seven,
so you don't apply it to the hyperlink you could list them out as hyperlinks.
So again,
it doesn't have to be list items,
so you could have them as just hyperlinks and apply the list group list group item action
to that hyperlink and that will list out the hyperlink within that list format.
There's also options so we can do a disabled option,
so that kind of gray's it out.
Whenever you hover over it,
there's gonna be nothing that's gonna happen on Website five.
You can also apply the list group colors,
so these air the item default colors.
So just as we've seen before,
there's danger.
There's Primary Secondary on there's a whole bunch of the typical ones that you'd expect,
and let's also create ah,
horizontal list.
So just below our regular list group,
you can also create a horizontal list.
And as mentioned,
it doesn't necessarily even have to be a list.
You can do it as an a nordeste or list item.
I got to do it them as dips toe have a little bit of variety,
so set this up as a list group,
and then I'll create the list items as gives supply it class,
so anything you apply the styling,
too.
And if we want to change it to be horizontal,
that's adding in into the parent where we specify list group,
and that will make the list group horizontal.
So that way we can see each one of the list group items.
Now they're horizontal,
and it's a Z Z.
Is that just applying this horizontal class?
And I could do that to the main this group that we were working on before as well,
and that will just turn them horizontal.
And there's also different sizing options for the horizontal.
And as we saw in this example,
so we can do a dash,
sm dash MD So the different break points that we can resize and we can turn it horizontal
on.
So what we do horizontal MD And whenever we shrink it under the break point,
then it's going to stock.
So it's not gonna be horizontal anymore.
And whenever we're above the break point,
then there are gonna be horizontal listed.
So that's how you can control how they get laid out and presented to the user.
Within the Web page.