this lesson.
We're gonna apply the scroll spy.
We need some of the content from the last one.
I'm gonna move this up to the top and we had a bunch of links here.
I can also update the content of these links because they were moving to particular
sections on the page and that was home about and contact.
And what we want to do with Scroll Spy is a just which one is active.
So whatever content were scrolled upon,
we want the navigation bar to indicate that,
and we do that with Scroll Spy.
And now we need to specify the content that we want to spy on.
So whenever there's scroll happening on this piece of content and we're gonna use the body
so we're spying on the body and looking for the event of scroll toe happen and then data
target is going to specify where we're getting the information.
So what?
We're targeting and what's being updated whenever the school is happening.
So we're taking the knave one as the target because that's where our navigation bar is.
And then there's data offset.
So this just offsets where the data starts.
That So let's see what happens.
And now,
as we scroll through the different sections,
you can see that it lights up there at the top.
So all we did is connected.
The enough one Teoh actual navigation.
And the rest is just being done through the scroll Spy,
where we're listening for the navigation bar to hit these particular anchors.
And as they hit the anchors,
it's gonna ply the active class to the various elements.
Used to see that as well.
When you go into the navigation bar,
make this a little bit smaller and I'll open up the an ordered list and we see that contact
has active what I scroll up,
the active goes to about and I scroll up right to the top.
The this one gets the active home gets the active so you see where the active class is
moving through the elements,
and that's automatically done with the scroll Spy