if you have multiple pages of content that Bootstrap provides a nice sweet toe,
have indicators for Siris of that related content.
So going through number different paid strings.
If you have a bunch of pages,
there's previous next and all the numbers in between.
So essentially it's a nice way to group those together those links together and provide
that capability.
So we're just gonna be doing a quick lesson on this as this is an option and there's really
nothing dynamic about it.
This is all hard coded,
but if you do are loading a bunch of pages of content,
you can also keep the structure and load this dynamically.
So it's creates our pagination on the page and going into our website,
we can create a new ordered list,
and you can use any element just as we've seen before.
So duck,
she doesn't matter which element you use.
They're all going to be able to handle this of creating the pagination because again it
just plying classes and the classes do all of the styling element for the element.
So the mean parent classes pagination and then each one of the elements that air nested
inside So in this case,
the list items is page item and I'll shrink this down and then wrapped within here.
You might typically have a page link,
and these would typically be hyperlinks with the class off page link that would say,
previous actually going to duplicate this one.
And this would be one and so on.
So as many as you need to 345 and go all the way,
and then the last one would typically be next to.
So if there was additional pages there,
if you had,
ah,
lot listed,
you might want to do next or something like that so that users can move through the pages.
And then you had code this with JavaScript to load additional pages as the user click
through the various links.