were you wondering why you need the Popper library that's included with bootstrap,
where you've got that within your code?
Well,
this is for the pop overs as well as the tool tips,
so they're very similar in nature.
And these provide a way to kind of cover over something with the tool tips and provide
additional information,
and that's contained within the tool tip itself.
So the title and this is the content that gets displayed within the tool tip.
You can place them to the top,
right bottom left,
and those are the options that you have.
The styling is typical with boots.
Dropsy can do the various button classes for the main button,
and then the tool tip just sits on top within the attributes of the element,
so you can add it to any element the tool tips and typically they would be used for buttons
and the same thing for the pop overs.
So the bought pop overs are more something that you might use for additional content,
and when you click it,
it has more a little bit more structure than the tool tip where you've got the pop over,
you get the same choices,
and this is also contained within the attributes.
So there literally very similar,
and all of the information that you've got within the pop up is gonna be contained within
here.
You can also add in titles,
so there's got an option for title,
and then the data content is the same.
So just do a quick run through of how these work.
And then,
of course,
with the JavaScript,
you can also do some customizing of what happens when it gets clicked and so on.
So if you need that additional coding option with JavaScript that's there as well,
with the pop ups in the tool tips.
So going into our code,
create some buttons and then we'll apply the tool tips to these buttons.
So just regular type of button and applying a class.
And again,
you could do this to any element that you want.
So it doesn't have to be buttons,
but primarily they are used on buttons,
and it will just say Click me for the button and let's add in the attributes so that
tributes is where the magic happens that you've got your data container,
and the data toggle is going to be a pop over so nothing happens yet because we haven't
specified any content.
Now we also have to equal that to pop over.
So no content yet.
And this is where we get the content.
So we've got data content,
isn't here is what's gonna be displayed in the pop pop over.
And you are also going to need to use within the script tags in order to enable it.
So there is the function in order to enable the pop over.
You could enable it to all of the data toggle whichever one's equal,
pop over and apply the method of pop over.
Or you can specify a particular element and apply the pop over just to that element.
So either one s.
So now when you click it,
it's gonna enable the pop over and that we can duplicate it and also apply a class of
margin top five to move that down and I'll put this one at the top.
So the 2nd 1 has the pop over at the top.
Let me just say that and a lot in some line breaks.
So does show up on the top and do a refresh the bottom top,
and they click it again to close it.
And it's gonna work that very similar to what we do with the tool tips.
We have to enable the tool tips as well.
So if one enable all of the elements with the tool tip the data toddler toggle tool tip
attribute that we can enable that I and do something very similar to what we've got with
the pop over,
where we've got data toggle is gonna be tool tip instead of pop over,
we also have the data placement.
And then instead of data content,
it's just gonna be titled.
And we can get rid of the data content for the body.
So the last one will be a tool to you can see when you hover over.
That's the tool tip and these ones you have to click.
So the pop overs you have to click the tool tip.
You could just hover over and you get that tool tip showing on