take what you've learned and you've witnessed most of the commonly used components and
bootstrap and how you can apply them into your project,
even go over to draw I o or take a piece of paper and sketch out a website and create that
website from scratch using the various components that you used.
So really challenge yourself and see what you can accomplish with boots.
Drop start from a blank webpage and then build out at in.
The components designed the grid first.
So it's always the first step when you are creating your website to design the grid.
So how it's laid out,
How many columns How many rows you're going to need for your basic website structure and
then go to Bootstrap for the various components that we've covered throughout the earlier
lessons and how they can fit in In order to accomplish the styling for the various website
design elements that you need,
We've covered quite a bit of functionality,
and there is really a lot of stuff that you can do and then once you've got your core
components in and you've got some of the styling in,
you can make adjustments going into the bootstrap utilities,
where you can update spacing,
sizing and,
of course,
all the different colors that are available in bootstrap and then really find,
too,
in the look and feel of the website in order to complete the complete website design using
boots drop And as we've seen for the most part,
you can accomplish everything with just some attributes that are added into the elements as
well.
As,
of course,
the various boots dropped classes that provide the styling.
And if you do need to Adam customize styling,
you can always do it within the style.
Tags directly within your file,
or you can link out to your own style sheet.
So if you do want to customize the way that some of the content is being displayed,
and bootstrap might not have the option for you,
you can do that by applying the style tags as well.
If you go over to the Boots Drop website,
there's a lot of documentation,
and it's well,
there's an example button.
So if you select the examples,
this would give you some of the commonly used types of styling that you need for building
websites.
So,
such as a sign in sticky footer,
sticky footer nav bar.
And then there's also some basic framework,
so you can take the basic starter template and select the source code for it on a browser
you can right click anywhere or within the deaf tools you can select from the right hand
side menu under more tools.
And from there you can select the deaf tools and that will open up the code editor.
Seek and inspect the code from that Web page,
so I usually just do a view page source and selecting the page source to have the page
source open.
You can select the HTML,
and it also includes all of the classes within the attributes to do a quick copy and paste
.
And that will be the quick way to get started in used the templates that they have on the
website.
And don't forget,
we also have some customized styling,
so we'll add that in as well in order to get the exact copy of what we see within the
example,
Web page select the starter template styling and noticed that they do have the padding at
the top because from our nap bar,
it's covering over the top content,
so they do have some customized styling.
So don't forget to include that as well.
If you are looking on the website for some of the examples and starter templates,
So now that I've set that up and I refresh it,
it moves the content down so that we can see the main content area.
We've got our nav bar,
and if we shrink it,
it shrinks nice and neatly so fully responsive and ready.
So try it the code and also try out the various components available on the bootstrap site
in order to get more familiar with what you can do with bootstrap.