this lesson is going to be a fun one,
because we're going to be creating the navigation bar.
So this is the core of most websites that you've got a navigation bar to help navigate your
users through the content and navigation in bootstrap is excellent because it give prides
you,
ah,
fully responsive navigation bar.
And there's a lot of options when it comes to the navigation bar.
I'm just over at the bootstrap website gives you more information,
but the navigation bar so you can set different collapse points.
So that's got S M M D L G Excel,
and these will collapse the navigation bar to the men ified bar that little hamburger icon
bar at various points.
You also have full structure.
You've also got the Nice nab,
our toddler icon that comes with boots.
Drop now and then.
You can create your section to have as much navigation this plot as you want.
You also can set up navigation on left side and on the right side.
There's a lot of options when it comes to navigation,
also including the input fields as well.
Within the navigation bar,
there's a ton of different examples you can also have header text,
logo,
text branding,
text,
and there's various color schemes that are available so the typical boots drop background
colors as well as you can set the navigation bar,
which will automatically update the colors of the tax contained within it.
And the one that we're also using is gonna be the sticky top.
And what sticky Top is going to do is it's gonna stick the navigation bar to the top,
and this is the one that we want because it's a single page website,
so we don't want users to always have to go to the top of the page to scroll themselves up
.
We want it just to stick at the top.
So this is the one that we're going to be adding in.
And then there's the responsive behaviours where the nab our expanded the different break
points the toddler option to toggle the bar.
And then there's also the option here,
where they're demonstrating how you can have content on the left and content on the right
hand side within the navigation bar,
with a ton of different code examples.
And that's an example of how it's gonna look like once collapsed with the collapsed content
and the toggle icon as well.
So shrink back down there a peach,
and I'm gonna go into where we have the placeholder.
For now,
I got a place that default sticky top navigation bar So there's obviously nothing in the
navigation bar yet.
But if we are scrolling the page and I have to make this page smaller and you see that it's
staying at the top,
no matter where you stroll to,
it's always going to stay at the top.
So we're ready to add content to the navigation bar and also do some styling to it.
So if you don't like the default look of the background light,
you can update it to any one of the default primaries.
So we've got.
And also,
if you switch the naff bar light to now bar dark,
you're going to see that the text color changes,
so make this a little bit bigger and we can get rid of some of the content that's contained
in here because we're gonna be building our own structure for the navigation bar.
So once we've set up the navigation tags,
give it a class of knave bar And that's going to indicate to the browser that this is a
navigation bar that we want to use and apply the appropriate classes.
There is one thing that I do want to know about the sticky top,
and there is a difference between fixed top and sticky taught.
That sticky top does use position sticky,
which isn't supported by every browser.
Up until that support is there,
I would suggest to use the fixed top class instead so that you get full cross browsers
support.
So let's make a quick update to fixed top,
and it's going to do the same thing where it's gonna specify,
and the only difference is that it moves the content down.
So if we're using fixed top,
we're gonna have to make an adjustment to the content.
So watch what happens when I do update this to be the fixed top.
We hide the first part of the content the navigation bar sticks on top of it,
so that's the disadvantage of having fixed top over the sticky top.
Whereas a sticky top is what it's designed for to push the content down slightly,
that option is available on sun available across all browsers quite yet.
So keep that in mind and update it to fix top,
and we're ready to continue to build the navigation bar.
So typical navigation,
Boris,
we've got the UN ordered list.
And then we've got all of our items that we have in the navigation bar as list items.
And there are classes for the navigation item.
So now item.
And there's also classes for the navigation item links,
so create a hyperlink.
And this is where we need to hyperlink to the various tags that we indicated in the
sections below.
So this could be home page and going to the splash,
which was that first header section that we had.
Let's also add in classes here,
so they do have default classes for links called knave link class.
And I'm gonna update this to nab or light.
You could just duplicate the list item for the other pages that you have with other
sections,
so specifying whatever the name of the section is to correspond to where the anchor is
going out.
So we also had the vote area,
we had projects,
and I'm just going to double check just to make sure that it is projects,
not project.
There was also the story i d.
And then lastly,
the contact.
And we need to also apply a class to the UN ordered lists to the wrapper off the list items
,
and this will indicate And as soon as I apply the class to it,
it's gonna be now bar naff is the class,
and right away you see that now they look like navigation items.
So there's the drop down for the navigation items.
As soon as you apply that,
there's also some automatic that we want to move right automatically.
So always put it to the right.
So that's some styling within bootstrap.
Now we want to indicate that this is gonna be collapsible content.
So let's create another rapper for that,
and that's going to wrap all of the content that you want to collapse in the navigation bar
.
So I'm going to wrap it with a div and give this one a class,
and the class is gonna be now bar collapse class and then also add in the collapse class to
it.
So it's gonna happen is it's gonna collapse the content.
But we haven't specified at what break point we want to collapse the content.
So that's where we need to go back up to the naff and specify the NAB our expand.
And I'm gonna use it on sm to expand on the S M.
So it's already taking shape that we've got a navigation bar and we do have the collapse,
but the collapse isn't showing.
And this is where we need to specify the I DS and collapse the content using the bootstrap
collapse format.
And this requires a button in order to have the collapse take place.
And this is the knave bar toddler class tight button and data caught Tuggle.
So you have to add in a bunch of attributes in order for the collapse to take place.
And by the way,
you also need to have your JavaScript,
Torri J Query libraries included,
and we need to specify the data target.
So this is probably one of the most single,
most important attributes here because we want to be able to select the navigation bar.
I'm gonna just call this knave one as the target,
and we have to given I d of now of one to the main rapper.
So that did that we created to go down to the DIV.
Give it an I D.
And this has to correspond with the I D that you want on your collapse bar and then within
the But you can have any type of character that you want,
and in this case,
Bootstrap does provide a default toddler icon that can be used.
And this is just a class of default toddler icon,
and it doesn't have to contain anything cause by default.
Bootstrap will add that in and before we try it,
this has to be have a hash in order to identify it as an I D.
So it's refresh,
and we're ready to try the Mugler.
Now.
When we shrink it down to the smaller size,
we get the button to toggle it.
You can also update this toe,
have different break points for the Togo bar to appear.
That's the medium size.
My preference is to keep it at the SM,
but you can have any break point that you want for the bar.
So coming up next,
we're gonna also introduce some items that we can add to the navigation bar on the right
hand side.
So typically you might see social media icons and I'll show you how to bring those into
your project coming up.
We're going to use fought awesome for that.