Hey,
welcome back in this.
Listen,
we're going to get social,
so we want to add in some social icons into our navigation bar at the top so that the users
have an option to see our social media sites.
So going into bootstrap by default,
there's not a whole lot.
They used to have geoglyphs.
They don't have the cliffs anymore.
But they do have really good connection with fought awesome and font Awesome.
If you've never used font awesome,
it truly is awesome.
I'm using gonna be using the font awesome 4.7 icon reference they have in a cheat sheet at
4.7 ford slash cheat sheet.
And this is or you can see all of the amazing,
awesome thoughts that you can have all these little gifts that you can have.
And of course,
they do have the social media,
and pretty much any type of lift that you want to use is typically available that for
awesome,
So I have to do is apply the CSS class,
and that will bring the icon into your project.
Or you could use the Unicode to his number different options to do that.
So all you have to do in order to bring this into your project is either download the style
sheet or linked to it through the Cdn,
so I'm gonna simply link to it through the Cdn,
So bootstrap cdn dot com for slash font Awesome has makes Cdn for that,
and they do have options for the different versions of font.
Awesome.
I prefer to use 4.7,
because for me,
it's one of these here one Steve's.
But there are different versions,
and some of the syntax might be different.
So just keep that in mind when you are looking at front awesome that this particular lesson
I'm using 4.7 point zero so there might be different versions and the syntax would change
slightly.
But if you are using 4.7,
then it's going to use all of the same ones,
and it's all available on the cheat sheet.
So let's go over to the Cdn,
and we're gonna bring it in with the HTML Cdn.
There's number of ways to bring this into your project,
so going into where we've got all of our style libraries just paste that,
and that's all you have to do to bring it into the project.
So next we're ready to add another bar to our top bar,
and this is we're gonna have our social icons.
So just outside,
but within the collapse area,
because we do want this part to collapse us.
Well,
we're gonna create another one ordered list,
and this is gonna be strictly for the two thoughts that we're using and we're going to use
the Twitter and Facebook.
So it was probably two of the most popular once.
So setting it up,
just as we did before,
where we've got the class and now have item class for the list item,
and then the hyperlink can go up to wherever the link for the social media is going to be.
So whatever that link is gonna be and setting it,
giving it a class of knave link.
So that gets the knave link class styling applied to it.
And then inside This is where the fun awesome comes in.
So you can go over to the cheat sheet and go down to where we find Twitter and cause there
are so many.
Usually I have to do a quick search.
S O.
C.
We've got a number of options for the Twitter one.
So f a square and they have the FAA Twitter.
I like to use the square ones,
but again,
this was up to you.
So in order to add that in to you could do a tag of I apply a class.
And this is where the fun awesome class comes in and then close eye off and go back into
the project.
And,
of course,
we have to update the a Norden list and give it a class of now bar now and then for the fun
.
Awesome.
We have to also apply a class of F A for fun.
And now we've got the Twitter icon there available for this hyperlink,
and we can duplicate that.
And we're also going to do the one for Facebook.
So include the F E class to indicate that it's a font.
Awesome.
So it gets that styling added to it,
and then the shortcut for this one is going to be Facebook square and safe.
And that applies the Facebook link within a navigation bar.
And because we've added into the collapse,
we see it's being applied within the collapse as well,
and just as we've moved right auto for this one,
I'm gonna move left auto for this one.
So it's always pulled over to the left hand to the left hand side,
and that one's pulled to the rate.
So that's it.
How that's how you can add fought awesome to your project.
So if you do need the social icons,
or if you do want to make use of any one of the other icons,
and we're going to use some more of them as we progress to the upcoming lessons,
so do check out,
find awesome for on awesome experience of different icons that you can use in your project
.