as nice,
says Bootstrap is it can't always do everything.
So we need to have some custom styling,
and especially for the single page websites.
You do need to apply some custom styling in order to account for the different section size
that you want to use,
as well as for the navigation bar that it's covering part of the content at the top.
So I'm gonna create some spacers as well a supply,
some default styling to the body,
to the header and also as 100% so set the height to be 100% of available height.
So some default styling there because this is a full page website and then creating the
spacer,
and this is what we can use at the top of the page.
I'll give it a height of 10 picks and a width.
So these air kind of like spacer bars,
and they're also visually appealing because that can give the user that's using the website
,
an indication that these are actually different sections.
I was gonna make a black line,
and of course you can style the colors as needed,
and I'm gonna ply ah,
margin for the talk and bottom off 40 and then left and right is zero and then do a display
block to make sure that takes the full with.
So it's the spacer and adding in these spacers,
I'm gonna add them in between the sections or at the top of the sections.
So where we have the about that's adding in these types of spacer breaks and then go down
and apply the same thing just above each one of the H twos.
So there is consistency in the design that separates out the content.
And we also need another type of spacer that we can have to move the content down because
of the navigation bar.
And this is just going to be a blank one and give it a height of 50 and display block.
And this is the space of that I'm gonna use to move the main splash page area down there
mean welcome content because we can't see it.
It's being hidden with underneath the navigation bar,
setting up a div class spacer,
and I just realized I called them both spacers.
So I called that one space or two and space or two.
So wherever we need that spacing that extra spacing.
We can add that in as needed,
and that's just doing that 50 block of space.
So now we can see that the content and we might even want to adjust it slightly.
Maybe that should be a 60 block of space moving the content down and also want to do ah,
100% for the splash,
so want that to take up a full percentage.
It's also select the splash element with the idea of Splash.
I use an image from placeholder dot com.
So if you don't have any images handy and if you need some place over content,
placeholder dot com provide you some good images.
You can set the different sizes,
the dimensions.
You can also add in some text,
specify some custom colors.
There's a lot of options here.
This is one of my places that I use in order to set background images and just general
overall place older images.
So it's add that background to this elements of Earl,
and then I'm just gonna pace in the background image and will specify no repeat and center
the image,
center it and have that fixed so it doesn't change and also for the background size.
I'm going to use cover so it's fully across and as well so it will work across browsers,
so Web kit,
background size,
mas background,
size and cover.
So they all get cover on that.
And now let's go down to where we have the splash content.
So it's contained within the header that we can update that contents off.
This added in a diff,
and I'm going apply a class so this class is going to give it a role and specify the height
of 100 will wrap the content inside of it.
So we've got quite a few dibs happening there and also on H one for this content.
And let's use the display for for the largest size and each one tags.
So going into boots drop,
they have some options for the various sizing severe to use the H 100 which is 100%
available with then they also have in line block in order to set that as ah block.
So if you don't have any content contained in there,
you can automatically select all of that.
So let's take the in line block and we also need to make some much of other adjustments as
well,
where we have the HTML to be full.
There's also positioning that we can do.
There's various positioning options,
there's spacing and there's a bunch of different layout options that we have available to
us.
So if you want to add in padding or margin,
that's also possible.
So we select the property.
Either it's patting emergent,
and then we can select the sides so we can do top bottom left,
right X,
why and then blank for all four sides of the element and then the number of sizes.
So there's a scale of 0 to 5.
You can also do auto and as well they do have some examples.
So we do use some of these spacing classes in order to provide spacing within the page
content.
So going back into the website where we've got each 100 I have paced the D line in line
block and also going up to here where we've got the body.
We also need to specify that the HTML so that will produce it at 100%.
So going back down,
I wanna center the content on the splash page.
So we've got our splash.
We've got the container fluids that's going all the way across,
and we want to use justify content center so it's within the contact positioning.
So if you go back into the website and you can always search the various classes so it's
got justify content,
it's under flex and give you more information about how that works.
So if there's ever a class that you need to search up,
the easiest way is just go to search and provide a search for that.
And what this will do is this will center that content because we're using the Flex Justify
Content center.
We don't need the in line block for the spacing of that element.
So once we removed that,
we'll see that the content does get centered,
and you also might want to add some additional another each to their kind of like as a
subtitle for your content,
and then apply PT so padding top and will do just a little bit of patting,
patting top,
and you can type in whatever content that is necessary for the page.
And of course,
you won't have something that says image here in the background as this is coming from the
placeholder,
you probably have something nice and bright in that stands out.
You also keep in mind that your text you don't wanna have you won't have a nice contrast
from your text to the content,
and maybe it will even make this bigger to display one.
So if you're using a dark background that make sure your text is a light color and if
you're using a light colored background that you can keep your text as a dark color.
And now,
whenever we click the links,
we get brought to the other pages so you can go back to home and about US Project's story
contact.
So there's no more scrolling.
That's why it's not screwing down because we don't have any content.
That means that we have to add some content in that's coming up next.
As we continue to build this project,