there's gonna be a quick lesson.
We're going to be looking at the about us section,
so this isn't gonna be 100% like the home,
and you can,
of course,
if you do need to adjust to be 100% you can add that into the styling to give it a height
of 100%.
But because we've got a specific amount of content and we might not necessarily want this
to be 100% where he's gonna leave it as is and let the content dictate how much height this
particular element gets,
we're also going to do the same thing that we did here,
where we're adding in the height 100 justify content center into the elements already be
thinking,
Oh well,
it does look centered.
And that's because we've got the call Dash MD Dash eight.
And if I make the screen a little bit wider,
we see that it is in fact only taking up eight columns of with,
and there's four that are empty,
so it's not exactly centered.
And when on the larger screens and that's where we could use the Flex,
justify Content center in order to center the content.
And of course,
if you want to add in another column off four column column,
then you could have added that in this Well,
so maybe if you wanted to have an image there,
so that is another option.
And again,
depending on how you wanna handle this,
you can treat it in a few different ways because the about us is taking up the full width,
and then we've got the various columns.
So how about we do that as well that we're gonna add in another column under just past it,
And this one is going to be four,
and this one can contain an image,
and this image is gonna be fully responsive.
And we're going to just use an image from the placeholder dot calm and take the same image
that we're using in the background of the splash.
And,
of course,
you probably already have images that you might want to use and adding in the image and
then the source for the image and set the source as the placeholder path,
or whatever the path to your image is going to be.
And then for the image itself.
Wanna add in the classes for image dosh fluid to make it Reese ice and fluid.
It's now we have an about section that's Centre Alliance of the content is center aligned,
and this is fully responsive.
So as the container gets smaller,
it will stack.
So once the break point under the midsize break point is underneath that it will stack the
rose.
And if we go larger,
it'll just have the different various columns.
And this is all contained under the about US section.
I also want to add additional content underneath about us,
so you want to add additional spacing.
So going back to where we had looked at with spacing,
we want to add spacing below.
And you could do that with utilities and under spacing and selecting to add a margin below
margin bottom and then specifying the margin that we want to add.
So we're gonna add a margin bottom and a margin of five for margin bottom.
So margin bottom five underneath about us and we could try variations for to see what it
looks like and then for consistency,
we're going to do the same thing for the additional content.
Also to the text alignment,
so there is obviously an option to text the line.
So let's align the text left as this is a paragraph.
So we don't necessarily want it to be center aligned for this example.
So we also wanted to add in some cards below,
So this is gonna take the full roll,
call him.
So adding in another rope and then within this role,
going back,
Teoh the bootstrap components we're gonna add in a few carts.
So basic structure of a cart is what we define as a class of a card,
and we're gonna be creating a card deck.
So number of cards together presenting the content from the cards,
we're gonna have an image on top a title and then some content about the card.
And this is what's a card deck where we can automatically group the cards together,
and we can include the card footers,
the card headers,
the car titles and,
of course,
the card body and as well as images within the card deck.
There's also option to do grids for the cards,
So that's another way that you can present the cards where you can just use the typical
grid format that we've been using from boots drop,
and this also allows you to accomplish the same thing.
But in this lesson,
we want to try the card deck.
So I'm gonna take the card deck,
and I'm going to copy that source code over into the project and save it.
It will make some tweaks and adjustments to the way the card deck is being output.
And also shrink this down a bit so that we can see the full size of how the car deck is
gonna look.
We're gonna add in a class of margin top five.
So we got some spacing between the card deck and the rest of the content in the about
section,
and we also want to add in some images.
So let's go ahead and paste some more placeholder images into the card deck.
So there we've got our image there,
and of course,
you can update detects to be whatever you want it to be.
And then within the card body,
you can also add in a card header if you want,
and then this part here at the bottom,
where we've got the card text.
So I'm going to remove that and I'm going to replace that with a button.
So using a div applying a classical buttons that could be added with bootstrap.
So going back into the bootstrap documentation.
And let's make this bigger.
So under buttons and buttons air really easy to add.
So typically they do use the button tag,
but you can use any tag that you want,
and this will still indicate,
because this is styling and styling that's being applied so that it's taking any form that
we want.
So I'm actually going to use the outline buttons of success and copy that in that has
mentioned these can be did is they don't have to be buttons,
especially if you're doing you're quoting with JavaScript.
It doesn't really matter what's accomplishing the button action,
so you can use any element and it's gonna look the same way,
and I'll update the text here as well as with the card title.
So maybe this is a silver plan adding in on icon from the font.
Awesome.
This is a great place to include those icons.
This is just a computer desktop,
and I'll make this a little bit bigger,
and of course you can adjust these as needed.
So now that you've created one card and this is all contained within the card deck,
we can duplicate that format and overwrite the other cards so that they all have the same
structure.
And that's one of the things that you do want with this type of action that you do want the
ability to have the same type of structure for all of your cards.
And of course,
the images would be changing so you can update some of the colors,
and this is what done within the placeholder image.
So these could be really easily updated.
And also we can update this to be just so it is different.
And let's update the text on the buttons to be by now and update the background color for
this one this well and update the plan to be gold.
And we're gonna update this one as well and a buy now button and safe.
So there's our about section so we can start whenever the page loads and then click about,
and that will bring us down to the boat section.
So coming up next we're gonna look at the projects,
are story and then create a form in order for the contact us