We're going to copy some of the format that we used in the last lesson about the about me
section,
and we're going to do the same thing for the projects area.
So this is where we can showcase the number of projects.
Maybe that we've worked on have a type of a gallery,
and in this case,
So the last one we used card.
So we used the card grid.
And this time we're going to use just the regular bootstrap grid.
We're gonna have a number of rows and columns,
and it put some visuals under the Projects area and for the A boat.
We did make some adjustments where we added in the margin bottom so that there is some
space between what the section or at the page is called and identified as and what the
content below.
Also,
click it just to make sure that when you do click it,
it is right at the top,
and there's no overlap with the navigation bar.
As we saw that that sometimes happens,
and that's what we added in the spacer.
So just get make sure that those are all in place,
and if you find that you don't have that in place,
then look,
to make sure you're adding in the proper spacers and structure.
So we've added and quite a few things.
So I'm gonna temporarily copy and then we'll write the stuff over just below.
So we've got the A boat and the text is centered.
So the more important thing is that everything looks the same.
So I could just paste this and update the about US two projects.
And then also don't forget if you are copying and pasting than update the I D.
Otherwise it's not gonna work.
So just make sure that things are still going to the rate section,
and that is still going to the projects.
And the reason that it's not at the top is that there's no more room to scroll.
So there's nothing to scroll the projects up to the top,
and that's until we we add some contents.
We're gonna add content in the footer.
There's going to contact us our story.
So what?
Next time,
when we do have content there,
it will scroll to the top,
just like that about works and the homework's.
The projects will work the same way,
so That means that we need to add some content.
So going into the projects and we did want to structure it with the number of rows and then
within each one of these rollers,
we're gonna have our dibs to divide up the content and then have a column and will force it
to MD for you could also just use call if you want them always toe have this grid structure
so again depends on the content that you're presenting.
And then with inside of each one of these columns,
you might want to have an image and I get a source for the image.
Use that same place.
Soldier will make some updates and adjustments.
That does look slightly different.
And of course,
if you already have the images that just use the images that you have also adding in that
class of fluid because this is just a regular image.
Other ones already were structured because they were within the card format,
so we didn't have to add the image fluid and always with the images,
you should have the old text as well.
So just out of police holder for the old text.
So now we've got an image and update some of the colors of this image.
This is just a hex value.
Just picking them at random.
No particular pattern to that.
And then underneath the image we can add in ah product.
So I'm gonna wrap the image in a diff and this is good if eventually we want to add some
type of classes to that that we can do that.
And essentially,
it's just giving us the block of content when were structuring with the diff.
Also wanna have h three so class of H three.
Because I want to have the bootstrap H three classes.
So this could be product one.
And then,
just as we did with the cards,
once we determine what we want,
the first product call them to look like that.
We could just duplicate that,
and then this would potentially have some info about the product,
and they're not gonna put product one.
So it's going to make it easier for me to copy and paste it.
So now that once we're happy with the way that it looks and remember with bootstrap that we
can have up to 12 columns on a typical grid So that means that we can do 123 and that will
take full with across and it will stack once we hit less than the and the break point.
So it's something else to consider that if we don't want it stacking like that,
then we might also just want to use the call so that it's always within the grid format.
So let's update that actually to call so that it doesn't matter how small we shrink it.
We're always gonna have it stacked as the three,
and this is really working.
Essentially,
just like the grid was working.
It looks the same.
Let's update thes product numbers so that there is some distinction between them.
So this is actually that's product three.
That's product to L updates some or random colors.
That's too similar and say that.
So now we've got the three different products,
and you can also change the what's being displayed with the placeholder where the equal
sign is just text and it doesn't look like you could do a hash.
So I just do the product names to some of the stuff,
obviously doesn't always work well,
and this is just placeholder content.
So typically you would have some real content that you want to use.
And we probably don't just have three products.
We might have six.
So that's two rows of three in each column,
and you might also have additional.
Maybe you have eight.
Let's do it for eight and we'll update it.
And then we'll duplicated across.
So it gives it a yellow color and,
like teal kind of color.
So selecting that entire roll,
all I'm doing for the projects,
I'm just duplicating it.
So we have another role and then making the updates to these products.
So this one is five,
67 and eight.
And then let's also update the corresponding values and save.
And then we should also update the colors just that that there are some differences and
what's being output.
I know some of them look fairly similar,
and there we go.
So let's see what this looks like on the larger sighs.
Refresh it,
make sure you see it and then now when we go to about when we go to projects so that it is
being shown here at the top,
you might also have some additional information or maybe even have 12 or so on.
So this is fairly flexible and how the content gets presented so you can take advantage of
the grid and present content.
You might also have some additional information.
So so info about the product.
This might be a little bit longer,
and the advantage of using the cards is that the structure is a little bit nicer,
so it's more self contained,
whereas here you'd have to add in than you've had in the borders and so on.
So depending on how you want output,
your content there is a big difference between using the cards and using just the grid.
It's up to you how you want to present the content on your project.
So coming up next,
we're gonna update the our story where we're gonna use somewhere components,
go back into the boots drop website,
and in this time,
we're going to use one of my favorites,
which is the carousel.
So that allows us to slide images and have multiple images that the user can slide.
So that's coming up next in this.
We're gonna include in the next section