this lesson,
we're gonna be continued to build out our project.
And we did the about.
We've got the whole and we've got the projects.
Next we want to set up the our story.
So this is a section on the website where we could include some information and additional
information.
Maybe some pictures and images of the company that's being presented on the site and we are
going to be using the carousel is a slideshow component,
which allows us to cycle through elements,
so images,
slides of text just like a carousel.
There's some great examples on the website and self and important thing here Is that the
carousel?
So these air,
based on the attributes,
it's gonna also require javascript for this component.
So we need to specify the class of Carousel slide.
The data rightist carousel,
giving it an I.
D and the I D will help identify it when were used in the carousel controls and then within
the carousel itself.
It's got the carousel inner and a bunch of different carousel items.
There's also the active one,
so that's the starting point,
and these are within a block with with of 100.
That's providing a full with of the images.
So in case the image itself isn't taking up the full with,
you can adjust it using that class.
There's also an option to add indicators,
so indicators are these things here at the bottom that we can add in,
and this allows you to go from slide to slide so you can even jump through different slides
.
And those indicator controls also require the i.
D in the data target.
And then we need to specify which slide with order of index.
And this is a rebased,
so it starts at zero.
So the 1st 1 is zero,
then 12 and so on,
and that's how you can add in the slides.
There's also a bunch of cool options like captions that you can add in,
and this you could added on top of the text.
So that makes a really nice effect.
Is also cross fade and a bunch of different ways to set the carousel.
You can adjust the carousel intervals,
so by default there is an interval of that's already preset,
so the default for the interval is 5000 so it's five seconds interval.
You can adjust that say,
suggesting the data interval.
And here it date.
Inderal is 10,000.
That's 10 seconds,
and these air in milliseconds.
So 2000 is two seconds and so on.
So let's build this part out on our project.
So going down to where we have the section our story.
And once again we want to keep the format the same that we had within the projects and
within about.
So I'm gonna do a quick copy and paste just to make sure that our section is the same type
of structure.
Because this type of thing it's it's really important that we do get the structure the same
.
And for the most part,
I think that we already had it.
But let's copy and paste it anyway.
And I think the only thing that we were making different was we were adding in the margin
at the bottom.
So let's update our story and also be mindful of the I.
D.
You do need that I d to touch to that anchor ideas in the navigation bar,
so make sure that that one is always in place and we're going to need some images because
that's going to be just a image beast carousel.
So I'm gonna use the placeholder content in order for the images.
And of course,
if you already have images that you want to use,
you could use those instead and we might not want the carousel to go fully across.
So we'll divide up the carousel into spacing of eight,
and then we'll have some content on the site.
So let's set up that structure first,
using the classes where you have the role and setting up a column of M D eight and also
another one for some additional texts or carousel will go in the larger one,
and we'll have some additional text in the m d for.
And I just have a place soldier right now for the text so ready to create start
constructing the carousel and we need a mean differ that and northen i d to give this one
an idea of how you want identify the carousel.
So of course you can have multiple cara cells,
and the way that they're gonna be finding each other is with the I d.
So I'm gonna give it a carousel off.
I d.
And I spoke carousel wrong there and we do need to apply those boots,
drop classes of carousel and slight,
and then it also needs the attributes of data.
Right?
So that's the attribute.
And the data ride is a carousel so that this bootstrap nose and the browser knows to ply
the carousel functionality.
And again,
this is done in javascript.
So that's what we're going to make sure that we do have that available,
that we do have the JavaScript libraries attached.
And I miss spelt that once again.
So it seems to be having trouble spelling Carousel says car O U S E.
L is the way to smoke carousel,
so you do have to spell them properly.
Otherwise it's not gonna pick up the rate styling and the attributes.
That's their mean carousel container.
So that did.
There is the main carousel container,
and next we're going to do the inner part of the carousel.
So this is where the contents of the carousel are gonna take place.
So this is carousel inner class to indicate that this is where the inner contents of the
carousel are going to be housed and within the inner,
we've got the dibs and these air the actual slights that we have within the carousel.
And these are all carousel items and usually the 1st 1 we set toe active.
That's the default that it's going to start on.
And then whatever is contained within here is gonna be how what gets output And we are
gonna place an image in there with a source,
and then the source is gonna be going over to the placeholder.
So just copy that,
and we'll make some adjustments by that,
an object that to be hello.
And this image is gonna have a class.
So D Block is gonna create a block object from this a block element.
And if we said it two with 100 where take up 100% of the available space and this is gonna
be keeping the dimensions so we might want not want to have.
So we want to make maybe set a preset height of this and with these carousel is you do
wanna have images with the same dimensions.
So this is one thing to keep in mind when you are selecting the images,
so usually they look way better if they're more wide than they are tall.
That's why I just did that to 500 by 300.
And with police older,
it's a lot easier with regular images that's going a little bit more difficult to to handle
.
That's our content for the first item,
and you can add additional content as needed.
But we're just gonna have images in there and copy it.
Don't forget to remove the active and these air ologists carousel items and put some
different text into it and color it slightly different and will leave the class when we
refresh.
And by default,
it's every five seconds.
It's gonna change,
and we don't have the indicators yet.
We're gonna add those.
Of course,
that's our next carousel item.
It's a little bit hard to tell,
So there it just went to the next next slide.
So grab the next carousel item and you could add as many items as you want there all
carousel items,
so there's no wait.
There's no distinction that you have to do.
I'll just do last one on this.
Those air,
all of the carousel items conceived that and again.
Default is every five seconds,
so we can adjust that as needed.
So it's add in the carousel indicators,
and this is typically done with an ordered bust or on order list doesn't actually really
matter,
because this styling that's going to overwrite the differences and the class for this one
is carousel indicators and that carousel indicators are done with list items.
So list items and we need to specify the attributes.
So this is the target off what it's targeting,
and we had given the whole carousel an I d.
Of one.
Don't forget to add in the hash to indicate that we're looking by I d.
If you've got one by class,
then you could do the dot.
But it's always better to have ideas because we know what I ds.
That there's only the one.
And because the 1st 1 is active so that that corresponds,
and then there's more data that needs to be added in so data slide to attribute and then
equal that to the index value and the class is actually active,
and I just put that class in the wrong spot.
So let's update the target,
the class too active,
and you don't have to include anything in the list items.
So there's our 1st 1 So whenever we click it,
we always go back to the first.
You can adjust this and go toe to toe.
Doesn't matter.
Whatever one it's set to is the one that's going to go to.
And usually you do wanna have it in order that the slides air being presented just makes
sense.
So Carousel one so still the same one.
And it just set that to one.
Remove the active because this one's not active.
So it's a little bit more of agreed out kind of effect to it because it's not active and
then duplicate this to whatever number off slights.
So this is not automatic that you have to list them and associate them with the number of
slights.
So if you have three slides,
then you should have three of the indicators there.
So make sure that that all equals and matches.
So one last thing that we wanted to do a swell is toe have the controls so that controls
for previous and next.
So the user coming in,
they have an option to move to the next ones,
and we saw there's a number of ways to do that,
so these air these controls here on the left hand side.
And they do have some carousel icons.
So I got I just copy these just to save some trouble.
And we always have to make sure that you are rating these properly A soon as I put that it
shows up,
but they're not hooked up yet.
We have to update where we're linking them to.
So they have to link to whatever the name of our main object is.
And that's gonna be the carousel one element with the idea of Carousel one.
And then also just make sure that this one matches to carousel one as well.
And that's all you need to get the functionality.
So now we can click them and we see that it works.
Let's make this bigger and looks like everything is working as expected.
And then also,
we want to add in some text eso going back into that other def that we have for text.
I'm going to copy the Laura Ipsen text that we have from this previous section,
and also I could just align it left.
You can do any number of things for this area.
Eso just got that Laura Ipsen text there within the our story.
And then the main part of this lesson was to explore what we can do with the slide show
with the carousel.
So coming up next is the contact us where we're going to use the form,
and that's again available from the bootstrap documentation.
So they have a really nice way to present forms that's coming up next.