can this lesson.
We are gonna be looking at the footer content and that's the one right at the bottom.
We haven't done a whole lot with it,
and that's just outside the main section.
So I'm gonna take all of these spacers gonna put under footer that will bump up the foot or
area and allow us to work on it and also have it kind of mid screen there as we're working
on it.
And within the footer.
Why,
No,
we haven't done a whole lot with lists yet.
Eso this lesson we're gonna look at list groups were gonna list out a number of links in
the footer,
create the footer area,
make it fluid so all the way across.
Also add in a background color to match what the navigation bar is and set up the lists for
the fluid.
Let's get started on that and going into the class for the footer and on a center,
the text so adding in text center class will center the text,
also setting up the container dosh fluid that will make it all the way across.
Background is primary and safe,
so we refresh and of course we don't have any content in there yet,
so we can add in some content that says Footer,
that we can actually see it.
Also,
let's make the text by default to be white.
So there's our footer area and already to continue to build that.
So make this smaller.
Remember,
the footers is going to be under the contact us,
and that means that we don't actually have a navigation to it.
So contact it's working.
Story is working projects about home all working properly.
So going into the footer,
let's create role and this.
So we're going to divide up.
So we're going to use the bootstrap grid just like we did in the previous lesson where we
set up our role and the row is going to contain a bunch of columns that are gonna hold all
of the information that we want in our Footer.
So within the footer,
we're gonna divide it up by a three column grid,
and the first column will be six.
So using just the default sizing on it,
and then let's set the copyright symbol for it.
So Copyright 2020 of 2021 whatever year it is make the copyright,
they might have some statement information for the users that are coming to your site.
So what could I do a whole lot on that as we did Want to focus on the lists.
So the lists are gonna be called him three across,
and we're gonna have two of them.
So both matching in size.
And let's set up the list for that so the list might have a title.
So give this a class to do that after my links.
That's the title.
And there's also some nice ways to transform text.
So I'm gonna just change this to uppercase associate gain change to upper case when you
apply that class to it and then the list items is going to be all within the UN ordered
list.
And let's apply a class to the an ordered list so that it applies.
The boots drops styling,
So this will be a list group class,
and I'll make the text dark for this one.
So we have some different types of links and the list items,
so the list items are all using the list group item class,
and that's going to style it with the bootstrap list styling,
and this could just be a number of websites,
the website one and we might have a bunch of websites that we want to showcase on our
website.
So in this case,
maybe we've got four different websites.
So 234 and then you could also update thes two hyperlinks or whatever information.
However,
you want to present the content.
That's the first list.
And let's duplicate this this structure,
and we'll do it within the second as well.
And going into the list groups,
you can set the top one as active,
so distinguish it from the other items.
You could also have disabled items in the list,
links and buttons.
So how the links and buttons air presented.
And this is a really neat one,
because this allows you whenever you hover over it,
toe have that kind of hovering effect.
So instead of list items,
you're using list group with hyperlinks,
and actually we're gonna change that.
We want to use the list a new ordered lists,
but we'll look use the list group so that we do have a different way of presenting the list
.
You can also do it with buttons as well.
So hyperlinks buttons doesn't matter.
Those just have default actions with HTML.
You can also stack it horizontally if you want,
so this is more like the navigation bar.
There's different colors that you can apply to the lists.
So it's also really neat feature with bootstrap.
And these are all that typical default functions.
Did default colors that you see in boots drop.
So whatever.
If you change your color scheme,
it's gonna change all of the primary colors.
Secondary success,
danger.
And that's the nice thing about boots Drop is that it does have all of that flexibility.
So now we see it.
We've got this list and I'm gonna get rid of some of this excess here.
I don't need an active,
so we'll remove that.
And then for the entire role margin bottom and I put a margin bottom of four on.
It actually changed this to pounding bottom of For that,
we have some padding around it,
and if we just wanted padding around the whole thing,
sometimes that looks better and that's a preference.
You could just do a patting of four around the entire object.
So now take a look at the project.
Make sure you've got the content as needed for your website,
and we're gonna wrap this up with a few tweaks and adjustments.
So one of the things is,
when you do click this.
We want the scroll,
spy toe work and scroll spies A really neat thing in Bootstrap because it allows us to
highlight whichever part of the navigation menu were on.
And this is ideal for single page sites.
That's a really cool feature and as well as I've got ah J.
Corey Tweak that will provide a smooth scroll.
So whenever the user clicks projects,
it will scroll it down in an animation format,
So that's still all yet to come in upcoming lessons.