this lesson is gonna be a quick overview of all of the content that we've covered earlier
and greet Joel on making it through this section.
I know we've gone through quite a bit of stuff with bootstrap,
and you can always mix and match components and bootstraps.
So if you find that some of the stuff on our in the early lessons might not be relevant to
how you want to put content,
there's a ton of information that get bootstrap dot com.
You can go to get started and then under the components.
That list said all of these components,
and these are all from commonly used components that you might have within the website.
And so adding all of these is really easy.
They also have all of the sample codes and just different ways to add that in.
There's also under the utilities.
So if you don't like the colors that I've used,
you can update the various colors as well as add in some padding and update how that looks
so.
The colors are all laid out under the utilities colors,
and they've got all of the different default colors and the nice thing about the color
scheme and bootstrap is that if you get a different color scheme,
it will update the primary secondary success,
danger,
warning and info.
And that's why it's really nice to use the boots drop classes because if you ever changed
the colors of your website scheme,
it's gonna be really easy to do if you've coded it all with the right classes.
So make any adjustments and tweaks that you want.
And,
of course,
you probably want change that place older images because that's rather ugly.
But they are just to serve as placeholders for the content that you might potentially be
adding on to your project.
So make sure that everything is as needed and you're ready to publish your website.
And we've gone over the most commonly used components.
Applied some customized styling where we had some spacers to take care of the navigation
issue that when we're using the fixed top navigation bar,
is going to stick it to the tops.
It doesn't work exactly as a sticky top does,
where the content has pushed down slightly,
and that's one of the disadvantages.
So some of the browsers still aren't up to date for sticky eso.
In the meantime,
you can use fix top.
And if you are watching this video in a few years,
you're able to use this sticky,
and you don't have to worry about all of the spacers s.
So this is how you would customized and add in different classes that you can use,
of course,
within the bootstrap and setting up the splash as a background.
So there are no default classes and bootstrapping toe handle that,
so that so we had to set up the cover and do that separately.
So navigation is always key to any website,
and because this was a single page website,
the boots top navigation bar is perfect because it collapses and users always have access
to get to the very sections of the website just by clicking the navigation bar.
And that's what we do have.
It's sticky at the top.
We have our splash area,
so this is meant as kind of that place wherever the user lands on your website to have a
really nice imagery in the background to get the users excited about your Web content,
give a quick introduction to what this website is about than that boat section.
And this is where you can highlight some of the content that you have some of the more
outstanding things,
maybe some products that you sell,
services that you sell and so on.
This is example of how it can be highlighted and output.
We went onto the projects.
This is a kind of a showcase area where you can showcase different projects.
If you got a portfolio,
you can showcase that portfolio here as well,
and then the IRS story.
So this gave us an opportunity to use the carousel,
the sideshow.
And this is a really neat component in bootstrapping,
another commonly used one,
and we saw how easy it is to apply that.
And just by using a bunch of images and bootstrap classes,
we could structure that slide slider really easily.
The contact form.
So bootstrap once again provided us a nice,
neat way to layout,
input fields and text areas to produce a form and,
of course,
buttons and boots drop always really nice and appealing.
We also added the pre penned were using the font awesome icons as we order.
He brought them in for the social media,
so why not bring them into the rest of your project.
And that's one of the nice things about fought.
Awesome is,
once you start using it,
you're going to realize how awesome and how many amazing icons they have so literally can
spruce up your website easily with font.
Awesome.
If you have any questions or comments,
I'm always happy to help.
But I always love to hear from you.
Hope you had fun and hope you've enjoyed creating your Web site.