This lesson we're looking
at the colors of Bootstrap.
So they do come with
default color palette.
And you can of
course update these.
And the idea is that
if you update like
a primary and by
default it's blue.
If you update it
to a custom color,
than that will
propagate across all of
the classes that are
using the primary color.
So it gives you an
opportunity to update
your entire website with
a scheme of colors.
These can be combined.
So I'm gonna give
you an example of
the text values and then
the background values.
And you can apply
these to any element.
And you can also use them in
combination with the text,
the background, and so on.
Let's talk coming
up in this lesson.
Bootstrap five comes with
contextual classes for colors,
and they can provide
different colors.
So you can provide meaning for
your elements just by
applying the colors.
Let's create an select a few
of those different colors.
I'm going to just add in
multiple elements and these
are just a bunch of divs here.
And then we'll apply some of
the color classes to the
various page elements.
We do have the
ones for the text.
And I'll set the
class here and set
that to be text slash muted.
And it'll just set that
as container muted.
That's slightly graze out
the content of the class.
Let's try another one.
And thus, this one is gonna be
the one that is commonly used.
So this is a Texts primary.
This is the primary
color that you can use.
And I'll set the container
value to be primary as well.
So typically by default that's
going to be a bluish color.
There's also a success.
So setting it as text success,
and then these colors are
repeated within the background.
There are also repeated
within the tables.
They're repeated over and
over again within
the various classes
so that you can reuse
and you can select
these color schemes
really easily.
And then if you update
the color scheme,
that will update
all of the colors
for those elements
within the page.
There's also a text info.
I'll set that to container info.
So that's light-blue
successes by default green,
the primary is blue
for the warning.
So this is another
one that you can use.
And this is gonna be by default,
an orangeish yellow color.
There's also a text danger.
So this one, by default
is going to be red.
And it'll set these
ones as well.
So that's a red color.
The warning is an orange color.
There's also a secondary text.
This is slightly lighter
than the mean text.
And that's a text secondary.
And I'll also put thought
into the container there.
So it's similar to what
we see with muted.
And there's a text dark and
a text Light class as well.
These can be used in combination
depending on what you're
setting your background.
If you're setting
your texts too dark,
then that means that your
background should be light.
Whereas if you're setting
your texts to light,
That's gonna be ideal
for a dark background.
Let's set all of those
so you can see the light
one disappears because it's
completely white there.
You can also set
background colors as well.
And I'll just copy this block.
We're setting these
divs and I'll set
the background colors
within the fluid example.
These are the text values.
So we can select
those and we can
update those two background.
And it's going to apply those
color schemes to the background.
And then you can use
various combinations
of these two set,
either the texts colors or you
can set the background colors.
And this is when we are saying
the background
color to dark than
the texts colors
should be set to
light and then vice versa.
Otherwise, you're not gonna
be able to see the text.
So you'd use it in a
combination where you'd have
the text light and
then you'd have
the text dark so that
you could see the texts.
So it'd be the opposite.
So that's how you can
use the light and
the dark for setting the colors.
These colors are
gonna be repeated,
so they're not always
all available.
But for the most part,
the primary success
info warning and
danger are pretty much
mostly available.
And even when we're looking
at tables and as well,
there's a lot of other
examples where you
can bring this in and set
the color values to the
elements within your HTML.