Hello and welcome back to the course and blotching.
So to understand what Web 3.0 is let's first understand what Web 2.0 is.
Here we've got a couple of examples of Web sites back from the 90s as you might remember them or you
might not remember them but this is what they looked like.
And back then simply a Web site was just text.
Maybe some images and some links and like in the case of Apple this is Apple upset.
I was very upset and because of the Apple website like it's a bit like probably later in time or with
more advice because you can see like a for me here some buttons and so on.
Maybe like even some advance coloring and things like that.
So yeah good old days.
This is what the Web looks like and this wasn't Web 1.0.
As you can see it's a very different experience to what we have now.
So let's have a look at the Web sites of Apple and Amazon as they are today.
There is Apple.
You get those vibrant colors.
We get all the menus at the top and how you can just go and watch a video right here of leaving the
page and there is the Amazon Web site.
Again you've got like a form here like a search form.
You've got this carousel that's changing the ads in the background.
There you go all these different other ads they're all tracking your purchases like you're you're being
served.
The most relevant things to you.
There's always these Pop-Pop says is very interactive things and I'm not even talking about social media
here.
That's a huge new thing in the web as well compared to version 1.0.
And so all of this together is called Web two point oh the term was popularized in 2004 and it signifies
a paradigm shift in how we experience Web sites and the Internet.
So we went from just basic text and links and images to everything moving around things.
Loading.
You can watch videos you can watch videos for adlibbing a page you can you you have social There's so
many things going on and some of them are listed here.
A big role in Web 2.0 was played by Ajax and or I-X and javascript's because those technologies allowed
that whole transition to loading pages with refreshing loading elements on pages without having to refresh
the page every time we've had the page refreshing itself.
And that's that's immersion into your experience that you get from there.
So that's Web 2.0.
It was like a prize in 2004 is like a specific date when that happened it just it just kept happening
and people realize that we're in a different world now.
And so this map that out on a typical Web site or typical experience user experience of the web we have
a front and the back in front end is what the user sees the back end is what happens in the background.
What they don't see.
So in terms of Front-End there is our back in Web 1.0 there is our app a Web site and now this is what
looks like in Web 2.0 front and has changed drastically the whole experience has changed a lot not just
what they see but like what they feel how how the machine learning technologies are serving and what
videos they interact with how the Web sites remembering things they've done before and adapting to them.
So that was that Web 1.0.
This isn't Web 2.0 but let's get them back in.
How does the back end change.
Well Bakken hasn't changed much.
We don't take into account all the complex algorithm that algorithms that sit in the back at the core
structure and the core architecture of how people interact with Web sites and things on the web is through
a centralized approach.
There's a central server for instance Apple in this case the central server and we're accessing it.
We're requesting things from a central server and then we're getting information back.
And so this is where lauching can play a huge part in Web 3.0 and probably will.
So there is Web 2.0.
We don't really know what's going to happen with the front end because it's also important to think
about that as well that that will change maybe it will become a computer vision or maybe will become
like an even more interactive or even more AI driven personalized that things like that.
That's not the question that we're answering here right now.
The question is how will the back end change.
Well this is where blotching play a major role and we can move from a centralized web in Web 2.0 to
a decentralized web the Web 3.0.
And let's have a look in a bit more detail how that can take place.
So here we've got all the people in the world and as we know we're all interconnected.
We all know something that somebody knows somebody and then people know each other and there's like
this whole concept of Six Degrees of Separation and things like that or now it's the lower that you
pretty much know anybody in the world through like four or five or six connections.
But nevertheless even though we're all connected where we want to interact to each other what do we
do.
Well we go to for instance Facebook which has centralized servers which belong to Facebook and all the
data is stored there.
And so we are actually interacting with Facebook or Facebook's servers and services which then allow
us to connect with each other.
So we have that middleman Facebook which so far has done a great job.
We've got we've got to give it to these companies that bring us closer together Facebook linked Twitter
and so like they've they definitely had a major role in the evolution of how society and just globally
the world is connected.
However the core the underlying foundational premise of all remains that we are still interacting through
a centralized way with each other through Facebook servers so they have control where data over our
privacy they can service the ads they want to serve as they can charge us if they want to charge if
they don't if they don't want to charge as adults.
And so there is a lot of control.
Are we giving away to them whereas in Web 3.0 with the block chain approach the hypothesized idea is
that we move back to using this interconnectivity that we have with each other and at the same time
they will be able of change or multiple block chains which would run the applications again a copy on
this block chain would be stored on every single computer and then they would be smart contracts which
govern how these applications work and what happens for instance in the case of a social media application
or social media network.
Smart contracts would say what happens when a person joins what happens when they add somebody as a
friend.
What happens when somebody posts something and so on.
So basically the code behind that social media network and that would all be stored in a block channel
shouldn't be running just as we discussed throughout this whole course how a watch chain works and a
great example of Blash in readiness for this is theory serious blotching where applications are already
created and we saw an example of steam in it which is a block chain version of Twitter.
And so basically the social media network live on this block chain we would all have either our own
data or fragments and bits and pieces of each other's data and then along the way.
But the point is that the control over the data would be stored using a private key on the block chain
so only you would have access to your data and you would through your interactions and through the smart
contracts you would be able to and through your actions you would be able to select who gets to see
your data doesn't who you want to be friends with who doesn't and befriend them.
So you get control back over your data completely entirely because it's not stored on a centralized
service store or near a computer again or there's other ways to implement this can be stored in fragmented
pieces all over the place but only you can put it back together.
And so therefore what we're doing is we're leveraging our own machines rather than a central server
to help make all of this happen.
All of the smart contracts are executing on all machines all the data is stored in our machines the
block chain is running on our machines.
The interconnectivity is happening between our machines we don't really need a central server.
We can have a social network which is completely which doesn't belong to anyone.
It just runs.
It just exists and it's crowdsourced and people add to it and like take away from it and we all vote
how it develops and things like that.
So a very democratized approach.
Where we all have control.
So this brings us back to that idea of the supercomputer that Israel was trying to build like the global
supercomputer using our little computers that we have rather than a centralized server.
So there we go that's how Beauchesne can contribute to Web 3.0 very easy an example of this steam at
a Web site.
And there's more and facts and interesting additional reading for you here.
Where
author tio talks about the theoretical concepts and implications around ball or block chain or Web 3.0.
Actually there is a screen shot there of the apps how they might change how the browser machine's storage
and video call social networking and so on.
So you actually see here steam it is over here.
So there we go that's web three point onwards.
And how blotching can play a role in that.
Check out this article is quite popular on medium and yeah it's a good idea I think to get up today
or upscaled with with what's coming ahead.
What to expect from what the Internet will look like and why.
Well because it will give you ideas on maybe how you can contribute to that or maybe how you can participate
in all of this and get started early and start you know transitioning your mindset again.
This is all just all might change in a few months in a few years.
It might look completely different to what we're speculating now but it does look promising it does
look like a very interesting way that world could go on that now.
I hope you enjoyed this story on that look your next.
Until then.
But Cheyne's.