[Autogenerated] in this clip will look at all APS elapses.
The list that appears to the left of our start menu while we're in desktop mode.
When we was 10 was first released,
there was actually a link that took you to a full
list of all APS on your device, but with updates.
The Windows 10 The Elapsed List is now present at all times here,
off to the left while you're in desktop mode.
In a later clip will look a tablet mode and how the start menu especially,
is laid out differently.
For now,
it's enough to say that tablet mode is ideal for touch
screen interaction with Windows 10.
While desktop mode is the default screen,
lee out for keyboard and most interaction.
So what exactly is all APS When we were looking at the Start menu,
we have this great navigation tool over here.
That's a scroll herbal list off.
All the applications are installed in your device.
This list is presented in alphabetical order,
and we'll look more at the differences later.
But the applications on your Windows 10 device I generally installed as
either APs from the Microsoft store or their traditional desktop
applications that are installed from an installation disk or downloaded
installer now with desktop applications.
This kind of a big effect on where the application appears in this
alphabetical list because many desktop applications air actually installed
into a folder that can appear in your all APS list.
Just to give you an example of one well known application
for video and audio playback is the V.
L C.
Media player.
Now, if I scroll down to V, we don't see the V l C media player listed here.
However, notice this folder Video land.
I can expand the folder, and there's the V L C media player,
along with a few related tools.
Now, if the application were named ABC Media Player,
it would still be here under V if the folder was installed.
Two was video LAN Desktop applications don't have to be installed in a folder,
and many aren't.
But developers often choose to do so when there are multiple
tools or applications that installed together.
It does help to keep things a bit more organized,
and clutter can really become an issue in this list.
Now,
another set of folders that you will find in the all APS list
our system related applications under W.
We can expand Windows accessories.
There's some great tools in here and to be aware of their kind of hidden
because few people would know to look in this folder.
No pad is in here.
WordPad,
which is a free document editor included With Windows 10
The old paint application is in here.
Quick assists and steps recorder.
Those were a couple of tools that can be used when working
with someone remotely for troubleshooting.
Even the older Internet Explorer, which is still installed,
that many Windows 10 devices will be found in here.
So I encourage you to expand folders.
Look at the application's installed in your device in the all APS list
and other clips will look at ways to keep your often used applications
easier to access and even share some tips to make it faster to locate
those seldom used applications.
Over time, the amount of applications installed in your device will tend to grow,
and scrolling will just become less practical.
An important navigation tool included in the all APS list
is the ability to select the letter,
which brings up this condensed menu and then jumped
to a separate letter in list.
Now that's a pretty useful feature in the slip.
We've looked at the all APS list. Thanks for watching Hamlet forward to see New in the next clip.