[Autogenerated] and this little look at some of the options
you have to personalize windows with color,
central concept and design.
The Windows operating system has always been to provide you with
options that enable you to personalize Windows.
Windows 10 allows you to customize the colors that are used throughout
the menus and toolbars so you can really make Windows.
Your own Hollis ability is especially useful for small
organizations and businesses that prefer to have their own
branding and color schemes reflected on their devices.
Of course,
larger organizations and businesses generally will use tools
like group policy that allow them to centrally managed these
settings on all of their devices.
To see the options you have related to colors open up the settings out.
There's actually a keyboard shortcut you can use.
Open it like the Windows Key and the Letter I the same time where you
can just select the Settings icon from the start menu in the settings
at select personalization from here, select colors soft to the left.
No, this large preview gives us an idea of the current color choices,
and it will update and reflect any changes we make.
There's a check box here that lets windows dynamically pick a color that
complements our current desktop background or wallpaper.
This could be a good option if we want a specific wallpaper
you're no is concerned about the accident.
Color itself in a separate clip will look at options
related to desktop backgrounds, But for now,
I'm gonna leave this unchecked.
Let's roll down to the palate of colors we see under windows colors.
So from here,
I can select a color from those presented and notice
what happens when I select a color.
Some of the changes that take place immediately not
only the preview displays changed,
but there's also subtle color changes to icons in the taskbar text.
Even selected items like the colors Time over here.
You can just select color from the palate if you see when you like.
But if you want a very specific color, select custom color.
Now here we can see there's some great tools.
First, the current color has shown, and we can tweak it using the slider here.
Or we could select from the color spectrum up here, down below.
We can also see some examples of how this accident color would be used
and I can actually see a helpful warning down here that text me not
display while with this current choice.
If we select more,
I can be very specific about using RGB or H S V values for my color and I.
Also, I really like this.
The option import Hexi decimal values.
Returning to the main colors pain.
We also have additional options.
Transparency may already be on by default,
but this basically just make some of our menu slightly transparent,
which has a nice effect.
There's also check boxes to use our selected accent color and then apply
this color to the Start Menu Taskbar and Action Center.
We could also use the check box to apply it to all title bars.
And when his borders again looking up here to a preview,
we can get a good idea of how these color traces will look.
Finally, there's a setting related to the default app mood,
but we only have two choices.
Your light or dark.
Currently, I prefer the dark moon myself.
The choice we make here will apply to many of the core system
maps that are included with Windows 10.
However,
one make changes to other APS that we might install from the Windows Store.
The default color mode you select manages the overall backgrounds,
the menus, that title bar of those APS.
And in a future update, Windows will get a much better light mode.
That's a lot better than the simple white background that's currently enabled
by default in Windows 10 anchored you to experiment of it.
Find the combination you like after the right.
You can also see helpful links to other settings.
It will impact your color choices, and we'll consider these later in other clips.
In this clip, we've looked at personalizing windows with color. Thanks for watching, and I look forward to seeing you in the next clip.