[Autogenerated] in this clip will look at working
with life tiles in the start menu.
There's no doubt about it,
one of the features that really grabs your attention when you first see a
Windows 10 device are the tiles on your Start menu.
Many of the tiles that make up your start menu are actually live tiles.
That's a really good name for him.
You can see they're always in movement.
There's information being presented images.
Live tiles are really designed to give you information from within the app,
so you can take that away at a simple glance.
As you can see here, information from calendar,
e mails, photos,
news and many other sources is being presented and updated constantly.
No, not every tile that appears in your start menu is alive tile.
The lifestyle feature really is associated with APS
that come from the Windows Store, their modern APS And really,
it's a feature that the developer has to enable in order for
the tile to present information from that.
At other factors that will determine if your live tiles are presenting,
information may be related to the size of the tile APS that have never
been opened may not present lifestyle information,
and occasionally I'll notice APS that I've not used in a while
that stop presenting live tiled information.
So there's a few different things you can do to make
lifestyles really work for you.
One of these has to do with actually managing that functionality from the tile.
When you right click a tile in your start menu,
you'll see there's a few different things that appear in the context menu.
Generally, when you select more,
you'll see the option to turn live tiles off or on now,
very default.
When APS are pinned to the start menu,
live tiles are enabled if that features available so it could be that you find
this to be a little distracting in the case of some maps.
So to disable this,
you would actually just select turn lifestyle off knows I mentioned previously.
Not all tiles are live tiles,
so if an application was installed by means of a
download or from an installation disk, you can still right click it.
You'll still see them or option here in your contacts menu.
But you won't see the ability to turn on or off lifestyle functionality
because it was really never part of that applications abilities.
Now some applications have special features that work with
live tiles from within the APP itself.
A good example of this is the photos out here If I open the photos
up and then select settings noticing my settings.
I have a tile setting.
So even though I can enable or disabled the lifestyle
functionality from the tile itself in the start menu here,
I can fine tune a little bit.
What appears on the lifestyle notice gives me a choice of using recent
photos or having one fixed single photo for my lifestyle.
So presently,
there's really not too many gaps that have the ability to
control or manage what appears in the live tile.
But it could be that with time we'll see more APS that leverage this
powerful ability of using live tiles within the start menu.
I mentioned previously that the size of the tile has an
effect on live tiled performance as well.
Basically, the bigger the tile is, the more information that could be presented.
If you go with a small tile, you can't really expect there to be any live tile.
Information is presented so medium wide and large certainly
function perfectly well for most applications.
Well,
some other things to consider when you work with
lifestyles is in some situations.
You may be concerned about data consumption.
Now, in the case of lifestyles,
it's a very small amount of data that's being consumed.
But that can add up,
especially if you have a big start menu with lots of different maps
that are constantly pulling information down from the Internet to
provide updated live tile information.
So it could be that you want to disable life tiles for
many of your APS in a case like this,
or even all of them if you're really concerned about
data consumption in this clip,
we've looked at working with live tiles on the start menu. Thanks for watching, and I look forward to seeing you in the next clip.