[Autogenerated] in this clip will look at using the Microsoft store out.
The Microsoft store APP was first introduced with
Windows eight as the Windows Store app,
and it's been updated and greatly improved since then.
In addition of finding new APS and Games free device,
you can also purchase or rent movies and TV shows.
And in some markets you can actually shop for devices and purchase E books.
When you first open the Microsoft Store APP, you begin at the hometown.
From here, you'll see sales,
promotions or featured content found throughout
different areas of the APP scrolling down.
I can see some daily deals, but a few top lists and new contact.
As you can see, the home tab has a little bit of everything.
We're looking for something specific.
Use the tabs to jump between available product areas and types.
Example.
Let's jump over to the AP stem Now.
Here again, I can see sales and featured content and scrolling down.
I'm seeing top lists and categories within APS.
If I scroll all the way down, I'll eventually get two categories,
and this could be a practical way to filter content.
As you browse through content, you can see prices are indicated.
You can tell there's many reviews and you give me an idea for
how favourable those reviews have been.
To get more specific details will select a nap now.
In some cases, the video might be displayed automatically,
such as a movie, trailer or otherwise.
You'll see artwork or an image purchase.
Options are primarily displayed, as well as a brief description of the product,
and you can see rating information will be displayed here as well.
Scrolling down just a little bit.
You'll see important.
Tam's or review gives you a full description of the product,
and you could notice that some maps may have availability for
specific hardware form factors that run Windows 10.
It's rolling down.
Pay attention to the approximate size down here.
This could be important when you're considering some maps
and games when you're looking at movies,
you'll also see size information indicated down here gives you
an idea how much space would be required if you decided to
download the movie to your toys.
Now, when you're looking at an APP, you can see screenshots.
Similar APS are usually presented a list of features.
You'll see information from the developer.
Usually it will also give you links to their website.
So if you need support for an issue for that application,
this would probably be the best place to start.
Notice that there's also a list of permissions for that app
listed under this app can know Absecon.
Very some will require access to your Internet connection location,
settings, webcam, a microphone or your contacts.
Depending on the APB and its purpose jumping to the System Requirements tab,
you can see the recommended and minimum requirements.
Some maps, especially gaming APS,
could be pretty advanced and demanding they could actually exceed
your devices abilities to render and play properly.
If that's the case,
generally you'll see an alert here that will let you know if this
particular app could be an issue on your particular device.
That's usually a good idea to look at the reviews,
and the review tab will show you whatever reviews
might be available for the out again.
Some of them may have more than others.
Reviews from other users may also reveal issues regarding
hidden costs or general support for the out.
Finally,
the related tab will show you more content that
similar perhaps from the same developer.
Or that's targeting the same type of user.
When you're looking at a product,
you can use the back arrow up here to return to where you are previously,
or use the tabs a top to return to any of the upper level areas within.
The Microsoft store knows I mentioned earlier, and some market.
You may see different tabs up here, so in the US you'll see devices,
and this allows you actually shop for hardware that sold through
the Microsoft store and on the Microsoft website.
The books have also is not shown in all markets as yet,
but from here you could shop for e books that can be
downloaded and red using your Edge Web browser.
Yet another town that you can see here is the edge extensions Tam.
Now this tab features plug ins or extensions for the Edge
Web browser that comes with Windows 10.
As with APS and movies, you can browse through extensions and look at reviews.
You can purchase an extension, which can then be downloaded,
and you'll find it available within the edge Web browser,
now off to the right of our tabs in the Microsoft store up.
We have the search tool.
You can use this to search for keywords,
and you'll see the content from anywhere within the Microsoft store app that
matches typing cruise and you can see there's a lot of results,
and it split up for us into corresponding areas within the hour.
While Microsoft account is not required to obtain freedom through the store,
you will be encouraged to sign into the APP want resigned in.
You could manage many things that are linked to your Microsoft account,
including purchases and payment options,
and also from this more list, you can also manage,
absent or install the new device, including updates.
Now we're gonna look in more detail at making purchases and many engineer
installs from the Microsoft store app in another clip.
In this clip, we've looked at using the Microsoft store out. Thanks for watching had looked forward to seeing you in the next clip