[Autogenerated] in this clip will look at using folders in the START menu.
The Windows has long used folders as a tool to organize files and other content.
It's a concept we're all used to seeing and pilots poor,
and we even see folders in are all APS navigation menu.
Recently,
Windows added the ability to create folders right in the start menu itself,
too great a folder.
Just select and hold a tile and then drag it onto another tile.
Make sure you're directly over the other tile.
Otherwise it will just try to reposition,
thinking you're simply rearranging your tiles.
Want your Tyler's position directly over the other one?
Go ahead and release it.
The two files will now be grouped into a folder.
No,
this will be a very familiar concept to anyone that
used an Android and IOS device.
Both allow for similar grouping of APS to conserve space on their home screens.
What you've created a folder.
You can continue to add additional tiles to it,
toe open an app that's in a folder.
Just select the folder and you'll see it expand to display
full size tiles within While expanded,
the folder looks pretty much just like a group,
and you can rename an expanded folder now,
while the folders expanded, live tiles will work and display live tile content.
When the folders condensed, you won't see any lifestyle functionality right.
Clicking in a folder lets you resize it so you could make a larger
where he could reduce it to even a small tile.
The folder time will display small icons for all of its content.
But if the size doesn't allow all the contain icons to display,
it'll simply show the quantity of tiles that size permits.
To remove a folder,
you need to drag the tiles out of the fold and
relocate them back in your start menu.
When the last tiles been removed, the folder simply ceases to exist.
Now folders are great solution for finding seldom used APS,
especially if they're often used for a related tasks
so you could group them together.
For example, you may only occasionally use games on your device,
so throw them all into a folder.
You'll know where they are when you need him,
and you won't have to sacrifice and he start menu space.
Perhaps you occasionally use a few different taps for editing your photos again.
A folder that you keep them all together and you'll know
right where they are when you need him.
In this clip, we've looked at using folders on the start menu. Thanks for watching and look forward to see new in the next clip.