[Autogenerated] in this clip will look at the Windows taskbar.
The taskbar has long been a essential feature of Windows,
and while Windows 10 doesn't present a lot of changes to the desk bar,
the taskbar itself is home to some new features.
Starting here on the left, you have your start button,
which opens your start menu.
You have a search field, which could also be represented by an icon,
and you have a few icons that already pinned there.
So, just like your start menu, you can pin APS to the START menu.
You can pin APS to your taskbar as well.
That makes him highly visible and easy.
Tow.
Launch by default.
You'll see a few that are already pitting here.
For example,
you have your task view Microsoft Edge File Explorer and the
Window Store and you're off to the right.
We see our notifications area, and you can launch the action center from here.
Well, look at those and other clips.
When you have open applications running on your device,
you'll see a narrow horizontal bar at the bottom of the icon on the test bar.
However,
your curse over one of these icons to get a live
thumbnail preview of that open application.
We have multiple instances you'll actually see
multiple thumbnails for each open window.
Now there's a few things you can do.
Customize the taskbar.
You can relocate it by selecting and dragging the taskbar
to a different border of your screen,
and you can select the exposed edge of the task fire.
To resize it right,
click an open area of the taskbar and select task Marcel aliens.
This will open the settings up directly to the settings related to your task.
For you can see there's quite a few switches here that you
can use to manage your task for lock.
The task for the switch prevents it from being
relocated or resized as we saw earlier.
You can use these switches to automatically hide the
task fire and notice that once,
which is for desktop mode and the other for tablet mode by default,
this has turned off for desktop mode and enabled for tablet mode.
Of course, you can change either of these settings if you need to.
The switch used small taskbar _______ as the name implies enabling.
This will use smaller sized icons or _______ on the task for which
will allow you to see more information on the task.
For some people, like depend a lot of applications to the taskbar,
so they're easy to find that describes you,
then this may be a good setting for you to enable the switch used.
Peak to preview the desktop prefers to a tool that's
located on the far right end of the taskbar.
One enable you can hover over it to temporarily see the desktop.
Or you can select the peak tool to minimize all of your applications at once.
Show badges on taskbar _______ will allow badges to be used down here.
The Avengers can indicate status for an open application,
or they could display numbers indicating new emails or messages.
Just give you a couple examples below this.
Our menus that allow you to manually manage the taskbar location on
the screen and to allow _______ to be stacked.
When you have multiple instances of the same application open,
for example, you might have several spreadsheets open an excel.
Now the switch will allow them to.
Either stack is a single button,
taking up less space braking force them each have their own button,
which could make it easier to jump between open files.
Well, look closer at the notification area in a separate clip.
So for now we will jump down to multiple displays.
Now, if you have multiple displays, you can make a few changes here.
First,
the switch allows you to display task bars on all of your
displays or just the primary or main display.
The next menu is again related to _______.
You can choose to show _______ for open applications on all of your displays,
just on the display that the APP is currently opened in,
or the main display and the current display again,
you could manage whether _______ are stacked on any of your task bars
beyond the main one that was managed from up here.
Well, look at the people up in a separate clip.
So for now,
we'll also skipped the taskbar settings related to the people out in this clip,
we've looked at using the taskbar on windows. Thanks for watching, and I look forward to seeing you in the next clip