Okay,
We have a title for a worksheet,
but it looks a little boring at the moment.
It's just in plain or Calibri 11 on.
What we're going to do now is learn how to format our funds.
So the first thing we're gonna do is select the cell that we want to format.
So just selected cell a one,
and there are a couple of methods to do this.
The 1st 1 we're gonna look at is using the home ribbon and specifically the font section of
the home ribbon.
Now,
we have a few options available to us here.
Not all of the options are available to us,
but we'll come to that in a little while now.
The first thing we can see is that we have a calibri currently selected.
So with the sole selected,
I'm gonna choose this little down arrow button just here.
And now every form that is available on your system will be listed in this in this little
scroll,
but scroll box here and notice what happens in cell a one.
As I move over each of the different font names,
you can see that in real time the phones is being updated in our spreadsheet,
so you can get a pretty good idea of what your text will look like if you were to choose
any particular funds.
Now,
at the moment,
I'm gonna stick with calibrate Now,
there is a quicker way of doing this.
If you know the name of the fund that you want to use,
you can just come up.
So here,
left,
click hit delete To get rid of the Texas in there and say we wanted to use times new Roman
,
we could we could literally just start type.
In times they go and it's already said times New Roman site enter on,
they go.
Our text has changed to times New Roman.
No,
actually,
like a livery.
So I'm gonna go back to Calibri Calibri.
So we're back a clean break.
Now the next thing we may want to do is also the size of our text.
Then we have three ways of doing this from the home ribbon.
We can use a little drop down box here,
left click on again noticing the sell.
What happens?
We can see that the font size is increasing as we scroll down and it will decrease as we
scroll back up.
Um,
let's just leave us.
It's 11 for now.
The other way is to click this little button here,
which is the increased phone sized button on for each click that we give it with our left
mouse.
You can see in this window here when l 2 14 Now we're up to 16.
So that will increase our font size by one of the uniform measures each time that listed
here.
Okay,
we can decrease our fun size by clicking this little button here,
and each time we click it,
our front gets smaller.
Now you may be thinking,
Well,
actually,
that there's a big gap between number 28 number 36 actually want to phone size of 32.
That's fine.
You can have a fun size of 32 by coming into this little box here.
Left click until you get the blinking cursor hit backspace to delete the number that's in
there and just type in the number on your keyboard that you want.
I said 32 didn't.
So let's say 30 to hit Enter and they go l font sizes No.
32 which isn't a standard form size listed here,
so you can even have decimals in there.
So if we wanted a 27.5,
we just talked.
27.5 hit,
enter,
and they go out of font sizes.
No,
27.5.
I actually,
like 22 4 titles,
so let's go back and change that 22.
Okay,
Next three things we're gonna look at are the bold,
italicized onda underlined,
which you can see are quickly accessed by using the B button on.
As we hover over it,
we can see the tool Tip tells us that this is bold and that the keyboard shortcuts his
control and bait.
Next to that,
we have I,
which stands for italics on We can see there that the keyboard shortcut is control.
And I andi underlying,
which we can see is the keyboard choker is control.
And you now you'll notice that the minute that all of these are Weiss in background until I
hover over them if I actually just want the text to be bold So I'm just gonna left click
bold.
We can see that that the text is being molded,
but as I move my cursor,
you can see that the B has remained highlighted.
That's a very useful way of finding out which formats have been applied to your text.
Okay,
so have a play around with those and make it bold making underlying to tell a size or any
combination of those three until you get a look that you're happy with.
Okay,
for now,
I'm going to skip over this option.
I'm going to skip over this option and I'm gonna come straight over here to the font color
.
If I select a little down arrow,
I have a range of theme Kalis that I could choose from.
And as I roll over them you can see that the you can see that cell a one is changing to
match whenever I'm hovering over,
have standard collis are available across the button.
Just here Now,
this should be good enough selection for you.
But if it's not,
don't worry.
Just left.
Click the more collis and you'll come to this option here so you can see all of your
standard colors.
You can see your current color is black and if I select this rather nice pinky color,
the new color is pink If I clicked.
Okay,
a text would go pink.
If this isn't a large enough array of colors for you,
you can hit the custom and you can left click and you can move around and literally select
any color that you could create far too many only Click Cancel for now on the left,
Click Next.
I quite like the green.
So they go with no successfully made a text green.
We've made it bold and we've increased the font size to 22 which looks much better as a
title.
Okay,
that's how you do that Use in the home ribbon.
The next method we're gonna look at is by right clicking in the cell itself and choosing
format cells.
So right,
click the cell.
Choose format cells left,
click.
Let me just drag that into shot.
And we now have the format cells dialog box which has now been displayed.
Now you can see across the top that we have six sections.
Here we have number.
We have alignment.
We have fund,
which is the one we want to play with.
We have border Phil and protection.
Don't worry about the other five.
For the moment we're just going to stick with front Now You can see here that everything
that we have displayed in the ribbon is displayed in this box too.
So we can see that we have Calibri Kelly Brick Nager.
You can see the no text is bold id on.
We can see by the highlight there that the Texas Bold We can see that we have a fun size of
22 which is reflected just here.
We can see we have no underlying on that are colored green.
Now the things that we get access to by going into it this way is we can also get to strike
through superscript and subscript.
Now,
if I want to make a change in this particular window,
it will not be updated in the cell until I click the OK.
So just to demonstrate,
if I chose red,
we can see in the preview window just here that the text will may be red,
but it doesn't actually show is ready in the cell until we click.
OK,
so let me just go back and change that to Green.
As I quite like it,
we'll use the preview window to see what these different effects do so if we left click the
little tick box their strike through,
we can see that we get a line through our text left click again to remove it Superscript
raises the text above the normal line Left click to remove it on Come down to sub scripting
Probably guess what matters left Click and it makes the script subscript And I'm gonna left
click just to undo That's I quite like it the way Liz Okay,
so hit.
Okay,
when you're happy with any changes that you made and away we go there The final method of
format in your font is some combination of the two.
If you look very closely at the top right hand corner of just zoom in here,
Okay?
If you look very closely at the bottom right hand corner of the following section of the
ribbon,
you'll see this little icon.
And if we hover over it,
we can see that we have fun settings.
So if we left click this little icon immediately,
have format cells,
dialogue boxes popped back up,
and it's automatically going to fund,
which is exactly what we want to play with.
Because we came from the fund section of the ribbon on again.
We can get access to the subscript and the superscript and all these different options.
If this is a way that you prefer to do it personally,
I prefer to use the ribbon because you can see the changes in real time happening in your
spreadsheet.
Where's with this?
You just have the little preview window.
It's a personal choice thing.
Have a play around with both.
See what you think in whichever one works for you.
Use that one.
OK,
that's funds.
Next,
we're gonna have a look at alignment.