right,
Let's take a quick look it alignment now at the moment,
just so it's clear what change in the alignment settings does.
I've made column F wider than the other columns,
and I made Row three taller than the other columns.
Xolo shy to help us as much as it can by using its default settings.
Now it does this very cleverly when it comes to entering data in cells by looking at the
data type and automatically apply in the appropriate format.
So for text,
it is always aligned to the left hand side of the sell by default.
So we just talked some texting.
Hey,
center,
we can see that it's on the far left hand side of the South.
Okay.
Similarly,
if we talked to number in,
although at the moment it's appearing on the left hand side of the cell,
assumes we hit Enter Excel will work out that it's actually a number on a line it to the
right hand side of the South.
These is the default settings,
but don't worry.
We can have the we can have the text appearing wherever we want in the cell and the way
we're going to do that is by looking at the home ribbon on the alignment section.
Just here.
Notice that the only option that selected by default is the bottom line,
Which is this highlighted?
One.
Just here.
Now we may as well go across the top while we're here,
so if we click the next button across the middle line,
you can see the text jumps up to the middle.
If we choose the next one across top,
ally moves to the top on below that we're dealing with the horizontal axis so we can move
over to the left.
We can have it in the center,
or we can move it over to the right again if we want to.
Text to appear dead center.
Just select center from the bottom and middle from the top and their text appears in the
center.
Okay,
let's go back over to the right.
Let's leave it there now.
At the moment,
you'll see that writer line has been highlighted.
So what that means is that we have just overridden the automatic default settings that
excel would normally apply.
So here,
if we type some text in normally,
it would leap over.
So the left hand side.
But no,
because we've overridden that default setting,
it's staying on the right hand side.
So that's the way to tell if you've actually selected the format or if it's the default.
If it's if all of these three are not highlighted,
you'll get the default options.
If you've highlighted one that will override your default,
okay,
that's how you change that use in the home ribbon on the alignment section.
The other two methods are exactly the same we talked about when we learned has a format of
found.
We have the right click option.
So click in the cell right click Choose Format sells the format cells box pops up on select
the alignment tab if it isn't already selected,
and you get mostly the same options here is.
Well,
I'm just gonna close that on.
You'll recall that the short cut to get to that is this little icon just up the corner here
,
which,
if you left click causes the same box to open,
have a play around with the different sentence.
Have a lot of fun,
as much fun as you can have with a line in text in cells,
and I'll see you in the next lecture