Okay,
guys,
shortly we're going to be entering the headings for all of our data.
But before we do that,
I'm going to show you a neat trick in Excel.
It's gonna make your life a lot simpler.
I mentioned a little earlier that Excel does whatever it can to help you on one of the ways
it does.
This is by auto filling sequences.
I can best demonstrate this by actually showing you how it does it.
So if we would type Monday into any one of our cells and hit enter when we go back up to
the cell that say's Monday,
If you look very closely at the bottom right hand corner,
you can see this little block.
If you have your cursor over there,
you can see that the curse of changes.
If you left,
click your mouse button there and drag across,
you can see that it automatically works out that the sequence should probably be the days
of the week,
and similarly,
we can also go this way on dragged down one day Tuesday,
Wednesday,
Thursday,
Friday,
and as soon as you let go of your left mouse,
it automatically populates the sequence for you.
This will save you a lot of time having to type in Monday,
Tuesday,
Wednesday,
Thursday,
Friday,
and so on and so forth.
Okay,
let's just delete these just here.
I'm just highlight and then hitting delete on the keyboard,
so you'll notice that I typed Monday in full.
If I would just hope just mum and come back up to the cell and again go to this little box
at the corner,
wait till the cat cursor changes left,
click and drag down.
You can now see that it's also populated the sequence automatically,
but because I abbreviated Monday,
two months,
it's automatically abbreviated Tuesday to chew Wednesday toe when?
Thursday to Fu on DSO one and so forth.
Okay,
so we know it could do the days of the week.
Let's come over here if you were to type,
not jam Jum and hey,
center and come over here.
It will also work out that what we probably want to type is a sequence of the months and
again,
you see,
because I abbreviated January,
you can see it's automatically abbreviated all of the names of the month,
right?
So that's fairly easy,
because there are very few things that would follow Monday other than Tuesday.
One Excel needs if we're working with numbers,
is to spot a pattern.
And to do that,
it needs to see at least two entries to work out what that pattern will be.
So if I come into this cell just here and type one If I were to try to also fill now by
Dragon,
then you can see we just get one more,
more,
mom one all the way down.
But if I were to Cyp,
let me just delete that,
Okay?
If I were to type one and then type two on,
highlight both the boxes,
either by left clicking and dragging over them,
or click in the first on Hit and Shift and Down Arrow to highlight them on.
Then I hover over this little box here you can see that the curse has changed.
Excel has no worked out that what we're doing is increasing by an increment of one each
time and consequently it will automatically populate 12345 all the way down for us.
Far as we highlight now,
it can also do things a little bit cleverer than that.
So if we were to type two full,
it would also work out that what we're doing.
His increase in my in increments of two each time.
So when we dragged down,
we can see that we'll never get 2468 10 12.
This could save you an awful lot of time if you have a lot of sequences of data that you
need to enter,
Okay.
Now,
not only does it auto populates sequences going down and going over to the right if we were
to tight Monday in here on,
then we re select the cell,
come to this little box up the corner,
hover over it until they occur.
So changes we can also go up,
and it would populate the proceeding sequence.
And similarly,
if we would just like Monday and drag over to the left,
we can see that we know get some day and then a Saturday.
So any sequence,
no matter where you start in your workbook,
you can either drank down using this little box up the corner and left clicking.
You can drag right,
you can drag left and you can drag up,
and it will automatically populate the sequence.
The only thing to keep in mind,
obviously,
is if you're doing a sequence of numbers such as one and two,
that you need to highlight both of the cells on.
If you want to populate the proceeding sequence left,
click and drag up and you can see that will go to zero a minus one.
And it gives you a hint as to what it's gonna talk in that tone,
a little box that's appearing just there.
So they go.
That's a very quick way to enter a bunch of data that's in a natural sequence in Excel.
We're going to use that,
you know,
next lecture.
When we put in the headings for our new table,
so you and then it clicked you.