Okay,
guys,
In the last lecture,
we have a look at the auto fill sequence,
and we know that we can use that very quickly to populate the days of the week all the
months of the year.
But wouldn't it be particularly useful if you could add your own custom lists?
Well,
luckily,
you can So imagine for a second that if you manage a particular department and you have
half a dozen members of staff from 10 or 20 members of staff rather than having to tighten
their names out individually in a column every time that you have to report on something,
you can just add them to your own custom list type.
The first name usually drag handle,
and they're automatically populated.
Well,
luckily,
it's really easy to do on.
What we're gonna do is we're going to use the file ribbon,
which is just that the top just here.
We're gonna left click on the file option.
We're going to come down to options just down the bottom.
Here,
we're getting a left click,
and then this little dialog box is gonna pop up.
You see,
we have another bunch of options down the left hand side on.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna come to the advanced option on left.
Click on this window is going to open up and see that we have a scroll bar.
What we want to do is left,
click and drag all the way down to the bottom until we can see edit custom lists.
So just left click the edit custom lists and they go,
you can see the built in ones that are already there in excel.
And what we're going to do because we have new list added,
is we're going to click,
add,
and our curse is going to jump over to the list and interest.
So I'm just gonna pause for a second.
I'm just gonna answer a bunch of names in there,
and then I'll come back to you in just a second.
Okay,
There you go.
So I've just talked to a bunch of names there.
So we now have Tracy,
Emmylou,
Orville,
Ricardo,
Maurice,
Mike am Belinda.
So what I'm gonna do now is click add and you can see that net.
That list is no populated over here.
We know custom lists.
We're gonna click,
OK,
and then we're going to click OK again,
and then we're gonna try.
And so Tracy was the first person in our department.
So let's just send to Tracy in there.
Hit,
enter,
then re select the cell.
Come to the drag handle.
Left click drag down on.
There you go.
You can see that all the members of our department automatically populated.
And then when they get back to the beginning,
their repeated again,
just like the days of the week and the months of the year.
Okay,
so that's one way to add a custom list into the custom list feature of auto fill.
There's also another way to do it.
Let's imagine that you have to report frequently on a bunch of departments in your company
.
So let's go ahead and add a bunch of departments for our company.
Okay?
I'm just gonna pause for a second while I typed them in.
And then I'll come back to you in just a few seconds.
Okay,
So what I've done have just entered a bunch of departments at random in the cells here,
So tight warehouses transport a camp sales tech support marketing human resource is in the
States and then what we're gonna do is we're going to use that list to build our own custom
list game.
We're going to go to the file option We're going to choose options again on we're gonna
choose Advanced again.
And this time I'm going to scroll down.
She was edit custom lists on this time.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna click this little symbol just here.
So we're just gonna left click there,
and we're gonna drag a box by left clicking and dragon with almost You can see that that
ranges being selected in here.
So now what we're gonna do is click this little button and we can press the import and you
can see their lists No,
been imported into our custom lists.
So again,
just here.
OK,
just hits.
Okay again against you know what we're gonna do to test it out?
We're gonna type in warehouse on.
We're gonna left click on,
we're gonna drag down and they go.
You can see that all of the other departments have been populated automatically because
we've already added that to the list.
We can go ahead and quite safely delete the original source.
The one that we imported.
And we can find out that if we type in again that that should still work.
So it's just left,
click and drag,
and they go nice and using.
Now,
the one thing you may notice is that here while I talkto warehouse,
I typed it in lower case.
So it didn't have a capital beginning on automatically.
Excel suggested that so that all in lower case.
But here I talked with the capital of the beginning,
so accept automatically capitalize all of those interests.
So there you go.
That's how you add your own custom lists.
Enjoy.
So you in the next lecture.