Okay,
now we're going to get to what?
X elders.
Best maths.
Now Exhale has a number of built in functions to speed up entering formulas.
At the moment,
we're going to start at the very beginning on do sums the old fashioned way.
So we're going to come over to sell G five and just left click to select it.
Now,
the first thing to remember whenever you enter a formula in Excel is it.
It always begins with an equal sign.
So if you hit equals on your keyboard instantly,
Excel will know that what you're entering is a formula,
and this is true for every single formula you'll ever enter in Excel.
Okay,
at the moment,
what we want to do is add up a total sales of Apple's for the week on Monday,
Tuesday,
Wednesday,
Thursday and Friday.
So what we can do is just simply left Click the first entry,
and you can see that it's been highlighted with the dancing ants hit.
Plus,
we can move on most over click Tuesday hit plus move and those over Wednesday plus Thursday
plus Friday and hit Enter and you can see that it's cleverly total everything up.
So that's how you do something old fashioned Way now.
One thing to notice.
With this,
if if I hit F two on my keyboard,
you can see that it shows us the formula rather than the result.
Now,
one thing to pay particular attention to I'll just move the mouse out.
The way here is that you can see that each of the cell references that is the B five,
c five,
d five,
e five and F five,
all highlighted in different colors,
and they correspond to the colors that highlighted in the cells themselves.
And then this is very useful because he makes it easy to spot which part of your formula is
referring to which sell.
So,
for example,
if we wanted to change D five,
we can instantly see that that it's kind of a purple color on.
We can see that this is a purple color.
Well,
if we have around most over until our cursor changes to this pointed cross,
we can left,
click and drag,
and you can see that I have formula is changing accordingly so we could move it over to the
left.
We can move it to the right,
we can move it anywhere.
So if for argument's sake,
we accidentally clicked the wrong cell and let's just hit Enter on DA and hit F two again,
we can see instantly by this highlight in that we've actually selected the wrong cell when
we typed her formula in.
So it's easy to correct,
rather than having to retire the entire formula,
just hover over the part that's incorrect because he should be adding up all of their apple
sales left.
Click drag up and you can see that your formula is being corrected.
Hit,
enter and they go.
And that's how you do a some the old fashioned way.
In the next lecture,
we will be covering how to use the auto some function.
See you in the next lecture.