Okay,
guys,
First things first.
We need to open Excel so we can begin to learn about it.
Now,
I find that the easiest method to do this is to have a short cut on your desktop already.
Now I have one just here called Excel 2013.
If you have one of these,
fantastic.
Just hover over it.
Double click your left mouse button and you're good to go.
If you don't have one of those,
Don't worry.
I'm gonna show you how to add one to your desktop shortly,
right.
Method number two.
Now,
if you already have a workbook that someone has sent you,
the simplest method is so literally just double click on the icon of that workbook.
You can see we have one down here that I have cleverly prepared earlier.
So if we double click this Excel file,
which is called a workbook,
Excel will automatically open and it will open that particular file.
The third way to Open Excel is using your start button.
So if you come down here to your start button left,
click your mouse button,
you may well find that you have Excel already appearing in this first menu here.
If you don't don't worry.
The more times you open excel,
the higher up this list that will become so if it's not there in the moment.
Don't worry about it.
It will be soon now method for also from the start menu.
If you If you didn't see excel in here,
don't worry.
You can always go to the all programs.
Let's go back a little.
You can go to all programs left.
Click and you'll find a little folder called Microsoft Office 2013.
Yours may say 2010 or at major same Microsoft office.
If you left click this folder,
it will expand and show you all the programs that you currently have installed in the
office suite.
Just go down to excel.
Double click with your left mouse.
Andi Excel will open for you now.
I did mention that if you didn't have a desktop short cuts already,
I would show you a Tad one.
We're going to do that right now.
So while you are hovering over Excel and it's highlighted,
click your right mouse button.
Choose send to choose desktop,
create short cut left click and then when we moved the menu.
We'll see.
We have a shortcut icon for Excel there.
Now,
this is called on my screen Excel 2013 to the reason for that being that I already have
Excel 2030 in there.
Don't worry about the name of it.
If you hover over the icon,
right click,
choose rename.
You can call it anything you want from there.
So that's called in Excel Press enter.
And there you go.
You have a desktop.
I come.
Okay,
The final method,
if none of those have work for you yet is again using your start menu.
But this time we're going to choose the search programs and files.
So if you click your left mess button in there so you get a little blinking cursor on tell
effects cell the it will go away,
and it will find everything that references excel in your computer.
So you're gonna be looking under programs and you'll click it.
You'll find Excel listed just there.
Okay,
So let's open Excel.
We can go to our desktop short cut or our newly created desktop short cut double click,
and you'll be presented with screen that looks very much like this now,
in order to learn about the anatomy of a workbook,
We're just gonna choose blank workbook for now,
so hover over it.
So it's highlighted.
Double click with your left mouse button.
Andi,
you'll be presented with screen that looks very much like this.
Okay,
next,
we're going to cover all of the main areas of this screen and what they do.