Okay,
guys,
we're just gonna very quickly cover a couple of ways of copying of formula to save you
having to rewrite it.
Then the last lecture recovered.
How to use the auto,
some function.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to copy that formula all the way across the
bottom of their data.
The first thing we can do is copy the sell by hitting control and see selecting the cell we
want to pace to by left clicking it on hitting control and V.
And if I move the cursor right,
the way you can see there that are forming there has been successfully copied to get rid of
the dancing on.
It's just hit the escape key on your keyboard and they go,
That's warm way of copying formula.
Let me just delete that.
Alternatively,
we could select the formula we have on.
We can come over to this little box just at the bottom right hand corner,
hover over its left click on drag as far as we want to go.
And then when we let go of the left mouse button,
there you go.
You can see that the former has been copied all the way across.
Let me just delete that.
On the other way is if you come to the cell immediately to the right of the cell.
You want to copy and hit control and are,
which is the keyboard shortcut for Phil?
Right?
Controlling our you can see that it's been copied across again so we can either copy using
control and see Move over either hit control,
envy or just hit.
Enter weakened drag over when it occurs to changes to the Black Cross.
Or we can left click in the cell immediately to the right of it.
Hit,
controlling our and they go.
And that's hey,
copyright!
Okay,
now,
very quickly.
I'm also going to show you the same way to do it.
Going downwards.
Now again,
we have exactly the same options we can either hit control with C.
Move down,
hit control and V.
Let me just delete that we can hit control and see come down and hit.
Enter Amega that gets rid the dancing Lance.
We can come to the cell immediately below it.
Hit control and D,
which is the keyboard shortcut for Phil down.
We can also drag down to fill down when we hover over the box on the corner and there
occurs to changes weaken,
just drag down,
let go and they go groups.
We can see that the formula's been copied.
But if we're talking about the vertical plane,
there is another very quick way to copy the formula down again.
If you come to this little box up the corner,
hover over it until your cursor changes to a plus double click,
and you can see that the formula is being copied all the way down.
Now,
the way it works out where the bottom of the range is,
it just looks to the cell immediately to the left to find out where the last entry is.
They go another time saving tip for excel.
Okay,
Next,
we're gonna have a look at how we can adapt the auto some formula so we can actually use it
to some a row of data.
Okay,
See you in the next lecture.