Okay,
guys,
let's have a look in there.
We adapt the auto,
some function that we've already used to work out the sum of a row of data.
Now,
at the moment in these cells,
we still have the old fashioned formula of this cell.
Plus that sell.
Plus that sell plus outsell.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm just going to delete that so we can start a fresh now if we
take a quick look at the auto some function,
the formula that was written for is automatically when we used auto some we can see that
the structure of the formula is the equal sign.
Which means it's a formula.
The function name,
which is some the brackets that open the range that we want to some on the brackets to
close off the arguments.
Okay,
What we're gonna do is we're gonna copy that,
and we're going to use it over the side here.
No one quick way of doing this is if you come up to the formula bar and delete the equal
sign hit enter.
You can see that no excel is treated.
This not as a formula,
but it's a string that is It's just letters and numbers.
OK,
so now we've done that,
we can easily refer back to it so we can copy it.
Okay,
so we're gonna come up here and we're gonna type equals because it's a formula that we're
entering.
We're gonna type some because we can see here that the function iss some.
We're going to copy that cell again by entering a bracket on.
Then we can see that we have excels tool tip that tells us what we need to enter next is a
number than a comma,
then a number than a comma,
so we could do it that way.
Let's just do it that way for a second.
So if we hit that and hit comma,
you can see that number one has been highlighted in the tool tip.
When I hit comma the tools it will expand and say no,
you need to enter number two.
So if I left click the second cell hit comma,
it will then say number three and on and on and on.
We're not going to do that because that's almost the same as the long way of doing it.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna highlight the range that we want to made up.
So I'm gonna left click on Selby five,
keep my mess but impressed on drag over to Friday.
So now we can see that the format of the formula is being copied so we can see down the
bottom that we have some open brackets arrange and closed brackets.
So all we need to do now is let go The left mouse button hit,
shift closed.
Brackets hit,
Enter And there you go.
We now have over some affording.
Now let me just come back down here and reinsert are equal sign They go So now we have a
formula down the bottom And as we learned in the last lecture just to quickly copy that
down hover over the corner to the drag handle to you curse the changes to the black cross.
Double click and they go,
we know know our total sales for each of our fruits and veggies on.
We also know actually a better put tight total in the boat.
Nasa.
We know what it is,
and we also know the total of our sales for the date by items.
So there you go.
That's how you adapt on auto some from a column and use it in a row.
See you in the next lecture.