right.
We're moving along at a great pace now.
Now,
the next formula we're going to look at is subtraction,
and it's very simple to do.
What we're gonna do is that two more columns to our data we're gonna add an opening stock
opening stock on we're then gonna add Are closing stock closing stock again.
OK,
let's just resize those.
We've done this before.
Just highlight the columns.
DoubleClick in between.
And I wish I could type closing stock.
They go.
Okay,
now,
I'm just gonna randomly make up some numbers here.
So let's imagine that we started the week with 75 of everything,
So I'm just going to hit 75 enter re select the Cell DoubleClick,
which we know Phil's down.
So they go there.
We know that opening stock waas,
and now it's time to do out subtraction formula never could do this in one of two ways.
What we could say is equals.
It's a formula that less that less that less that left that less that an enter to find out
that we would have 35 left,
is over close in stock,
and we can do it in a much quicker way by utilizing something that we've already done.
So what we can do is win type equals opening stock on as we've already worked out.
What the total of all of these are in this formula just here.
We're just going to say opening stock minus total sales hit,
Enter.
And there you go 35 on again to copy that formula down.
We're just going to double click when our cursor changes to the black Cross to fill down on
.
There you go.
We can see that we started with 75 of each of our items and we ended with 35 apples,
40 oranges and so on and so forth all the way down just in case it wasn't obvious to you
Excel will automatically re calculate.
So if we look at oranges,
we can see that I open stock with 75 Andi,
Once we subtract all of ourselves,
we have 40 left.
If we change that to 50 in his enter,
you can see that this result has also changed.
So excel automatically Recalculates.
You don't have to do anything again.
It automatically works it'll for you.
And they go nice and simple onto the next lecture