Okay.
We're covering a lot of ground very quickly.
We've learned how to do addition the longhand way,
the old fashioned way.
We've learned how to do addition using the auto some function on.
We've also learned how to do subtraction.
Next,
we're going to cover multiplication.
And to do this,
we're gonna add another column to ever table on this time,
we're going to call it monthly sales.
Okay,
we're gonna do this very simply.
I'm just going to resize out there,
OK,
now,
because we already know how many of each item we sell a week because we used our some
function over here in column G.
We're going to utilize that again just to do a simple multiplication,
for simplicity's sake.
Well,
just imagine their four weeks in each month.
I know that's not strictly correct,
but let's just do that for simplest is sake.
So we're gonna type equals,
which tells excel that we're about to enter a formula.
We're gonna click total because we already know the total of our weekly sales.
We're gonna hit,
multiply four and hit.
Enter and then you go.
We can see that if if a month had four weeks their monthly cells of apples would be 160 on
.
We're gonna hover over there and just double click to fill down so we can instantly see
what our monthly sales of each of their items would bay.
They go on.
That's how you do Multiplication.
Very simple indeed.
Onto the next lecture,
where will cover division?