Okay,
guys,
let's have a look at a simple division formula now a game.
We're gonna add another column over here at the end,
and we're gonna work out this time with an average daily sales are so I'm just gonna type
average daily sales on they go.
Okay,
I'm just gonna resize that again.
We're going to come into our first empty self,
and we're going to hit equals to tell Excel that we're about to do a formula.
Next,
we're going to utilize our some again from column G.
So we're just gonna left click there and we can see that That's also massively been
highlighted.
We're going to hit divide.
We're going to count up family.
We need to divide by.
So we have Monday,
Tuesday,
Wednesday,
Thursday,
Friday.
That's five.
So we just hit 500 keyboard hit,
Enter on.
There you go.
We can see that our average daily sales for apples is eight.
And again,
we'll just click that cell double click window cursor changes.
And there you go.
We can see our average daily sales for each of our items.
Now,
that's how you do a simple division.
obviously,
because we working out on average.
We may also want to use the average function,
and we're going to cover that in the very next lecture.
So you in a few seconds?