Okay,
guys,
we've covered a lot of ground.
So far,
we've covered basic addition.
We've covered basic subtraction,
basic multiplication and basic division in our earlier lectures.
We've also had a quick look at our first Excel,
built in function of auto some.
And we're about to come to our second built in function of excel,
which is average.
So just so I don't forget what it is that we're gonna be doing.
I'm just gonna type the title average,
you know,
less there.
So they will know what this is when we're looking at it.
Okay.
Now,
when we click auto,
some you'll recall from the earlier lecture excel automatically,
right?
So complete formula using the auto some now some is the operative word there.
If you've noticed there is actually a little down arrow below the auto,
some I come.
And if you left,
click with your mouse.
You can see that we have other options available to us on.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna hover over average left,
click on we can see there that excel is automatically written the complete formula forests
.
Now,
at the moment,
the formula is incorrect because we have not only ourselves for apples,
oranges,
all their fruits and veggies at the bottom.
We also have a total which is going to skew the result.
So for now,
let's just hit Enter and we can see that the average is 12.
Now,
what we need to do is edit the formula,
so it ignores the total on.
The way to do that is to hit F two on your keyboard,
and you can see that you now have access to the formula to be able to edit it.
Now we can see that range be five to be 14 as being selected,
which is reflected in the highlighted area on the worksheet on.
What we're gonna do is we're just gonna come up to the formula bar up here.
We're gonna left click just between the full and the closed brackets.
We're gonna delete before and we're gonna site five begin to lead the four.
We're gonna cite three.
So there we can see that the highlighted area is actually now only for our fruits and veg
is So Now we're happy that I have formulas being successfully edited.
Hey,
center on.
There you go.
We know about average sales of 6.666 lots of six is on the seven.
And again,
What we're gonna do is we're gonna copy that across for all of our days of the week by left
clicking dragon over with their mouths,
but impressed.
Let go the mayor Spartan.
And they go,
No,
we have our averages.
And that's a use the auto.
Some average function.
Okay,
so you in the next lecture.