Okay,
guys,
this later is the result of something that I learned only yesterday.
Now,
I've been using Excel for 20 something years on.
I've never even seen this function before,
but it's so useful.
Had to squeeze it into the curriculum just so that you're aware of it.
And it will really help to cement the electorate just on the order of mathematical
operation.
Okay,
here goes.
Now what we're gonna use is a tool that I have I only discovered yesterday,
and you'll find it in the formulas ribbon.
So if you come up here to formulas just left click and this ribbon will open up now,
The formula we looked at in the order of mathematical operation was equal.
Three plus three divided by two.
Okay,
so all we're gonna do is enter that formula in our cell on.
They were going to come up to the formula auditing section of the formulas Ribbon on.
We're going to click,
evaluate formula.
Let me just drag that into shot so I can ah,
consuming and you'll see clearly again.
There this little window appears here on what this does is it will allow excel to walk you
through step by step every single part of your formula so you can see that Oh,
formula up here in the formula bar say's equals three plus three divided my to.
And if you look in the evaluation section of the evaluate formula box,
you can see that innocently Excel is underlined.
Which part it's going to do first so you can see that it's gonna ignore the three plus for
the moment,
and it's underlined three divided by two.
So now you can see instantly that that's the first part of the formula that's going to be
executed.
So let's go ahead and click the evaluating That's gonna left Click there,
and now you can see that it's changed the three divided by 2 to 1.5 because it's completed
that part of the formula.
And there we can see the wallets left with is three plus 1.5.
So if we click again,
they go on.
This is going to be 4.5 hit restart and it will go through it again.
Okay,
now,
that's one way of doing it when we just use the values and what we're gonna do now,
rather than using a number in the cell.
We're gonna typo values into these cells here.
And then we're going to write a formula that references those middle That means is we're
going to click the cell rather than type the value in the formula.
So we're gonna type equals to tell Excel.
It's a formula we're going to click that Plus that divided by that may be pressed to that
That plus that divided by that hit Enter Re select the cell and hit Evaluate formula.
Let me just move that down a little bit.
Okay,
Now,
let's quickly go through this right.
Okay,
Now,
because we didn't type of value into our formula,
such as three plus three,
divided by two.
And we use the cell references.
The very first thing that Excel needs to do is go to those cells and actually extract what
the value is.
So at the moment are formula,
Say's a one plus a two divided by a three.
Now we've got a new function that you can see in here,
which is called Step In and you can see that a one is underlying,
So the first thing excels going to do is retrieve the value from a one,
and if we hit stepping,
you can see that a one has been highlighted and it's being selected on our spreadsheet.
And it says that the value in a one is three.
Okay,
so step out.
If you want to step in,
that's what it does.
It will select the So it's just about to look at now.
You can see there that previously we had a one on.
No,
it says three,
cause it's retrieved the value there was going to take a look at a two.
So when we hit evaluate,
it will say in a two you have the value of three,
and finally it's going to have a look at a three to see what values in there.
So when we click evaluate,
it will say to and there is going to say OK,
I've retrieved all my values.
Now I'm gonna work on the formula itself and again,
just as it did before.
It's gonna look at the division part first,
so it's underlining three divided by two,
and when we click,
evaluated or calculate that and say three,
divided by two is 1.5 and they're the final part of my formula is toe.
Add three to that answer.
So when we hit evaluate,
they go 4.5.
That's how we get it.
And if you want to go through it again,
hit restart and just click your left mouse button on this button and it will go all the way
through and they go evaluate formula.
Very useful on gun.
I've missed it for as long as it's been in Excel,
but they go No,
you know bad.
It's enjoy.
See you in the next lecture.