Okay,
let's talk about the anatomy of a workbook.
And the first thing I want you to notice is that the name of the fall you're working on is
always displayed in the top center section of the screen right here they can see it.
The moments is,
as we have opened a new workbook that Excel is called it Book won by default.
If we were to open another workbook,
that book would be called Book to Shortly will be covering how to rename the workbook to
something more meaningful.
Okay,
the next thing I want to draw your attention to is this large area right across the sub.
Just here.
This is called the Ribbon.
Now the ribbon is a really useful tool that allows us to do some really cool things in
excel.
And the ribbon is split into different sections.
As you'll see,
we have home.
We have insert insets.
We have page layouts,
formulas,
data and so on will cover each of these particular elements in more detail was,
of course,
progresses.
But just for now,
I just want to remember that this section across the top is called the ribbon righty ho The
next thing we're gonna have a quick look at is the quick access toolbar.
Now,
that's this small area at the top,
left hand side of the screen.
Just here.
Now,
at the moment,
all we can see is the excel.
I come he save.
I can't the undo and redo buttons.
I'm gonna show you shortly,
Hagen it how you can add more icons to that.
The things that you use all the time to save.
You haven't to go and navigate through the ribbon to find them.
The next thing we're gonna look at is at the top,
right hand side of the screen.
Now we have five little icons.
Just up here on the 1st 1 is a question mark on that is the help function for Microsoft
Excel.
You will see from the little pop up box that's just appeared underneath it,
that it will give you a tool tip to tell you what this particular icon does on also in
brackets weaken C F one on for the keyboard shortcut junkies out there.
F one is the keyboard shortcut to save Yemen to scroll around with the amounts to get to
the help function.
Just say F one on your keyboard and you're straight into Microsoft's help in this first
section of lectures.
Will will briefly touch on Mark Soft Excel help and have a look here that can help us.
Okay,
next icon along is to do with the ribbon display,
and we can either auto hide the ribbon show taps,
show tabs and commands a recommend leaving that exactly as it is at the moment.
Just so you always have the exact view that I have on that will save any confusion a little
later on.
Okay,
the next button along is the minimize button.
Now,
at the moment,
we can see that this is expanded to fill the whole screen.
If we were to click the minimize button,
it makes it disappear down here to our menu bar down the bottom.
Now we have a lost our work.
We haven't closed Excel.
It's still there,
Andi,
If we hover over it there,
you can see that it's popped back up a little picture so we can either click on it to bring
it back or just double click on Beacon will get our work sheep back.
Okay,
The next one along is the restore down.
Now,
if we click this,
it will shrink the size of the screen that we're looking at.
So if you prefer not to work with Excel occupying the whole of your desktop,
you can use this and it will shrink it down.
Now,
if you want to make that a little narrower,
you can just come to the right hand side here till the arrow changes left.
Click on Dragon or drag out.
You can do the same from this side so you can left click Dragon drag out.
If you just want to make it taller or shorter,
come down the button here,
left click,
move down,
move up.
Or,
if you want to move in both axes at same time,
just go.
One of the corners on do that Now Excel will remember exactly that size and that position
on the screen.
So if we know,
go to maximize.
So we expand the view to our full screen on,
then we choose to restore down.
It will go back to exactly the settings we just so exit.
Okay,
let's go back to full screen and finally the little X up the corner is too close now Don't
worry.
If you've made any changes to your workbook and you hit close accidentally,
you'll get a pop up message that asked you,
Do you want to save this file?
So don't worry.
If you accidentally click it,
you'll have an option to get out of it.
In case you didn't mean to click it,
the next area of the screen will look at is the formula bar.
That's this area right here.
Now,
as its name suggests,
this is a place where you can type formulas,
but you can also use it to input your data.
Be dates,
text numbers,
whatever you want.
So there are essentially two ways of entry in data into excel,
either directly in the cell,
which will come to short length or in the formula bar,
which is this area right here.
Don't worry too much about what we're going to do with this at the moment.
Just remember that this area is called the Formula Bar.
Okay,
the next area is the worksheet area,
and that's this area highlighted just here.
This is the main area that will be working in an entry.
Now,
data and I have formulas into Andi.
It's made up of lots and lots of little cells,
and we'll cover ourselves now.
So cells Excel is made up of thousands and thousands of cells and cells are these little
rectangles that you can see just here.
Now a seller's referred to by its column letter,
and it's road number.
So if we were to select to sell at random here,
we can see that this cell is at the intersection of column K and wrote six.
And you can see that just here in the name box.
So similarly,
if we were to click over here,
we can see where at the intersection of column Double A and Row 29.
Now,
this is easy enough when Europe here and you can quickly see the intersex.
But if you move,
why over to the screen it becomes more difficult to look down the column and then look over
at the row.
So using the name box up here is a very useful way of finding out exactly which sell your
in Okay s.
So that cover sells next,
we're gonna have a look at the name box.
Okay.
We refer to the name box just a few seconds ago.
Andi,
that's this area right up the corner.
Just here that the name bucks has a couple of functions.
The 1st 1 is to identify which sell your in very quickly and very easily.
It has another really useful function which will come to later in the course.
The next thing we're gonna look at is how we actually move around the worksheet area.
Now we have several options.
To do this.
We can use the arrow keys,
which you'll find on your keyboard and look something like this.
And obviously you can use the up arrow to move up one line to time or the down arrow to
move down one arrow a two time.
Similarly,
you can use the left arrow to move left on the right arrow to move right.
If we want to move around a little more than that over to the far right hand side of the
screen,
you can see a scroll bar that's this area just here.
Now that the scroll bar you can either left click with your mouse on,
drag it down and up,
or you can use the little arrows at the top on the bottom,
the bottom area.
When you click,
it will take you down one row at a time on the upper will take you up.
One wrote a time now,
similarly at the bottom,
right hand side of the screen.
We also have the left and right scroll bar,
which is this scroll bar just here and again.
You can left click and drag left or right to move left,
all right,
or you can use the little arrows on the right hand side.
Moves you over one column at a time on the left hand side.
You could move over one column to the left each time.
Okay,
now Excel.
Workbooks are called work books and just like a normal book,
a book has multiple pages,
and so can an Excel workbook.
Now,
at the moment,
you can see that by default.
Excel when we open.
This file just gave us one and cheat.
In the olden days in Excel 2003 possibly 2007 and 2010 we had three sheets by default,
but at the moment in version 2013 we just get one sheet.
That's this one just down here.
You can see at the moment there is a little plus button at the side.
So if we want to and another sheet toe a workbook,
we simply left.
Click the plus button and we get sheet to on.
We can keep clicking this to get sheet 34 and five on.
That is simply have you add extra sheets to your workbook.
Now,
at the moment,
you may not see the need for multiple sheets,
but it will become clear little later on in the course of three progress.
But for now,
let's just delete those sheets we've added by right clicking choosen delete and we'll right
click Delete right click delete right click delete.
There you go and we're back to where we started.
A very useful thing to know is how to save your work in Excel on.
We're about to cover three different ways of saving your work.
Okay,
at the moment we have a workbook with no data in whatsoever.
So we'll go into the quick access toolbar just up here.
You'll recall we looked at it a little bit earlier on.
We'll click on the save icon.
So when we click this ah,
I come,
this box will pop up now,
At the moment,
it's a save as because we've not previously save this file.
So all we need to do is pick out path.
I'm not going to use one drive.
I'll go to computer,
I'll choose desktop.
And here this.
This meant this dialog box will ask us to pick a new name for our file.
So let's just call it something useful,
though my workbook isn't particularly useful will call it that.
Ignore the other options for a moment.
Just name the file,
something that you can recall hit safe and they go,
our file saved.
That's the first method the next method will use to save our work is using the ribbon that
we spoke about little earlier.
If we move up to the top left,
you can see by default.
The home ribbon is displayed on right next to it.
On the left,
you can see the foil ribbon.
If you left,
click with your mouse button.
You'll come back to this area just here.
What you want to do is scroll down to save left click amega.
Your work has now been saved on the final method for saving.
Our work is to use the keyboard shortcut.
Ctrl control button and s.
You can see if we hover over the save option just of here in the quick access toolbar.
It will cleverly tell us in the tip box that control and s is the keyboard shortcut to save
our work.
Now,
you won't actually see anything happen when I do this.
But when I hit control and s that slight flash of the screen just indicated the Excel
Understood what we said on our work has just being saved.
Next,
we're going to cover hair to save as that is renaming a workbook from one file name to a
different one.
Okay.
Save has as a couple of different functions.
No,
at the moment,
we've just saved this workbook as a workbook called my workbook.
Now,
we It could be that we continue working on this,
but we actually want to keep the original file and keep the new file under a separate file
name.
That way we can always go back to a previous version of a file if we find that something
has gone horrendously wrong.
So now we're going to cover save as now again.
We have a couple of different ways of doing this.
The 1st 1 will use is the file menu.
So come up to the top.
Left hand side,
left click file,
Come down,
choose save us again,
specify your path.
I'm gonna choose computer Desktop and we'll get this little dialog box and we can see there
that we already have my workbook,
the one we've just saved.
But this time,
what we're gonna do is we're going to call this my workbook to which is a very creative
name indeed.
Again,
don't worry about any other options.
For now.
Just change the name of the workbook and save as a different workbook.
Now we still have my workbook,
the original version still intact.
All the days that we entered in there,
even though we didn't enter any data in there is still there.
And it's fully protected and will stay there until you delete it.
But now we have successfully rename the file as my workbook to okay,
The next method will use to save,
as is the keyboard shortcuts.
Because at the moment,
in the current view,
we can't see a save as option.
We can't hover over it and have excel.
Tell us in a tool tip What the keyboard shortcut is.
So at the moment,
I'm just going to let you know that the keyboard short cook for save,
as is F 12 and that's the function key on the top of your keyboard.
So if I hit F 12 just now,
you'll see that we get the same vast dialog box pop up again.
We can just nip in here,
change the name of their worksheet,
ignore the other options from now click Save,
and we've no successfully saved as a new workbook name.
Okay,
the final thing I want to point out to you is you.
You may find that the cells are a little small.
It looks fine at the moment,
cause the data's completely that this spreadsheet is completely clear.
But as we progress and we get lots and lots of data in here,
it could become difficult to read.
So if you look down to the right hand side of your screen,
you'll see a little slide out with a minus button on the left on the plus button on the
right.
Now,
at the moment our view is 100% on.
We can see columns A through a C.
We can see lines.
Want to 39 down the side there.
If we want to zoom in to make the data a little bigger,
weaken just left.
Click on the plus button and you can see tells us zoom in,
and that will make each of the cells a little bit larger.
You won't be able to see as many columns or rows,
but it may make the date or a little easier to see.
Similarly,
you may want to zoom out just to see how big your data is on by left click in this bar,
you'll come out and out,
probably to a point where you can actually read the data anymore.
Alternatively,
you can left click this little bar in the middle and either move to the left to zoom out or
move to the right to zoom in and they go.
That should make it a little easier if you to see.
Okay,
there you have it.
That's the detailed anatomy of a workbook in the next short lecture.
We're just gonna have a couple of minutes just as a quick review.
So if you ever need to come back to it in the future.
Just go to the short version and you'll quickly be able to find all the different areas of
the workbook on what they're called.
See you soon.