righty ho guys,
in this lecture,
we're gonna have a look at the difference between cutting and copying.
And we're also gonna have a look a insert and delete.
If you thoroughly oaf A with this already can probably hit complete lecture,
move onto the next one.
But I know with regards to cutting and copying When I first began using excel,
it took me a while to grasp the difference between the two.
So just so you don't have to go through that pain will just cover it here.
So you have a thorough room to stand them from the beginning.
Okay,
I'm just gonna answer a bunch of data into these cells here,
and I'm going to use our,
uh,
auto fill sequence unjust.
Dragged down with the handle.
OK,
so now we have a column of data one through 10.
Now I'm going to right click anywhere in this highlighted region,
and then they choose cuts.
You can see that we have our dancing and some.
What I'm gonna do is I'm gonna select cell C two.
I'm gonna right click,
and I'm gonna hover over paste.
Now you can see that.
Oh,
menu box.
That was there a few seconds ago has been grayed out on in the background.
Next cell is giving us a clue.
So what it's gonna do so it's gonna paying stare values into columns.
See?
And you can see that column B where data used to live is now completely blank.
So when you hit the button,
you can see that our data is being cut from here on moved over to here and paste it in here
.
So cut essentially cuts the data that you've selected.
Okay,
so that's how cut works.
If we right,
click and choose copy.
When I'm gonna come back over to this Soldiers here,
right,
click and choose Paste.
I'm just gonna do the first option.
And you can see again that our menu has been great out and in the background exiles going
to give us a hint as to what it's going to do.
So you can see this time that all about original data remains with the dancing ounce around
it.
Just there on that.
When we hit the button,
it's going to be copied into this range.
So no,
let me just escape.
So now we have our data twice.
We've copied it from column C on.
We've pasted it into column B.
So the essential difference doing,
cutting and copying is cutting.
Cuts it from your spreadsheet,
that is,
it removes it entirely.
And copying will just delay to pace the same data somewhere else.
So your original data remains okay?
Cutting and copying covered.
Now,
let's have a quick look at inserting.
Now.
What I'm gonna do at the moment is I'm just going to click one of the cells on going to
right click and choose in certain and just drag that up there so you can see it better.
Now,
we have four options in here in the bottom to our entire wrote an entire column.
this is just another way to get to something we've already covered.
You'll recall when we inserted an entire row,
we just left click the road number on we chose insert and all of our arose moved down on
when we chose to insert an entire column.
We just left click the column head in and chose the insert and all their columns moved over
,
So we're not gonna cover them again here.
We're just gonna have a look at 1st 2 options so you can see by default that shift cells
down has been selected because it's got this little black dot in the in the radio button
that notice what happens to values fall through 10 when we click.
OK,
you can see that everything has moved down one cell.
So any data that was down here would also have moved down one cell.
They're just so it's apparent it moved down one cell because we only had one cell selected
.
If we chosen four cells and we chose right click insert on day shift cells down,
you can see that four blank cells were inserted because we had four selected earlier.
So it just it control and said to one day.
So however many cells you have highlighted is how many cells your data will move down.
Okay,
Now,
let's have a quick look at insert,
right?
So again,
I'm just going to slight one cell for now on the right click and insert on this.
So I'm gonna choose right now notice when I click OK,
that the four that we currently have selected will move over to the right just for
clarity's sake.
What's happened is the whole of lime Five from that point has moved over to the right and
side.
So four didn't get deleted and pasted into column day.
Everything here moved over one cell to the right.
Okay?
And we just take control and said to undo And that's how we do insert there to delete.
What we're gonna do is we're going to choose our first column here and we're going to right
,
click on and choose Delete Notice that we only have one cell selected.
So if we chose the default option of shift cells up,
notice what happens to 56789 and 10 when I hit,
OK,
you can see that four has gone.
It's been deleted and all of the cells below it have moved up.
One cell.
No,
again because we only had one cell selected.
They've only moved up one position.
So let's just hit control and sent to undo that on notice that if I selected three sells
right click and chose delete.
Onda had shift cells up that the data billow will move up three cells.
So we've deleted three cells on all of our data below that point has moved up by three
cells.
Okay,
so now we're gonna have a look at delete on.
We're gonna have a look at delete left.
No,
it is here that we have four in the column immediately to the right.
So when I click,
OK,
you can see that the four has moved from there to there hasn't deleted from here on being
pasted there,
the entire range over to the right here as being moved over one column to the left.
Okay,
so hopefully that makes it a little bit clearer than we just hit.
Boom do.
And there you go.
That's the difference between cutting and copying on.
That's Have you used the inserts and delete options right onto the next lecture?