Okay,
guys,
before we get to the next lecture,
we're just going to do a quick one on.
It's going to be a primer on how to build a complex formula or right to simple formulas and
then squash them together.
Okay,
let's crack on.
The simplest way to work out how to build a complex formula is to use what you already have
.
Now this is just a screen cap of the spreadsheet that were already building.
And if we're looking at average sales in Cell L five,
we can see that we have the formula of equals which tells Excel.
It's a Formula I five because it's looking at our total of sales for that line.
And then over one in column m five we wrote our round formula,
which was equals round open brackets.
Then we referenced l five comma one to share that it's toe one decimal place.
Then we closed off our brackets to encapsulate the arguments hit,
enter and they go We were all good so far right now this is what we have.
This is just cooked down view.
Now,
the thing to remember in this formula here on the right is that where we said round L five
l five is just using the value that's been calculated in the cell of l five.
So it's not L five itself.
It's the value that's been calculated in l five.
Do you remember from an earlier lecture that we use the phrase bless my dear Aunt Sally,
which gave us the order of mathematical operations.
So whenever you're in doubt,
when you're building a complex formula,
always bracket off your formulas is not gonna do any harm,
and it just makes them a little easier to read.
So what we're going to do first is we're gonna bracket off their formula in l five.
At the moment it say's equals I five divided by six on.
We're gonna insert a bracket before the I five and after the six.
So it's gonna look something like this,
and you can see down here in the bottom corner that we've now got that formula just that
Now,
remember,
bless my dear Aunt Sally.
So in this video,
we're gonna have a look at the round formula that's in.
Sell em five on.
What we're gonna do to make this a perfect formula is we're going to school.
Gee,
this part over just a little bit.
We're gonna take the l five reference.
We're gonna get rid of it on.
We're gonna take the formula from the other cell on.
We're going to drop it in there.
Okay,
So now we have a perfectly built,
complex formula.
We're no longer reference in the cell.
Were actually calculating the whole thing all in one formula.
And that,
my friends,
is hell.
You build a complex formula.
If you ever endeavor,
Just remember the phrase.
Bless my dear Aunt Sally.
Always do it simply first.
So if you can work out what your formula should do,
but you need to take a couple of steps to do it.
And that's perfectly fine.
And then once you worked and how to do it simply squashed them together.
OK,
so you in the next lecture