Okay,
guys,
Time to look at building our first complex formula.
Now,
at the moment,
we have our average daily sales over here,
which currently displays a 6.8.
But you'll remember that if we increase the decimal places,
it's actual value of 6.8333 on day three,
Rikers forever.
Now,
also,
we've worked out over here.
That's around that number,
actually makes it 6.8 because we've rounded toe one decimal place.
Now let's imagine that we actually want around this toe one decimal place,
that having tohave another column where we perform that calculation.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to turn this into a complex formula utilizing
the formula were already written just of here.
But in certain,
this formula into it.
Okay,
here goes there.
You remember from an earlier lecture.
The phrase bless,
my dear,
aren't Sally,
and you'll also hopefully remember that the that is the order of mathematical operation.
So it's brackets,
multiplication division addition,
subtraction,
because we know that this former already works perfectly well.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna keep that part of the formula,
but just to keep it nice and clean.
I'm going to click in the formula bar.
I'm gonna insert a bracket before the formula.
After the equals,
I'm gonna close it off a the end with close brackets.
So now formula size open brackets equals I five,
which is our total divided by six and close brackets.
It still has exactly the same result.
All we've done is enclosed that formula in brackets.
No,
for the clever part,
what we're gonna do is we're gonna incorporate this formula into this formula.
So we end up with one perfect,
complex formula that gives us the answer that we're looking for.
Okay,
now,
just to make this simple,
what I'm gonna do is I'm just gonna delete the equals on his center.
So,
no,
we can actually see what that formula Saiz.
Now you'll remember that l five was this cell here,
So this formula looked at this result and then rounded to one decimal place.
So we need to do is look at the format of this formula and edit this formula to match so we
can see that the L five value is immediately after the brackets.
So we're going to do here is come before our brackets,
we're gonna type round.
Imagine in that round is the option that we wanted to select on.
We have to open brackets to enclose arguments.
So now we can see that number is selected.
But we've already calculated our number because we bracketed.
It's off already here,
So I'm just going to click at the end of the formula.
I'm gonna hit comma.
I'm gonna go straight to number of digits,
which was one on a tight one,
and I'm gonna close brackets.
So now you can see that what we've done is exactly the same formula.
But rather than referencing cell l five,
we've actually calculated the value of l five by enclosing it in brackets.
So when we hit enter,
we can see that we get an answer of 6.8,
which is exactly what we wanted to do.
And now I'm just going to decrease the which ones decrease.
I'm just going to decrease the decimal places so they go,
No,
we can see that we have 6.8 just to demonstrate that that works.
Let's just increase the brackets and you can see we have many decimal places in this one
here in this one here in this one here.
So I'm just going to copy that formula down and they go,
No,
you can see that they all only go to one decimal place.
So let's let's just reduce that,
which is that one?
So there you go.
And you have just built your first complex formula by using two formulas that you already
had and just copying the answers from one to the other.
Just so that's complete.
When you when you download this file,
I'm just gonna put that one back.
So there you go.
We've no negated the need to have a second formula to calculate the answer that we wanted
to get to.
Okay,
that's how you build complex formulas.
But no,
you know how they work.
OK,
so you in the next lecture