OK,
guys.
Now we're gonna have a quick look at sorting out data.
Now,
at the moment of,
um,
hidden all of our sales days Monday through Saturday on have also inserted a blank line
between celery and total.
Just so Data's nicely sectioned off there.
Okay,
we have three options.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna highlight the entire range that we want to sort,
and we're going to come up to the home ribbon and to sort and fills that just here on when
we left click.
We're just going to choose the first option,
which is sort eight,
or said and that's going to sort all of our data.
But notice what happens in the first column highlighted.
Currently,
we have apples,
which is an A followed by oranges,
which isn't Oh,
and when we click,
source data said,
you can see that it's no gone alphabetical.
All the other data to the right hand side has been sorted with it.
So whatever was against salary and all those different columns is still exactly as it waas
.
We just changed the source order.
Now equally,
we could choose the sort set to a which,
funnily enough puts it in the reverse order.
Now what we're gonna do is we're going to insert another column.
So I'm just going to right click,
choose Insert.
I'm gonna copy all that data down using control and day,
but change the answer of pineapple.
Two coconuts.
So now you can see that we have two entries for coconuts,
one that has let me highlight that one that has average monthly sales of 44 and one that
has average monthly sales of 128.
Right now,
we're gonna have look at the third option in sort again.
I'm in a source,
all of our data.
But this time we're gonna choose custom source.
Okay,
let's imagine we start from a blank.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna add to the level,
and we're going to tell it first,
that we want to sort by column A So we're gonna click Column A.
You have a few choices.
He you consort by cell color font,
color,
cell icon.
Let's just choose values,
which is the default option again.
We're going to stick to eight or said,
but this time we want to rank it According to the monthly sales.
Let me just move that over a little bit.
We want to rank it according to the monthly sales.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna add a level.
So we're just gonna click this button here.
Once on,
we look over and we can see our monthly sales is in Colin K.
So I'm gonna choose column K.
We're gonna leave it of values.
Now,
at the moment,
it's saying smallest to largest,
but what we actually want to do issues largest to smallest.
Now,
before I click.
OK,
let's let me just draw your attention to this little box just up the corner.
Now,
this is if your headers are in your first line of data.
Hours aren't because they're headers,
Aaron,
Line three and we have a blank line.
But if they weren't,
you can just click this box and you can see that now is going to completely ignore the
first line of data.
So just tick that box.
If your head is are your first line of data,
that's just unclip that click,
OK?
And they can see that we've gone alphabetical down here.
Oh,
coconuts of being grouped together on because we said largest through smallest.
Our sales of 144 have appeared above themselves.
So that worked perfectly well.
Okay,
let me just highlight that again.
Choose custom.
Sort on.
Obviously you can.
Ada's many as you like in here so you could sail.
Actually,
I want to sort by then on.
Let me have a look.
I want to sort by Saturday.
So we look at Saturday.
Saturday's column h on We can choose smallest through largest,
and we can rearrange the order.
So if we want sort by a then K,
then h we just highlight H.
And then we hit the little down button and you can see the Leitch has moved to the bottom.
If we then decided we don't actually want K,
we can just click it hit,
delete level,
and there are sorts on A and h r left.
So there you go.
That's how the salt works.
I'm just gonna click council there.
There.
There are two ways to get to this.
The way we just looked at from the home,
Riman.
And you can also come up to the data ribbon left click Data and you have exactly the same
options.
Just here in the sort and filter.
OK,
that's it.
I'll see you in the next lecture.