OK,
guys.
Now we're gonna have a look a rapping text and soft enters the You may not have come across
the term soft enter before,
but it's very simple what it does.
Basically,
whenever you're in their cell in excel and you hit,
enter whatever you've talked in,
the cell is automatically stored to the cell and your cursor will move to the next cell.
But it could be that you want to stick in an extra line of data in there,
just like when you tell him a letter room word.
The way to do that is through a soft return.
Okay,
at the moment I'm gonna do is I'm just gonna hide these last three columns.
Just so when you download the file there Still,
they just unheard them by left clicking l on dragging over to pay,
choose right click on a new height.
But for now,
I'm just gonna hide them.
I'm also going to copy over these two formulas here by hitting control and are okay.
Let's have a look at wrapping text.
First,
we can see that closing stock makes a cell a little too wide for the two digit data that we
have stored underneath.
So what we're gonna do is left click the soul to select it.
We're gonna hit right click and choose format cells.
It's just dragged round up to that.
Now,
if your alignment tab isn't selected,
just click.
The alignments have,
and you can see them here that we have the option to wrap text.
Just go ahead and click that little tick box there.
Click OK.
And you can now see that if I squeeze that column a little narrower that the Texas
automatically wrapped so it no occupies two lines we can see in the formula bar that the
Texas exactly as it was.
We still have the word closing space and stock immediately after it.
But when we get the enter,
we can see that it's now allows us to narrow the columns.
Okay,
that's how you do a wrap text.
Then the other way to do it is to use a soft return,
and you can do this while you're actually entering the data.
So there are two ways to do it.
We can either edit directly in the cell or edit in the formula bar.
I'm going to show you the formula bar first,
So I'm just going to click before the D on a hit backspace.
So I have no space.
Then I'm gonna hit old and enter.
No,
don't worry.
If you can't see what's happening in the formula bar,
I'm just going to drag it down.
So if I just hover the bottom of the formula,
Bartle,
the curse of changes left,
click on,
drank down.
We can see that we've made the formula bar a little larger.
But now I'm gonna click before sales hit backspace his old and enter.
And now you can see in the formula bar that what we actually have is average a new line
daily.
A new line sales No.
When a center,
you can see that.
That's actually now move the data into three separate ones within the same cell.
And just to resize,
I'm just gonna hover between till the curse of changes.
Double click on Diego.
Never that looks much more appropriate for the width of the data that we have.
The second way to do it is to edit it directly in the cell.
So I'm gonna do monthly sales this time when they hit F two to lowers 20.
The data.
I'm just gonna move my cursor in there.
Hit the backspace.
Hold bolt press enter.
And no,
You can see that monthly sales has become two separate lines,
which is reflected in the formula bar just up here.
Okay.
No one in the center resource column automatically.
Like clicking between K and L.
And they go l columns air more appropriate wits based on the data that sits underneath.
Um,
the only thing missing now is that we have this text lying on the bottom.
Andi,
this text of here moving open,
open up.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm just gonna highlight all of those I'm going to,
right.
Click choose format.
Andi,
I am going to say in the vertical plane center,
and it's OK.
And there you go.
That looks a little bit cleaner.
Okay.
See you in the next lecture.