OK,
guys.
Now we're gonna have a look at how to create a simple chart from the data that we've
already created.
Now,
I'm not gonna highlight Absolutely everything here woman do is I'm gonna left click item,
hold my left.
Most button down.
I'm gonna come all the way over and just highlight our sales up to Saturday.
No,
I'm gonna go up to the insert option Just here.
Left click on this will bring.
Got our insert ribbon.
Now we can see that we have the option in the charts section just here to choose
recommended charts.
So let's just left.
Click that for a second on.
Let's have a look what it's going to give us,
OK,
we could have this particular one more I'm gonna choose Here is this one,
And this is going to give us a stacked chart so we can see all of our sales for each day.
And we can also see the breakdown of what?
Each of the fruits and vegetables Where now,
if we just click okay for a second,
you can see that our chance being created now I'm just gonna drink that out so you can see
the little better,
but you'll notice that what we have is this huge blue area just here.
If we look down to the key at the bottom,
we can see that this is the opening stock.
Now,
if we were to look at that chart immediately,
we could see that Apple's it looks like we've sold somewhere near 120 both groups.
I didn't mean to do that when we just didn't it.
If I move that chance head the way and we look at our total sales of Apple's,
it's actually only 41 now.
The reason for that is we've included the opening stock because the opening stock is our
second column of data after our item titles.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to select a non contiguous set of data.
Okay,
I'm just gonna delete that chart for just one second,
and we're going to do it.
But this time we're gonna miss out this column completely there.
So far,
we've looked at how you highlight a range by left clicking,
but we haven't yet looked at how you highlight two separate ranges.
So we're just gonna do that now I'm gonna left click item tracked down with my mouse button
clicked Let go!
And now I'm gonna hit the control button on the keyboard and hold it down.
And now I'm gonna left click Monday and dragged through to Saturday So they go,
You can see that with no highlighted two separate ranges of data on We've missed out our
opening stock So let's go back up to insert.
Have a look at the recommended charts.
Let's just left click.
This is the one we selected before and there we can see ourselves for each of our items.
So let's just click,
OK,
they go on,
let me just make that little bit bigger by dragging out.
Okay,
so now we can see instantly that apples are Monday the blue.
We sold seven by hovering over it.
It will tell you what the actual value is.
On Tuesday we sold 10 and so when the so full so we can spot instantly,
our biggest seller is lettuce.
So we can see by just looking at this chart which are our best sellers,
in which are porous sellers.
If we look over here,
we can see that oranges and pineapples don't sell particularly well,
but lettuces were pushing nearly 50 a week on that.
This is so lettuce is our best seller.
So it's just a quick graphical representation of one.
Our sales data actually tells us because we created a new child in the other worksheet.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna copy this chart,
take it from this sheet and stick it in our chart.
Eso Let's just left click cut left,
click our chart And let's just go ahead and paste it right in there.
So they go No,
we can see the chart data.
Let's just make a little bigger Occupies our entire screen.
We may want to change the chart title,
so we're just gonna left click,
highlight the date and say,
uh,
sales chart,
call it ever sales chart,
click off.
So they go.
We now have a nice simple chart based on the data they have already created account just
going to go back to sheet one.
Just click off and they get That's how you create a simple chart.
So you in the next lecture