okay and go is what we're going to do now is have a look out to format the cells with
borders.
Now,
what I've done just now is I've copied the formula from here.
Our total have copied it over two column B and have also extended over to J.
K and L.
So we have totals for all of our different data sets to change the border on a cell.
All you're gonna do is left.
Click the cell and we're gonna use the home ribbon on.
We're going to use the front section of the home ribbon on.
We're going to look at something we haven't looked at before.
We skipped over it in an earlier lecture on that is the border option.
That's this one just here.
They concede we hover over it,
that by default we get the bottom border selected.
So just so you can see what that does,
I'm just gonna left,
click it and move out of that cell and you can see now that we have a line across the
bottom of that particular cell.
So that's a bottom border.
So I'm just going to re select the cell.
But this time I'm gonna choose the little down arrow by left clicking,
and we can see here that we have a bottom order top,
border left,
borders,
right?
Borders,
no borders,
thick borders,
all sorts of it from borders.
But what we're actually gonna do is we're gonna create our custom border.
So we're going to choose the option at the bottom,
which is more borders by left.
Clicking in this little box will pop up here.
Now you can change the color of the borders by just clicking the collapse down here.
We're gonna leave it automatic so it becomes black.
You can see because we had a bottom board run,
But it's actually there now,
so I'm just going to click to remove its Allegan.
Now what?
We have no borders in their cell,
and we're going to create one from scratch.
They're here,
the different styles that we can choose on because accountants like double lines over the
top of totals.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna select the double line by left clicking it.
We're just going to go to the top,
which is exactly where we want it,
and click there.
And now you can see that we have a double line over the top of our cell.
So when I click,
OK and just move out the way you can see that we now have a double over line across the top
of their first total.
So all I'm gonna do is left.
Click that cell,
copy the format in left,
click and drag along the way over an agency that we have the double overline across all of
their totals.
And just to make it a little tired,
I'm just gonna left click Insert a blank line between total Andi after inch.
I mean,
move down,
they go.
So that's how you change your borders.
See you in the next lecture.