OK,
guys.
Now we're gonna have a look at how to set up a worksheet to print.
Then we have three ways to get to the print interface.
They're all the same methods.
Once we get in there,
it's just the different ways to get into the interface itself.
So the first thing we're gonna do is we're gonna look at the ribbon and we're gonna choose
the file section,
which is right up here on the left hand side.
So it's gonna left click file on this window will appear on.
We can see from the options down the left hand side that we have the option to print just
down here.
So I'm just gonna left click,
and that's going to open this window there.
We can see in the main window.
We have a print preview.
This is what the print will look at if we were to hit the print,
but immediately.
But if we look down the bottom there,
we can see that the print will actually go over onto two pages.
What we can see there is the first page,
and if we click the little arrow to the right,
we can see that that will be the second page if he wants all of out dated to appear on one
page,
we have two ways of doing this.
The first way would be to look at the scaling option,
which is down the bottom just here now.
Currently,
you can see that we have no scaling selected.
Well,
we're going to do is click the little down arrow and we can see that we have the option to
fit sheet on one page.
So if we left click that we can no see that our table will print out on one sheet now
because this is set up to print in portrayed,
you might find that this is a little difficult to read.
So let's just go ahead and them do that for a second and choose no scale in on this time
caught two portrait orientation.
So I'm just gonna left click there and switch it to a landscape by left clicking on there.
We can see that that's much easier to read,
but we still have it over two pages without last column just tripping over onto the second
page.
So let's just come back again and again.
We're going to choose the scaling option.
We're gonna pick fit Cheeto.
One page on they go.
That looks much better.
Will bounce here entire data at all on one page,
nice and easy to read.
And then when we're ready to print,
we just make sure we have the right princess selected.
Currently I have one nose.
I think it picks that by default.
So just hit the little down arrow,
pick your printer on,
hit the print button and there you go.
That's how you do you print.
And it's a simple Is that the second way to get to that interfaces to hit the keyboard
shortcuts Control on DPI on that will bring you straight back here again.
And they're just finally the third way Just hit the little back arrow is to use this new
button that we've added to our quick access toolbar.
So we can see then that we have the print preview and print button just left.
Click that and that will bring you straight back here.
Now that could be that You want to print the second tab on their work sheikhs as well.
Now that the moment you can see in the settings that we have prints only the active sheets
.
So foods the left,
click this button just here and click print entire workbook.
We can see that this pages remained exactly the same,
but we now have page one of three.
So if we click next page,
we can see that we have a chart and we click on the next page.
We can see that our chart trips over onto the page after that,
too.
So let's just go go back here again,
change it to let escape orientation on they go,
and then we can see that it will print out onto two pages without a data table on the first
page on their charts on the second page.
So when you're happy that you've got it all set up just right,
hit the print button on.
There you go.
That's how you print Easy is that I'll see you in the next lecture