OK,
guys.
Now we're gonna have a look at what I think is one of the most useful features in Excel.
Now,
at the moment,
we can see all of our data because their data set is comparatively small.
Bruce,
we have a massive set a day to say 100 lines or 1000 lines or 10,000 lines.
A filter will come into its own.
Now it's done easy to apply fills that.
What we're gonna do is apply it at line four.
So it appears here between their title on our data set so long,
then do is left click line for come over to this area just like the corn.
And then we've already used a sort function before.
And we've looked at the 1st 3 options that we're gonna pick the fourth option,
which is filter.
Now,
when I click off,
you'll notice that we have these little boxes that appeared on the sides of each of
ourselves.
And these are our filters.
Now we're gonna do is I'm just going to click on it with the left most button,
and you can see that all of their data has shown down here.
So all of their fruits and vegetables have appeared.
They're One thing to note is that we know that we have two entries for coconuts,
but coconuts only appears once in the list.
Now that's because it filters out any duplicates.
So if I were to just want to see coconuts,
I can just left Click the select all,
which then blanks all of our data on re select Coconuts by Left Click in,
which takes it.
Click OK and they go.
You can see that all of our other sales have been hidden away,
and we're only showing our coconuts.
That sounds wrong.
Okay,
so let me just click that re select all.
And obviously you can pick any combination.
These So if we wanted to show everything except bananas on cucumbers,
just click bananas on click cucumbers.
Click OK on a go,
we can see all of their data.
Except for those two items,
you can have multiple filters applied,
so at the moment we have a filter over in column A there.
We may also want to filter out column D Tuesday,
we may say,
actually,
we just want to say anything that we sold 10 off,
so let's just select everything click 10.
So,
no,
we can see that those particular items have been filtered out on.
We're only showing items that we sold 10 off on Tuesday.
Now,
a very quick way to find out if you have any filters applied is to look at the road numbers
.
Now you'll notice that most of the Rhone,
um,
has just appear in normal black funds.
But where we have a filter applied,
you'll notice that the row numbers have gone blue.
Now that tells you instantly that you have a filter applied,
netted to find out which columns you have filters on.
If you have a look at the Icahn,
you'll know sis that the ones with filters applied have the little filter picture within
the ICOM itself.
There's a very quick way of removing all the filters that you have applied,
and that's to come back over to the sort and filter option just up here and hit the clear
option.
So when I hit clear,
you can see that all of their filters have been removed.
But we still have the option to filter on here because,
although likens air around now,
if we're talking about numbers,
it may be useful to find out what your top sellers are on locally.
We can also do that within the filter.
So I'm just going to click Friday.
You can see that our sales are either 012356 or seven Never going to this option just here
.
We can see that we have a bunch of other different options so surprisingly,
if you left clicked equals you would get the equal.
So you could say equals 10th and they go.
We have nothing with 10 sales on that particular day.
So let's click.
All we could say does not equal one.
Funnily enough,
that will display anything that does not equal whatever value we have on.
We also have our top 10.
No,
let's just say we want to see our top two items.
Let's just scroll then.
So we get to top to hit OK and they go our top two sellers on a Friday.
We're bananas and cucumbers because we sold seven of each of those items.
If we just select all again at up to settlers,
did have seven items sold.
Okay,
we can also let's just asset,
select all you could also look for any cells that above the average for that column.
So just left click above average on all of these sales for these items were above the
average for that day,
and equally if we wanted to have a look and everything that was below average,
we can just click below average.
And these are all the items below the average sales for that day that we can also create
our own custom fills that by choosing this option just here.
So if we click custom Filter,
what we could say is we actually want it to be greater than on Let's say to Onda,
We also want it to be less than six.
Let's say so here.
The thing to note is that we want Andi.
So this is going to show everything that is greater than two on and is less than six.
Okay,
so they go.
We can no see that Fire 553 on two.
Indeed,
Fit that criteria.
Okay,
clear fields from column G.
On they go.
You can have any combination,
as I say,
so you can fill trade anything that begins with Let's have a look.
A text filters create a custom filter.
We can say anything that begins with C on click.
Ok,
And then we can only see our items that have see in it We could say anything that's custom
fills there ends with on s so anything that ends with s so they go We can see Apple's been
honest Coconut,
cucumbers,
oranges,
plums and tomatoes All end with s And anything that didn't end with this has been filtered
out from our view.
Okay,
let's just go ahead on clear all of those filters and they go have a play around the
filters.
You'll find it's very,
very useful,
particularly when you're dealing with large data sets on.
I'll see you in the next lecture.