Okay,
guys,
welcome to part one of the bonus section.
And in this lecture,
we're gonna have a look at how you was around Excel like a ninja.
No.
One of the first things that we looked at was the ribbon,
which is this area at the top of the screen just here.
And you'll recall from earlier in the course to navigate between the different sections of
the ribbon.
We just hovered over each of the names and we would left click to get to insert would move
over with our mouths with left click to get to page layouts.
The same with formula.
Same with day to same with review.
But there's an even faster way of doing this.
If you're looking of toe,
have one of those,
most with scroll wheel.
Just hover your mouse cursor anywhere within the ribbon on with your scroll wheel just
rolled down,
and you'll find that your move over one ribbon to the right,
and if you keep rolling,
you can keep rolling and you'll get all the way over to the right.
So I'm just moving one click with the wheel each time to move over one ribbon to the right
.
If you roll upwards,
you'll move over one to the left.
If you want to move over multiple,
just give it a quick roll and you can scroll through all of the different ribbons.
That's one very quick way of navigating the ribbons.
If you couldn't be bothered with the point and click method,
Okay,
so there's your first tip.
Use your most wheel to scroll through the ribbons.
Superfast.
Okay,
the next thing we're gonna look at is how you navigate your way around this data table.
Now we know that we can instantly click on each cell by just left,
clicking it and getting around.
But let's imagine we want to get from here all the way over to here.
What we could do is just left click.
But you need fairly good marriage control to instantly do that,
which I'm sure you have.
But there are quicker ways you can hit the control button and hit your right arrow to
immediately go to the end of your data set.
You can also it the control arrow and hit the left to come right the way over to your left
.
Most column.
You can hold down the control and hit the up arrow to go to the top of your data set.
Or you can hit the control on the down arrow to go to the bottom of your data set.
That's a very quick way to immediately get to the far right,
the far left the top or the bottom of a particular day to set.
Now there's another way of doing this that I've only just learned about.
If you look closely,
you'll see that this sow has a green line around it now to move immediately to the top.
If you just hover on the top section of that bar,
you can see that the curse has changed.
Just double click with the left mouse button and you immediately go to the top.
And similarly,
if you just hover over the bottom line until the curse of changes,
double click.
You can see that your cursor immediately dashes down to the bottom of your data table.
Similarly,
if you click on the right hand side,
double click it was is over to the far right,
and if you have her on the left downside till the curse changes,
double click and you immediately zap over to the far left column.
Okay,
if you're anywhere in your data set and you want to get back to your home,
sell your home.
Sell is the top left hand corner of your data.
Just hit control and home on your keyboard on that will immediately wish you back up to
your home.
Sell.
Okay,
so that's how you move around the spreadsheet very,
very quickly.
Okay.
If we've got a large data set,
we may want to move down more than one wrote a time,
which is what we do when we hit the down arrow.
But and But sometimes you may want to move down an entire page at the time,
and that's really quick to do.
All you do is hit the page down button on your keyboard to move down a complete page at a
time.
So if I paid job,
I can go back up and see that we have visibility of lions five through 20 hit page down,
and now I can see lying 20.
So I can still see the bottom line of the data that was previously visible,
but no down to 35 so on and so forth is eight page down or page up.
Very useful if you have big data sets.
Okay,
so that's how we was around the table within this sheet.
But what if you wanted a quick way to flip between the different chiefs that we have Now we
know that we already have two sheets on this one.
We have sheet one on.
We have our charts on again looking like this.
A keyboard shortcut.
For that.
You just hold in your control button and hit page down.
So for every time you hold control and hit page down,
you'll move over one sheet to the right and similarly to move back.
Just hit control and page up and your turn the page back one.
So page up moves you to the left page down,
moves you to the right.
Just remember to hold down your control button.
So they go move to that page on,
Moved back to that page.
Okay.
Now,
if we wanted to highlight our entire range of data,
which is all of this here now?
Ex old defines a range of data.
If it's bordered by empty cells on,
we can see that we have empty cells all the way around this data set so we could left click
here,
dragged down to here,
and that's highlighted.
But there is a keyboard shortcut to instantly do that,
and that is control in a.
So if I hold them control and it's a you can see that that entire range has been
highlighted.
Now the easy way to remember control and a is that all begins with a so control and a
highlights all.
If you want to highlight the entire sheet,
you can hold down control and hit again,
and then the the selection will expand to cover the whole of the sheet.
Okay,
so it's just choose another self so control and a highlights all of your table control a
again highlights all of your sheet.
Just one more thing that I want to bring to your attention in this lecture,
and you'll remember when we used the format paint and that we copied the format in here.
We hit format painter on.
Then we copied the format in there.
But if you double click the format painter,
it retains the four matter that you've just copied until you hit the escape key.
So just to show you that I'm just going to randomly pick one of these cells which one sees
formatted differently to all of these.
I'm gonna double click the former painter,
and then I'm going to click there.
You see,
the formatting is being applied,
and you can see by the curse of the formatting is still being retained.
So I could click There,
There,
there,
Anywhere I wanted to.
So if you have a bunch of data that you need to format in the same way,
but they're all over the place,
just double quick format pains that and it'll retain that format in until you click escape
.
Okay,
let me just undo all of that.
Hits escape on.
There you go.
That completes the first lecture in the next lecture.
We're gonna have a look at all the different keyboard shortcuts for cutting,
copying and all that kind of stuff.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.