Okay,
guys,
Welcome back.
No.
In the next four lectures,
we're gonna have a look at all the variations of absolute and relative cell reference in No
,
I'm no.
At the moment,
that probably doesn't mean much to you,
but it will become clear as you work through these four short lectures.
So I've created this Excel file which you can download,
and you can see that we have four tubs.
We have a one which in technical terms is relative.
A relative one.
We have dollar sign,
a dollar sign,
one which would be read as an absolute,
a absolute one.
We have dollar sign a one which is absolute.
A relative one and a dollar sign.
One which is a relative A and an absolute one.
No,
don't worry.
If you don't understand what that means,
just that the moment the easiest way to understand this is watching in action.
And then it will become really clear.
Okay,
so let's begin with relative a relative one or otherwise just referred to as a one.
So island do is write a simple formula to multiply this figure by this figure,
and you can see when we hit F two that the Blue sell a three is being multiplied by the red
cell B three on hit.
Enter.
If I copy that formula down by using that short cut,
just double click in the drag handle on,
we come down to here and hit F two.
Now you can see that the cell references the A's and the B's have moved relative to the
formula that we've just copied down.
So we copied it down one cell on the cell references of both moved relatively down one cell
to.
So before we had a three B three and then we hit enter,
and now they have moved in relatively.
So we have a four b four,
and then as we move down,
we can see that as we've dragged the formula,
each of the soul references has moved down relative to where the formula lies.
So that's a relative relative cell reference in the legs,
like you're gonna have a look at absolute cell reference.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.