Okay,
guys,
welcome back.
Never gonna have look at an absolute and relative cell reference.
That is one such as dollar A on day one.
So what I've done is I've got a couple of columns of numbers in here morning and do is
write a simple formula that says equals this multiplied by this.
But this time I'm going to do is his F four once,
and that gives us the absolute a absolute one.
I'm gonna hit it again,
and then we get a absolute one,
and I'm gonna hit it 1/3 time.
So this is F or three times,
and now we get absolute a one on What that's going to do is look all of our formulas when
we dragged them around.
Two column A not necessarily lying one,
but it's gonna lock two column A.
So let's just copy that down and we can see how that works.
So here,
when we hit,
have to we can see that we are multi playing,
be one which is relative relative to absolute,
a one on move down.
And it's doing exactly the same.
That pretty much looks like it did before,
but now you'll see when we copy that formula across that if we click in one of these at
random,
we're in some seriously big numbers over here.
What we have when we hit F to is that this cell has always stuck to column a so di three as
moved over as we've moved the formula.
But the second pass of the formula has been locked.
Two COLUMN A.
It will happily move down based on the line number so we can see here that we have absolute
a seven,
but it's always locked.
Two COLUMN A So they go.
If you type a dollar sign or hit F 43 times,
you will lock the column,
but not the rose.
So you now have an absolute column reference on a relative row reference.
So they go.
That's what you do an absolute relative on.
You can probably guess what's coming in the next lecture,
but watch it through anyway and will cover the relative a absolute one.
I'll see you in the next lecture