OK,
guys.
Now we're gonna have a look at an absolute cell reference.
So I have a column of numbers down here I'm gonna do in Cell.
A one is just type three.
Let's just type three.
So I'm gonna write a similar formula wrong and say,
Is this cell multiplied by this cell?
But when I'm selecting cell A one,
what I'm gonna do is push f four on the keyboard and you can see in the formula bar that we
now have.
The formula equals a three multiplied by dollar sign a dollar sign one.
So that's absolute a absolute one.
And I'm gonna hit enter,
and there's our formula.
Now I'm gonna copy it down just as we did before,
using the drag handle and double clicking.
But this time,
notice what's happened as I moved down here.
When they hit F two,
you can see that the a reference has moved down in line with our copy in the formula Dem.
So instead of calculating on a three is now looking at a four.
But the other cell,
the absolute a absolute one,
has bean anchored up the corner to always be a and one and then if I come down,
Teoh here and his have to again.
You can see that the first cell a 10 has moved down relative to where the formula is but a
game because we put the dollar sign a dollar sign,
one that is,
we absolute cell referenced it.
It's always going to multiply by a one because those dollar signs Luckett in his column.
I unluckily INS column one.
So if we if we were to copy that formula across what would happen,
let's just copy it over there on Copy it down.
Oops,
tracking that down.
So even when we come over here and hit F two,
you can see that this sellers moved relative to its position where the formula lives but
still absolute.
A absolute one is always the second operator.
So by putting a dollar sign or hitting,
F four once puts a dollar sign in front of the column letter on the road number on.
Wherever you move your formula that particular cell reference will absolutely never move.
It becomes an absolute cell reference.
So they go.
That's an absolute cell reference.
In the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at an absolute and relative cell reference with absolute a one.
I'll see you in the next lecture