Hi,
David.
Hopefully the audio on this comes out.
Clearly.
I'll be able to come to adjust it so you can read it.
I've got your file.
It's it's It's all pretty much straightforward stuff.
There's just an awful lot of straightforward stuff in there.
So if I started the top,
we've got there just emerged incented cell,
which looks like it's going from a over to end.
Probably put that over 20 actually,
at the end.
But for now,
we'll just replicate exactly what you've got.
So I'm just highlight in a through to I m going to hit emergence center on.
I'm gonna put the texting E T p.
Whatever.
Excess attendance.
Forgive any typing errors that Aaron this s so I'm just going to click that I'm gonna make
it bold hitting the bold,
but in there.
And I'm just going to increase the font size by hitting the little plus button.
So you've got attendant stretched attendance roster actually saves,
doesn't it?
Underneath that looks like we have merged from a through two K,
another merged incented cell.
So I'm just gonna emerging center that this one says training site lips training site.
Okay,
so far so good.
After the train insights,
we have another two merged incented cell.
So we have this one here merged incented,
and this one saves roster.
Eso we have roster and I'm gonna make that bold on we have an outline.
He s so I'm just going to choose outline outside Borders,
which is gonna just gonna call around the outside there.
And I think we have a background of yellow,
uh,
more colors.
It's probably that kind of color.
Okay on then we have just this one that's being merged incented on that has an outline
around it too.
So they go.
That's almost what the first couple of lines look like.
The next line's been scrooge it up a little bit,
so it reduces in size and then we've got down the side.
We have number of trainees,
then that goes from line unnecessary.
We have contractor type.
Next,
don't make so we have a contract or turn that right.
Ignoring spelling mistakes that are made during this contract to name on,
then in line here.
Whatever that sees on this one's merged incented over to E s.
So I'm just gonna merge in center on,
then it looks like it's left aligned,
but you probably have a few spaces in here to make it look like it nudges in a little bit.
The next one we have is I think we have ah,
Line five has been Scrooge it up a little bit to make it look a little contractor Names
also got a background of yellow,
so just selected that choose the color on Choose that outline Borders option again.
And I think the text is bold,
so it's a little cumbersome,
but luckily you only have to do it once.
Then we have emerged and sent itself from a six down to a 12.
So I'm just gonna highlight a six.
Enter a 12 hit merge in center on.
There's a trick in this one.
So what we have is hashtag dot I think train this on.
What we need to do is a line that differently.
So I've just selected that sell at the moment.
The text is going from left to right.
What we wanted to do is go from bottom to top.
So I've just hit that there and you can see this little option here Orientation.
If you just click on that,
you can see that you can flip it.
So format sell.
Let's go to format cell alignment on.
Then we're just gonna drank this little red dot here all the way up until it goes upwards.
So it's 90 degrees and then we'll have number of a number of trainees.
It say's groups.
Number of train,
EES.
I think that's what it says on the game.
We can weaken send to that in that cell by using the the center in the middle alignments,
and that is also in yellow and it is also boarded.
So now we have that one in there.
Now,
the next thing we have is this E t p thing,
which looks like it's done over two E and down this father's line 10 eso I've just
highlighted that I'm gonna hit merge in center.
It is colored in yellow on it has a border around it.
Now,
here's the trick.
Okay,
so we're gonna type,
uh,
inside the right thing in here.
So we have our first line of text now if you hit old and enter at the same time,
you can see in the formula bar that it's actually given you a new line of text type into so
in he content my second blind off data and then it bold and enter on.
That will give you another one.
And so you can put my the line on adult and intact and you can get new lines like that seem
,
type something else ultimate enter something else hit ends at,
and then it will all line up.
So I'm just going to re select that just the line is over to the left.
And if you want to change the front formatting on any of these,
just scroll opinion into your formula bar.
Highlight the text.
So my first line of text on my line of text will be bold.
And then when they hit enter,
you can see that that 1st 1 has appeared is bold.
So if you want to just highlight some of the text in this,
just select the text in the formula bar and we could say,
Make that larger,
and then we can scroll down a little bit and say,
My third line.
We'd like it to be read on bond bold and italics and just scroll down through here if you
If you got a mouse with a scroll button.
You can just use that.
If not just clicking and usually arrow keys on.
Then you can just select by highlight in any bit of the cell that you want to highlight.
So we could say,
Well,
make that blue Andi increase of font size and make it bold.
And then when you finish their continue text in the formula bar hit,
enter,
and then your text will look exactly as it needs to.
Okay.
Next.
We have,
um,
some merge in centering over here all the way over column.
Oh,
so emergence center.
Make it yellow.
Make it outline bordered on.
We have training dates,
and then it looks like underneath we've just got at bordered cells for each of those.
So I'm just gonna highlight all of those on this time.
I'm gonna choose all borders.
So there we get those lines and they're just like we did before on to speed it up.
I'm just gonna copy that Serve highlighted from here down to here.
Hit control and see Come underneath Control.
Envy.
That gives us our start and ending times and and on day I'm going to copy that against we
have another one for heroism in its own copy.
And that left click drag down.
Copy Andi paste that in there.
And here we have hours on end lips.
Now it looks like Road 12 is just being made taller.
So I'm just gonna drag it down to where Line 13 would be by left clicking.
And then I'm gonna merge in center this emergence center,
make it yellow.
Make it outlined on it.
Say's trainee in the Schoen's colon.
There to get to the new line holding old press.
Enter Andi more text in here on whatever that needs to say.
And the next thing we have is another merged in sentence self,
which is here.
So I'm just going to highlight the to emerge in center,
make it yellow and use that outside border again cause I don't want a line through the
middle.
And here we have a job both and Andi,
what do we have?
Jump no dot Enter Andi.
That one needs to be centered.
So we're gonna choose this option here.
Rips this option here on this option here to put it in the middle.
And I think we also have it bold and underlined.
So there we have job number.
We have training name across here,
which is another merged in sentence emergence center,
yellow and again,
I'm going to choose the outside borders.
And I'm just gonna line this up in the middle.
So chosen this option and this option.
And in here we type training,
name,
trainee,
name Andi.
I think that's bold and underlined.
Bold underlined.
Now,
this cell is a little bit wider,
so I'm just gonna widen that out a little bit on DWI and have And do we have another
merchant sentence cell that I think we do?
So I'm just gonna highlight here and here.
Hit merging center,
Make it yellow on doing outside Border on.
I'm gonna put trainee signature colon bolt and enter and whatever the texts who's in here?
Okay.
And then you can you can talk whatever needs to go in now,
trainee.
Sick.
Well,
this entire box looks like it's centered,
which is good,
but its top aligned.
So I'm just going to come over here to topple line left click,
and it will go to top on trainee.
Signature is underlined.
So I'm just gonna highlight Trainee signature in the formula bar.
And I'm gonna hit the little underlying Lemina here.
Tender.
You can see that.
That's no Got training.
Signature underlined.
Could be boulders.
Well,
now,
if I look over at these end columns over here,
there are a little bit narrower.
So I'm just going to click on your original document,
which I've got open here just a second.
So just going to click on here,
right?
Click and choose column wits.
And we can see that the common with this 5.14 So I'm just gonna copy that Hit counts on
dragging out the way,
and I'm gonna change.
The column went from all of these by highlighting f through toe.
Right click.
Choose column.
It's on tight that over the top.
So it's 5.14 Okay,
so that should be starting to look like the original documents.
It looks like we have a bunch of numbers down this side there that go from one through 20.
So I'm just gonna hit one on too.
Andi,
I'm just going to drank that down using the fill handle until we get to 20.
Keep going,
uh,
Okay.
And it looks like they've been central lined.
So I'm just gonna choose this option here.
So they go somewhere.
We have number of trainees,
sub liquor that looks compared to the original.
So far,
so good.
Andi job number always appears to say one.
So I'm just going tight one in the 1st 1 and just double click there,
and it will fill one all the way down.
And we also want that centered by the looks of it.
So I'm just gonna hit center now.
All of this area here.
Trainee name is merged.
Incented.
So most incented on C 13 and d thirties or just highlighted there on,
I think if I just dragged down and hit control and day and I didn't do it just a second.
So I'm highlighting their I'm his emergence centre,
and I'm highlighting here underneath emergence center.
And now I'm just gonna copy that one down on holding shift.
So selected this cell.
I'm holding shift.
I'm going all the way down to the bottom,
and then I'm gonna hit control in D to fill down.
And that should give us merge.
Sells all the way down.
Perfect.
Okay,
this isn't merged on the rest of this looks like it said just but wind.
So I'm just gonna highlights all of this area.
Let me come down to the bottom on.
I'm going to go into here.
I'm gonna choose all borders because we want the lines to appear in these little lines,
coming down as well.
So all borders.
So now it's starting to look something like the original.
Let's just narrow this column appellate or here between A and B on narrow.
This column up here between being see Andi that let's have a look on the limit.
Just regular original into shots.
So this column here c and D.
If I highlight the to and hit column,
Wittes says,
15.43 I don't know if that's the two of them,
so let's just try it column.
It's 15.43 was it?
Let's bring the original backend.
Okay,
that's starting to look something like the original document.
Let's just check the width of AEA's well by right clicking it and choosing column.
It's and that want to say is 32.43 Let's copy that using control and see and do the same
for this one column.
It's 32.43 Enter.
Okay,
so that should Where's your original document going?
Hang on a minute.
Way Go.
Okay,
so that's starting to look.
so we're good for all of this bit.
Then we Let's just zoom in a little bit.
It looks like we've got a motion sentence cell across here as well.
At the bottom,
eso will just come down to the bottom.
Hit merged incented.
So dragging from a 33 all the way across Emergence center said,
Look at the original.
Um,
it looks like some spaces in there,
so it will say note one.
Whatever the notice in their Andi,
it's being left aligned,
but it looks like they've just entered a few spaces before the word notes to make it no gin
.
A little bit Onda.
We have no to so highlight the cell that we've just done the no motion centered hold down
shift Come down hit control and D and that will copy that down.
Um and that will now say note to on whatever note to will say that he is texting here.
Okay,
So far,
so good a game.
It looks like down the bottom we have something has been merged and centered across A and B
.
So we'll emergency and 2 a.m. b on what does it say?
It say's date.
So we have date.
Andi,
I'm just going to re select the cell and it looks like we now have a different color.
So we now have a blue kind of color.
This probably won't be spot on the date on.
Then we want the outside border again because we don't want to call her that,
Lyle.
And down the middle today we have date.
We now have trainer name,
which is in column c train name Andi.
That looks like it's bean.
Some look that's been centered and it's got the same for matters.
These cells.
So we're just gonna hit center,
make it blue and color the outlines.
Okay,
Training name.
I think these are actually in bold as well trained Signature.
I'm just going to copy that.
So I'm just going to select control and are and just change the word two signature picture
train a signature course titles again.
I'm just going to select the cell to the side and hit control and are because these air
single cells.
That's so that that and that are single cells,
so you can just copy it and paste it in here we have course titles,
lips stifles,
and that looks like it's being centered.
Right now we have another merged incentive,
but let me just drag leading.
Okay,
so now we have emerged Incentive cell that's running from F over 20 for the next one.
So I'm just gonna drag from F over 20 on hit Emergence center.
Andi then whatever text that say's what Ever Text Gu's in here.
Uh,
and that also needs to be blue in background on having outside border.
I think this entire lines actually bold.
So I'm just gonna highlight line 35 by left clicking it hit in the bowl.
But eso let's just find your original documents again on Zoom out.
I have to do that so you can actually see it'll scroll down a bit on them.
It looks like we just got some most incentive cells again underneath here.
So I'm gonna hit,
merge in,
center on.
I'm going to give that an outside border.
And hamli,
do we have We have 123 groups,
1234 So I'm just gonna highlight that Left click one That's 23 foot four rows Control and D
something.
We have our date boxes in there back to the original document,
train and name.
That's just outside borders.
So I can,
in fact,
I'm gonna highlight all of those that,
I'm gonna highlight there,
through there but rather than outside ball that because we wanted to actually color in all
the lines will come up to here and we'll choose all borders So they go.
No,
we have are all borders.
Let's have a look at the original document again.
It looks like it's exactly the same thing over here as well.
This is an all borders thing.
So a lot borders.
So just highlighted all of those sounds I'm gonna hit the this one with the cross in its
services.
All borders.
And that's colored that in Let's have a look at the original.
Okay,
it looks like we've just got emergence center thing across the bottom there,
so I'm just gonna highlight away across the bottom hit emergence center.
This is the last cell on the sheets and let's also in blue.
Andi it has an outside border.
There we go.
So let me just shrink that down.
The colors are probably not right,
but it kind of looks something like the original.
If I could just put that to the side of it,
make that a little bit bigger on Zoom.
And it looks something like that.
I think now,
actually,
on your original what you do have where is that?
You have a bold line around this section here,
this this middle section up to there by the looks of it.
So it looks like it's from 31 0 31 up to probably goes all the way over to D six.
Yeah,
so let's just highlight all of that there on this time we're going to go here on,
we're going to say thick box border and click that and know when we click off,
you should say that you got a super white,
a super thick border around all of that section.
And you may want to do that around this section here by choosing the thick box border on
maybe even at the top.
I don't actually know what the original looks like.
Now think around.
That's up.
And then if assuming,
uh,
that looks something like your original document.
Sorry,
that's a 22 minute video that went on a bit,
but that should cover everything that's included in that document.
So,
as usual,
if you have any questions,
ping me an email or ping me a message or post in discussion on day,
I can see if I can source it out for you.
Have a great day.