Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another student.
Question answered.
Now in level one of the course.
How the question says,
How can I make Excel right?
The first letter in a cell in capital letters automatically.
Now,
by default,
proper words automatically capitalized.
So the days of the week and the months of the year are automatically capsulized because
their proper words Beyond that,
what we need to apply is a formula to do that.
And then the formulas are very,
very straightforward.
So here and you can download this file from this lecture.
What we have are a few examples.
So when I have in cell a three is Mary had a little lamb,
and what we're gonna do is convert that from lower case,
toe up a case a woman do in B three,
you say equals and I'm going to say upper open brackets.
Then just point to that cell and closer brackets and it enter.
And there you can see we have Mary had a little lamb all in uppercase on just conduce.
Copy that.
They're going to paste special values here.
So now I have Mary had a little lamb in upper case to convert it back the other way.
What I'm gonna do is say,
equals lower open the brackets,
point to that cell closer brackets and hit Enter.
And now you can see I have Mary had a little lamb back in Lo que So again,
I'm just gonna hit control and seeing Copy that click here and pay special.
So now I have it in lower case.
And I'm also going to copy that and put it in uppercase.
Oh,
no.
We have it both here.
One in lower case one in upper case there to capitalize the first letter of each word.
We're going to use the proper function,
so we just come type equals proper open brackets.
Point here.
Closer brackets on hit,
enter.
And there you can see that everything has its first letter capitalizing.
If I just hit control in D and copy that down,
you can see that it doesn't matter whether it's in lower case or upper case.
It will automatically capitalize the first letter off each word.
Now,
a mindful that the specific question says head,
I capitalize the first letter in each cell,
not in each word.
So here,
we're gonna use will use this as an example.
I'm just gonna pace that in there.
So here we have.
Mary had a little lamb in lower case now to capitalize.
Only the first letter were really into Level two stuff here,
but I'm gonna wish through it anyway,
what we could have,
what we're gonna need to do is combine a few different functions.
Eso I'm just gonna wish through the so we can use the left function on what the left
function say's is point to the text that you want to extract the left most character from.
So we're going to be looking at D three and then we're gonna hit comma,
and it says in hair me characters Do you want to return?
So Mary has four letters,
So free hit four and closer brackets left four off this cell here returns Mary.
So there's the left here for completeness.
We're also going to do the right,
so it's gonna copy that.
Paste it in here.
Going to say equals right on.
No,
no,
we're extracting the right most character.
So getting an a point here on I'm gonna hit comma.
Let's let's just say three for a second.
So that should give us a M.
B.
So now we have a M beat.
But if I change that to four,
I would actually get the full word lamb.
Okay,
to complete this,
we're gonna have a look at the mid function.
We don't actually need to use that for the capital ocean of the first letter,
but just for completeness,
we're gonna cover it.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna say equals made,
and there is one extra argument here again,
we're gonna point to the text that we want us extract the middle from.
So again,
we're going to say D 11 here,
comma start number will be the number of characters in that you want to start from.
So if we wanted to extract had A from this,
we would say Mary has four letters.
We have a space that's five.
And we want to begin at the sixth letter,
which is the h So six on hand A has a h a d three letters,
a space for andan I,
which is five.
So come up number of characters to extract five and enter May go.
We extract had a no finally,
on one thing that we are going to need to do to capitalize.
The first letter is working out what the length of the string is.
So what we're gonna do is just copy that there,
copy and paste it in here.
And what we're gonna say is equal Len,
which is short for length.
They're just gonna point that sell close brackets Nager.
Many had little lamb has 22 characters.
So here we're going to build a complex formula.
It's going to capitalize the first letter.
So we're going to Firstly,
we're gonna utilize the left so we can say left.
We're gonna point here on groups and say the first character,
Intesa.
And there we have the M.
But what we want to do is make that upper case.
So we're gonna enclose all of that in upper case.
So now we get capital M.
That's capitalized our first letter.
Now what we need to do is return the rest of the string in lower case.
So what we're gonna do on Bear with me here?
We're going to say andi,
which is the equivalent of a can Katyn eight.
We're going to say Andi on,
we're going to say,
right,
we'll do this in stages Were going to say the right off this string just here,
comma on the number of characters is going to be the length of the whole string minus one
because we've already captured that first letter.
So we're going to say length of this string close of rackets minus one on down.
We're gonna close that off.
So that's going to give us.
Mary had a little lamb,
but let's imagine for a second that the lamb was also capitalized.
So now what we have is Mary had little.
And with a capital M in the capital,
l full leme.
So what we're going to do here is just wrap a lower around that west part of the formula.
So there we have the capitalized first letter and everything else in lower case.
Okay,
I hope that answers your question.
As always,
any others just post them in and I'll be happy to help.
Have a great day