Okay,
We've learned how to enter text in Excel,
which is very straightforward,
but we may want toe edit the text we've just entered.
Now we have a couple of ways of doing this,
the most obvious being selecting the cell hitting delete on your keyboard and wiping out
the cell completely.
But we may just want to at least a part of the text that we've just entered.
Now we have a couple of ways of doing this.
Justus.
We did with Enter in text.
We can either do it in the cell or we can do it in the Formula Bar,
and we're going to cover both of them now.
Okay,
we'll do the cell first will left click the cell to select it,
and then we can either double click left mouse button,
and you can see that we now have a flashing cursor inside so we could scroll over and
change our title to fruits and veggie shop hit.
Enter and there you go.
That's one.
Let me just move the cursor.
They go.
That's one way of editing your texts by selecting the cell and double clicking.
Alternatively,
you can select the cell and hit F two on your keyboard like that,
and you'll instantly get your flashing cursor at the end of your text so you can then
scroll over.
Use in your arrow keys.
Onda delete whenever you want to do or make.
Whatever changes you need to hit,
enter and you're done on the third and final way is too slight the cell that you want to
read it.
Come up here to your formula bar,
and you can add whichever text you want to add in just up here.
And that will also edit the text you just entered.
Okay,
there you go.
That's how you edit text in the cell.