The Spring Framework is what started everything that is Spring today.
It's where it all began.
And remember that when we say Spring,
we're usually referring to the Spring family or the Spring ecosystem.
Enterprise Java development at the time was a rigid and complex process,
this was around 2003, and the creator of the Spring Framework,
Rod Johnson,
set out to fix that by creating a framework that applications could
build upon to really simplify the development process.
The Spring Framework ended up being very successful in this aspect,
and over time it sort of grew and evolved into what it is today,
and what it is today is actually quite different
than what it was when it started.
In addition to simplifying Java development,
it also became the foundation for which all Spring projects were built upon.
For instance, like Spring Boot.
Applications could then in turn utilize these projects,
along with the Spring Framework, to even further simplify their development.
Next,
let's take a deeper look at what the Spring Framework consists of and what it provides.