Hi.
My name's Dustin Schultz, and in this module of Spring: The Big Picture course,
we'll learn about one of the key projects in the
Spring family called Spring Boot.
We already had a very brief introduction to Spring Boot in the previous module,
so we'll use this module to take a slightly deeper look at Spring Boot.
Again, remember that we're keeping things high level,
so we don't want to be digging too deep here.
We certainly won't be learning how to use Spring Boot
or doing any sort of in-depth demos.
Instead, we'll be focused on what Spring Boot is,
and what it's about, and what it provides.
We want to use Spring Boot as our first introduction to Spring
and sort of get a flavor for what it's like.
Learning any new technology can be both confusing and frustrating.
It's really, really hard to know where to start,
and you can quickly become overwhelmed.
Thankfully, Spring Boot makes learning Spring both quick and easy.
Developers can jump right in and get started without having to fully
understand everything that's behind the scenes.
Then as they get more advanced and knowledgeable,
they can circle their way back and learn more about the details.
I want to be absolutely clear though, easy does not mean lack of features.
It's somewhat common for frameworks to boast about how
great and easy their technology is,
only to be disappointed when it's used in real-world
scenarios and falls flat on its face.
Spring Boot on the other hand is fully-featured and is heavily utilized in production by many companies today.