Hi.
My name is Dustin Schultz, and in this module of Spring: The Big Picture course,
we'll be taking a tour of several of the other Spring projects that exist,
understanding what they do and how they make development easier.
If you open up a browser and visit spring.
io/projects,
you'll be brought to a page that contains all the projects
that exist within the Spring family.
You can scroll through the projects and see what's available and
click into any of the projects for more details.
There's over 20 different projects at the time of this recording,
and as nice as it would be to be able to explore all of these projects,
we'll only be focusing our tour on a subset of the most
popular and widely used projects.
The projects we'll be exploring in this module are Spring Data, Spring Cloud, and Spring Security.