In this section,
we'll briefly take a look at the features that the Spring
Framework provides for integration.
Now what exactly do I mean when I say integration?
Well, applications don't live in isolation.
Applications often need to share data or work with other applications,
and integration is all about making different systems
and applications work together.
So how exactly does the Spring Framework help?
Well, one problem you need to solve is how one application can talk to another,
or communicate.
And this is a multi-sided problem.
So A) you have to figure out how do you expose operations to other systems,
and B) how do you invoke, or run, operations on other systems?
There's certainly many different ways to expose operations to other systems,
such as RMI, or Remote Method Invocation,
or another way is via a messaging system,
and the Spring Framework supports both of these,
but one such popular way to expose operations is something called web services.
And web services are simply operations that are
exposed and accessible via the web.
And the Spring Framework makes it easy to both expose and invoke web services.
Let's take a look at an example.
On the left we have a very simple example of a web service,
and this can be used to retrieve account information.
So you might think of this as being used in a banking
application to look up your bank account.
And at the core of this web service are three annotations.
Remember that annotations are just metadata that's added to the code.
The first annotation is the @RestController annotation,
and it denotes that this code is going to be exposing operations
using a style of web services called REST,
and the details of what REST is aren't really important,
just know that rest is a way or style of implementing web services.
The second annotation, the @GetMapping annotation,
is used to denote the operation and the path that need
to be used to invoke this operation.
And we can see that the path is just like any regular URL that we're used to
seeing on the web with some additional added curly syntax.
And the curly braces are related to the third annotation,
and they simply indicate that this part of the path is a placeholder.
In our case, it's a placeholder for the account number,
and in other words,
it's the way that we tell the operation what
account number we'd like to retrieve.
So even if you don't understand the code,
you can see that with these three simple annotations,
we've exposed a service that can be used to look up
an account by its account number.
Now that we've seen how to expose an operation via a web service,
let's look at the other side of the problem and how the Spring Framework helps
us to invoke our service from within another application.
Remember how we utilized REST to implement our web service?
Well,
the Spring Framework provides support for
programmatically invoking our REST service,
and you utilize something called a RestTemplate.
And that RestTemplate abstracts away all the tedious
details of interacting with a web service,
like opening a connection to the web service,
sending over the command, and handling the response from the web service.
In fact,
it's so easy to use that it'll only take us one line of code to call a web
service that looks up an account by its account number.
Using the RestTemplate, we can call the GetForObject method,
pass a few parameters,
one of which is the path to the web service with the
account ID that we want to look up,
and the RestTemplate will take care of the rest. No pun intended.