Testing is an important part of developing software,
so it's no surprise that the Spring Framework
strives to help in this area as well.
And there's many different levels at which software is tested,
and the Spring Framework focuses on two different areas,
on unit testing and integration testing.
Let's start by talking about unit testing.
Unit testing is a software development process in which the smallest
testable parts of an application called units are individually and
independently scrutinized for proper operation.
And explicit support for unit testing in the Spring
Framework is actually minimal.
The Spring Framework support for testing largely comes as a
side effect of using one of its key concepts,
and that's dependency injection.
And we talked about dependency injection in the section on Spring Core.
So just to quickly refresh your memory,
dependency injection is all about dealing with the way
objects fulfill their dependencies.
So you're probably wondering how exactly does dependency
injection help make testing easier?
Well, remember that with unit testing,
the idea is to test the smallest unit of code possible,
and when the code that's being tested has no dependencies,
meaning that it doesn't depend on other code to do its work,
this is a fairly easy process; however,
when the code under test has dependencies,
it's important to be able to control how those
dependencies behave in order to restrict the testing to
just the code and not the dependencies.
If the code is written with dependency injection in mind,
the testing becomes a lot easier.
The developer is forced to declare what the code depends on,
and the code expects to be given those dependencies,
and the code doesn't necessarily care where they come from,
just the fact that something fulfills them.
So during testing,
dependent code can be replaced with code that behaves a certain way,
and this action of replacing pieces of code with
controlled code is called mocking.
Now just to be absolutely clear, in unit testing,
we don't actually use dependency injection to inject
dependencies into our unit tests,
but the way that the code is set up for dependency injection,
mainly that the code is forced to declare what it depends on,
that helps to make testing easier.
If you're confused or still not grasping the concept,
hopefully it'll make sense with an example.
Suppose you have a piece of code that grants people certain
permissions based on their security clearance level,
and suppose that there's three different types of security clearance,
confidential, secret, and top secret.
Now I don't expect that you'll understand this piece of code,
so let's quickly walk through it.
If you notice the method, the getPermissions method,
is passed a parameter called the SecurityManager,
and the SecurityManager is responsible for getting the security clearance level.
And then we have a series of if/else if statements that just check what that
level is and grant certain permissions based on that level.
When testing this piece of code, you want to be able to test every condition,
or what happens in every scenario, every if block,
and luckily this code has been written with dependency injection in mind
and declares that it depends on the SecurityManager.
During testing,
instead of using the real logic to determine what the
user's current security clearance level is,
we can mock this dependency and control the way the SecurityManager behaves,
or in other words, we can control what security clearance level is returned.
So for instance, if we were writing a test here,
for our first test we could make it so that the SecurityManager
that it uses always returns confidential,
and that would ensure that we enter that first if block.
And then for our second test,
we could make it always return secret and it would make
sure that it enters that second if block,
and so on.
If the SecurityManager had not been declared as a dependency,
this code would have been much harder to test because we wouldn't
be able to as easily control the logic of the SecurityManager to
test all of the various conditions.
As part of the support for unit testing,
the Spring Framework includes a number of prewritten
mocks that can be used in testing,
and this ultimately makes testing easier and faster for a developer
because it saves them from having to write their own mocks.
The second area of focus for testing within the Spring
Framework is integration testing,
and integration testing is the phase in software testing in which
individual modules are combined and tested as a group.
It occurs after unit testing.
And as the name suggests,
integration testing is focused on how various parts of a
software application integrate together.
Integration tests allow you to run whole pieces of an
application and test how they all work together and not just
pieces of code in isolation like unit tests.
Outside of explicit support for integration tests,
the Spring Framework plays an important role in integration testing,
as it could be used to piece together various parts
of the application for testing.
In terms of explicit support,
the Spring Framework provides support for common integration testing scenarios,
like setting up and testing data access,
as well as other scenarios like setting up and testing whole parts of
a web application to ensure they're functional.
Another nice feature provided by the Spring Framework is
the ability to clean up after tests.
And let me explain what I mean by that.
So when you're writing integration tests,
it's very common that you'll be changing the state of the
application just by running the test.
For instance,
maybe you do some data access tests and you insert
some new data into a database.
And if you leave that data in there after the test is complete,
it could end up affecting how other tests run after it.
So the Spring Framework provides support for helping you clean up those tests after they run.