We've reached the end of this module,
so let's take a moment to recap what we've learned.
We've covered a lot of content in this module.
We first saw Spring Core and how it's the foundation of the Spring
Framework and how it provides support for dependency injection,
which is a key component of the Spring Framework.
Then we got to see the web support within the Spring Framework,
as we talked about Spring Web MVC and Spring Webflux.
After that, we got to learn what AOP is,
or aspect-oriented programming,
and how Spring AOP can be used to solve cross-cutting concerns.
We then learned all about the Spring Framework's Data Access
module and how it removes a ton of boilerplate code and
makes it easier to access data.
And then after that,
we took a brief look at the Spring Framework's integration features and how
they help different applications and systems work together,
and we finished out the module by learning about the Spring Framework support for unit and integration testing.