So now that we've see the advantages and disadvantages of using Spring,
we're back to our original question, is Spring a good fit for my project,
my team, my company, etc.? Well, unfortunately,
I'm not going to directly answer that question for you
because every scenario is different, and no matter how I answer it,
I'll probably be wrong.
And likewise,
coming to that conclusion on your own will be much
more meaningful and thoughtful.
When it's your decision and someone asks you why you chose
Spring for your project or your team or company,
you'll be in a great position to be able to back it up
with well thought-out reasoning.
I will say consider the pros and cons against your situation,
as pros may not always be pros in different situations,
and the same goes for cons.
I would love to hear your comments in the discussion section
on what conclusion you came to and why, or why you're considering using Spring. I try my best to read and reply to all of the comments.