Hi and welcome back.
In this video, I wanted to talk about a really important
concept in programming which is mutability.
Somethings in Python are mutable
and some things are immutable, so what is mutable?
A mutable pice of data is one that
you can change after you've created it.
An immutable piece of data is one you cannot change.
Here you may be wondering,
aren't all pieces of data mutable?
Like, when you create a variable, you can then change it?
Yes, that is true, however the
variable itself is not the piece of data.
Let's go back to our dictionary that has how long
ago we saw some of our friends.
Here the data is the dictionary.
So Python creates this dictionary and then the variable
is essentially like a Post-It note that's been attached
to the data that says this piece of data now has this name.
However, when you do something like another variable
equal friends last seen, these two are the same dictionary.
Once again, what we've done is we've attached another name
to the value in here, this dictionary here.
This is a really important concept in programming.
Let's forget about this name tagging for just a moment.
And I'll ask you, "How do you know it's mutable?"
Well whenever we create a new dictionary, it's stored
physically in your computer's RAM, random access memory,
which is a type of memory that only lives while
the computer is on and your app is running.
As soon as your app terminates, your programme finishes.
And if we run this and it reaches the end, the RAM does
get lost or rather the memory that was assigned to
this Python programme gets lost and then it
can get overwritten by other programmes.
Python can give us the ID of the object.
The ID function here is used to give us the ID of any object
and in this case we're parsing a friends last seen variable
here which points to this dictionary.
So it can give us the ID of that
and in the majority of Python implementations,
that's an interesting concept by itself,
but in your Python implementation, the one you will be
running most likely and certainly here in repl.it,
the ID is the address of the object in memory.
And that's precisely the first cell in a group of cells
in your RAM which stores your object.
This ID function here gives you the first cell in the group.
That's because the object can take up
multiple cells and they normally do.
Okay, so let's run this programme.
And now you get a number, seemingly arbitrary number.
But when we run the programme again, notice that we
get a slightly different number.
It wasn't so easy to see but
trust me it's a different number.
Now when we say friends last seen is now this dictionary,
which looks the same but is an entirely new dictionary.
And you can tell that by once again calling the
friends last seen function, the ID.
Notice how these two numbers are very slightly different.
That's because these objects are not the same object.
They are two objects which have the same content.
Think for example of two cars coming out of a
production line, they both have four wheels, a steering
wheel, they both may be red, they both are the same
make and model but they're not the same car.
Same thing here, we have a variable which
has a name and that is assigned to
this dictionary here, this particular object.
And then we get the idea of it, then we assign it to another
dictionary which looks the same, and get the ID of it.
And those two dictionaries are created one after another.
The reason why this dictionary cannot have the same ID
as this one is that when the time this is created
and the time this is created, this one still exists.
So they cannot possibly appear in the same place.
The other one is taking up the space.
Okay so even though the dictionaries have
the same values, the ID values are different.
New dictionaries were created each time
and hence their memory addresses,
what the ID function returns, are different.
However, what if we do this?
We create a new dictionary here which has an entirely
new ID and then we say friends last seen, Rolf is now zero.
What do we think this is going to print?
Is it going to print an entirely new ID
or will it print the same ID as before?
Well it doesn't really matter what you guessed,
but what matters is that the ID will be the same.
As you can see, these last two numbers here are identical.
That's because when we run this line
of code we have modified this object.
We have not created a new object, we have mutated it.
This is a mutable data structure, the dictionary.
Okay, this is the case with many many things in Python.
When you create your own classes and you change a property
of your objects, you're not creating new objects.
You're just changing something that is already there.
However, there are a few immutable things in Python.
Integers, for example, are immutable.
Let's say that you get my int and that's five.
And then you say print ID of my int.
When we run this we'll get an ID for our integer object.
But how can we modify the five?
You cannot change five, five is always five.
If you make it six, that's an entirely
new thing, an entirely different thing.
So indeed if you do my int is equal to my int plus one
and then you print the ID of my int,
that's going to be an entirely different value.
And as you can see here, it's pretty similar
but it's not quite the same one.
So integers are an example of something that is immutable.
You cannot change it because five is always five.
Other things that are immutable
are floats, strings, and tuples.
You cannot change tuples for example, okay?
Lists, however, are mutable and
I'm going to show you an example.
Let's have a friends list, Rolf and Jose.
Then we can print the ID of friends.
We can then do something like append.
And then we can print the ID of friends again.
And now notice how these two will have the same ID.
We've got five values here, so we'll now get seven
and these two down here have the same ID exactly.
We've changed or mutated the list,
we have not created a new list.
When you use list comprehension
for example, a new list is created.
So these are the immutable types in Python.
Integers, floats, strings, tuples.
And there's not many more, in fact I don't
know any other immutable types.
So what is really happening when we mutate an object?
Maybe you can see a pattern here,
which is that we've got a mutable type
and then here, well but this is our mutable
type in this case, the dictionary.
And then here we're mutating it.
So what's happening here on the innards of Python?
Well this is happening, friends last seen set item.
A function is happening, a function call is occurring.
This function call here that takes in self as
an argument is modifying the self object.
It is not creating a new dictionary
which you would do with like, you know, creating a new
dictionary you would be like, Rolf is now zero.
This would create a new dictionary.
But this set item function is not creating
a new dictionary, it is modifying self.
That is why it mutates the data, it does not recreate it.
So what happens when we do this?
Well something happens when we add my int plus one together.
This happens, my int add one.
But the difference is the add function
takes in the value of self
and returns a new integer object,
potentially something like this.
I'm not exactly sure how the innards work,
but all I know is that it returns a new integer object.
It does not modify self, which could be for example
self dot value plus equal one.
This could modify self, potentially.
Okay, note that my int plus equal one is another
function call, my int iadd self one.
If the int object was programmed to create
a new int object when this function call happens then the
int object would not be mutable, it would be immutable.
Because this iadd function is programmed to create a new
int object every time, the int object
is immutable, you cannot change it.
So immutability.
All functions return new int objects.
You cannot change existing int objects.
This is why some of these things are
immutable and some of them are mutable.
Because you create new objects of their type
when you call some functions and in other cases you never
modify existing objects, you only create new objects.
This is the concept of immutability
and it's sort of difficult to wrap your head around it.
But in the next video we're going to look at
some examples of where mutability matters.
So I'll see you in the very next video.