Hi there and welcome back.
In this video we're talking about any and all.
Those are two functions that are really straightforward,
but in some cases can be really useful.
The any function takes an iterable and returns true
if any of its elements evaluate to true.
And the all function returns true
if all the elements evaluate to true.
So here's an example of when it might be useful.
Imagine you've got this list of friend locations.
It's a list of dictionaries where each dictionary
has a name of your friend and the location of the friend.
Then we ask the user for their location.
And then we're going to calculate which friends
are in that location.
So bit of a longer list comprehension there.
Just get in the friend for each of the friends
in friends, if their location is equal to
your location variable that the users entered.
So imagine that they enter San Francisco.
We're going to put in the friend object.
Sorry this dictionary, for each of the friends
if they are in San Francisco.
Now we could say, something like,
if len(friends_nearby) &gt; 0:
that means there are at least one friend,
print you are not alone.
I'll just to that so it's a bit more readable for you.
However this is not terribly nice
because what we want to do, is we don't care
about the length, what we care
is whether there are any friends.
So here is where the any friends comes in handy.
If any friends nearby print you are not alone.
What this is doing, it is going over
each of the elements in friends nearby
and it's checking whether they are truthy.
Now are truthy value,
notice how these things are not booleans,
they are dictionaries.
A truthy value is one that evaluates to true.
So here are some values that evaluate to false.
Just because there's not that many,
and it's always good to know them.
Zero evaluates to false when you try
to get a boolean out of it.
So does none of course.
So do empty list, empty tuple, empty sets.
Does does false, and of course zero point zero
and all these type of numbers that are zero,
evaluate to false.
You can whether something evaluates to true or false
by doing bool of zero.
So we can run that and we can enter San Francisco.
Notice how it says you a not alone first of all.
And then it also says, false
because bool of zero is false.
So that's what the any function does.
It goes through each element and it asks them
if they were a boolean, would they be true or false?
If any of them says true,
then it says, okay this is true, you're not alone.
You can also say all friends nearby.
But again, the friends nearby function
is going to contain either zero friends
or one or more friends,
so all doesn't make much sense
because all of your friends are going to be dictionaries.
So if one of them is true, all of them
are going to be true because they're all
going to be dictionaries,
and dictionaries are always true unless they're empty.
Any would return true if there's at least one.
Or false if empty,
so it's a pretty handy function in this case.
Okay.
Now let me just delete that.
And of course all would print, for example
all of one, two, three, four, five.
These will print true.
So I'm going to run this,
I say San Francisco,
and now notice how it says true here
because one, two, three, four, five are all true.
But as soon as we put a zero in there and run it again,
we now get false because not all of these things here
are true, one of them's false and that's the zero.
So it can be useful in some circumstances.
I just wanted you to know about this function
just in case you encounter a situation
where you need to use it.
This is again, of me giving you some tools
for you to use in your construction project.
You may not need them all for one particular project
but they may be useful for other projects.
And these functions are essentially
those slightly more obscure tools
a lot of people don't know about,
but they're still handy to know
and understand that they exist.
So that's it for this video,
and I'll see you on the next one.