Hi and welcome back.
In this video we're talking about special methods.
In a class, as we've seen, not all methods are the same.
Python sometimes makes a distinction
depending on the method name.
Here's an example of one of those methods.
That's def dunder init method.
The dunder init method gets called for you
when you create a new object.
The new blank object is parsed to self
and the name is whatever you put inside
your constructors arguments.
And then we've sort of defined a new property
as hight self and viewed in the value of our parameter.
So the dunder init method is a special method
because Python calls it for you automatically
when you create an object, you don't have
to call it yourself.
So here's a couple other interesting, special methods.
First of all, let's define a list of movies.
What do you think is going to happen
when I print out the movies class?
Now, we looked at printing the student's class earlier
and you got some sort of student thing printed out.
What is the movie's class?
Is it an error?
Well as you can see, we get a class list.
That's some pretty bizarre functionality there.
Does this mean that a list is somehow an object?
Yes, pretty much everything in Python is an object.
And this list is no different.
Only we've not had to create it using
this constructor like students type thing.
Instead, Python's created it for us automatically
when we use this syntax.
You can, however, print for example, hi dot class,
and that's gonna give you a string class, see str.
So everything is an object in Python.
What does it mean for a list to be an object?
Well, it means that everything we can do
with a list, we can do with our own classes.
So here's an example.
We can print out the len of movies.
Okay, now we know that movies is an object.
So what is going on behind the scenes
that is allowing us to call this len function,
give it the movies object and it's given us two.
Well, let's do it.
Let's create a class garage.
And in it we're going to define an init method.
That is going to define self dot cars to be an empty list.
Now, we can create our garage,
let's say Ford is gonna be in garage.
And now this Ford has a, Ford.cars
has this cars property here, that is gonna
print out an empty list when we print it out,
because that's what we've assigned it to.
However, we can add, we can say Ford.cars.append fiesta.
And Ford.cars.append focus for example.
Then when we run this programme again,
now we get a list of two items, fiesta and focus.
Now what if I wanted to do len of Ford.
Ford is the garage one but I want
to get the len of Ford, because that's
gonna tell me how many cars there are inside my garage.
Of course, when we run this, we get a type error.
Object of type garage has no len.
Okay, that's an interesting error.
It tells us that Python cannot calculate the len
of this garage, because it doesn't know
what the len of the garage is meant to be,
what it's meant to mean, even.
So in order to tell Python that this garage
has a length, we have to define another dunder method.
And that's underscore underscore len underscore underscore.
Again it takes you to self, like all methods do
and then it has to return the length of the garage.
In this case, how many cars there are.
So it's gonna return the length of self.cars.
Now when we run this programme again,
we'll see that two gets printed out
even though we've called len of Ford
our garage object instead of len of Ford.cars.
That's because when we call len,
ford comes over to here, self and then
we return the length of self.cars.
The list also has this dunder len method
that gives us the number of items in the list.
That's just a slightly more complicated definition,
but nonetheless, what we have to know
is that this len dunder method allows
us to do something and return a value
that we get returned to us when we call
the len function on our object.
Let's do something like, for example ford zero.
Ford zero should give us the first car
in the queue of cars that we're working
with for example.
In this case, it should be fiesta
because that's the first car we appended.
Of course if we run this, we'll get
that garage object does not support indexing.
Remember, this is accessing something by an index,
Python calls it indexing.
What to do?
Well you guessed it, we'll define another dunder method.
Here's a challenge for you.
Pause the video and go an find out
how you can index your own custom object.
It's gonna be a bit of a challenge, a bit tricky,
but I'm sure you can do it.
Okay, I'm sure you got that.
We have to define a new dunder method.
And this time it's called get item.
And it takes self of course, the object
that we're calling this on.
And it also takes the index that we're trying to access, i.
So remember, this is just another
way of calling ford.getitem, with ford,
sorry, garage.getitem with ford and zero.
Okay, this is syntactic sugar for this.
What we're doing is calling the get i's
and the function of the garage class
and we're parsing to it the ford object
that we've created and the index we want
to access, which is zero.
And all we have to do is return self.cars.i,
so the car's i.
And that's gonna give us the i index
of the self.cars list.
Let's run it.
And there you have it, we get fiesta back.
So these are two pretty important dunder methods
that can be quite useful in many circumstances.
Whenever you want an object that will store things
and that you can access, these two methods
can be pretty useful.
Now, as soon as you've implemented the len and get item
methods, some new functionality gets unlocked.
And that is, that you can iterate over your garage.
You can use a four loop on your garage.
But only when you have these two methods defined.
Because Python is gonna use these
two methods in the background of the ford loop
in order to iterate over it.
And there you have it, you get fiesta and focus.
So it's some pretty cool stuff.
The first time I learned about this
I was, pardon the expression, flabbergasted.
Because I really didn't know much about these
dunder methods, and it's pretty interesting,
because everything you can do in Python,
all the built in functions like len and some,
and all the constructs like for,
are all built on objects having these special methods.
And so learning about these is really exciting.
And we will learn about them as we go along the course.
But I wanted to give you another two special
methods, in fact, that are the dunder repr
and dunder string.
So let's implement dunder repr.
This is how you define the repr.
And this repr should be used to print
out a string representing the object.
So let's once again, put self in here.
And we can return, I'm sorry, I said this
should be used to print out a string, that's a lie.
It should be used to return a string,
that represents the object.
So we can define this as being a garage.
And inside of it we're gonna put self.cars.
That really represents our garage.
It's a garage object and it has
this list of cars inside of it.
The dunder string should be used
to return a string that tells the user
some information about this garage,
such that if you were to print the object out,
the user might gain some useful insights
about the garage you're printing out.
So in this case we should return something like f.
And garage with len of self cars.
Notice how the repr, the dunder repr
returns a sort of codified version of this garage.
It includes everything we need,
in order to represent this object.
And the str method turns something
that a user might want to read.
That's really the difference between these two.
Notice how here we've accessed len of self.
I love this, self is the object.
So when you call len of self, you're really
calling the len method that you defined up here.
Now when you print ford down here, you see
the str gets used, garage with two cars.
So when does the dunder repr method get used?
The dunder repr method gets used
particularly when you are coding.
When you're using a debugger, we're gonna
learn what that is in a few sessions time,
it can be really useful for you to look
at the object and understand exactly
what it is made up of, in this case cars.
As we look into debugging, we're gonna
look more at the repr function and why it can be useful.
So don't worry too much about it for now,
just know that the str function
can be really useful when printing things out to a user.
However, if you are only going to implement
one of these two, choose the repr.
You can just delete the repr.
You can turn the str into a repr, delete this repr here.
And make it print something a user will want to see.
And this is a better approach,
when you now print ford, it's gonna
call the repr function instead of the str function.
Because repr is sort of a bit more important.
So if you're only gonna implement one, implement the repr.
But of course, if you can implement both
one for a more code oriented description,
and the other one for a more user oriented description,
this is much better.
I am a strong proponent, that every class
you create should have a repr and an str methods.
There's many more magic dunder methods
you can implement, including some to add objects together.
After all, integers are also objects.
You can overload what boolean operators do.
You can make your objects callable.
And you can do things like add context managers.
We're gonna look at what those are, and much, much more.
We'll be learning about a lot of these
dunder methods throughout the course
because this again, is the most comprehensive
Python course that you can take.
So I want to cover everything about Python.
That's it for this video.
I know it's getting a bit more advanced,
so you're still with me.
When we get to building our next project
everything's gonna be a bit clearer.
So that's it for this video.
I'll see you on the next one.