Hi, welcome back.
In this video we're going to talk about
launching multiple processes.
So you can launch multiple processes with Python.
You can have your main Python process
that gets created when you launch your Python App.
And you can ask your Python code to launch another process.
When you do that, each process can have its own thread
running in two separate cores.
Okay, so the two processes would be entirely
separate from one another.
As part of doing that it can also set up communication
between the processes, and that communication is slow,
but it can allow us to run through things
actually at once in two separate cores.
It's not entirely that simple.
Let's have look at some code.
Okay, I'm going to copy some things from
the earlier section here.
Oh sorry, let's copy from here.
So I'm going to copy all of this,
and I'm going to delete the thread code in here.
I'm going to delete that.
So what we've got are our two functions,
ask user and complex calculation.
Once again we've got our timing functions
that we're going to ask the user first,
run the complex calculation second,
and print out how long that took.
If you want to have multiple processes,
you can do that.
All you have to do is say from multi processing,
import process.
Now you have the process class from the
multiprocessing module, and you can use that
to launch a new process.
Let's do it.
We're going to say,
the new process is process.
The target is complex calculation, so that's going
to be the target of this process.
And then we're going to say process start.
We're going to say start equals time.time.
We're going to ask the user for something.
We're going to wait for the process to finish running.
And then we're going to print, you know,
two process total time is time.time minus start.
Okay, very similar to what you would expect
from the thread code processes.
You've got your new process.
You give it a target, you start it.
And then when you want it to wait until it finishes,
you do .join and that's it.
Okay, very straightforward.
Let's run it and see what happens.
Let's right click the processes file and run it.
Asks me for my name first.
Then it starts calculating,
and then it's going to ask me for my name again.
And notice how that's sort of screwed up.
That didn't look so good there, yeah.
And again, it takes in, it took me a bit longer
to type in my name now because this was a bit messed up.
But it took the same amount of time
as the multi threaded code.
Some would say it takes a little bit longer,
it probably does take a little bit longer
because creating a new process is a bit more expensive
than creating a new thread.
But generally, you know, it works, yeah.
This thing here though, enter your name,
started calculating, dot, dot, dot,
is a symptom of the problem,
and the problem we're going to see it
when we try to do something else.
Which is now I'm going to create another process
for my ask user function.
So process two is going to be process,
and the target is going to be, ask target
is ask the user function.
Then we're going to start process one.
We're going to start process two.
We're not going to ask the user anymore
in the main process.
We have now two processes for that,
and we can do process2.join.
Okay, same thing as before.
We created processes, we start them,
we start the timer, now we wait for them to finish.
But you'll see that this won't work so easily.
Let's run this again.
Go on the single threaded code first.
Starts calculating, and then it's going to,
when it finishes it's going to launch my two processes.
But alas, we get an error.
And sometime after, we get the complex calculation finished.
So here the problem is that we get an EOF when
reading a line, end of file when reading a line.
Our process could not run this input function.
And the reason the function could not run
this input function is because it doesn't have access
to this terminal here.
Remember the processes cannot share resources very easily.
So it doesn't know where we're meant to be reading from
when we tell it to finish to finish by doing
process2.join, it says okay you didn't type anything.
There was nothing, there was no way for me
to get the input.
And also there's no way for me to type it.
So, you know, finish the process.
And you get an error there.
There's no place for me to type the input
because it doesn't have access to this thing
that I was about to type.
So a bit of a strange problem there,
but this is the reason why earlier on
you got your two lines in the same line.
They were accessing the console simultaneously,
but it was essentially, sorry, a separate entity.
So a bit of a complicated thing.
Using processes is not easy, okay.
Because they are separate, you start getting
sort of separate resources, sometimes duplicate resources,
one of them doesn't have access to something.
The other one does, so not terribly easy to use processes.
Normally you'll use processes if you have
a multi core machine like my laptop is
and you want to do complex calculations on both.
So if you want to do that, you can do that.
You can run the complex calculation on both machines.
Now you won't get this error.
Let's run this again.
And let's see what happens.
This is the single threaded code, by the way,
it took six point four seven seconds.
Then we started calculating price.
And now we're hoping the operating system
has given us two cores to run in,
and it seems like it did.
And now the two complex calculations ran
in a longer amount of time, closer to seven seconds now,
instead of six point four seven.
But they ran both at the same time.
This is why you use multi processing when you need
two things to run at the same time in the CPU.
If your problem is you have things that are waiting,
like this user input here, you don't need multi processing.
What you need is multi threading.
And you want to, you know, have cooperative
multi tasking between the two threads.
So this is multi processing.
I just want to show you quickly when to use it
and when not to use it.
And we're going to be encountering a couple more
scenarios of where we want to use this later on
in the course.
So that's it for this video,
and I'll see you in the next one.