Hi guys, welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be taking the contents
of one of our text areas and we're going to be saving them,
and putting them into a file in our system.
Let's start by creating a function that will do that.
So I'm gonna call this save_file(),
and what we have to do here is we have to ask the user
where in the system they want to save the file.
We're gonna do this first of all,
so that we know that they actually want to save it,
because they can always press cancel,
and so we know where the file is gonna go.
So we'll say file_path equal,
file dialogue dot ask save as file name, all one word,
which is not very nice and but nonetheless that's how it is,
and make sure that from tkinter you import file dialogue.
This file dialogue here is going to ask the user,
using the system dialogues,
where to save the thing that you wanna save.
So let's go ahead and before continuing with this,
just to show you what it looks like,
add an element to the menu that will call this function.
So down here in the file_menu dot add_command,
we're going to copy that,
but instead of "New" we're gonna call this "Save",
and the command is gonna be save_file,
and again, make sure to not call the function.
Let me run this app here,
and I'll type "Hello world" and I'm gonna go and save,
and notice that we get a few things going on.
First thing that we got was an error,
or seemingly something that looks like an error,
it's actually a warning,
and what it says is that somewhere in your system,
there is an ambiguous way of calling this dialogue.
So you don't have to worry about that at all.
That's just a problem in my system.
You may not even encounter this issue,
and the second thing is that you get this dialogue.
This is a Mac dialogue,
and in Windows and in Linux it'll look different,
and here you can save as a specific name,
and you can give it tags as it's just a Mac thing,
and you can decide where you wanna save it.
Now, I'm gonna press cancel and that's it.
So this is what our save file function does for now,
but note that it only asks the user
for the file name and the location.
It doesn't actually perform the saving,
which we do have to do.
So we're going to go ahead and import os at the top,
and then we're going to try to get the file name
from the file path.
So we do os dot path dot base name,
and we will pass in the file_path.
Given a path such as for example,
slash users slash jose slash file dot txt,
os_path based name will give you file dot txt.
If you're using a Windows style path,
it'll also work with that.
So this is a great way of ensuring
Cross-Platform Compatibility.
Next up, we're going to get
the currently selected text widget.
Remember that we can have multiple tabs in our system,
so by selecting the current one,
that is the one that we've just tried
to save to our computer.
So let's say that text_widget is equal to,
root dot name to widget, notebook dot select.
Now this does a few things.
First of all, the select in the notebook is
Something that returns the widget name
of the currently selected pane.
Now, you can pass in a tab ID,
and then what it does is,
it actually goes and selects a particular tab,
but if you don't pass in a tab ID,
which we'll not doing,
then it's gonna give us the name of the widget.
In tkinter, names can be used
to uniquely identify particular widgets,
such as text_areas, notebooks, frames and so on.
So by getting the currently selected widget,
we're then going to use the root,
which is the main window to turn that name into a widget.
This has to be called on the container of
whatever widget name you are getting.
Then we're going to perform some pretty ugly black magic.
We're gonna say that the content of the text widget
is text underscore widget dot get,
and we're gonna go
from the first line and the first character,
so this is the first line starts at one,
and the zeroth character, which is the first one.
So just before the first character,
we're gonna go until the end
of the content in the widget;
however, due to the way that text areas work in tkinter,
if you do from 1.0 to end,
then you're gonna end up with
an extra new line character at the end.
just because, that's always there in these widgets.
There's always an empty new line character at the end.
So what you wanna do, is you wanna go to the end,
except for the very last character,
which is always this new line character,
that you didn't add yourself.
So we do end minus 1c for end,
except the last character.
All right, so now that's out of the way,
you can go ahead and actually open the file path,
and we're going to open for writing,
as file and then we will do file dot write content.
Okay, next up, we're going to add an except,
and we're gonna except for AttributeError,
and FileNotFoundError,
and we're gonna just print an error message,
"Save operation cancelled",
and then we're going to return.
So if we close the window or we didn't get a file name,
or the file was not found in the system,
then we are going to print "Save operation cancelled",
and we're gonna return;
Otherwise, we're going to of course,
save the file into our disc,
and then we're also going to say, notebook dot tab,
and we're gonna pass in a tab ID,
but there is a special tab ID in notebook tabs,
which is "current",
and that selects the currently selected tab,
and here we're gonna pass in a text of file name,
and this file name here is what we extracted earlier,
and what this is going to do as you might imagine,
it is going to rename the current tab,
so that the name of the tab will henceforth be filename.
Let me run app dot pv,
just to show you everything we've done in this video.
And here we have our first empty file,
that we created using the create file function.
I'm gonna call it "Welcome to our text editor",
Then I'm gonna go ahead and save this,
and what's happening when we do this is,
first of all, we ask where we wanna save.
So I'm gonna save it as test dot txt in my desktop,
and then a bunch of things happened all in one place.
First, we got the file name,
which is test dot txt from the path,
that the dialogue gave us back.
Then we got the current widget,
which is the one that we have selected
at the time of saving.
We got all the content.
We opened the file using just good old Python,
and we wrote the contents into the disc,
and then at the end, we renamed the current tab,
so that it is now no longer called Untitled,
It is called test dot txt.
So, hopefully that makes sense.
We have done quite a lot of work in this video,
but most of it is just normal Python,
and there is a few tkinter use cases,
like asking for a file name, getting a particular widget,
this piece of beautiful code that gets you the content,
and then of course renaming a tab.
So thank you for joining me in this video.
I hope you've learned something.
I'll see you in the next one.