Hi and welcome back.
In this video,
I wanted to show you a little bit about deleting nodes
in a binary tree.
Deleting nodes is the most complicated part
of dealing with a binary tree
because you can delete any node in here,
so let's start talking about deleting nodes
and you'll progressively understand why it's such
a complicated thing.
Let's start with this tree here as an example.
Let's imagine we want to delete the node three.
Let's say we want to delete three from this tree.
The first thing we have to think about is
what makes three be in this tree?
It may be a bit of a strange question,
but remember we've got our binary tree object,
and the binary tree object knows about this head node,
the root of the tree.
It doesn't know about any other nodes.
The binary tree object only knows about this six.
The six points to five and six points to nine,
that's the left and the right.
So you could say that five is in the tree
because the head points to it.
If the head did not point to it,
then you wouldn't know that it's in the tree,
so therefore it wouldn't be in the tree.
Similarly three is in the tree,
because five points to it and the head points to five.
It's the relationships between these nodes
that end up describing the tree.
If you made five not point to three,
if you deleted this arrow,
nothing would point to three,
you wouldn't have any variables of this node
and Python would recognise that there are no
variables referenced in this node.
Nothing is pointing to it.
It's completely isolated.
You've go no way of accessing this node in your programme,
and when Python realises that,
what it does is it deletes it from memory,
or at least it allows other programmes to overtake
that memory and other variables to override that memory.
So if nothing points to a node,
that is essentially the same as deleting it,
because Python takes care of that for you.
With that said,
if we wanted to delete this node three,
now you know all you have to do is make node five
not point to it.
If instead of three,
we point to none,
then three is deleted.
Three would still be here somewhere,
but Python would be aware that you're not using it
and it would eventually erase it from memory
or it would be overwritten by something else.
So that's how you delete a node
that has no children itself.
Notice how three has no left and no right.
When a node has no left and no right,
all you have to do is set the parent
to not point to it anymore.
Let's say you want to delete node number 5 here
which does have a child.
Five points to three.
If you now say six doesn't point to five,
what you've done is you've deleted five and three.
You've deleted the entire branch here.
That may not be what you want.
If you want to delete node five only,
knowing that it has only one child,
all you have to do is delete five
and make six point to three.
Essentially skip over five.
The way to do that is just make six point to three
straight away like this.
Nothing points to five now.
Six doesn't point to five.
Three doesn't point to five,
even though five points to three.
Nothing points to three
and if you don't have a variable for this node,
it would get erased from memory as well.
So when you want to delete a node that has one child,
all you have to do is point the parent over to the child
and then nothing points to the initial parent five.
Those two are the easy scenarios in a tree deletion.
When you have no children,
very easy,
just point and none.
When you have one child,
very easy,
just get the parent to point to the child instead
of the node.
But when you want to delete a node that has two children,
then it becomes a bit more complicated.
Here's why.
When you want to delete five,
all you do is make six point to the child.
If you want to delete nine,
maybe you'd think,
"Hey, just make six point to the child, right?"
"That'll do it."
It doesn't quite work that way.
Imagine you decide to make six point to seven.
Now six points to seven,
seven points to eight,
but nothing points to all of this,
so you delete nine,
twelve and eleven in it's entirety
'cause nothing points to nine,
so Python removes it.
Nothing points to 12,
if nine's deleted,
so Python removes that.
Then nothing points to 11,
Not great.
It would be nice if you could delete nine
and put seven in here.
But then you'd have to delete this
make seven point to eight and this doesn't work,
because now eight is on the left
and eight cannot be on the left of seven
because that would be strange, right?
Eight is bigger than seven so it should be at the right,
but 12 is also bigger than seven,
so it should also be at the right,
so now seven ends up with two right nodes,
which you cannot have.
So how do we do this?
Nine has two children,
which we're gonna call two sub-branches.
We've got our left branch here
and a right branch here.
We said we can't put seven here because then,
what do we do with the eight?
But we can put eight here
and delete that.
This is okay.
Now seven is smaller than eight
and it stays at the left,
12 is bigger than eight and it stays at the right,
so this is fine.
Similarly we can put 11 here,
this child,
and delete 11 from here.
Seven is smaller than 11,
so this is fine,
and 12 is bigger than 11,
so this is fine.
Okay?
So what am I doing?
What I'm doing is in the left branch,
you can pick the node that is most to the right.
In this branch,
the right most node is eight.
You know that's gonna be the biggest node in this branch.
The biggest node in the branch is always gonna be bigger
than this one,
because in this branch the biggest node is eight,
therefore eight has to be bigger than seven,
and not only that,
but you know that the biggest node in this branch
is always going to be smaller than this node.
Why?
Because if this node was bigger than this one,
it would end up here.
So when you're deleting a node with two children,
you can just replace the node by the largest node
in the left branch.
Or by the smallest node in the right branch.
The left most node in the right branch.
Those are the two options.
Either the largest node in the left branch
or the smallest node in the right branch.
That gives you one node that is closest to this one.
Then you can replace it,
essentially put eight here,
and delete this one.
What we're doing there is just saying
this is the one we want to delete
so the parent is now going to point
to the right most node in the left sub branch.
So the parent's going to point to the right most node
in the left sub branch.
This node's parent is gonna point to none,
already deleted,
and the eight node is going to point to this
and this;
the children of the original node you wanted to delete.
Programming that is not so simple,
let me tell you that.
There is quite a lot of code that we have to write
in order to get that deletion working.
I just wanted you to be aware of these difficulties
as we start in the next video coding these deletions.
Okay?
Thanks for joining me.
I'll see you on the next video.