Hi guys and welcome back.
Thank you for joining me in this section.
I hope you've learned something and I hope you will be
testing your applications as you go along.
Remember you can use this testing knowledge
everywhere else in the course.
So if you've got already some Python code
you can write some tests for it to learn more.
Also, the official documentation while a bit lengthy
and can be a bit confusing is really good.
So I would recommend reading it.
Finally, just some parting words.
Try to write simple code.
It's often much easier to over-complicate code
than to write simple code, but simple code is much simpler
to test and much simpler to maintain longer term,
especially if you're working in a team with other people,
focusing on writing clean, simple code
will really help you, especially if you're wanting
to take that next step in your career.
Thanks for joining me in this section.
I'll see you next time.