Hi and welcome back.
In this video we're going to be adding
a little bit of error handling to our app,
just so we can deal with any eventualities that may happen.
We're gonna come here
and we're gonna surround everything in here
by a try/except block.
Okay.
And the first section is gonna be
InvalidTagforAuthorError as e
and it's just gonna print the error message
and then we're gonna have a more generic exception.
And we're gonna say something like,
"An unknown error occurred.
"Please try again."
So this double except,
I'm not sure we've looked at it before,
but what happens is if an exception is raised
in this block here and it is an InvalidTagForAuthorError,
then it's gonna run this.
If it's not that, then it is gonna run this
because Exception is the base class for every exception.
But you can have many of these
and then they get less and less specific.
We also do need to import our error there of course.
So now if we run our app and we say we want Bob Marley
and then we want something like magic.
What you'll get is Chrome will launch,
Bob Marley will be selected
and then you'll get your message here,
"Author Bob Marley does not have any question"
Any question?
Why question?
I'm not sure why I typed question there.
Does not have any quotes.
I'm not sure why I decided to type question there
but that's no problem.
We fixed it and we've added our error handling
there as well.
That's it for this video.
Thank you for joining me.
I'll see you in the next one.