Hi guys and welcome back.
In this video we're quickly going
to talk about two different types of wait.
You've got explicit waits and implicit waits.
We're going to be using these
when JavaScript is taking longer to run than our code,
and that would mean that
our code would be faster than the JavaScript
and that can cause a series of issues.
For example, if the JavaScript is responsible
for changing an element on the page
and your code tries to access that element
before the JavaScript runs then you're gonna have a problem
because the element's not gonna be there.
That sort of stuff is the,
on occasions when you wanna use waits.
An explicit wait, as you can see here,
is very straightforward.
You import the time module from Python,
that's a built-in you don't need to instal it,
and you do time.sleep,
and that's gonna sleep for five seconds.
You can use this in Selenium,
you can use it anywhere else in your Python code,
and it can be quite helpful but it's also a bit limited
because if the element appears after one second
then you've got four seconds of waste
and if the element appears after ten seconds
then this is not enough.
And sometimes JavaScript takes longer to run,
other times it takes less time to run
so it's not ideal to do something like this.
The other option for explicit waits is
to do something like this.
I know the code looks a bit complicated,
we've not seen it before but don't worry too much.
To do an explicit wait you need to import three things.
You need to import By,
you need to import expected_conditions and WebDriverWait.
Then what you do is you use WebDriverWait,
you give it the browser that you wanna use
and how long to wait up to.
So this code here is going to wait up to 10 seconds,
unless the condition that we say happens.
So when the condition happens the wait ends.
So this is essentially a wait until but it can end early.
The condition is,
expected_conditions.presence_of_element_located.
And this is a way of telling Selenium
to wait until an element exists in the page.
The element doesn't have to be visible,
it just has to be there in the page.
So these two lines of code are telling the browser
to wait up to 10 seconds,
unless an element appears on the page.
And the element that has to appear on the page
is the final line here line seven which is this tuple.
A tuple of selector type and selector.
Up 'til now we've been using CSS selectors as our selectors,
but for the expected conditions module,
you have to give it the selector type.
So that means we give it a tuple that says
By.CSS_SELECTOR and the locator.
Here's how you use the By class.
Up 'til now we've been using something like line three,
TAG_DROPDOWN equal select#tag.
That means we wanna access a select element in the HTML
and the ID of the element is tag.
Then when we run code like in line number eight,
we do self.browser.find_element_by_css_selector
and we pass in that stream.
However, you can do find element instead,
only that you have to pass it
what type of selector you wanna use.
So here we're gonna do self.browser.find_element
and we pass in By.CSS_SELECTOR
and then the string as the second argument.
That means that we can then use other types of selectors
if we want.
So here's how you could do that if you wanted to organise
your selectors in this way.
Imagine you've got a selector like in line number four
that says By.ID, "tag".
Now this is how we define a tuple in Python,
so JUST_ID is a tuple of two values,
By.ID and tag.
And here's how you can use them.
You can do something like line 11,
self.browser.find_element_by_id
and you can pass in the string directly.
In that cause you would not need
to define just ID as a tuple,
you could just define it as the ID.
You could do something like line number 12,
which is self.browser.find_element
and then you pass By.ID and the string.
And finally, and this is actually
my preferred way of doing things in Selenium,
is to do something like line 13.
You define your locators as in line four,
and then you do like in line 13 self.browser.find_element,
and you pass in the two values of selector as arguments,
and that's why we use the asterisk.
This is essentially argument unpacking.
So we say asterisk JUST_ID and that passes By.ID and tag
as the two values as the two arguments
to the find element method.
And what that allows you to do is to very easily
and very concisely define your selectors
while also being explicit in what they are for
so you don't have to assume that they're all CSS selectors.
You can use say By CSS selector and then they tag dropdown
or By.ID and then the tag.
In our project we've not done this
because I felt it added a little bit of complexity,
but nonetheless it is my preferred way when
I'm working on a larger project.
So other things you can use with the By class,
you can do By ID, XPATH, LINK_TEXT
so you can actually search for links,
you can do PARTIAL_LINK_TEXT, you can do NAME,
TAG_NAME, CLASS_NAME and CSS_SELECTOR.
So more information on all this
is linked in the resources section of the lecture
so feel free to take a look at the official documentation
that I've put in there if you want more information on this.
Finally we've got implicit waits.
An implicit wait is defined at the very start of
your Selenium code.
So just after you create your ChromeDriver or your browser,
you can say driver.implicitly_wait and then a number.
And what this does is whenever
you try to find an element and it's not there,
the browser will wait up to 10 seconds in this case
by checking continuously until the element appears.
I do not recommend doing this,
although it's much simpler it's kinda obscure,
and then when you're looking at your code it's not clear
that it's gonna wait up to 10 seconds every time.
And also it can hide problems.
If your code is always waiting 10 seconds for everything,
it probably means something's wrong with your application.
So usually you want to avoid implicit waits.
However, they do exist,
they are in the official documentation,
you can use them and you should probably know about them if
you want to apply for a Selenium-based job.
Thanks for joining me in this video,
let's jump into the code,
so I'll see you in the next one.