Hi and welcome back,
in the last video, I said we were going
to look at the pages,
but I actually think it makes more sense
to look at the quote parser first.
So what I've done is I've opened here
the quote parser and what we're going to do,
is first of all, import our quote locators.
And then we're going to create class QuoteParser,
and this class is going to be used to,
given one of the specific quote divs,
find out the data about the quote.
Quote content, author, and tags.
Now, this is going to make use of a new thing,
in Beautiful Soup that we've not looked at before,
but nonetheless, that's the purpose of this project,
to introduce things, and that is that,
what we're gonna receive here in the init method,
a parent, and then we're gonna say self.parent equal parent.
Just to explain why I'm calling this parameter parent, here.
Going back to Chrome, what we're going to give
our quote parser is this div tag.
So that's going to be our first quote parser.
We're gonna give it this div tag.
And our second quote parser,
we're gonna give it this div tag.
And the third quote parser, we'll give it this div tag.
Previously with Beautiful Soup,
we looked at loading using Beautiful Soup the entire page.
And then we were able to search
on the entire page using Beautiful Soup.
But actually, when you find one element with Beautiful Soup
such as say, you find this div using Beautiful Soup,
you can then search only in that element.
So what we're going to do is, our quotes page
is going to find these elements and is going to give
each element to a quote parser object,
and they are going to use that element to find the children.
In this case, the children of this element will be
the quote contents, the author, and the tags.
Let's go back to PyCharm and quickly write these
property methods here.
The quote content is going to return,
well, it's going to get a locator that's going to be
quotelocators.content and it's going to return
self.parent select one, locator.string.
Notice how self.parent is going to be that div tag,
that encloses the quote, but Beautiful Soup allows us
to select and search for within the parent.
It doesn't have to be only on the page itself,
it can be on any of the elements.
Okay, then for the author,
it's going to be fairly similar.
The locator in this case is going to be the author locator,
and then it's going to return self.parent, select one,
locator.string, so very similar.
And finally, the tags.
Tags, the locator's going to be quotelocators.tags
and it's going to return self.parent.select(locator).
Again, this is going to select all the individual
tag items that are available.
If you wanted, you could extract the text of each element
by doing e.string for e and this.
So this would be definitely an option as well, okay?
Now, this doesn't make a lot of sense until we have
sort of joined our programme together and it all
starts to make a bit more sense, believe me.
I'm also going to add here a rapr method that is going to
return this quote, self.content by self.author, okay?
This is just so that when we run our application
we can print these quote parser objects out,
and it may make a bit more sense.
So far, what we will receive is a Beautiful Soup tag
that is the div that contains this quote.
Within that div, there will only be one locator
for the content, one for the author, and one for the tags.
So we're not going to be able to get mixed up between
different quotes at this level okay?
Now, let's go over to the quotes page
and we can begin sort of joining the programme together
and it'll start to make a bit more sense.
I'll see you in the very next video.