Hi, and welcome back.
In this video, we're talking about extracting data
from our tables using the Select statement.
In this table, we've got four columns, id, name,
and address, and four rows going from one to four.
When we want to use a Select statement,
we have to specify three important things.
The first one that we want to actually select data
and not insert it, for example.
The second one, we have to say what columns we want to get
in our results,
whether it's the id column, the name column,
or the address column, or all of them,
or any combination of them.
And finally, we also have to say what table
we want to get our data from.
In this case, let's get it from this table here
which I'm going to call people.
So this would be a Select statement.
First the Select keyword,
then a star which means all columns, then the keyword from,
and then the table that we want to select from.
So this means select all the columns from people.
And it would give us a result set that looks exactly
like the original table.
As you can see, it looks the same, three columns,
four rows, all the data is there.
Notice how we've not had to specify what rows we want.
We're only specifying that we want all the columns.
That's what the star means.
By default, the Select statement will select
all of the rows.
So, all of the data in your table.
And we are going to learn how to limit that,
how to get only some rows very soon,
in a couple of video's time.
Let's have a look at another example where we won't select
all of the columns, we'll just select a couple of them.
And, this would be this.
Select name, address from people.
And that's of course, going to give us two columns,
name and the address.
Notice how the id column is not present in our result set
because we've not requested it with the Select statement.
Of course, we could select id and name if we wanted
for example, and that would give us again, two columns,
id and name and it wouldn't give us back the address.
Totally fine, you can do this if you want.
Notice how the general formula here,
the structure or the syntax of the statement
is first of all, Select.
Then, the columns you want, whether it's a star
or whether it's a comma separated column names.
Then the keyword from, and finally, the table.
You can also merge them together so you can
select id, star if you want.
But this is a pretty silly thing to do in my opinion.
I'm just telling you this because you can do this.
But again, you get double the id columns,
which is not very useful in most scenarios,
probably any scenario.
But none the less, it's something you can do.
Again, the star just gets replaced by
all of the column names in your table.
So of course, you can use a star as well as
other column names if you want.
And this is gonna come in handy.
The fact that we can do this
is gonna come in handy later on.
Doing this with single table is not so handy.
Okay, that's it for this video.
I'll see you in the next one.