Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to look at running
multiple threads at once and sharing
some state between them.
Okay, so I've cleared the new file, which I've called
nonlockedthreads.py, but before we start writing some code,
I just wanted to sort of tell you about something.
And that is, what is an atomic operation?
Atomic operations are very important
when you're doing multi threaded codes.
An atomic operation is one that cannot be interrupted
in the middle of it.
So you cannot interrupt an atomic operation
halfway through it by changing to a new thread, okay?
Whenever you're doing an atomic operation
you know that it's going to finish before you can
unplug the thread from the core and put another one in.
For example, a print statement cannot print
only half the line and then be interrupted.
Similarly, appending to a deque or a dq if you're like me
and you like saying that, appending to a deque
cannot be interrupted halfway through.
If you start appending to a deque, you say,
you know, deque.append, you know that the thing will
appended to the deque before you remove
the thread from the core, okay?
So atomic operations are very important
when you have this shared state between threads.
And we're gonna look at an example of where we're gonna
have a function that's not atomic
and why that poses a problem.
Okay, so let's do that.
I'm going to do, from threading import threads,
I'm going to use good old threads instead of the
thread pull executor, just for this,
I think it's gonna be a bit easier to see what's going on.
We're gonna import time and we're also gonna import random
because we're gonna be randomising some things.
Then, we're going to have a global variable in our file,
which is going to be zero, okay?
And then we're gonna have a function
called increment counter.
And what this is going to do, is it's gonna say,
global counter, access the global variable counter,
do counter plus equal one,
and then print new counter value is counter.
And then it's also going to print a few lines
just so we can separate new counter values,
from one before the other.
Now, from what we know about single threaded code,
if we do for x in range 10,
and then we do increment counter,
what do we think is going to happen?
Hopefully you said, you know, what I would expect
is that you start up here, x will be zero, you know,
it's gonna run 10 times.
The first time you're gonna go into increment counter,
you're gonna access global counter, which is gonna be zero.
You're gonna increase it by one, so it's gonna be one.
You're gonna print out new counter value is one.
You're gonna print out these lines.
Then, you're gonna go back to the end of the function,
you're gonna repeat you're loop, gonna go in here again,
counter's gonna be one now, because it was increased before.
Then you're gonna increase it by one going up to two.
You're gonna print new counter value is two,
and so forth, for three, four, five, six,
seven, eight and so forth.
So let's run this non locked threads,
which is not using threads at all,
and you can see that that is indeed what happens.
You get one all the way down to 10, so good stuff.
This is what we would expect.
Now, what happens if we make a thread,
we're saying t equals thread,
and the target is increment counter?
And then we're going to remove this increment counter,
then we're going to do t.start.
What do we think is gonna happen when we run this?
Let me tell you that we're not gonna see any difference.
Okay, we get one, two, three, four, five, six, seven
all the way up to 10.
Hm, okay, so, what was the purpose of threads
and are they running at the same time?
Using, writing multithreaded code is dangerous,
because you may not see the problem straight away.
The problem may only appear under some circumstances.
Here is where time and random are gonna come in.
What we've got here is,
10 times we're gonna repeat this block of code.
We're gonna create a new thread.
The target is gonna be increment counter.
And then we're gonna start thread,
and then immediately we're gonna move over
to the next thread and we're gonna start it,
but this function is so quick to run that
before we get to start the new thread,
that function is already finished running.
So essentially, this is sequential code.
Essentially, it's single threaded code.
Because you create a new thread, you started,
by the time you created a new thread,
that one's already finished,
so essentially it's happening one after the other.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna do time sleep
random.random, okay?
We're gonna put some time sleeps in here,
essentially between each line, like that.
This technique of adding random sleeps between statements
when you're doing multithreaded codes is called fuzzying,
its very popular, because it's gonna let us see problems.
Okay, let's run this file again.
Ooh, that's not looking so good now.
So as you can see, what happened here now
is that all our threads were running at the same time,
because, you know, one of them started
then it encountered this random sleep
but by that time another one had maybe started
and encountered another random sleep.
You've got a few of them starting, you know,
some of them are here, some of them are here,
and what happens is, you've got a couple threads
getting the counter value at three and increasing it by one,
both at the same time, okay?
So you've got two threads coming into the global counter.
Two threads are stopped here, the counter is three.
Then, they both increment counter by one at the same time.
So it ends up as four.
And then they both print out new counter values four, okay?
So multithreaded code with shared state
can be really tricky to get right,
because two threads can try to access the same thing
at the same time, and you know that's fine,
you can access the same thing at the same time,
but you may not end up with what you'd expect.
Particularly if all the threads are changing something
in this variable at the same time.
And you may not see that unless you do this fizzying
technique or you know, other techniques.
So what we've got here are all our threads running,
you know, they're messed up, essentially.
We cannot proceed with this,
and if you remove the fizzying it would work,
until you know, your computer is running slowly
or you've got a bunch of things running at the same time
on your computer and these threads are jumping
in and out of course very quickly.
Then you may start encountering problems like this one.
So, you must be careful when you write multithreaded code.
You must be very careful.
Especially if you threads are,
really only if your threads are
accessing or modifying shared state.
Here the variable is the shared state,
these threads have half that variable shared amongst them.
Dangerous stuff, okay?
This code, by the way, and also the code that follows
is taken from a talk that one of the python developers,
the creators of the python language made.
I'm going to link you to this talk
at the end of this section, it's really good.
I just want to guide you through it first in my words,
just to help you understand it,
and then you can go and watch their talk later on.
Okay, if we wanted to make sure the operations happen
sequentially, like we want to do
new counter value is one,
then new counter value is two, three.
Then we would have to do something much more complicated.
But again, if you want to make sure the operations
happen sequentially, don't use threads.
That's the first thing.
If you want to make sure the operations happen sequentially
but you want to use threads,
then you have to set up a queuing system,
where each thread can perform the operation
of incrementing the counter but they happen one by one.
So it's going to be more complicated code,
let's go over it in the very next video,
how you may do queuing with a thread so that
the operations happen sequentially.
I'll see you in the next video.