Hi, and welcome back!
In this video, we're talking
about reraising errors
and the on success block.
As you can see, I've written some code here.
That's just because I didn't want to
bore you going through, writing all of this code,
especially because it's only example code.
This code is also available
in the code lecture on GitHub,
and that lecture is at the start of this section.
So, if you've not yet downloaded or had a look
at the code for this section,
you can go to the first lecture of the section
and go to the GitHub link that's there
and you can see this code.
The resource that's attached to this lecture
contains an explanation
for some reasonably related sample code as well,
but it's not exactly the same thing.
Just because the resource attached this lecture
has some explanations
and it uses some pseudo-code
to explain some concepts.
The code that I'm seeing here on my screen,
the code that you're seeing on your screen,
is on the GitHub.
So, feel free to download it and have a look
if you want.
Now, what we've got
is a user class, nothing new here,
it's got an init method that takes in a name
and our property "engagement,"
our variable "engagement,"
and then sets the name to be "name,"
and the "engagement metrics" to be
the "engagement" property there.
Then there's also got a dunder wrapper function
that returns the user's name
in a nicely formatted string.
This User class is going to be used
by this "get_user_score" function,
that takes in a "user" parameter.
This is going to try to return whatever the
"perform_calculation" function gives us,
with the engagement metrics
of the user passed in,
and if it fails, it's going to print out
"Incorrect values provided," with a KeyError.
"Perform_calculation" takes in the user's
"engagement_metrics" as a parameter,
there as an argument,
and returns the "clicks" property
of that "metrics," multiply by five,
and the "hits" multiplied by two.
So, imagine this is a user
that's visiting a website,
and we want to calculate their score
for, to see how engaged they are with our brand.
If the "clicks" multiplied by five
and the "metrics,"
the "hits" multiplied by two
gives us a particular value,
we're gonna say, you know,
this person is very engaged.
We've also got down here
another function called
"send_engagement_notification,"
and this would send them an email saying
"Thank you for being so engaged with our brand,
here's a coupon code
for you to download or something."
Of course, this doesn't actually send any emails
right now, but we could do that,
and we'll look at sending emails
later on in the course.
Then, at the very bottom, we're creating
a user, Rolf is the name,
and these are the engagement metrics.
He's done 61 clicks and 100 hits.
And then we're going to call the
"get_user_score" function here for my user.
So this is the sample code we've got,
not too much code, I hope,
fairly understandable I hope.
It can sometimes be handy to do something
with an exception,
handle it, like we do here.
But then it can also be useful to not silence it.
IE, keep letting it bubble up
and eventually crash your programme
so you know that you've done something wrong
at some point.
For example, the exception here,
"KeyError" is caught,
and if we were to mess up
and create our users with a
"click" key instead of "clicks,"
this is going to fail with a KeyError
because "clicks" won't be a key
of our "metrics" dictionary that is down here.
So, let's run user_score.
Remember, right click it and run it.
And you'll see that we get:
"Incorrect values provided
to our calculation function."
And we get that because, of course,
the KeyError was raised
and we then printed this out
and nothing else happened.
If we are not paying attention, we may miss that.
Let's face it,
if-- this is the only line
of output in our programme right now,
but if this was a long programme,
there may be many lines of output
and you may miss that one
amongst all the other ones.
So, the best thing to do,
at least while you're developing,
is to allow the errors to continue bubbling up
and crash your programme.
When you're going to give your programme
to your users,
make sure that your programme
doesn't crash too easily.
And that may mean catching the error somewhere,
or not allowing it to continue bubbling up.
The way we allow it to bubble up,
is we just type "raise."
And that has to be inside the "except" block.
So, inside the "except" block, we can "raise,"
and what that does is,
that reraises the error
that got us into this block in the first place.
So, if we press play again,
you'll see that now we get our traceback
after we get our print.
The traceback now says KeyError: 'clicks'
and that was used here, in "metrics,"
"clicks" I multiply by five, and so forth.
This was inside the
"perform_calculation" function,
as you can see here,
and this was called up here
as you can see in this line.
This was inside the "get_user_score" function,
as you can see here,
and that was called here,
which is down here, line 27,
and that is in your module,
which is your file that you're running.
So it's the file that you're running.
Okay, this is, again, the stack trace,
you need to get good at understanding
and following the stack trace,
that's a really important skill.
So, the "raise" keyword here
must go inside the except block,
otherwise you cannot use raise on its own.
You have to give it the error you want to raise.
But that's only if you use it
outside the except block.
If you use it inside the except block,
you can just type "raise"
and it will reraise the error
that got you here in the first place.
Okay, now let's say that we want to
send an engagement notification to this user,
if we
got some
limits of clicks or something.
Let's say, that if the user's score is
over 500,
we want to send them a notification.
We only want to send the notification,
and by the way, I'm gonna remove this
raise thing here for now,
we only want to send the notification if
we didn't raise an error,
of course.
We only want to send the notification
if the perform_calculation succeeded
and we got a correct score.
So, how may we do that?
Well, we've seen the "finally" block.
We can say "send_engagement_notification"
to "user,"
but the "finally" block runs
no matter what.
The "try" is gonna run,
the "except" may or may not run,
and the "finally" will run.
So, "finally" is always going to run
after the try except block no matter what,
unless, of course, you reraise the exception
and your programme crashes.
If you do that, the "finally" won't run either.
But, let's assume we don't want to
reraise the exception, but we want
the engagement notification to send
if our user does have the correct score.
Well, we can use an "else," actually.
And that's a pretty bizarre thing to use here,
because what it means
is that we're going to
try to run this thing here,
and if there is no error,
we are then going to go to the "else."
So this "else" is only going to run
if an error does not happen,
unlike the "finally," which runs every time.
Of course it's telling us
this code is unreachable,
because if this code succeeds,
we are returning
which means we're exiting the function,
so this is never going to run.
Either we will have this error,
in which case this won't run,
or we will have this return,
in which case this won't run.
So we just have to remove the return there.
And if we did want to perform a calculation here
and just return that value,
and then we should do that
and we should not use this construct.
Instead this should go down here.
Right.
So, this function maybe should be renamed
to something else other than "get_user_score,"
if we want it to do this.
Okay.
Maybe it should be
"email_engaged_users"
or "_user"
something like that.
Okay, so I just wanted to show you this construct
because it's not a popular thing
and not a lot of Python developers know about it,
and indeed if you go on the Internet
and look at tutorials for try except in Python,
I guarantee that almost none of them
will mention this "else."
And it's not that used,
but it's interesting to know about it
just in case you wanna run something
only if an error doesn't occur,
like send an email notification.
We will be using this later on in the course.
So that's it for this video,
we've looked at the on success block,
that's this one here,
because this happens when we succeed
in our try except.
And we've also looked at reraising exceptions,
which is very simple,
just put a "raise" inside the "except" block,
and if our exception does happen,
we will raise it again.
So, by the way, I changed the "clicks,"
the "click" back to "clicks,"
so now we should be able to run this.
And, of course, I've also renamed the function,
so let's
make sure that we're calling the right function.
We should be able to run it
and...
Oh, this one here.
Sorry, I can change it.
Now we see that the notification was sent
to user Rolf,
because we performed the calculation,
and then we send the engagement notification
and if we wanted, of course, to check
that the user score is correct,
we could do something like
user.score is that,
and then, if user.score is greater than 500,
send the notification.
Now, we've said that user.score here
is equal to something,
but user.score was not defined
in the init method.
This is a bad practise.
You should generally define all the properties
in the init method,
just so you know what exists.
So you can define the score as a zero in here,
and then this is not creating a new property.
Although you can, it's not advised.
And now this is just updating it,
which is better.
Now we can see that a notification was sent
to the user Rolf,
because their score is greater than 500.
Indeed, 61 times five, plus 100 times two
is 502.
I think.
I'm pretty sure.
Let's not say it is any number,
it is greater than 500.
That's what I know,
so that's why we're sending a notification there.
Anyway, that's it for this video,
I won't keep you any longer.
This was a try, except, else
and how to reraise exceptions as well.
I'll see you on the next one.