Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be adding select
statements to our milestone project.
First of all, let's remember to delete this milestone
or books file, here because we don't need it any longer.
Just to make sure that it gives us an error
when we try to use it, we're not misusing it anywhere.
Then let's go down to our get all books function.
And notice how now, it's giving us two errors.
Trying to open the books file that no longer exists
and it shouldn't, because we don't want to use it.
And also it's using the json module, which it shouldn't.
Because again, we're no longer using json.
We want to retrieve all the books
from our database and from our table.
You know how to do all of this,
except for actually getting the books back.
So, you know how to set up the connection, get a cursor,
execute the the query that will
select all our books, commit, and close.
I'd encourage you to give this a go, now.
Just implement as much as you know about this function
and then we'll explain exactly what
we're missing and how it works.
I hope you got that.
All we have to do, is, of course,
first of all, open a connection
Make sure to use the same date file as before
so that all of these connections go to the same file.
Get a cursor,
then execute our query, which is going
to be select, start from books.
And that's going to give us the name,
the author and the read status.
Then we can commit, but of course
we've not actually written anything to our database.
We've just read something from it.
So there's nothing to save to the disc.
Therefore, we don't need to commit in this case.
We can just go straight to connection dot close.
Now, we've not saved the output of this to any variable.
So, as soon as we close the connection of course,
this is going to get lost, we're not
going to have access to our books.
And here is the exciting part,
or the interesting part about cursors.
Remember when I explained about cursors
that they are a pointer.
When you make a select statement that starts at the very top
of your table, and then moves over to the next row when you
ask for the next row, and then go to the following one and
so forth, until you get to the end of the table.
Well, now that we've executed the query with a select,
the cursor is at the top of the results returned,
and we want to go down one by one in all of the rows
until we reach the end of the table
so that we get all of our rows back.
The way we do that, is we say for example, books
which is now our variable of books is cursor dot
and notice how there are a few fetch methods in here.
You've got fetchall, and that's
going to give you all of the rows.
Fetchmany, and that is an argument here,
which is how many rows you want to fetch.
And fetchone, which gives you the top row
of your table of your results set only.
So we're going to go for fetchall.
And remember that our results are going to be the entire
table, because we've selected star from books,
which gives us all the columns, and we've not limited
any number of rows, we don't know how to do that yet.
We're gonna learn in a moment.
So this is going to give us the entire table, cursor dot.
Fetchall is going to give us all of the rows.
If you wanted just one book, you could just fetchone,
but that's just going to give you
the top most book in your table.
Now, this, and when you do fetchall,
is going to give you essentially a list of topalls.
Each topall is going to have a name, author, read status
and then name, author, read status, and so forth.
So when you do fetchall, you essentially get this list here.
So we can return that, and then make a programme access
the zeroth element of a topall, the first element
of a topall, the second element of a topall,
or we could convert these topalls that we are receiving,
we're just going to bring them back actually.
Convert these topalls we're receiving into dictionaries,
so that the rest of our programme can still use them
as it would normally, and I think this is the best
thing to do, just make sure we are
using consistent data structures.
So again, what to do, is fetch them all,
but, put this in a list comprehension.
And then what we're going to do in this list comprehension,
is put in a dictionary of name.
It's going to be row zero.
Notice how that's going to be the first element of the row.
Author is going to be row one,
and read is going to be row two.
And I know that things are disappearing
off the side of the screen, so let's just bring them back.
I'm just going to delete this now.
And now notice how we have a list comprehension that puts
a dictionary as the first value here of our list
comprehension into this new list
where row is each of the elements in cursor dot fetchall.
Notice that each of the elements is a topall,
so we access row zero as the name,
row one as the author, and row two as the read status.
Hopefully this makes sense, as we do this, we'll end with a
dictionary with a list of dictionaries,
where each dictionary represents our book.
Then at the end, after we close the connection,
we can return books, and that's the list here.
Now our app dot PUI, which was using book name, book read
and book author, doesn't have to change at all because
it's still using the dictionary in the background.
Even though our database does not return dictionaries,
the interphase that we've designed here has kept things
consistent so that our business logic,
our app dot PUI, doesn't have to change.
And that's a really good thing to do.
Now that we've selected all of the books, we can go and
look at the next thing, which is figuring
for specific books using the where statement.
Let's look at that in the next video.