Hi, welcome back.
In this video, we're looking at update and delete.
I wanted to talk about this briefly
before going into filtering
just so you know why filtering is so important.
Let's say we've got this table here of our people,
and we want to do an update.
This is a good old normal update statement.
We do update and the table name that we want to update,
and then we say set and we give the column
and the value we want to end up with.
So here we're going to essentially update the people table,
setting the name column to be equal to Jose.
I hope you realise what this is going to do,
but if you don't, that's totally okay.
We're not telling it to update any given row.
We've just said update the whole table
and set the name column to Jose.
So, of course, it's going to do just that.
Notice how in our results,
all the rows now have a name Jose.
It's a good name, but you probably don't want to change
all your customers or all your people in your table
to have this name.
It would get a bit boring, so this is not a good thing.
What we've done here is we've said update the people table
and set the name to something,
but, of course, we've not told it
what we want to update specifically
so it's just gone and done everything.
Here's another example: delete from people.
This is a delete statement, allows us to delete a row,
or multiple rows in this case,
and again we've not told it what to delete so, of course,
it's all going to go,
and we'll end up with an empty table.
This is why we need filtering.
We need to be able to say delete from people
but only these specific rows.
Otherwise, we'll end up with everything deleted,
and, trust me, you don't want to do this.
This happens a lot, it happens to everyone eventually,
that you forget to put in a filtering statement in there,
and it is a dangerous thing to do,
so you don't want to do this.
Let's look in the very next video
at how to use filtering to make sure
that this problem doesn't happen.
I'll see you there.