Hi and welcome back,
let's review our quotes project in this video.
Instead of starting from the quote parser
let's start from the top of the project now.
The first thing we do, is aside from importing things
we get the page content,
this is the entire HTML content
of the entire QuotesPage
We then give that content to our QuotesPage constructor,
the in its method, so let's go over there,
that then initialises this BeautifulSoup object,
using the HTML parser
so this lets us search within this page.
The quotes property of that finds a locator
which is this QuotesPageLocators dot Quote
which is just div dot quote, okay.
Then it selects all the instances
of that selector so every div that has a quote class
will be selected by this,
and if we go back to Chrome we can see
that the divs that have a class quote
are all the individual quotes.
And it's gonna return a QuoteParser
given each of those tags
for e in the tags that we found.
Remember the tags that we found there
are not strings, they are BeautifulSoup tags,
so if we go into the quote parser,
this parent will be a BeautifulSoup tag
which is that div.
In BeautifulSoup, everything is a tag,
so when you load the entire HTML page,
that's a tag that you can search on,
that's an HTML tag.
When you load one of these parents
when you find one of these divs,
that's just another tag, in this case,
it's a div tag that you can search on as well.
So now this quote parser has one of these divs
and in their properties here we are searching
under this parent only and we're searching for
the span dot text, the small dot author,
and the different tags.
In addition, this quote parser also has a repr method
that allows us to print it out nicely,
but of course we can choose to print out
specific properties if we choose.
So hopefully this makes sense,
the way this app is structured
is to separate concerns,
separate the locators away from your logic,
and also separate the page from its components.
In this case, we're separating the quotes page
from an individual quote.
Even though they're both sort of similar,
I don't like calling a quote a page
because really it's a component within a page.
If you separate your scrapers in this way,
I am confident you're going to be able
to do anything you want with your scraping project.
Just because doing this is going
to make them so much simpler
to work with and as soon as you want to add a new page,
all you have to do is add a new file here
and a new set of locators.
If your locators change for any page,
you just go there and modify them,
and if you want to add a new component that you want
to get data out of from a page,
just have a new parser for it.
Now we're going to build another project as well
in this section, looking at scraping books
and that's gonna be a larger project with a bit more sort
of logging and changing pages and things like that
so it's gonna be a bit longer,
so don't worry too much if not everything is crystal clear,
we're gonna do this again
and we're gonna do more in the books project.
So I'll see you in the very next video.