Hi, welcome back.
We've just looked at some regular expression examples.
We've not going very in depth,
but as we progress through the section,
we're going to learn a little bit more about it.
And as we do more Python
and we encounter more uses for regular expressions,
we're going to learn some more.
Regular expressions is one of those things,
that you use it, you learn about it
and then you just don't find any use for it for a while,
and then you just sort of forget,
and then you have to go back
and learn it again.
So it's not that great if I just spend a few hours
to show you all there is to know about regular expressions.
I think you'll forget quickly,
I don't think it'll bring you that much benefit.
When you want to use regular expressions within Python,
you can do that.
You can import the RE module.
RE stands for regular expressions,
and it comes with Python,
and it lets you test an expression against some text.
That's essentially what we did in the last video.
So this will be our text, it'll be an email
and this will be our expression that we are testing,
A to Z plus.
What is this going to match?
The A to Z plus would match the Jose,
it would match the tecladocode,
and it will match the com
because there are three separate words in here
and the a to z plus, what it's measuring is
or what it's testing is any letter,
at least one
and as many as possible.
Okay?
So what we'll do is we'll say matches
is re.findall
expression on email.
What that's going to do is going to take this expression,
and it's going to try to find all the instances
in which it occurs, so it's going to find three.
Jose, tecladocode
and com.
Okay?
Let's print out the matches,
then we're gonna say a couple of things here.
Let's run it first.
Notice how our matches are now turned into a list
of Jose, tecladocode
and com.
So that's all the matches that we've found
in this expression here.
So that's pretty cool.
As we can see, the name is matches zero, that's my name
and the domain tecladocode.com
could be made of matches one dot matches two,
like so.
So that's tecladocode, that's the dot
and that's the com.
So in total we make up tecladocode.com,
but of course this is wrong because it has to be like that.
My bad, it has to be like that.
So, then we can print the name, we can print the domain.
Let's run that.
And you'll see that this all seems fine.
We've got Jose
and we've got tecladocode.com.
Now a better way of extracting the name
and the domain
would be to modify this expression
in order to make it A to Z
and include the dot,
because now there are two matches.
Jose, because that matches four characters in this range,
so you've got A to Z or the dot,
and you've got four, or one or more of those
and you have four characters,
and you've got tecladocode.com,
because that matches a character or a dot many times
and you've got there a lot of matches.
So now you're gonna have two matches.
Jose
and tecladocode.com.
So the domain is going to be matches one.
Let's have a look.
And there you have it.
So now you've got two matches, Jose
and tecladocode.com.
Jose is the first match,
tecladocode.com is the second match.
Of course, if you did wanna do that,
if you wanted to extract the domain of an email
the best thing you can do is
you can not do any of that
and instead you can have your email here
and you can have something like parts
is email.split on the @ symbol.
We've looked at the split method before,
that does exactly what we need.
So we either need regular expressions for this et all.
So again, the name would be parts zero,
the domain would be parts one, in this case
and you can print them out.
So in some cases, you won't need regular expressions at all
and it's important to recognise those instances.
If you just wanted to get the name
and the domain of an email,
you don't need regex, you can just do it with Python.
Here's a slightly more contrived example.
Introducing a couple of new concepts
that we didn't look at in the last video.
So we're gonna import RE for the Regular Expression Module
and then this is gonna be our text.
Price is
$189.50.
So what's our expression gonna be?
Well I'll let you think about that for a wee bit
and I'm just gonna check our matches here.
And notice how I'm now doing RE.search.
What this is going to do is it's going to do
something slightly different.
I'll tell you in just a moment what it's doing.
So let's say that our Regular Expression
is going to be 189.50.
What do you think we're going to find?
Let's run this.
And notice how now we get 189.50 as matches dot group zero
and we get an index error no such group
as the second group.
Okay, so something's going on here,
it's only able to get one group,
so presumably group zero is the thing that's matched.
And that would be correct.
Now I'm going to modify my expressions slightly
to include the price
and let's include the dollar sign here.
But actually this pattern here is not gonna match
this text because the dollar means something
in regular expressions.
So we have to put a backslash in front
to make sure that this gets treated as the dollar sign
and not as what it means in regular expressions.
So let's press on.
Now there is so we can see that the entire thing
is the group zero, price colon space dollar 189.50.
Now I'm gonna do something that's gonna be a bit weird
but I'm gonna put some brackets in here
around the 189.50.
So I've just put some brackets
and that's it.
Now lets run it again.
Notice how now we don't get an error.
We get price is $189.50
and now the group one is 189.50.
So this is important, this is really useful in Python
because what we've done is that we have
evaluated this pattern against the price.
That's what RE dot search does.
But then it has allowed us to extract particular parts
of that by using the brackets into group one.
So group zero is the entire match.
Group one is the first thing in brackets.
So why is this useful?
It's useful because now instead of 189.50
we can say, for example, zero to nine
dot plus.
We can put a backslash in this dot
since it's meant to be not anything but rather the dot.
Zero to nine
dot plus.
Sorry, just the plus, not the dot plus, my bad.
So what we've got now is
any of these characters zero to nine
and any amount of them
followed by the period which separates
numbers from their decibel place
followed by zero to nine any number of characters.
So this could potentially be for example, this.
Right, any number of characters,
any number of numbers
followed by any number of numbers with a full stop
in the middle.
So this can match any number.
The great thing is now whatever
this price thing here is,
for example, let's say, we change it to $18000,
we're going to match it here
and when we run
you see that what we have extracted
is the number.
So why is this great?
It's great because we can say the price
or price number is a float of matches dot group one.
So let's run that.
Print price number.
Notice how now we get a third thing printed out here.
18649.5.
So essentially what we've done is
we've turned this incomprehensible piece of text
and we have extracted a Python number from it.
Just imagine you were extracting some data from a website,
now we're gonna be doing that very soon
and you want to extract the price of something
you need to be able to get it out of the text.
And really the only way to do that reliably
is by using regular expressions.
Okay, what about if we do like a comma after the
thousands, like a lot of countries do?
Well, it's pretty simple.
Zero to nine
and you include a comma in there.
So now this is going to match any number of characters
or digits or a comma
any number of times.
So any character from zero to nine or the comma,
I actually don't think we need the backslash here
because I don't think the comma is anything
in Regular Expressions, so it doesn't need a backslash.
Okay, so now we run it again
now the first group here, group one was this 18,649.50
but then we got an error because we cannot convert
18000 with a common in there to a float.
Because Python doesn't know that the comma means.
So what we have to do is, of course, say price
without comma is
and this matches dot group one
then this is a string, remind you.
We're gonna call a method of the string
that is a very useful that is the dot replace method.
And what we're gonna do is we are going to replace
the comma by an empty string.
That's essentially, so now remove the comma.
And now we can turn the float off price without comma.
Let's run this again.
And notice how now we get our float back here.
For Python float we can add it, subtract it,
multiply it, you know anything you want
because now we have the actual price as a number,
not as a string.
So potentially let's say you were getting some data
from Craigslist or something like that,
you could look at the websites with Python,
you could download them, you could load the price,
you could convert it to a float
and then you could compare it against, say your budget
or the hourly rate that you want for your job
or whatever it is that you're searching for in Craigslist.
Craigslist, by the way if you are not in the United States
is a classified ads website like Gumtree in the UK.
So it's pretty useful to be able to extract
meaningful information from text.
That's what Regular Expressions do best.
So again, we've looked at a few examples of how you can use
the RE Module to search through regular expressions.
As we do more,
and as we require the regular expressions module
we're gonna learn more about it.
I don't wanna delve too deep into it
without a use case because I think that's
gonna just be a bit confusing
and a bit pointless.
So let's wait until we have a better use case
but in the meantime I would recommend
that you take the time to look through the
Regexer website if you want
and the official Python documentation for the RE Module
as it's quite good.
And the code that we've looked at in this section,
everything we've written
as well as a couple of links to the other sites
are gonna be included in
the resources section of this lecture
so feel free to have a look if you're interested.
That's it for this video now
and I'll see you on the next one.