Hi guys and welcome back.
In this video we're going to be learning
about list comprehensions with conditionals,
which we can use to figure out some elements
while we're putting them into a new list
using list comprehensions.
So let's say you've got some ages of your friends
and you to get only the odd ages.
You could do something like, odds equal
age for age in ages.
And that is a list comprehension that puts the value
age for age, which is the new variable
you're creating, in the Age's List.
So it's going to put every age in the Age's List
into a new list that you're calling Odds.
What you can do is if you wanted to get only
the odd ages, you can actually put an if statement
at the end, if age modulo two equal one.
And what this is gonna do is it's going to put
this value into the new list if this conditional
is true, and if this conditional is false
then it's not going to put the value in.
So if we run that you'll see 35, 27, and 21,
which are the odd ages in the original list.
Now I appreciate as soon as you start
putting conditionals into a list comprehension,
it does get a little bit more cluttered
because you have the for keyword,
in keyword, and if keyword, all in one line.
So something you have to be careful with when you're writing
list comprehensions, is that if it's getting
too long and too complicated, you can split
things out and move them outside the list comprehension,
or you can just use a normal for loop,
like we learned in the last video to add to a new list.
That can reduce the cognitive load on your brain
because it can make the code a bit easier to read.
So list comprehensions are good when they are kept simple
and they help your code, but if they're too complicated
they can actually detract from your code.
Let's say you've got the names of some friends
and they are in a mix of uppercase and lowercase
spelling, and then you've got another list of guests
that have come to one of your parties.
We're going to turn every friend in our friends list
into lowercase, so that we can easily compare them
with our guests.
But if we wanted to compare, now let's say
we want a final list of those friends
that have come to your party.
So there are two approaches.
The first approach is that you can turn
all of these guests into lowercase as well.
So you can go guests_lower equal g_lower
for g in guests.
So now you have two lowercase lists.
If you turn both of these into sets
by actually passing them through the set function,
then you could print the intersection of the two.
So friends_lower.intersection with guests_lower,
and this will give you those friends
that are here and also here, which are Charlie and Rolf.
So this is one way to do it, but it's a bit more
difficult to get these names out as capital C
and capital R because in the sets you've got them
all as lowercase.
So instead we're not going to use sets
for our approach, and we're going to use
a list comprehension where we create a present_friends list,
because it's going to be a long list comprehension,
I'm going to split it out into multiple lines.
And you can do this, you can just put the square brackets
in one line, and in another, and in the middle you can
write out your list comprehension.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going
to put the name for name in guests if the name.lower
is in friends_lower.
And what this allows me to do is put each of the names
of the guests inside my new list, if that name
turned to lowercase, is in my friends_lower list.
And of course, instead of just name,
I can do name.title.
If we print this out, you'll see the output here,
which is Rolf and Charlie.
Another benefit of this that might be a benefit
or it might be irrelevant for your programme,
is that the output is in order of the guests.
So Rolf and then Charlie.
When you turn these into sets they lose the order.
So potentially if this order had some sort of meaning
in your programme, such as who arrived first,
or something like that, then you would get to keep
that if you use lists, but you wouldn't get to keep
that if you use sets.
As an aside, here's something that you probably
should never do, which is nest list comprehensions
one inside of another.
Here you've got friends_lower, which you know
is this list comprehension here, which turns
each friend into their lowercase variant.
But you actually don't have to define a variable,
you can just copy it and paste it in there,
and delete this variable entirely.
But as you can see, this is a very dangerous
thing to be doing, cause it quickly becomes unreadable.
Splitting this out into variables is almost always
the better choice because it's going to make
your code more readable.
If you do have a long list comprehension,
where one line is not enough, you can split
it further into something like this.
It's usual to have the first line as the new thing
that you want to put into your list.
The second line as the iteration over
an existing iterable like this list.
And finally the comprehension, if there is one.
Splitting list comprehensions in this way
can be helpful to make your code a bit more readable,
but it is a sign that it is getting a bit too long,
so it's almost always better to put this here
to a separate variable, and either keep it in three lines,
or put it back into one line.
That's it for this video though, I just wanted to show you
that you can put if statements inside the list comprehension
where it makes sense.
Don't overcomplicate things.
Writing simple code is almost always better
than writing complicate code.
Thanks for joining me in this video
and I'll see you in the next one.