Hi, and welcome back.
In this video we're going to talk about context managers
and we're going to be developing our own.
This is not something that a lot of Python Courses get into,
so you should feel pretty good that you're getting this deep
into the inner workings of Python
and how to do some pretty advanced stuff.
In the last section we looked at files
and particularly at a new bit of syntax.
Thus said, something like this, I'm just gonna put it here
and I'm gonna delete in a moment.
With something, something, something,
as something, something, something, colon,
and then do stuff.
And this here was the context manager.
And by context we mean that the current status
of the application at the point
in which this block runs, is modified by this statement,
that it's controlled by that statement.
You could even see, it's managed by it.
And that means that it modifies the status,
or the context, when you go in,
and it also modifies it when you go out.
That allows you to do some set up when you start,
and some tear down when you end.
We can create our own context managers.
That is reasonably straightforward.
So that we can use that syntax for our database connections.
We can see, and I've been pretty explicit
throughout this section in, for example,
copying and pasting code.
We can see that we've got a setup.
And we've got a tear down,
and this happens for every function in this file,
pretty much, except for this one that doesn't have a commit.
So as you can see
there is here a good idea that is using a context manager,
so that we don't have to get this done every time.
Let's create a context manager for our database connections,
so that we don't have to open
and close the connection every time.
In order to create a context manager,
all we have to do is go into our utils package, for example,
and create a new Python file,
which I'm going to call database_connection.py.
This database connection is going to import sqlite3,
because it's going to actually connect to the database
and it needs sqlite3 to connect.
And it's going to be a class, database connection class.
A database connection,
in order to be able to be used as a context manager,
it of course needs two dunder methods.
Remember dunder methods are the way
that everything happens in Python
and if you want to use a with statement,
you need two Dunder Methods.
You need enter and you need exit.
Notice how the exit method has a few arguments here.
We're gonna talk about what these are in the next videos,
so don't worry too much about them right now.
Naturally, the enter dunder method,
it's called when you go into the context manager
right before you start running it,
and the exit method is executed
right when you leave the context manager.
When we now have these two methods,
we can go over to database.py,
we can remove the sqlite3 import,
and instead we can say, from database connection,
notice how I'm using a relative import here,
.database_connection, import, database connection class.
Now, instead of doing this, or rather,
instead of doing this here,
we can say with database connection, as connection,
and then we can just keep this stuff here.
Of course, this has to be indented
so that they are inside this context manager block.
Okay, this is the syntax with database connection,
create a new object of type database connection
as this connection variable,
this is the variable we create now
so that it can be used inside the context manager.
And then, we can create a cursor with it,
and then we can execute whatever we want.
Of course, we could make this database connection
return a cursor object,
but I think that would be fairly confusing.
A database connection probably should return a connection,
and not a cursor.
So, of course, our enter and exit methods
don't do anything yet.
So this connection variable here is going to contain none.
That's what this enter method returns.
Pass just means do nothing.
All functions, all methods in Python return none by default,
so this connection variable will be none.
We don't wanna do that.
Of course, here we are also creating a new object,
therefore, if we want, not necessary, but if we want,
we can also have an init method here.
This init method is going to be called first
when we initialise this object
and then the enter method is going to be called
as we go into the context manager
and the exit method is gonna be called
as we leave the context manager.
Of course, we have to initialise the connection.
We have to do this sqlite3.connect, so let's do it.
I think we should do the sqlite3.connect in here,
in the enter method,
so we can return sqlite3.connect, data.db.
Now, when we go back to database.py,
this connection variable is now a sqlite3 connect result.
It's the result of whatever the enter method returned.
So, that's correct.
Now, this will all work, but when we go to the end,
we've not yet added any code to commit
and close the connection.
So, we have to do that in here in the exit method.
Now, we don't have access to this connection
inside this class,
there's no way to access the connection that we've got,
and it's not passed to us as a parameter.
So what to do is use this init method
to say self.connection is none.
Then, we're gonna say self.connection
is this connection here, return self.connection.
Now, we're doing the same thing,
but we've defined a new property
of our database connection class
that is going to store this sqlite3.connect result,
the enter method is going to return that,
which means it's usable from our database.py,
and now we have access to it here in our exit method
as well as self.connection,
so we can do self.connection.commit,
and self.connection.close.
There are some instances where we won't need to commit,
but it's okay to leave that there
even when we don't need to.
The sqlite will just not do anything,
if we call commit but there's nothing to commit,
no change is made to the database so this is fine.
Okay, I would improve this by also saying self.host = host,
and pass this in here as a parameter to the init method,
and instead of data.db, use self.host.
That way, when we go back to our database.py,
we can say data.db in here,
and that makes things a bit more explicit.
We can see that we're now connected to a database
called data.db, we're getting the connection here,
presumably everything is being handled,
including closing the connection and everything like that.
This looks pretty similar to,
with open books.txt in read mode as file, as you can see,
the open here is a class as well,
it's creating a new object of type open,
and it's getting two parameters to the init method,
and then the enter function inside this class
is returning a file for which we're using
as this variable here.
Very much the same, of course,
this has another argument there, but that's fine.
What we've done is we've created a new object,
and we've given it what we want to do with that object,
connect to databse.db,
and that is gonna handle everything for us.
This with statement is a very Pythonic way of writing code.
It's not something that other programming languages have,
and I really encourage you to use it.
Now that we've got it, of course, we can copy it
and use it on all of our functions.
In the at book, we do exactly the same thing.
Notice how this context manager
is gonna commit at the end as well, so nothing to do here.
Also here, we can of course, do all of this.
We don't have to close the connection,
and we can return books
either inside or outside the context manager,
it's up to you, it doesn't matter.
I'm gonna leave it outside, just for kicks.
We can do it here as well, of course,
and we can, of course, also do it here.
Now this code is made much simpler.
None of this code has to deal with connecting to a database
or committing or closing the connection.
All of that is done for us with this context manager.
That means that if we were to forget
to commit or close or something,
now we can no longer forget,
because as soon as we do this everything is handled for us.
You could try to make another context manager
which generates the cursor,
and then use a single context manager for both.
You can try that if you want, play around with it,
and see what you come up with,
if that's something that interests you.
Context managers are really exciting,
and it's quite cool to work with them,
and really finally understand
what's going on behind the scenes.
With almost everything in Python, what's going on,
is that some dunder method is getting called.
When you do with, the init method gets called first
for the object you're initialising, then the enter method,
and finally the exit method at the end.
In the next video we're going to look at
these three things here, so don't go anywhere.
I'll see you on the next video.