Hi, and welcome back.
In this video I wanted to encourage you to watch the talks.
I've linked them as resources through this lecture.
Now that we've explained a lot of how concurrency,
doing multiple things at the same time
works behind the scenes,
I think it's time for someone to walk you
through a couple examples,
and the reason I've picked these guys and these talks
instead of just doing it myself
is because these two guys actually developed
asynchronous development in Python.
They are Python, the creators of the Python language
or they help create the Python language,
so they really poise to guide you perfectly
through these examples
without misguiding or doing anything incorrectly.
Doesn't mean they're perfect by any means,
but it is a really complicated topic
when you start getting into the depths
of how everything works behind the scenes,
so I think we've done a pretty good job
of explaining what's going on.
These guys are gonna take you that one step further,
and that's gonna be the case with any course you take
or anything you do.
There's always going to be more research,
more things to learn.
And by going to conferences and listening to talks
like these ones that I link you now,
is a great way to do that.
However, of course, the purpose of this course
is for you to learn the most you can,
and as such, come back to me with any questions you have
after watching the talks,
and I'll be more than happy to help you out
and answer any questions.
Again, watching conference talks and going to conferences
is a great way to learn more about obscure
and complicated topics like asynchronous programming.
And of course working with it,
doing some programming with it,
is a fantastic way as well.
So watch the talks
and then come back to me with any questions.
I'll see you there.