Hi guys, and welcome back.
In this video, I wanted to tell you
about set and dictionary comprehensions.
In the last video, we had a look at this code
where we have our friends list and our guests list.
And in order to compare them both,
we tried to turn them both into lower case
and then pass them through sets,
so that we could then print the intersection
when we did friends_lower.intersection(guests_lower).
However, we can just use set comprehensions
instead of list comprehensions
and then pass it through the set function.
Just like we can do list comprehensions
by using square brackets
and then putting the thing we wanna put
into the new list for the iterating variable
in the iterable, we can just do this.
Instead of creating a new list first
and then making a set out of it,
we can just create a set straight away,
and that is going to be faster,
and it'll sure be more readable.
Let's do the same down here.
Now one of the problems we had in the last video
with doing something like this is we weren't able
to output the names in capitalised format.
So we always had the lowercase names at the end,
because that's what we used to sort of compare them.
But actually, we can create a final set comprehension
that does this for us.
(keys clicking)
So what I've got here is a third set comprehension
that puts the name turned into title case
for the name in the intersection.
Of course, it is easier if you take this out
and put it into another variable
(keys clicking)
just like that.
If we run this, you'll see
that the output is now what we wanted.
Though it is a little bit longer,
it does have the extra benefit
of removing any duplicate friends if there were any.
So if somebody was in this list twice,
for example, for some reason, either due to an error,
or maybe they RSVP'd twice or something like that,
then this would get rid of that.
However, you could also have the problem
of removing duplicate (laughs) elements,
so if two people have the same name, you could end up
with only one of those people showing up in these sets.
Either way, I wanted to tell you
that you can do set comprehensions,
which is the same thing as a list comprehension,
but using curly braces instead of square brackets.
And you end up with a set at the end of it.
Let's say you've got a list of friend names
and how long ago since you last saw them,
and you want to create a dictionary out of these two.
What you can do is you can create something
like a variable called long_timers.
And once again using curly braces,
just as we do with dictionaries,
you can do friends(i): time_since_seen(i).
And what this does is it accesses the i-th element
of the friends list.
So for example if i was zero,
it would access friends zero, and that's Rolf.
And it would associate with that this value here,
which is time_since_seen zero, which would be 3,
so you could end up with Rolf, 3.
Now if you repeat this for every index,
so zero, one, two, and three,
you'd end up with a dictionary of the elements,
which include all of these in these two lists.
So you could do for i in range of the length of friends.
And what this means is you are creating a new variable
called i, and its values will range from zero,
which is the start of the range function,
up to the length of friends, which is four.
So we would go from zero to three, inclusive,
and that would give you all of these.
If we print this out and run it,
you'll see what I mean.
You get Rolf and 3, Bob and 7, Jen and 15, Anne and 11.
One of the benefits of doing a list comprehension
like this one is that if you were only interested
in those people that you haven't seen for five days or more,
you can of course put a conditional in here, as we've seen.
(keys clicking)
Something like that.
So now you're only running this
if the time_since_seen(i), which would be the number
that we're currently looking at, is greater than five.
So now you would only get Bob, Jen, and Anne.
Running this, you'll see that that is correct.
So dictionary comprehension, which is this,
works in exactly the same way as set comprehension,
in that you use the calibrators,
but instead of putting a single value
into the set comprehension,
you put the key, colon, the value,
just as we did with dictionaries before.
Dictionary comprehension is used much less
than other types of comprehension,
but sometimes it can be really handy.
So I just wanted to show it to you,
tell you that it's possible,
and maybe you'll encounter it in the future.
Thank you for joining me in this video.
I hope you've learned something,
and I'll see you in the next one.