Hi and welcome back.
I hope you've watched the talks from the last lecture
and in this one, we're going to be turning our scraper
that we created earlier on into an asynchronous scraper.
Just to use the stuff that we've learned
and also a couple of things that were mentioned briefly
in the talks that we're going to explain as well.
When we looked at scraping websites before,
we sort of got up to 50 pages here, one after another,
from our books.toscrape.com site, but it could be a bit slow
because of all these pages.
If you remember, when we ran the menu,
which I'm gonna do just now, we then sort of have a period
where nothing seemed to happen.
This was when the pages were all loading.
Eventually something appears once all the pages have loaded
and we've extracted all of the books
into our sort of master books list.
I'm just gonna exit this menu and collapse that.
If we could do this asynchronously,
we could increase the speed massively
and the reason for that is as follows.
What's happening here is that the first thing we're doing
is we are sort of creating a new string,
fairly straight forward.
Then we're requesting it and getting the page content,
and then we're sort of logging something.
Creating an AllBooksPage and sort of extending that.
The main improvement from using asynchronous requests,
which we're going to look at soon,
is in this line here, line 22.
The reason for that is because there are a few things
happening in the background when we do this.
This line starts a request to the server,
sends something to the server telling them,
hey, I want to start a connection to you
and then it has to wait for the server to respond.
Once the connection is set up,
it has to ask the server for the URL
that contains the page content
and it has to wait for the data to come back.
It has to download the entire page content
and wait for all that data to come through.
As you can see, there were a couple of times there
where we're just waiting for the server
to give us something.
To tell us that a connection has been set up
or to tell us that the data is now ready,
and, of course, for us to download the data.
From what we've looked at in asynchronous programming,
wait means potential improvements from using concurrency.
In Python we cannot run two things at once,
unless we use the multi-processing module,
but we could potentially send the server,
hey, give me this, hey, give me this, hey, give me this
and then just wait for all three at the same time.
The server will presumably be able to respond
to these requests more or less quickly
and then we won't be waiting too long.
We'll only be waiting for the server to respond
to all three, more or less, simultaneously.
Okay.
Just as we did with our simple generator task scheduler
where we had our three countdowns and we sort of started one
and then started the other, and then started the other,
and then we used next to go over each one.
We're going to be doing something like that.
We're going to be having a task scheduler,
but we're gonna use the Python asyncio library
in order to loop through the various tasks
that we'll be creating and each task is going
to be responsible of fetching one of these URLs.
We're gonna have a task per URL
and we're just gonna start them all
at the same time using yields.
We're gonna sort of wait and resume or suspend them
as data comes back.
Okay.
We're also gonna be using a new library called
aiohttp and we've previously used the requests library,
like we've done here,
but the requests library does not allow us
to make requests asynchronously.
It just doesn't have that juicy yield statement inside.
So, aiohttp does have them and it's all set up
to be used with asyncio, so we're gonna be using that
throughout this next few videos in order to turn this
into an asynchronous web scraper.
Also, as a reminder, the asyncio library is built-in,
aiohttp is a third-party library.
Just a minor distinction.
We're gonna be looking through that in this section.
Let's move onto the next video
and we'll start with making a first request with aiohttp.
I'll see you there.