Hi and welcome back.
In this video we're going to be making it
a bit more efficient to get multiple pages.
Here in this function you can see
that we've had to create a client session.
And each session as I said earlier
contains a pool of connections
so that not all connections have to be created each time.
It also contains a cookie storage,
so that any cookies that websites send us
can be shared across requests made with the same session.
If you're not sure what cookies are,
I've attached a resource link to this lecture
just with a brief explanation on what they are.
So we then use the session which uses a connection
from that pool that was just created
in order to get the URL
and to get the content, and so forth.
It sends a request to the server
and then awaits the data to come back.
The function can suspend at that point
until the data comes back.
But of course, we said that we've created
a connection pool here in the client session
so that we don't have to recreate the connection every time.
But we've not really done that,
because each time we do this
we create a new connection pool,
so instead of a single connection
we're creating a whole bunch of connections
each time we want to fetch a page.
And then we're only using one of them.
So this is not great.
Instead what we should do is we should create the session
and use it for all the URLs we want to request
instead of creating a session for each time
we want to request a URL.
So the way we're going to do this
is we're going to split this out
into another thing that is going to allow us
to create multiple tasks.
So async def,
get multiple pages,
and to this thing we're going to pass the loop
and also the URLs we want to get.
Notice that this is an unpacked argument there,
so we can pass in many different arguments,
one for each URL that we want to get.
Then we're going to say tasks is an empty list.
Async with aiohttp.clientSession.
And to the client session we can actually pass in
the loop that we want to use,
which is the one we create down here.
And their parameter is going to be this loop.
The reason to do that is just so
it doesn't create a new loop.
Now when you do asyncio.get_event_loop,
no matter where you do that in your programme,
it's always going to give you the same loop.
But in case you forget to do that,
passing the loop in here can be quite handy.
Just so not a new one is created
that maybe runs independently or doesn't run until complete.
And so this is just a safe guard to make sure
that you use the loop that you've defined earlier.
So with aiohttp client session as session,
we are then going to populate our tasks list
and wait for them.
So for each URL that we've got here,
we're going to say tasks.append,
fetch page of this session,
sorry, the URL, like so.
Now when we do this, what we do is
we call this fetch page function.
That creates a coroutine
and that gets then put into our tasks list.
At the end of the loop but inside this statement,
this context manager,
we're then going to wait for them, okay?
So grouped tasks is going to be asyncio.gather.
And this is going to be our tasks.
Again, all this is doing is gathering
all the tasks that we've put in our list
and it's treating them as a single task
so that we can then execute it in a loop
like loop run until complete.
Except instead of running them using this loop,
we're going to await them.
So return await grouped tasks.
This, all it's going to do as you know,
is yield from, so it's going to allow us
to suspend execution here,
and wait until something happens here
and then resume the function and possibly repeat
all of that until this returns.
And this will return when all of the tasks are finished.
So when we do this, now we can run until complete
these get multiple pages.
Let's finish of this code before we review it
and make sure that it all makes sense.
This fetch page is still creating its own session here,
we don't want to do that.
So what we're going to do is delete that entirely
and then make sure that we pass in the session,
smession.
Make sure that we pass in the session,
correctly spelled there.
Then pass it in here as well.
Just so that that has access to a session we've created.
Now okay, now our tasks are no longer
going to be fetch page,
they're just going to be these strings.
And we shall not call them tasks,
we're going to call them URLs.
So now we have 50 times Google.com
inside our lists, and what we can do
is run until complete
our get multiple pages with the loop
and the URLs.
Notice how URLs is star URLs.
And so we must also pass in the arguments individually
by unpacking them.
If you prefer, you could just pass in a list,
that would be fine as well
and then all you'd have to do is delete them too.
It's up to you how you want to do that.
Alright, so what we've got now, let's review that,
is 50 strings of Google.com.
Then we pass them all to this get multiple pages function
and we also pass in the loop that is running through
as a task scheduler.
So they go in there.
The loop is using the client session
just so it doesn't create a new loop
in case we forget to pass it in
or we forget to create one.
It will say hey, you didn't pass me anything,
something's wrong.
So this is a safeguard,
and the URLs, we are then going to iterate over them
and append the coroutine that they create
into our tasks list.
Remember, we could suspend the function execution
before or during this creation of the session.
But inside it, once we go in it,
it doesn't suspend at any point.
All it does, it writes over all the URLs
and creates all the coroutines synchronously
one after another, there's no suspension
anywhere inside here.
So we create all the coroutines
and then we're going to gather them as one.
What this does is it essentially awaits
each task and only returns when they're all complete.
We then await that, so if we want to suspend
we can suspend in between each task
or we can suspend at the start
before we start any task,
or we can suspend at the end
once all the tasks are finished.
That means that these tasks that we group here
are all running individually in this event loop.
And so that is what this gather does.
Then we return the awaiting of that,
so this function only returns
when this has finished running,
but it can suspend on the way.
So when it has finished running,
that returns and that is the end
and that function has run until it has been completed,
so that's why we do run until complete.
Run until complete is going to run
until this return actually executes.
And that's only going to execute
when this has been fully awaited
and this has completed itself.
And once that happens we can print out
that all of them took the amount of time they took.
It seems slightly more complex,
but there is a key performance improvement,
which is that you're not creating a session
for each of the pages you want to fetch.
And of course as long as you do create
your event loop first,
this thing here is not necessary.
You could not pass it in if you want.
It's totally up to you, either of them will work,
so you can run this and as you'll see,
you still get the same thing, yeah?
Notice how they seem to take slightly longer now
and this could be due to any number of reasons,
somebody else using the internet in the house
or Google being more hammered down
by somebody making requests or anything else.
If you do want to pass the loop in there
this is fine as well
and this is what we did earlier.
And it'll work in the same way.
It seems like this is now faster,
possibly because it didn't have to go
and get the loop each time,
and so this is possibly a performance improvement as well.
Anyway, that's it for this video.
I just wanted to show you how to make this
a little more generic in order for you to then
be able to use this in our book scraping programme.
So if you want to go ahead and try that out,
try and turn our book scraper into something
that uses these two functions and an event loop
to get all the pages instead of getting them synchronously,
I'm pretty sure you can do that now.
All you have to do is import a couple of libraries
that we've already installed,
copy these functions, and then instead
of going through each URL one at a time,
get them all at the same time first
and then you'll be able to use their contents.
Again, it may be slightly complicated,
it may take some time and some investigation.
Once you're done or if you want to see how we do it,
come back and we will implement that together.
Okay, see you in the next video.