Hi, welcome back.
Just a quick aside to warn you of something that can happen
in these asynchronous programmes.
Because we're running until_complete
and we're gathering all the tasks here,
potentially if one task takes a really long time
or maybe takes a few minutes or a few hours to,
for the server to respond, we want to say,
you know, if it takes more than 30 seconds,
I just wanna terminate this and treat it as an error.
Sometimes the servers won't send you an error,
they just won't send you anything
and you'll be waiting for content for a long time.
This run_until-complete means
that your programme won't actually finish
until all of the tasks have given you something.
So, it can be a bit dangerous if you don't have anything
to say timeout after X number of seconds.
Aiohttp in the latest version comes
with something called the async_timeout
which you can import, async_timeout,
that you can use as a timeout
in an asynchronous environment.
You can just say async with async_timeout.timeout.
Maybe 10 seconds, 10 seconds is a pretty reasonable number,
I think.
So, now if this session.get takes longer than 10 seconds,
it's gonna be cancelled and an exception is gonna be raised.
And as I said, that can be quite handy
for when something does take a long time.
For Google, this is not gonna be a problem,
but maybe for a book scraping and business,
it could be a bit of an issue.
So, that's it for this video, just wanted to share
with you this async_timeout as something that exists
and that you can use.
I'll see you in the next one.