Hi there and welcome back.
In this video we're looking at how to
get data out of multiple pages.
So the most important thing is for us
to look at what the different pages looks like
and how we can go to them.
Any patterns you can recognise from doing this
are going to help you so much in your programming.
As you can see, the url right now of this page
is books dot toscrape dot com.
If we go down to the bottom and we go to the next page,
which by the way, there are 50 of them.
This is gonna be an important number later on.
You can see that the url changes.
And it changes to slash catalogue slash page dash two.
But before it was not page dash one.
So we can see that we've gone to page dash two
and if we go over to the next page,
it'll be page dash three and so forth.
So what happens if we go to the first page?
This is the same page that we were seeing
earlier on at the start.
But now it has slash catalogue slash page dash one dot html.
That means that the home page is either
the catalogue slash page one, or it can be just
books dot toscrape dot com.
Because all the pages can be accessed at
slash catalogue slash page dash one
this could be helpful for us in extracting
all the data we need.
Now okay, the next thing is if you want to go
to the next page, all you have to do
is request a different url.
You don't have to click the button.
You don't have to make Python click buttons
or anything like that.
Not that that would work, you can't do that
with the knowledge we've got.
But you can request a different url entirely.
So if you want to get data from 50 pages,
which is what we've got, you just have to do
a for loop 50 times and each time get all the books
out of the page and put them into a list.
And at the end you'll end up with a big list
of all your books.
I'd recommend you try this out now
and then we're going to implement this a bit better
and we're also going to look at how to extract the 50
from this place here so that if the number of pages changes,
you're only going to get or you're going to get
all of the pages or less pages if there are fewer pages.
Okay, that's it for this video.
Go and try to implement this.
Get the 50 pages by calling this url
instead of the url we've got right now
and then we'll go and implement this ourselves.
See you on the next video.