Hi guys, and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to look at return values,
and that's because functions can not only perform actions,
which is what the calculate MPG function does here.
It processes some data and then prints something out.
They can also take some inputs and give us some outputs.
What that allows us to do is to extract
some of this code into a separate function
so that they don't get too long.
This calculates MPG function at the moment
does a bit more than just calculate MPGs.
It calculates MPGs and then it also calculates the car name,
and finally, it prints it out.
So there are few things going on in this function,
and that's usually something
that tells you that you can have
multiple functions instead of just one.
A few things are going on.
You can have one function for each thing.
Let's make our calculate MPG function
actually only calculate MPGs.
What we'll do is after the calculation,
we will just do return MPG.
This is how you can return values,
and what that means is whenever this function gets called,
you can then assign that to a variable.
For example, we could do something like this,
and then the value of dividing the mileage
by the fuel consumed, which is a float,
will be assigned to the MPG variable via this return.
We'll have 50.0 let's say as an example.
We will return 50.0,
and then we will assign 50.0 to MPG.
Now because that's happening,
as soon as Python encounters a return statement,
the function ends and none of the other code evaluates.
So what we've done here is we've made
our calculate MPG function actually only calculate MPGs.
Now we need another function to do the rest of the stuff.
So I'll define a function called Car Name,
and it will also take a car and it will just
calculate the name and then it will return it.
Finally, I'll make a function called Print Car Info,
which will take a car as well,
and it will use these two functions
to get the car name,
and to get the car's MPG.
Finally, it will print it out.
Notice that this function here does not have a return,
so when we run this function,
if we were to assign it to a variable like this,
this variable would be equal to
the special value none in python.
None just means no value.
So all functions in Python
return the value, none by default,
or you can of course just do return none
if you want to make that explicit.
None has a capital N,
and again, it just means no value.
What we've done here is we now have three functions.
So I appreciate that this
is a little more complicated than it was before.
We've got a function that calculates the miles per gallon,
and it accepts a parameter which should be some data,
which has to be a dictionary,
since we are accessing a dictionary's properties,
and this car data has to maintain a property mileage
and a property fuel consumed.
Then it's going to divide one by the other,
and it's going to return that value.
In the function print car info,
which also takes a variable car as a parameter,
which should be a dictionary with this structure,
it then passes the value of that variable
to the car name function and to the calculate MPG functions.
Let's take the calculated MPG function
as an example for this float.
We will receive the car information
in the print car info function,
then it gets passed over the same value to the MPG function,
which uses the properties to calculate something.
This return value then gets assigned back
to the MPG value inside print car info.
So you can see how Python is jumping around.
As soon as it encounters a function,
it goes and runs the function code.
If there's a return,
then we can assign that to a variable.
So running this function here is exactly the same
as just copying this code and putting it there.
However, because it has a name, such as car name,
it's a little bit easier to read
when you're looking at this function
to understand what it does.
Clearly, this function first gets the car name,
or calculates it in some way,
then it gets the car's MPG and calculates it in some way,
and finally prints some information out.
And you don't necessarily have to go
and look at these other functions,
as long as you believe
that it calculates the name and the MPG correctly,
but you can do if you want,
in order to understand
how the name and the MPG are calculated.
Notice that here at the end
we have now got MPG equal print car info,
but this print car info function does not return anything,
or rather it returns none by default,
so this is kind of useless, so we can just remove it.
We can just call print car info,
and that is going to run through this code here
and print the information by using these other functions.
I also say that it's good form in Python
and generally recommended to leave two lines
between each function definition
so you can read through it a little bit quicker.
Now this code is getting a little bit longer,
but we can still run it
and it will print out the same thing as before.
Something that my students frequently do is a small mistake,
which is to print this function here.
If you say print of print car info,
what you're doing is you're passing the result
of calling print car info to the print function,
which is then going to print this value out.
The value that we get printed out
is the return value of the function,
but because this function returns none,
what you'll see here is none printed out.
So you still get all of the stuff
from our previous functions,
but now you get none in between each function as well.
This is normally not what you want,
so just don't print the result of calling that function.
You can just call the function and let it print.
If you wanted to print here, you can make this return,
and then, this function
will now actually return this string,
which then you can print out.
If you don't print it out,
you won't see anything output in the console
because we haven't printed anything out.
We've just got some values.
If you want to show them, you have to print it out.
So if you make the function return something,
you can then use that value.
If you make the function print like we had earlier,
then you don't have to use that value.
Functions can return multiple times,
and what that means is let's say that you've got
a divide function that takes two numbers
and divides one by the other,
but you want to make sure that you can't divide a number
by zero, because that's illegal in mathematics.
You can say if Y is equal to zero, then you can return.
You try to divide by zero.
But otherwise, we can return X divided by Y.
This works in exactly the same way
that all if statements do,
which is that if Y is zero, then this code runs.
But if Y is not zero,
then this code runs and this one does not.
Both of them will cause the termination of the function
and the value to be given back to the caller,
but only one of them will ever run in one function call.
So you can have multiple return statements,
as long as they both won't try to run.
So if you have this instead,
this if statement will never run,
because when this one runs, the function terminates.
So having two return statements,
one right after the other is not very useful,
because only the first one would ever run.
So if you put them in an if statement, that's better.
Either one will run,
but both can run given the right circumstances.
So if we print the divide of 10 and two,
you'll see that you get 5.0,
but if you print the divide of six and zero,
then you'll see this string gets printed out.
You try to divide by zero.
Once again just to reiterate,
if you call these functions but you don't print,
nothing will get printed out,
because these functions calculate a value,
and give it back to the caller
so that you can put it in a variable
or do something with it,
but you still have to print it out
if you actually want to show it to the user.
That's it for this video.
I wanted to tell you about return values for functions
because they really start allowing you
to split out your code and move it
from one place to another,
putting it into functions
so that you can reuse them in other parts of your code.
As you learn more Python,
you will increasingly put code into different functions
so that you can use them in multiple places.
Thanks for joining me.
I hope you've learned something,
and I'll see you in the next video.