Hi, welcome back.
In this video we're going to add logging to our
scraping app.
Just to get a bit better of an idea of how to add logging
to an application like this.
By the way I always recommend adding logging
as you start your application and not add the logging
all at the end, like we've done here.
When you start, as you develop, you can add logging
and it'll make more sense.
Once you're done, you sort of lose a bit of the
bigger picture, and sometimes adding logging
can be a bit more tricky.
So by all means, add the logging while you develop,
not all at the end.
But nonetheless, in order to save you time and not to
add logging in every video and so forth, we've added
it all at the end here.
And, but again, don't do this normally.
The first thing we have to do is import the logging
module, and then we're going to configure the logging
module so we're going to do logging dot basic config
and then in here we're gonna paste in format, which is going
to be the format of the logger.
And this is in all Python string format.
And syntax, you've seen it before, I've showed you
this earlier, and what we're gonna do is print out
and the current time and the current level like debug
or info and so forth, but this is always going to be eight
characters long, so that the longest level, critical,
will be the same width as the shortest level, info.
They're all gonna be eight spaces, and it's just gonna
pad with spaces at the end.
Then we're going to add the file name.
File name.
By the way, the S at the end just means string.
It's just Python's way of assuring that what we're
printing out here are strings.
D is for number.
And finally we're going to add the message, which is
gonna be an S as well.
So as you can see our format is the time, then the level
name, filename, and line number of where this was logged.
And finally the message that we logged.
The date format, that's what this argument is for,
is what format you want to print your dates in.
Percent D, percent M, percent Y is gonna be date, month,
and year, year has four digits.
And then percent H percent M percent S is going to give you
hours, minutes, and seconds.
So I think this is pretty good accuracy there.
The level is gonna be logging dot debug as a start.
And then we can turn it down to info or even to warning
if we want.
And finally, if you paste in the filename here like
logs dot txt, then it's just going to write all your
logs to that file instead of showing them on the console.
So this is normally a good idea.
Then we're going to get a logger,
so we're going to say logger.
Nope, cannot type logger equals logging dot get logger.
And we're gonna get our base logger, which is
gonna be called scraping.
Okay, so in app dot PY, the logger is going to be
called scraping, and as soon as you do get logger
and you paste in the name, the logging module
is going to create a logger in the background.
In any other file when you paste in the same name
it's gonna get the same logger.
So there's only one instance of a logger at any given time.
And this is in case you're interested in an example of
a singleton pattern in software development,
this is an implementation of a singleton.
If you don't know what a singleton is, don't worry,
we're gonna look into that much later in the course.
Okay, then we can start logging using this logger.
So what can we log at line 13?
Well, whenever we import something from app, we're gonna
run through these lines of code, then start getting
the books and then finally it read over all the pages
and get all the books in each page.
What we can start logging here is that we are about
to load the books list.
Loading books list.
By the way, my typos are generally caused by me
having a microphone on my face and not being
able to see my keyboard at all, so I apologise
for any typos.
So what we're seeing here is, we're loading the books list,
and that's what's gonna appear in our logs when we run this.
Let's run the menu again.
It's gonna go through all of this stuff.
It's going through, or it has already gone through line 13.
And it's now loaded everything, we can see for example
the best books and we can exit.
Then you get here, logs dot text.
So let me open that up.
You can see that this contains quite a lot of stuff.
One info message at the top are saying app dot PY
line 13 loading books list.
And then it's got a bunch of debug messages.
These debug messages are not added by us,
they were printed out by another library that prints
out debug messages and that's the requests library.
So here it just says starting a new http connection
to books dot to scrape dot com.
And then it's starting another one to books dot to scrape
dot com, but now it's trying to get catalogue slash page two
slash HTML, and so for page three, four, five, and so forth
up all the way up to 50.
And as you can see, you also get the response so that's
the code 200.
That means all is good.
So these logs here tell you that all your requests
to the page succeeded because they're all code 200.
So this is good.
If you don't want to see these messages
because you're not interested in such a low level operation
of your application, all you have to do is turn the level
up to info and then they will disappear.
Okay, so if you're showing a debug message that is only
for when you're developing and you wanna know exactly
what's going on, use debug.
If you want to give some information that is not needed,
use info.
And of course if you wanna talk about warnings and errors
and criticals and so forth, use those levels.
But normally you'd be using debug info at this level, okay.
For example, we could put a debug message here,
logger dot debug.
Creating all books page from page content.
Like that.
Maybe not the most necessary message, but if there is
a problem between the debug message and this message
here you know that something has gone wrong retrieving
the content of the page.
Now let's go over to our books page and we can
do some logging in there as well.
Let's go in here.
Once again, all we have to do import logging and down here
create out logger.
And inside the logger here, nope, by the way I'm gonna
make sure to use the right letter there.
We're gonna say scraping dot all books page.
This is going to give me a child logger of the
scraping logger, the base logger that we defined earlier.
And so all configuration and everything is going to
be inherited, so if anything,
if we'd set up anything on the scraping logger it would
also be available on this child logger.
But generally the usefulness is also to keep them related.
So you'd know that this logger is also related to your main
logger, they're part of the same application.
You know, you've written them it's not
like some other library is doing the logging for you.
So here we could have something like parsing page content
with beautiful soup.
Inside the books function you could add something.
Like that, finding all books in a page using the all books
page locator dot books is gonna give you the locator
in your logs, so then as you are analysing the logs
if something goes wrong you can look back and see what
locator you tried to use and then identify if maybe
it's changed now, if something does go wrong.
Similarly in the page count here you could add some logging,
logger dot debug finding all number of
catalogue pages available.
And then you can do things like logger dot info.
Found number of catalogue pages available.
Something like that.
This is going to print an info message, so it's gonna
appear even if you've got, if you have debug
disabled but that can be useful, I think that
printing out this message can be interesting
so that in your logs if you do strip out the debug
messages you'll still see how many pages you're gonna
go through.
And that can be interesting.
And here we're gonna debug the message that we've
managed to extract a number of pages as integer.
If we fail we know that something's wrong with
our pattern or something here.
Notice how by the way I'm putting these things
around backticks, that's just to tell me that
this is a value that's come from the code.
It's not just a string.
This will appear on the logs as backtick page one of 50
backtick, and then you can look at it and see, okay,
this is something that's actually been printed from
the code and it's not just a string that we've
printed out in the logs.
And so if this is, for example, like none,
you maybe think there's an error there.
So that's why it's in backticks, so it's
a bit easier to see.
We can now go to our book parser, for example,
and see what we've got there.
And we can, again, import the login module.
And create our logger.
And that's it.
Then we can use this logger inside the module here.
We could do something like this, new book parser
created from the parent.
And this is actually going to print out the entire HTML
that you decided you wanted to create the book
parser from in your code.
So this is gonna be a really long log, 'cause it's gonna
print out the entire HTML of the parent but it
can be useful for when you're debugging something
that went wrong in your book parser.
So I'm gonna leave it as that, but you may want to print
something less verbose, less HTML code in here
if you are going to be using this extensively.
Here we print that we're finding a book name
and then down here we're gonna say that we found it.
That way if something does happen after finding
the book name we know that is a problem here
and not elsewhere in our code.
And we can do the same thing for these others.
So we're going to do that.
Of course, changing these things.
And finally, of course, we're gonna print also that
we found the thing.
We're gonna extract the price here to a variable
just so we can then print it out.
From the book price.
And this is gonna be float price.
Like that.
So again, we're just adding in here the different
things that we may need in order to understand what's
going on through our programme.
And so that's it.
Make sure to not delete the colon there,
that's gonna be pretty useful.
And then we are going to do this thing here.
I'm just gonna paste it from the code.
Like that, okay.
Well, that is pretty much it for our logging.
We could add some logging over to your menu
if you want.
It would be fairly straight forward, there's not
much logging to add in here.
But we can do it just for completeness.
Like that.
And then we can add some logging when we try to print out.
These are info messages because they're not really
concerned with how the application is working
or what it's doing.
It's more like informative messages of what you did.
And so that's why I'm making them info messages,
but again this is all a matter of thinking about
how you're gonna look at your logs.
If you're not gonna look at your logs of course
it maybe doesn't make so much sense to do
any logging at all.
And down here we're gonna do a debug message
after terminating programme.
Okay, so now we can run our menu.
This is going, again, through all of that logging.
Therefore the connection handlers and, you know,
getting all the pages and then we end up here
we can do something like B or C, and then queue.
Now, our logs file is going to be enormous.
By the way, these logs here are from earlier
because it's now 21:42, so we are going down here
these are now, we're low in the book space, this is
our programme starting again the second that we run it.
We started to get the HTTP connection
and you can see here that in the books page
we started parsing the content with beautiful soup.
Then we started finding all the books in the page
using that locator.
And it seems like we succeeded.
And then we say new book parser created from and then we
started printing out the parent.
So here we have all our article and everything that is
inside that parent that we're gonna extract data from.
And then we moved on to the next book parser.
And so from here you can see there's quite
a lot of these book parsers in here.
Should be a couple thousand, a thousand exactly.
And eventually you go down here and we say that we
finding the best books by rating.
And then we're finding a book rating and we found it for
a book that was three, another book rating was one,
and so I'm sure you can add some more information here
like the name of the book maybe.
And for which this was found.
And then we're finding a price,
and then we found a name, and so forth for the other books
that we were searching for.
Notice that when we print, when we call the repr method
of a book, that finds the name, the price,
and the rating again.
So there is definitely some duplication here in our logs.
But you know, they give us all the information we need
in order to understand exactly what happened.
And if there was an error, for example, here after we said
finding book rating, we would know that the error is
inside the rating property of our book parser.
And we wouldn't have to go searching anywhere, we'd know
that something's gone wrong there.
So the logs can be really useful, particularly when they
stop in the middle of somewhere.
You don't see your terminated programme or anything,
they just stop suddenly and you know that you've encountered
some problem there.
You normally wouldn't read all the logs, there are 31,000
lines in here, you wouldn't read them.
You would just look at them when there is a problem
and you'd see what has gone wrong.
So having good logs is important but sometimes of course
particularly after we're done developing
and we're sort of, you know, confident of what's going on,
we may want to decrease the logging level down to info
so that we can look at the logs and more or less
see what happened at each point in time.
So we can do that.
Then I'm gonna delete logs dot txt, let's delete that.
And we're on the menu again.
And believe it or not, all this level of logging actually
takes time, it slows down your application.
So that's definitely something to be wary of
when you do a lot of logging, make sure that when your
application is running and you need the performance
to not go too far.
And here we have something here, I think my rating
here was an info message but it should have been
a debug, my bad.
So this should've been a debug, I copy and pasted
it from my notes and it was an info there.
And let's delete that and run it again.
Just for you to look at what's happening there.
And there we have it.
Then we have our logs and as you can see
when we only print info
it's sort of very straightforward.
When loading the books list, found the number of
pages we're going through, then we found the best
books by rating and then we found them by price
and that was it, nothing else happened really.
And I'm sure there are improvements that can be made
to this, you'll want to log warning messages
in moments when you think you might get warnings.
Like if you are on a try except block.
In the except block you'll probably want to log
some sort of warning or error to tell you that
there was an error that happened here but you caught it.
And so forth.
And of course in some cases you cannot deal with an error
because the error happened and your programme cannot continue
and in those cases you should log a critical error.
Critical message to say the programme crashed at this point.
And you should know about that.
Debug and info messages not so useful in your logs,
so normally you would be on warn and above
when your application is running for users in the wild.
When you're developing debug and info can be very useful.
Alright that's it for this video, I just wanted
to show you really quick how to get logging
into your application, again, give you a few examples
of how the logging module works and how you can
just put it in anywhere you want and then
some examples of looking at your logs and what
sort of things you can find.
And that's it for this video, I'll see you on the next one.