Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be implementing
our first Flask application.
It's not going to be a very large application
but it's going to give us a taste
of how Flask works.
Now that we've imported the Flask class here
from the Flask module, we're ready to start.
The first thing we have to
is to use that class to create our Flask app
and every Flask app must have a unique name.
We can do something like app equals Flask
and then dunder name.
The reason why I'm using dunder name here
is just because that's always going to be unique
for an application, you know that the file you run
has a name of main and all the other files
are gonna have different names so there's no chance
of us creating another Flask app with the same name
throughout our entire application by mistake.
In this project, we're only going to be creating
a single Flask app but, you know, this is important anyway
make sure to have a unique name there.
Also, when you are seeing logs and things like that
you may wanna see there the name of the Flask app
and it can be helpful to know that this is
the main file that you ran.
The next thing we wanna do,
is define the first URL of our application.
Remember this is going to be a web application
which means users are going to be accessing this application
using their browsers like Google Chrome
or Internet Explorer.
So the first thing we have to do is say,
you know what happens when somebody arrives at our page?
What happens when somebody tells the browser
to send us a request for data?
What do we do?
So the first thing we do, is we use a decorator
to say app dot route
and then we're gonna give this forward slash there.
The forward slash on any page is always
the homepage, we're gonna see this in action
in just a moment.
Then we're gonna do, def home for example
defining a function, and as you know,
this decorator here is going to act on this function here.
So the function name doesn't really matter
all that matters is that we've got
the right decorator on top.
This function is going to run
when the user visits this route.
And for now, it's just going to return hello world, okay?
So what's gonna happen when a user visits our home page
is they're going to be received
with the words hello world.
The connection goes as follows,
the browser, the user's going to type our website
into their browser and the browser is going
to send us a request, it's gonna say hey I want
the home page.
Then we're going to run this home function
and Flask is going to take care of, you know,
communicating with the browser and sending information
over the internet and so forth,
and at the end this function is going to return hello world
and that's what we're gonna send the browser
as data to display on the webpage.
So the browser is then going to show that to the user,
the words hello world.
Finally, we have to run our app
to start the server that allows Flask
to receive connections.
The way we're gonna do that
is of course if name is main,
so that we only run this when we actually want to run it
as opposed to when we import the file,
which again we're not going to do in this section
but nonetheless it's something you may
wanna do in the future.
All we do is, apologies by that by the way,
app dot run, debug is true.
This starts running our app
and we can give it this debug flag
which usually is just here for development purposes
but it just means that we're gonna get a few more errors,
sorry a few more informations
if an error happens, so a couple of more
bits of information if something does go wrong.
We don't foresee anything going wrong with this app
but nonetheless, it's always a good thing to have here
when you are developing.
Once you share this with your users,
you may want to turn this off.
Okay so that's it.
This is our first Flask endpoint,
now we can right click app dot py and run it,
and as you can see,
we get something from Flask.
We get that it's running, we get the URL
in which it is running the address
and then you know get some debugging information here
because we've used debug is true.
This here,
is the address of the application.
When we send a request to this application
it's going to be interacting with this Flask app
what was in the request with this address
is gonna be interacting with this Flask app
and the Flask app can then choose
to return some information.
Let's go over to Chrome and access this URL.
I've accessed the URL here with Chrome
and as you can see we get the words, hello world.
I know they're a bit small there,
we're gonna look at how we can style things
much later on, but this is what the application has returned
so going back to PyCharm you can see that,
we get some more information now on these logs.
We get that on this date,
there was a request being made to the homepage,
this is the protocol used to make the request,
it's just version of you know the way the browsers
communicate with servers, HTTP 1.1.
You can see that this is a get request
and all that means is a particular type of request,
there are various types,
we're going to be exploring other types
throughout the section.
A get request which is what a browser sends
when they access the page, just asks the server
to send some information,
it doesn't ask the server to you know
make changes or add things to a database, things like that.
And there are other types of request for that.
And then we also see that the code
that the server returned is a 200
which means okay, it means everything's fine
there were no errors or anything happened
that was incorrect.
This log here, if you can see that,
means that everything's good.
Sometimes you may see more than one log,
and that's because some browsers do multiple requests
for a single page like Safari can do that sometimes,
don't worry about it.
If you can see these logs even if you see a couple of 'em,
this is good.
This means your server is running
and we've created our first endpoint.
This here is known as a route
or an endpoint and they essentially mean the same thing
and this here is the, essentially the address
of the route.
A single forward slash, if we go back to Chrome
just means nothing.
But we can access other pages
by doing, as you've probably seen in other sites,
something like posts, or something.
So you can see we've got a few test URLs here
that I've been accessing already
because what we're going to be creating in this section
is a blogging application so we're going to be looking
at various different posts.
If you access the URL here
with a single forward slash at the end,
it's just going to take you to the same page
you're already at.
And then going back to PyCharm
we can see that there's another log that appeared here.
All I wanted to say here is
the forward slash is the homepage
but we can add routes for other things.
Anyway that's it for this video.
I wanted to show you how to go about this
and I'll see you on the next one
where we're going to look at some more complex Flask.
I'll see you there.