Welcome back.
In this video we're talking about the Dining Philosophers.
The Dining Philosophers is a common problem
in computer science.
It's an example or an illustration
of a very common thing in computers.
So here we've got five philosophers
sitting around a table for food.
There is one fork between each pair of philosophers.
So we've got five forks, five philosophers
and each philosopher has endless hunger and endless food.
So let's say there's a lot of food on the table
and they are extremely hungry.
But in order to begin eating, one philosopher
must have two forks; one for each hand.
So as you can see there is not enough forks
for everybody to go around.
So how would the philosophers tackle their problem
without talking to one another?
Well,
obviously there is a problem which is if each one of them
picks up one fork.
If each one picks up their left fork, say,
or in this case their right fork,
they then are gonna wait then they're gonna
pick up the right fork and wait,
and they're gonna eat,
put the right fork down then put the left fork down
and then start again.
But if everybody picks up their right fork
and then they're gonna wait for the left fork
to become available they could be waiting
for a long time because every philosopher
is also waiting for the other fork
to become available.
None of them releases their fork
so they'll all end up starving
waiting for the other fork to become available.
So if the solution involves waiting for the fork
to become available they could potentially starve
and so we don't want that.
The problem is that if all the philosophers
pick up the fork simultaneously
nobody can pick up the other fork
so they keep waiting indefinitely
and they end up starving.
Similarly, if any of the philosophers
does manage to start eating, somehow,
taking up two forks they may never stop eating
and so the other philosophers are forever
without two forks and now they've got to share
two forks amongst four philosophers, that's even worse.
Sorry, three forks amongst four philosophers.
So what can you do to solve this problem?
There are many ways to solve the problem
and these are normally covered in concurrency courses,
computer science degrees, you know, so on.
Not gonna get into too much depth.
But normally the easiest, simplest way,
which is how Python itself does it,
is to have a waiter at the table, like this one.
So what can happen now, or the way we could restructure
our algorithm is to say that a philosopher
can request two forks from the waiter
and the waiter will give it to them if they are available.
And then when a philosopher has two forks
they're gonna eat for a fixed amount of time
and after they're gonna return the forks
to the waiter and the waiter can then
give it to other philosophers and so forth.
So something like this could happen,
one philosopher could ask for two forks
and then the waiter will be like, "sure",
take two forks on the table
and give them to the philosopher.
Now this philosopher has two forks
and all the other philosophers are doing nothing.
Then some time passes,
maybe, 10 minutes,
and then the waiter will take the forks back.
"Give me them back", and I will take
the forks back and put them back on the table.
Now one philosopher has not starved which is good.
The other four, however, not so lucky.
Instead what could happen is something like this:
We could get all the philosophers asking
for their forks, more or less simultaneously.
Remember, nothing can truly happen simultaneously.
At least, not in Python.
Okay?
Because there is a limited number of forks,
in Python, let's say.
So all of these people ask for their forks
more or less simultaneously,
but there is someone that asks for it first.
So that person, let's say number one,
is the first person on that list
that you see on the bottom right.
The next person to ask for forks was number two,
and then three, then four, and then five.
So let's say they ask for them in order.
So what happens then is
the waiter first get two forks
gives them away to number one,
number one is now on a different list, lets say.
Now he's on a different waiting area.
On an eating waiting area let's say.
Then we still have forks available,
so the waiter would take two forks
and remove two from the list of waiting for forks.
Give them the forks, and put them in the list
of, say, eating.
So now we've got one and two are eating.
Three, four, and five are waiting.
Then number one finishes eating after some time.
So the waiter gets the forks back.
Number one disappears from the eating list,
forks go back on the table,
number one goes now at the end of the queue.
Three, four, five, and then one.
Similarly after some time number two finishes eating,
disappears from there, and goes back on to the other list.
Now if we were to repeat this process
the next person to get the forks would be number three
and then number four, then number five,
and then we would start over.
So as you can see this enables each philosopher to eat.
Not all at once, but they all get to eat eventually.
So what's happening here is that we have
a limited number of resources.
In this cases forks.
And with these resources we can, at most,
run two things at the same time, two philosophers,
because two philosophers take up four forks
so there's only ever one fork left over
and that philosopher cannot eat with just one fork.
So it does not matter how long and hard we think
the simple truth is there is no way
that we can have three philosophers eating at once.
But what we can do though is trick the mind
into thinking they're all eating at the same time.
If instead of giving each of them five minutes
before releasing their forks
we give them, say, five seconds
or 50 milliseconds,
someone looking may not be able to tell
that they're not eating at the same time.
Very much like a movie.
Just a set of still images one after another.
If the passing of forks happens sufficiently quickly
we won't be able to notice that it's not happening
all at once.
So if each philosopher eats for one millisecond
it would look to an observer that they're all
eating at the same time whereas really they are not.
So remember, even if we cant see it it doesn't mean
that it's happening all that once, okay?
And in Python this is particularly important
because Python cannot run multiple things at the same time.
We're gonna look into this more very soon.
So now that we know about the Dining Philosophers problem
we are ready to move on and start looking
at how things happen in Python.
With that said,
I'll see you on the next video.