Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to talk about yapf.
Yapf is a Python formatter, in fact it stands
for Yet Another Python Formatter and it's used for things
that a linter wouldn't really catch,
but that are important still.
For example, you've got here some code that I've written.
And if you've been developing in Python for a while,
you may see somethings that are just a bit weird.
For example you got a list here, this is fine,
you've got two elements and then, you've got another
element and a new line which maybe okay.
Then you've got an element in a new line
but is less indented than the previous element.
You've got four loop here that has a colon this time,
but then the body is on the same line.
This is okay in Python, it's just a bit strange.
Then you've got a print statement, this is, we're done here.
But, it's using single quotation marks and it's escaping
another single quotation mark inside it.
It would probably be better
to use double quotation marks here instead.
But, hey this is fine, this is Python code that actually
works, you know, we can run it.
Run app py, you can see that things have printed out.
So this all okay, the linter wouldn't necessarily complain,
although, it would complain about the missing doc string.
They always complain about that.
But what about the format, right?
Well the format is also important.
You want all the code within a project
to have consistent format.
The reason for that is so that as you go from one file
to another it looks the same.
You're not encountering any jarring experiences that are
a bit strange, and also so that everybody working
on the project, if you're working with more people,
has the same standards of what a good style is
or what the style project is.
That way you're not going to, sort of, go from one file
to another and be able to know who wrote it,
just from what the code looks like.
Everybody should have a consistent style
so that the code base is the same for everyone
and it doesn't feel, some files
don't feel wrong to some people.
For that, you have the formatters.
The formatters you can, sort of, customise them
and tell them what style you want and then all you do
is run your files through the formatter and it will change
the files such that they are still valid Python code,
but sort of, rearrange the elements around to match a style
that everyone in your team likes.
So, if we go back to the terminal,
what you're going to do is, once again,
you're going to do ptp3.6 or ptp3 depending
on how many versions of Python you've got installed.
Instal yapf, yet another python formatter.
You're going to instal that and in my case,
it's already installed, possibly was installed
in a different Python version and then all you have
to do is run yapf and see if something happens.
What will happen normally with yapf is it will just hang.
Which is not a very nice way of running a programme,
but because yapf needs a file to format.
If you don't give it, I'm not really sure what's it's doing,
but it just seems to hang up.
So if that happens just press control and C and that will
terminate the programme and then you can run it again
and give it the file that you want to format
and when you run that it's going to give you the new file.
So this is what the file should look like according to yapf.
As you can see all the elements are in one line
and you've got a new line after the four loop.
Notice that yapf has not changed the single quotation marks
to double quotation marks, just because it's got
an inner escaped quotation marks.
So yapf hasn't really cared about that,
and you know I can get behind that.
I think this is okay, but there are other formatters
that would change that.
So if you like this, then you can just do yapf--help
and it will tell you the different options
you can give yapf.
So you can use -h or --help to bring this help message up.
v or --version to see what version of yapf you've got.
Then you've got -d or --dif, either of these two options
is valid to print out the difference between you're local
file and the file the yapf is creating
and you've got another one recursive in place and so forth.
Really the one we're interested in is the in place.
This is going to make changes to the file.
So if we do yapf-I app.py, nothing seems to happen.
When we go back to pycharm you can see
that the file has changed.
Now we got everything in one line and this is in two lines.
If you do decide to use pycharm,
pycharm comes with its own formatter,
so if we do this, you'll see that pycharm actually tells
us that you're doing something a bit weird here.
PEP 8 continuation line under indented for visual indent.
You find that visual indent means that this isn't a required
indent in Python, just a visual thing and it tells
you according to PEP 8, which is the, sort of,
style guide for Python this is a strange thing to do.
It also tells you here PEP 8 multiple
statements in one line.
So the four is one statement that prints another
statement that is telling you shouldn't do this.
And also, by the way, you can then put a semicolon
and put more statements in there if you want,
it's going to tell you again this not something
you want to do.
This is not something all people know about Python,
you can use semicolons in Python as well,
just like you can in Java
and JavaScript to separate multiple statements in one line,
but it's a bit weird.
What you can do in pycharm, though, is that you can select
everything and then you can go to code
and you can go to reformat code
and it'll format it if it can.
So, once again that reformat code
and that will do what it can.
I'm not sure what altering net lines
is going to do, nothing.
So has you can see it didn't quite fix this problem here
and that's because depending on the formatter
it will consider some things to be fixable, sort of,
if you do this pretty much any formatter will tell you.
You're definitely doing something
you don't want to do there.
But if you do this, in some cases you may want to do this.
In this case, pycharm's formatter
doesn't change it for you, yapf does.
So that's just a difference between formatters and there
are ways of customising the formatters.
Yapf can be customised, I'm not sure if pycharm
can be customised too, actually.
To make it change it if you want.
We're not going to go into that in this course, though,
that's for something for you to investigate if you want
to customise it more to your needs, but of course,
the little grey lines in pycharm still tell you where
you're doing something a bit strange and in that case
you can just fix it manually, if you want.
So that's it, that's how you use the pycharm
formatter and also yapf.
I'm gonna put another link to another
formatter that is up and coming called black,
that is more strict, if you wish.
It will change more things,
but allegedly for a nicer end experience.
So I'll put a link on that in the lecture
so you can give it a go if you want.
That's it for this video, though.
Hope you've enjoyed it, and I'll see you on the next one.