Hi, and welcome back.
In this lecture we're talking about understanding
HTML with BeautifulSoup.
Now that we understand the structure of HTML,
we can tell Python how to understand it as well,
and how to extract some data from it.
Because HTML is so structured,
always with its opening and closing tags,
it's fairly straightforward to get data out of it.
And as addition, as part of this lecture,
we're also going to instal our first library.
Because Python doesn't come with any functionality
to understand HTML, we need to instal a library
from the outside in order to do that.
There are a lot of Python libraries.
It's one of Python's strengths, actually.
In order to do all sorts of things.
And understanding HTML is one of these.
There are other libraries for things
like doing web development, data science,
showing up Windows on your monitor and things like that.
There's loads of libraries, and we're gonna instal one.
In order to instal your library,
we have to go over to PyCharm and find your preferences.
In Mac, it's under PyCharm community edition, preferences,
and I believe in windows it's under file
and it's somewhere down here at the bottom.
So if you go to your preferences,
then you'll be greeted with this window
that you may have seen before.
And in here, there's one section
that's particularly important for installing libraries,
and this is your project.
In your project, you can chose your project interpreter,
and here you'll see the current version of Python
that you are running.
So as you can see, I'm running 3.6.0,
because there's not that many differences
between 3.6.0 and 3.6.4, which is the current version.
But if you're using 3.7 or something like that,
you'll see that here.
Then down here, you'll see all the libraries
you've got installed.
It's possible that this will be empty
because you have just started your Python journey
and don't have many things installed,
and that's fine.
Now there are other ways of installing libraries
other than through PyCharm,
and we are going to learn how to use those other ways,
but not in this video.
We're gonna keep it simple for now,
and in this section, we'll just stick to installing
things through here.
Just press the plus icon,
and here you can see, all of these things are
Python libraries you can instal,
but Python doesn't do any sort of sanitization,
so these libraries, you don't really know what they do.
I recommend you don't go
installing random libraries from here.
Make sure you know what you want
before you go through this and instal anything.
And what we want is a library called beautifulsoup4.
It's this one here.
Notice how there are two at the moment,
beautifulsoup4-slurp and beautifulsoup4.
We want to instal beautifulsoup4.
Okay.
There are others, like BeautifulSoup
and a bunch of others.
Make sure you pick beautifulsoup4.
This one here is version three.
You don't want to go for that,
you want to go for number four, okay, and then instal it.
Because I've already got it installed,
my library is blue, as you can see,
so I don't need to instal that again,
but all you have to do is select it,
and press instal, and it should all be fine.
You don't need to do anything else.
Once that's done,
you should see BeautifulSoup
appear here like it has for me,
and then that means you are ready to use it.
Press apply, and then okay.
Once you've done that,
we can go ahead and look at our first example
of understanding HTML using BeautifulSoup.
And also we'll look at exactly what BeautifulSoup
does and why we want it.
So let's create a new Python file,
and you can name it, for example, simple_HTML.
The simple_HTML is because in this first example,
we're gonna be looking at some reasonably simple HTML
that we can understand with BeautifulSoup,
and then in the next example we're gonna look at something
a little bit more complicated.
So what does BeautifulSoup do?
Well, I'm gonna create a variable here,
which is my simple HTML,
and I'm basing it in here.
And look at how the HTML is structured into it's tags.
You can see the HTML tag, and the HTML closing tag,
and inside this tag,
you've got two children, essentially.
The head tag and the body tag.
The body tag contains a bunch of children,
like there's h1, this p, this p here,
this ul here.
The ul contains a bunch of children, which are these lis.
Ul, by the way, stands for unordered list.
Li stands for list item.
We've already looked at h1 for header one
and p for paragraph.
Also notice how one of these
paragraphs has a class, subtitle class.
What BeautifulSoup can do is
it can sort of understand this structure,
and it can determine that
head is a child of HTML,
and it can determine that there are two paragraphs.
It can look at the attributes of different elements,
like this subtitle,
and it can also do things like search,
so you can tell it I'm looking for an element
that has class subtitle,
and it will give you this p tag here.
So BeautifulSoup is used for understanding
and searching through HTML code.
By the way, just for completeness,
HTML is very similar to another language called XML.
They look, essentially, identical,
which a few minor differences.
So BeautifulSoup can also be used for understanding XML,
be we are not going to look into that in this video,
or, indeed, in this course.
So now that we've got our variable,
we have to make sure to include
BeautifulSoup into our file to import it.
And imports in Python should,
generally, go at the top of the file.
So we're gonna do from bs4 import BeautifulSoup.
Notice how we're not using beautifulsoup4 in any place?
We're only using bs4.
That's because the BeautifulSoup library has been coded,
has been programed so that the import happens like this.
Other libraries are slightly different.
In other libraries,
you may do something like
from beautifulsoup4 import something,
but in the case of beautifulsoup4, this is incorrect,
you must do from bs4 import BeautifulSoup.
That's just the way it's coded.
This doesn't mean anything specific.
And then we're going to give this HTML over
to BeautifulSoup for parsing.
Parsing is just a programing term
for understanding something that has a structure.
So I'm gonna create a variable called simple_soup
for our simple HTML,
and it's going to be BeautifulSoup, and this is a class,
so we're gonna instantiate a new object of this class,
we're gonna create a new object,
and the arguments have to be the HTML you want to parse,
and as a second argument,
you must give it a string of what type of document this is,
and this is an HTML document, so we must give it the string
html.parser.
That way, that tells BeautifulSoup to use the html parser
in order to understand this document.
And then it can understand.
Now, BeautifulSoup is able to go through this document
and fully understand it, so we can do things like
print simple_soup.find h1.
Notice how all we're doing is accessing this soup object,
this simple soup object,
and accessing the find method inside it,
and giving it what we want to find as an argument.
In this case, what we want to find
is this heading one.
Because there's only a single heading one in the page,
this is going to give us that element.
So what I'm gonna do is go ahead and run this.
And you can see how it gives us the tag that we found.
H1, this is the title, and closing h1.
If you want to find the contents of the tag,
as opposed to the entire tag,
so only this is a title,
you can do that by doing
simple_soup.find h1,
this is the tag that you want to find,
and after it you can do .string.
And then it gives you this is a title.
Notice how our h1 tag is this simple_soup.find h1,
and that is an object which has this property here,
string, that you can access.
No magic's happening here.
This all exactly else we've seen so far in Python,
we're just instantiating new objects of type tag,
in this case, and then we're accessing
a property of that tag.
If we wanted to extract this functionality
into a function, we could do that of course.
Ope, deleted one too many things there.
Or rather many too many things.
We could say something like find_title,
and this could give us this content here.
Pep eight asks me to put two blank lines
before a function definition,
and then we can, of course,
do find title here.
We don't need to print,
because that's already printing.
When we run that,
we get this is a tile.
Okay.
Now, another thing we can do,
is, for example, find the different things in a list.
Let's do that now.
We're gonna do def find_list_items,
and this function is going to print out Rolf, Charlie,
Jen, and Jose.
So it's going to go and find these list items.
BeautifulSoup is going to return them as a list of tags,
because there are many of them, and then we're going to
get the string contents of each.
Okay.
So what we're gonna do is say
list_items = simple_soup.find_all.
And this is going to give us all of the tags,
if there are many,
find is only gonna give you one.
So we're gonna do find all, and then li.
And what that's going to do,
is it's going to give us these list items that we found.
Let's print them out,
just for you to see exactly what's happening,
and I'm going to call the function down here as well.
And now notice how BeautifulSoup gives us a list of tags,
and each tag is the list itme,
and includes inside it, Rolf.
Now you already know how to extract the string
for each of these list items.
You can use a list comprehension, for example,
to create a new list
of the string contents of each tag.
You can go and do that right now.
I'm sure you managed.
All you've gotta do is say list_contents is e.string,
for example, for e in list_items.
E is the variable we're creating to go over each element
in list_items, and we're accessing the string property
of that, and putting that into a new list,
which is the list contents.
Now if we print out list contents,
you can see that we get a list of the contents,
Rolf, Charlie, Jen, and Jose.
Okay.
Let's now look at something a bit more complicated.
Let's look at this paragraph.
Let's find the paragraph.
Notice how there are two paragraphs,
so in order to find it,
we're going to have to give
BeautifulSoup some information other than
we're looking for a paragraph.
So what we're going to do, is we are going to tell
BeautifulSoup we're looking for a paragraph
that has a class of subtitle.
So we're looking for this one, not this one.
Let's do it.
We're going to define a new function, once again.
Find_subtitle.
And what we're gonna do is simply find the paragraph,
which is going to be simple_soup.find
and now we're going to give it the p tag
that we're looking for,
and then notice how the second argument is an attrs
dictionary.
This attrs dictionary is the attributes of the tag
we are looking for.
So that is, if we are looking for
something that has a class,
we're going to give it a dictionary
that represents what we're looking for.
So in this case it's going to be class is subtitle.
Okay, then we can print paragraph.string
and it should give us,
once we've run the function as well of course,
our subtitle there.
And there you have it.
And that's how you can find something that has
an attribute so that you can drill down
on a specific entity
as opposed to a more general tag.
If you've got a lot of p tags in your code,
in your HTML code, you're going to want to be able
to narrow it down using some other attribute,
in this case we're using the class.
Notice this HTML is fairly simple,
so we need to make sure to learn a bit more
about BeautifulSoup if we're going to do something
more complicated.
Talking about more complicated,
let's now find the other paragraph.
Notice how BeautifulSoup cannot do
find the paragraph where the class is not subtitle.
But what we can do is find all the paragraphs,
and then remove the one that has this class.
So let's do that.
What to do is say find_other_paragraph,
for example.
And then we're going to look at all the paragraphs,
you know how to do this
simple_soup.find_all p.
This is going to give us all the paragraphs in the same way
that doing this up here gave us all the list items.
And then we're gonna do other_paragraph is
p for p in paragraphs if the subtitle
not in p.attrs.get class.
And we're gonna look at what this gives us,
and fix it in just a moment.
And then we're going to print out the other paragraph
zero.string.
So what is happening here?
This is not quite gonna work, by the way.
But we'll fix in just a moment.
We're finding all the paragraphs,
then we're gonna put the paragraph in its entirety
inside this list, which we iterate
over the paragraphs we found,
but we're only gonna do that
if the subtitle string
is not in the paragraph's attributes.
And this dot get here is a different way of doing this.
So p.attrs, the attributes of p, is a dictionary,
as we saw when we tried to access it here.
BeautifulSoup likes these attributes as a dictionary.
So the attributes is a dictionary,
and we can access them use the square bracket notation,
or using the get method.
The get method has a benefit,
which is that it doesn't raise
a key error if it can't find it.
Instead it returns none.
So that's a benefit of the get method.
However, it's not quite gonna work.
Let's run it and find out.
And as you can see,
we get an error here.
And the error is reasonable,
but maybe not so obvious if you don't know
exactly what's going on in this list comprehension.
So it says type error, argument of type NoneType
is not iterable.
Okay.
So what is happening exactly?
We've got, evidently, something that is none.
And it's telling us none is not iterable,
which we can probably agree on,
because it's not a list or a sequence,
or anything like that.
And it's saying you're trying to iterate over it.
What are we trying to iterate?
We're not iterating over anything?
So there are two options.
Paragraphs could be none,
and then it's telling you
hey, you can't iterate over paragraphs because it's none.
So let's bring paragraphs out and see if that's the problem.
Let's run it again.
You can se that we've printed the paragraphs,
and we found both paragraphs here.
So this is not the problem.
When we do for p in paragraphs,
Python will be okay with that,
because we're iterating over paragraphs,
paragraphs is a list,
so that's fine.
The only other instance we're using in is here,
p.attrs.get.
And I just said that the get method returns none
if it can't find this thing in the dictionary, this class.
So we've got two paragraphs.
One of them has the class,
the other one does not.
So for this paragraph,
p.attrs.get class is going to be none.
And then we're checking subtitle not in none,
and what that's doing in the background,
this is going over every element,
and comparing subtitle against each element,
and saying whether it exists or not.
So here we are also doing iteration,
only it's a bit more obfuscated by the Python syntax.
But it's doing iterations,
and it's saying that, hey, p.attrs.get of class
is giving you none,
and then you're checking whether something is in it,
but you can't check whether something is in none,
because that doesn't make any sense.
Fortunately,
the get method allows us to do something
which is pretty useful.
Instead of returning none,
which is the default,
which is, essentially, this,
we can return something else
if we cannot find the thing.
So what we're going to do
is we're going to return an empty list
if we cannot find the class
in this dictionary.
That way, we're going to check with the subtitle
is not in an empty list, instead on none.
Let's run this again.
Now you can see how we found it.
Okay.
So it's important that you understand
exactly what's going on in your code
so that you can debug your errors.
But if you don't, go on debug.
We know how to debug now.
Put some print statements is also a good way.
Or, indeed, use the logging module that we've learned about
in order to check it.
Now we've looked at some simple HTML parsing in this video.
We have looked at individual items, like h1.
We've looked at multiple items, like the list.
We've looked at a specific item,
using the attributes, finding with this dictionary
of attributes, and we've also looked at
finding all the elements and then removing some
by using this p.attrs.
Okay.
In the next video, we're going to look at something
a bit more complex, so stay with me,
and I'll see you there.