Hi and welcome back.
In this video I just wanted to introduce to you
another function called sum that along with length
we can use to calculate an average of a list.
Imagine you've got your grades and you have
something like 80, 75, 90, and 100.
And you want to calculate the average of these grades.
Something you could do is you could sum up
all of the grades by doing something like
total equal sum of grades.
And this is the new function I wanted to tell you about.
You've got the sum function and inside the brackets
you put in the list or tuple or set
that you want to add together.
And that is going to add all the values together
and give you the grand total.
You've also got length which is len of grades.
And we've seen this before but I'll forgive you
if you've forgotten about this.
Len gives you the length of the collection.
So in this case, this list is going to give us four.
You can then calculate the average by doing
total divided by length.
Just like that, you get 86.25.
Now this is a perfect opportunity for a quick question.
Which of these data structures is less ideal for grades?
You've got a list of grades.
You've got a tuple of grades.
And you've got a set of grades.
The tuple of grades may seem like a bad choice
because you cannot add new grades over time.
And indeed, if you are currently in the middle
of your programme, say, and you want to be adding more grades
as students takes exams or the user gives you
some more data or something like that.
Then the tuple might be a bad choice.
But the set is actually the worst choice here
because if you have a set of grades,
you cannot have another 100 percent on another test, say.
Because if you put 100 and a 100 in a set,
one of them will be removed
because you cannot have duplicates.
So, in this case, I would say that the set is
the worst of these collections for the use case,
storing student grades.
The tuple might be a bad idea depending on
what you want to do in your programme.
And the list is the safest of them all.
It allows you total flexibility while giving you
all the power you need.
Again, remember if you do not have to add more things
to your collection, I would use a tuple.
Otherwise I would use the list.
And finally, I would only use sets for when
you want to compare sets together.
Thanks for joining me in this video.
I hope you've learned something.
And I'll see you in the next one.