Hi, welcome back.
In this video we're going to talk quickly about ABCs.
ABCs are pretty useful in Python
because they let you define some functionality
without implementing it.
We're going to leave our users and admins for a moment
and create a new file that I'm going to call,
"Animals"
and this is going to be maybe a not great example
on using ABCs in a real project
but just a quick overview of how they work
then we're going to use ABCs on the rest of our code.
So, let's say we've got a class Dog,
for example
and this,
you can initialise it with,
let's say, a name
and there is something that all dogs
or at least a large majority of them have in common
which is the number of legs,
let's say.
In a Dog,
let's say that this is going to return four at all times.
So, not the most useful method for any class,
this might as well be a property of the Dog
or maybe a class variable there
but none the less let's define it as this method.
Now, if you wanted to define another class,
let's say a Monkey
that also has,
let's say, a name
and also has a num_legs,
let's say that now returns two.
You've got a bit of a problem.
Before we said you can extract functionality
into a class like
some Animal class
and define some functionality here
and then return something
and then you could make the Dog
extend from Animal
and then you could delete this method
but you cannot do the same with the Monkey
because the Monkey has two legs not four.
So, how do you do this?
Well, here's where ABCs come into play.
Let's say that you have a bit more functionality
for each animal that you want
to make available to an Animal.
Let's say for example a walk method
and this walk method that is going to return
or print 'Walking...',
of course this could be something a bit more useful
in a real programme but now that is just an example.
Now you want both your Monkey and your Dog
to extend from Animal so that they
can both use this method walk
but you don't want the num_legs method
to be four for both animals.
So, what to do is to cut it again,
oh by the way,
let me just say this would do what you want.
This current status of the code,
defining num_legs in the Animal class,
the dog would inherit that Animal
and it would return four.
The Monkey would override the method
and would return two,
so this works
but there is a problem
which is that you can now
say that,
you can create a new Animal
and then you can print a.num_legs
and that's just kind of weird
because not all animals have four legs
but if you run this file,
you'll see that your Animal class
that isn't a specific animal,
it's not a Dog or a Monkey or a Cat,
it's just this abstract Animal class
returns four for the number of legs
which doesn't make any sense
because animals don't always have four legs.
So what to do is
to cut that and put it back into the Dog.
Now of course,
if we say a is Animal
and print a.num_legs,
it gives an error because it says,
I don't know what that is.
So, that's fine but if you have
a Dog and Monkey
and potentially let's say a Whale.
The Whale will have some code here
and the Monkey will have some code in here
and the Dog will have some code in here
and just by looking at the class
and the inheritance tree,
you don't know whether they have a num_legs or not.
The Whale should probably not have num_legs
or perhaps it should be 0.
Maybe Whales should not inherit from Animal
it should inherit from something else.
So, what I mean to say is just by knowing
that these two are Animals,
you don't know they have num_legs
but it could be interesting for you to know that,
so here comes the ABCs,
let's do from ABC import ABCMeta and abstractmethod
and then we're going to
make our Animal class inherit
but in a slightly different way from ABCMeta.
Now, ABCMeta is a real class
but it allows us to some things
that normal classes don't allow us to do
and that's using this abstractmethod.
Now, one of the great things
of having this abstract base class,
this is what ABC mean,
abstract base class,
is we can do abstractmethod
and then define our num_legs method
and then do something like pass.
Okay, so now we've defined this abstractmethod
and we've said Animal has this method,
num_legs but it's not about a specific animal in the world
its a bit abstract,
it doesn't refer to anything concrete,
so then it is the responsibility of the child classes,
like Dog and Monkey to implement that method.
Now, if we run this code,
if we run Animals,
we get an error and it says,
"Can't instantiate abstract class Animals
"with abstract methods num_legs."
Python doesn't let you create an object
of type Animal anymore
because it realises that an Animal isn't a thing
in your programme,
an animal is something that you've used
to extract functionality and give you a bit of information
but it's not something
that you want to interact with directly.
So, it doesn't let you instantiate an Animal class
because it doesn't make sense to do that.
You instantiate specific animals,
like Dogs or Monkeys
so this is how you use an ABC,
an abstract base class
and how you define an abstractmethod.
If any of your subclasses don't implement
to the abstractmethod,
you won't be able to create objects either,
so if you delete this from the Dog class
and then try to create a Dog
and then you print num_legs,
it won't let you,
so let's delete that,
run Animals again
and it says you can't do that
but as soon as you have this method in here
and you run it,
now you can and you get four back.
So, abstract base classes can be quite useful
in a number of scenarios
in order for you to know that the sub classes
will all have this method.
So you know when ever you have a sub class of type Animal
this method will be available.
Let's expand a little bit on why this is useful
in the very next video.
I will see you there.