Hi, welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be implementing
our milestone project two using our in-memory database,
which is a Python list.
I really hope you did give it a go
following the project brief
and you tried to implement this project on your own,
and hopefully you succeeded and made it work.
You can always ask questions in the course Q&amp;A
if you need help with anything specific before moving on.
But now that you're here,
let's go and implement this project
using list as our in-memory database.
Of course, the first thing we'll do
is define the user interface
so that the user can interact with our programme
and then we can add functionality little by little.
The first thing we've got is we ask the user
to enter their choice.
That's a, l, r, d, or q.
If they enter q, we're not gonna go into this loop,
so in here we have to deal with four options,
if the user_input is a,
if the user_input is l,
if the user_input is r,
and if the user_input is d.
And if there's none of them, we can print
Unknown command.
Please try again.
Okay.
Now, of course, in order to go back to the top of the loop
with a different user_input,
we must reset the user_input to something else.
For that, we're going to ask the user again,
but make sure that that's not inside the else or anywhere,
just here within the loop,
outside of any of these statements.
I also gave you a few hints
of what you could call your functions,
so I'm just going to use those names here.
So I'm going to call prompt_add_book(),
the function that doesn't exist yet, when they type a.
We're gonna call list_books() when they type l,
prompt_read_book() when they type r,
and prompt_delete_book() when they type d.
The reason why these functions have prompt in front of them
is because these functions aren't just gonna do things.
They're also going to ask the user for something,
and that's just my way of telling myself
these functions are gonna ask the user.
They have to ask the user for some information
in order to do what they wanna do.
If you wanna add a book,
you have to ask the user for the name and author.
If you wanna read a book,
you have to ask the user at least for the name.
And if you wanna delete a book,
you also have to ask at least for the name.
Okay, so let's go ahead and implement our functions.
Python styling suggests we leave two blank lines
between two functions, so we're gonna do just that,
and then we're going to define
our prompt_add_book() function.
What this is gonna do
is ask the user for name and author.
So name
and the author,
and then all it's gonna do
is ask the database to save this book.
Notice how it's not going to interact
with the books list directly,
but it's going to ask the database
to save the book to the list.
So what to do here is say database.add_book(),
name and author.
Now when we call this, we pass the value of name, a string,
and the value of author, another string,
to our add_book function,
and this is now going to use this global variable
to append this dictionary, which represents our book.
It has a name, an author,
and a read status which starts off as False.
We're going to be able to change this later on.
Okay.
Now we can delete our first comment
for we've already accomplished it.
Once again, leaving two lines, we can say list_books().
And the list_books() is just going to ask the database
for all the books
and it's going to print them off one by one.
So for book in books,
we're gonna print some representation of the book.
We can do that later.
For right now, we're just going to print the dictionary
that will come back.
Remember, we're storing dictionaries.
Dictionaries are gonna come back.
The get_all_books() function does not exist,
so we're going to create it in the database.
And what should this function do?
Well, in order to get all the books,
all it has to do is return this list here
that will contain all our books,
so just return books will do.
When we set up this programme and work with files,
this is going to get more complicated, of course.
It's going to have to actually open a file
and read the contents.
And suddenly when we move on to databases,
it's gonna get even more complicated,
as we will have to connect to the database
and retrieve the data.
But for now, because we're using
a simple in-memory database,
we can just return the books there.
Now we can delete our list_books() comment there
since we've already implemented it.
Let's move on to prompt_read_book(),
and this has to ask for the book name
and then go to the database and change it to read.
So name,
Enter the name of the book you just finished reading,
and then all we wanna do is say
database.mark_book_as_read with that name.
Of course, this function does not exist,
so we have to go over to our database.py and define that.
mark_book_as_read(),
and it is given a name.
This parameter here will receive the string
that the user entered,
and that should be the name of the book.
So how would we mark a book as read,
knowing that we have a list of books?
If you didn't try this before,
then I hope you pause the video there for a moment
and give it a go.
All to do is just iterate over the books,
and if the book was read,
if book is equal to the name that we gave it,
then say book
read is now True.
Okay, that's it.
Just go over the books and for each book,
modify it if the name matches.
Of course, this does suggest that if two books
have the same name,
they're both going to be changed over to be read,
but, you know, we can deal with that problem later on.
If you want, of course, you can change this
to take two arguments, the name and the author,
and that gives you a bit more granularity in what you do.
Finally, we're going to delete this comment here
and define the prompt_delete_book().
Once again, this is going to take a name,
and it's going to do database.delete_book() with that name.
Naturally, that also doesn't exist,
so once again we go to our database
and we define that function.
So how may we do that?
This is a slightly more interesting thing.
There are few ways in which we could delete a book.
Pause the video and give it a go if you haven't already.
One way that my students frequently come up
with removing a book is by going over
to the list documentation and see where the list
have any way of removing elements from them.
And normally we end up with this.
Go through each book.
If the name matches what we want to delete,
then do books.remove(book)
because the list objects have this .remove method in them
and they take one of the objects in the list
and allows you to remove the object entirely from the list.
So this would certainly work.
However, it is generally considered bad practise
to modify a list while you iterate over it.
That's because as you go from one element to the next,
elements are disappearing, Python will get a bit confused,
so generally not a good idea to remove elements from a list
while you iterate over it.
However, this is a way that you could do it
and it would work in the majority of circumstances.
Instead, I would
do this.
The first thing we wanna do
is say books is equal to, no, that's our variable up there,
and now we're gonna use a list comprehension
with a conditional.
A list comprehension with a conditional
is going to go adding each book over to this new list
if the book's name is not equal
to the name we got as an argument.
Add each book
to new list if book name
is not equal to the name argument that we got here,
the name parameter, sorry.
Once again, I'd encourage you to pause the video
and give this list comprehension a go just for practise.
Make sure that you've not forgotten
how to implement list comprehensions.
And if you have, then continue watching
and we shall implement it.
Okay, I hope you got that.
But if you didn't, that's totally fine.
All we wanna do is create a variable
for book in books
and then we only want to put it inside the list.
Remember, this is the value we're putting in our new list
if the book name
is not equal to the name argument.
I'm gonna delete this comment now from there
since we don't need it any longer.
So this is going to put the book element into a new list
for book in books, which is our list,
if the book's name is not equal to the parameter.
But, of course, Python doesn't quite like this
and there's a really good reason why I'm getting a red line
and this is something that you should preempt against
and you should understand.
The reason why it's giving me a red line
is because of a concept of scope.
Once again, I did mention that scope would appear
throughout the course a number of times,
and this is an important scenario for understanding scope.
What we've got now
is we have a global variable called books.
However, Python has also created
a local variable to this function.
This variable books only exist within this function here
and it is not the same variable
as the global variable books.
So now it thinks that we are setting this variable,
we're creating this new variable books,
but we are also using it in the statement that creates it.
And this is obviously nonsensical
because this variable doesn't exist yet
since it's being created in that same line.
What we have to do is tell Python
that we don't wanna create a new variable.
We want to use the global variable books.
Another option will be to rename this variable books_new,
as that, and then it doesn't complain anymore
because it realises that this variable we're using
must already exist.
So instead of looking in the local scope,
it looks in the global scope.
However, we don't want to do that
because we want to change this variable.
In order to do so, we must tell Python
that we are looking to use a global variable,
and that's really straightforward.
We just do global books.
What this does essentially is say books
in the local scope is equal to books in the outer scope,
makes them the same,
and then we can use it as normal.
Now it knows that when we use this variable,
we refer to the outer variable.
And similarly here,
we're also referring to the outer variable.
So we're not looking to create a variable
in the local scope.
Okay.
That's it for deleting books,
so we can go back to our app.py and delete our last comment.
And now we have our application completed.
Of course, I went through this quite quickly.
I'd expect you to take substantially longer
the first time that you develop this,
as per the brief,
but if you've gotten this far,
now you hopefully understand what's involved
in making this app.
We just have to get the data from the user,
create dictionaries for the books,
and then store them in a list.
Each of the other operations
is just going to go through our books and change them,
go through our books and delete them,
or just let the user read them.
I'm just going to make a small improvement
in the list_books() function.
I'm going to print something a bit nicer.
So I'm going to print
the book's name.
Now, of course, when you use the single quotes
inside a dictionary and you've got single quotes outside
in your left string, it doesn't like that,
so I'm gonna use double quotes on the outside
and just for Python's benefit.
I'm gonna say book name by book author,
and read is gonna be
book read.
So this is gonna be something
like
Fluent Python by the author,
read False
or True.
In my case, it's False, I haven't read it yet.
Okay, the author is, by the way, Luciano Ramalho.
I think that's how you say his name.
It's a good book.
You should read it.
So now we've got the name and the author.
And read, is it a True or False?
If we wanna make that a bit nicer,
we can say something like read is YES if book read,
else
NO.
This is a ternary statement in Python.
It just means use this value if this is True,
otherwise use this value here for assigning to the variable.
So if book read is True, it's going to say YES,
if book read is False, it's going to say NO.
And remember, this is essentially the same as this.
Book read is True, you can remove the is True
as we looked at in the very first section of this course.
Now instead of book read, we can just use read
since that's the variable we've created here.
Okay, let's go and run our app and see what happens.
Nothing.
Of course, we've not ran the menu() function.
So let's go over down to the very bottom
and run the menu() function, and now we see our input.
I'm just going to extend this a little bit.
We can add a new book.
Let's say, for example, Clean Code is a good book as well.
You can also read it.
It's by Robert C. Martin.
Martin.
And that's it.
We've added it.
Now we can press l to see them
and we get Clean Code by Robert C. Martin, read NO.
We can add another one.
Let's say, for example,
Test Driven Development
by Kent Beck.
Also a good book.
Now we can list them
and we can see that we've not read either Clean Code
or Test Driven Development, but we want to.
So let's go ahead and read Clean Code first.
So we type r,
and, by the way, add a space after your choice.
It's just poor planning on my part.
It just looks awful.
Enter the name of the book you just finished reading.
Let's say Clean Code.
Now we can list the books again
and we see that Clean Code says YES.
Of course, when we quit and we start again,
we don't have any books
because we've stored them in an in-memory database.
That is a database that lives in memory,
in the memory of our computer, which is volatile
and is only available for as long as the app is running.
As soon as we stop running,
the database gets erased by Python to save memory.
We don't want this.
So what we want to do is go ahead
and use a file instead.
And now you understand why
I have tried to decouple our database
from our app.
Now
nearly all the changes are going to be in the database file
for us to swap over to files instead of in-memory database.
Here's an example.
books is now not going to be a list any longer.
It's going to be a file name.
For example, books.txt.
add_book is going to open the file
and it's going to append a book to it.
get_all_books() is going to read the file
and return all the books in it.
mark_books_as_read is going to read all the books.
It's going to change one
and it's going to rewrite them to the file.
And delete_book is going to read all the books,
is going to delete one,
and is going to rewrite it to the file.
You can store the books in CSV format or in JSON format.
It's up to you.
Of course, if you store them in JSON,
it's slightly easier to work with
since we've already worked with dictionaries here.
But if you store them in CSV,
it's not much more difficult either.
In the next video, we're going to go over
changing this to use CSVs, so I'll see you there.