Hi and welcome back.
Mutable default arguments,
it's a terrible idea, so here's a common pitfall in Python
that you definitely want to avoid
and that's the mutable default arguments.
You know what mutable means
and you know what default argument means,
so let's join them both together
and let's take this function here.
I'm gonna say, create_account
and it's gonna make a name of the account,
which is gonna be a string,
an account holder, which is going to be a string,
that's probably the name of the account opener
and also, account holders, which is going to be a list
and it's going to equal an empty list at the start.
So, the logic behind this is that
you're gonna create a new account with this name,
this is gonna be the account holder
and it can have also other account holders as well
and they'll be coming through in this list here,
so you can give it a list of account holders,
so we'll say, account_holders.append(holder).
By default, when you create a new account,
you'll append the holder of the account
that you just added over to the account holders list
and if there are any other account holders in that list,
you will also use them.
And then we're gonna return
a dictionary representing our account,
so that's gonna be the name of the account,
the main account holder,
that's gonna be the holder parameter here
and then, it's gonna be account_holders,
it's going to be the account holders list.
Again, how we call this is we have, for example,
an account one, let's create account, checking account
and the holder is Rolf.
Notice how we don't have to pass an argument
to the account holders parameter
because it has a default value, which is this list,
so what's gonna happen is the name is gonna be checking,
the holder's gonna be Rolf
and to the account holders, which is an empty list,
we're going to append Rolf,
because that's the only holder in the account
and then we're gonna return a dictionary,
which is the main account holder, which is Rolf,
and a list of account holders,
which, at the moment, only includes Rolf.
If we wanted to have multiple account holders,
we could do this for example
and then the account holders would be Jen and Rolf,
because we append the opener, the main account holder
over to the list of account holders.
But let's say we don't want
to pass in an argument to this list,
we just want to create an account
and this'll be handled for us,
it would put Rolf into this list.
Then let's create another account,
let's say a savings account, but this time,
Jen is the owner of the account and let's imagine
they've got some sort of shared finances there
and we choose the owner of the account
and she's the only holder in that account,
let's say Rolf sends her the money every month.
a2 and a1 are both dictionaries,
that's what this function returns,
what are we going to see when we print a2?
This is a trick question, of course, I know
that you already know about functions and dictionaries,
so why would I ask you this?
This is a trick question, what is it gonna return?
And important, try this out first
if you don't want to be wrong.
Hopefully you tried that out.
As you can see here, what we see is the name is savings,
the main account holder is Jen,
but the account holders are both Rolf and Jen,
so how did that happen?
This function here never saw Rolf anywhere,
Rolf didn't get passed to the function,
it's not in any of the arguments,
I've not hard-coded Rolf in here, so how did this happen?
Well, what happened here is that the default parameter
for the create_account function gets evaluated
when the function is defined,
not when the function is called, so this list here
and what this parameter points to by default is this object,
so this gets created when the function gets created,
not when the function is called.
I'll make this clearer for you,
I'm going to, here, bring the id of account_holders
and run this again and notice how,
in both times we run the function, the id is the same.
When we didn't pass an argument here,
we used this list, we didn't use a new list,
we used this list and that was defined
when the function was defined,
so it's always the same list
for every time the function gets called,
so when we modify the list, when we mutate it,
that is still the same list
the next time the function calls,
so now it contains Rolf, first of all,
then it's gonna modify to contain Jen again
and if we do this again,
it will be Rolf, Jen and someone else.
So, there are two ways to solve this problem,
this is a common problem, by the way,
and not one that a lot of people realise
and a lot of people start doing this
and then they're like, what the hell is going on in my code?
I do not understand it.
So, two ways to solve this problem.
The first one, of course, is to not have a default argument,
simple enough, don't have a default argument,
instead, pass in an empty list here, these empty lists
get evaluated when the function gets called,
so they are going to be empty every time,
there's a new empty list, new empty list
and option of course.
The second option is to not make this a list,
but make it equal to none,
then you don't have to pass anything here,
because it has a default argument,
but of course, it's none, so you can't append to it,
so then, what you'll do is you'll say,
if not account_holders, so if account_holders is none,
then say, account_holders is now a list
and then you can append to it.
So, what does that do?
If you don't pass a list in here, it'll create a new one
and if you do pass a list in here, say, for example, Jen,
it will use this list and it will append to it
and the account holders will end up being the holder
and whomever else you defined in here.
So those are your two options
to avoid mutable argument problems,
mutable arguments are, of course,
any datatype that is mutable.
You can have dictionaries, lists,
you can have objects of your own types and so forth.
If you want to avoid these problems,
use immutable datatypes as your default values,
integers, strings, floats, tupples and so on,
that way, you cannot change one
and it won't change across executions of the function.
So that's it for this video,
I just wanted to make you aware
of this very, very common pitfall
so that you don't fall for this trap.
So that's it and I'll see you on the next one.