Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we are going to look at sending emails.
Sending emails with Python can be done in multiple ways.
The simplest way, though, is you can send the email
by using your personal email account.
For example, if you have a gmail account,
you can send emails using that account and Python.
Something you may not know is that emails all go,
or the majority of them go through something called smtp.
Smtp is a protocol, very much like http is,
used to communicate between two different things.
In this case, we're gonna use smtp to communicate
between our Python code and the gmail servers,
and we're gonna tell gmail servers to login using our
gmail account and send an email.
So let's create a new Python file that I'm going to call
email_smtplib.py,
and we're going to start sending email.
It's actually really straightforward when you have all
the code together.
So the first thing we're gonna do is we're going to
import smtplib.
Smtplib comes with Python and it's used to talk to
an smtp server.
Gmail servers are smtp servers and you can communicate
with them directly by using this library, okay?
So, what we're gonna do is we are going to start off
by connecting to the smtp server.
What we're gonna do, is we're gonna do smtp_connector
is smtplib.SMTP, and in here we're gonna pass in
a host name that is going to be smtp.gmail.com
for the gmail servers.
If you're using a different server, like Hotmail or Yahoo,
or anything else, make sure to figure out the smtp server
and also the port name, that for gmail is 587.
Okay, this is normally the port for smtp servers, 587.
So make sure to figure out what the host name is,
and what the port is.
Then we're gonna do smtp_connector.starttls,
and this just starts a secure connection to it.
In some cases, tls won't be required to connect
to your smtp server, so in those cases you won't
have to do this and then smtp_connector.login,
and we're gonna give him our email account,
you@gmail.com, and our password.
Of course, I'm not gonna type out
my email and password here.
I hope you understand that,
but nonetheless that is all you have to do.
Now it is possible that when you press play,
for example if we press play right now,
we will of course get an error.
In this case, username and password not accepted.
If you type in your username, email account and your
password correctly, you may still get an error,
and that will happen of course if you're using
two-factor authentication.
If you're using two-factor authentication,
you'll need to get a special type of password that your
provider will give you, which is an app password normally,
so I'm going to add a we don't string here at the top
of the file to say that, okay?
So if you get...
"An SMTPAuthenticationError even when
"your password is correct, it's possible that
"you have 2-factor authentication enabled.
"You'll need to use an App Password to log in
"instead of your normal password."
Now, particularly in the case of gmail,
there is something else, that if you don't have
two factor authentication enabled,
you'll have to allow access by less secure apps in gmail.
You're app here, that logs in with your
username and password directly, is what gmail classifies
as a less secure app.
So through your gmail security preferences,
you can enable less secure apps so that you can test this
out, and of course remember to deactivate less secure apps
once you finish learning about sending our email, okay?
If you use an app password or you enable less secure apps,
and you don't have 2FA enabled, this should work
and you shouldn't get any errors.
But of course we don't have an email that we're sending yet.
We haven't written anything to send.
So we can do that.
We're gonna use the email module that is present in
Python 3.
We're gonna say from email.message import EmailMessage.
This EmailMessage class is a way of constructing
an email message very easily, so what we'll do
is we'll create a new EmailMessage object,
and then we'll just set the subject
to be something like Test email.
The from to be your email, you@gmail.com
And the to, to be whoever you wanna send an email to.
This email will actually go to someone, so feel free to
send that email to someone you know.
Preferably don't send them to me.
I could get quite a lot of emails if we do that,
but you can send them to someone else,
someoneelse@gmail.com, okay?
Then you're gonna do email.set_content,
and here you can type in some text content
that the email will contain.
What you'll normally do in these cases, when you want
to set the content of an email, if it's, you know,
simple content, you will at some point here,
create something called email_content
and use a multi line string to say something like,
"Dear Sir/Madam,
"I am sending you an e-mail with Python.
"I hope you like it.
"Kind regards, me."
And then you can just set the email content like that.
Now that you've got your email and you've got
your connection to the smtp server, all you have to do
is say smtp_connector.send_message,
and you're email object that we created up here,
and that has all our headers, subject, from, and to,
and the content, and then remember to quit
the smtp_connector as well.
That closes the connection to your account,
and all is good.
This is all you need to send an email, using your
personal account as well as taking care of the security
concerns of your email provider.
Of course, for many apps, as soon as you release them,
and you sort of put them out there, give them to your
users to use, you don't really want to be sending email
with your personal account, so a stop cap
can be to create another gmail account that is
for your business, but gmail doesn't really like that,
so what we normally do, instead of using smtplib,
which is a way to send, you know, a few emails.
What we do instead normally, if we want to send a lot
of emails, is we use an email sending service.
There are a couple of them like Mailgun or SendGrid,
and in this course, we're going to be looking at Mailgun
in order to be sending email to
a larger scale of users.
So this is how you can send email with smtplib
to send small amounts of emails,
using your personal account.
In the next video, we're going to look at using Mailgun.
I'll see you there.