Hi and welcome back.
In this video, I wanted to show you
a couple of commands that you can run
in order to navigate your computer using the terminal.
These can be quite handy.
The commands I'm going to show you
are only going to work on macOS10 and on Linux,
but I'm going to give you the windows equivalents as well.
So when you are on
macOS10 or Linux,
you can type P-W-D
and that tells your the folder you're currently in.
So in my case I am in /users/jslvtr.
On windows, this will be dir for directory.
If you want to move to a different folder,
you can do cd for change directory,
and then you can type whatever folder you want.
So for example, if you wanted to go to your desktop,
you could type desktop.
Notice how now I am in my desktop here
and if I type pwd, I am now moved to my desktop.
On windows, this will be chdir for change directory.
Now of course the desktop folder that we've just moved into,
is inside users/jsslvtr.
Otherwise, it would tell us folder not found.
For example I'm now in my desktop.
If I try to do cd, into an asdf folder,
it says no such file or directory.
So you have to make sure that the folder
you want to move into is inside
the folder you're currently in.
However you can also choose to move to a particular folder
even if it's not inside where you currently are.
In order to do that, you have to tell your computer
the absolute path to that folder,
starting at the very root.
In windows, you would do change directory of C,
going to C:\users\something
or C:\data\whatever
and in OS10 and Linux you do cd /
which means the root of your computer
and then you could do something like,
/Library/Python/ and so forth.
Then you can change directly into this folder.
This is where I am now.
As a small aside, if you want to go back
to the previous folder, you can just type cd -.
And this, I don't think works on windows,
it just works on macOS10 and on Linux.
If you want to look at what currently is
in one of your folders, all you have to do
is type the ls command.
On Windows, this will also be the dir command.
OK.
So let's go over to one of the
scraping books project for example,
that we created earlier on in the course.
Then we can type the ls command and we can see
that we've got a few things here.
Some of these things are newer,
you may not have seen them yet because they are part of
the asynchronous development section.
The project here has been modified slightly,
but don't worry, all is good,
what we've covered in the course has not changed.
This is just some new stuff I've added.
And you can see that we've got here
app.py, we've got this async_request.py,
menu.py and so forth.
There's even some folders you may not have seen before.
Like this __pycache__ folder.
That is fine, you don't have to worry about the pycache,
it's jus a Python thing.
Now, if we wanted to run this project here,
we could do that by,
in my case I'm going to type python3.6
because I remember when we started this project
I was using Python 3.6, python3.6 menu.py
and then our application starts running
and you know, we've got some extra logging
that we added later on.
I know that you've maybe not seen this,
but nonetheless our programme starts working
and then you'll see the menu up here
and you can interact with it.
This is, just your programme running
as if it was running inside Python,
now it's running inside this text console
that you've got here.
However, we had to run Python 3.6
in order to run this project.
If we wanted to create a virtual environment
for this project so it was separate
from the system installation of Python 3.6,
we can do that.
All we have to do is a virtualenv venv --python=python,
I'm gonna use python3.7 for this virtual environment.
This is going to create a brand new virtual environment
and now when we type ls, we can see that there is
a virtual environment folder that wasn't here before.
This is the Python installation
that we have copied into here.
It doesn't have any of the libraries that it had before.
So if we activate,
by doing this remember to do,
(clears throat) apologies
\venv\scripts\activate.bat on windows,
don't do that on mac, but do that on Windows.
So if we activate and we try to run our menu,
now it says no module named whatever it is that we needed.
And again, this had changed slightly since the last time
that we saw this project, but nonetheless
Beautiful Soup would also be another one
that wouldn't be found.
If so, all you have to do is pip instal
and you know, instal everything that it asks you
ask it asks you it.
We can then repeat, and by the way,
I am cycling through all commands by pressing
the up arrow in my console.
Now it says "requests couldn't be found" so we can
instal requests
we can also instal Beautiful Soup 4
and I think that's it.
There you have it, now the programme is running.
We've installed all the libraries
in our virtual environment that we needed,
and our programme is now working.
So that's what we need in order to make it work.
Now, if you type pip freeze,
this is going to give you the libraries that are installed
currently, in your version of Python that you're using.
The version of Python we're using
is the one in our virtual environment.
So this gives us the libraries installed
in our virtual environment.
Notice how they're in the format of aiohdp==3.0.5.
So we've got version 3.0.5 of this library.
We've got version 2.18.4 of requests and so forth.
And it's fairly frequent, when using virtual environments,
to actually save these into a file.
And just so you don't forget, that these are the versions
you've got installed in this virtual environment.
When you give this programme to someone else,
they can then go and instal the exact same versions.
So we can create a new file and put this content in it.
You can do that in Python,
or you can do that in any other editor.
Or if you want, if you're using macOS10 or Linux,
you can do pip freeze into requirements.txt.
All this does is it says,
all the output of pipfreeze, instead of printing it out,
dump it into this new file called requirements.txt.
OK, now if you were to open requirements.txt,
you'd see that it contains all of this stuff.
OK, in macOS10 and Linux,
you can do the cat command
in order to see the contents of a file.
So as you can see, when I do cat requirements.txt
you can see the contents of the file here.
Now, why is this useful,
if now I'm going to go and to pip instal?
If you share this with someone else,
they're gonna have to go and do pip instal aiohttp,
I mean do they do this, do they do ==3.0.5
in order to instal this specific version?
Yeah.
This is what you do in order to instal
version 3.0.5 of this library.
But if you share with them, this requrements.txt file
they can actually do -r requirements.txt.
So pip instal -r requirements.txt
and then they're going to go through and instal
all of these libraries, these specific versions of them.
So as you can see, this can be really good
to share everything you need for a project
with someone else.
For example, if you're working with someone else,
or if you want to participate in some sort of team,
you're probably gonna want a requirements.txt file
so that you can share it with one another,
and make sure that you're all using
the same versions of libraries.
If one person on the team is using a specific version
and someone else is using a different version,
you may actually encounter some inconsistencies
in some things that may work differently.
So make sure to not do that,
and by having requirements.txt file is a great first step
towards making sure that you're all on the same page.
So that is how you would instal everything
from my requirements.txt file,
and as you can see, it's all pretty straightforward.
Over the next few videos, we're going to look at something
even more important when working with these projects.
And also, this new thing that we're going to look at
in these next few videos, is actually the recommended way
of managing projects and dependencies in Python,
as of Python 3.7.
So stay with me and I'll see you on the next video.