[Jose Salvatierra] Hi guys, and welcome back.
In this video,
we're going to be learning about variables in Python
and how to show information to the user.
After all, programming is mostly about
taking data in from users
and giving them data out after doing some processing.
So being able to show users some data
is an essential part of coding.
Let's begin by defining a variable.
I'll say age equal thirty.
This is how you define a variable in Python
and give it a value.
You first state the variable name,
then an equal sign,
and then the value that you wanna give it.
If you want to print an age,
all you have to do is say print
and then inside brackets,
the thing that you want to print out.
So here, we've created the variable age
and given it the value thirty,
and then we are going to print it out
and show it to the user.
All Python programmes start off by running on a text console.
Something like what you see here on the right.
What that means is that for the foreseeable future,
all our Python programmes are going to be dealing in text.
They're going to receive text from the user
and they're going to show the user text.
If we run this programme,
you'll see that thirty gets printed out
because that is what our programme does.
I will be keeping this code for you to see,
so if I'm deleting things and moving things around,
don't worry about it,
you'll be able to see the complete code
in the resources section just linked
so you can go and have a look.
Instead of printing age,
you can print thirty directly
and that's totally fine,
it means exactly the same thing.
Because age was a name for the value thirty,
you can just use the value thirty directly
and this will always be the case.
Instead of a variable,
you can always use the value that that variable refers to.
However, there is a key benefit of having variables,
which is that if you define an age variable to be thirty
and then you print it out,
then you can change the value and print it out.
And now you only have one variable or one name,
but initially it was a name for the value thirty
and then in line four we changed it
so that the name age is now a name for the value forty.
So if we run this,
you'll see that thirty gets printed out first,
as we do in line two,
and then forty gets printed out after.
So this is just how variables work.
You give them the name,
then an equal sign,
and then the value.
If you want a longer variable name,
for example, something like friend age,
usually in Python you will use the underscore character
to separate different words.
In other programming languages
you may do something like friend age like this,
but Python developers don't like that.
We use friend underscore age.
And variable names can contain underscores
and they can also contain numbers if you'd like.
But they can't contain anything else,
so you can't put dashes in them or any special symbols.
In addition, variable names cannot start with a number.
Here's another example of a variable
that uses this type of separation between words.
In programming,
this type of separation is called snake case,
so maybe something to remember
in case you want to search for it in Google later on.
If you have a variable name that you are
arguably never going to change,
then we usually write those all in uppercase letters.
So for example, the number pi,
which is 3.14159,
you would write that all in uppercase,
because you're never going to want to change it.
This is just a convention,
and what it tells you when you're reading this programme
is that this is a constant,
so it's never going to change.
You can still change it, though,
but it is just not recommended.
Another example would be something like this.
When you do radians to degrees,
this defines a new variable
and the value is one hundred and eighty divided by pi.
So this is how you create variables and give them values.
Now we're going to be looking at numbers
in a bit more detail,
so that we learn more about how mathematics works
in Python.
See you in the next video!