Hi guys and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to learn about pack.
Pack, you can think of it as putting the components
in the window where they fit,
given that they adhere to certain constraints
that we give it.
Pack can be a little bit confusing
and a little bit unpredictable at times.
This is why, in this video, we're going to explain
how pack behaves by giving you many examples.
Let's start by creating a couple of labels.
And here, I'm using tk labels as opposed to ttk labels
just because we don't need the themed
or the styling of those labels at this point.
So we're gonna put two labels in the root.
Okay, here, we have two labels
and we have placed them in the root.
Now, if you remember correctly,
whenever you run a code like this,
you won't get anything in your window
because you've not packed the components into it
or you've not placed them.
I'll say at this point that as well as pack,
there are other algorithms for placing components
in the container, but we're only learning about pack
in this course.
Let's give these labels some text, so I'll say Label 1,
and some background, which will be green.
And the other one is gonna be text equal Label 2
and the background is going to be red.
Then we're gonna pack them.
So the first one, we will pack on the left
and the second one, we will pack on the top.
Let's run this here.
You can see that they appear side by side
even though one has been packed on the left
and the other one has been packed on the top.
So what does side mean?
Well, you can think of side as the anchor point
to the component.
And what that means is that this component, Label 1,
is glued to the previous component or the window
by the left side of it.
By contrast, Label 2 is glued to the window on the top
and not on the left.
You can see that that happens as you expand the window.
The Label 2 keeps being stuck at the top,
but Label 1 is stuck on the left.
As the space expands, Label 1 has no knowledge
of vertical distance because it is glued on the left,
so it always stays in the middle,
and Label 2 has no knowledge of vertical distance,
so it stays on the left
as close to where it originally appeared as possible.
Next up, let's use fill.
So we will say fill equal y
and fill equal x.
Let's run this again.
And now, look at what happens.
We have filled on the y-axis, the left
label,
and that means that it now takes up as much vertical space
as is available.
So the background and indeed the entire label
spans the whole vertical space.
Similarly, Label 2 spans the whole horizontal space
or as much as is available,
but there is a gap here where the green label is.
Because the green label was added first, it takes priority,
so it fills on the y-axis first
before Label 2 has a chance to expand.
If we do the other way round, putting Label 2 first,
then you'll see what I mean.
So now, Label 2 is glued at the top, Label 1 is on the left.
As we expand this, you can see that Label 2 now takes up
the entire area because it takes priority.
It was put in there first.
Let's go back to this.
Instead of x and y, we can do both.
And here is where it starts to get interesting.
So we've got both of these labels here
and as we expand, you'll see that nothing happens
that is different from what we had before.
That is because even though these labels have a fill
that tells them to take up all the available space
on both x and y,
there is no available space on x and y.
This label here only takes up this much space horizontally
and this label here only takes up
this much space vertically.
That comes to mean that you can only fill a label
cross-axis.
So if it has a side of top,
then you can fill it in x.
And if it has a side of left, you can fill it in y.
Unless
you use expand.
And we're gonna learn about that in just a moment.
Now, if you remove fill both from one of them,
then this is what happens.
The label stays in the middle of the axis
that you told it to.
It doesn't have any knowledge of the vertical spacing
and indeed it doesn't take up that space.
However, the space is still reserved for it,
so this label cannot span into that.
Now, let's use expand.
So we'll do fill
equal both
and expand equal true
in just the one label to show you what happens.
Now that we've got expand equal true,
what that does is it requests from the container
as much space as possible,
so that the other containers don't shrink
past the minimum content width.
So this is a little bit confusing.
But essentially, Label 2 still gets to keep
the space it needs to show its text.
Label 1 takes up all the other space
and because it has fill of both,
then it takes up the entire space there.
Notice that if we say fill only on y here,
now, this label is still taking up all of the space,
but the component itself is only taking up
as much of the y space as possible.
The rest of the space is still reserved for it,
but it is not being used.
Next up, let's make both labels side top
and both labels with fill both and expand true.
Now, what happens is that both labels are stuck to the top
of the previous element.
So Label 1 is stuck to the top of the container,
Label 2 is stuck to the top of Label 1.
And in both cases, they're gonna take up
as much room as possible
and they're both requesting all of the space.
In that case, it gets shared 50-50,
so both labels will fill in the y-axis
as they would normally because side is top,
and both labels grow on the x-axis
because they both have expand equal true.
Whichever side comes first gets the expansion priority.
We mentioned this earlier briefly,
but let's create another label in the root
with text of Label Left
and the background is going to be green.
And we're going to pack it on the left
with expand equal true
and fill of both.
Now, these other labels are gonna stay on top
with fill both and expand true.
And I'm gonna make this one red as well.
So if we do this and we press play,
you'll see that the side of left gets the expansion priority
and takes up all of the horizontal space,
and these labels here are only taking up vertical space.
That is because they have a different side
and they were placed afterwards.
If you do it the other way round,
you'll see that now, the opposite happens.
These labels take up all the horizontal and vertical space,
and this one is left with basically nothing.
I would recommend that you play around
with a lot of these different examples.
It took me a long time to fully understand what's going on
with these before moving on.
Finally, something worth mentioning in this example
is that even though this label has a side of left,
it still appeared underneath these other labels.
And that is because when you anchor a label
and give side of top, it takes up the whole
vertical space available.
Anything after it will appear underneath it.
Similarly, when you give a side of left,
it takes up all the vertical space
and the next element will appear on its right.
So this is what happens when the first element
has a side of top.
And again, going back to the previous example,
if you have a side of left first,
this element takes up the entire vertical space
and all future elements appear on the right.
So this element took up the entire vertical space.
The next label appears on the right
and it takes up the whole horizontal space,
so the next label appears underneath it.
So this one has also taken up the whole horizontal space.
So if we have another label top,
it will also appear underneath it stacked.
But what happens if we add another left?
Well, because the previous label has a top,
this one also appears underneath.
So the label itself's side is irrelevant
where it is placed.
What matters is what previous elements have as their sides.
Okay, so now, if we put another left,
given that this previous one has a side of left,
you'll see that it appears here.
So this one took up all the vertical space,
then this one took up all the horizontal space,
then this one takes up all the horizontal space,
then this one takes up
all the vertical space that's remaining,
and this one appears next beside it
since there is no more vertical space to go around.
So as you mix and match these spaces,
essentially, the distribution changes,
but what matters is what the previous element
had as their side.
If the previous element had a side of left or right,
if it has one of those two,
then that takes up the whole vertical space.
And if it has a side of top or bottom,
it takes up the whole horizontal space
and the next element will appear accordingly.
Please, again, do play around with these.
Play around with expand, fill x, fill y,
and with different configurations of these labels
to really grasp how pack works.
And if you have any code snippets that you don't understand
how they work, do put them in the course Q and A
and we will be more than glad to help you understand them.
Thanks for joining me in this video.
Hope it's been interesting and you learned something.
And I'll see you on the next one.