Hi, welcome back.
In this video, we're going to look at MailGun.
MailGun is one of a family of email sending services.
And MailGun, in particular, I like because it's
really straightforward to use, and it's not,
you know, the most powerful
email sending service in the world,
but it sort of does everything you need
to send simple emails using Python, or indeed,
any other programming language.
Now, if you want to send an email using MailGun
to anyone in the world, you need to have a domain name.
For example, mailgun.com is a domain name,
and collabacode.com is a domain name.
If you don't have a domain name,
you can still go through this lecture
and learn about using MailGun,
but you'll only be able to send emails to yourself.
So, that's just something to take into consideration.
If you don't have a domain, the assumption is
you don't have people who want to receive your emails,
or who have signed up to receive your emails yet.
So, that's why they don't let you send emails to people
if you haven't got a domain name registered with MailGun.
And so, what we're gonna do, in order to learn about
sending emails with MailGun is
we're going to first sign up.
Now, to sign up is free, and it takes
57 seconds, allegedly.
I'm sure it takes longer than that.
But here, all you wanna do is, you know,
fill in the details.
You will not need to add payment info now, if you want,
at least not at the time of recording,
and you wanna stick to the free plan, okay?
If you add payment info, it's going to put you on
the pay-as-you-go plan, which means,
in the unlikely event that you do an infinite loop
of sending emails, you will have to pay.
So the best thing to do, don't add payment info
if you don't wanna pay, and that'll give you the free plan,
and you won't be able to go over it.
So, in case you make something wrong,
nothing bad will happen, okay?
So, just fill in your details, click "I'm not a robot,"
and then you will have your account.
Now let's go over to what happens
when you have an account already.
When you log into MailGun, you'll be received with something
that looks more or less like this.
A couple of things are very different
because I have a domain that I've added to MailGun already,
and you won't have that.
But nonetheless, you'll have sort of a dashboard.
If you go over to your domains list,
you'll have a sandbox domain, such as this one.
With a sandbox domain, you can only send emails
to the email you signed up with.
So, in my case, that's up here on the right,
jose@schoolofcode.me.
This is an old account.
I no longer use School of Code.
If you're interested in our stuff,
it's CollabaCode now, .com, in fact.
So, this sandbox domain, you can click on it,
and you'll be received with some things here.
And default SNTP login.
This is the email account that you can use using SNTP.
You've got an API-based URL,
you've got a password, and you've got an API key.
So, the SNTP login and the password
are used to log in via SNTP,
as we saw in the last couple of videos.
Two videos ago?
Yeah, I think so.
Or the last video.
Nonetheless, when you are sending emails using Gmail,
you can instead swap that for
this default SNTP login and default password,
and you can send emails using SNTP, using these two things.
The other option is to go on a more Pythonic scale
and use the API.
Using the API is pretty straightforward.
All you need to do is instal requests
and run an API request.
So, we're gonna look at using that in this video.
Okay, now in the authorised recipients,
you're gonna wanna add your own email.
So, this is actually quite new.
It used to be you could only send to your own email,
but it seems that now there's a new thing.
So, you can invite yourself, and there, in my recipient,
and I'm guessing I'll get an email saying,
"Hey, confirm you wanna be emailed by this guy,"
and we're gonna say yes.
So, if that's the case, I'm sorry about
the misinformation earlier.
This is the new way to do it, apparently, which is good.
And that's it.
So, all you need, now that you've invited
your authorised recipients is get the API-based URL
and the API key, run with these details,
and go over to PyCharm, where we will continue
setting up this and sending emails using MailGun.
So, let's go over to PyCharm after we copy this.
We're gonna put MailGun API URL.
It's gonna be this, and MailGun API key
is going to be this key.
There you have it, now we have our two
different values here.
What we need is also a way to store
who the emails are coming from,
who they're going to, and sort of the subject
and the content of the email.
Okay, so FROM_NAME is going to be Jose, in this case.
FROM_EMAIL is going to be jose@schoolofcode.me.
TO_EMAILS, and this is going to be a list of emails,
is going to be another email, another@gmail.com.
And you can put multiple emails there if you want,
so you can send emails to more than one person.
The SUBJECT is going to be "Test e-mail" for me,
and the CONTENT is just going to be a simple content,
"Hello, this is a test e-mail."
Okay, now we've got all our data.
And notice how these are all constants in Python.
Constants in Python are always uppercase,
and that just means we're not going to change them.
Then all we have to do is import requests,
so we're gonna do import requests.
If you don't have it installed, just instal it
in the environment that you're using for this project,
and then we do requests.post, and here it goes.
We're gonna put MailGun, MAILGUN_API_URL.
This is where the request is going to go to.
Then we've got an auth variable here,
and the auth variable is a tuple.
So, the first element of a tuple is API,
and the second one is API_KEY.
Okay, so there's a tuple there.
And all this says is the request is gonna go through
with some data to the API URL,
and in that data it's going to contain
this authentication data.
This is called Baisc Auth.
This is Basic Auth, and essentially,
it just contains sort of a key and a value,
and they can identify you with this value here.
It's not terribly secure.
It's not the most secure way of doing things,
but it is basic and simple.
And then we're gonna have a data dictionary,
and in this dictionary, we're gonna have a from,
which is gonna be the FROM_EMAIL.
Then we are going to have a to.
That is going to be TO_EMAILS.
We're gonna have a subject.
That is going to be the SUBJECT.
And text, that is going to be the CONTENT.
Now, where is FROM_NAME used?
Well, this from is actually not meant to be just an email.
It's meant to be a f strain that contains
the FROM_NAME, and then FROM_EMAIL here as well.
Okay, now we've got here the name
and the email's coming from,
and this format, I'm sure you've seen it before,
like when you get an email through,
I'm not gonna say a legacy system,
but through something like Outlook or something like that,
normally it's like Rolf Smith, and it's like
rolf.smith@example.net.
So yeah, it's normally in this format,
and this is the format we're replicating here as well,
and MailGun understands that,
and it allows us to give a name to the sender,
so that when somebody receives it,
they'll see who it's coming from,
as opposed to just an email.
Okay, I'm gonna put this in the same line,
just because that looks a bit nicer to me.
And that's it.
Once the authorised recipient is successfully authorised,
you can run this, and it'll send the request
through the MailGun API URL.
It'll authenticate you with your API key,
and then it'll send this data over,
and they will do all the hard work of
constructing the email, making sure it's sent,
and of course, it's really simple to put this in a function
and make it take a few parameters,
and very easily you can send email to multiple people.
So normally, when I am making a new Flask application,
I don't wanna send emails.
All I do is, honestly, this, I put in a function,
and then I call that function from
multiple parts of my application,
and it's really simple to send emails with that.
We're going to look, over the next couple of videos,
at how to sort of organise this email sending method
a bit nicely, and that way you can reuse it
in your applications if you want.
So, that's it.
Try it out, let me know if it works,
and hopefully you enjoyed learning about
sending emails using MailGun.
The same method, by the way, or a very similar one,
will apply for other email sending providers like SendGrid.
That's it for this video.
I'll see you on the next one.