Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're talking about how to structure
your programme and be better to deal
with HTML parsing.
So, the first thing I want to do
is I'm actually going to select everything
in my file, in my middle HTML file,
and go and create a new file that I'm going to call
class HTML parsing, for example.
And I'm gonna paste it all in.
And what I want to show you is a way
that you can structure this, so that instead of
just single functions, you have something
a bit more self-contained, a class.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to put all of this,
except the HTML, all of this into a class
that I'm going to be calling ParsedItem, for example.
And this is going to be a class to take in an HTML page,
or part of it, and find properties of an item in it, okay?
So, it's gonna take in a page, or potentially
a section of a page, and it's going to do self.soup
equal BeautifulSoup of page on html.parser, okay?
The good thing about this is that now,
let's say you have a page that has many of these articles.
You could create a ParsedItem for each of those articles.
And the only thing you'd have to do is, sort of,
get the article tag and parse it into here
and then this item would be something
that represents that section of the page.
But, of course, these functions all have to be in there,
right?
They all have to take in self, self, self, and self.
And you don't need two spaces anymore,
PEP 8 doesn't like that inside the class.
Then, instead of soup, you're gonna do self.soup.
And what's happening now is that for this soup
that you've created when you parsed in this portion
of the page to this class, you're going to be able
to find the name and the link and so forth
for each item.
So, if you had many articles, you could just give each one
to this class and this class would find,
inside the article, the item name or the item link
and so forth.
Now, in order to make them actually find things,
instead of printing things out, we're gonna return.
So, instead of print, we're going to return.
And you're gonna see how easy it becomes
to deal with all this stuff.
I'm gonna delete this print matcher group there.
And then we're gonna return him, as well.
You're gonna see how easy it is
to deal with this stuff now.
'Cause all you have to do in order to get something
out of this item is to say ParsedItem ITEM HTML.
This can be your item and then say something like
print item.find item rating.
Then, run the file and you get Three out.
So, what's the benefit of this?
Well, you've done encapsulation, now, essentially.
You've encapsulated all the logic,
you've stored all the logic away inside this class
and now you can reuse the class
for each of the articles you've got on your site.
You don't have to, sort of, wonder about trying
to get any drilling down into specific articles
using more complex locators.
What you could do is if you have a larger site
with many articles, say something like
soup.find all article and then for each parsed item,
p for p in that.
Something along these lines.
We're gonna look at exactly how it would go,
but I just want you to see that then you would end up
with a list of these parsed items and each item
would be able to find its own rating or price
and so forth.
If you want to make it even better,
you can just remove this find item
because the class is already called item, you know,
you don't need find item things.
All you need to do is know the item's rating,
the item's price, the item's link,
and the item's name, and you have yourself,
essentially, something that could come from HTML,
or it could be a class that maybe comes from
adjacent or something like that.
It's a nice API for the data.
If you want to make it even better,
you can add a @property tag in front of each.
And this is now very simple,
item.name.
And that's what you have at the end,
A Light in the Attic.
Now, when you're interacting with an item,
you don't know if this is coming from a database
or if it's coming from a CSV file
or if it's coming, indeed, from some HTML
that you're parsing.
You don't know and you shouldn't have to care
when you're doing that.
So, this is a great way of making your items
much easier to work with when you're writing
something in a different part of the programme.
So, I just wanted to quickly tell you about
this method of structuring your parsing,
so it's a bit easier to work with.
So, that's it for this video.
In the next one we're gonna look at
another improvement you can make,
which is much shorter, and then we'll be moving on.
I'll see you there.