Hi, welcome back.
This is a small, side video.
What I just wanted to tell you
about this dark theme I've got.
I like developing on a dark theme, but a lot of people don't
and I actually just realised this as I was
recording the video, that I'm working on this dark theme
and it's probably not the best thing to do for recording.
I don't want to you suffer through my developing
in a dark theme if you don't like it
and for recording we're going to swap over to a white theme.
Also, sorry if you do like the dark theme 'cause we are
going to be using a white theme.
But, nonetheless, I wanted to show you that you can change
from white to dark if you prefer it, so all you have to do
is go over to your Preferences
and in here in Appearance, you can choose your theme.
So you can go to Default
and that will be the white theme.
So that's what we're gonna be using throughout the course.
My apologies that the last video was in dark theme,
we're going to stick to this theme, okay.
This gives you this white theme.
Now, by going back to the Preferences
you can also change your editor,
and in your editor, you've got your fonts
and you've got a bunch of other things here
like your colour schemes and things like that.
For the
I'm sorry I don't know why this is here.
For the recording, I'm going to go over
to my colour scheme font and I'm going to choose
a different scheme, there is quite a few and that gives you
like different colours of your fonts, like for example
Twilight will give you a font that looks like this.
Darkula will give you a font that looks like this.
And I'm going to go with my recording scheme
which is one I created that has a nice readable font
and it's quite large so you guys can see it in the video.
So that's how you can change the font,
the colours and the theme in PyCharm,
just in case you want to do that before you
start developing, and there is quite a lot
of fonts that you can use for developing.
Normally I recommend monospaced fonts, that's fonts where
all the letters have the same spacing around them.
All the letters are the same size,
that just makes things a bit easier when you're programming.
And if you're interested in knowing some of the fonts
that I like for programming, just feel free to ask
and I'll be happy to tell you.
Anyway, that's it for this video.
Just a small side video to tell you about these themes
before I make you suffer with my dark theme.
Now, we can move on to the next video and we're going
to start developing this milestone project.