Hi and welcome back.
In this video we're going to talk about a topic
that nobody talks about in online courses
so I hope you're excited about covering this one.
And that's the Python GIL.
The Global Interpreter Lock.
This is a pretty advanced topic
and we're not going to go into all the technical text,
but we re going to cover what it is,
why it's there,
and what it means for us.
So when you launch a Python app,
you actually get a new Python process.
We know now what a process is,
a process is at least one thread and some resources.
So the process can deal with going into a core,
coming out of the core, reserving some resources it needs,
like access to a file or something like that.
So you get one thread in Python, you get the main thread,
but you can make more threads if you want.
When you launch a Python app you get a thread that runs
through your Python code from top to bottom as we've seen,
but you can make more threads if you want.
We're gonna look at how you can do that.
But given that we know
only a single thread can run in a core at once,
why would you, what's the benefit of making more threads?
Well of course the benefit of making more threads
is so you can run one in each core.
If your computer has more than one core, you can get
Python to make two threads and run them in two cores
at the same time.
Not so fast.
Due to how Python has been implemented,
so the people who wrote Python, you cannot run two threads
in one process at the same time.
So if you have your Python process create another thread
the main thread and that other thread are not going to
be able to run at the same time, even if you have two cores.
And that's because each process in Python creates a key
resource, a critical resource, and when a thread is running
it must acquire that resource.
And every process creates only one of these.
Okay, think of it like a core, except it's not a core
it's just another type of resource.
The process creates this unique resource
and when a thread is running it must acquire it.
And Python is going to check that your thread has
that resource before it runs it.
Because there's only one of those resources,
you can only run one thread in that process at once.
So you may think, well why is this resource being created?
And that's a good question,
we're going to go into that in just a moment.
The resource in question here is called the GIL.
That's the resource that the process creates
and the threads must acquire.
The GIL is the Global Interpreter Lock.
And a lock is a specific type of resource in threaded code.
So this is what the process creates,
this Global Interpreter Lock.
A thread must acquire it then they can run,
and then they must release it for another thread to run.
So you cannot run two threads at the same time.
Okay, so what about multiple Pythons?
I'm sure you have run multiple Python apps before
and they ran side by side, right?
Well yes, we can launch multiple Python processes
like we saw and just by opening another Python app
and that's fine because each process creates it's own GIL,
Each process creates it's own thread.
But they cannot collaborate,
you cannot have collaboration between processes easily.
I mean there are ways to do it but it's not free,
it's quite expensive, it takes a lot of computing
power to communicate between two processes.
That's just how computers have been designed
so that you can have separate resources in each process
and they are completely separate entities essentially.
They cannot easily share data.
For example, if you have some variables in one process
you cannot send the values of them to another process
and receive responses back, it's not that easy.
Whereas it is quite easy when you're doing threads.
So what is the point of threads in Python then?
Python allows you to make threads.
What's the point of threads?
Sometimes when you go to conferences or you talk with people
people will tell you threads in Python,
they're crap, you shouldn't use them.
Because using threads is not free.
It takes some computing power to,
as I said in the last video, remove them from the cores
put them back in, so when you have threads you can actually
see your Python code become slightly slower.
So what is the point of threads?
If they can not run at the same time,
and also they can make your code slower.
Well, let's say you have a Python programme
that does two things, just these two.
One of the things it does is it does a complex
mathematical operation, something that takes a long time.
Let's say that thread, this operation takes a long time
because it's a complex calculation, your computer
has to do a lot of things in the CPU,
in your processor in order to arrive at a solution.
And it also does an entirely separate thing, this programme.
Which is it collaborates with a user.
It asks the user for some input, then it greets them or
it lets them pick something from a menu
or something like that.
This operation can take a long time
because the user can take a long time to type.
So you can see that there are
two different things going on here.
Number one,
your computer is being used to perform calculations
and number two, the computer is not being used
because it's just waiting for the user to type something.
But the whole operation of asking for the input
and greeting the user can take a long time
because of that wait.
So in a single thread you can do one of these two.
First do your mathematical calculation,
which is going to take a long time
because there's a lot of things to do
and then you can sort of interact with the user,
ask them for something and greet them back.
But notice how this one, there's also quite a wide rectangle
that was my way of signifying that this can take a while
because the user has to type,
and the user's typing normally takes a long time.
So this is one option, single threaded code,
or of course you can do the reverse.
You can ask the user for something first,
and then you can run your mathematical calculation after.
In either case, these threads end up taking
a reasonable amount of time.
This single thread ends up taking a reasonable amount
of time overall.
So we can instead do cooperative multitasking.
But you must remember, no matter what we do
we can only run one thing at a time.
So here's what cooperative multitasking
would look like in Python.
This is one of the exciting bits about Python, by the way.
First you would run some of the user code,
where you would ask the user for input.
And then you'd immediately release the GIL
and run your mathematical calculation.
Remember, when the user thread releases the GIL
another thread that is waiting
can then acquire it and use it.
And that thread is going to continue running
until they release the GIL.
So when the user responds,
this code is then going to have something in it to say hey,
if the user responds release the GIL.
So we release the GIL and we go back to the user
And here we can greet the user, which is really quick
because we're just constructing a string and printing it out
and then we can release the GIL immediately
and go back to running our mathematical calculation.
Notice how the yellow segment is smaller now in conjunction
because what we have removed,
all that bit there,
was our code waiting for the user to type.
And because of threads, we no longer need to do that.
Okay?
Because now our threads are only running
when there are things to do in the computer.
When the user is waiting, or we are waiting for the user
to type, or some data to come into a programme from some place
we don't have to be waiting.
We can be doing something else during that time.
Notice that this bottom set of rectangles would take
slightly longer than just the addition of the user
and the mathematical calculation
because of the threads communicating with one another,
GIL being released, GIL being acquired.,
and being put in the core and then removed from the core.
So there would be a little bit of overhead
but overall, it would take less time than the one above.
So going back to what the point of threads in Python is
is to reduce waiting time.
That's about it.
If all your threads are doing things in Python,
if all your threads are using your CPU, your processor,
multiple thread is not going to help you in Python.
Because Python doesn't do very well that
running things in parallel.
And the reason this works is because the OS is going to
give priority to threads that are doing things.
So in this case out mathematical calculation thread.
So if a thread is waiting, it's going to run less frequently
because the OS is going to realise there is a thread that
wants to use the CPU, and there's a thread that doesn't.
So it'd probably run the one that does a bit more often.
So that it gets way more time on the CPU.
Okay, that's it for this video.
I just wanted to tell you about the Python GIL
and now you know that you cannot run two threads
at the same time in Python under the same process.
But there are things you can do in order to
make your code more efficient with the use of threads
if your code involves waiting.
That's it for this video, I'll see you on the next one.