Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to not use virtual environments
but use something else that builds on top of them
in order to make dealing with these projects and
dependencies a little bit easier.
Enter pipenv.
Pipenv, spelled like this, is a new library
that has now become the standard for managing
projects and dependencies in Python.
Virtualnv was the standard up until maybe a year ago or so.
But now pipenv has taken over just because
it's slightly better and slight simpler to work with.
The first thing we have to do is
delete the virtual environment we've already created
if we are going to use pipenv instead.
In order to delete a virtual environment,
make sure to stop using it by typing "deactivate".
If you type deactivate, once you've activated
you will come out of the virtual environment.
I'll show you exactly what I mean.
I'm going to do activate/venv/bin/activate, or sorry,
source venv/bin/activate and then deactivate
will just bring you out of it.
As you can see, the venv inside the brackets disappears
and we're back at our normal Python.
You can double check by typing which Python
and you can see that we're no longer using the virtual
environment's Python here, you're using the system Python.
Okay, then we're going to remove the virtualnv folder
that we've created so we're going to do rm -rf venv.
I'm not actually sure of the Windows command, so
I'll make sure that it appears here on the lecture.
But what this does, is it deletes the folder that
we've created called venv, so just type that.
When you type ls again, you'll see that the venv folder
is gone, it no longer exists because we have now removed it.
This remove command is what it does, it removes things.
Then, the next thing you must do is make sure you use pip,
and make sure you use pip 3.6 or 3.7 to instal pipenv.
I've already got it installed, but if you don't have
it installed and you get some sort of error, you may have
to do pip3.7 instal dash dash upgrade pip.
That, and just allows pip to upgrade itself
to the latest version.
And then you'll be able to do pip3.7 instal pipenv again.
Once you've got pipenv installed,
all you have to do is type pipenv,
and then you get all the commands and
usage examples that you may need.
The most important one is the instal, okay?
If you have a requirements.txt file already created
then typing pipenv instal is going to use that
requirements.txt and it's going to instal all the packages
in that requirements.txt into the new environment.
Notice the first thing this does, it creates a virtualnv
for the project, and then it, sort of, it goes through
and it instals a bunch of things and it creates
a pipfile, and it creates a pipfile.lock, we're
gonna explain what these are in just a moment.
And at the end, you have your set up complete.
If you type ls, you can see that there's a couple more
things now, you've got a pipfile and you've got pipfile.lock
Let's open up the pipfile to see what's in it.
So I'm gonna do cat pipfile to see the contents
of the pipfile, so these here are the contents
of the pipfile.
You've got a source url, that's where you're downloading
your packages from.
Verify_ssl, whether you want to make sure that the
certificates you're using for ssl are correct.
The name of where you're downloading from, that's a source.
And then the important part here,
are the packages you've installed.
And notice how they are coming direct from my
requirements.txt file.
So, this is all good.
The pipfile.lock is much longer.
As you can see, it is quite long and it has
a lot of stuff in it.
I typed the command up here,
so all of this is my pipfile.lock.
And what this is, is a bunch of hashes.
And these hashes are the version,
and sort of the some of the contents of the
libraries that we've installed and coded into this.
So, essentially, the entire library
has been converted into this number.
If the library changes, the number will change.
So what is the point of having these numbers?
Well this number is a representation of the library,
like if the library changes, the number changes.
So let's say that somebody hacks into the place
you're installing your libraries from, and then
change the library without changing the version number.
You could potentially instal the hacked library by accident
because you wouldn't have a way to tell.
But if the entire library is converted into a number,
and this number is generated from the library,
so that if the library changes, the number is going to
change as well, you're not going to be able to instal
a wrong library by accident, because now you're checking
against this hash.
Really, the way this works is quite complex,
but that is the general idea behind it, so that
if the library changes, with or without you knowing,
you're not going to accidentally have installed a wrong
version or a hacked version, essentially.
So that is the purpose of the pipfile.lock.
Now we can remove our requirements.txt file,
because all of it's contents are inside our pipfile.
Instead of sharing a requirements.txt file with people,
you can now share a pipfile and the
pipfile.lock with people.
If they have both of those and they type pipenv instal,
the pipenv is gonna get the contents of the pipfile
and the pipfile.lock and make sure
to instal everything that you need.
Now because we've got a pipfile.lock, we don't actually need
a couple of things inside our pipfile, which get added there
by virtue of us having a requirements.txt file.
So if you remember the requirements.txt file had the
version numbers of everything we needed.
But the pipfile.lock also has the version numbers
of everything, and it has added security, which is
this number that is generated from the library.
So now, we have the version numbers and the security
on the pipfile.lock and on the pipfile.
We don't need it in two places, so we can actually tell the
pipfile to instal any version of the library.
Then, pipenv is going to make sure
to instal the one in the pipfile.lock.
So, let's go ahead and modify our pipfile.
And I'm going to do this by using the vi command.
I'm going to type vi pipfile, this is not available
on Windows, you may want to just open
it with a notepad or with PyCharm.
But this is going to let me modify this folder here,
and all I'm going to do is remove the version numbers,
and replace them by asterisks.
Make sure to not forget the quotation marks around things.
That can be quite a dangerous things to forget.
Now that we've got all of these, using any version,
as opposed to a specific version, we can save that,
that is what I've done there.
I'm not going to go into how vi works in this course,
it's a bit more just different content, it's not really
more advanced, it's just a bit different,
and not really the place for that.
But now that you've modified the file, what the pipfile is
saying is "these are the libraries I need."
What the pipfile.lock is saying is
"these are the versions I need."
So now you have these two files here, the pipfile.lock has
a lot of information and exactly what you want to download,
and if it doesn't match exactly, you're gonna get an error,
and it's gonna say, "hey, we're trying to instal this, but
it doesn't match what we thought it should be,
this number, so we're not gonna do it."
And that's for security.
And the pipfile is telling you,
"these are the libraries you need."
So this now is a better setup, a more secure setup
than just using requirements.txt and that is why pipenv
has now become the new standard
in Python for dependency management.
Once you've got your pipfile and your pipfile.lock created,
and you've done your pipenv instal, what's actually
happened in the background, we saw that earlier up here,
is that there was a virtual environment created.
Let's have a look at what this virtual environment
looks like in the very next video.
I'll see you there.