Hi, welcome back.
In this video, I'm going to show you
how you can re-use your Mailgun sending code
just by putting it inside a library file
and calling it from your other code.
So this is just a re-factoring of this code here.
I had to make it up at night,
but nonetheless, I thought I should show you
how I do this normally in my other projects.
It's really straightforward.
What we do is in your project, you'll want to have
a new Python package that you're gonna call libs.
And normally, you'll have a package like this one
in most projects as long as you're using
other external services.
In this case, we're using the external service Mailgun.
Mailgun gives us an API that we can interact with
but there is a small issue of sorts
that here we're not really, in terms of our code,
we're not really interacting with Mailgun directly.
When you read this code, it's a bit too raw.
You can see that what you're doing is
you're making a request to some API
and then something's happening and so forth.
And unless you know exactly what this API is doing,
it may not be immediately obvious
that this is sending an email.
Of course, you now know what this code does
and if you see a post request to something
called Mailgun, you know what Mailgun is,
and you see a from, to, subject, and text,
you can probably guess this is sending an email.
But what I need to say is that this code here
isn't what you'd read as send an email.
You'd read this as make a post request to someplace.
So it's always a good idea to put this code
inside a function and call that function
send an email and that way when you read
in some other part of your programme, send email,
you'll know that that function is sending an email
and you won't have to worry about
whether it's sending a post request or a get request
to some place.
So with that said, we'll go into our libs folder,
create a new Python file.
I'm gonna call this Mailgun dot py,
because this is gonna contain our Mailgun library.
This is going to be a Python file
that is going to encapsulate that sending of a request.
And it's going to encapsulate it
and call it in a bit nicer way.
So we're going to import requests in here.
Then we're gonna have our class Mailgun
and this class Mailgun is going to have a few properties,
an API URL, API key, and also a from name and from email.
So we're gonna paste those in here.
Now the assumption for this class is
that these are all static properties,
they're never going to change
and so we can just set and hardcode the values in here.
This may not be true for your project.
Maybe you'll want to be sending emails
from different people and in that case,
you'll wanna re-structure this slightly.
I'll show you how in just a moment.
Then, we're going to have a class method in here
that I'm gonna call send email.
And this is going to get three arguments:
the emails that you wanna send an email to,
the subject, and the content.
Now, okay?
And then what we're gonna do is,
we're gonna copy this requests.post
and instead of Mailgun API URL,
we're gonna do cls.Mailgun API URL.
Instead of Mailgun API Key,
we're gonna do cls.Mailgun API Key.
And instead of to emails as a constant,
we're gonna do to emails, the parameter.
Subject is also going to be the parameter.
Content is also going to be the parameter.
And of course, from name and from email
should also be inside CLS.
That's it.
We're gonna remove this comment here.
Let's assume we already know what that does.
And really, that's everything you need.
You put in here your API URL and your API Key
and you can hardcode your name and your email
that you're sending from.
If you don't want to hardcode them
because your application requires
sending from different places,
just add them as arguments here.
From name, from email.
And if you want, you could even make these
constant variables by default.
Make sure to use the right thing here.
But because my applications normally have a single email
that is sending the emails, I normally don't do this,
but you could do it and then just replace them here as well.
And that would be a way of making this a bit more flexible.
That's it.
You have your Mailgun class that can send emails.
Now when you wanna send an email anywhere
within your application, all you have to do is say
Mailgun dot send email and give it the email subject
and content.
So we're gonna create a new file inside the project
and I'm gonna call that using Mailgun lib dot py.
And this is gonna do just from libs Mailgun,
import Mailgun class.
And then we're gonna do Mailgun send email
and this is gonna go to test@gmail.com.
The subject is going to be something like test email.
And the content is going to be "This is a test email."
It could be anything you want.
That's it.
You can now send emails.
What's this say?
Oh, of course, I've put the list in there.
We don't wanna put the list there.
This is the emails that this email is going to.
In this case, it's just a single guy or woman.
And if this is the title or the subject,
and this is the content.
If you want to call this a bit nicer,
you can say to emails is that.
You can then say subject is that.
And you can then say content is that.
So that's just calling it a bit nicer.
It's up to you what you do, of course.
Normally, I think I would do it this way
just because it's pretty clear
that the email is gonna go to this email.
And then you may wanna put subject and content here
just to make sure that nobody gets confused.
Maybe they think this is the content,
this is the subject.
If you call them with named arguments,
that's just a little bit clearer,
maybe a bit nicer way of doing it.
Whenever you want to send an email from your application,
all you have to do is call your Mailgun library
send email function, or method, sorry,
and that'll send an email.
So this is a bit of a nicer way
of structuring your email sending
and this is actually what I use very often,
a library just like this one in many other projects.
There is an issue with security
if you put your API key inside your code.
You don't want to put your API key inside your code
if you're gonna share that code with other people,
but that is a bit more of an advanced concept,
how you're gonna secure your code
if you're gonna share with people and so forth.
Not something we're gonna cover in this course.
But there are ways of doing that.
It's just a little bit more advanced
and you have to worry about sharing your code
with other people first
before you start worrying about security.
That's it for this video.
I hope you've enjoyed structuring this application
in a bit of a nicer way,
and I'll see you on the next video.