Hi guys and welcome back,
in this video we're going to learn about for loops.
A for loop is used to repeat something
a defined number of times.
That is,
when you know how many times you wanna repeat it.
But a for loop in Python has a slightly different way
about it that in other programming languages.
So if you're coming from a different programming language,
this is more like a foreach loop.
And if you don't know what I'm talking about,
don't worry let's learn about it.
First of all I will start with a friends list,
which has the names of my friends.
And then we would create our for loop.
What we want to do is we want to print the names
of each friend separately into its own lines.
So what we'll do is we'll do for,
that is the key word that signals
that we want to start a for loop.
And then we will do friend in friends.
Print friend.
So a few familiar things going on in here.
We've got the colon,
we've got the indented body of the loop,
but we do have something a bit weird going on in this line.
Friend in friends,
we learned that this was Boolean comparison,
earlier on right?
But what is friend?
We've not defined this variable anyway.
And here's the thing,
this is not a Boolean comparison.
What's going on here is you're telling Python to give you a
new variable called friend once for every friend.
So we're saying,
friend will be the first element in friends.
Then when the loop repeats again,
friend will now be the second element in friends.
Then friend will be the third element in friends and so on.
This is why it uses also the in key word,
but it means something different
than if you use it anywhere else.
In the for loop you've got for, new variable, in, list.
And then you get one iteration of the loop,
or one repeat of the loop for every value in that list.
Note that instead of lists you can use tuples,
you can use sets or dictionaries here,
and that's totally fine.
Those are all known as iterables,
because you can iterate over them,
you can use them for exactly this.
So this is well and good when you've got a few values,
and you wanna do something to each of them.
But if you wanna repeat something say 10 times,
you can do something like elements equal zero to 10.
And then you can do for index,
which is a new variable,
you can call this whatever you want by the way.
In elements and we will print index.
What this is doing is now we're going to
repeat this loop 10 times because there are 10 numbers here.
So by running this we will see
that we get the numbers zero to nine printed out.
So we are getting the numbers zero to nine,
but we don't have to print them out.
We can print something else like hello world.
And we know,
that because there are 10 elements here,
this loop will run 10 times and therefore,
we will get 10 hello worlds.
So what I'm trying to say here is that just because
you are getting a variable for each element,
you don't have to use it for anything.
And usually when you do something like this where you
create a variable but you don't use it inside a loop,
we often in Python give it the name of underscore.
So we just call it underscore,
and that usually signals to other Python programmers
that you don't intend on using this variable for anything.
You could if you wanted to,
because that's a valid variable name,
but this signals that you don't want to.
Of course you can give it any other name you want,
and that's fine.
I will go back to for index in elements just because
I think it's a little bit more readable for you guys.
But instead of creating our own list of 10 elements,
you can actually just do range 10.
And this is pretty much the same thing
in that it will also run 10 times.
What range is doing behind the scenes,
it is creating something similar to that 10 element list.
But it comes with a few more powerful things,
such as you can do five comma 10 inside range,
and this will give you the numbers five to 10.
So five six seven eight and nine.
Or you can do something like two twenty and three.
And what this does,
is it gives you the numbers two to 19,
but only every three numbers,
so two five eight 11 14 17.
Now these are just some of the things you can do with range
and I don't expect you to get much use out of them just now.
But it is one of the reasons to use range over
creating your own list of 10 elements.
It's a lot shorter,
it also more convenient and more powerful.
Imagine you've got a list of dictionaries,
where each dictionary contains
the name and the grade of a student.
You could do for student in students,
and remember what we've got here is
the for key word the student,
the new variable we are creating every iteration,
and in students which is our list or our iterable.
We can then get the name of each
student by doing student name.
Now remember student is each of the values in the list,
so that's the first time the loop runs,
student will be this dictionary here.
The second time it runs,
student will be this dictionary here,
and then it will be this one,
and then this one.
So by doing student name,
what you're going to do is you're going to get the name key
of this dictionary the first time the loop runs,
and you're going to put that inside a variable name.
The second time the loop runs,
you're gonna get the name property of this dictionary,
and you're gonna put that inside this variable.
And then you're gonna repeat that for
this dictionary and this one too.
Lets do the same with grade.
And finally lets use them for something.
Lets run this and you'll see that we can print this
information much more nicely rather than
just printing out a dictionary,
by using this for loop and saying
Rolf has a grade of 90, 78, 100, and 80.
So when do you want to use a for loop?
When you want to repeat something a certain number of times
and you know how many that is,
or when you want to use each of the values of an iterable,
such as a list, tuple, or set, or dictionary,
and you want to do something once for each of the values.
I hope you've learned something in this video.
I know that we're looking at a
lot of different bits of Python,
and maybe right now you don't quite
understand why they're all important.
But very soon everything's going to come together
and we're going to be able to develop very useful programmes
just with the knowledge we've got so far.
So thanks for sticking with me,
hope you've enjoyed it,
and I'll see you in the next video.