Hi welcome back.
In this video I wanted to move that abstract class
into our other code just to give you another example
of where this can be useful.
Going over to our saveable.py remember that
it's got this save method that calls a to.dict method
but the saveable class doesn't have that method defined.
However, it relies on a subclass like admin
to implement the to.dict method.
Relying on the subclass to implement the to.dict method
is okay, but it's even better if you can force the subclass
to implement the method.
And now that you have ABC's and abstract methods, you can.
So lets go ahead and implement this using an ABC.
So from abc_import, ABCMeta, and abstractmethod
and now we can define the to.dict method
using this abstract method, we can say to.dict
and then just pass it which means it doesn't do anything.
Now this is happy because it says, "Okay I can see that
"there is a to.dict method defined."
But it doesn't actually do anything in this class.
It only does things in the to.dict.
The whole purpose of the abstract method is to
force the subclass to implement the method that it needs.
Again, the fact that we have this saveable class now
means that admin is an instance of saveable.
And that can be quite good if you want
then a list of saveable things.
You can then call save on each of them
even if they're not all admin objects.
If we cut the saveable from here,
and we put it into user.py,
now user becomes saveable and admin is also a saveable
because it's a subclass of user.
So again, admin has a to.dict.
So when we say some admin object.save,
it'll call admin's to.dict.
If we have some user object and we call save
it'll call the user's to.dict, which doesn't exist
so we have to implement it.
So just like that.
Now the user has a to.dict, admin has a to.dict which
overrides it and they both can be saved by using
the saveable class.
From now onwards you can refer to saveable as an interface.
By the way, sorry, I forgot to define this metaclass there.
This is important of course,
otherwise it doesn't make much sense.
Python won't be able to understand what's going on.
So saveable here is a super class because it's
an abstract class, you can see it's a class here.
In many other programming languages,
this would be known as an interface
because it defines the functionality that
should be in a subclass.
That's what an interface is.
An interface is not a class that you can instantiate.
It is a thing in programming that
defines what a subclass must do.
So in those terms, and to adhere to that definition,
this is an interface, but because it has this save method
that it is actually implemented, we can't say that this
is an interface in the traditional sense.
However, I quite like these quote unquote Python interfaces.
I like them because you can define them as interfaces.
Just say subclasses must implement the to.dict method.
And you can also add some functionality that
is shared amongst the subclasses, like this save method.
In Java for example, you can define interfaces as something
that is separate from classes, completely different things.
So you can define in Java things like these.
The subclass must implement this method.
But in Java you cannot define or at least you couldn't when
I did Java a long time ago.
You couldn't define the save method.
You couldn't say the subclass will be able to
do this as well and implement it.
So pretty useful in Python that these interfaces
can have both definitions of what the subclass must
be able to do, must implement, and also provide some
functionality that will be shared among subclasses.
And this is what an interface is in Python.
It's as close as you're gonna get.
You don't have defined interfaces like in other languages,
like in Java, but you do have abstract methods and ABC's
which allow you to force subclasses
to implement particular things.
And then of course if we go into app
and you have some users.
You'll have to import user of course.
You can then naturally have a list of users,
and then, save them all like that.
This is perfectly fine because each user is a subclass or
implements the saveable interface.
Because they all implement the interface,
you know that they're all gonna have the save method there.
If you're not sure when you're going to use this,
don't worry the purpose of me teaching you about these
advanced concepts in object-oriented programming is not
so you'll immediately get some ideas on what to do with them
but as you develop more, maybe when you get a job doing
Python development or maybe if you already have a job
and you're working more and more with Python, you will find
yourself a situation where this will
be the perfect thing to use.
And knowing about it is going to
let you design programmes much better.
Of course try it, give it a go, write the code,
download the code that I've made available in this section
and play around with it so that you do internalise it.
Otherwise, a few months on the line you will have forgotten
that this exists and if you do encounter a situation
where you'll need this, you won't remember.
So make sure to play around with it and give it a go
and I'll see you in the very next video.
We're going to talk about something else.
I'll see you there.