Hi guys and welcome back.
In this video we're going to learn about frames.
As you can remember from the previous video,
we have three labels.
Two of them that have a side off top
and one of them that has a side off left.
And what that means in practise is that
each of these takes up the entire
horizontal space.
And finally, the label that is with side left
has to appear underneath them.
If we want different behaviour to this,
we can use frames to contain certain labels.
So, let's do from tkinter import ttk,
and as well as the root,
now we're going to define a main frame,
that is placed inside the root.
We're gonna say main.pac,
and the side is going to be left.
And fill is going to be both
and expand is going to be true.
Now we're gonna place these
two labels with side of top,
instead of in root,
we're gonna place them in main.
And we're gonna leave this final
label with a side of left.
Now here's what's important
about this distribution.
The main frame is the first element
inside the root.
The label is the second element inside the root.
These elements affect each other
because they're both inside the frame
but they won't affect this one
because they're not inside root.
So when we do this,
we get this distribution,
which is different from before.
Now this here
is the main frame
and this is the label.
Both are side left.
Both have fill both
and expand equal true.
What it means when two components
are on the same side
with the same fill
and the same expand
is that they are gonna share the space
equivalently as long as that's possible.
So as long as the elements inside them
don't take up more space.
That means that you get a 50/50 split here.
These two labels are inside
the main frame
so they have a top anchor in both occasions,
and they both have fill both
and expand equal true,
which means they take up 50% of the available space.
We create frames in tkinter
precisely to do stuff like this,
to group together components
that we want to affect each other,
but not other components.
By using multiple different frames,
we can achieve the layouts we want.
Pack() is a very powerful
and very flexible algorithm
for putting components into a window.
But as you've seen throughout
the last couple videos,
it can be a little bit confusing
and also depending on the size of your window
and also on the order in which you put elements,
things can change in how it behaves.
This is why there's other algorithms as well
as I've mentioned before.
But we won't be looking at them in this course.
For most simple applications,
to get data from users
and to show them data back,
pack() is a perfectly valid and useful algorithm.
And it is very simple.
You just say, "pack()", which side you want,
and whether you want components to expand or not
and there you go.
You don't have to worry about positioning,
or grids,
or layouts and all that.
Hopefully this makes sense.
Thank you for joining me in this video
and I'll see you in the next one.