Hi guys and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be testing our printer class.
Let's go over to the test printer and add our input
and then create our TestPrinter case.
Now let's write our first test.
So we'll say test_print_within_capacity.
And we'll say that the printer is a new printer
that has a certain number of pages per second,
let's say two pages per second,
and a capacity of 300.
And I believe that this should be a float.
Apologies for that,
you do want a float there
just in case you can print 2 1/2 pages per second.
Now we've got our printer object here,
and we can sway print 25 pages.
Now there are two things that you could do here.
You could say that the test passes
if the correct message is returned.
Alternatively, you could say the test fails
if an error is raised.
So if you think the test should pass if there is no error,
then this is an sufficient test.
Because if you run it, you'll see that no error is raised
and therefore the test passes.
All tests pass by default unless there is an error in them.
Alternatively, you could say that the message is that,
and then you could say self.assertEqual message,
or rather, printed
25 pages in 12.5 seconds
is equal to the message.
Oh, that should be 12.50 seconds
because we formatted it to two decimal places.
And I have a error here.
So you can see how writing this message out is actually
potentially a helpful thing.
There you have your test passing.
Either of these is correct.
I personally would not check for the message.
I would have a separate test for that.
I would just check that the printer prints.
Now for all our tests that we'll be writing,
we'll be using a printer object.
So in order to reduce duplication,
we can extract this and put it into a separate method
that we'll call the setUp method.
And you don't need this return none, that is implied.
So we'll say self.printer is a printer
where the pages per second is 2.0
and the capacity is 300.
And then what that means is you no longer need that,
but you do need to use self.printer.
Now this setUp method here runs before each test.
So if you have multiple test methods,
this one will run before each one.
So you always get a new printer every test.
If you want to run this method only once
for the entire test,
then you will do setUpClass,
ad you will get rid of this self here,
and you could do cls.printer is this printer.
And of course you do need to make this a class method.
And here you can still access the self.printer
and it will know that you refer to cls.printer
just because of how Python's inheritance works.
You would choose one or the other purely depending
on whether you want a new printer every test,
or you want to reuse the same printer for the tests.
Because the printer has a state that varies over time,
and that is this capacity here,
I strongly recommend
that you do not share the printer across tests.
So I would make this into a normal setUp method like that.
The reason for that is because if you write a test
that uses up all of the capacity,
then you have another test
that tries to print some more,
but you've run out of capacity so the test would fail.
if you have one printer for all tests.
By having a printer for each test,
you don't have that problem
because you always get a new one for each test.
So whenever you have state that changes in the object,
create a new object for each test.
Do not share objects across tests.
All right, I just wanted to show you
about the setUp and setUpClass,
and also I wanted to tell you
that there is a tearDown and tearDownClass.
So you've got tearDown and tearDownClass,
these two methods here,
in case you wanna run something after each test.
That you can do of course.
That's everything for this video.
Thanks for joining me in this one.
I'll see you in the next one,
where we're gonna continue with some of this.
I'll see you there.