Hi guys and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be writing some more tests
for the printer just to give you a bit more practise
and show you a couple more things.
Let's begin by writing a test for printing outside capacity.
Like we did earlier, we will do with.self.assertRaises
and now it'll be a PrinterError that we're gonna catch.
We'll do self.printer.print 301.
Notice that we printed 25 pages in this nest.
So, here we could, in theory, do 276
in order to still breach capacity.
No, that's absolutely not correct.
I hope that you didn't believe me there.
You're getting a new printer for each nest
because we've got this setup and not setup class.
Remember exactly what I said there,
this dependency between two tests is a bad thing.
You do not want that.
So, you do need 301 pages in order to breach capacity
because this printer is a new printer related to this one.
Okay.
So, this should raise a PrinterError.
And indeed as we save the file, these tests run
and you get two out of two.
Notice that if we do 276, the test fails there
because the printer is a new printer.
So, it says PrinterError not raised.
Hope you didn't believe me there.
So, next one is we are going to print the exact capacity.
So, we'll say test print the exact capacity.
And we will do self.printer.print, self.printer.capacity.
Now this is a private property
or at least a property that has an underscore in front it.
So, in theory, you should not use it,
but really what it means in Python
is you should not change it, but you can still read it,
and that's what we're reading here.
So, we're going to print exactly up to the capacity
of the printer, and this is an important one to check
because it is very frequent
that you will have something like this in your if statement
is a fairly mistake to make
and then you'll see that it fails.
And you will never be able to print the last page
in your printer.
Even when your printer has one page left of ink,
if you have a check like this one,
you won't be able to print it
because one will be equal to one,
which is the capacity left.
So, you want to do,
if the pages is greater than the capacity,
you want to raise the error.
So, if pages is one and capacity is one,
you will still print.
If pages is one and capacity is zero, then you won't print
and you'll raise an error.
Okay.
So, this is an important one to check,
a very frequent mistake.
Next up, we could test the printer speed,
and this is really what we're doing here.
So, you could write a separate message
that says test_printer_speed
and then you can have a pages 10
and an expected message of printed 10 pages in 5.00 seconds.
Then you will get your result,
which will be self.printer.print 10 pages,
and then self.assertEqual the result
and the expected message.
I would do this instead of checking the message here
and then I would remove this and put it there.
That way, you have two tests that do two separate things.
If you get an error because you run out of capacity
just by print 25 pages, even though the capacity is 300,
then you're gonna catch it with this test
and not with this one.
Similarly, for example, let's say that you set capacity
to 300, but you have hardcoded capacity to 20 here,
then your test will fail.
Self.printer.print 25 fails
even though you've set capacity to 300
because you hardcoded it to 20 here.
This could happen for example if you forget to make it equal
to capacity and instead you hardcode it to a value
while you're developing the class.
That's why I'm a big fan of having separate tests
that do separate individual checks
as opposed to one that does multiple things.
Of course, sometimes you're not sure
if your test is testing one thing or two things.
It can be difficult to gauge,
but don't worry too much about it,
just do the best you can
and I'm sure that, over time, you will get better at it.
Next up, let's test that the speed here
or how many seconds it takes
is always printed out to two decimal places
and not, say, 10.
So, we will say that we've got a new printer
called fast_printer, that is, another printer object,
where the pages per second is 3.0
and the capacity is also 300.
The pages we're gonna print is 11 and the expected message
is printed 11 pages in 3.67 seconds.
This is important because the way that Python will do it
if you divide 11 by 3.0 is it'll be 3.666667
and you don't want that normally
when you're giving a message to a user.
So, we will say fast_printer.print pages
and then we will do self.assertEqual
the result and the expected.
Okay.
So, run this and look at the tests passed,
five out of five.
If you go back to your printer and you take away this .2f,
you'll see that this test then fails
because you get first of all 5.0 seconds instead of 5.00
and then you also get 3.66665.
I thought it would be seven, but it is not.
Okay.
So, this is why we have that and these tests here.
Really both of these are testing something similar,
but this one is more gauged to testing,
making sure the speed is correct.
This one is making sure that the decimals are correct
when there would be many of them.
Next up, we can test for multiple print runs,
making sure that a printer can print
multiple times in succession.
And we can print up to, say, the limit of capacity,
then we can test multiple runs and there'll be an error
where we essentially do the same thing
but the last one is 226 or maybe we can even make it
a bit more explicit just like that.
All right.
So, here are a few of the tests that we've come up with
just for this simple printer class.
And remember, the purpose of the tests is two-fold,
or mostly two-fold.
The first purpose is to document and to show the reader
what the thing you're testing does
and how it behaves in different scenarios.
So, by looking at these tests here,
you need to take your time to of course understand them,
but you'll be able to glean that this printer
has a print method that returns a message
and it reaches errors, gets over here
to when you go over the limit
and you can print exactly up to the limit
and you can do multiple print runs and so on.
So, it's a little bit like documentation.
If you're working on a team
and you're working with other people,
they'll be a lot of code in a large code base
that you've never seen before.
By looking at the tests in the large code bases,
you can much more easily understand
everything that's going on
as long as the tests are good, of course.
The second purpose of tests is to check that the code works
in the same way that it did the last time.
So, if somebody comes into your printer
and makes a few changes,
for example if they change this print method
so that it no longer raises an error,
you almost certainly want your tests to fail
because if they don't, (laughs)
then you can see that it tells me that, two failed.
If your tests don't fail,
it means that potentially in many places in your code,
you could be depending on the error being raised
and you are none the wiser.
You don't know if that error is being raised or not anymore
if you don't have tests for it.
So, the tests, the second purpose of the tests
is to keep you right in what you believe about your code.
Of course, there is a third and final use of tests,
which is that by writing tests,
it will force you to write better code.
If the code is very difficult to test,
you're gonna have problems testing it.
And that means usually that the code is too complicated.
So, you should split it out into functions
and test those separately and so on.
In the coming videos, we're going to look
at how you can split your code into functions
and how to test when you have multiple layers.
So, we're gonna be using patching and mocking
in order to do that.
It's really simple.
It looks complicated, but it really isn't.
Thanks for joining me in this video.
I'll see you in the next one.