Hi, guys, and welcome back.
In this video we're going to be creating our notebook,
and this is the start of our text editor.
Let's create our notebook.
So we'll say notebook equal ttk.notebook
and put it inside main.
Next up, let's say notebook.pack,
and we're gonna type fill for both and expand equal true.
What this is gonna mean since this is the only element
inside our main frame,
and the frame is also doing fill both and expand true,
it means that this notebook is going to
take up the entire window.
By the way, notice that
these pack methods don't have a side.
That means side top by default.
So let's press play in our app, and you'll see
something that seems like nothing.
That is because we have created a notebook,
but we haven't created any files inside the notebook.
Let's do that now.
We'll say text_area equal tk.text,
and we will put it inside the notebook.
Text is different from entry in that text is a text area,
so it takes up more room.
It takes up some vertical space as well as horizontal space.
Notice that the entry fields are just one liners.
Text are multi-line.
Then we will pack it with again
fill both and expand equal true,
and we will say notebook.add text area,
and the title is going to be untitled for now.
All right, let's press play.
And you'll see that we are here.
We have created our text area, and we have now a full width,
full height element.
Padx of one means that there is one element of padding
on the left and the right.
Pady of four comma zero
means that is four of padding on the top
and none on the bottom.
You can get rid of those if you like.
Next up, what we're gonna do is notebook.select text area,
and what that's gonna do is as soon as you press play,
that is going to be selected, which is the same as before;
however, when you create multiple of these,
you want to select the latest one you created.
So what we'll do is we're going to put all of this here
inside a function, which I'm going to call create file.
Now, we can run create file down here,
and it will create the same thing that we had before.
But if we run create file multiple times,
then we will always have the last one selected.
This is going to be useful because when we create a new file
using our menu or something like that,
we do want to select the file that we've just created.
That's why that's there.
All right, so this is how you create a notebook,
which is a collection of tabs
with different elements inside it,
and how you create text areas
to put inside each of the tabs.
Notice that you don't have to put text areas
inside these tabs.
You can put whatever you want in them,
and so potentially, this could be a way of creating
a tabbed menu if you wanted.
That's everything for this video.
Thank you for joining me.
Now let's move on to the next one
where we're going to be adding a menu
so that we can create more files.
I will see you there.