Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be simplifying
our Flask code a little bit
by allowing our end point here
to both give the U to the form and receive the data.
So it's just going to be a little bit nicer,
fewer routes for users to access
and just generally, a bit easier to navigate.
What we're going to do is we're going to do two things.
We're going to allow this end point
to see get requests as well.
Now, the browser does get requests.
The form does post requests.
So we know that if we get a request that is get,
that's the browser wanting to load the page.
And probably the user wanting to see the form.
If users see the post request,
we know that the form sending us data.
And therefore we should deal with that form data.
So, if the request method is post,
we're going to do all of this stuff.
Get the title from the form,
get the content from the form,
you know create a new post
and then redirect the user to the post.
As soon as we return,
you know this from general Python knowledge,
as soon as we would return I think, the function ends.
So if we have another return down here,
this return will only execute
if we did not execute this one.
And we will always execute this one
if the request method is post.
So if the request method is not post,
we will jump right to this return.
And that means that if the browser makes a get request,
we are going to render the template.
If we receive a post request from the form,
we're going to deal with that data.
Now we no longer need /post/form
because this end point can be both.
And it's just a little bit simpler
to have the same end point dealing
with both serving the way of creating data
as well as dealing with that data input.
Our create.jinja2 also has to change
so that this action here can now be removed.
If you remove the action,
that means use the current page that you're at.
And because the current page
is the page that serves the template,
is also the page that takes in the data,
we don't need an action there.
This also simplifies things
because if you move this form around
or you change the URLs or anything like that,
things can break the form.
But now because it's the same page,
both giving the form to the user
and accepting the form's input,
it's just a bit more stable.
And so this way here simplifies your code a little bit,
makes it a bit easier to work with.
And also reduces the amount of code you've got.
All good things.
So that's it for this video.
I wanted to show you how to do this.
And I'll see you on the next one.