Hi and welcome back.
In this video we're going to talk about property setters.
Let's create a new file that I'm gonna call Flight,
and in here I'm going to just define a simple class
that will be a flight object.
In case you don't know,
flights are normally something that looks like this.
It goes for example from Glasgow
to London Heathrow.
This could be a flight,
and in this flight you have one segment.
A segment is essentially you getting on a plane,
and you landing somewhere else.
If you're going from Glasgow to Toronto,
you'll actually stop in London Heathrow in the middle.
So you'll have something like this,
Glasgow to London Heathrow to Toronto.
So these are two segments.
And the whole thing is known as a flight leg,
so flight leg in this case has two segments.
Glasgow to London Heathrow,
and London Heathrow to Toronto.
Just a bit of background information,
I am sort of getting a bit
disillusioned with the animals and the friend example,
so now that you know a bit more about Python,
I wanted to give you some more interesting examples
of things you can do.
So let's create this flight class.
I'm gonna not repr,
define an init method,
and we're going to get a list of segments.
So this is going to be a list of segment.
Okay, we can import this, of course,
and just import it,
in Python you can press Alt + Enter, if you're on Mac,
or I think it's Control + Enter if you're on Windows
to get that, the type hints,
and then we're just going to say self.segments
equals segments.
Down here we're going to define the class segment,
which is just going to have a departure
and a destination.
Okay, pretty simple class there.
All it does is it has a departure, for example,
GLA, if I can type,
and a destination, let's say London Heathrow,
so that just gets stored in this segment object,
and we're going to get a list of segments passed
over to our flight constructor.
Then, we're going to have something like a property,
that is gonna be a departure point.
So where does this flight begin?
That, it begins
in the first airport of the first segment,
so that's where this flight is gonna begin.
So we're gonna return self.segments[0].departure.
Okay, and it's gonna return a string.
So this is the departure point.
Now if we wanted to overwrite the departure point,
let's say, make the flight depart from
Edinburgh instead of Glasgow,
there is no easy way to do that,
so I'm going to down here write some code to do that.
Okay, I'm gonna say my flight is a flight object there,
that has, let's say a single segment
that goes from Glasgow to London Heathrow, okay,
so now we have a flight object
that has a list of segments,
but it only has one segment in there,
and the segment is going from Glasgow to London Heathrow.
If you print the flight departure point,
notice how it's a property,
so you don't need the method brackets,
you'll get Glasgow, or GLA for Glasgow Airport.
If you then want to make the flight depart from Edinburgh,
you would have to do something like
flight.segments[0].departure equal Edinburgh.
Not terribly simple.
I would rather do flight.departure_point equal Edinburgh.
But of course we know departure point is a method,
so this, can it be done?
Can you do this?
The answer is no, by the way,
you cannot do this right now,
but of course Python knows that you may want to do this,
and it provides you with another decorator you can use.
The decorator is actually quite a magical thing now,
because the decorator will be called departure_point.
So now we use @departure_point which is the name
of our property, .setter,
and then, we can call our method the same thing,
if you want, or you can call it something else,
and of course it needs the value that you're going to
pass in, that's the EDI down there,
and then all we have to say is self.segments[0].departure
equal EDI, okay?
An even better way of doing things,
just because of, sorry, the,
the departure should be equal to val, of course,
not EDI.
An even better way of doing things is the following.
Normally segments are specific flights,
they have specific flight codes,
specific numbers associated with them,
so you can't just say
this flight is now going to depart from Edinburgh.
But what you can do is you can put a different segment
in there altogether, if you want.
So I would rewrite this, so instead of doing this,
just in a professional environment
where your segments cannot change
because they have specific flight codes
associated with them,
I would say the destination is self.segments[0].destination
and then I would say self.segments[0] is a new segment,
where the departure is val,
and the destination is dest,
this thing we calculated up here.
Potentially here you could also, you know,
find out what the flight code is gonna be,
find it in from a database or some other place,
and you know, decide that there.
The only reason I'm doing this
is to show you again
what you could do if you were not able
to change the segments themselves.
You could just create a new one,
replace segments[0] for that,
that would be fine.
Okay?
Now, you can do this.
So you can delete flight.segments[0].departure equal EDI,
and now say flight.departure_point equal EDI.
And if you print flight.departure_point
you'll see when we run flight.py, oh,
yes, sorry, my bad, with the typing,
you have to define this class before the other one,
just the way that Python sees the classes,
it evaluates this method typing,
before it has imported the class,
so you have to define that there,
and then you can see that you can get Glasgow and Edinburgh.
In my notes I actually don't have the typing defined
in the methods,
that's why I didn't realise this before.
So as you can see,
this helps you identify how to change the departure point.
Now you don't even have to know
when you're using the flight object
that this is a property or not.
So whether this is an @property decorated method,
or whether it's an actual property of the flight.
This lets you set them and get them.
Just for completeness as well,
I'm going to define a repr method.
In order to show you how I would do this,
this repr method has to return something,
string in the format
of Glasgow, London Heathrow, Toronto, for example.
So how are you going to do this?
How would you create a string that has this format,
knowing the segments?
I'd encourage you to give this a go, by the way.
Pause the video and give it a go, if you can.
Hopefully you tried that.
What I would do is say,
get a list of the stops.
So the first stop of your flight,
or rather where it starts is Glasgow.
The second stop is the end of the first segment,
so you've got the start of the first segment,
end of the first segment.
Then you have the end of the second segment,
and then if it was going somewhere else,
you'd have the end of the third segment, and so forth.
So the stops initially are
self.segments[0].departure,
and self.segment[0].destination,
these are the two initial stops that you know
you're always going to have,
you're always going to have
segments[0].departure,
and segments[0].destination.
Then I would say for seg in self.segments[1] onwards,
stops.append(seg.destination).
Simple enough.
You start then at the first segment,
rather segment number one.
The second segment, if there are any,
and then you append the destination over to your stops,
and at the end you can return
.join(stops).
I'm not sure if we've seen this before.
All this allows you to do is
join each of the elements of the stops list
with this string.
So it will essentially put the first stop
at the start of the string,
the second stop after the string,
and then it will put another string after,
and put the third stop, and so forth.
So essentially creating a string that looks like this.
Now we can just print the flight
instead of printing departure point.
We can run it again,
and we can see that we've now
gone from Glasgow to London Heathrow,
over to Edinburgh to London Heathrow,
and here we've learned about a few things
like the setter,
and also how to use the setter in a property,
and we've got some more practise
at defining some actual, real examples of code.
That's it for this video.
I wanted to show you
how to use the setter in a property.
So thank you for joining me,
and I'll see you on the next one.