Hi guys and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be learning
about patching and mocking.
Let's start by creating a new file
that we're gonna call page.py,
and here we're gonna import the requests module.
So, if you don't have it installed,
just go over to your settings,
open your project interpreter settings,
and instal the requests module.
This module here just allows us to get a web page
and look at its contents basically.
So, it allows us to make web requests.
Now that that's installed, we can go to okay
and this should disappear at the redline,
and then we're gonna create a class.
That I'm gonna call PageRequester,
and it's gonna be a very useless class,
but nonetheless it's gonna allow us
to learn about testing.
So, we're gonna get the PageRequester class
and it has an init method.
This one receives a string and URL.
We can say that this is a string there,
and then it has a get method
that all it does is it calls the requests module.
And it gives you back the content of the response.
Now you may think that this is a useless example,
but very often what you'll see is that your classes
get very long, and as your classes get longer and longer,
understanding them becomes naturally more difficult.
There is more code to read,
you have to be jumping from one place to another and so on.
So, it's often a good idea to split out the code
in your classes, take it out, put it inside another file,
create a function for it or potentially another class
if it's necessary, and test that separately
from this class.
This class now where we've taken all of the code
that actually goes and gets the URL and so forth,
we've taken all that into a new file, the requests module.
Now this class is very simple.
All we have to do is make sure that
the URL is stored in the class,
and that the get method calls the requests module.
So, we can go ahead and write our tests for it.
Let's create a new file that I'm gonna
call testpage.py,
and once again we will begin by doing from unittest,
import TestCase.
We will do from unittest.mock import patch,
and from page import PageRequester.
Then we'll create our test PageRequester,
which is a test case,
and we are gonna set up the method here
to do self.page is PageRequester,
and we will pass in google.com, just a simple page there.
Now what we want to do is
we want to make sure that when we call self.page.get,
it calls the requests module.
We do not want to have a test
that actually gets google.com.
Here's why, so we'll say test_make_request,
and we're gonna do with patch of requests.get
as mocked get, and what this does is it goes
into the requests module, looks at
or rather it goes into the requests import,
which is what we've imported here,
and if we use requests.get anywhere in our application,
is going to be replaced by whatever
this patch function returns.
So, it's gonna get replaced by a mock
and I'll show you what a mock is in just a moment.
So, what we want to do once we've patched requests.get,
we just want to say self.page.get.
And then mocked_get.assert_called.
All right so now let's get into why we're doing this.
When we write the requests module,
so whoever wrote the requests module,
he wrote tests for the requests module.
You don't have to use the requests code
and make sure that it works.
If we write this test without patching requests.get,
really we're testing two things.
The first thing we're doing is we are testing
that our function calls the requests module
because that's really what it does.
But the second thing is we're testing that
the requests module also works,
because we're actually interacting with the requests module.
If you patch it, you are never interacting
with the requests module.
All you're doing is you're interacting
with this mock that we're creating.
That means that there is a separation
between the requests module code
that we are not testing, and our code that we are testing.
And on the line between those two is this mock.
By checking that we are calling the requests module,
that is everything we need to check,
because the requests module is tested separately
and we don't have to test it ourselves.
Now there is a thing that our function does,
sorry that our method does, that isn't tested by that one,
and it is that it gets the content of the response.
So, we do have to write a test for this specific thing.
Make sure that whatever we get back,
we are accessing the content property of that.
This mock here that we've used
does not have a content property.
And I will show you exactly how I know that.
Going to type response is that
and we'll see print response.
Now we're gonna run this test here,
so we'll right-click it and press run these tests,
and you see that what you get back
when you do this patch is something called a magic mock.
This is part of the Python unit test module.
Whenever you access anything inside the magic mock,
it will allow you to access it.
So, for example you can say print response.rolf.
Let's run this again, and notice that
it is totally okay with it.
And what you get back is another magic mock.
When you do magic mock dot anything,
the magic mock automatically creates the property,
and gives it the value of another magic mock.
So, really with this test here,
we're not testing that we get a valid content thing
from our response.
We are not checking that this stuff here is working.
We're just checking that we are getting
something from the requests module.
If you want to patch this
and make it return something that has a content property,
so that you can then make sure that you are getting
the content property back,
you have to do that separately without using the magic mock.
So, let's write a test for content returned
and here we need to define an inner class
that is going to be a fake response.
So, we're gonna say requests module,
when I call the get method instead of returning
the real response from google.com,
give me this fake response.
So, we will define the init method here
and we will say self.content is hello.
And this is a fake response that we've used in here,
and now we'll say with patch requests.get,
and the return value is gonna be a FakeResponse.
And what this does is,
when you do requests.get like this,
you're gonna get back a FakeResponse object
that we've created just now.
That means that when you do result equals self.page.get,
what's happening is self.page.get
is calling requests.get,
and this stuff here will be your FakeResponse object
and then you're accessing the content property
of your FakeResponse.
So, you can do self.assertEqual result
should be hello.
And we can do fake content is hello
and put it in here.
All right now this will pass as well if we run it,
and we have successfully faked what the method
here is going to return.
This is a very common pattern,
where you fake the return value of something.
We've learned how to fake the return value of a function
and also how to make sure that it was called.
There is a lot more on patching and mocking
in the official documentation that I have linked
in the resources section of this lecture.
So, please do give it a read if you want to do more on this.
There is a lot to know and it can get a little bit confusing
when you start to play with different side-effects
and other things that these mocks can do,
and when you start using mocks instead
of magic mocks and so on.
So, if you want to do more testing I would recommend looking
at that and potentially also going deeper
into learning about unit testing in Python.
There is quite a lot to do.
Thanks for joining me in this video.
I'll see you on the next one.