[Autogenerated] at its core A.
W and step functions are state machines.
Estate is what we used to tell it what to do next.
They are seven types off AWS states that we can utilize to
build our work flows in a step function.
A task represents a single unit off work performed by a state machine.
Any work that is to be done is performed uniform off a desk.
Tasks belonged to three categories.
A Lambda Function Step functions can call Lamda functions directly.
We could use this easy integration to write our logic in
a server less lambda function toe build our work flows
tasks can also be activities.
Activity is a program that run somewhere else.
Maybe Izzy Poole or um, Premise.
The activity continuously pulls for pending tasks,
runs them and post the information back to the step function so
the workflow can continue to the next state.
And also we have other supported AWS service is when you reference or
connected resource step functions directly called the P I.
On that resource, for example,
we can run any ws patch job publisher topic in Amazon.
Simple notification service Send messages to Amazon.
Simple Q service trigger glue jobs, et cetera.
No workflow would be complete without the ability to make decisions on dhe.
For step functions, we use the choice they tow.
Add branching logic to our work so we can use and or
and not operators for our logic.
Currently, we can compare billions, strings, numbers and time stamps.
Let's look at an example.
Here we have a choice state that looks for a property called in grief.
If the angry property is set to true,
we goto the angry Steptoe encrypt our document First.
If the ankle properties that falls,
then we go directly to the email step and send the document.
And if none of these conditions meet,
we go directly to the e mails that the weight state,
as the name suggests,
it delays the state machine execution for a specified amount of time.
We have two types off ways.
We can wait for an amount of time in seconds,
which works like a delay, or we can wait until a specified times them,
for example, wait until December 31 to execute.
Here's an example off how we would define awaits state.
We specify the type.
Wait and we can either specify a value in seconds or a time stamp.
The weight duration can also be dynamic.
We can use values from the input as para meters for the times time duration.
For example, we can use the property expired date as our times time property,
using the times, time path setting on the steppe definition.
This way we can have our work flows be more dynamic.
Next, we have the best state A pest.
Lee doesn't perform any work.
The main purpose is to pass its input to the output.
They are mostly used for constructing and debugging state machines.
Let's say we want to add some data out of the state machine result.
We can use the best state and we can pass the data in
the result property off the past day.
We also have the option to use a result path.
This will group our data into a property that we specify in the result path.
So in our case, we specify first name and last name.
And in the result path, we specify that we want our data Toby under identity.
Once this step is executed in the result,
we would see an identity object with the first name
on the last name for properties.
Each workflow has to have an end and succeeded and failed.
States are used to stop the execution off a workflow.
When our workflow execution comes to a land,
we can either use a succeeded or failed state to mark our workflow.
Accordingly on the fields tape,
you can specify a cause and an error for the field.
It helps with better visualization and understanding work flows.
There are cases where we might want to run some
parts off our workflow in parallel.
These are cold branches, for example.
We can have a work for where we can look up the address and
the phone number in parallel for a customer.
We can run this in parallel using a parallel state.
It's branch must be self contained.
Estate in one branch cannot target field in another branch.
Here is how we might achieve above example.
We start by specifying a parallel state.
In this case, it's name look up customer info.
The state itself has branches, and each branch has its own states.
So each branch is like its own isolated work floor,
which executes in parallel with other branches in our case.
Each branch has only one state.
Look up a dress and look up.
Phone both the steps with executing parallel,
which allows for work flows to complete with optimal performance.
And finally, we have the maps D, sometimes even an import.
We might want to run a set of steps multiple times
to eat a rate over that import.
For example, if we have a list of items we want to process,
we can use the next day to run a series of steps for all the
elements off the input array and Matt Steed.
Well, it's a raid,
a serious off steps to run for each item in the in pottery and passed
each element off the ray tweet steps as an import.
Let's look at an example off a map.
Steve has any put.
We have a date Object,
which has an email is for our clients that we want to send e mails to.
In our email step.
We have said the type as man, and we need to define the input bath,
which tells it where the data is and the items bath,
which specifies the least the data resides in in this case,
the input path is data and items bath.
His e mails, where are email least resides.
We then specify the steps that need to run inside the operator.
They, the raider, can have as many steps as I needed for our case.
This gives as a convenient way when we need to reiterate over an
input rather than call the workflow multiple times.
In our case,
this will iterated through each email and execute the emails
that passing the email object as a perimeter.
This is all the different states AWS step functions currently supports. We'll see the states in the actions in the cliffs to calm.