[Autogenerated] creating a W A Step Functions is very straightforward.
AWS makes it very easy for us to use the causal.
Ooh, I to create our work flows for our demo.
We're going to build a simple workflow that execute
to Lambda functions in sequence.
Let's start by navigating to the AWS Step Functions management console.
Once in the Step Functions menu,
we need to navigate through the state machines on the last sidebar.
As with every other service, let's start by creating a new state machine.
When creating workflow, we get the option toe,
author it ourselves,
run a sample project or start with the template for this demo.
We're goingto author the workflow ourselves.
We also have the option to either to standard or express.
We're going to use standard for this day more.
We look into the difference later on.
Now all the work that we have to do is at the definition section.
The definition is based on Amazon States language,
which is a Jason based traction language we will use to
define our state machine For our demo,
we're going to build a simple workflow that execute
to Lambda functions in sequence.
Here is a Jason for our workflow.
Let's break it down.
The main part of a workload is defined in the state's property.
For our demo.
We are going to execute to London functions,
so we're going to have to task states,
which is what we used to do any actual work are States are
named Step one and step to keep things simple.
In order to execute a lambda function,
we need to tell the task what type of resource we're trying to execute.
In our case, it's Lambda and we'll be using the invoke A P I.
Next we have the pyre meters for the resource for London functions,
we need to perimeters Ah,
function name and the payload I have already created to Lambda Functions,
which do nothing but return an object with a property named
Function one and function to respectively.
The function mean is going to be the end of the function and for payload.
We're going to tell you to pass the entire output off the
state machine at the time of execution.
Next, we need to tell it which step to execute next.
For this demo,
it's going to be another similar step named Step two step two is
going to be exactly like Step one with two main differences is
going to invoke a different land, a function called Steptoe,
and it will not have a next step.
These will have a property called and which we need to set it as true.
This will tell the state machine that this step is
the last step on the workflow, and it needs to terminate here.
We also have to define a starting place.
The workflow needs to know which state needs Toby.
First, we specify that using the stock at property on,
we need to provide the name off the first step.
In our case, it's Step one.
Once we get through fresh on the right,
we can see the diagram off our newly created workflow.
On the next page, we need to choose the permissions for our state machine.
If you have already role created for the state machines you use,
then you can go ahead and use that role.
Otherwise, use a create new role option,
which will create a new role based on the state machine
definitions with appropriate permissions already attached
Once on state machine has been created.
Let's go ahead and execute it to see the results we get.
We have the option to provide an input for our demo.
We don't really use the input.
So let's start the execution without any.
We can see the execution ST on the diagram as well as in the execution history.
Clicking on its step, we can see the details of the execution for that step.
For step one,
we can see that the input was empty since we did not provide any
input and the output is the output that was returned by the
lender function in the bailout section.
Off the output, we can see the payload.
We return from the London function.
The rest is meta data from the London function Execution.
Now, if we look into the second step, the input is no longer empty.
The input is the state machine output.
At the time of the execution before it was executed,
the output of the state machine was output of the first step.
And now that output is the second steps input and also the output off.
The second step is very similar to the 1st 1 except the payload
returns the value function to instead of function one.
As we can see,
the output of Step one is now over eaten by the output off Steptoe.
Because they have similar property names.
We can also see that we get a lot of unnecessary information
that we do not need from the Lambda execution.
We can choose what information to get by using a property called Output Path.
We can decide what properties to show on the final output and filter out all
the unnecessary information from the execution meta data.
Let's edit the state machine definition so we can parse the
result from the Lambda Function execution.
We can do so by using the edit state machine bottom for the output.
We only want the payload information toe.
Get that we need to set the output bath $2 sign.
That payload dollar sign is the root object and payload is
the object that we want to retrieve.
We also need to do this for the second step as well.
Once we save, I start a new execution.
We can see now that the Step one output is just a
function one property and also, if we take the second step,
we can see that it's output is the function to property that is pro.
Creating a simple workflow using Amazon step functions and
using Lambda functions for the tasks will build more advanced work flows in the cliffs to come.