[Autogenerated] throughout this motion recovered how to
monitor secure and some of the best practices when it
comes to building step function.
Work flows.
We learned how to use Cloudwatch Matics to look at
our workflow execution history toe,
identify potential performance issues and errors to improve upon.
We also looked at setting up alarms so we can get notified when the
performance off our work flows falls below unacceptable threshold.
So we don't have to constantly tech dramatics on a regular basis.
We learned how to create custom policies based on the service is that are
utilized in the work floor and how to find and customize those policies or
great new custom policies for our work flows.
We looked at how using attack based policy can be really powerful way off,
creating policies that are based on the work for properties that allow us to
be very specific on who s permission on which work for.
We also went over the data encryption issue when building step function,
work clothes and how the payloads passed between steps cannot be in
creep it and how we can use as three or another storage medium to
avoid sensitive data between steps but rather as file ideas where
the actual payload resides.
We went over the different limitations that step functions head,
and we learned how to avoid reaching those limitations or how to get
around them when we do reach those limitations.
And finally,
we learned about some of the common best practices why we
should use time outs and handle exceptions,
how to better pass payloads between states and what
types of worth close to choose.
I hope this has given you a good understanding on how to properly monitor,
secure and identify limitations for your work flows and how to use some of
the best practices when you're building your work clothes. Thank you for watching.