Hi everyone!
My name is Kesha Williams, and welcome to my course,
Data Transactions with Spring.
I'm a software engineering manager in the IT department of Chick-fil-A.
In this course, we are going to learn about Spring transaction management,
which is one of the most widely used and important
features of the Spring Framework.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include
declarative transaction management, programmatic transaction management,
when to choose declarative over programmatic,
transaction propagation and rollbacks.
By the end of this course, you will have mastered Spring transaction management,
which will help you as you introduce transactional
behavior to your applications.
Before beginning the course, you should be familiar with Spring Data and Java.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn transaction management with the Data Transactions with Spring course at Pluralsight.