Hi!
This is Kesha Williams from Pluralsight.
Welcome to my course, Data Transactions with Spring.
Spring transaction management is one of the most widely used and
important features of the Spring Framework.
Let's learn when to use programmatic transaction management
over declarative transaction management,
and vice versa.
We've seen both programmatic and declarative transaction management.
Now I'm sure you're thinking,
"Given how easy declarative transaction management is,
why would I ever want to use programmatic transaction
management and have all of the extra manual work?
" Let's talk about why you would want to use programmatic transaction
management over declarative transaction management,
and vice versa.
Sometimes declarative transaction management doesn't
quite give us the flexibility we need.
Programmatic transaction management allows developers to manage
transactions via the code giving developers complete control.
It's also useful when you have minimal transaction logic.
Programmatic transaction management is very flexible,
but it can be difficult to maintain as it tightly
couples transaction and business logic.
Programmatic transaction management provides us fine-grained control over
transaction management giving us extreme flexibility.
But like I said, it is difficult to maintain and, well, boilerplate at times.
Declarative transaction management allows developers to manage
transactions via configuration and annotations,
but it is less flexible.
It does allow developers to separate transaction logic from business logic,
which makes it easy to maintain.
Boilerplate code is kept away from the business logic.
It's preferred when working with large amounts of transaction logic.
Declarative transaction management allows the container to manage the transaction for you.