Aspect-oriented programming is a programming paradigm that
breaks programming logic into distinct parts.
Spring uses this paradigm when implementing transaction management.
Transaction management in Spring is enabled via proxies.
But, first, let's talk about how it works when you're not using a proxy.
When you call code, you invoke a method on an object reference.
The method is invoked directly on that object reference.
However,
when a proxy is used and you invoke a method directly on an object reference,
the method is no longer invoked directly on that object reference,
but instead on a reference to the proxy.
And, as such,
the proxy delegates to all of the interceptors
relevant to that particular method call.
Specifically, the proxy uses a transaction interceptor,
which intercepts method calls or indication of lifecycle
events on the associated target class.
This occurs in conjunction with an appropriate platform
transaction manager to handle transactions.
Here's a tip.
The default advice mode for processing @Transactional annotations is proxy, which allows for interception of calls through the proxy only.