Transaction management is a useful feature that the Spring
Framework makes available out of the box.
Spring provides support for automatically committing or
rolling back transactions when they fail.
There are several different APIs that help developers manage transactions.
The advantages of using Spring to manage transactions is that it provides
a consistent programming model across all of the APIs.
What do I really mean when I say Spring provides a consistent programming model?
Well, let's say you're currently using JDO to help manage your transactions,
and one day down the road you want to change to Hibernate.
Well, if you're not using Spring,
you'd have to make coding changes to support the migration because JDO and
Hibernate have different APIs for transaction management.
If you're using Spring, then coding changes aren't required.
Spring provides a uniform API that is simpler for programmatic
transaction management than other complex APIs.
Let's see an example of this.
This code contains manual transaction management.
The developer is responsible for beginning the transaction,
and the developer is also responsible for committing the transaction.
It is all very manual.
Now let's see this code using Spring transaction management.
This second piece of code is lightweight and flexible and
lets Spring handle the transaction.
Notice the @Transactional annotation.
Let's say we needed to execute saveTicket as a part of complex transactions.
The first piece of code that has the manual transaction
management places a lot of burden on the developer.
But using Spring in the second chunk of code,
propagations of the transactions work smoothly.
In this example where we have to first save a ticket,
assign it to a release, and do other stuff,
the automatic rollback happens in the case of exception.
Spring makes all of this possible by providing support for
programmatic and declarative transaction management.
Going back to the first chunk of code,
this is considered programmatic transaction management.
The application code begins a transaction and then performs some
operations against one or more resource managers.
The second chunk of code is considered declarative transaction management.
The underlying transaction manager should intercept resource
manager requests made by the application and perform the
necessary transaction management, begin,
suspend, commit, or rollback.
Declarative transaction management can also include the specification of
transactional parameters such as isolation levels.
When possible,
declarative transactions are a better choice since they allow the
container to manage the transaction for you.
And this saves you from having to put transaction
management calls into your application code.
Declarative transaction management can lead to much cleaner
separation of business logic and transaction code.
And applications written to depend on declarative transaction management can be much easier to maintain and evolve.