Declarative transaction management uses the @Transactional annotation.
The @Transactional annotation can be used at either the class or method level.
When placed on the class or interface level,
all methods within it will become transactional.
Method annotations override the class level annotation.
Here is a tip.
Spring recommends that you only annotate concrete classes and
methods of concrete classes with the @Transactional annotation
as opposed to annotating interfaces.
There are two ways to configure transactions in Spring,
XML based or annotation based.
I find the annotation based easier to use, so that's what I will demonstrate during this course.