So now I will provide a tour of the baseline TrackZilla application,
which we will build upon during the course.
This will include an introduction to the TrackZilla Spring Boot
application and its controller and service layer,
the associated domain model, the associated data access objects,
and the in-memory H2 database.
So let's look at how the baseline TrackZilla application is set up.
Here I'm in the TrackZillaController.
java file.
Notice on line 18, it is a RestController.
On line 19, there is a RequestMapping to tza.
On line 22, we have an applicationService,
and we have on line 25 a ticketService.
So now let's look at one simple use case for the getAllApplications.
So on line 34,
we have the getAllApplications method that then
calls out to the applicationService.
getAllApplications.
So let's look at the ApplicationService and navigate to the
getAllApplications method on line 17.
Notice that calls out to our applicationDAO.
Let's navigate to our applicationDAO,
and the getAllApplications method is found on line 20.
Here we see on line 21 a JPQL query that retrieves all
applications and returns them sorted by name.
So essentially this method returns a list of all applications that a user
can log either a bug or enhancement request against.
So the getAllApplications method can be tested through a unit test.
So let's go down to the test folder and
double-click on TrackZillaControllerTest.
And you see on line 32,
we have a very simple test to exercise our getAllApplications code.
So now let's go to our resources folder.
I'd like to point out one thing underneath application.
properties, so double-click on that, and notice on line 10,
we have the URL to our H2 in-memory database.
So this is very important when you want to access
the data through the H2 console.
And, lastly, there's data.
sql. This file populates our database with seed data.