In this section we will explore developing your team's capacity.
In other words, how much work can they really produce?
Let's see.
Team capacity is incremental and iterative as well.
So our first step is to determine just what our ideal capacity is.
Now,
ideal capacity for your team is how many hours of work can your team complete,
in a given ideal time period?
Now in the past we discussed ideal time.
So what about ideal capacity?
What is the ideal amount of work the team can produce?
Okay, that's our goal.
Second step though, is let's determine historical capacity.
That's based on, of course, historical actuals.
Since we track our time,
we can quickly look at data to determine just how much capacity,
hours of real work, have we as a team historically produced?
And the third step is what I call determine 'pretty good capacity, ' PGC.
That is going to be a very quick and usable indicator to
help us create the team's capacity.
So we are looking for a quick way to go from ideal capacity to
a more realistic capacity in what I call,
'pretty good capacity.
' Now, let's look at some examples on the next slides.
Now let's discuss how to determine ideal capacity.
Scenario, your boss comes to you and says,
doesn't everyone work 40 hours a week?
Well now you're going to have an approach to explain
to him or her what really happens.
So ideally, people work 8 hours per day,
for over 2, 000 hours per year, per person.
Now if you have a team of 3 people,
of course you have an ideal capacity of 3 x 2,
080 for a total of 6, 240 hours.
Ideal capacity.
Now we want to refine that by some known parameters.
Such as paid time off and company holidays.
Between paid time off and company holidays,
we have 184 hours that we are not working.
So let's update our ideal capacity number.
We want to reduce for paid time off by 120 hours.
We also want to reduce that number by 64 for known holidays.
So now our total ideal capacity is only 1,
896 hours per year, per person, for a total of 5,
688.
Now you only have to do this maybe once quarter or twice a year,
because these factors probably won't change a lot.
But if any known parameters,
easy to understand and easy to put into your formulas,
come up in your company, then you can do this.
Also you want to update this at the size of your team changes or
other drivers that we're going to talk about later.
So if in your company or situation, you have other known parameters,
apply those and come up with your ideal capacity per person and also, therefore, for your team.