Here is a starter process to help you get going right away.
Someone's going to come up to you and say hey,
can you give me an estimate for... And what you're going to do
is you're going to pull out your Project Definition Document and
you'll start filling it all out, gathering all the appropriate requirements.
You'll get back with that person or steering committee
that asked you for the estimate, and then next step will be a go or no go.
You'll provide that information, they'll either say great,
start or they'll say hey, I need a little more information from you.
So the next step we're going to use our pre-launch models to
refine the estimate and also update the PDD.
And in this module we're going to talk about those pre-launch models.
After you do those pre-launch models, one or more of them,
to improve your Project Definition Document,
and to refine your estimates, there'll be another point of go or no go.
At this point you're either going to launch the
project or not launch the project.
They may even ask you to refine your estimates further.
Let's assume they go ahead and say go with the project.
Then we're going to start tracking actuals versus our estimates,
see how we're doing.
We're going to adjust our estimates with actual data.
We're going to maybe reprioritize and refine our estimates,
even while the project is going.
That's a key element we're going to talk about in this module.
Now, let's talk about how easy it is to design and build your PDD template.
What we want to do is just create an MS/Word document with a title page,
table of contents, headings like head 1,
head 2, head 3, to contain your PDD template for reuse.
Now if you want to use other tools that's great,
but something as simple as MS/Word will work just fine.
We want to use all the categories as a starter point from Module 1.
Recall, these were the categories we talked about.
Purpose, goals and objectives, success criteria, etc.
And in Module 1 we gave you an example of what each one of these would be like.
This would be your starting point.
As you do each project you're going to add more sub-bullets,
if you will, or subheadings under each one of these.
Maybe you'll add new headings.
And so with each iteration, for each project, you'll do a better and better job.
So you'll want to use always the last template for your next project, okay. And as I said, always add, enhance, and improve the list with each new project.