The Agile philosophy supports, even encourages, an adaptive process.
Clint Eastwood once said in a movie, "You adapt,
you overcome, you improvise, let's move!
" It is harder to adapt if you are taking big,
risky steps and easier to adapt if you're taking smaller,
safer steps.
The term adaptive is a common descriptor of the Agile process.
Always adapting to requirements, budgets,
resources, staff, schedule etc., that are always changing around us.
Requirements are guaranteed to be uncertain and unpredictable.
And therefore, so are estimates.
You might want to check out another one of my Pluralsight courses
on Best Practices for Requirements Gathering.
My approach and process assumes that requirements are
in fact uncertain and unpredictable.
Constantly adapt and re-plan your work and activities.
Basically, that's Agile.
You're going to re-plan and re-estimate all the time.
Now let's explore what makes projects Agile.
The Agile philosophy.
Fundamentally, it's a different process from traditional development.
Traditional development has sometimes been known as the waterfall approach.
In Agile we want to satisfy the highest priority for the customer first.
Yes, we always want and wanted to satisfy the customer,
but the process is more customer centric.
Accomplished by early and continuous release of
immediately usable deliverables and software.
So the Agile approach wants to avoid long periods of development,
then tests, then deployment.
But I also use the word deliverable here,
since a release could be a document,
requirement or an estimate and not necessarily software.
We're going to talk about that more later in this module.
In an Agile environment, we want it where changing requirements are welcomed.
Yes, I know that sounds strange.
Even late in development.
We're going to also talk about that more later.
Agile provides a more flexible approach to system development.
It's really short durations, and just in time approach.
And lastly, customers realize a much greater return on investment, sooner.
They see and use features sooner, rather than later.
Agile is an adaptive process.
"Wouldn't it be nice... if we could figure out a way to deliver software so
fast that our customers don't have time to change their minds.
" That's a very interesting quote by Tom Poppendieck.
The longer the period of time between when we begin writing
software and when we deliver software,
the greater the chance that the business has changed.
Maybe resources have changed, budgets or schedules have changed.
The customer is still left with, possibly, nothing.
So users aren't necessarily indecisive.
Yes, some are.
But in general, they're not.
But dynamic business requirements drive this unpredictability in their
environment and thus drive unpredictable changes.
So what he is trying to say is how do you change our software
engineering approach in such a way as to accommodate the rapid
changes in our business environment?
And in a nutshell,
this is one of the big reasons that help create
Agile-based planning and estimating.
So, if the business world is so unpredictable, what must we be able to do?
And that's adapt. Let's explore this further.