Developing team schedules.
Now that we have discussed ideal time and our pretty good multiplier,
we know about what our team is capable of producing.
Now let's see how we schedule that work.
That is come up with the complete elapsed time
necessary to accomplish the project.
We have focused to date on estimates.
But estimates are only part of the picture.
The minute you come up with an estimate,
someone will want a date, or a milestone.
Or basically, hey when are you going to be done?
So what they're really asking for is a schedule.
So definition of a schedule.
It's your plan for carrying out a process,
giving lists of intended events or milestones and dates.
Up against those tasks that we've already itemized with our estimated hours.
Estimates and schedules, as we know, are completely different elements.
Both are required by your customer or your management team.
Estimates alone are just not enough for the picture.
That's why we need estimates, of course in hours, and not dates.
Estimates come up with hours.
We apply those hours onto a schedule or a calendar to
come up with the dates based on the resources we have to
consume those tasks and hours.
Completion dates therefore can be derived by
scheduling your resources on a calendar.
It's really that simple.
As you apply resources on a calendar, you can determine completion target dates.
Let's see some examples.
Now let's do a quick first cut schedule example.
In what I'm going to call an ideal schedule, just like we had ideal estimates.
So the estimate in ideal time is 220 hours in our example.
So using my 'pretty good capacity' multiplier from the previous sections, 1.
12 x 220, so we think we need about 240 hour,
excuse me, 247 hours of a window of time in order to accomplish the 220.
Okay, so now we have a rough cut of elapsed time required.
In order to execute those 220 hours it'll take an elapsed time of 247 hours.
And again, we would only be billing or accounting for the 220.
Remember, we think we need 220 hours of real work to get it done.
But we know with sick and vacation and such,
there needs to be a little more time.
And of course those would be charged to other cost centers,
like sick time, vacation, jury duty and things like that.
Now let's follow through with our team example of 3 developers on our team.
So, 247 hours divided by 8 hours a day, is about 31 days.
And 3 into 31 is about 10 days.
So about 10 work days for 3 developers to implement the requirement.
Okay boss, this will be about a 2 week assignment for my team.
Obviously this is an ideal schedule because you're
assuming that all three developers,
are all available for 10 straight working days.
I've also accounted for maybe a little bit of vacation or
sick that might happen in those 10 days.
But I'm pretty confident that hey, I need two weeks to get this job done.
But let's look further in terms of, because the world's not ideal certainly,
and how other projects or issues can affect our initial first cut.
We saw on a previous slide just how easy it is to get a first cut,
quick, ballpark schedule.
This isn't complicated rocket science guys.
You have a few little spreadsheets,
you can crank these numbers together and really quickly get some pretty
confident estimates and/or quick schedules back to your management.
Now let's look a little further and do a detailed,
what I call detailed second cut schedule.
Again the first cut was ideal, but doesn't account for other projects or tasks.
The second cut, we're going to do a resource load chart,
more of an elapsed schedule now.
So you can see the chart here on the screen.
And the first row going across is Week Number.
So I have 1 Week, 2 Week, 3 Week say.
Second row is going to be the headings.
I'm going to have a column for Resources,
% Available that that resource is available.
And I have my, I use week ending dates.
So these are Fridays.
You could use Mondays.
Mondays or Fridays is the best.
I like Fridays.
Okay, so I have three weeks, three columns, 1, 2, and 3.
And then I look down and I have the Resources of Michael, John, and Jim.
Michael is only available 45% of the time, because he's on other projects.
So 45% of, you know, his 40 hours is going to be 18 for Week 1 and 18 for Week 2,
and 18 for Week 3.
John's available 90%, almost a full week, so 36 across.
Jim's available 70%, 28 across.
So then I have a Total.
So my team of three, is available,
based on looking at other projects about 82 hours a week.
Now given that my target is 247 hours, you can see then in the Weekly Cum line,
at the very bottom, that the first week I'll consume 82,
the second week cumulative will be 164, 2 x 82,
and the last week will be 246, 3 x 82.
Now my estimate was 247.
So now I can say, hey boss,
given that I need to consume 247 hours and I did my first
rough cut and my pretty good multiplier,
and now I look at my other projects, now I think I need three weeks,
elapsed time.
Three weeks should do it based on the allocation percentages.
So going forward, again remember we're always so,
so serious about tracking our time, that okay every developer,
when you track your time, you get 45% Michael,
90% John, 70% Jim per week.
The other time is allocated.
Now what I might recommend is standups and things like that,
because life's going to change.
Other projects or fires might occur and you rework this and you refine it.
You might have a third cut and fourth cut, as the project progresses.
So you always know your target date.
Now let's talk about the unfortunate habit of padding, and how we should deal with it.