For a project to be Agile they generally conform to the following practices.
Work as one team.
A successful Agile team must have a 'we are all in this together' mindset.
All team members, in their respective roles, must collaborate together.
Customers, product owners, project managers,
analysts, designers, architects, software engineers and testers.
Even other roles I may have left off must all work together as a team,
bringing their own ideas and perspectives together.
We work in short releases.
No grand phases or waterfall steps.
Each release is in and of itself a mini project,
if you will, with analysis, design, coding,
testing, user acceptance, etc.
Each iteration, and sometimes we call this a sprint,
has a fixed time length, AKA, Also Known As,
a time box.
And there are a few more on the next slide.
So here are some more items for the Agile approach to projects.
Deliver something in each release.
Typically at the end of each release is usable software.
It may also be some other concrete usable elements,
such as a document or a plan as well.
Typically it's a software release, but it could be an analysis result,
an estimate, a spec, some analysis, things like that.
We also focus on business priorities.
Deliver features in the priority order specified by the user.
Focus on completing user-valued features rather than isolated software tasks.
For example, something that's not business focused would be design a database.
Yes, I know you need to design a database,
but we want to word the features in such a way that
they're business-customer oriented.
For example, enable the closing of a billing period.
That may make sense to someone like a CFO or an account-type.
That's important to them, they understand that.
But focused on designing a database, even though we need that,
and we know we must do that,
it's really inconsequential to the actual end user and customer.
So again,
we focus on business priorities rather than more of our
technical viewpoints that we may be more used to.
We inspect and adapt.
Life changes, things happen.
So we always have to be able to inspect what we're doing,
observe what we're doing, and then adapt and change the plans accordingly.
So based on the previous release or iteration,
we may adapt our plans for the NEXT release or iteration.
So we're always modifying, correcting, taking in the business world,
taking in the resources that may have changed,
maybe budget changes.
And again, the customer changing their requirement priorities,
adapting our plans, and then sending out a new release plan,
another term would be sprint, and then moving forward on that.
Over and over again.
You likely can't change plans every hour.
But also, your plans shouldn't be so rigid,
that it only changes every six months.
Now that we have covered some of the simple basics of Agile,
let's talk about the different implementations of Agile on the next slide.
There is only one way to do Agile.
Absolutely not.
Agile consists of values and principles.
It does not specifically document implementation details.
But here is some actual Agile implementations such as Scrum,
Extreme Programming, Kanban, Feature Driven Development.
The most popular that I'm aware of is Scrum and I'd recommend that you
take a moment and maybe research the Scrum methodology.
Now, as long as you're adhering to Agile values and principles,
you and your team should be considered Agile.
It doesn't necessarily have to follow one of these implementations.
In fact I think it's okay to roll your own implementation
that works for you and your organization.
And that's what we've done in my company.
Leverage as many best practices of Agile as you can.
And also adoption may vary and take time,
based on your team and based on your customer as well actually.
Okay, in the next section we will talk about how Agile affects traditional estimation.