How Agile philosophy affects estimation.
Now let's explore project estimation from the perspective of Agile.
Agile planning, Patton style.
"A good plan" or estimate, I added that to the quote,
"violently executed now... is better than a perfect plan executed next week.
" That was stated by General George Patton.
What Patton, or Agile, philosophy is trying to say is,
don't take too much time to plan.
The longer it takes to make perfect,
the more likely it will actually not be perfect because the
opportunities of success may have passed.
This is not to say that we don't plan anymore.
It's just a bit different approach.
And let's see how.
Old thinking, new thinking.
On the left will be the typical way we have thought about
projects and planning and making estimates.
And on the right will be the Agile way, what I'm calling the new thinking.
On the left, Typical,
we plan by a series of tasks and/or steps that typically are
very detailed and more IT related sometimes.
On the Agile side,
it's more a series of useful capabilities that we're
going to provide to the customer.
Next, on the left,
a typical way of thinking is these are then incorporated
into a very detailed project plan.
And from an Agile perspective, it's incorporated into a product release.
It's actually tied right to what we're going to give the customer,
their new product.
Typical, more detailed level, and on the Agile side,
more of an abstract approach to making estimates and planning.
And we're going to talk about that throughout this section as well.
Lastly, we're still delivering things to the customer, in both cases, of course.
But, in the Agile approach the customer can relate better to what's delivered.
Because these are useful capabilities or features that they can relate to.
So the old way, or typical way of thinking,
is that we know or we think we know everything necessary to
create that task list or steps for the project.
The new way is that we assume we don't know everything,
which is usually true in the world and life.
In fact, maybe very little we know.
And in each step of the way, we are learning,
re-planning, re-estimating with each iteration and release, in the Agile process and planning activities.