Our next model is what I call bottom up.
Used to develop detailed estimates.
So we're going to do a little more work here.
It's still done early in the cycle,
but we're going to spend a little more time creating our estimates.
Provides an estimate at the lowest level of WBS.
Remember WBS is a hierarchical set of tasks with
each level going deeper and deeper.
So we may want to go to a deeper level of all the tasks we think we need to do.
Obviously, if we do do that,
we're going to provide much greater accuracy in our estimates.
It's also a good technique for identifying risk factors.
Because you are going to more depths and more detail,
you're going to uncover things you may not in some
of the higher estimating models.
So this is pretty good if you want to really get at
the root of things and avoid risks.
Takes a little additional time of course and the effort to produce,
but I think well worth it.
And I use this model, as I mentioned,
I use all the models for all large projects and then
work them together for my estimates.
But I use bottom up as well.
I have a lot of templates for that so I can easily pull one out
and quickly come up with a good estimate.
So instead of quantifying a unit of work as a simple,
moderate, or complex as we talked about before,
we're going to go into a lot more detail of each one.
So, on the next slide let me show you a simple example of a bottom up estimate.
Here's an example of bottom up.
The WBS of tasks for this project are partially shown below.
It's a simple spreadsheet grid of three columns.
You may want to add more columns based on,
you know, what you're trying to do for your project.
In the bold areas I have Project Setup and Delivery Tasks.
And then the next bold area is Development Tasks.
I have Item number, Description, Hours.
So it's a very simple layout.
Let's look at one in particular.
100.
50, this is where we generate QA builds.
I'm going to go ahead and estimate it at 24 hours.
And that's me, say as a project leader doing that.
Then I'm going to sit down with the team.
I'm going to share it with them.
I want them to add tasks, remove tasks,
and adjust any hours that might need to be adjusted,
by their particular level of experience.
This spreadsheet could be five pages long and add up to 2, 000 hours, who knows.
That's why we call it bottom up.
We go down to the necessary detail and build up the estimate.
Hey a final note, each time you do one of these,
you will find yourself adding more and more types of
tasks and the tasks themselves.
So just like the PDD,
you will build up the WBS templates to make reuse very easy and
refining your estimating skills a success. Now we're going to move into the estimates that are made during the project.