Predicting elapsed time is very difficult indeed.
Each way of measuring is important and serves its own purpose.
So we're going to talk about reasons for ideal time and
some good reasons for elapsed time.
These are some of the elements that drive and extend
unpredictability for elapsed time.
Okay, reasons for ideal time, referees need to measure each quarter.
So I'm kind of using the football analogy again.
Referees need to know when the game is over.
So there's a lot of good reasons for ideal time.
Same thing in project management, making estimates.
It's very important to know the true ideal time of what a task takes to do.
And basically what you're doing is is you're coming
up with a common denominator, removing all assumptions,
because they can be so varied by each person and personality and experience.
And here are some reasons for elapsed time, because this is important as well.
You will need to know how long to get a babysitter for your children perhaps.
You will need to also plan driving time to and from the game.
And you may even need to fill your tank with gas.
So these are some really good reasons for elapsed time as well.
And, in the project manager world,
you need to know that someone may be on vacation for a while,
may be sick for a while, may be on another project for a while.
So, we want to know ideal time and then we want to know elapsed time.
Think of one as the raw hours to get the job done and the other one,
the amount of elapsed time, wall clock or calendar,
in which that task could be in fact performed.
So it's more of a schedule.
Now let's discuss more about why estimating with ideal time is best.
Estimating ideal time is almost always easier and more accurate to predict.
Remember the question, how long is a football game?
60 minutes in ideal time.
Clear, concise.
And we can build from there.
Estimating elapsed time is much harder, has more variables,
and is more difficult to predict.
Where before, how long is a football game?
Well, it depends.
And we discussed commercials, half time length,
injuries, penalties, weather, and other elements.
Your project will have the same variables and unknowns
that will make your life more difficult.
Hence we must start with ideal time and work from there.
Remember,
being able to predict an estimate is a key skill and major point of this course.
Beginning your estimates with fuzzy elapse time is not a good
approach and in fact is very difficult to predict.
So we're going to talk about unpredictable elements,
such as sick time, personal issues, phone calls,
the boss calls, email you have to go through,
bug fixing, changing tasks, priority updates,
production failures.
All these elements will affect your team and affect
your estimating capabilities.
These are all very unpredictable and let's just engage that,
we know that,
so let's start with ideal time first and then add on the
appropriate hours into the schedule to accommodate these.
And we're going to talk about those in the next section.
Somewhat predictable elements might be meetings,
demonstrations, developing an architecture.
I may know how many meetings I may need for this project,
I know I need to do three demonstrations.
I must lay out the architecture.
Two of my guys need to get trained,
I have four project reviews and maybe a management review.
I know maybe my team size.
I have a steering committee to report to.
And I have some developer tools maybe to be trained on.
These kind of things I might be able to better predict,
put into an estimating model,
and come up with the ideal time in hours to do those.
On the left side of the slide, it's very difficult to predict sick time,
personal issues, phone calls and such.
That's much more of a challenge.
Each of these we're going to talk about in the following
sections to make it easier and more understandable for you
to predict really good estimates.
In summary for this section, when building your estimates,
start with ideal time, always!
I want to really make this point clear.
The first step in building an estimate is to use ideal time, always.
Now let's see how we can apply our knowledge of ideal and elapsed time, in building team estimates in the next section.