Hello, I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the course Best Practices for Project Estimation.
Course overview.
This course is comprised of three modules.
Fundamentals of estimation.
This module discusses the fundamentals of project estimation and
will give you a broader understanding of terms,
definitions, and background of estimation.
Tools and techniques.
This module provides an overview of several methods and tools that
can be used to help you develop your estimates.
And you will become more comfortable and accurate with your estimates.
Agile estimation.
This module teaches you how to apply Agile approaches to project estimation.
I am sure you've all heard a lot about Agile.
But seriously,
we can learn and adapt several of the Agile philosophies to
attacking estimations in a new and different way.
Let's go over the fundamentals of estimation module overview.
Why are you here?
Planning is everything.
Why do planning?
Runaway projects.
Fears of estimating.
The importance of estimating.
What you need for an estimate.
The right level of effort.
Elements of a project definition.
The project triangle dilemma.
Are you up for the job?
The importance of process.
These will be the topics we will be covering in Module number one.
Let's explore some of the reasons why you may be here today taking this course.
You are asked to be planner and not a doer.
Maybe you have been programming for a while and now you're asked to
step up and play more of a project manager role.
Are you a software engineering expert,
yet feel like fish out of water when it comes to making an estimate?
You are not likely comfortable possibly performing a
management skill test rather than programming.
Do you need help augmenting or transitioning your technical
skills with planning and estimating skills?
I think it is a smart move to grow your soft skills
to augment your technical skills.
Have you been asked to be a project manager on a new project?
With such small staffs today,
many of us are asked to perform more than one kind of task.
Is your project over schedule or over budget?
Maybe you have been doing some planning and estimation,
but your projects are over budget and possibly late.
Are you confused on just how to make a reasonable estimate?
Some people just wing it without any templates or process.
This course will help put some tools and processes in your hands.
Are you afraid of making estimates?
Many developers are just plain nervous about making an estimate.
Generally, it is about committing to an estimate that they know is very weak.
You mean I have to deliver based on what I said?
Ah, yes you do.
"Plans are Nothing; Planning is Everything.
" This is a quotation by Dwight D.
Eisenhower.
Now he wasn't actually saying that plans were worthless of course.
I mean, he did plan the D-Day invasion.
So what did the war hero and former President really mean?
It is the process of planning that is the most important element.
A plan is still very important,
but not as much as the process that creates the plan.
Plans help you consider opportunities and challenges and ways
or approaches to take advantage of them.
Without plans, the planning process,
your projects are at risk of failure to meet its goals.
So plans are certainly important,
but the planning process itself is of the most importance.
Why do planning?
Planning and estimating is difficult.
Yep, we all know that.
Sometimes we don't do enough planning.
Planning is hard.
Let's just start programming.
Sometimes we spend too much time on our plan and we become
rigid and fall in love with our plan.
Organizations, especially the fiscal part of organizations,
expect and in fact demand plans.
That is the business world.
Estimates and plans are not just about determining schedules,
resources, and budgets.
Plans and estimates drive value for the business and investment decisions.
In order to provide optimal value to the business,
plans and estimates are created iteratively and incrementally.
So if earlier in your career you were a software engineer,
you were probably focused on important technical
capabilities and other cools things.
But now, if you are entering the project manager lead role, you will need to better learn the key planning activity of project estimation.