Next, estimate the size using story points, the size of the user story.
Story points are a unit of measure for expressing
the overall size of a user story, feature or task.
Remember in the other modules,
we used more time-based units of measure such as hours and days and weeks.
And in the Agile approach we were considering using planning
poker to develop those story point estimates.
Remember those are abstract values.
And each item or feature is assigned that abstract value or relative value.
The actual value is not relevant, only the relative values.
So for example, let's say I have three user stories below.
And I just used the template to make it simple.
And the value of the first one is 8, the next one is 13, and the next one is 50.
So in this step we had three user stories and through
planning poker we came up with three estimates,
one for each user story.
Next we want to prioritize our user stories by looking at the point values.
So using planning poker we have derived the following
Agile estimates featured below, in the list.
Provision and new customer, 8 points.
Enable the shopping chart, 13 points.
Enable payment with credit cards, 20 points, etc.
So that is the outcome of the planning poker.
Now in this step we want to prioritize.
So what I've shown below is the priority list.
So through further discussions,
including your customer and other subject matter experts,
you're going to prioritize these.
So now instead of the bullets, I have numbers.
So number 1, is Provision a new customer.
Enable the shopping cart, etc.
So this is the order of implementation that is important to the customer.
Now let's see what the iterations are and how we put these
prioritized items together in the next slide.
A key part of any work is to deliver software based
on the priorities of the customer.
So what I've shown here is a simple chart,
Iteration #1 on the left, Iteration #2 on the right.
And on the left I've used the template to keep it simple with the
three priority items from the previous slide.
Values of 8, 13, and 20.
They total 41 points.
Let's just assume my velocity of my team is 50 points.
That would fit nicely into one iteration.
Now the remaining three items, I just threw over into Iteration #2,
but we notice that one is 100, one is 40,
one is 20, so that's 160.
That cannot fit into a normal iteration of our team.
So either one, we increase the length of time for iteration,
I do not like that or recommend that.
So what I'd probably do is get the team back together.
Maybe even use planning poker.
Break up the one that's 100 point value into sub-user stories,
and provide more granularity.
Come back into this room, lay out Iteration 3,
4, 5,
and use these stickies on the wall to kind of place
them into the different columns.
And I like using stickies and I like using a whiteboard.
I like it to be very,
really old school and very interactive to move things around very easily. Okay, now let's look at velocity in more detail.