Our final section of this module is an overview summary.
This module has covered many practical and simple tools and techniques to
help improve your estimating skills and techniques.
Let's review the key points on the next slide.
Summary.
Constantly refine your techniques.
Observe what works and what doesn't.
View my information as a starter kit and improve upon it yourself.
Include as many subject matter experts as possible.
Work as much as you can as a team, and pull in the right smart people.
Track your actual cost.
Track, track, track.
As you learn, tracking your time plays a key role in producing quality estimates.
Tracking is critical to your success.
Educate your management on why estimation is good for business.
You may need to explain to management the benefits of a good estimation process,
but also if they see your documents and templates,
they'll begin to build trust and support your efforts.
Ideal capacity is the best place to start.
Determine what your team is truly capable to produce.
This is critical for quality estimates and planning.
Use resource schedule planning.
This provides really good granularity of your resources over a timeframe.
Arbitrary padding must be avoided, and is never a good thing.
Only managed buffers should be used.
Schedules are the next step after your incremental estimates.
Estimates alone are not enough.
You next need to determine what the schedule will be.
The 5 and 50 rules help you manage the work effort.
5 minutes to review the assigned task and ask any questions,
and at the 50% mark are you 50% complete?
It's just plain, good project management.
In the next module, Agile Estimation,
we'll explore how the approach to estimation has changed in the world of Agile. See you there.