Runaway projects.
Two of the most common causes of runaway projects are,
poor requirements and poor estimation.
Poor requirements and poor estimations drive runaway projects.
By the way,
I have another Pluralsight course on Best Practices for
Requirements Gathering that addresses the other piece to
the puzzle of runaway projects.
You might check it out.
So getting a handle on developing quality requirements is very
important to helping you create quality estimates.
Requirements gathering and estimation go hand in hand and are tightly coupled.
Here's the typical estimating process that you've probably experienced yourself.
You're in the middle in the blue shirt.
On your right is the CEO and on your left is the CFO.
Chief Executive Office, Chief Financial Officer, oh great.
The CEO says, I need an estimate for this project, now!
I have no idea!
I don't even know the requirements.
Don't worry, says the CFO.
I won't hold you to it.
Oh, help us all.
I'm sure you've all experienced that.
And so this course will help you work through that situation.
You may have been assigned to provide the estimates for this project.
But really, who's making these estimates anyway?
Problem.
Estimates are done by management or marketing and maybe not by you.
Many times the subject matter experts are not involved.
The people that are closest to the business and the
implementation must be involved.
Solution.
Build trust, have an estimation process,
and earn your place as the go to person for making estimates.
It is up to you to be assertive and proactive and assume
control of the estimation process.
Don't let it control you.
Problem.
Estimates are rarely adjusted as the project proceeds.
Once a number is thrown out there, it seems to unfortunately stick.
Solution.
Estimation must be iterative to be successful.
Work and educate management on the benefits of this approach.
This may mean giving management presentations on your estimation process,
for example.
Management buy-in to an iterative estimation process is critical and
required for improving the quality of estimates.
This is a biggie everyone.
You will need to work with managers and leaders to secure their
buy-in to your process and philosophy of estimation.
This will make your life as a project manager or planner much, much easier.
Estimate versus budget.
As a PM or lead you may be requested to provide an estimate.
You also may be told what the estimate is.
Huh?
You're going to be told what the estimate is?
I thought that was your job to create the estimate?
Typically though, when you're told the estimate,
it is really the budget that they're telling you.
Let's define budget.
A fixed amount of money allocated for a particular
purpose such as IT or capital expenditures.
So basically what they're saying is, is this is all I have to spend right now,
so make it fit.
The definition of an estimate is an estimate or approximation,
which is a value that is usable for some purpose.
So when you return to give your estimate to management,
there will likely be a gap between the budget and the estimate.
And typically the estimate will be greater than the budget.
Right?
This course will provide the tools and the techniques to negotiate the gap trap.
Fears of estimating.
Yes, we all have them.
Let's see if any of these resonate with you.
Initial estimates become the target estimate.
Once someone hears that magic number, they seem to never forget it.
Do they?
Failed estimates, failed projects that is, in the past.
I've never given a good one before, so I doubt this one is any good either.
Job insecurity, job security.
I don't want to be fired so I better make it big — pad, pad, pad.
Later we'll talk about padding and why that is not good to do in general.
Fist time project.
If this kind of project has never been done before,
it is really hard to make an estimate because there may be a lot of unknowns.
Here are a few more fears to share with you.
Unclear or improper work definition.
We talked about that before.
Poor requirements make quality estimates almost impossible.
A moving target.
If requirements keep changing, how can I possibly make a good estimate?
Customer expectations.
Don't they always want it all?
Sometimes customers want it all,
hence a large estimate is just around the corner.
Plus there are other things you just can't control.
The economy, budgets, people, life in general.
This course will help give you the confidence to overcome those fears to produce quality estimates.