All right everyone, welcome to this bonus lesson on the storefront API.
Until now, we've been working just with the online store sales channel.
If I look in my Shopify store,
you can see a list of sales channel and online store is
the one that comes pre-installed with your Shopify account.
Of course, the way to customize your online store sales channel is through themes.
We've been doing everything from within a theme.
Well, the storefront API actually allows us to
access our store data from anywhere on the web.
I thought about how best to explain this and I think
probably the best way is for you guys to see it straight away.
What I'm going to do is show you an app that I created.
I call this app the Shopify customer storefront app.
I've hosted on a free app host called Heroku app.
In order to use this app,
I'm going to have to insert some Store details.
I've got the access token that I've created already
ready to go and the store domain is right here.
If I hit submit,
it's going to connect to my store and then suddenly you're seeing
a custom storefront that I've built on a completely different address to Shopify.
Right here, this app is made with a JavaScript framework called view JS,
which I recently learned and it's really cool for making interactive client-side apps.
What you can do with this app is you can browse collections within a particular store,
in this case my store,
the Chris testing shop.
You can browse the different pages of content,
you can click on a particular item,
you can select a variant,
you can add the variant to the cart,
and this is all done on the client side.
As you can see, there's no page refreshes at all because I've
made this completely with a JavaScript framework called view JS.
You could also use this API to create apps in angular or react,
it's a great way for you to use your store data in a completely client-side way.
Now if I click checkout here,
it goes to the actual checkout of my store,
and so it goes back to Shopify,
but this whole shopping experience here including looking at blogs,
is all on this third-party hosting platform.
Each time I click on something and load data,
it's coming through via the storefront API.
Let's open up my network tab and we can actually see these requests coming through.
I'm going to go to my Network tab and click the tab for XHR.
Let's refresh my app.
You can see we've made three requests here.
The storefront API uses something called GraphQL,
which is a whole topic in itself.
If you haven't been familiar with the GraphQL way of doing APIs,
but essentially we've GraphQL,
there's a single endpoint rather than multiple endpoints,
and you send a query to that endpoint
and it gives you back the exact data that you're looking for.
If you've used rest APIs before,
maybe there's an API endpoint where you request all of,
let's say the collections in your store,
but in this case I only want the image,
I want the title and I want the link to the collection.
Well, in a rest API,
you might not be able to select only that data,
and so what you would do is you would request all of the information about collections.
That means that you might have to make multiple API requests
or just make requests that are bigger than they need to be.
Again, this is a little bit more of an advanced topic,
but I just wanted you to get the concept and perhaps maybe you
can use the storefront API for your own purposes down the track.
Going back to this network tab here,
if I click on the first request, if I go into header,
you can see the query that I send through to
the API and this query right here is a GraphQL query.
It basically says that I want
the shop object and I want these attributes on the shop object.
That's just some GraphQL syntax.
Here you can see what we get back from the API.
We get the shop data and we get things like currency code,
the name of the store,
primary domain and the reason why this request
exists is because I'm using the name of the store right here.
Let's look at the next one.
It looks like this one is accessing the collections.
As you can see here, this is the GraphQL query.
I know it's quite big,
if you don't understand GraphQL, don't worry,
you're not going to understand this,
but the point I'm making is you get something back from the storefront API.
It is all the collection data,
but no more than what you requested.
In my case, what I've done is I've
requested each collection and I want to know its handle,
it's ID, and I want the first product of
every collection and the first image of every product in that collection.
The reason why is if the image is null,
I want to be able to access the first image of the first product instead,
so that's why I've accessed deep into this collection.
Then you've got the third request.
The third request as you can see here,
is accessing the pages with in my store.
Where I use this is right down here to provide some links to different pages.
I'm using the name of the page and then I'm using
the handle to create a unique link to that page as well.
If I click on about us,
you can see this pulls the data from the about us page.
If we click here,
we can see another request to get more information which in fact is the same information.
If we do some more clicking around,
if I click on blog,
you can see we make another storefront API request.
If I dig in here, you can see we've got a list of articles.
Then of course this data is being represented on the page using view JS.
So to give you a little bit of a look into the app if you're interested,
I've got it right here,
the services folder is where I make all my API requests.
In my base service,
I've got the settings for the storefront API request.
Then I create this API call function,
which uses a library code axis to actually query the storefront API and I expose
that function to the product service and here's all my GraphQL queries.
Now again, this is going deep into a lot of different concepts like view JS,
which you might not be familiar with,
GraphQL, which you might not be familiar with
and maybe you don't even have much experience with APIs,
so don't get overwhelmed right here.
We're not going to spend a lot of time going through this,
but what I want to do in this lesson is show you an example
of how we can use this data in our theme.
This class of course, is about Shopify theme programming and it is
possible to use the storefront API in your theme if you so choose.
So that's what we're going to focus on in this lesson,
but for most people,
the storefront API is going to be most useful when
you need to access the data of your Shopify store.
But you want to be able to do that in a completely custom way, for instance,
creating a custom storefront or perhaps a phone app that uses the data of your store.
The store for an API is all about accessing data that the customer sees.
So none of this has to do with accessing things like adding products,
adding customers, creating discounts.
That is all through the admin API,
which is what you use to build apps that go right here in your apps section.
Again, I don't want to talk too much about all of that because that is
outside the context of Shopify theme programming,
but what I want to do in this lesson is show you an example of how we can
actually use the storefront API in a theme on our own store.
What we're going to need to do is if I go back to
my app and I've sent an option here to disconnect.
We can see that I need a sharp domain and I need a store for an access token.
As you saw before, I already had a token and I put it inside,
but let's go and recreate a token so
that you guys can see how you would do this yourselves,
so if I go into apps,
then I go into manage private apps.
You should be familiar with this process if you've configured theme kit before,
because as you can see here,
we had to create a private app in order to use theme kit.
As you can see down here, I've got this storefront API app.
I'm going to delete that and recreate it for you guys so we can
see how we can create a storefront API app ourselves.
Up here there's a button for Create a new private app,
I'm going to click that and name this app something appropriate.
I'm just going to call it storefront API app.
This is basically the interface that will allow you to connect to the storefront API.
We're going to put in the emergency developer e-mail.
As you can see here,
we can set some admin API permissions.
We don't need that. What we need is some storefront API permissions.
Right here, all we need to do is check this check box and then we can
customize what permissions we're going to enable this API.
The ones that it's checked already should be good
enough but let's just check everything just in case.
If we hit "Save",
it's going to warn us that anyone who has these credentials can make
requests to the API so be careful about who you share this API with.
I'm going to click "I understand, create the app".
Now you can see that the app is created and if I scroll down,
it gives me the storefront access token.
I'm going to leave this page open so we can access that token later,
and I'm going to open up my online store sales channel in a new tab.
What I'm going to do is head back into our new theme and let's edit the index template.
We've got all of this code here from our advanced liquid lesson,
going to remove that.
What I'm going to do instead is put one div that's going to hold our content.
Actually I'm going to give it an ID because there's only going to be
one and I'm going to open up some script tags.
Because we are using an API that can access data from wherever on the Internet,
we could do this in any template.
It doesn't have to be in the index.liquid template,
could be literally anywhere.
For this video, for demonstration purposes,
it just makes sense to do it in the index.liquid template.
What I'm going to do is grab some data using the storefront API and then represent
it on the page via jQuery inserting that content into this div.
I'm going to copy and paste the API code because it does take some configuration.
This is a function that I created earlier, obviously.
What it does is it takes a query and then sends that query to the Ajax API.
Then with that response,
we can actually access the data that comes back.
Let's step through this really quickly.
We're using the inbuilt fetch function within
JavaScript to make a request to the storefront API endpoint,
which is just your storefront name/api/graphql.json.
If we were making this request off of Shopify,
we would of course have to include the store name.
If I switch over to my app and I go to the settings in my apiCall here,
you see that we've had to set the store name here.
But because we're already on the store itself right here,
we can just use the relative URL and send a request to /api/graphql.json.
Then we open up this object here.
We make sure that the method is post and we have to send these headers.
We have to make sure the content type is GraphQL,
we have to allow control origin and of course,
we need our access token.
This is what we generated before.
If I go back to my private app,
remember I wanted to keep this open,
I'm going to have to go down here,
copy that access token,
and replace the access token here with my own.
Next we're setting the body of the request to
the query which is going to be passed in to here.
Then with the response,
we are going to encode it with json.
We need to do this in order for us to actually read the data.
The two things that we're going to need is we're going to need an actual query.
Just going to set up a blank query up here.
Then we have to actually call the API.
I'm going to set them up now,
going to API query,
and then I'm going to use that promise.
I'm going to say response, console, log response.
All this is going to do, once we send the query
is console log what we get back from the server.
In order to create this query,
a handy tool is on the storefront API documentation.
I believe it's on getting started or the first page of API reference.
Just to note, there is a lot of information here if you want to do
your own research into the storefront API.
This is more of a practical little show and tell of how you can actually use the API.
But if you go to this page,
the API reference page for the storefront API,
you can scroll down and you get this interactive GraphQL Explorer.
This helps you to create GraphQL queries.
As you can see here, we've got a very basic one which
grabs the sharp object and then gets the name from it.
If I run that, you can see what we'll get back is something like this.
Let's just use this to test whether our API call is set up correctly.
In this query, I'm going to send through this GraphQL query.
If I hit "Save" on that,
and then I preview the theme,
we should see nothing come up on the page apart from the header.
But if I open up my console,
we will see we've got an error,
we've got a missing bracket after an argument list.
Let's just go back. Maybe there was a mistake somewhere here.
Yes, I have forgotten to put an extra bracket there.
Let's refresh this page.
Now that we've got this console open,
we can see that we've got an object that comes back from the storefront API.
We can verify this is from the storefront API by going over to our network tab,
and you can see here is a response from the API.
We can see the query that we sent through and we can see the response.
Since we console logged that object,
we now have it available in our console as well.
We've got our store name,
which is something we could easily do within a theme anyway.
Let's do something a little bit more involved.
What I'm going to do, head back over to here,
and I'm going to copy across a GraphQL query that I had in my custom storefront app.
If I go over to my project code,
I'm just going to grab the API code here for grabbing
the first 20 products of the store and I'm going to update our query here.
Let's save that and let's see if that works.
Going into here, we have got an object coming back with all these products.
So if we open all of this up,
we can see we have got all the data that we asked for.
If we go into the Network tab, everything's still good.
We've got what we sent through in our GraphQL query,
and we've got the result back.
Again, I'm not going to spend a whole lot of time teaching you
GraphQL because that is a whole topic in itself.
But I just want to show you what we're able to do here.
We've got all this data, which is lovely.
But we want to actually use this data.
What we can do is use jQuery to update our page.
Most themes have jQuery already installed.
If you're working on an existing theme,
definitely check if you already have jQuery
because this is the new theme and it's very basic.
I'm going to have to actually import jQuery from the CDN.
If I just look up jQuery on Google,
there should be a link here to the jQuery CDN,
and this gives us a link to a minified version of jQuery.
I can grab that,
and using my knowledge of liquid tags,
can put in that as a string and then use
the script tag filter to actually create a script tag out of that.
What I'm going to do in order to test whether jQuery is working,
is use a jQuery function which shouldn't work if jQuery isn't installed,
but should work if jQuery is installed.
What I'm going to do, this just console log ready when the document is ready.
If I hit "Save" on that,
I refresh the page,
open up the console first rather,
and then refresh the page,
you'll see we've got ready and then data.
We know that we've definitely got jQuery installed now.
I'm going to get rid of that ready function.
Now what we need to do is handle our response differently.
What I'm going to do is put in some curly brackets here,
and I'm going to keep the console log response because I'm going to reference it.
But what we're going to do is actually loop through
the products here and have something come out on the screen.
I'm using what's in the console log to figure out how to navigate these objects.
We've got a data object,
then we've got products,
then we've got edges inside of that.
Edges is an array.
Then we're going to loop through that array,
find the node of each of these array items,
and then that is the data for each of our products.
I'll go back into here,
and I'm going to take the response,
then I'm going to navigate into data,
then I'm going to navigate into products, then edges.
I know there's a lot of dots here.
Then this is where we start our loop.
So I can say for each and I can grab the product,
and then what we're going to do for each product
is I just want to make sure that we're looking at the right thing.
I'm going to actually just console log product.node.
Let's have a look if that works.
I'll hit "Save', refresh the page over here with the console open.
As you can see,
we've got the initial console log,
which has the entire response that we got back.
Then you can see an individual console log for each of
the products with their attributes that we got back in that data object.
Now we're inside this loop,
we can actually translate this data into content on the actual page.
What I'm going to do is create a template.
I'm going to call this const template,
and in this template,
I'm going to construct some HTML.
Let's say div class, product.
Let's break this up into another line so that we have some nice spacing,
makes it a bit more readable,
and then I'm going to do a heading for each.
Using string interpolation, I'm going to navigate into that product node,
so product.node, and the attribute I'm looking for is title.
I'm going to grab the title of the product,
then underneath, what should we show?
Maybe the product description,
product.node.description, one more thing, maybe the image.
There's going to be multiple images for a particular product.
Well, the possibility at least for a multiple images for a particular product,
so this one is going to be a little bit more complicated, but we'll get there.
What I'm going to do is open up an HTML image tag,
and in order to get the src,
the actual address to the image.
What I'm going to have to do is navigate into our product node,
and then from within our node,
I need to access this images,
object, and then inside the edges.
I am going to do this little bit step-by-step, so images,
edges, and I want the first image of the list of images available in this product.
I'm going to select that using it's zero index.
Now, we're going to be inside this one,
and we want to get the node,
and then within node, the transformedSrc, node.transformedSrc.
If you're wondering what transformedSrc is,
we can actually in our graph QL request,
specify what we want the maxWidth and maxHeight of the image to be,
like what we did with image URL tags or filters in Liquid.
Hopefully, we have navigated our objects correctly,
I've missed out one final step here, and that is,
I have to actually append the template to this div up here.
I'm going to open up a jQuery selector,
target that div, and then I'm going to append the template.
This is going to be added for every product in the loop to this content div up here,
so I'm going to hit ''Save'' on that, refresh the page.
Now you'll see we have the data that we got from
here in our Storefront API represented on our page.
We've got the title, we've got the image,
we've got the description,
and you can see it,
all the first 20 products in our store are coming out.
Now, this is all through JavaScript,
we're not using any Liquid here,
this is all client side.
You can maybe see this on a slower connection or maybe if I just refresh the page,
you'll see there's a slight delay before everything loads,
and then the products,
and their names, and images loads.
Basically what's happening is,
the server side code gets generated first,
you get the page back,
the page finishes loading,
and then shortly after,
we get the asynchronous load in JavaScript.
Again, it's not entirely clear perhaps why we
would use the Storefront API to access this data when we can already access it in Liquid.
But this is an example of how you could actually use the Storefront API in your themes.
Again, the best use of the Storefront API is if you
want to create a fully client-side application.
If I just throw in my store for an access token into this app again,
this right here is a perfect example of a purely client-side app,
and it makes sense that we would use the data using a JSON API,
which doesn't make us reload the page every time.
You can see here that this is all done in the client side,
meaning that we don't ever have to reload the page.
I guess that would be a major benefit of using the Storefront API.
Again, this is why this is a bonus lesson,
and it's a bonus lesson because you're probably not going to use the Storefront API,
but I wanted to leave you with a short lesson on this API to show you what's possible.
Maybe you actually want to create a custom Storefront,
or maybe you actually need to access some data that's
available in the API that is not available in Liquid.
I actually know of a few examples where
the Storefront API gives you data that Liquid does not,
so maybe you want to use it for those fringe cases.
If you want to learn all about the different objects in the Storefront API,
here's where you can do so.
Just like we saw in the Shopify Liquid documentation,
we can look at the objects available in the Storefront API through this menu here.
It did take me a while to figure out how to actually read this correctly,
but if we have a look at what we did for today's lesson with products,
you can see here that this shows you all of the, what's called connections.
This is other resources that you can access from a product as an entry point,
and then down here,
is all the attributes.
For instance, if I wanted to access the product handle, this is how you would do it.
The description in HTML,
the createdAt date right here,
and metafield stored on that product.
Finally, right here is what's called a QueryRoute,
which is the entry point for queries,
this is what we used to access all the products.
As you can see from the QueryRoute,
we can access articles,
blogs, collections, pages, and products as we did.
Then once you're inside the product,
you can click here to learn about the product connection and you navigate
this API documentation as if you were navigating a graph QL response.
This mimics what we saw here in the sense that right here we're at the QueryRoute.
So we go back to QueryRoute,
and in our QueryRoute,
we're going into products,
so down here, products.
If I click on products connection,
you'll now see we can do edges or page infur, here we go.
Edges. If I go into edges,
each edge is going to have a node and cursor if we ask for it.
As you can see, each has a node,
and then if we click on ''Node'',
it gives us a product,
and then you can see the connections on that object and the fields available.
As you can see, we accessed some of those fields, we accessed description,
handle ID, and we accessed connections to the images and tags as well.
This is definitely a more advanced a lesson,
and it took me a while to figure out how to use the Storefront API myself.
It's definitely not something you can learn in a 20 minute lesson,
but this is why it's a bonus lesson.
It's a bit of an eye-opener to show you
another way that you can represent your store data in a custom Storefront,
or perhaps in a unique way on your online theme.
There is, of course, one more API which I mentioned before,
which is the Admin API,
and if you want to go into Shopify App Development,
this is the API that you're going to need to learn.
I have actually created a Shopify App myself using this API,
it was a pretty cool experience,
but definitely not something I could cover in a 20 minute video ever.
That's perhaps a topic for another class.
But that's pretty much it guys,
that should cover a pretty good overview
of everything to do with Shopify Theme Programming.
If you've made it this far,
I want to thank you and congratulate you on sticking with it.
There is a lot to Shopify Theme Programming,
and if you want to learn more about it,
the blog post is out on my website, christhefreelancer.com/Shopify-Liquid-guide/.
It's over 10,000 words on Shopify,
so if you're feeling bored or adventurous and want
to have a long read about everything, Shopify Liquid,
obviously we can't cover 10,000 words of content in a single skill share class,
but this is where I would go to learn more about the different pots.
If you have any questions,
as always, leave them in discussion box below.
Thanks a lot guys, and I'll see you in the next one.