Hey students, I just wanted to jump in here before we start and make sure you're
aware of something Shopify are calling Online Store 2.0.
As you can probably tell,
this video was recorded a few years after the original class was posted,
but I thought it was important to jump in here and let you know about some updates.
If you know what I'm talking about here with Online Store 2.0,
feel free to skip this video.
But for the rest of you,
I just need to update you on a few changes to
the online store experience since this class first went live.
Just to address some of your concern students,
the content in this class is still all relevant.
Liquid is still in that same form.
JSON is still used for section schemas and locales.
The JavaScript APIs I talk about in this class all still exist at the time of recording,
but we just have a new format for template files.
So now templates can be of either Liquid or JSON.
We'll get further into this in the class.
You should probably by now know what a template is.
But previously, templates were coded as only
Liquid and you had to hide program in the sections.
Now, in order to allow for sections everywhere,
Shopify have enabled the use of JSON templates.
So now instead of storing Liquid directly in your template,
you store a JSON object in your template,
and that JSON object has the list of sections that
you can then reorder in your theme editor,
and this allows you to create re-orderable sections in all of your templates,
not just your homepage.
If you want to learn more about JSON templates,
I go deeper into it in Lesson 11 of the previous class.
I just added a new video in that class for you guys so you can
learn what JSON templates are and how to use them.
That being said, it's going to change
your development tool now if you want to use JSON templates.
In the next video, I mentioned Slate.
I don't recommend you use Slate unless you're picking up a legacy project.
Slate is well expired now.
Shopify ended support officially for Shopify Slate back in January 2020.
I don't recommend you use it unless of course,
you have to because you're taking on a legacy project.
But even then, I would recommend migrating off of Slate.
In the last video,
I mentioned a tool called Theme Kit,
but there's also a new tool now called Shopify CLI,
and it's important to note Shopify CLI here
because it's the tool that you're going to have to use if you want to use JSON templates.
For whatever reason, Theme Kit hasn't been adapted to work with the new JSON templates.
So if you want to use JSON templates,
you're going to have to use Shopify CLI.
Those are the main changes to note before we get into the class.
As I said, Liquid is still the same,
JSON is still the same,
JavaScript API still exist.
The latest change from Shopify is that
template files can now be of either Liquid or JSON.
Again, to learn more about Online Store 2.0,
you can check out the three new videos I added to the Shopify theme development class,
I mentioned the JSON Schemas one.
If you want to learn about the CLI,
that's in Lesson 6, I believe,
so Lesson 6 of my previous class,
and there's also an intro to Online Store 2.0 in that class as well.
I also have a Online Store 2.0 playlist on YouTube
that you can check out for more information about Online Store 2.0.
But with that being said,
let's return to the class and learn how we can program in Shopify theme development.