All right guys, in this lesson we're going to put
together everything we've learned so far about
Shopify Liquid and JSON Schemas to practice creating our own section.
What I'm going to do is create a gallery section,
which will be a section that we can include on the homepage for content,
for index or on a specific page and it'll just show a gallery of
images that the user in the customizer specifies.
What I'm going to do, head over the sections,
add a new section,
and I'm going to call it gallery.
As usual, Shopify gives us
a Schema and we just need to change the section name to gallery.
Hit "Save" on that.
I'm going to just set up a div with a class of gallery and there you go.
Now, how this gallery is going to work is,
I'm going to allow the user to specify how many columns they want per row,
and then also the height of the image,
and then I am going to allow them to
insert blocks which are going to be the images that we will include.
Going over to the documentation and looking at the section on
blocks within the document on theme sections,
let's scroll back down there again for blocks.
You can see here that we can put in blocks which are containers of settings and content,
which can be added, removed,
and reordered with intersection,
and that is ideal for what we're doing here.
We want them to be able to add in as many images as they want and reorder them,
and we just need the same settings for each.
I'm going to skip over the settings array for now and create a blocks array,
and in this blocks array,
I'm going to open up a block.
Now, for a block,
what we need is a type and a name,
as it says here,
a block must have a name and a type.
A block's type may be any value set by the theme developer.
So the type is not something that's specific in Shopify,
it's just something that we set ourselves.
I'm going to make the type and image,
and you'll see later we can add in
different types and then check the type within our section.
I'm going to give it a name and call it image block.
This is going to be the label that gets shown up to the user.
Now, I believe we can just create a settings array just
like we would do on the parent object here.
I'm going to add a settings array,
open that one up and inside start with the first object,
which is going to be an image input.
For that, we're going to swap over to this part of the documentation called
configuring theme settings and I'm going to look for image.
The input setting type for an image is
image underscore picker and we can just copy the setting value here.
It's going to be image picker,
we just need a type,
ID, and the label.
Going back to our code here, pasting that in,
we're going to change the ID to image,
and we're just going to put image here, very basic.
So that is the settings that we'll have for every block.
If I hit "Save" on that,
let's see if there's any errors, no, there isn't.
What I can do now is I can create a loop through all the blocks in OWL section.
I'm going to create this loop and I'm going to say,
"for block in section.blocks," and then I'm going to enter the loop.
We'll format this, make this look a bit nicer in a little bit,
but for now let's just get this content out in the page.
Now, we can reference block directly and I'm just going to create
an image tag with the image that gets set, so block.settings.image.
Remember how we access different attributes is just navigating this JSON object.
So at the top here,
we find blocks on the section object and now we're looping through
an individual block and then we have access to what's in here,
the settings object, and then within that,
we can access the attribute using its ID.
That's what's going on here.
If I just output this,
what I'll get is just the image address.
Before we can actually look at it, however,
we need to include it somewhere and what I'm going to do for that is
create an alternate template for page template,
and then we're going to use the ultimate template to display this section.
Fortunately, there's a few steps involved with doing this.
We need to first go into our templates folder and add an alternate page template.
I'm just going to call this one gallery, create the template.
One thing that's frustrating with Shopify is we're going
to have to create this on the current theme as well.
So if you're currently working on the theme that you're
previewing and not actually live on your website,
you have to create the same template on your current theme as well otherwise,
you won't be able to select it.
But for now what I'm going to do is include this section on here.
So I'm going to strip out all of this and in this custom page template,
just call the gallery section,
and I'll hit "Save".
Now as I said,
in order for us to select it from the list,
I'm going to have to go into the current live theme,
which is debut and create the same template which I may have already done here.
There is already a template with the name page.gallery.
If that didn't exist,
I can just delete that one,
go into add page,
exact same way we've done before for the other theme,
and what we'll do will insert the same content as the regular page template.
So you don't need to worry if you switch this within the page,
it's still going to show the same page template on this theme,
if that makes sense.
Now, if I go into pages and I add a page,
call it gallery, I can use
that specific template that we just created by selecting it here.
If I save the page,
now we can look at what the address of it is.
It's going to be @pages/gallery.
So let's go back into the code.
As we saw, we have already included the section on that alternate template.
Now, we just need to go to the page that we just set up.
Pages gallery.
Right now we haven't added any content so nothing is going to show up.
What we want to do is open this page in the customizer.
We're going to have to first refresh because we've made
changes to our theme codes since we had this
open and now we should be able to see that we can edit the gallery template.
Picking on that. Now we can see the section for Gallery.
Just taking it a little bit slower,
we're in the page for gallery and as it's using this specific alternate template,
it's going to link directly to this section and
then within that page now for the customizer,
we can see the section showing up here.
So in the gallery,
you can now see that there's going to be
this content section and you can add an image block.
That is all from the settings we set up in our gallery section.
So we don't need this anymore,
we just need that one tag.
We can start working directly from the gallery section right here.
But remember, we called it an image block and so here in the customizer,
it's add image block.
If there are multiple types,
we'd be able to click this and it give us different options,
but we just have the one option for now.
As you can see, there's our image setting that we've got here.
We can now add an image.
We've got men on the front and we can add another image, block,
the guy with the suit and you can see here what happens when I do that.
Instead of the actual image,
we've got a URL section.
What's happening here is that the image being
selected is not actually going to give you an image tag.
So in order to get the image tag,
what I'm going to do is use the image tag filter right here.
Now, we may need to specify a distinct path as well,
let's have a look, so there you go,
they are showing up and because we didn't
add a parameter they are showing up quite small,
this should be 100 by 100.
If we have a look, so the width is a 100 and
then the height is relative to the width in terms of its aspect ratio.
We're going to need to make them a bit bigger.
I'm going to add in a parameter for this image tag of, let's say 500x.
So now they're going to be five times as bigger,
five times as big, rather.
I've made a mistake here and I see that the parameter,
it actually represents the alt tag.
If you want to put in alt value, that's where you put it.
What I need to do is chain another filter in here.
I'm going to filter this for image URL like
before and that's where I can specify the dimension of the image.
I'll save that, refresh the page,
and now the image is five times as big.
What we've got here is we've got,
if I just refresh the page in the customizer,
we've got this gallery.
So we can add another image block.
If the image isn't set yet,
Shopify just inserts a place holder,
which isn't very beautiful,
but it shows us that there is at least supposed to be
an image there and I can add in another image,
and basically what's going to happen is they're all going to
be 500 wide and they're just going to
stack across the horizontal and vertical space of our page.
If I refresh the page,
maybe this is good enough for your gallery,
but I want to make this way more responsive.
What I'm going to do is I am going to give this
a responsive width and create a height that the user can change.
What I'm going to do is in here,
instead of just outputting an image,
what I'm going to do is create a image wrap and in this image wrap tag,
I'm going to give it a background image of the image that we set here.
The benefit of doing this if you're not familiar,
is that we can control the height and width of the div and then the image will fit within
that and it'll crop based on the dimensions of this div tag right here.
What I'm going do is add in a style attribute and have
background image URL and I don't need the image tag anymore,
and I can insert this here.
Now we need to give it some dimensions.
Just to give it something straight away,
I'm going to give it a width of 500 pixels and a height of 500 pixels,
and then I'm going to give it a [inaudible] ,
create some space here.
Here we go. Then I'm going to give it a background size of cover. Save that.
See what happens when we refresh the page.
You'll see now, if we have a look,
these aren't image tags anymore,
they are actually divs,
and that's why they're stacking on top of each other because these are
set to default to display block,
as you can see here in the computed values.
We want them to display next to each other, so inline-block.
Now, we can either set it up in
our main CSS file or we can do it in the actual section by refactoring this to style,
not style sheet and putting in our styles here.
Now, in this case,
I'm going to put it in the actual section and there's a good reason for that,
because when we use these style tags,
we can see things live update in the customizer.
We could always just throw in styles using HTML.
But if we do this,
if there is a user generated style within here,
like something they set in the customizer and we changed that.
It's not going to show up straight away.
So using these liquid tags,
we can actually store our styles in
the section and that's going to make it easier to find.
But also we're going to get the ability to see
those live update if we use customize a data in here.
So I'll show you what I mean by that in just a sec,
but first I'm going to create a style rule in here
for image rap and what I'm going to do is
set all image wraps to display inline block and if we go over to our page,
even the customizer or over here and refresh the page.
We'll see they are now stack next to each other.
If we go over here,
we'll see that we've got display inline block.
This is a little bit better because if we resize the window,
so I'm going to move this over to the side and see how the window resizes.
It's going to knock it down to the new line if there's no space.
But to make it a bit more responsive,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to set the width to a relative value.
Going back into here,
we're going to set image rap to width of 33 percent.
That way we get three in a row.
So I'm going to remove this value right
here and actually let's move these values into the class just to make it a bit cleaner.
Right here, these are going to be the same for every image rap,
so we're going to put this down here in the actual style row here.
Refresh the page and now you can see our images are responsive.
So again, if I was to resize,
you can see there's always going to be three on a row
and they're going to resize in order to achieve that on any screen size.
Now, for the user, they might want to choose how many images they're up for
a row and they also might want to be able to change the height of the images,
because, as I said,
with responsive images, they automatically crop.
Like we saw before,
if I reduce this,
they're always going to be three on every row,
so now we're losing parts of the image.
So maybe we want to make this less tall if we're using a lot of images per row.
Anyway. So I want to give the option to the user to be able to
affect this value and also the ability to affect this value.
Because this is going to happen to the entire grid,
this is going to be a setting up here,
not in a specific block.
The first setting I want to do is I think I'm going to have a select.
We haven't used select before.
So let's go into the different input types we have available to us and look at select.
I'm going to grab the example as
a starting point and replace this empty objects with the example.
So we've got the type of select,
I'm going to set this to,
per row and it's going to show to the user products, oh sorry,
images per row, and then for our options,
we don't need a group,
we just need a value and a label.
In our options array,
I'm going to have three different values and this is going to be the widths.
If they choose two per row,
it's going to be 50 percent.
So two per row and if they choose three per row,
it's going to be 33 percent, three per row.
We need to duplicate that across,
ends this one 44 per row,
is going to be 25 percent.
Let's just do five per row as well.
Add in another option and we'll make this one five per row.
The default, it has to be one of these.
Let's make the default three per row.
That's going to be 33 percent and the info we don't, really need.
I'm going to hit "Save" here and I've deliberately added in a error,
or I've deliberately left an error in my JSON schema.
Now, unfortunately,
in Shopify in their code editor and when you're using theme kit as well,
they just say error invalid JSON and if you have a big schema,
it could take you forever to figure out what the issue is.
So I know what I've done wrong,
but maybe you can't pick it right now.
Luckily, because it is just a JSON object,
we can actually put it through a JSONLinta and
see what the issue is.So I just want to show you how to do that right now.
I know that the issue right here is that we've got a comma at the end here.
So remember we remove that value.
The last value cannot have a comma after it,
but we might not know that so one thing we can do is use a online JSONLinta,
so I've just copied the whole JSON object and I'm
going to go to a website called jsonlint.com I believe.
I'm going to paste in our JSON object,
doesn't matter that it represents Shopify data.
All this does is take the format of the JSON and check whether it is correctly formatted.
So right here, we have a much more detailed error message,
which is we've got an error on line 24.
It expected a string it got a closing curly bracket.
So that's still might take a little bit deciphering to figure out what the issue is here.
But at least we get a specific line number and we can say,
oh, I've got this comma here.
So if I go back,
take away that comma,
hit save, now you'll see that we have no errors.
So the next thing I need to do is actually reference
this value that's been set in the customizer here.
So instead of 33 percent I'm going to,
as we have done numerous times throughout this class,
reference the section object,
go into its settings and grab per row.
I'm going to hit save on that and let's go back into our customizer and refresh.
All right, so now I'm going to go into the gallery section and you can see that we
now have a drop-down for selecting how many images per row.
If I change this to two,
it doesn't work with 50 unfortunately but if I change this to four,
you can see this live updating.
Unfortunately, there are some margins that are affecting how
many can fit per row so we just need to change that.
But you can see this is live updating.
So going to hit save on that,
you can see if we look at this in the browser,
these are each going to be 50 percent.
This is a little bit of an issue with inline-block,
but if we reduce it by 0.5 percent,
that should get around the issue of margins and now you can
see we've got a two by two grid.
So I'm just going to go back into our code here.
Change two per row,
give it a percent of wiggle room.
Same thing here, and same thing here.
That should hopefully get around that issue.
Now if we refresh the page on both of these,
let's do it in the customizer so that we can actually live update this.
Change it to three per row,
change it to two per row,
four per row and we don't have five,
but if we did have a fifth one,
it will show up here.
All right, pretty cool.
Now, as I mentioned,
if we're showing two per row,
then we've got a nice aspect ratio going on here.
But if we set it to four per row,
we're going to lose a lot of the image because remember they
crop automatically in order to stay responsive.
So I also want to give the user the ability to specify the height of all these images.
So let's add that in now.
I'm going to add it in as another select.
So, whoops, let's go copy that example again from
the documentation and replace this empty object with that.
This one is going to be the heights,
and I'm going to call it image height.
We don't need group,
as I mentioned before,
the default value is going to be,
let's say, what do we have right now, 500 pixels.
Let's say it's going to be 500 pixels.
Don't need need info.
So we'll make the last 1500 pixels and this 1300 pixels.
Now we probably want to make more options.
So let's just create one extra option,
you probably want a few more as well,
but it's the same process for each.
So let's just put this somewhere in between 400.
Now before I hit save on that,
I'm going to actually insert it.
So just like I've done here,
instead of coding or hard-coding in a height,
I'm going to reference this setting so put it in there as height.
Again, we've got an error in JSON schema.
I know that just from the last one we've got the same era we've got this comma here.
If you didn't pick that up,
you can always put it for the JSONLinta.
So now if I look at this in the customizer,
we've got an issue here.
Let's have a look on what we might be doing wrong here.
I forgot to put the semicolon on the end, refresh the page.
So now we should be able to,
as the user in the customizer,
change the image height. There you go.
So if we're doing a four images per row,
we probably want the image height to get smaller as well.
So we can set a smaller image height.
We can set it to 400,
it's 500 so a good combination,
maybe on two per row we have it set to 500.
But if we're doing four per row,
we set it to something a little bit shorter, like 300.
Now, I know this video is probably pretty long already,
but I want to show you one other thing, and that is,
we can add in different types of content in this gallery.
Doesn't need to just be photos,
we can actually add in embedded videos as well.
For this, I don't want to be writing a lot of codes,
I'm going to be copying across something,
but it should be pretty simple to understand regardless,
what I'm going to do first because we're going to use a different type,
is put in a conditional.
I'm going to say block type, remember,
we now have access to the individual block because we're looping through,
and if the block type is image,
then I know I'm going to have an image setting.
I'll close that, and if now because all of our block so far,
the type of image,
nothing should change when we refresh the page.
Now, everything is normal,
but we can add in a different type here.
Instead of wherever we got here,
I'm going to add in another block for a video embed.
I'm just going to copy and paste to make this a little bit quicker,
and this one instead of image is going to be a video block,
and this is going to be the label that shows up to the user,
and for the settings,
I'm going to, I believe it's called a video URL,
and so the ID of that is going to be video URL is it's just called a video URL as well,
and the label is going to be video URL.
I think there are a few more attributes I've got right here to look at,
we can put in what it accepts as well.
We can make it except YouTube and Vimeo.
We're going to need to remove that comma of the end,
otherwise, we'll get an error.
If I hit Save on that, hopefully no errors,
and now when I refresh the page and our customizer,
and I go to the gallery,
instead of add image block,
it's just going to say add content.
The reason why is when I click this,
it's now going to give me the option to add in the different types.
I can add in another image block like before,
or I can add in a video block.
In here I can paste a YouTube or Vimeo link.
For that, I just need to find a YouTube video,
I'm going to quickly find one from my own YouTube channel.
What better video to use then,
one of my videos from my series on Shopify theme development,
let's use that as the example video right here,
and let's hit save.
Now, even though we've saved this video block,
we need to actually output something to the screen.
What I'm going to do is copy across some logic here,
but what I'm going to do is because it's going to be different code for
the video block instead of
the image block is I'm going to put the conditional in straight away.
This value here is what we created here,
so we've got type, image,
type video, this is what we are checking right now.
Now, I'm going to copy and paste in some code,
to save us a bit of time.
To briefly explain this code,
what we've got going on here is if the block type is video,
we know that this is a video block,
and if the URL is blank,
we're going to put in a placeholder video with these different attributes.
If it isn't blank,
then it definitely has a value,
so we just check if the type is YouTube,
if so, we use the YouTube embed link, if not,
we check for Vimeo,
and if it is Vimeo,
we use the Vimeo embed link,
and then we grab the ID of video URL.
This is a bit more of a complicated one because
we actually get an object out of this video URL,
and so we've got an ID and a type on that object.
That's why I copied and pasted this code because it is a little bit more
complex and it's not very common that you would use this anyway,
but this is a good example here of having different types.
What we're going to need to do to finish this off is also have this effect our iframe.
In each of these scenarios,
the iframe is going to contain the video,
so I have just added the iframe onto here as well.
It's going to have display inline-block width
and height that we've set in the customizer.
This one is not going to make any sense for the iframe,
but hopefully it still works,
if I go now into,
let's have a look in the customizer.
You'll see we've got my video showing up, unfortunately,
the width isn't correct,
so let's refresh the page,
see what's going on.
Here we've got our image wraps, image wraps,
image wraps, and then we've got the iframe here,
which doesn't have any styles attributed to it,
so it's just doing width and height.
Let me look at what I could've done wrong here,
and I can see I've put a dot in front of iframe,
presuming it's a class,
but I'm targeting the element itself,
so I don't need to use that dot.
If I refresh the page,
you'll now see that it conforms to our grid that we've set up.
Let's customize that in the customizer,
maybe let's set it to five per row.
Let's do five per row,
and now you can see that the video embed is
the fifth item in this row and we can actually reorder the content.
Now, the user can go in,
add any number of image blocks and video Blocks,
maybe some nice women's fashion videos and photos,
and that'll go on to the new line.
We might need to play around with mobile styles,
change the grid to be different on mobile,
so we're going to need some media queries,
but that is perhaps a project for yourself to take on,
I just wanted to give us some practice with schemas and liquid,
and what better way to do that is through a section.
If we want to be able to put this on the homepage,
don't forget, we need to insert a preset on here.
Let's just do that to finish the lesson,
so we'll put a Presets array, and again,
I'm going to go back to the reference numerous times presets right here,
we just need one with a category and a name.
Going back here, put in an object,
I've put up that object.
We've got category of what do we call the other one.
I think it was custom content,
so you can get it to show up in the same category,
and we'll give this a name of gallery,
hit Save on that.
Now, this section will be able to be included on the homepage as well.
If I go to the homepage,
add a section, we've got a problem here. That's right.
I haven't reloaded, a customizer yet,
always remember to do that guys.
Now when I add in a section,
you'll see gallery is here,
and it won't hold the same data as the place over here,
because every time a section is included,
it's got its own data.
We can go in and create different galleries.
There we go, let's put it in another image block, the woman's fashion,
and let's make the last one a video,
let's see if I got the add up.
Haven't got the video link,
but there you can see the placeholder there.
We've got our custom gallery section,
we can put it into our homepage now,
we can use it on specific pages, and by now,
you should have a pretty solid understanding of a Shopify liquid and schemas.
Now of course, the more experience you gain with Shopify liquid,
the better you'll get at it,
but I believe this should be a good foundation for you guys.
Remember the documentation, the liquid reference right here, where is it?
Liquid reference there you go.
This is your textbook,
this is your documentation,
you've also got my article,
which I'll highly recommends to give you a different perspective on Shopify liquid,
and then you've got the cheat sheet as well,
but that's more of like a quick reference.
For anything to do with learning all the different parts,
maybe there's an area of liquid
you don't know too much about and you want to learn more about.
Either check out the blog post or check out the official documentation.
Look it up, see if you can gain an understanding that way,
because now we'll be moving on from liquid to talk about the Ajax API.
Remember, I said that Shopify liquid is like
the back-end programming language with Shopify.
If we want to do something purely on the client side,
we're going to need to use JavaScript, and luckily,
within our theme, we've got this API called
the Ajax API to allow us to do certain things.
We'll learn all about that in the next lesson
and maybe two lessons if it's a particularly long one,
anyways, I'm excited for the next one, I'll see you there.