Hello there.
My name is Saravanan Dhandapani, and welcome to my course on
Managing Source Control with AWS CodeCommit.
I'm an architect working at Sabre Corporation focused on
middleware and cloud technologies.
If you have worked on a software project,
I'm sure you would have a version control software like SVN or Git.
AWS, being the industry leader when it comes to cloud software, has
plenty of developer tools, and AWS CodeCommit is one said service that
can be used for source code management.
In this course,
we are going to see the core features of AWS CodeCommit and how to create
and manage repositories, AWS Cloud9 as an IDE for your development work and
how to seamlessly integrate with AWS CodeCommit repository, set up
notifications and triggers, then notify changes that are happening to the
repository, create a new development project in AWS CodeStar and integrate
Cloud9 and CodeCommit, and, finally, perform a code review for the changes
that were pushed to the repository in AWS CodeCommit. By the end of this
course,
you will know all the features and benefits that are offered by AWS
CodeCommit in managing version control of a software project and how to
integrate CodeCommit with some of the other related services like Cloud9
and CodeStar. Before beginning this course,
you should be familiar with basic Git commands, and exposure
to AWS management console is always a plus.
I hope you will join me on this journey to learn about CodeCommit
and its related service in Managing Source Control with the AWS CodeCommit course, at Pluralsight.