Hello there.
Welcome to this module on Integrate AWS CodeCommit with AWS CodeStar.
In this module, we will look at different features offered by
AWS CodeStar and some of its limitations.
Then we will look at all AWS services that our
integrated together as part of AWS CodeStar.
We will take a look at the default project templates that are offered by
CodeStar and how a project manager will have one single view that gives a
snapshot of the current status of the project at any given time. We will see
the various options that are available to choose for your development
environment and to maintain the code repository. We will be selecting Cloud9
as our development environment and CodeCommit as our source control
repository. Once the environment is set up, we will launch our development
environment,
perform code changes in a separate branch, and merge the changes back
to master. Before merging the changes, you will also see how to
compare different commits and perform a code review in AWS
CodeCommit. With so many developer tool services offered by AWS, it
may be tedious in switching back and forth between services in a
typical development project.
AWS CodeStar provides a nice facade that integrates all the core AWS
services that are required in a typical development project. With so
many programming language options that are available both for front end
and back end, CodeStar offers many different project templates that can
be run in a serverless or virtual service or in a managed application
environment.
Once the development project is created,
you can add the roles and permissions for the selected users.
Once the project is created and users set up, AWS CodeStar
provides a project dashboard where you can track bugs, monitor
latest commits, check the status of the latest build, and maintain
a project wiki all in one place.
One major drawback with AWS CodeStar is that this can be used only for new
development projects, and existing projects cannot be migrated to leverage
these features. Before we jump into a demo,
let's quickly look at the different roles that are part of AWS CodeStar project.
The first one is owner,
which is the highest access level, and this role can add and remove other
team members, push code changes to the depository, configure project
dashboard, and can even delete the project. Contributor, this role cannot
add our remove other team members but can perform other project‑level tasks
except deleting the project.
And the third one is viewer, and the users with this role
will only be able to view the resources and cannot push any code changes to the depository.