Let's see a quick demo as how to create a new repository in AWS
CodeCommit. I just logged into AWS console.
Let's search for AWS CodeCommit in the Find Services search bar and
hit Enter. You will see the CodeCommit dashboard.
You will have a button to create a depository.
Click that. Give a name to the repository, a brief description. AWS allows
customers to assign metadata to their AWS resources in the form of tags to
uniquely identify a specific resource. Since this repository is going to be
used by the front‑end developers, I'm going to mention application as the key
and front end as value. CodeGuru is another service provided by AWS that you
can optionally select,
which lets you perform code review as you commit changes. Click Create.
You'll see an alert message saying you cannot configure the SSH
connections and HTTPS connections for a root account, and it is
suggesting us to create an IAM user.
Under Clone URL, you have the option to copy the HTTPS or
SSH link to the repository. Let's go back and search for
IAM service from the console.
Under Users, click Add user, provide a name to the user.
You can select if the user needs to have programmatic access and console access.
If you want this user to access the management
console, you can give both accesses.
I'm going to choose both the options and select Custom
password and uncheck Require password reset.
In a typical project scenario,
you may need to keep this on so that the user can change the
password once he logs in. Click Permissions, choose Attach
existing policies, and search for AWS CodeCommit. I'm going to
select AWSCodeCommitFullAccess.
You also have an option to assign a tag. I'm going to leave it empty.
It shows you the summary of all the settings for this user.
Go ahead and click Create user.
You can see the sign‑in link to access the console, which is a
different link compared to the usual link that you use to log into
the AWS console. You can view and download the credentials as a CSV
file, or you have the option to send an email with the username and
the URL directly from here.
Password of the downloaded credential file must be emailed separately.
Click Close. I'm going to sign out as root user and log back
in with the IAM user that we just created.
Let's go back to AWS CodeCommit. Click on the name of the depository,
and it shows the required connection steps.
It also shows the URL to clone the depository.
Let's go ahead and create a new file and add some text. Give the
file a name, an author name, and commit message, and click on
Commit changes. Now click on Branches, and we currently have master branch,
which is the default one.
But it's a good practice not to do any development work in master branch.
Let's go and create a new one.
Click on Create branch,
give the branch a name, and select the branch from where
you want to create this new branch. You can see we have two
branches now. One is master.
The other one is develop.
Let's edit the file in develop branch. Let's perform some changes and commit
it. Now in order to merge this change back to develop,
let's create a pull request.
Choose the destination and the source branches.
Give the pull request a title, and click on Create pull request.
Ideally,
you need to set up some approval rules so that the changes can be reviewed
before they can be merged. Since there are no merge conflicts,
the Merge button is enabled. Go ahead and click Merge. You can choose one of
the three merge strategies and click on Merge pull request.
Click on Commits. You can see two commits now. Now let's go back to the
master branch and check if our changes are merged properly.
Click on the file name.
You can see the change that we performed in the develop branch
has been merged to master branch successfully.
Congratulations! You just created a new repository, committed
changes, created multiple branches, performed a pull request,
merged the changes back to the master branch, all from CodeCommit console without writing a single line of Git command.