Let's jump into a quick demo and see how AWS CodeStar
streamlines the process from coding to deployment.
Click on Globomantics‑P2 repository.
I went ahead and performed a few more changes to index.html
and pushed the changes to the repository.
Click on Compare commits. Choose master as destination and develop
as source. Click Compare. And you can see the differences between
the two branches have been highlighted.
You have an option to add comments at the bottom.
Or you can also add in line comment.
Click on the small blue icon to your left, add your comments, and click on Save.
Now that the code has been reviewed, we can go back to the pull requests.
Click on Create pull request. Choose master as the destination and
develop as source. Give the pull request a title and click Create
pull request. Click on Merge, and then Merge pull request. Let me go
back to AWS CodeStar console, click on Application endpoints,
and you can see the HTML page that is currently being deployed.
You can see the code that we pushed has been successfully
committed and the build is currently in progress.
Once the build is successfully completed,
you can see that deployment has started.
Click on Deploy history and you can see the
previous deployments under its status.
Now the deployment is completed, let me click on Pipeline history.
You can see the latest deployment and the duration of deployment.
CodeCommit history shows the latest commit and its commit ID.
I'm going to go and click the endpoint again, and you can
see now our latest changes have been successfully
reflected and successfully deployed.
Let's quickly summarize what we learned so far.
We saw how CodeStar can be used in creating new projects
using preexisting templates and how it may not be a good
candidate for existing projects.
We saw all the different AWS Service's that are
required from setting up access control,
to project development, to deployment,
having connected together and how AWS CodeStar provides a unified dashboard
which gives a complete snapshot of our project status at any given time.
With all the code services that are needed for continuous integration and
continuous delivery being in place, the time it takes in a typical life
cycle from coding to deployment is much reduced and, hence, it helps in a faster time to market.