Hello everyone, this is Mohammed Osman.
And in this module,
we will learn what is AWS QuickSight, how it works, and
what benefits it brings to the table.
Let's see what we are going to learn in this module.
First and foremost,
we are going to position our course in the AWS Big Data exam and define
what domain in the exam this course is going to cover.
Then, we will proceed with discussing why we need to do data
visualization. From there, we will introduce AWS QuickSight, which
will be the bread and butter of our course.
After that, we will take our discussion more deeper and
understand the core components of AWS QuickSight.
Finally,
we will introduce the housing prices dataset, which we will
use to apply the data visualizations on.
Are you ready? Let's start another exciting journey.