And now, let's discuss the pivot table visualization type.
The pivot table present dimensions and expressions in table form.
There is no formal limit to the number of dimensions or expressions possible.
I will rename the sheet to Pivot Table,
and let's now create a pivot table to show the
Actual SalePrice by three dimensions, Overall House Condition,
Overall Material Quality, and the Garage Quality.
I will choose the Pivot table visualization type. And in the Rows, I will
choose the Overall House Condition and the Overall Material Quality, and
in the Column, I will put the Garage Quality.
Let me expand the visualization for better visibility. And in
the Values, I will put the median of the Actual SalePrice.
And as you can see on the left,
we can filter by the Overall House Condition and the Overall Material
Quality with the corresponding Garage Quality on the top, and the Value
of the cell represents the median SalePrice.
However,
a word of caution is that please avoid creating
visualisations with too many dimensions.
It will easily confuse the user. I would say, at max, three dimensions.
However, I did that here in the Pivot Table to show their power.
And now, after we are done with visualizing our data,
we might want to share the dashboard for other users so
that they can have visibility to our data.
I will create a dashboard by clicking on Share on the top right, then I will
click Publish dashboard, I will fill in the dashboard name,
say, Dashboard1, and I will click Publish dashboard.
After that, it will ask me which users I would like to share the dashboards with.
The users should have licenses in the AWS Quicksight account. You will not see any users here because I don't have users.