Let's now recap what we have learned in this course. In the first module,
we started by learning about different aspects in AWS QuickSight.
We learned about its different usage scenarios and features, and
then we introduced its architecture and general components that
constitute it. And in the second module, we took a look at AWS
QuickSight in action, and we learned about different types of visualizations,
such as bar charts that count the number of instances in a certain
category, scatter plot which help us to identify the correlation
between two variables, pivot table to explore the data from
different dimensions, and many others.
And finally,
don't forget to rate the course from the options on the right and share
your questions and insights in the course discussion. Thank you for your time, and I hope that I see you in future Pluralsight courses.