And now,
it's the time to have a discussion around the core components in AWS QuickSight.
Firstly, everything starts with data sources,
and AWS supports many types of data sources,
such as relational data sources, which include Amazon S3,
MariaDB, or MySQL among others.
It also supports file data sources,
such as comma‑separated values and XLSX files,
JSON data sources, and Software as a Service data sources through APIs,
such as Adobe Analytics, Twitter API, or ServiceNow.
And then on AWS QuickSight,
the data sources can be loaded into what's so‑called datasets
to be ready for usage by AWS QuickSight.
The datasets can be loaded to SPICE Engine for higher performance.
After that, we are ready to perform what's so‑called analysis.
In a single analysis,
we can have multiple visuals that will be created from the dataset.
Notice that how a single dataset can be shared among multiple
analyses. A visual simply represents a specific visualization,
such as bar chart or pie chart.
From these visuals,
we can create dashboards, which can be shared with other users, or stories,
which represent a multiple iteration of analysis that can be displayed
sequentially to tell a narrative about the data.
The creation of datasets, analysis, and dashboards is done
by users who are in the author role.
If you are using the enterprise edition of AWS QuickSight, we can have users with the reader role.