Docker was designed for the cloud.
It works great everywhere but it really works
well when you're focusing your apps on
12 factor design patterns.
You maybe don't know what that is yet. But, you're going to
learn in this section about design optimization
for things that are distributed.
And, the cloud is distributed.
In fact, your data centers are probably becoming more and
more distributed, so you definitely want to understand
these principles so that your Node apps are using the best
parts of Docker they can.
You're also going to learn, in this section, about the
dockerignore file that's similar to the gitignore.
That will help you keep things out of your images that you
don't want. You're going to do an assignment that's very
much like real-world stuff that I do all the time.
Which is take existing Node apps and migrate them into
containers. Even old Node apps that you maybe
need old setups and design.