This section is all about your Node Dockerfiles,
which are going to be the fundamental building blocks for
everything we do for the rest of the course.
To get it out of the way, we're going to jump
into understanding the different types
of Node from images, or which base images you should
use to make sure that you're building the right images, on
the right foundations. Then we'll jump into a quick
assignment just to see how to make your own custom
Node image for something like CentOS that doesn't have a
default image on Docker Hub.
Then I'll go a little bit into how you're going to use
least privilege and increase security to lock down your
Node containers.
We'll also look at some features in the Dockerfile to make
your images efficient, which mostly has to do with size
and speed of building.
That's important once you get to automated CI and
especially when you get to production when you want minimal
size and also speed of deployments.