If you've been using Node since before containers,
you've probably done something in production like PM2, or
Forever, or Nodemon to manage your Node processes,
as well as scale those processes for multi
CPU servers.
What that really means is Node, by default, is
not multithreaded.
On most servers, you're going to have multiple CPUs.
Node won't take advantage of more than one of those CPUs by
default. In most Node apps,
you need to consider how you're going to run it across
multiple CPUs on a server,
and across multiple servers in a lot of cases.
Traditionally, before containers, we had things
like PM2, Forever Nodemon
and other tools that would spin up one or more
Node processes, running the same code, to be
able to run on multiple CPUs concurrently, and then it
would manage incoming connections and distribute it across
all those. Well, Docker does that for us.
So, whether you're using Docker, or Docker Compose,
or maybe Swarm, or Kubernetes, or ECS,
or some sort of container solution,
that solution is going to take into account how
you manage incoming connections, rather than these
older tools that we used before containers in
Node world.
So, think about it from the container manager point
of view. Realize that it's designed
to spin up multiple containers, and most solutions, they
call it replicas.
You're spinning up multiple replicas, which is copies
of that image, in multiple containers, all running
together.
A lot of solutions create some sort of load balancer for
talking about incoming connections.
They create load balancers in front of that to distribute
incoming connections. So, you don't need to worry about
those older tools. That's why throughout this course, I
have asked you to run Node directly in your container
images so that when your containers launch, there's
not this middle layer managing different
Node executables.
My general guideline for production systems
is to look at your Node apps, and of course you've got to
consider what kind of load you want to have, and you're
going to have to probably test some load stuff in order to
understand how your Node app is going to work.
But in general, in terms of CPU and consuming
all the CPU resources, you'll want to start one
to two containers per CPU,
assuming that you wanted to use all of the CPU resources
on that machine. If you had a cloud server, or some
data center server that had
two CPUs, then you would probably launch between four to
eight Node containers of that image
out-of-the-box. You may not need that many.
Maybe you only need a couple just to provide redundancy,
but you don't necessarily need more than that for capacity.
And that's fine. But, realize that when you're starting
up things in Docker, just because you have one or two Node
containers running, doesn't mean it's going to use all
those CPUs.
That Node limitation still exists in Docker, which is why
we want to start up replicas.
Swarm does this. Kubernetes does this.
Other orchestrators have this concept.
If you're using Docker Compose or Docker run, you're
going to use aliases and replicas in those
features as well.
When it comes to these containers inside of your CI,
be a little bit careful about when you run multiple
replicas, or containers, of your code inside
of CI. You want to know specifically why you're going to do
that because it's much harder to test when you've got
multiple copies of your app running there.
So, usually when you're doing unit testing, or other very
basic testing of your code, you're going to want to run
just one replica and have that single container output
all the things. If you get advanced in the CI, just
like any other solution, you could always spin up different
containers to run different tests.
That way, you could spread out your workloads and
distribute them so that your testing would go faster
instead of in a linear, synchronous fashion.
But, that doesn't really have anything to do with Node.
That's just how you design your CI system.
In general, for integration testing, I might consider using
multiple replicas if I have something that's like maybe
a Node API, or some middle layer of Node,
where I want to make sure that across different
containers running, that I still get the expected output
of my full integration and functional testing.
You might consider that as a part of your testing workflow.
Again, that part isn't really Node specific, but when it
comes to containers, it's so easy for us to spin up
multiple copies of these images into many containers
that we sometimes forget that there are design limitations
inherent in our application, that we may not realize
until we're running multiple copies of that same thing,
all at the same time.