Now that we've gotten some of the little details about
Compose out of the way, let's focus on getting your code in
the container. Because this is deceptively simple, but
there are definitely a group of things that I see people
having problems with, or designing incorrectly, when
they're focusing on local development and bind mounting
their source code into a running container, right.
This is the ideal setup.
The whole reason we're trying to do this locally is so that
we can have all of our Node.js apps and its other
apps, like your databases and all the other stuff that's
going to be running, in your distributed app.
All these things are ideally going to be running on Linux
in production. That's the most likely case for Node.js.
You want to develop on that same system
and have all the conveniences of your different parts all
talking together of the same network.
Here, bind mounting of the code
is a little bit different on each operating system.
The first couple of gotchas that I want to make sure that
you're clear on is that in your Compose files, it
works best where everything is referenced as the parent
working directory or the pwd.
In this example here of my bad YAML in that
same directory that we had in the last lecture, the
my full path to the files
on the host.
That may work for you, but that's not how Compose is
supposed to work. Really, the left side of this bind mount
path should always just be a dot.
If it needs to be maybe up a directory, and move around,
it's always a relative path to the one you're
currently in. If you're in a big project, you're going to
have lots of different clones of repos,
probably in one master directory with a bunch of different
micro services maybe, in different subdirectories.
You could have one, large Compose file that
then bind mounts and runs a lot of different services.
That's totally fine.
In this line, you would then have a
../ that means back up a directory and then maybe bind
mount some path in a different directory.
Ideally, that's how your products are set up, right.
Usually, we don't get to run just one Git
repo. We usually have to download a bunch if we're in a
very large app, or just any old app, really.
You're going to be able to do that here.
No reason to do hard paths or fully qualified
paths. You don't want to do those because when you pass
these around your team, not everyone is going to have the
same path. So, it's definitely not going to work well.
And that's true on Windows, Linux and Mac.
Sometimes people on the Windows side get a little confused
because they see examples using the C drive and that's just
not needed when you're in a Compose file.
Docker run, sometimes you might need that depending
on if you can use the pwd variable.
But, here in the Compose, it's different.
In the Compose, we can always use the dot.
The one thing you don't want to do here is bind mount your
databases. I see this happen all the time.
It's a very common question.
If I scroll down in my bad YAML file here,
you definitely don't want to do this, where I'm bind
mounting my databases into some subdirectory.
That may seem like a good idea at first, but chances are
you're probably developing on Mac or Windows.
They don't work well across the OS boundary.
If you happen to be one of the lucky few
that are developing natively on Linux, and so your machine
that you're on every day with your GUI and everything is
pure Linux, then great.
You can bind mount all day because that's really the same
file system. It's just symlinking a little
path between one part of the file system and another.
If you're on Mac or Windows, these containers are running
in a different OS. They're running in a mini Linux VM.
These bind mounts are having to go over the
file IO path and even on the Windows side, it can be
even a little more tricky because it's actually using Samba
or SMB file shares, and that can really be slow if
you're in very large projects.
All right. The next tip here is that if you
are just using this Docker image for local
development, and you're doing a docker compose up with
a --build, or maybe you're doing a docker compose build,
you don't necessarily need to do that.
Not every time at least.
If you don't change your package file, then
just keep doing docker compose up.
You don't need to rebuild your images every
time you change code, right. That's not what we're here
for. We're not here to rebuild our images.
We're here to just develop and restart Node,
not restart the image build process.
If you think about it, you're mounting your host
files over top of the ones in the image
anyway. So, you technically could have an image with no
source code in it.
It just has your package dependencies from your Node
modules, and then your code you're bind mounting in.
In a lecture, in a little bit, of this same section, we'll
talk about how you get over the problem of your
Node modules on your host not getting into
your container, not interfering with the ones in your
container. That's a different setup.
We just need to change a few bits for that.
But for now, I want to reiterate that you can actually get
away with just doing a docker compose up, not rebuilding
the image every time until you change something with your
dependencies, or something about the Dockerfile itself.
Next up, a big deal here, is if you're on Windows
and you're developing on Windows for Node.js, or really
anything with Docker and Windows, you want to make sure you
go in the settings and you enable the permissions
for sharing the drive letter where your code is at.
Your code may not always be on C.
C is there by default.
If you're on a different partition.
Maybe you store your code on an external SSD or
something, then you need to go in there and check that box.
Also, if you have problems with files not sharing
properly into your container, then the common fix there is
to go back in your settings and uncheck that box,
and then recheck it. That will reinitialize the permissions
sharing thing that's going on in Windows that sometimes
gets broken, especially on Enterprise machines
where you're inside of an active directory and you have to
deal with Enterprise policies that might be affecting you.
Here on my Windows machine, I have my C
drive selected, but if I needed to put source code
on my E drive and share that into a container with a bind
mount, I would then need to check that box and apply it.
Again, if you wanted to sort of fix any sort of
inconsistencies, you could unchecked that, apply, then
recheck it and apply. That sort of refreshes things.
That's been a quirk for a few years now.
So, I'm pretty sure that's still an issue for certain
machines. You also might have a prompt for permissions
here that it asks you for a login and if your login is not
working, you need to get an admin log in.
You might even, in some cases depending on the security
settings of your machine, you need to get a local admin,
not a domain admin, if your box is on an active
directory domain, you might need to get a local account
created. There's a couple of different scenarios where
these things don't work right depending on corporate
policies. So, you might have to go down that road.
As a side note, you might be seeing a warning, at times, on
Windows, if you're developing on Windows and you're doing
builds on Windows.
A warning about file permissions.
This is something here at the bottom where you would see
security warning, you're building an image.
This is really talking about the difference between file
permissions on Windows and Linux, and how
Windows uses NTFS and Linux doesn't.
Over that share, the files that you would copy
into an image from Windows may not turn up in Linux
with the permissions you'd expect.
That is a common struggle for building when
you have your source code on Windows.
Every problem has a different solution there.
You might need to just make sure you're not building on
Windows if you have certain permission problems.
Or, you may need to design your Dockerfile to go and
check those permissions after every Docker build,
like a line down below in the Dockerfile that says, you
know, go and chown these files, or chmod
these files to certain settings that you need
in your app. Those are a couple of common Windows problems
when bind mounting.
Let's talk about performance for a minute, because this
comes up in larger projects, when people are getting
large amount of files, hundreds of package
dependencies.
This can get really big.
Bind mounts, because of that crossing the OS
boundary like we talked about, that can cause some serious
delays.
If you're on Mac OS, and you're using Docker Desktop, I
would like you to read a couple of resources on the Docker
website about file IO caching.
This is an interesting and complicated topic around how
Docker is tweaking Mac and Linux
in order for the files that you're bind mounting into the
container to have improved performance.
Because if you think about all the things that have to
happen in order for your Mac to tell a Linux machine,
over some special little connection, that a file has
changed, it actually turns out that this round trip can
cause around 100 milliseconds of delay.
Not a big deal. That sounds like a small fraction of time.
But when you're dealing with hundreds of thousands,
possibly millions of reads and writes, this can get
really, really slow.
I want you to read the references that I have in here
specifically for Mac OS in this lecture so that you fully
understand the different settings you can have here.
Because these are unique to Mac OS.
Then I'm going to show you an example here in my good
YAML. This good YAML shows a bind mount
of a directory, inside my parent working
directory, then under content, then it just mounts to some
place inside of the container.
But it has this delegated flag on the end.
That delegated flag tells Docker that
essentially, if there's writing going
on in the container, that it's okay for the container
file IO to get ahead of the host.
In other words, not every file IO
transaction has to be identical on host to
container. And, that if there's any reading or writing
going on in the container, that the container sort of wins
out and the host writing can catch up later.
This is handy when you're doing things like npm installs or
anything where you're maybe taking typescript files
and turning them into JavaScript, or taking a bunch of
static files like Hugo or one of these static site
generators, and turning a bunch of files into something
else. Maybe you're turning your CSS
into minification mode.
All these different things are doing lots of writes, and
there's a lot of potential for delay there that you
can help solve if you add delegated to every one
of these bind mounts on your Mac.
And I mean just about every one of them.
I default to putting it on there, and I have to come up
with good reasons not to do it.
You wouldn't normally do this if you were doing something
like a database because you wouldn't want your read/writes
to be out of sync.
It can cause different inconsistencies, but in general,
I have never experienced any of that.
Again, like we talked about in the last lecture, I
don't bind mount databases because that can just cause
problems anyway.
If you're on the Windows side, slightly different scenario.
You don't get that advance delegated mode or setting
the cache like you do on OS X because on Windows,
it's really using an SMB file share between Windows
and Linux. The disadvantage there is that it's
not quite as performant and there's not as a deep a level
of OS integration.
You're also on Windows dealing with the file permissions
and executable changes between Windows and Linux.
So, a couple of scenarios there if you get into trouble.
First, I should say that a whole lot of developers do just
fine, Node.js and Windows, and bind mounting stuff
in, and they don't need any special setup.
But, once you start hitting edge cases where things either
get really slow, or you start having problems that you just
can't resolve another way, a couple of options you have
there. One is to consider doing file synchronization
rather than linking the containers through a file share.
File sync tools, there's at least three of them that I know
of that are still at least being maintained.
Here's one called docker bg sync that runs
a file copying utility, essentially, in the background
that will copy files from your host into
the container and then your container's running them
natively in the container. There's a little bit of a
disadvantage there because you have a potential for more
delay of keeping files sync'd.
In general, the people that have figured out how to set
this up have told me that this works well for them,
especially when they're in larger projects and they maybe
have slow hard drives.
SSD's are definitely a thing you want to have if you're
doing Docker. But, if you can't have something like that,
then this might be an alternative to you.
It's outside the realm of the official Docker Desktop and
the support model there, but it does work for a lot of
people, so definitely check those tools out.
I give you a link to a few here in the references.
The other option you might consider is setting up the WSL
or Windows Subsystem for Linux.
Again, this is a little more advanced.
It's beyond what I really wanted to teach in this course
because it requires a lot of understanding and knowledge
about different shells, different setups, because
WSL is essentially a synthetic
Linux, or a Linux interpreter, inside
your windows machine that translates Linux
system calls into the windows kernel.
It's advanced stuff and it's super slick when it works
well, but it doesn't work in all cases.
Anyway, there's a great Readit about this from
another Docker Captain, Nick.
He talks about his setup of how he
is using WSL plus an optimized
bind mount configuration for his own development needs.
Again, this is definitely not for the faint of heart.
These are advanced setups that you probably shouldn't do
until you really need them.
And you will know you need them when things start to get
really slow, and you just can't take it anymore.