Real quick, let me be specific about the config factor.
Of the 12 factors, one of them is config.
It's actually one of the ones that I consider the most important
because if it's not done right when you start deploying
your applications,
and considering all the different values that you have for
each environment, it will be hard work later to get these
things updated and make sure that they don't break when you deploy them,
and whatnot. What I've seen over the years is different
combinations of things where people possibly put hard values
to things in code. Some things they put into different config files
that are maybe not obvious
or hidden in subdirectories somewhere.
They're not well documented.
So, my goal is that whenever I'm developing
an app, that anything that I can,
for that Node app, it's going to pick up an environment variable,
if that's set,
to override it. Now, it might have a default that in case there isn't any environment
variable, it will set something.
Maybe it'll do a console log
or some other logging so that it's knowing that it
doesn't have a value so you can see that.
But, really what I want is that whatever I'm putting into
my app, that it's going to search for environment
variables, and all those environment variables are defined in
the Dockerfile. Now, you're also going to deal
with Docker Compose files,
and you can even have Docker Compose use a .env file,
if you're familiar with that standard.
You can set them inside your shell
or so many other ways
when you read through the Docker documentation on how you can change
and set environment variables.
Now, these are always things that you're setting on container start.
You can't change environment variables in the middle of a container
running, and quite frankly,
most apps wouldn't pick up a change even if it did.
This doesn't replace secrets.
If you're familiar with Swarm
and Kubernetes, they have secrets
and configs, or config maps.
Those are for changing entire files
or for storing secrets.
The environment variables shouldn't be used to replace those
things necessarily. But,
this is things like host names of your database that
need to go into the Node app,
or remote API DNS names.
Or, maybe just the username,
or the database name, that you need to use in your databases.
Stuff like that. Ideally you can use secrets through
secret files and maybe use environment variables as a backup method.
We'll be talking about those in this course as well.
But, right here, if you have a complicated app,
you may be frustrated
with just sort of the setting of all of these different environment variables
and how you have to deal with those in the Dockerfile
and the Compose file, possibly,
if you're trying to overwrite them.
Then also tracking them in your app.
So if you're dealing with legacy apps,
you might consider a tool that is
envsubst or environment substitute.
That's really what it does is it pulls out environment variables
from, and file you give it,
and then it dumps those into a template.
So, maybe you would have a different file in your configuration,
and then this would go through
and change every one of those environment variables in your app
with whatever you set when you started
Docker. This is a tool that you'll use in an upcoming assignment.
Usually in Node, we don't see it that much because
it's a more modern development framework so
we tend not to have such bad habits that we maybe
did with decades old programs where we kept all
sorts of hard coded settings and environment variables all throughout the app
that we needed to worry about changing on the fly.
Usually in Node, we have them all either in a single
JSON or YAML file,
or we're setting them in the app
but the app itself is looking for environment variables to change those.
If all this isn't obvious to you,
or something that you're definitely well versed in,
then please go check out the 12-factor website for
the config page. It's not that long,
but it will give you a sense of why you
need to care about this.
In case you're confused, what is considered config
and what is considered in your app.
The short answer to that is that anything that would change based
on either a test environment,
or a production environment,
or a dev environment, anything that might change in those three different
environments, is a config setting that you need
to pull out of your apps so that it's not hard coded in there.