Now that you've got the basics of multi-stage,
there's lots of other ways to create flexibility
in your Docker images that will benefit Node apps.
In most situations, you're going to end up
with some sort of testing infrastructure.
Hopefully, you get that automated at some point that's building your
images and testing them every time you're committing on specific
branches, or even all branches,
of your Git. In this case,
you could build a separate stage just for testing
that your CI infrastructure will run.
It maybe runs npm test,
or something else in addition.
But you can allow a specific stage that's there in the
middle somewhere of the image,
maybe after production
and before development,
depending on how you want to set it up.
And then you call that specific stage
with a Docker build command inside your CE giving
you a way to test before you build the final production
image. We're definitely gonna make this more complicated
as we go along to add more features.
In this case, we could also do an npm install of
development to make sure that our development tools like nodemon,
or gulp, or bower,
or something else that you need inside development only,
you can put that inside the development stage
and have npm run it a second time.
So you would think of having an npm install in the production
image, and that would normally install only your default
packages. And then for your dev packages,
you could specify only development in the second stage,
and we'll do that later on this course.
Also, another trick of multi-stage is because,
by default Docker,
when you build without specifying a target,
it will build all these stages.
So, one of the goals I usually have is to not repeat things.
I try to only have my copy command for my code,
copy in once during development
and not copy in multiple stages
or in a very early stage because if you're going
to rebuild your image to update your code
on your local dev machine, you really don't want that to happen a
lot or repetitive times over
and over. You really just want it to happen as low
as possible in the file. Like the same rules we have for every
Dockerfile. The good news here is we're definitely
going to be adding more multi-stage features as we build out
this Dockerfile for various uses,
like local dev and production specifically.
So, you'll see this Dockerfile get bigger
and bigger as we add more features to it.