One of the potential problems you can have locally with
Node modules is if you're used to developing Node
on your host, and you're just doing an npm install in your
repo, which we've all been doing forever since Node was
invented, and that's fine.
When you're building a container image, one of the things
you want to make sure is that you don't copy the Node
modules from your host into the container image.
Especially if you're on Mac or Windows where the
architecture is different.
One of the reasons that matters is because some
of the Node module dependencies are built binary
by binary into a compatible format for the
architecture. A good example with that is the node---
module, which is very common in larger, complex projects.
It's their design to build things
on the fly during an npm install for the architecture
that you're currently sitting on. If you do that on a Mac,
or on a Windows machine, and you're not using Docker,
then it's going to build for that architecture, you know.
It's going to be something .exe on Windows and then a
binary compatible with the Mac OS and the Mac
kernel. That's important to not put
into the image because the images in this case, throughout
this course, we're talking really about Linux images.
So, they need to have that node--- building inside
the image build. The way that we do that is like a previous
lecture talked about, using the .dockerignore
file and putting the Node modules directory in there
so that we make sure that Docker ignores anything
we do on the host.
Let me show you an example of that real quick using the
sails framework, which is a MVC
framework for creating websites.
It's rather large.
When you do an npm install of sails, it does create
a lot of Node modules, so it's a good example to show the
distinction and the difference here.
I have a sample sails app that just comes out-of-the-box,
and I've created a simple Dockerfile.
If I just cat that Dockerfile.
You'll see this looks pretty standard compared to some
simple stuff we've done in the course already.
If I do a build of this file, so I just do a
docker build.
Tag it with sailsbret
or whatever you want to call it.
When we do that, you'll see that the first thing it does is
it creates the build context and
ships it over to the engine.
And if you're not aware of what Docker is doing in the
background here, it's actually tarring up all the files
in the current directory, and all subdirectories,
into a big file, then shipping them over to the
engine, and then extracting them.
In this case, because I'm on a Mac that's in a Linux VM,
so I had to send 180MG worth of data that
you can see there, just before it can start building.
That's a pretty big thing for just a sample little app,
right. If I do that same build, but after
we create the dockerignore file.
And in this case, just because of this particular
framework, you can see here that they have
their own .gitignore that they've already created.
Chances are, your .dockerignore is going to be very
similar to any .gitignore recommendations that you're using
in a project. Of course, all Node projects and all projects
in general aren't going to have this file.
But in this case, it's nice and simple.
I could just do a copy of that gitignore
into a dockerignore and see if that works
for me, right. I could start from that.
Sort of dive into the file and away
we go. I could just create a generic dockerignore file
and only copy in the Node modules but I happen to know
that if I do a cat on that dockerignore file,
that it does include a lot of things, log files,
temp directories, stuff like that, including the Node
modules right there.
So, I know it's not going to be copied in.
If I do that same docker build, with the same tag.
Watch what we see there. When I build, it only copies
over 3.7MG instead of 180MB.
That's a huge difference, and that was all nothing but the
Node modules. So, even when you're doing local development,
you want to make sure that you've included
that .dockerignore for all Node apps.