Building on the last few lectures, the next thing we
can add here is security scanning and
auditing. This comes in many forms, and there's lots of
tools out there that can do that.
Your first choice is where to put it.
You can put it in that test stage that we just built.
Ideally, that stage is not run by default, and it's really
something that you elect to choose as your target from the
command line. But, you could also make a new stage
based on the test stage.
Then you're going to have it running tests and
then if those succeed, assuming that your code is right
and it's going to work, then you're going to do auditing
and security scanning.
You probably don't need to do those if your code is not
correct, right. So, it seems to make sense to me to
do the testing first.
I think it's a little more flexible to just add that extra
stage in.
Some of these tools require that the image be built and
that you test them from the outside, maybe by running them
and doing stuff against them.
In those cases, of course, you're going to want to change
the cmd to do whatever you need to do and then run
that image, maybe from Docker Compose and spin
up the things you need in order to test it from the
outside. I've given you lots of links in the resources
here to go check out different security tools, scanning
tools, all that stuff.
Because if you're new to this in containers, it is a whole
new world of stuff out there.
I'm going to give you a quick little example here of one,
but it doesn't necessarily mean it's the best or my
favorite. Before we get started, a few things
to remember. One is that most of these tools
will fail by default.
So, if you're introducing it into your existing
applications and workflows, you probably want these to
silently fail, or to continue on failure,
so that they don't blow up your systems and automatically
stop the production workflows that you may already have.
You're going to want to take it easy at first.
Just have it reporting so that you can see what the stats
look like. Because a lot of these things, especially when
you're talking about CVE vulnerabilities, those
things are common to be in images, especially
in the base images that you might be depending on.
It's really hard to be perfect, and to be zero risk
and zero vulnerability.
It takes a little more methodical approach to decide
which things you're going to consider pass or fail.
Then as a part of this, consider just putting in a run npm
audit. That gets you some free stuff right out-of-the-box.
It's a great feature of npm that will simply make sure that
your dependency Node.js modules don't
have any known security vulnerabilities.
That is above and beyond what an image scanner might do
because not all image scanners, or code scanners, would be
specific to Node.js.
The nice thing is about npm audit is you get it right
out-of-the-box.
I definitely recommend that one first.
Then if you want any third-party security scanning tools,
add those in into this same stage at a
later line.
Let's go take a look at an example that I've given to you
in the multistage scanning directory.
In that directory, it's built on the last couple lectures,
so it's the same example demo app, and it's the same
multistage Dockerfile that we started with.
This time, we've added a another stage.
If we scroll down past the stage 1 and the stage 2 for
development, stage 3 for the copying of
source. That's that small little intermediate stage there.
Then we see the testing stage like we had in the previous
lecture. If we scroll down a little bit farther, we will
see a new stage that I've added for you that is just
about auditing and scanning.
In this case, I've done the npm audit like I recommended.
Do that first because it's usually very fast and it's an
easy one liner.
Next, I added in the Aqua Security
MicroScanner from Aqua Security.
MicroScanner is one of the many tools you can scan.
There are other ones out there that I've listed in the
resources that you can definitely check out all that stuff.
Try different ones.
They all are...it's kind of like antivirus scanners.
All the different scanners have various success and
failure ratios depending on what you're talking about,
and the unique CVE vulnerabilities.
So, you may eventually, if you're in a very
secure environment, you might want to use multiple scanners
or paid scanners.
But this is an open source one.
I've added some lines here.
You'll notice that the ARG is first, and that requires
me to then sign up with their scanner to get my own, unique
API key that I would then maybe store as an environment
variable in my CI system, or on my local box.
Then I would need to build with that argument.
We'll do that in a second.
Then I'm downloading the scanner into this image.
I'm changing it to be executable.
I'm then adding dependencies that I need
through the Alpine package manager.
Then I'm running the scanner against the local
code in that image.
You'll notice that right past that is just the standard
stage 6 that we use for production.
If I wanted to do all
testing and all scanning, I could just target
the audit stage, and it would do the testing
first and then the audit after that.
Here's a sample command on how I would build that.
I would build it. I'd call this maybe auditnode.
I would target the audit stage.
Then I would throw in a build argument to get that secret
key in there.
I'm using a local environment variable I've set in my
shell already called microscanner, so that's going to
pass that in as a build argument.
Then that build argument will pass it into the run
command for the MicroScanner.
All right. So, my build finished.
It probably took about a minute or so on my
machine.
Of course, the size of the project, and the amount of
scanners and things you want to run, will affect that
speed. You can see here that I've got at least
30 steps in this Dockerfile.
Now we're getting to real world Dockerfiles.
Once you get to complicated projects, be okay with the
fact that you're going to have 30 steps, right.
It will cache a lot of this stuff.
You can see here that I've got some output from the
MicroScanner and above that, we have some output
from the audit security report that says it found zero
vulnerabilities. That's good.
So this stuff really either works or it doesn't.
You have to kind of get to get used to the different things
that it will trip up, and you might have to make custom
config files to make sure that it fits your project and
your needs.
It's an easy add.
It doesn't require a whole lot of new learning and tooling,
especially if you using just the open source stuff and then
later, you can consider maybe buying one of the scanners
out there. Docker Enterprise has a scanner.
Lots of other security companies offer scanners as well.
Again, I've listed those in the resources, so go check that
stuff out.