Now we get another assignment.
This section might have seemed, to some of you, deceptively
easy. That the lectures were short.
There was mostly just words and me talking about concepts.
But, this is where the rubber hits the road.
And you may have to refer back to things, might need a
little bit of Internet research on some things, especially
on the Node part of this assignment.
But this is real-world stuff.
These are activities that I do with my clients
every time I work with them on migrating their old
applications into Docker.
We've adopted the phrase, and actually Docker sort of was
the first ones to coine this phrase, MTA or migrating
traditional apps, rather than Legacy.
Legacy might seem like it's an old, bad app,
but we have lots of apps around that were created, or
started, in the projects before those
projects were used in Docker.
We might have been using that absence
way before Docker was even invented, or maybe that was an
application that was simply created recently in your
project, or in your company, or in your organization or
wherever you are. That was something
that was not yet in containers and now you want to put it
there. So, perfectly normal.
Happens all the time. In fact, I would say most
applications in containers are MTA's,
and that's going forward going to be more and more of
them as we take our old systems and move them into
containers, right. Not everything put into a container
is a greenfield application where it starts in containers,
by default, on the first commit.
That's pretty rare.
So, in this application, you're going to take a very simple
CLI app, a command line app that I've created,
that simply takes images and turns them into different
images, or slightly different, altered images.
This uses something called GraphicsMagick or ImageMagick,
if you've ever heard of that. It's a standard command line
tool for Unix and Windows systems that manipulates
images. We're going to have sort of a command line app
that imagine this was running on servers somewhere that was
operating on images that were uploaded, and it needed to
spit out something in a different directory, and it's been
running for years, and it's running on Node versions that
are old and stuff like that. So, this is real-world stuff.
It just happens to be a very simple app that takes a lot of
these concepts and adopts them into one little, problem
set. You're going to look in the assignment-mta
directory of this course repo for
this assignment.
You have three, main activities which I'm going to dive to
here in this lecture.
The first one is you're going to need to create a
dockerignore file to make sure that certain things don't
get into the image that don't need to be there.
Secondly, you're going to need to create the Dockerfile and
of course, you can create that first and then the
dockerignore later.
It doesn't really matter the order here.
Then third, you're going to have to change something in the
app because in this app, it's logging to a file using
the Node Winston package.
That's a very common way to log, and we talked about
it in an earlier lecture.
You're going to need to change the transport of that
from logging to a file to logging to the screen, or a
console, so that Docker can capture those logs.
Imagine you are the devops engineer for
this organization that's running this app and you're
sitting in a project meeting.
You probably didn't create this app, but it's now your job
to Dockerize and get it working on the servers.
Maybe you don't know anything about Node.
Hopefully you do because you're taking this course.
But there's not a whole lot you need to know.
You're just going to need to do some basic research on
stuff. The first is that the
application has a readme that shows you the basic
requirements. This is maybe what would be
the operations documentation.
It's obviously only a few lines in the file, but in
the real world, a lot of times developers hand operators
definitions like we need Node 8 installed, and
we need these directories, and this needs to be installed
on the server first before Node, and stuff like that.
That's in that file, and you're going to need to read that.
That's going to help you build the Dockerfile.
When you build this image, you'll notice inside this repo,
there are an in, an out and node_module directories.
The in is going to be where the
images come into this app, right.
This app is ingesting images and then spitting them out
into the out directory as
you'll find out in the readme.
Those two directories are not necessary in the container
because the idea is that we're going to run this app
in a container and then bind mount wherever we need it to
ingest files coming in and out of it.
So, think of it as a command line utility that will take
files on a host and then spit them back out to the host
from a directory to a directory.
We don't want those in the image, right, because this is
more of a utility that's going to process things on a
machine. Doesn't need to store those images in the image
itself, the Docker image that is.
So, you're going to want to make sure that in your
dockerignore, that you're definitely never including the
Node modules.
But you're also ignoring the in, the out
and the logs directory. Now, the logs directory,
traditionally with this application, was used in the code
with Winston to log the error and the info
output. But, we don't really want to do that anymore.
So, you're going to need to open up the index.js file and
change three lines.
Basically commenting out the old Winston transports,
and then adding a new Winston transport that simply goes
to the console. If you have no experience with Winston,
no worries, because really there's several options you have
here. One is you could just change that line
if your project allowed you to edit the code, right.
You could go look up on Winston.
In fact, if you go to GitHub and look up the Winston
package, in that readme, it tells you exactly
how to create a transport in order to log to the console.
I've even given you a hint here that you could just search
for Winston transports console and that would tell you the
line you kind of need to put in this file, and then you
could comment out the other lines.
Secondly, you could, if you weren't allowed
to change any code in this app, which is
true in some cases. We're just simply not allowed to change
it. We must get it working in a container.
You could do a symlink, or an ln command,
in the Dockerfile where the logs are going to go.
That's how the official Nginx app does it.
So, if you're curious how to link, or symlink,
those log files, you could go check in the Docker Hub
for the official Nginx and go look in the Dockerfile for
that one, because they do the same thing.
They symlink those log files into
stdout and stderr because they can't change the
app's behavior. In this case, because we have the source
code for this Node app, we could change that and that's
what I'm asking you to do in this because that's hopefully,
if you're a Node developer, you have access to change the
Node app. So, that's a better way to do it.
The backup plan there, and if you want to play around, you
could test simply taking that same
code and only changing in the Dockerfile through symlinks
instead of changing in the code itself.
You're going to want to run this app as a docker run,
and you will want to bind mount the in and the out
directories back out to your host so that it pulls
in those images from the repo that I gave you
and then spits them back out into the out directory
so that there's the results.
Really what this is doing is this utility is using
GraphicsMagick to change a regular
GIF into, or any image really, into
a charcoal-based one.
Charcoal is one of the filters that will make it look like
its hand drawn with charcoal, essentially.
In this app, there is an environment variable that it
depends on called the charcoal factor that changes
the way the image is drawn, and makes it look a little bit
different. It has thicker lines with the bigger the number.
Okay. You could go look up how the app works, but you know,
that's not really the point of this lecture.
Really, this is about you making sure that that environment
variable is set in the Dockerfile and it has a default.
Then also testing it when you run your docker run
command to see if you can override that environment
variable. Change it to a different number and see if you
get a different output in the image.
The outcomes of all this, now that you have that basic
information on the requirements, if you've run the
container successfully and bind mounted both
the in and the out directories, and
on your host, whatever file you stick in there, what other
image and I give you a few, some GIFs, by default.
You can throw any image you want in there and then run
this, and it will take that image and then spit out that
exact same named image into the out directory on your host
that looks like it was drawn with charcoal.
If you do it correctly, that will be the result
and you'll know that that works.
The next outcome is that if you do a docker run with the
--env to change the factor to something like 10,
that the image does look different when you open it
again. The next outcome is that we definitely don't want
any of these images either in
the in or out directories stored in the Docker image
itself. You definitely make sure that your dockerignore is
correct so that that works, and that there's no bloat
or unnecessary files in the image.
The last outcome here is that when I do a docker logs
command on this container, that I get the
Winston results, which will tell me which images it
has processed and if it processed them correctly.
By default, if you didn't do anything with the logging,
your Docker logs would be empty because essentially the
apps Winston module is writing those files that Docker
can't see. Now, you have those four outcomes
that are the results you need to have to consider this semi
finished. In the next lecture, I want to do this myself.
Of course, you can follow along there too, but give this a
shot. Spend some time on it.
You may have to go look up the Winston documentation to
check for that one line you need to add.
You can simply do symlinks if you wanted to do it that way.
Then everything else should have been self-explanatory from
previous lectures on the Dockerfile itself and
the dockerignore file.
Good luck and have fun.