Once you've started using Node.js in production, you're
eventually, if not already, going to be using
orchestration.
Orchestration is something that lets us use many
different nodes, one or more, to act
like one, single Docker engine.
You might be using Swarm, ECS, Kubernetes,
Mesos, Nomad.
There's a lot of options.
The two most popular are the distributions of Kubernetes,
whether that's OpenShift, or Amazon's option,
or DigitalOcean's option, or Azure.
Really, all those Kubernetes options use standard
Kubernetes deployment files and configurations.
We're going to be able to look at that in a couple of
lectures, as well as the next lecture where we'll talk
about Swarm specifics for Docker Swarm.
Right now, I just want to get you refocused on the few
things that really matter when you're dealing with Node
in orchestration. When I say orchestration, what I really
mean is using more than one container,
from the same image, whether that's on the same host
or multiple hosts.
Because then you usually have to deal with things like load
balancers, or concurrency, or storing
state, depending on what type of app you're running in your
Node container. The big, three areas that you need
to focus on, which we've covered in this course, are
the startup and making sure that you have healthchecks,
or readiness checks, to ensure that your container
doesn't go live for whatever clients it needs,
before it's ready to be live.
Second, is dealing with state.
That's common even before containers when
we had multiple server setups.
You had to worry about state of your apps.
Usually you store the web state, or your session
state, or whatever the state of the container, you usually
store that in a database.
In an example in a minute, I'll talk about sockets I/O
and how even that requires state if you're using a multi
container setup. So, sockets I/O, we'll need to use
Redis backend or something to store your web socket
sessions. Then most importantly, is when
you shut down the containers, or replace them in most
cases. We're not often getting rid of containers.
We're usually replacing them with a new version or
something else. When you do that, you're going
to need to make sure that you have proper shutdown so that
your healthchecks, your liveness, your readiness.
All these different types of checks, whether it's Swarm, or
Kubernetes, or just regular Docker.
All those things properly shut down.
You properly close database connections and tell clients
that they need to reestablish their connection so that the
load balancer can move them to the proper node.
There's all sorts of stuff to worry about there.
These are the three areas that you need to work on and test
thoroughly to make sure your app works right before you go
production. You've seen us use the voting app before
in this course. I wanted to give you one, last little
glimpse of what result the result app, if you remember that
web app, it was using angular sockets
I/O, Express, sort of standard stuff that you
might see in a Node web app setup.
That result app, for the voting example app, I
have updated it inside this directory.
So, you go check this one out, and I basically have put a
few of the production concerns in there.
I've created a healthcheck URL, a
liveness and readiness check URL for Kubernetes.
I've added Stoppable, so it will track connections and
properly shut them down.
I have a whole shutdown process in there that will
disconnect clients through Stoppable and then shut down the
database connection, and then properly tell the
healthchecks to stop allowing connections.
And other things like using Redis as our storage
backend for sockets I/O.
And on and on and on. There's stuff in there that you
definitely should check out. I would not say that this is
production quality code.
There is very little error checking, but I've at least
added some of the concerns, like the termination
signals received from Docker and dealing with those.
Let's go check it out.
Jump in the sample result orchestration
directory and then open up the server.js file.
That's where I'm going to be looking at this.
From the top, I'm just going to scroll through this
really quickly to show you, in case you're not looking at
it yourself. You're maybe just watching this on the go.
Some of the things that I've added in here to a standard
Node app that maybe was precontainer like this one.
This is a Legacy app.
This was actually built on Node 6, so I've updated
the Dockerfile to 10, but that's not really important here.
I could have changed some of these things to be more modern
JavaScript and ES6 ready, but that's not
the case. I just really wanted to plug in here some of the
features that were probably necessary in a production
cluster.
You'll see that I have added Stoppable, and then I've
added the Redis option to
socket I/O because in a single server setup, socket
I/O doesn't really need to worry about sessions.
It keeps session state of your connections in memory.
Like many different web apps and other apps with session,
you need to deal with them in a database if you're going to
run multiple copies of that same app, right.
In this case, we're definitely to be running two or more
containers of this in the cluster for redundancy, so we
need that sort of setup.
As you'll see later, I add a simple little true/false
on whether the database is connected.
That will allow me to add that to part of my healthcheck
for a simple setup of, is my app talking
to the database so that it can be ready for clients to talk
to it.
Down here under my database connection, under this async
retry, I will add the DB connected true once
the client has connected to the database.
So, this will just mark it as true. It's a pretty simple
little example, but it gets the job done here.
It makes sure that essentially, my connections don't start
going to this app before it's ready.
If we scroll down a little farther, you'll see that we're
looking at healthchecks. This is me adding URLs, or routes,
to this Express app for the different types of
healthchecks. I talked earlier about the difference between
Docker and Kubernetes healthchecks.
Docker has a single one that you can use either in a
Dockerfile, which is the case here.
I've updated the Dockerfile with a healthcheck, or in the
stack or Compose files.
This one, I've just set the single URL that has to do
everything. In other words, it has to make sure that the
app is healthy, as well as make sure that
it's up and started, and all that stuff.
I give some information here in the comments that you can
read on your own around what different things this does
or what it should do.
If you're running this in production and simply scrolling
down, it just makes sure that if I'm
DB connected, then return a positive, or
a 200 result, on that URL, or an error
state if something else is wrong and a database isn't
connected. If you keep going, I've got one for readiness
that's very similar to that, and another one for
liveness. Those are the two types of connections that
you can use for Kubernetes because since Kubernetes has
two, the liveness really is about, is this
container working?
And readiness is, is it ready for connections?
When you start up a Kubernetes container, you want to make
sure that the database is connected and it's ready
to listen for incoming ingress connections before
the pod starts to return a positive
result to readiness.
Then past the healthchecks, you'll see that I've added the
SIGINT and SIGTERM from a previous lecture where we talked
about signals, making sure that Docker takes those signals
and does certain things.
You can see that for both of those, I am simply doing a
shutdown function, and that function is
below where we do a server stop.
In this case,
if you saw at the very top, I'm using Stoppable, which will
track the connections and then properly give those sections
a FIN packet.
It doesn't work with websocket so it's a little iffy in
this particular app because it is using long polling
and websocket type connections.
So, it doesn't work in all the cases of this app, but it
will help with anyone who's not websocket based to properly
give them a FIN packet to tell them to reset their
connection, or re-establish it to the load balancer, giving
them the opportunity to go to a new server without being
hard disconnected.
Then we set our little flag for DB connected to false so
that our readiness check, and our healthchecks, will stop
turning true.
Then, it will do a pool in to stop the database
connection and then properly exit the app.
And that's the end of the file. Again, not really a full
production setup, but it does give you the requirements,
making sure you have healthchecks and you're ready for
proper startup. Making sure that you have
the connection tracking so you know how to shut those down.
Then, and most importantly, for proper shut down, you're
dealing with connections appropriately so that when you
recreate this new container on, presumably
an updated image as you're constantly deploying new
versions of your app, that this app will have a much better
rolling update or blue-green update deployment.