This lecture is me doing the assignment just like
you should have done it, and I'll be sort of starting
fresh. I've actually not even thought about this from a
practice perspective or exactly how every line is going to
go. So, I'm going to talk out loud as I do
the assignment. Hopefully, if you either had stumbling
blocks, or if you just wanted to watch this for bonus, you
can maybe get some tips or information out of
it on how I'm thinking about making this Dockerfile.
Because Dockerfiles, Compose files, all these things,
they're never going to be 100% exactly the
same between one person and the next person.
There's always a little bit of art involved, and
hopefully you'll learn something from this.
The assignment was to start with CentOS.
So, the first thing I've got to do is create a Dockerfile
and go get it on Docker Hub,
or at least learn which tag I need to use on
Docker Hub.
Over on Hub, I can probably just go there and search,
but
I'm pretty sure I could just type it in from memory but
just for you, like I would look for the official.
This is marked official image over here on the right.
So, that's definitely the one I want.
Then I go through all the tags.
I could click on the tags but really I just want the
latest. I'm probably going to stick with that, right.
So, CentOS 7 in production-like settings,
you would definitely set this to a specific
image tag, exactly the one you want, and you would manually
increment that. Because usually in production settings, you
want to control every version update of anything including
your from image. So, I never recommend using from in
production.
All right. We've got this here, so I can just type in
CentOS 7, right.
From
CentOS 7.
You'll notice if you're using VS code
and you have the Docker plugin like I have down here,
you'll get this extra functionality where it will go and
search Docker Hub for you as you type from name so you can
see that I have several to choose from.
I'm just going to stick with CentOS 7.
This is where the sort of tricky part is.
I know I need to set an environment variable and
that it needs to be the Node
version I'm going to use.
I could just call it node version,
right. In this case, I just want to
do 10 for now.
I know that it needs be 10 something, but I'm basically
going to go look at Docker Hub and
get more information from how the Node repo does it.
So, I can go to the top here, search for Node,
official image for Node.
Yep. All right. Click on that one.
I know we need to use Node 10 so I
want to use
the default 10 repo.
So really, sometimes what I do is I just, you know,
control f on Windows, command f on Mac.
I just want to search the page for
10. It looks like .15 is the latest.
And Stretch is...now I
just happen to know this about Debian releases.
Stretch is a little newer than Jessie.
It's the release after Jessie in terms of versions
of Debian. So, Stretch is probably the most current.
I can also just search for 10, right.
Because you can see down here this one is...so if
I did node:10, it would be this one.
So, these are all sort of aliases, or extra tags, for the
same one, right. So, let's go in here, and
I'm going to dig through
exactly what this thing is doing.
And see they have sort of the same thing.
Environment Node Version 10.15.1.
This is a best practice I always recommend around
if you have versions of things that you need to download
and install, or any apt packages, or yum packages, or apk
packages on Alpine.
I really prefer to have their versions hard coded and then
I have those versions as environment variables at the top.
The biggest reason there is anyone who is going to edit
this Dockerfile in the future is going to want to
know what versions or possibly change versions of things.
At first, it might seem logical to keep the versions of
things near where you are installing them.
But, really I think it's best practice to put all those
versions in environment variables that you want to change
at the top because if you end up with 100 lines in your
Dockerfile, it'll be confusing as to where you need to go
and you have to scroll through everything.
So, I like to keep them all at the top.
So, I'm just going to copy that and jump over here.
Back this out and do the same thing.
A third doing. The idea here is that I'm keeping it as
close as possible to the official Node
repo as I can.
That way, anyone in the future who wants to mess with this
or take over for me, maybe I leave the company or the
project, and it'll make sense to them because they
can just go look at it online.
In fact, I might even say here,
you know a comment. Always love the comments.
Node install taken
from official
Node image Dockerfile.
All right. So that way, they know where to look.
I could even make a link to the exact one I'm using.
Here, it looks like...it's just
happening..having read this before in many Dockerfiles,
because a lot of the standard open source
official images are very similar in the way they install
things. This is all setting architectures which
we only care about one in this, you know, in most cases
you're really only caring about x64.
That's the most popular by far.
So we may not need to set that.
And that's dealing with keys, so that we have keys
to download packages that we might need.
Essentially, it's downloading a tarball,
if you can see here.
Downloading a tarball of the Node
binary that needs to be installed.
You can see that it's using the Node version environment
variable here so that if you ever change that environment
variable, then it will pull the new version and we won't
have to go changing the code inside this run command.
You can see here that it's doing a GPG
to validate. It's actually doing a little bit of validation
here to make sure that the package that you meant to
download is the right one and that there wasn't any sort of
security man-in-the-middle attacks or anything.
It also...so yeah, it does the SHA right here.
Then you can actually see that it removes the tarball
once it's untarred it.
So, it's actually taken at the tar command and
pulling out the binaries.
Then it deletes and cleans up the extra tarball that you
don't need. Then it makes a link
for Node so that you can actually type the node command and
that will technically install Node.js.
In certain...or certain distributions of
Linux, the node command that you install is
not actually Node by default.
It's a Node.js because of...there's another package that
already uses the word node. So, in this case it's at the
very end it's making that, right.
You can see down here, if we even go farther, it looks like
they're setting yarn version, installing Yarn.
If you needed Yarn, you could definitely do this, too.
We're not going to do that in this case because npm still
comes with the default node that's installed
here. So, all I'm going to do is
to keep it easy, I'm going to just copy this
and try this first.
See if it works.
Right. So, I'm just copying in all of that stuff.
Because I'm on CentOS and
I'm not on Debian, it's
probably not going to work out-of-the-gate because this
is all designed for apt get and the Debian
architecture of where files are and what packages are
installed by default. So, this may not work
out-of-the-gate. We may have to do some googling to
figure out what's going on here.
Of course, you can see up here that they're smart.
They're actually adding the Node user,
setting up that Node user so that later on, it
can run Node as least privilege.
So, ideally we can do that, too.
We can maybe just copy that right out.
Save that. And then just do a docker build.
And we'll call this centos-node.
Okay. So, we got our first error.
That's one of the tricky things about
doing this kind of setup where you take and copy and
paste stuff. You're not exactly sure.
Maybe, see where it says here D package
not found. So in that case,
that is because, I just happen to know this, but you
probably look at this on on the Internet, you would find
that that's because Debian package, that's
essentially what this little utility is, and that's not
going to be on a CentOS platform.
There is going to be a different command for that.
So, one of the things I could do is I could
either just do random Internet searches, or I could
also look at the
CentOS packages and maybe see how some
of them, you know, maybe if I can find something based on
CentOS, I could find out how they do it.
What commands they're using and maybe get some hints
on that, especially if I'm not familiar with these base
images.
I could look in here, and you can see that the CentOS
images, themselves, are very, very minimal so they,
themselves, will not help you.
You're going to have to probably search around Hub or just
search around the Internet for, you know,
in my case I might just search CentOS, then look around
for people that are doing stuff with CentOS,
and that they have...if they've got a lot of downloads and
that means to me that they're probably better thought
out, better supported.
This is from Pivotal which is a popular IT company,
so they definitely provide
developer and project management software so they're going
to make good images. Maybe I'll go look at theirs.
Of course, you know, this one doesn't have a
Dockerfile so that kind of stinks.
Actually, well maybe there's one here.
Yeah, that doesn't work.
So, you get the sense. I'm going to fast forward this so
that you don't spend ten minutes watching me search the
Internet. But, imagine that this is what you have to learn,
right. You have to figure out what that command means and
you're troubleshooting that error.
The other thing I will normally do is once I start getting
these errors in these sort of installations, I will go
back into my file, and you'll notice how all of this here
is all one, huge run command. So, that can be problematic
because if, at the very end, in the very last line,
that's what errors out, then this whole run command has
to be run each time.
And that kind of stinks. So, I might do something
like, you know every time
there's two ampersands,
I might do this.
Well, not for this command. That's a bad example.
Sorry.
Because set, you want to keep in there.
So, when it gets down to here,
then maybe, you know, you can see there's a do done loop.
So maybe I don't want to break up that bash loop there.
So, again that requires you know a little bit about bash
and that it's doing a for each loop down there.
So, when I get down to these commands, maybe what I want to
do is I take out the little
ampersands, and then I take out the
backslash, and then I could do a run here.
And what this does is this basically provides
a new layer. This isn't efficient for in terms of
long term, you know size
and space in the image, but for troubleshooting and getting
your images working, you can do that.
Sometimes, I will do this for each line.
So, I would go to the end of this line, take out the
backslash, go to the next line,
and take out those, and then do the run thing here.
So that way, when each one of these is successful, if it
errors out on the next one, at least I don't have to run
the image layer above it, right.
It gets me a little bit faster and the troubleshooting
gets me through the problems that I'm having.
You know maybe I error out in the GPG, or the grep, or the
tar because maybe those aren't installed in CentOS, and I
have to go find those utilities and install them.
So, yes.
That could be helpful if you're trying to figure this one
out.
But, the problem that we're having right out-of-the-gate is
that it's saying the D package, which you can see here, is
not available and it's trying to print
out the architecture for Debian,
and we don't have that.
So, what we're going to do is in my case,
I'm going to take all of this out because we know our
architecture and I don't...so
x86 is the little x86 right here.
And if you kind of read through this, what it looks like
it's doing is it's setting environment variables based on
my architecture.
If you think about it for a minute, or even if you just
search those three letters in this file,
you'll realize that those are used down here,
right, in that same run command.
That way it pulls down the correct architecture tarball
for Node for your particular
setup. But since this course is all based on standard
x86, we don't need to pull
the architecture. In fact, I could do a
search and replace,
and for every time I see dollar sign
arch, let's just replace it with x64.
All right. And then, up here at the top,
I can delete all of
this.
I'm just going to get rid of this comment just because we
don't really need the comment since we're pulling from
official.
And then I'll clean this up.
So, it's going to first run that set and then
it's going to basically, for each one of these keys,
add them in to
the key server, and then...which
this may all error out because we may not have those
utilities and we'll have to go find them.
This is going to run cURLs, which may also not be
installed, but at least our
first problem is hopefully solved.
Let's go back.
Try it again. Just hit the up arrow.
All right. So, it looks like the keys all correctly
happened because we went to the next step, where I did the
run cURL and look at that.
So it looks like cURL was already in the image.
The GPG utility that's needed to validate
to basically put the keys are in there to...what's
the next step. You can see each one of these steps.
Step six was finished
and there we go.The last step.
So, a couple of things we can do.
First, I need to pull back
out these runs.
Put back in,
in order make this more efficient, right.
I want to make this thing as small as possible.
All right. Then down at the bottom, we need to change our
cmd just like they do on the official repo.
When we go back up and go to the Node.
If we go to the official Node repo.
Go back down to the 10 release,
and it just changes cmd to Node
by default. So, we need to do that as well.
Then one more build.
See if this works.
And yeah, and you know things are red sometimes in
docker build, but it doesn't necessarily mean that there's
an error. If it completes, then chances are,
you know, if any command line utility were to error out, it
will usually stop the docker build.
So, we know we've got something going on here.
So, now that I have this image, I can just do a real quick
test, right. I could do a docker...docker
run centos
node and I could just type
node version. There we go. So, cool.
That's what we wanted and it worked the first time.
I was very lucky. Didn't have to do a bunch of googling and
Internet searching. So, that's how I would have came
about it. It's not too fancy.
If I zoom out, I've only got 35 lines and almost
all of them, except for that first part talking about
architecture from Debian,
is pulled out, and then of course we changed the
environment variable down here to x64.
That's all I had to really do.
So great.
Hopefully yours was that easy.
See you in the next lecture.