You've arrived at the assignment answers for
the first assignment in the course.
Hopefully, you're not cheating and that you've tried this
on your own a little
bit and at least got as far as you can before
reading this assignment or watching this assignment.
I also note in the assignment itself,
there's also a resource there that is going to have
the information from the slides so that you can just pull
down a text file
and that way you don't have to keep watching the assignment
video.
Hopefully, you saw that.
I'm going to run through this, just like I was you,
and I'll pass along some information along the way on why
I'm doing what
I'm doing and how it works.
We're in the sample -O2 directory,
and in here I have a Node
app that you probably saw from Docker Mastery.
It's similar to the one in Docker Mastery if you
actually took that course.
Then here, I'm really just going to run this
with Docker Compose
and go through the typical workflow of the day.
You'll see that I have a Compose file already here
and a Dockerfile for you, so we don't really need to change
those
yet. I'm going to run a docker compose up.
It'll build my image,
running through each of the steps, including the npm
install that will take a second.
This is running in the foreground,
right. So, we're gonna see the logs,
and if you wanted to actually
see something, you're going to have to,
at the command line, if you want to run other commands.
Really, we need to run this in detach mode.
I like you to hit control c,
and then we're going to do a docker compose
down. One thing you should note here is if you just kind of
wanted to dig around,
is if I did a docker image ls
and looked through my images, you see that I have the
sample 02
image in there.
If I do a docker compose down,
it will delete the container
and the network,
but it won't delete the image.
If I did a docker image ls,
then you can see it's still there,
right. You would have to run other docker compose down
commands
to delete other things.
If you just did a docker compose down --help,
you will see that there's multiple options there.
We talked about the -v in previous lectures.
You also have the option here to remove images if you so
choose.
If I wanted to delete all images for this
project, I could do a --rmi space local,
and that will be this line right here.
That will basically tell it to delete all custom images it
built as a part of the docker compose up.
It won't delete ones it downloaded,
but it will delete custom built ones.
I don't normally do that, or have to do that,
because I find that Docker's build process,
it either works or it doesn't. The cache works correctly,
so you don't need to delete images as a part of a
troubleshooting
step. If I wanted to not use
the cache, I would need to do a docker compose
build no cache,
which is similar to the docker build no cache option,
and that will build it from scratch every time
if I run that command. So,
you don't need to delete the image manually.
You could just use that no cache option if you think you
want to start from scratch.
Maybe you had a run command that succeeded
but you actually want it to force running that run command
anyway,
you could do that. Again, it's not a common problem
and a common issue, but there it is for you.
We'll do another docker compose up
with a -d this time so we get our command line back.
Then, there's other common commands you'll run,
like a docker compose ps.
That's going to give me several things.
It's going to tell me the name of the service.
I can kind of tell over here,
without even looking at the compose file,
the name of the project is sample 02.
Then here's an underscore that separates the different
parts of the image
name. The second part there is just the name of the
service.
Then the next one is the numerical number of the
replica. By default, every service has one
container or replica.
If I told it to spin up multiple containers
for that service and run basically multiple node
containers at the same time off that same image,
we would see 1, then 2.
Then, of course, you have a random number after that,
just to make sure that they're unique.
Then on the right, I can see the port that's being
redirected through publishing from my host into the
container
itself. So, I could now go over to my browser
and do a localhost
3000,
and I'll get the app. Note, if you're on Windows
and you're using Docker Machine
with an older version like Docker Toolbox where you can't
use
localhost, remember that you'll have to use the IP address
of the Docker Machine.
You can get that from the command line.
If you're on Windows 7, Windows 8.
Windows 10 Home
and using Docker Toolbox,
you can just do a docker machine ls at the command
line and it will show you your machine
and the IP address for it.
That's what you use in the browser along
with port 3000.
If you're already running something else on port 3000,
then you'll get an error that says port already
in use or address already in use.
That means you're running some other container
or some other application on that port.
So, you would just need to go in the Compose file
and change the port that it's publishing.
Remember, the left side is what you would change.
The right side of that port is what
is used in the container by the node app.
All right. I can also do docker compose logs.
That will give me the logs. If I had multiple services,
as we will throughout this course,
I could do a docker compose logs
and then the name of the service,
web in this case.
That would give me the logs just for that service in the
Compose file. Often when you're running Docker Compose
and you have active containers,
you may want to troubleshoot something
or get inside the container so that you can look at things
more
closely if something's not behaving the way you expect.
So, you can use the Docker Compose command to do that,
docker compose exec web,
since that's the name of the service.
Then I can just do an sh shell here.
I'll shell into the container
and then I'll be right in that directory where the app runs
from.
In this case, I was asking you to run a cURL,
curl localhost.
You'll notice that it says cURL not found because cURL is
not installed in
the container. In this case,
I could just do apk,
which if you know this Compose file
and you look at the Dockerfile for this app,
you see in the Dockerfile that this is based on the Alpine
image
and Alpine has a different package manager than you might
be used
to. The Alpine images use apk,
or Alpine Package Manager.
Here, I would do an apk add update
and then curl. That would update the package manager
and then add the cURL package all in one go,
right. I could do that, but I want to permanently have it
in the image,
so I'm going to exit out.
Then I'm going to go back over to my editor
and inside my Dockerfile,
I want to change this here.
And save that file.
While you're still running docker compose up,
you can still run another up,
and it will just make sure that everything is as it should
be.
So you don't have to bring it down before you bring it up
again.
So, docker compose up -d.
You'll notice that even though I change the Dockerfile,
it did not rebuild.
And that's because if the image already exists,
Docker Compose will not check for file changes unless you
do a --build.
So, we're going to have to do that same command again,
but at the end add a --build for it to see the
changes.
If I hit my up arrow a couple of times,
I can get back to that exec command
and I can exec back in
with a docker compose exec web sh.
This time, I should be able to curl localhost
and cURL works,
but I'm on the wrong port.
That's because you need to remember that the port in
the container is different than the port on your host.
So, if you were doing curl from your local machine,
you're going to do the published port.
You're going to curl the localhost of the published port.
In this case, the nice thing is they are the same,
right. If you go and check in the Compose file,
you'll see that 3000 is what we're publishing on.
We're also listening on 3000 inside the container.
So, what I need to do here is curl localhost 3000.
And there we go. We get back the cURL response.
This is just a small example of some of the workflow you
might do.
I don't normally need to cURL inside the container on a
daily basis,
but it's a simple example of how you might want to jump in
and run things inside the container.
If you exit out of there
and then do a docker compose down to clean
everything up, you'll be ready for the next lecture.