Earlier in this course, we talked about healthchecks.
At that time, we were talking about it for local
development and to be aware around depends on
availability. That's not what I want to talk about here.
But, I do want to focus on healthchecks for production.
The first rule here is that you always want healthchecks.
Regardless of how you're using it, whether you're using it
in Docker, or Swarm, or Kubernetes, or
ECS, or something else, you want to have a
healthcheck possible for your application.
Here in this lecture, I just want to talk about
healthchecks in the Dockerfile for Node.js apps.
If you want to learn about larger healthcheck stuff, there
is certainly a lot of material out there.
If you check out my Swarm Mastery course, I talk about
Swarm healthchecks a lot in there.
Of course, Docker, Kubernetes, and all the others, all
have documentation that you can check out.
What if you put the healthcheck command in your
Dockerfile? What happens then on a server?
First, if you're just using regular Docker on a server,
that's just the Docker Engine where you'd be running Docker
run commands, or if using Docker Compose, which is
essentially the same thing.
They will technically run that healthcheck, but they're not
going to do anything about it.
They're not going to respond to a failed healthcheck.
So, they're not really that effective. They're not going to
be helpful in reacting to problems with your Node app.
If you're using Swarm, I always advise you have that
healthcheck in the Dockerfile.
That way, the operators who are operating your app,
maybe that's not you, can see exactly what you
expect for a healthcheck inside your application.
Remember, these healthchecks are running inside your
container. The Docker Engine is actually executing the
cmd of that healthcheck inside your running container.
So, you're going to need to have the tools in there that
you need for that healthcheck.
If you don't provide that healthcheck in your Dockerfile,
then you're leaving it up to someone else to maybe
implement it, or maybe not.
Then, you're just not going to have as great of a
production experience, especially when it comes to updating
your containers, or rolling them over and replacing them
with new ones. If you're interested, or already using
Kubernetes, know that Kubernetes itself does not
use the healthcheck command out of your Dockerfile.
Because Kubernetes has two types of healthchecks,
readiness and liveness checks.
Those would be in your Kubernetes deployment files,
which are not the same as your Dockerfile itself.
I would still recommend that you put the liveness check
in your Dockerfiles.
That way, even if someone likes to run it without
Kubernetes, they're still getting the benefit, and it also
serves as good documentation for someone who might be
building your Kubernetes deployment files for you.
I have a couple of samples in the healthchecks directory of
the course repo. Let's go check them out.
What I've given you here is a sample app with a
Dockerfile that has three healthchecks in it.
This doesn't make any sense. This Dockerfile won't actually
work as you expect. There's no such thing as three
healthchecks.
I just want to give you three, different options and we're
going go through them here.
Really, in each Dockerfile, you would keep one.
If you actually did try to build this Dockerfile, it would
just replace the second and third ones over top of
the one before it, so you'd end up with the third one being
the one that's actually used.
The first one here, option one, is the one that we always
see exampled in documentation.
I actually copied this straight out of Docker's
documentation. This works for Node web
apps. In fact, for Node apps, really if it doesn't have
a public endpoint, or it doesn't have something listening
on a TCP port, healthchecks get a little trickier.
In this example, we're talking about just HTTP
endpoints that you might access.
It doesn't mean that this container needs to be public on
the Internet because again, these are all running from
inside the container themselves so they can just talk
directly to the localhost and access the other apps
inside that container.
In option one here, we're using the cURL, and make sure
that you have cURL installed because it needs to be in the
container to be used.
Make that connect against the localhost and you'll see that
it has a -f and the exit 1 at the end
with the two pipes.
That's really there to make sure that the output
of cURL, in case it fails, is compatible
with the healthcheck command. Because the healthcheck
command expects either an exit code of 0 or 1,
and not some other exit code.
That way of using that bash command there, with the pipes,
forces either cURL to return a successful 0,
or to only return exit 1.
If you're using something else besides cURL, you just want
to make sure that it's going to use either one of those
exit codes. Here in example 2,
we're getting a little more advanced.
We're using a custom endpoint.
So, we're still using the cURL command, but we're hitting a
custom URL that presumably has some logic
behind it. In my sample, little happy app
here, if I scroll down, I've created a special endpoint
just for the healthz endpoint.
Really, the endpoint you pick for your apps doesn't
really matter. But, it is common in distributed computing,
cloud computing, and especially containers now, for you
to create a special endpoint just for healthchecks
that isn't just the default webpage.
You've seen some examples, especially if you're in the Go
language community, around healthz.
I'm using that standard of the name here, but again, it
doesn't really matter. Just as long as you're consistent.
Presumably, this particular endpoint
would do some logic and things that you'd want to check.
Piece of advice. Don't have these internal healthchecks
asking for database queries, or things outside
of this container's control.
Because you don't want to have a container's healthcheck
cause it to fail that container and replace it if there's
a problem with some other container.
You really want individual container healthchecks
to be isolated just to that container itself.
So, you're really just checking the internal health of that
particular one.
You're going to leave the larger monitoring of a
cohesive system of distributed applications, you're going
to leave that up to third-party tooling
and monitoring for some other day.
Of course, in my example here, I'm not having it do
anything other than return a healthy 200 code.
But, really you probably should have it doing a little bit
more advanced checking here.
Of course, if it simply responds, that does mean, at least,
it's accepting requests.
This isn't a waste of time here, but as you get
more advanced in your application development, you're
probably going to want to add more advanced stuff here.
Maybe you're going to have it checking for proper files on
the machine, or proper permissions, or stuff like that.
Back to the Dockerfile, for the third example I have here,
this one is running a Node command
outside of the Node Command running the
application itself in the container.
So technically, while this healthcheck is running, there's
two, different Node binaries running, and
they're running different files. In this case, it's running
a special JavaScript file I've created just to do
the logic I want for the healthcheck.
The nice thing here is there are several advantages.
One is I don't need cURL in the image because I'm just
using Node to check Node.
I can skip the extra utility.
Second, I can put a lot more logic on the frontend,
or the client side of that HC.js file,
and how it checks. It may do more than just check a web
URL. It may check permissions and not require
the Node app it's calling to to do that for
it. You can see I have a healthcheck.js file.
Here it does a very simple check using an HTTP
client that essentially just checks the server healthz
endpoint.
So, it's not really gaining us much here, but maybe this
client script could do other things in the file system, or
check for specific files that it expects, something like
that. It's really up to you whether you put this into the
healthcheck logic itself, or you build it into your app,
and the healthcheck itself is just simply cURLing or
testing a URL.
You also have to think about the third-party monitoring
tools that are going to be outside of this Node.js
app and how they're going to talk to this app and
check health remotely.
Really, to sum this up, in the end, it's up to you how
you do these healthchecks.
I've provided a link or two in the resources here
for you to go read more on Node.js healthchecks specific
to Node.js because really, it gets into the
programming of the language and how you want your apps to
be checked.
My rule of thumb is to always have something,
even if it's simply testing the root URL of
a website or something else.
If it's a non web app, some
of the things that I might recommend to you are to have
your Node.js app simply writing
out the health to a file every so often.
Then the healthcheck command is checking that file.
OK. Because if you don't have an endpoint in
your app itself to check remotely from a different
application, you're not left with much.
So maybe that's just a worker Node.js app and it's just
sitting there waiting for files to be ingested.
Maybe it's an image processing solution.
In that case, what I would do is I'd have a healthcheck
that was running some custom JavaScript logic in
this third option here.
That would simply drop a file in the location inside
the container for that Node app to find it, and
then it would process it, and then the test script would
check for the result.
Then if everything looked great, then you would know that
the container is processing those images correctly.
Once you get into the non website stuff,
it kind of gets very specific to the domain of
what your app is doing.
But you can still do healthchecks.