In the last lecture, we talked about the dependencies and
startup order in your Compose file, and how you need to
work with that to make sure that your multi-service
application goes well when you're local developing.
Now, I want to get into the specifics on the depends on
healthchecks. If you haven't heard of healthchecks, they're
a built-in Docker feature that you can put in Dockerfiles,
Compose files, Kubernetes deployment files,
Swarm stack files.
Basically, you can put them everywhere. You can put them in
at the command line even.
They're just little tests that ensure that the
container is available and ready.
Normally, we don't worry about that stuff in local
development, but they can be very handy for
making sure that your backend database, or API
containers on your local system, are ready to go before
other containers start.
This gets you away from the whole restart cycle of Node
apps because your database is starting up.
I really like to use these when I'm local and
I especially like the convenience of them ensuring that
everything starts in the proper order.
If we look at the depends on feature of the Compose file,
it doesn't have anything extra in terms of features
in the V3 of Compose.
We have to go back and use the V2, which I've stressed
throughout this course, as the appropriate version for
local development right now.
That depends on feature in the V2 gets an extra
bonus for it can depend on the healthcheck before
it starts other services that depend on that service.
This is the true wait for style, dependency
stuff that you might go searching Google for and find
people talking about creating scripts, and other types
of automation, to solve this problem.
But, it's already there. It's already solved in the
Compose. We just have to enable it.
I want to show you some quick, simple examples of how this
works. We'll look at a Web, a Mongo,
a Postgres and a MySQL example so that we see
how simple this can really be.
If you want to follow along, there's the depends on
directory inside the course repo where I have two, simple
examples. The first one is a standard Docker Compose YAML
file. It has the old style, or what I
would consider incomplete depends on example.
This example is all over the Internet and in the
documentation where it solves two of the three problems
that I discussed in the previous lecture.
It shows relationships so that when I do a docker compose
up node for the Node service, it will first start
the DB. It will not wait for the DB to be healthy
and ready for connections, though, because we need the
healthcheck.
It also solves the problem of DNS, so when the Node
service comes up and it needs to resolve the DNS for
database, the database container has at least been started
at that point, and it will not fail DNS resolution.
Let's go to the more complete example which is what I would
encourage you to use.
This example is using the full healthcheck
feature set of depends on that we got in Version 2.3,
or newer, but you also have to be less than Version
3.
Remember, Version 3 of the Compose file format is designed
for orchestration where we don't really get to control
startup order across multiple servers.
So, this example doesn't make sense there which is why this
feature really only exists in Version 2.
You see that the standard depends on exists here.
This would be maybe a frontend with an API backend,
and in the API depends on databases.
So, you've got multi-tiered dependencies.
You see here that the API has to have this line,
condition service healthy.
So underneath every depends on statement, for each thing
you depend on, you have to add this extra line.
Then on the thing you're depending on, you've got to put in
the healthcheck. So, for the API, it's a very simple
web API, so I might just do a simple cURL command here.
Note, that cURL may not be in all of your apps by
default. It's in the Alpine image, but it may not
be in all images, so make sure that your image
has cURL in it or the tests will always fail.
Then you'll see I have three dependencies for this API.
The Postgres, Mongo and MySQL. Hopefully,
your database and API situation isn't requiring
all three database types.
But, really this is here just for me to show you the
example of commands.
If you scroll down here, you see that I'm showing a very
simple test command for each one.
The Postgres one uses a built-in utility to simply
say, are you ready and it will succeed,
or fail, with an exit code.
The Mongo does the same one.
It's a little bit longer where it actually uses the Mongo
client. It sends a true JavaScript ping command
into a test database.
Then the MySQL one uses the MySQL admin utility, which
is bundled with the MySQL container image.
It does a ping on the localhost there.
All three of these, essentially, are the simplest
way for you to verify that the port is open and the
database can receive connections.
For production systems, obviously healthchecks would need
to be more complex.
You might also make more complicated ones that would ensure
that there were select statements in there to see if real
data exists. But, I don't know that that makes any sense
for just simple, local database dependency
stuff. These commands here solve my problems
so that when I start up Docker Compose, I never
get my Node app failing because it can't connect to the
database. Because it will wait.
Or more accurately, Compose will wait, to start
that Node app until the database starts returning a
successful healthcheck.