One of the things that will help you look like a pro when
building out your Node files, and is generally also
important just for sanity, is to make sure your images
are efficient. That means efficient in terms
of smaller space when it's possible.
But, also in terms of building speed.
Because you don't want to rebuild this thing dozens,
hundreds, maybe even thousands of times, over the lifetime
of this image, on your machine or on a build server, and it
be slow for no, good reason.
We want to go through some steps here that may
affect build speed and size, and then just general quality
of efficiency in terms of making sure you don't have
redundant lines or anything like that.
The first one I want to talk about is the from image.
We just covered that, but you can see in the sample-02
that we were using before, that the first line there is
defined as node:10 alpine.
So, we're at least pinning it to the 10 version.
If I was building this app in Node, I would probably start
with 10. Then as I got closer to production, I would start
hard coding it to a patch release to make sure my app
worked as expected.
But for now, I'm just going to start with 10.
I'm choosing Alpine out-of-the-gate with this newer image
just to make sure that I get the smallest image possible.
The times you're going to have problems with Alpine are
usually going to be related to Legacy, large Node apps
that you're trying to get into a container image and
maybe they have some things that don't quite work yet with
APK, the Alpine Package Manager.
Anyway, let's move on to the next one here.
That's the ordering of lines.
Line order matters because as you remember probably
from your early days of Docker training, that Docker
builds naturally go from top to bottom.
So, each line is executed as a new layer in that
image. If you have layers
that don't change very often, but they're at the bottom of
the file, then you will end up with those layers being
built over and over again for no good reason because of
cache busting. If you're not familiar with cache busting,
that's the term we use whenever you get to a line in the
Dockerfile that has changed.
Either the files that have to be copied in are changed, or
that actual line of the Dockerfile itself has changed.
Whenever that event happens, that line, and any
other lines below it, will have been busted and have to be
rebuilt. That's normal, but we don't
want it to happen if we can avoid it.
In this case, you'll see that I actually have the expose
line, line 3 here, up higher in the
Dockerfile. That is not what you see normally in online
default samples.
But, if you think about it, it's never going to change,
really, if your app is always running on the same port,
then it's likely going to be changed once or twice, maybe,
in the entire lifetime of the image.
So, put that up top so that that line doesn't have to run
near the bottom every time.
Next, whenever I'm looking at a Dockerfile for Node,
I'm always expecting to see at least two copy lines.
The first one is actually something that you don't
see in this file. I deliberately avoided it so that we
could have the situation where we want to talk about it.
That is, you will notice a mistake here.
It's really not something that will prevent this
image from building, but it's a huge inefficiency in
that I'm copying in all the source files before
npm install.
Which means, any time a source file changed, which is
all the time you're working on your app, it will then bust
the run line for npm install and have to rerun
that line every single time it copies in files.
We definitely don't want that.
So, what you will normally see in Node is we will first
have a copy line that copies in just the package JSON
and the package lock JSON.
Then we run npm install.
Then we copy in ..
which means everything from the host directory
to everything in the current working directory of the
image. That's going to be normally run after
npm install. That saves us a huge amount of time.
Even with the modern efficiencies of npm and yarn
in their latest releases, they're still something that is
going to take a while, especially in a larger app, they
could take minutes. We want to keep that to
a minimum and only rerun npm install when
we have to because of a package change.
So, we want to change this.
In your sample directory, you can open up this Dockerfile,
sample -02, and you're going to move
this copy line down
underneath the run.
And the spaces, by the way, are not required.
I'm just doing them for easier reading.
And then we're going to add a copy line up top here
to copy the package JSON and the package lock.
Two things I want to note here.
There's a trick here that the community actually taught me
that you can put an asterisk at the end of the package
lock file in case it doesn't exist.
Dockerfiles will treat this as a copy
if it's there, but don't fail if it's not.
If you've ever tried to be literal about a copy command, if
the file doesn't exist in the host, it
will fail the build unless the file exists.
So, it creates a problem for lock files if you haven't
really run npm install yet and haven't created your
lock file, because that's auto generated.
In a lot of cases, you're going to create a new app
on the host and then you're going to run all the commands,
like npm install, in the container.
So, you need to be able to get the package file in there
somehow.
The way we get around this here is we put this asterisk,
which means, copy it if it's there, but don't if
it's not. The last part is we're going to be literal about
where we're copying it to just to be very specific.
We're saying, copy it into the current working directory,
which you can see in the line above it.
That way, we know exactly where these files are going and
not accidently put them somewhere else.
Again, I always look for the two, different copy commands
in the file at a minimum.
The next little tip is about package managers at the
host level. So, not necessarily your npm package manager.
I'll be honest, this isn't as big an issue for us Node
people because we don't necessarily always have
to run apt-get installs, or yum, or
APK, the Alpine Package Manager.
But if you do, realize that you need to put them
up high in the file, above any copying in of package
files preferably.
And you need to pin the versions on them, like I always
recommend anyone do for any package manager.
Always pin versions.
We won't talk about that here in this course because it's
not a Docker specific thing.
But if you're curious, you can always search your package
manager of choice and just search Google for pinning,
and you'll usually come up with some really good
recommendations on the easy way to pin those files.
And make sure you get the specific versions of your
dependencies, as you do with everything else, right.
Your code is versioned.
Your Node version at the top is there.
Your package versions are here, locked in the JSON file.
So, why not pin your APK or
apt-get package manager.
The point I want to make there is something that people
don't maybe realize about an apt-get or a another package
manager. That is if I do hear a run
apt-get update.
You'll see this in a very common way, apt-get install,
yada yada. Let's just say cURL.
That wouldn't work here in my Alpine image, but if it was
on a Debian based image, I would be able to do this.
What you might see people do later is then they install
something else later. Maybe they do a run apt-get
install something else, okay.
This you would never want to do, well, for a few reasons.
One is it's much more efficient to have all that stuff
installed at the top of the file at once.
The second, and major issue here, is that caching
will work against us.
The cache can sometimes actually be bad
for us. In that case, what's happening here is the apt-get
update is only going to be run when this
line is cache busted.
Which means later, if we copy our package
file in, and we change some things, and then we run the
apt-get, it will technically be installing something from
an old version of the apt-get
update because that line was not busted.
So ,that's why you always see in all the official images
where you get apt-get update, apt-get install, and then the
cleanup is all one, large run line,
so that that all happens in the same layer of the image.
Again, lucky for us, in a lot of Node apps, you won't even
need a package manager outside of npm or yarn.
So, yea for you if you're that lucky.
For the rest of us, just be sure to run it all at once at
the top of the file.