Welcome to the assignment answer for the
Ultimate Node Dockerfile.
Hopefully, you've spent a significant amount of time, more
than a few minutes, going through the assignment.
There's a lot to it, so I don't expect your
Dockerfile to look like mine.
They might even get to the same, exact result and not
be the same thing.
That's the thing that happens when we all start getting
more complicated in our designs as they get a little bit
more opinionated. Maybe you like something that I don't
prefer. So, there's not necessarily a black and white.
That's why I wanted the outcomes at the bottom of the
readme file, that you've hopefully gone through that.
That is important because those outcomes
don't necessarily reflect, line by line, what needs to be
in this Dockerfile, right. That's really just, does it
work the way you'd expect?
So, I'm going to go through it, and do it like you would
do it, and we'll have some fun.
All right. I am in the directory, the ultimate node
dockerfile directory.
Now I'm in the readme, and I'm just going to
go through each line.
The first one here, on the finished
Dockerfile, is creating a multistage Dockerfile
that supports specific images for production, testing and
development. If I open up that
Dockerfile, the one that I've given you,
has...it's very simple.
It's a single stage Dockerfile.
The first thing I notice is that it's saying that these
apt-get commands are really only needed for dev and
test. I don't need them in a production
image. So, I definitely know that I need three, different
stages, at least, because I need a production,
a development and a test.
I also need to move these out of this
first image. Like you've seen several times
whenever I've shown the multistage examples, there's
typically a base stage where you do
something that's going to be in every other stage.
So, I end up just calling it base.
It doesn't always have the source code in it.
It might just have dependencies. You know, something like
npm installs or apt-gets, stuff like that.
Those are often the things that take the longest when
you're building an image, other than maybe some of the
testing stuff. So, I usually want that as early on
as I can in a base image, and then I'll refer to that base
image, or pull from that base image for later
images. The first thing I want to do is, when
I'm going to do multiple stages, is
I'm going to think about it in a way where I'm just
going to outline it.
I'll just do a from base as.
So, dev, because I'm going to have a dev image.
Then a little later, I'm going to have
from dev as test.
The reason that I know, right away, that
it's probably going to have a test based on dev is
that I know that my dev dependencies, that all those tools
are going to be needed when I do testing. To
make it more efficient, I'll just have those hopefully be
able to pull from each other.
So, that dev will depend on base, and it'll just go from
the first, to the second, to the third kind of image
building scenario. You know, when you're creating these,
you have an idea in your head how many stages
you might need. But then once you get really into it, you
might realize you need more stages.
You might realize that you need to reoptimize your stages
because there's too much stuff going on.
So, I tend to find that whatever I thought
I was going to have at the beginning of this is not exactly
what I end up with at the end to get it to work.
Then I want to do something that's...call it
from base as prod.
Just because I've done Node multistage
before, and I know that I typically want my prod images
to be so lean, and not have any of the dev stuff
in them, or any of the test stuff in them.
If you've been around a while, you know that you can
actually do some npm uninstalls, where you can tell
it to remove dev dependencies.
But, I'm not so much a fan of that because
I don't feel like that's guaranteeing me that my production
image is exactly like I want.
Basically, there's some magic that npm will do that will
get rid of dev dependencies, and it's probably just
removing a bunch of files.
One is that that doesn't necessarily
mean that my image will be smaller, because
it would have to happen in some other image, right.
It can't happen in the prod image.
Because the prod image can't have anything in it
at all. Otherwise, those layers will just bulk up
the image. But, that all goes back to the way that images
work. If you have a previous layer of the same image
that has a bunch of files in it and then you remove them,
they're still in the image. They're just not going to show
up when you run it, but they're still taking up space,
making it bigger.
So, one of the scenarios is I don't want to use that
npm remove dev dependencies command because it's
kind of tricky on where I put it, in which stage, in order
to make sure that those aren't there in the production
image at all. So, you'll see me go through that, and
I'll skip that option when I'm working in Docker.
Here up at the top, I'm going to have to rename my first
stage as base.
That tends to be my standard.
That's not necessarily anyone else's standard.
I don't want to put these comments in here.
I want to keep this as lean as possible just for the
ease of you looking at the screen.
Then, the next thing I want to do is put this
dependency install stuff down here in the dev image only.
Because I know that it's not needed in production according
to that documentation.
I'm going to clean up some spaces here, just so it's easier
for us to move around.
Save that for now.
I've got three stages not really doing a whole lot there
yet.
Dev dependencies should not exist in production image.
So, I know that now I'm going to need two, different npm
install commands.
The first one was already up here.
All right. Really, in order
to control npm install here, I need an
env. I need that to be
node env=production.
Then, I can come down here to my
dev image and paste that and change it to development.
Then I can probably copy this npm install command
and also put that down here
under development.
Now, I'd like to be more literal, so I
also put in
--only like
that. Then I'll do the same thing up here
at the top, I'll do a --only.
So,
it's a little clearer to someone reading it.
That way, they don't have to go up to find the env line to
see what's going to be installed later.
They see that, oh, npm install will only install
production.
So, I kind of do both.
You could get away with using one or the other.
At some point, you're going to need a node env in there
because other things in Node will act differently based on
the node env, not just npm install.
Here, I just like to put it in so that it's easier to read,
and I can be doubly sure that it's definitely going only
install the production stuff.
That's enough, I believe, to qualify
for that line.
The next line, use npm ci to install production
dependencies. Here, I want to change
this from npm install to npm ci.
Then, that means this production doesn't work.
It doesn't need that because it will only install
production dependencies anyway.
All right. Use scenario one for setting up Node modules,
the simple versions. If you remember back earlier in the
course, that just means that we're going to put everything
in the same app directory. We're not going to try to split
out the Node modules and put it higher in the file path.
So, I won't do that.
Set node env properly for dev and prod.
Done.
The dev stage should run nodemon from dev dependencies,
either by updating the path or hard coding the path in
nodemon. Cool.
So, I've already
got the env path here, so I think I'm good to go on the
path. It actually puts the Node
module's bin in there, which will have the nodemon for me.
That means down here under
dev, I just need to do a cmd
and change...just
change it to be like that, where it's running nodemon
instead of Node.
Edit Docker Compose to target the dev stage.
I have called this stage dev, so that
way, in my Docker Compose to tell it to run
that stage.
Target dev. Add labels from OCI standard values are up to
you to all the images.
While I certainly don't memorize all these, and I certainly
don't want to type them all out. So, I'm going to go back
to the command line and back up a directory,
and go to the label examples from the previous
lecture that talked about labels.
If I see in there, they're actually all in the Dockerfile
there. So, I could open
that up in Visual Studio Code.
Or, if you have cat available, just cat the
Dockerfile.
Copy and paste those in.
I may not use them all.
But, I'll put them up here at the top. One of the
requirements was all these labels would be in every one of
them, which means I had to put them all the way at the top.
I do like to put them at the very beginning so that people
can see it. I'm not going to use created or revision here.
I don't have a URL or source, so
I can't really use them all.
But, I can use some of these.
Yeah. Something like that.
Doesn't really matter. I've got those in there.
It will pull the Node version from the official Node image
that I'm using, Node 8 slim.
Add npm config list output before running the npm install.
In my base and in my dev
images, where I have both these npm install commands...Oh,
look at that.
I don't have my npm install down here.
So, I do need to do a run npm install.
Oh, look at that. I've already made a mistake where my test
is where I've got this Node env
development stuff, and not the dev image itself.
So, I'm going to fix that before I go any further.
You're probably wondering why that was the
case, and it shouldn't be that way.
I should be putting all this in the dev image, and
then leaving the test image blank from not, because I'm not
really sure what the requirements are for that.
All right. That's a little better.
Now, according to that readme, I need to add
a run line in for npm config
list. Have
that line run on both images
right before it does npm install.
The reason I'm putting in this as multiple
run lines, because technically, you could combine
these two run lines together.
It would maybe save you like a hundred milliseconds
on the build so that it doesn't have to stop and recreate a
new container for the next line.
But, when I'm building images,
especially up front, when I'm just building it and I'm
writing stuff down, I don't even know if it works yet.
I always break out my run lines as much as I can, where I
think they might have a problem, or might fail, because
it's easier to troubleshoot and it's faster to rebuild when
each one of them is on their own line.
So, I'll worry about efficiency later, and maybe
I'll combine these on my own when I just want to make
this thing as fast as possible.
I could possibly combine all these run
lines together once I know they're working really well.
For me, I tend to keep them separate as long
as there's no serious delay or it's not going to cause
a file bloat issue.
You know the reason you do the apt-get update and the
apt-get install all in one line is so
that you get the right of current
updates. So, if you put those in separate run lines,
there's actually some potential problems you could have
there. The same goes with the npm install and the cache
clean. The cache clean won't really save you any space.
But, I always make sure that's there, right.
This hasn't really gained anything if I combine this run
line here. I'm just going to leave it separate for easier
troubleshooting. All right.
Create a test stage that runs npm audit.
All right. I can do that.
I've already got the test stage, because I was going to
have a dev test prod.
Then I can just do a run npm audit.
Really? Should work.
Test directory should only exist in test image.
Interesting. So, this one can be a little tricky.
It may not be something that we fully fleshed out in a
previous lecture.
Sometimes you want to clean up some stuff before you put it
into production.
But, that stuff is included on the host.
So, you can't put it in a Docker ignore because it has
to be in at least one of the images.
It just can't be in all of the images.
That means you need possibly some images
where it's only doing cleanup for you.
Remember, you can't just copy stuff in, then clean it up in
the same production image that you're going to ship.
Because then you end up with image bloat where that stuff
is sort of hidden in an old layer, and it didn't really
get removed from the image. It's just not going to show up
in the final layer.
So, in this case, I'm going to need
probably some sort of intermediate
image where I do a remove command
at the command line just to delete the files, and then I
copy the final into the production.
That way, I never have those unnecessary
files in the production image, and it's as small as
possible.
I know that my copy command is all the way to top here.
That's not really ideal.
It never really should be like that in a multistage image,
because the copy command will bust everything
else. As soon as I change a single file, every line below
this is going to have to be rebuilt unless you're using
BuildKit. BuildKit gets a little bit smarter, but in the
default building, it's going to require a lot of work.
So, I'm going to move that down as much as I can.
We know we don't need it in the base.
We just need that package JSON in there so that we can do
the npm installs.
We don't necessarily need it in dev, like I covered before.
Because in dev, I am going to bind mount, so I don't even
need the source code in my image because it will be ignored
when I do the bind mount.
I'm going to try to put it here.
I might be able to put it later.
I'm not really sure yet.
So, once my test image has done the npm
audit, and presumably some other test commands we
might have to add in later, I'm going to need to
remove those files.
I don't necessarily want to do them in a test image,
though, because I'm going to need them throughout the
image, and I don't want to end that image with the remove
command, because it'll screw up that image.
That image won't run properly in CI if doesn't have the
test stuff. So, I'm going to have to create some other
image here before I get to the production image.
I'm
going to have to pull it from the test and I want
to call it pre prod, I guess.
The way this is going to work is I'll do a run command in
here to remove the
files I need. So, let's do a
test, right.
That's what it said in the readme to remove that.
Then over here, I'm going to need to copy that source
code into the production image. I'm going to do a copy, but
I'm going to have to do a from and tell it what
stage.
So, we're going to do it from pre prod.
Then
I need to give it full paths.
What I've noticed is when I'm doing the copy command
with the from, doesn't necessarily obey my working
directory. So, I want to be more literal here and say app
app.
The other thing I know just from experience, really,
and doing this wrong the first couple of hundred times,
is that when I do it this way,
when I'm copying my source code out of a development
or testing situation, into my production image.
What I don't want in Node is to also copy that Node
modules, with all the unnecessary Node modules
from dev and test.
I have to remove that as well.
Running this here means that when I copy
this here, it will merge essentially what's already
in that base image, which includes the production Node
modules from base.
Then it's going to copy all the source code, but not the
test directory, and not the Node modules from my
dev/test image.
This right here is...it
could be considered an intermediate layer.
It's never used as its own
image to run. It's just there to help me clean up
some stuff before I copy it to a new image that is
then production.
Healthchecks should be added for production image.
That's a nice thing that I can add down here at the very
bottom.
cmd and cURL is in the image.
That is enough for now. I probably could make it fancier
and do the exit 1,
but really, it's just there as a basic
test just to validate that I have a container working.
Next, prevent repeating costly commands like npm
installs or apt-gets. I think I've done that pretty well.
I don't have any repeating commands here that are
unnecessary.
No unnecessary npm installs.
No unnecessary copy commands because I'm only copying in
once with the dot dot.
Then, I'm doing a little removal.
Only copy source code once.
Then copy from to get into other stages.
Well, I did that.
Maybe because I wrote these rules, I knew them before I
read them. All right.
Now what I'm going to do is we're going to skip bonus.
That's going to be in the next lecture.
I'm going to go straight to the outcomes.
I'm going to run through these different
commands and things that we need to do to make sure that
everything is as I would expect, and it builds and runs
as it should.
The first one on the list is build all stages as their own
tag. Ultimate node test should be bigger
than ultimate node prod.
All right. So, I'm going to call it ultimate node.
Let me get
back in the ultimate directory.
All right. So, let's do a docker build here.
We're going to tag it ultimate node.
We're going to
start with dev. I'm just going to do dev and then the test
image is in the prod, because that's sort of the flow
they're going to be in anyways. Target dev. OK.
It has successfully built the dev image, so I'm going to
just hit the up arrow and do this for
test. So, I'll change the target and I will change
the tag to test.
Now that I've done it for test, I'm going to do it for prod
as well.
Then, I'll do a docker image ls, and look at the three
outputs just to see the sizes.
The goal here, really, is that your prod image is the
smallest size.
So, your dev and your test will probably be pretty close
together because they'll have the same stuff except for the
source code, which will be in the test image,
but not in the dev image.
So, if you have lots of source code, then the test would be
the biggest one. Typically, that's what I expected.
Test has all the stuff it needs.
Basically, everything you could possibly want for testing
and production is going to be the smallest that I would
expect. These are working as I would hope.
All builds should finish. Well, definitely that one.
So,the first two are finished.
Run dev test prod images and ensure they can start as
expected. All right. So, these are just one-off
docker runs. So, I can do a docker run.
Because I ran this a while ago and knew
that it wouldn't control c, because this app is not aware
of Tini and doesn't capture signals, I'm going
to do an init here just to save me some time.
We called it ultimate node.
I'll
do the test one.
And it started. Now, it's going to wait for DB because I
didn't use Docker Compose, and that's normal.
I can control c out of that, and then
do the same thing for prod, which should not
be using nodemon.
All right. That looks good.
Then I could do a docker compose up
and see if everything works here.
All right. Once I see connected to DB, then
I can jump over to my browser.
Do the localhost 5000, or whatever
Node your Docker is running on and then
the result is 5001.
I can click on dogs and see dogs.
And click on cats and see cats.
All right. We're good to go there.
I've now done the first four, it looks like.
Build all stages. All builds should finish.
Run dev test prod images.
Docker compose up should work, and you can vote and see
results. Now, it says ensure prod images
don't have unnecessary files by running docker run
it. Okay. So, what I'm doing here is I'm
going to run an image, the production image,
manually and get a bash shell in it.
Then, I can dig
around. If you're familiar with
tools in Docker, there's a tool that's pretty cool called
Dive, D I V E.
So, check that tool out if you're interested
in a visual understanding of diving into
what is in an image.
This tool, Dive, does exactly that.
And it's a pretty good one. But I'm not going to show that
off. I'm really just going to do a simple docker run into
the bash, and then do a couple of ls's.
So docker run -it ultimate node prod
and then bash will give me a shell inside one of those
containers. I can do an ls
real quick.
I can see that I don't have
the test directory in here, which is a good sign.
Then if I do an ls of node modules/.bin.
Good. So, I don't see nodemon in there.
Part of the problem with a lot of these is that
once you get into production, your image
gets complicated enough that it's easy to accidentally put
stuff in the production image because your different build
stages are out of order, or maybe you don't have the
commands just quite right.
So, this is a really easy way to just dig around the
production image to figure out what's in here and what
isn't. Then after docker compose up, run
the docker compose exec result.
Test test to perform a functional test
across test containers.
All right. I'm just going to copy this command
out and paste it in.
So, I need to do a docker compose up first.
I'll do a -d so it runs in the background.
Then if I do a docker compose exec on the result service,
and then run the test command,
it'll take a minute for it to validate the tests.
If you go digging around, then it's
a shell script that's running from
the result against the vote and changing votes,
and then seeing if they show up in the result.
All right test passed. Great.
That's really it for this assignment.
For the bonus stuff, see the next lecture where I'll dig a
little bit more into the more advanced
stuff of this
assignment. Thanks for watching.