Hopefully you have finished the assignment.
Maybe you've checked out the assignment answers, and then
you've tried the bonus material.
The reason I put the bonus in here was it's relying on
two things. One is you've got to go back to previous
lectures earlier in the course, and depending on how fast
you're consuming all this content, it may have been days
ago, could have been weeks ago, that you did that stuff.
It's always hard to remember, and that's why I'm bringing
it back. You're definitely going to need
to repeat this stuff over and over to remember it long
term. So, here's another chance.
I'm glad you're checking out the bonus and you're
considering doing that yourself. Hopefully, you've tried
all that. You've gotten it to work, or maybe you got stuck,
and you're here for that reason.
That's all fine because this is, one part, going
back to those other videos, and the other part is doing
Internet research. A lot of these things, if you did it in
a previous video, you maybe didn't do it exactly the same
way as you'll do it here.
Or, maybe it's something that we only mentioned and didn't
practice in a previous video.
That's all good stuff because in the real world,
you are going to be doing stuff every day that you probably
have never done before. That's the life of tech, right.
Especially in DevOps where everything is new.
So, that's a good pattern to practice.
Here we go. I'm in the bonus area and the first
thing it tells me is security scanner.
We had a whole lecture on that earlier.
I'm going to go ahead and do the same thing as we did
before, only we're going to fit it in this Dockerfile we
just built. You've got the Dockerfile that you built
in the previous assignment answers.
We're just going to keep rolling through that.
We're basically building on that answer file.
Down here in the test
area, is where I probably want to put the scanner.
I could make it it's own, separate
stage. That way I could do code testing and not
security scanning.
And, you know, leave them a little bit flexible such you
choose one or the other when you build the image.
But, I'm just going to add it in here because it doesn't
require, in the readme, that I do it in a separate stage.
And since I'm going to use the MicroScanner, let me just go
to the Web and go find that GitHub repo.
Like all good GitHub repos, it's got the basic
use and install stuff right here in the page,
just like we used before.
In fact, if we go back to that previous lecture in
the course repo, I can probably cut and paste from there.
That example was in the multistage scanning
directory. The Dockerfile in there was a multistage
Dockerfile that had the MicroScanner included.
I'm going to copy and paste this out.
We're going need to change something.
You'll see it in a second that,
what's wrong with this line.
This is APK. This is for Alpine.
But, what are we using in this example?
We're using the Node slim.
Node slim is Debian based.
If it was going to be Alpine based, it would say Alpine
somewhere in the name or tag there.
We definitely can't use this line.
When you go back and look at the repo though, the repo
says, add ca-certificates if needed if you're on an apt-get
based distribution.
That's what we're using.
We just need to get the ca-certificates.
You might have remembered seeing that.
If we go back into the repo here and
scroll up in our Dockerfile, you'll notice that we
installed the ca-certificates already in dev.
That was for the dev dependencies.
It just so happens we'll get to use that again here, so we
don't even need this line.
We can take out the APK, and we don't need to add
back in an apt-get line because ca-certificates  is already
there. We're going to use an argument in
this case, which means we need to specify at the command
line. What I've done at the command line, just like in the
previous example, is I've created my own environment
variable, in my session, that stores
that key.
Then I don't need to specify that key every time.
I'll save this and we'll go run it and see if we can get
the test to build.
We're going to need to do a manual build here.
So a docker build.
I'm going to need to add in that build argument for the
MicroScanner. So, inside the Dockerfile is called
microscanner token.
On my host, I've set it as an environment variable,
just called microscanner. Your's might be different.
Then I need to tag it, so we'll just call it ultimate
node test. Then
I need to target it to the stage
test. Then I am building in this directory.
All right. My scanner ran, and worked,
and that's good.
Moving on. Back in the readme, the third line here is about
the best practices from that earlier section.
So, let's enable BuildKit and try again.
In order to use BuildKit, I could do something like
export the docker buildkit equals
1, but I could also just rerun that last command.
Then add in the beginning of it docker
buildkit equals 1.
Then, yep. You'll see that it is now using the new
interface to build that image.
I'll assume that's going to finish properly.
So, I'm going to go back over and check the next line.
Add Tini to images so containers will receive shutdown
signals. We could go look that up,
right. We could just do docker runs or docker compose and
manually add Tini in. But in this case, where you have
an app that doesn't have signals in it, it's not accepting
signals built into the code, Docker recommends that you
install Tini into the image as a permanent part of your
app, if you have no plans to update your app.
Because your users, people that might run this
container, or run Docker Compose, may forget to throw in
Tini. So, you want to make sure it's always
there and always working.
Let's go back to the browser and go
look up Tini.
Down here, there
is some install info.
What I'd want to do here is copy
this out, whatever version is the latest Tini version.
Then add it in my Dockerfile.
If I add it as an entry point up here
at the very root, then
it should be used in all future
stages. Which means, that the entry point
here, which essentially puts Tini on the front
of any of your cmds, will always be in front of the cmds of
future images.
So, we only have to put it in once.
It will, though, cause us to do a complete rebuild because
it'll bust the cache and require all future stages
to be built again. If we do that one more time, just hit
the up arrow, do the BuildKit.
All right. So, that built on the test with that new Tini in
there. Let's build and run the production version
with Tini, just to make sure it works as expected.
I'm going to change this to prod.
I'll change the tag to prod.
All right. That should have built pretty quickly because
BuildKit is more intelligent at caching the layers.
Now I can do a docker run, and I shouldn't need to run
--init. I can just run this ultimate
node prod.
Of course, it'll be waiting for the DB because it doesn't
have a DB be running in the background.
But, I can control c.
And on Mac and Linux, it will actually stop the container.
Remember on Windows, it doesn't actually stop it.
The way you could test this on Windows,
if you remember from the previous lecture, was you do a
docker stop, and the name, or ID, of the container,
and if it takes more than a few seconds, then you know you
have a problem with signals.
All right. Enable the non root Node user for all dev
prod images.
The next one after that is you might need root user for
testing or scanning images, depending on what you're doing.
This is an interesting conundrum.
In this case, we're going to be in the Dockerfile.
Let's say that up here at the top, I
would want to add the user Node.
Well, the problem with this is that any future
stuff, like this apt-get down here, wouldn't work because
it requires root.
So, maybe I shouldn't be putting user Node up at the top.
I should put it down closer to the bottom.
Ideally in development, I'm also running as user
Node. That way I find permission problems that are
potentially going to cause production problems.
So, let's go ahead and put that here
right before nodemon runs.
Unfortunately, that particular
line right there is not going to be passed into production.
So, we're going to need to repeat this line, but that's OK.
It's just a metadata line.
It's not a huge deal.
It's not going to slow down anything in the building.
It is not pure dry code, as
you would call it. But I think we should allow
it because it gets things working.
So, we're back down here user Node.
Then it will
change the user to that Node right before it starts.
So that means when the MicroScanner runs, it will run as
root. What's interesting, though, is we got another problem
here. At least I'm predicting a problem.
Is that the user Node up here in the dev is
going to be rolled into the test.
Which means, all these things will run as user
Node, including the MicroScanner.
The MicroScanner probably needs root.
I don't even know. I haven't checked, but most scanners
need authorization to see all the files in the file system,
and if they're not root, they usually can't do that.
Let's go see if this actually works.
I'm going to do my build again and do the production build.
Which in the case of our Dockerfile, we'll end up building
all stages, because it needs the test output
in order to get the files.
So, let's do that and see what happens.
There we go. All right. We're getting a chmod issue
because run can't change the mode, because
that normally requires root.
So, we are going to go back and forth a little bit.
We've got the user Node for the nodemon command here.
Down here, we're going to need to change user again to user
root.
Then that should mean this line will work properly.
That's okay that it's there.
It doesn't need to be set back to Node because we've
already got the Node down here in production.
All right. I'm just going to hit the up arrow and try again
with the prod image.
That time, the change mode worked.
And there we go. A successfully built file.
I'm going to hit the up arrow a couple of times back to
that docker run.
I'm going to run the production image just to make sure
that it does run as expected with the new user.
Here, you will see an interesting,
new area that we haven't talked about.
I kind of threw this in by accident
when I ran through the material initially.
But, then I realized this is a great example.
In Linux, you may not know that you can't run
non root applications on low ports.
So, by default you need to be root to have the permissions
to use port 80.
A port like 4000, or 3000, works
fine as a regular user.
But, those low ports are reserved for root only.
If you did some Googles, you would find out pretty quickly
that this needs root to run.
That doesn't mean we should be running our app as root in
the container. That doesn't mean we should back up and just
punt and say, I have to use the root
user. That's not true.
In the container, it doesn't really matter, in almost
all cases, what port we use.
Because if we're going to use it outside of that
Docker network, we're just going to publish it on whatever
port we want. So, it's going to do that translation.
Inside the container network, we are probably able to tell
other apps what port this is on.
So, we just need to go over and change the default port
it's using.
If we scroll up, of course, we have the expose here.
I'm just going to use 8080 in this case.
But, that doesn't change what the app listens on.
In this case, because it's a Node app, hopefully you can
dig into the Server.js and find that
the port, right here, is defined.
If you're not receiving a port as the configuration,
then it defaults to 80.
What we want it to do is run on 8080.
It'll default to that one.
Between that and the Dockerfile, let's try
to rebuild and run again.
Then I'll try to run the same image.
There we go. App is now running on port 8080.
It's waiting for DB.
If control c, or on Windows docker
stop. There we go.
Both of those things are working together.
That kind of wraps up the bonus here.
I hope you got through that. If you have time for the bonus
because I think a couple of those scenarios, down at the
end there, are pretty common dealing with going back and
forth between the Node user and the root user.
Dealing with low ports and Linux because a lot of people
may not realize that. That once they locked down the user
to non root, that they're restricted in that low port area.
They can't necessarily use the low ports.
That stuff is common in dealing with
Docker containers day to day.