Hello there, and welcome to this course,
AWS Developer: Serverless Architecture and Monitoring.
My name is Ryan Lewis,
and I'm excited to introduce you to some of the most
cutting‑edge technologies on the web today.
You've likely heard the buzzword serverless around the water cooler or
in the schedules of conferences around the world,
and I'm here to demystify much of the buzz around that term and guide you
through how to use serverless to your own ends in AWS.
In addition to new architecture patterns,
AWS has been innovating in the world of cloud application monitoring,
and you'll also learn in this course how to use services like
X‑Ray and CloudWatch to monitor your application,
lifecycle and health.
Let's take a look at how this course is structured.
This first module will explain what serverless is
and some of the history around it.
Then we'll cover some specifics of architecting a serverless application,
including what I call the four major pillars.
Finally,
we'll look at the demo project we'll be building in this course
and some of the tools you'll need to set up.
The next module will focus on using the compute side
of serverless with AWS Lambda.
There are some other courses on Pluralsight that go deep with Lambda,
so we're going to focus on security, stability,
and performance concerns.
The module after that will cover serverless event sources that
can trigger your lambda compute functions.
We'll look at using API Gateway for HTTP events and
Kinesis for messaging events.
In the last module, we'll go over how to monitor your applications in AWS.
We're going to configure X‑Ray to see how you can view the
entire serverless execution lifecycle,
and then we'll configure alarms in CloudWatch to alert you
if something happens to your application.
This is the last course in the AWS Certified Developer Associate path here,
at Pluralsight.
While this course can be watched on its own,
if you're planning to take the exam,
then I would recommend watching all the courses in order so
the knowledge you gain can build on itself.
This course is going to cover a lot of material in a pretty short time, so let's get started.