Serverless architecture involves many
interconnected resources working in concert.
Some of those resources will need to be located inside a virtual private cloud,
like your databases.
Connecting to a resource in a VPC requires some calculated forethought and
definitely adds some complexity to your architecture.
You will want some resources in your VPC to be
accessible from the outside world.
Take a lambda function, for example.
Our demo application has a lambda that returns a random trash panda.
That function is accessed through an API gateway endpoint.
The lambda function is inside the VPC,
but the API gateway endpoint is able to give access
to the lambda through the VPC.
So, to be a little bit more explicit,
API Gateways can connect to lambda functions that are inside
a VPC and allow access to the internet.
There are other resources in your serverless architecture that
you won't want to have public access to.
One example from our demo project is the RDS database instance.
These should be well protected from the outside world,
and RDS instances actually are required to be created inside a VPC in AWS.
In our demo project,
we have many lambda functions that read or write to the database instance.
Connecting resources in a VPC to resources not in a
VPC is a difficult problem to solve.
In the case of RDS instances,
one thing you could do is to make the RDS instance open to the public via the
instance configuration and configure the database security group to give
access to the security group used by the lambda.
While this should be fairly secure since the
security group is controlling access,
it means assigning a public IP address to the database instance.
Any time there is a public IP for a resource, it creates an attack vector.
For this reason, I'd recommend not adopting this approach.
The next approach is the simplest.
Just put the resources in the same VPC.
In the case of our lambda and RDS instance,
this gives the lambda instant access to the database and
avoids having the database open to the public.
The downside to this simple approach is that by putting the lambda in a VPC,
it cuts off the lambda's access to the public internet.
For many of the lambda functions in our demo project,
this is fine since the function only writes some data to
the database or returns some data.
With API Gateway providing the outside internet access to the lambda,
everything works fine.
But complications arise when you want your VPC‑located lambda
function to access a resource like DynamoDB or Kinesis.
These services and a few others in AWS use REST endpoints to communicate,
meaning that requests go out into the public internet.
If your lambda is cut off from the internet because it's in a VPC,
then communication to these services is cut off as well.
The third approach, which will resolve this issue,
is to properly configure your VPC to have internet access
by creating a NAT gateway resource.
Here's what that would look like.
You would create the NAT gateway in a public subnet inside your VPC.
Then, in the private subnets,
you would change the routing table rules to send all non internal
traffic to the NAT gateway for internet access.
This used to be the correct way to connect your non‑VPC resources together.
But a new service, AWS PrivateLink,
was just introduced at the end of 2017 and provides a better way to do this.
PrivateLink lets you create VPC endpoints that connect
to nearly all public AWS services, including services like DynamoDB and Kinesis.
The way this works is that you create an endpoint in your VPC
that connects to certain subnets and allows them to access AWS
service endpoints without leaving AWS.
This is much more secure and can sometimes be even faster.
You have to create an endpoint for each AWS service, and
that endpoint creates a network interface that gives
direct access to that AWS service.
Since PrivateLink was introduced,
it has become the preferred way to keep your AWS traffic
secure. In the next video, let's create a VPC endpoint to see how PrivateLink works.