There are many different events sources you can use in
AWS to trigger lambda invocations.
In this pattern, Lambda is really the brains,
and event sources are the appendages.
In this video,
we're going to take a look at all the different event types you have
available to you with serverless architecture in AWS.
The first is AWS IOT.
You can configure a lambda to be invoked when an IOT button is pressed.
IOT buttons are these little things you can purchase
from Amazon that connect to your Wi‑Fi.
Amazon first released them as dash buttons that would
order common household products for you.
The AWS IOT service also allows you to configure rules that evaluate
an IOT according to input from connected devices,
and these can also invoke lambdas when desired.
The next event source is API Gateway.
This is the most straightforward way to expose your lambdas to
be invoked in response to web‑based URLs.
API Gateway lets you configure URL paths that invoke
lambdas when they are accessed.
We'll get more into API Gateway later in this module.
Alexa is actually the event source with which I first tried out Lambda.
Using the AWS Alexa service,
whether triggered from an Amazon Echo device or an Amazon Smart Home device,
you can invoke a lambda that receives the event information,
such as what was said to the Echo device or what the
Smart Home device was instructed to do.
You can have a CloudFront distribution trigger a
lambda via the Lambda@Edge service.
There are some restrictions in place, like you can't use environment variables,
no dead‑letter queues, and the lambda won't be in a VPC.
Lambdas you would want invoked by CloudFront would likely be simple functions,
potentially just returning documents from S3 or a pure function.
Both CloudWatch Events and CloudWatch Logs can be
event sources for invoking lambdas.
Events triggering a lambda is a good way to set up a more complex flow
for when metrics of AWS resources might trip alarms.
With log sources, CloudWatch will search logs.
And when a log is delivered that matches a preconfigured pattern,
it will invoke the lambda and pass in the log entry.
You can invoke lambdas based on two types of streams, DynamoDB and Kinesis.
Both will deliver records as they're added to the streams. In Dynamo's
case, a stream is attached to a table, and records are sent down the
stream when they're created or updated in the table.
The records that come into your invoked lambda could be one or a
batch, and the delay between adding records to the stream and
the lambda invocation is very low,
usually only a couple of seconds. Modifications to an S3 bucket
can be configured as a trigger to invoke a lambda function.
When configuring the event source,
you set up what type of action you want to listen for and can
also set up object prefixes to restrict the invocation to
certain folders in your bucket.
The last two event sources are for Simple Notification Service or Simple
Queue Service. Like the Kinesis or DynamoDB streams, these events sources
will get records sent to them, and the lambda will be invoked as they appear.
As you can see, there are a lot of different ways you can invoke your lambda
functions, and each one of these events sources play a huge role when
designing a complete serverless application. For our demo application, we're
going to connect both API Gateway and Kinesis Stream event sources to make
the Trash Panda Buffet game completely function. In the rest of this module, let's get started on making that happen.