CloudWatch alarms are really useful for ensuring your application
isn't going off the rails without you being aware.
The CloudWatch service is flexible enough that you can do more than
just send a notification if an alarm is tripped.
It can even execute lambdas to do basically anything.
So let's take a look at how we could use CloudWatch to
monitor our serverless application.
One of the challenges with serverless applications is the number of
resources that may be created and keeping track of all of them.
What if one lambda is failing and you aren't aware?
It's never good to have blind spots in your application.
With CloudWatch,
we can ensure all corners of our distributed
application are constantly monitored.
Pull up your AWS console and go to the CloudWatch service.
CloudWatch serves a lot of purposes, like events and logs,
but today we really only care about alarms.
Click on the Alarms menu option and then the Create alarm button.
First, we'll select a metric, so click Select metric.
You'll be presented with some metric categories based on
the services that you're using in AWS.
In the search bar, type lambda and hit Enter.
You'll see that you're able to select metrics across all
functions or metrics on specific named functions.
If there was a specific function we wanted special alarms on,
we could do it directly.
What I prefer to do though is set an alarm for all lambda functions.
That way, we can avoid those blind spots in our application.
In this case, let's set up an alarm for errors.
Select the Lambda > Across All Functions group.
Then, select the metric Errors.
Click Select metric.
Scroll to the Conditions section.
Setting the error threshold count for when to trigger
our alarm is essentially a balance.
We want the alarm to trigger when it's meaningful,
but not trigger it so often that we just end up ignoring it.
It'll depend on the application.
But for this video, let's just put 5 here.
The operator of greater than is perfect.
In the above metric section is the period.
It's set to 5 minutes.
So with this complete configuration,
it means that if we have greater than 5 errors within 5 minutes,
the alarm will trigger.
By adjusting this period to a shorter time length,
the alarm would likely fire less, but this is fine.
Now click Next.
Here, we'll configure how CloudWatch should react to an alarm,
such as notifications or scaling.
In our case, we're interested in the SNS notifications.
If you'll remember from previous videos,
you can have lambdas be invoked from an SNS topic.
This means that although the first idea that might come
into your head for SNS is to notify you,
you could also have it trigger a lambda invocation that
actually does something to resolve the issue.
In this case, we don't really have enough information about
what type of errors to expect to really do anything about
them, so notifications is fine.
You can connect this to an existing topic or create a new one. Then click Next.
We can finally name the alarm, so let's call it lambda_error_alarm
with dashes in between the words. Click Next. And then after
reviewing the alarm details, Create alarm.
The alarm will immediately go into insufficient data status as it takes
some time to actually create the alarm and get data in there. After a few
minutes, it will either move to okay status or alarm status based on if the
error threshold has been triggered.
Let's take a look at one more type of metric that you can create an alarm
for. Click the Create alarm button and then Select metric. And then click
the API Gateway box and finally the By Stage box.
There are several metrics here that you can set alarms on for your
APIs. The lowest level you can set alarms for is the stage level,
but I think having metrics on 400 or 500 errors or latency are
actually pretty valuable.
We could keep adding alarms all day, but let's just end it there.
It's useful to explore the available metrics you have for each AWS
service you use so you can ensure your entire application is being well
monitored. In the next video, we're going to spend down all the resources we've used for our demo application.