Most lambda event sources are from inside AWS,
like Kinesis Streams or CloudWatch Events.
You don't need to authenticate the caller because it's AWS itself.
With API Gateway, especially with lambda proxies,
you're getting traffic from who knows where.
If you don't have some type of authentication in place,
you're opening up your application to attack.
API Gateway has preempted this type of vulnerability by building in
the ability to use authorizers on your endpoints.
These can be either custom lambda functions that you've built yourself,
Cognito integration to let it manage users,
or IAM integration.
An authorizer is a little different than something that does authentication.
Ultimately,
the authorizer should return an AWS IAM policy saying
what the caller can and cannot do.
If you use the authorizer like an authenticator,
you can return a deny all or an accept for specific
services based on some initial endpoint,
like a header or cookie.
For our demo application,
we're going to configure a custom lambda function authorizer.
Take a look in the code base in the src/lambda folder at the game.js file.
At the bottom, there's a verify function being exported.
This function looks at the gameId query parameter on the event,
then retrieves the game from the database,
and then returns an unauthorized payload if it isn't found.
If it is found, it returns an authorized payload.
We're going to use this function to slightly
authenticate our sendAction endpoint.
I say slightly because to truly authenticate,
we'd want to lock down all the endpoints and use
something like a cookie‑based system.
This slight authentication should be plenty to
demonstrate how API Gateway authorizers work.
If you want to see what the authorizer payloads look like,
go one more step down into the lib folder and open the response.js file.
At the bottom are two functions, authorized and unauthorized.
These return that JSON that API Gateway is looking for,
specifically a principalId, aka an ID for the user who made the call,
and a policy document saying what the user can do.
You could make the principalId unique or meaningful,
but user is fine for our purposes.
The policy document is what changes.
In the authorized function,
you'll see it says the user is allowed to invoke any API,
specifically an API Gateway endpoint, The
unauthorized function says the opposite.
It's denying that access.
The authorizer returns these payloads according to some input,
and then the API Gateway endpoint processes it to determine whether the
user should or should not be able to invoke the endpoint.
In this way,
we're giving and denying access based on the existence of a valid gameId.
Now let's set up this authorizer in API Gateway.
With the trash‑panda‑buffet API selected, go to the Authorizers section.
Click the Create New Authorizer button.
For the name, enter gameId_authorizer.
For the type, ensure Lambda is selected.
In the Lambda Function input, make sure your region is selected,
and select the gameVerify function.
With the event payload, you could use a header token,
but we'll be looking at query parameters instead,
so select Request.
Then click the drop‑down that says Header and select Query String instead.
In the input box, enter gameId in camelCase.
This is the query string parameter it'll pass into your authorizer.
The authorization caching works based on the same identity source being passed.
This means if another request comes in with the same gameId,
it'll cache the authorization result.
This is enabled automatically and will cache for 5 minutes based on this TTL.
This may not be the behavior you want in your application, but we can leave it
enabled here. Now click Create and then Grant & Create. Our authorizer is
created now, and if you want to test it out, click this Test link and enter
something to pass in as a gameId. Because it's probably not a valid gameId, you
should get a response code of 200. And in the last log message, it should say
that it's using your valid authorizer policy. The policy in question is here
and has the Invoke API action denied. So your authorization test was
successful, and if a request had come in with that gameId, it would have denied
it access to the endpoint because it wasn't valid. Now let's hook this
authorizer up. We first need to refresh the page so our resources will load in
the new authorizer as an option and then go to Resources and the action POST.
Click the Method Request box again and then the pencil next to Authorization.
In this drop‑down, you should see the gameId authorizer we just created. Select
that and click the check button.
The last step is to deploy these changes. So, click the
Actions drop‑down and select Deploy API. Then, select the
dev stage and then click Deploy.
Now, at least one of our API endpoints is doing some slight
authentication, so we're on the right track to have a more
secure API. To complete this,
you could add the same authorizer to any endpoint that
gets a gameId as a query perimeter.
Next, let's take a look at a different type of event source for serverless applications.