When AWS runs your lambda function,
it is running it on servers somewhere in its
infrastructure despite the serverless nomenclature.
And really,
these servers are actually EC2 instances, meaning they're running on a
virtual machine that matches one of the EC2 instance types.
If you want to run your lambda function on beefier hardware,
you have a single parameter you can use to make that change, memory.
Each lambda is configured with a certain memory allocation.
If you take a look at the general configuration for your lambda function,
there is an input box where you can enter the amount of memory you
want your function to have access to. This value not only affects
the memory available to your function,
but it also affects the CPU resources available to that function. As you
increase the memory, the CPU also increases proportionally.
The exact CPU being provisioned isn't published,
but just the equation of more memory equals more CPU
should be easy enough to remember.
So, if the execution time of your lambda is higher than you'd like, consider
raising the allocated memory to get some better hardware.
When AWS is running your lambda function and gets another invocation,
it runs both concurrently. Again,
Amazon is handling the infrastructure and configuration
for how all this works, so you don't need to worry about
how the concurrency happens.
You do, however, need to be aware of how many lambdas are running concurrently.
The reason for this is that AWS has limits on how many concurrent
lambdas can run at a time in a single account.
It's a soft limit, so it can be raised. But it's really there to help you from
unintentionally being driven to the poor house from lambda executions. Because
you're charged by the millisecond of lambda execution time, a limit on the
number of concurrent lambda invocations means there is a finite maximum cost
that you can be billed for. If, for some reason, you have a rogue lambda running
like crazy, these are guard rails to help you out. You have even more control
over concurrency.
In the Concurrency section of a function configuration,
you can see settings for reserving concurrent executions.
This is both reserving the concurrency,
ensuring its available to this lambda in the event that other
functions are also executing concurrently, and also setting a limit to
the maximum number of concurrent invocations for this lambda. In the
event that limit is reached, the lambda will retry the invocation for
a certain number of times.
If the invocation retry limit is reached,
the event will be sent to a dead‑letter queue. In a previous video, we saw the
throttle graph in the Monitoring section of your lambda.
If a lambda invocation is stopped because a concurrency limit was hit,
then that means that run was throttled.
This throttle metric is available through CloudWatch so you can set
an alarm to notify you if a lambda begins to get throttled a lot,
meaning it might be time to up your concurrency limit. In that same
concurrency configuration,
you can also add configuration for provisioned concurrency.
This is designed to reduce what we call the cold start latency,
which is when your lambda function is being invoked for the first time in a
while and the environment is booted up on an instance.
This doesn't usually take that long,
just a few seconds. But provisioned concurrency will ensure
that your lambda code is always ready to run.
There is an additional cost to this, as you can imagine. So, keep that in mind if you decide to configure it and enable it.