The power of serverless architecture in AWS is mostly due to the many
number of events sources and what you can do with them. With things
like S3 events, Streams, API Gateway,
CloudWatch Events, and even just invoking lambdas directly via the AWS
SDK, you can create fully functioning applications without managing
any servers and with minimal infrastructure. I think we have yet to
see how far the industry will push this pattern, and the future is
only looking brighter.
Let's review what we learned in this module.
We started out the module looking at how VPCs work with serverless architecture
and created a VPC endpoint to connect to Kinesis Streams.
Next, we looked at all the different types of events sources in
AWS and set one up by configuring an endpoint in API Gateway.
Security is essential for any application.
So, I also showed you how to configure a custom authorizer for API Gateway
endpoints. And since API Gateway is an example of a push event source, we then
configured a lambda to consume Kinesis Stream events,
which is an example of a pull event source. And that's all of the
serverless architecture‑specific content in this course.
In the next module, we're going to look at tools and best
practices for monitoring your applications,
including setting up X‑Ray for tracing requests and CloudWatch alarms for monitoring application health. See you in the next module.