Time for our first demo.
In this demo,
what we're going to do will include creating the first
CloudFormation stack by implementing AuroraStack.yml,
that you will find in the folder you downloaded from my GitHub repository.
If you missed the module entitled Download and Install Course Prerequisites,
revisit that module and follow the instructions.
What the AuroraStack.yml script will do is it will set up the
entire infrastructure that we're going to use in this course that
has to do with relational databases.
Once the AuroraStack is running,
we're going to review the CloudFormation stack's parameters,
resources, and outputs.
And then we're going to navigate around the AWS console to confirm all the
resources that our AuroraStack was supposed to create,
and confirm that yes, they are indeed created.
Navigate to where you downloaded the code assets from my GitHub repository that
are all in a folder entitled ETLAnalyticsUsingGlue-master.
Double-click on it, and at the top of the list, you'll see AuroraStack.yml.
That's the first code-related asset we're going to use in this course.
Login to your AWS Management Console.
Take note, in order to run this analytical workflow,
you must be in either US West 2 Oregon or US East 2 Ohio regions only.
Start typing in the search bar CloudFormation, and when you see it, click on it.
This opens the CloudFormation console.
If you don't have any CloudFormation stacks created
yet in the region you selected, your screen will look just like mine.
Click on the top button that reads Create Stack.
In the Select Template window, click the button that reads Design template.
By choosing this method over upload,
we can visually see the CloudFormation stack being
created and what the configurations are.
This opens the CloudFormation Stack Designer window.
Before we open our AuroraStack.yml script,
there's a couple of things we need to do first.
At the bottom of the new.template window,
there's two tabs, Components and Template.
Be sure Template is chosen,
and then at the upper-right portion of the new.template
window that reads Choose template language,
change it from JSON to YAML.
In the CloudFormation Designer menu bar at the top,
look for the little file icon that when hovered over reads File,
and click Open to open a template.
Choose Local file, and navigate to the folder ETLAnalyticsUsingGlue-master.
Choose AuroraStack.yml, and double-click on it to open it.
I think what just happened here is really cool.
Simply by importing a script file,
CloudFormation created an architectural diagram in the Designer window,
which essentially is your infrastructure architecture.
The Designer window is pretty awesome.
Let's open this up a little bit.
If you hold down your left-mouse button,
you can move the architectural diagram around in the Designer window.
You can also zoom in and zoom out.
That's really handy when you have a very large CloudFormation
template with a lot of AWS resources being defined.
Let me open up the template window a little bit.
Another cool thing is if you click on any of the services in the diagram,
for example, for the AuroraCluster,
the script jumps to the line of code that defines
that resource and its dependencies.
CloudFormation is one of those services that's really
easy to learn backwards-forwards.
AWS has a number of pre-build CloudFormation templates,
and if you load them into the Designer window and scroll
around in the either JSON or YAML script,
you can see how everything is defined and the dependencies between them.
So now that our template is loaded,
it's time to validate the template to ensure there's no errors.
Go back up to the CloudFormation menu bar,
and go to the little checkbox that when hovered over reads Validate template.
You're going to have to watch real close because any
notifications about the Validate template process will be shown
right about here in the middle of this bar,
so I'm going to click it, Validating the template,
Template is valid, gone, that would be really easy to miss.
Now that the template is valid,
look for the little cloud icon in the CloudFormation Designer menu
bar that when you hover over it reads Create stack.
Click on it to return to the Create stack process.
This brings you back to the Select Template page.
But if you notice, under Choose a template,
the radio button is selected that reads Specify an Amazon S3 template URL.
That's because CloudFormation by default saves your template
automatically in an S3 bucket in your account.
Click on Next, and in the Stack Details page,
give your stack the name AuroraStack.
Scroll down to the Parameters, Network Configuration, MyIP address.
This is where you paste in your IP address that I
asked you to find in the last section.
Paste in your IP address.
Notice that AWS wants you to append your IP address with /32,
so please do that now.
If you scroll down a little bit more, under Amazon Aurora Configuration,
notice that the AuroraDBUsername and the AuroraDBPassword are pre-populated.
That's because those values were passed into the stack
creation process and input parameters.
Click on Next, and in the Options page,
you can leave everything as is and click on next.
This opens the Review page.
The Review page gives you a chance to look over the
configurations to ensure that the CloudFormation stack that
you're creating has the right information.
Then click on Create.
After clicking Create, you'll be in the CloudFormation stack monitoring screen.
You probably have to click the Refresh button to see anything being provisioned.
And right here, our AuroraStack is being provisioned.
It has a Status of CREATE_IN_PROGRESS.
If you click on the Stack Name,
that brings you into the Stack Detail page where you can
look at the events to see what is happening as everything
is provisioned and configured.
Return back to the Stacks,
and if you check the little checkbox that's to the left of the AuroraStack row,
you can then look at quite a number of tabs that hold different information.
This lets you expand that lower section with all the tabs.
I encourage you to click through all of those tabs
when you have your stack running,
so that you become familiar with all the information
that's given to you in those tabs.
Click on the Resources tab.
If you have the Resources tab open,
you can scroll through and see some of the resources that
the CloudFormation stack is provisioning.
Occasionally,
it's a good idea to click again on the Refresh button because
you'll see more resources created from time to time.
Just looking at all of these resources,
aren't you glad that we didn't manually configure all of these?
It's really worth the time to learn about CloudFormation.
CloudFormation is infrastructure as code,
and there's a lot of companies that have their entire global information and
configuration in AWS defined in a CloudFormation stack because they can just
replicate it in a new office whenever that happens.
It's very convenient.
Once your AuroraStack shows the Status CREATE_COMPLETE,
everything is provisioned and up and running in your account.
Now, we're looking at the Resource page here,
and everything here can be mapped to the AuroraStack.yml script.
If you click on Outputs,
Outputs in CloudFormation can be used as inputs to other CloudFormation stacks,
which is exactly what we'll do when we launch our
Glue stack in an upcoming module.
If you click on the Parameters tab,
you'll see the values that were input into the CloudFormation
creation process via the AuroraStack.yml script,
or in the case of MyIP, we input that parameter in the stack creation process.
It's a good idea to open up something like Notepad,
a plain text editor, in the AuroraStack.yml script,
and copy in the connection values that are in the CloudFormation stack screen.
All of the connection information values are in the Outputs tab.
So copy the AuroraClusterEndPoint, paste it into Notepad,
and then copy in your AuroraDBUsername and AuroraDBPassword.
The username is here, copy that, and paste it into this document.
The password is the AuroraClusterPassword.
So copy that, and paste that in, and save it.
This way,
we have everything convenient when we're connecting with our third-party SQL
client to the running Amazon Aurora database in the AWS cloud.
I'm going to minimize that, and maximize this.
So in the Resources tab,
there's quite a few resources in there that are really important,
and it's a good idea to navigate to each service's
console so that you can validate that yes,
these resources are created, and they're up and running.
Let's look at the AuroraDB and Cluster first.
If you go up to the AWS dark menu bar, and you click on the drop-down,
you can choose the Services from here, but if you just click on them,
what's going to happen is you'll have to go back and forth in the browser,
and it's really hard to remember where you're at,
or I should say it's really easy to get lost.
So the way that I like to do this is scroll down to
the resource that I want to look at,
and in this case it's a relational database service,
and if you right-click on it, you have the option to open the link in a new tab.
It's much easier to have multiple tabs open when you have a lot of AWS
resources that you're working with at the same time,
and then you just go from tab to tab.
So I'm going to say Open link in new tab,
and here it's coming up, and then click on it.
This is the Amazon Relational Database service console.
If we want to see if we have an Aurora database running, click on Databases.
So we do have our AuroraCluster running.
If we click on the name of either one of these,
you get more detail about each one you click on.
For example, under the tab Connectivity and security,
you can see that there is 2 endpoints, and if you click on Monitoring,
Amazon Aurora has some Amazon CloudWatch metrics enabled by default.
So if we had this cluster running for a long time,
these charts would be much more interesting.
But I'm going to leave it to you to click around in the consoles that
I'll be showing you now with our resources running because it's a really
good way to find out what's connected to what.
AWS does a great job of having links in various consoles that link together all
the different services because AWS believes in primitives,
not frameworks.
What that means is that there's a lot of little LEGO
pieces around that you have to build with,
and it can be confusing especially if you're starting.
In reality,
it's the best way to build anything really because your creativity is unlimited,
what you do with the individual LEGO pieces allows for a lot of innovation,
rather than getting the whole kitchen sink in a framework,
where you're forced to use what the creators of the
framework thought you needed.
Now that we confirmed the cluster is running,
let's now go back up to Services,
and then right-click on S3 and Open a link in a new tab.
If you go to S3, and filter by Date created,
you'll see that this bucket is where CloudFormation
is holding our template code.
Go back up to Services again, and right-click on EC2,
Open link in new tab, we can see in the EC2 console,
if you click on Security Groups under NETWORK and SECURITY,
we have an AuroraStack security group.
If you click the button next to the name,
you have information that you can scroll through again on
your own time when you're building this,
and I suggest that you do that.
If you click on Network Interfaces,
you can see that we have a network interface associated
with the Security Group AuroraStack.
And this is a great example of where AWS gives you links
to move around between the services,
and it also contains a lot of other useful information.
Now if you go up to Services and start typing in VPC for virtual private cloud,
when it comes up, click on it.
This is the VPC console or dashboard.
You can see here that we have 1 VPC up and running,
and it has a lot of information that you can scroll through,
and you can go down to where the tabs are,
you can click on the Route table that was configured,
the Network ACL, or access control list,
etc.
You can also click on the CIDR Blocks and more,
and I encourage you to do that on your own.
If you click on Subnets, we have two subnets,
and they are associated with our AuroraCluster.
So if you click on Route Table, you will see that there's an internet gateway,
as well as a VPC endpoint.
And again,
click around in here because it's really cool how everything fits together.
You can also just click on Route Tables from the left menu,
and the top one says it has 2 subnets.
It has route tables that's connected to 2 subnets,
and you can click around at the Subnet Associations,
the Routes, and more, and I encourage you to do that.
If you click on Internet Gateways, you get more information again.
If you click on Endpoints, we do have an Aurora endpoint.
Returning back to the CloudFormation stack page for our AuroraStack,
we've now confirmed that these resources are up and running,
so it's time to connect to our AuroraStack from our third-party SQL client.
Open up your third-party SQL client.
I'm using MySQL Workbench.
If you already have a third-party SQL client,
you're already familiar on how to connect to a database,
but I'm going to walk through these steps.
It's a good idea to have side by side your third-party SQL client taking up
part of this screen and the text file that you copied the connection
information into on the other side of the screen.
So the first thing is we click on database, and you choose Manage Connections.
Click on New, you can use any Connection Name that you want,
I chose Kimmys_pluralsight_aurora_demo, okay,
that's so Kim, like why couldn't I just call it whatever?
I mean, call it whatever, but I have to pick this big, long, hairy name, ha-ha.
Under the Hostname, if you get rid of the default value that's there,
and copy your AuroraClusterEndPoint, and paste that into the Hostname field,
and then in the Username, put in the AuroraDBUsername,
and MySQL Workbench doesn't prompt for a password
until you actually try to connect.
For now, let's click on Test Connection, and it's asking me for my password.
So copy it and paste it in the Password field, and then click on OK.
You get a popup that sounds like an error to me,
but what it is saying, if you look at the bottom paragraph,
it reads a successful MySQL connection was made with the
parameters defined for this connection.
So click OK, and then simply close this.
And we can get rid of the text document now, and maximize MySQL Workbench.
Now we go back up to Database, and we say Connect to Database.
MySQL Workbench will have the Connect to Database popup
reconfigured with the connection that you just defined.
So click on OK.
It's opening the SQL editor, and when it opens,
we don't have anything in here yet,
we are connected to our Aurora database in the cloud because
we successfully connected in the last step.
So the first thing we have to do is give our Aurora database a schema.
Go up to File, and then choose Run SQL Script,
and in your folder, ETLAnalyticsUsingGlue-master,
there was a sakila-db ZIP file, and if you unzip it,
you have two SQL scripts, one for the schema and one for the data.
So choose the schema now.
That opens the Run SQL script popup window where you can
scroll through to see what's being defined,
and I encourage that you do that.
So I'm just going to click Run,
and the Run SQL Script window reads at the bottom,
Operation completed successfully.
So I'm going to close this.
Now what you have to do in the Navigator left pane is click
on the Refresh button next to SCHEMAS, and there's our sakila schema.
We expand this,
we're going to be doing things with the film table and the film_category table.
Just to confirm that we do indeed have a schema,
type in use sakila, highlight it, and execute it.
And if you look at the bottom in the Output,
it shows that it ran successfully, but 0 rows were affected,
and that's because we just have a schema,
we don't have data.
So, let's confirm that.
If we run a simple select query on the film table,
and highlight it, and execute the query,
we get exactly what we should if all we have is a schema.
We have the table names, we have the column names for each table,
but there's no data, everything is null.
So what we need to do is go back up to File,
and click on Run SQL Script, and this time we're going to choose sakila-data.
The Run SQL Script dialog comes up again,
which you can scroll through, and then click Run.
We're watching the script running, And again,
at the bottom it reads Operation completed successfully.
So now we can close this, and let's run this again and see what we get.
Voila, we have data.
What you're looking at in this sakila database are the
favorite films of the NBA players.
So you can see the columns that the film table has,
let's now look at the film_category table and see what's there.
Execute this query, and voila, we have data again.
The film_category table only has three columns.
If you look, it has a last_update column,
and so does the film table, and both tables have film_id,
but the film_category has a category_id that the film table doesn't have.
So we're going to do a join of the film and the film_category table.
This SQL statement is included in your course assets folder if
you don't want to just manually type it in.
If you select it all and execute it, alright, we have data again.
If you scroll to the right, you can see that the two tables were joined.
The table has two last_update columns, one from each table,
and we've got the category_id, which is what we wanted to get through the join.
Through our third-party SQL client,
we connected to the Amazon Aurora database in the AWS cloud remotely,
and we populated the Aurora database with a schema and data.
In another module,
I'll show you how to do this using state-of-the-art methodologies.
We'll use AWS Glue crawlers to crawl this Aurora database,
and then put the schema and statistics into the Glue Data Catalog.
Once the crawler does the work for us,
we'll use an AWS Glue job to perform an ETL transformation,
joining the film and film_category tables just like we did here,
but in a much easier time-saving way.
In the next section,
we'll review in a little more detail our AuroraStacks resources, outputs, and parameters.