In this section, I'll explain exactly what AWS Glue is and how it works.
So what is AWS Glue?
The emergence of unstructured and semi-structured data produced
new problems of performing ETL on non-relational data that's
necessary to do prior to analysis.
Glue is a fully-managed ETL service that solves that business problem.
As a side note, I'm sure many of you have heard of not ETL, but ELT.
That's the way data is transformed today using a service like AWS Glue.
Today, we don't extract, transform, and load,
but in an S3 data lake, you keep raw data so you can go back to it at any time,
thus what's happening now is extract, load,
and then transform.
Looking at this diagram,
you can see some of the many different types of data
sources we're working with today.
With Glue's ETL on the fly,
you now can load the raw data regardless of the type or where the physical
location of the underlying data store is into Amazon S3.
You connect to your various heterogenous data stores,
you can run Glue ETL at any time in this workflow,
which in this diagram is after data arrives in S3,
but it can be performed at any point in this workflow.
Glue crawlers crawl all your data stores,
determines the schema,
then populates the Glue Data Catalog with that schema and
other metadata necessary to reconstruct the database when
it's ready to be used for analytics.
Most often, after you have the results of your data analysis,
it's common to visualize the information.
In this diagram, the visualization is done with Amazon Quicksight,
but you can use any visualization tool you like.
Let's now look at how Glue works.
To crawl the data source, you simply point a Glue crawler at the source data,
and the crawlers populate your Glue Data Catalog with enough
metadata and statistics to reconstruct the source data when you
request that data to be used in analytics.
Glue jobs perform the ETL on the raw data in an Amazon S3 data lake.
During the ETL process, many different types of transformations can be done.
Once the ETL is complete,
the Glue job puts the transform data into wherever you specify,
which is called a target data source.
You can run jobs on demand,
or you can set up triggers to automatically start a job
whenever certain criteria are met.
Triggers can be time based or event based.
When your job runs,
an automated script written in either Python or Scala
extracts the data from your data source,
transforms it, and loads the transformed data into the data target.
AWS Glue solves the business problems that come with the
need for analyzing heterogenous data types,
which in the past was laborious and very time consuming.
Glue provides one centralized location for literally all your company data,
thereby solving the common business problem of globally scattered data silos.
The AWS Glue Data Catalog is a central repository to store structural
and operational metadata for all your data assets,
even from on premises.
The AWS Glue crawlers connect to data stores to extract the
schema and other statistics about the data.
Then it populates the Glue Data Catalog with this metadata.
Glue eliminates dark data.
Dark data is information assets organizations collect,
process, and store during regular business activities,
but generally failed to use it for other purposes.
It's not used in any manner to drive insights or for decision making,
but hiding in those modes of dark data might be pivotal
to a solution today or in the future.
Glue automatically generates the ETL code necessary
to extract data from the source, transform the data to match the target schema,
and load it into the target by pointing to your data source and target,
making it easy to prepare and load data for analytics.
There are many other types of transformations that
can be done during the ETL process.
Glue has a flexible job scheduler.
Glue jobs perform the ETL processing.
They can be invoked on a schedule, on demand, or based on an event.
You can start multiple jobs in parallel or specify dependencies
across jobs to build complex ETL pipelines.
Glue handles all inter-job dependencies,
filters out bad data, and retries jobs if they fail.
Glue has monitoring built in,
all logs and notifications are pushed to Amazon CloudWatch,
so you can monitor and get alerts from one central service.
So what's so cool about AWS Glue?
The title on this slide gives you one primary advantage,
it allows different people to work on the same data at the same time,
but using different tools of their choice for
analytics to solve different problems,
and since you're working on the metadata for the
database in the Glue Data Catalog,
the underlying source database isn't touched at all.
One of AWS Glue's core values is not only having
all data in one central location,
but that there's native integration with all AWS' and
third-party business intelligence tools.
There's native integration with all of AWS' and
third-party artificial intelligence, machine-learning,
and deep-learning tools.
This benefits the company as a whole because anyone with any role
that works with company data can use their favorite business
intelligence and/or advanced analytics tools on the same data in an
Amazon S3 data lake simultaneously.
In the next section, I'll go over what Amazon Athena is, what it does, and the business problems it solves.