I thought it would be interesting to go over what's in the
Python script before we create the GlueStack.
By doing this,
you'll have a good bird's eye perspective on why all of
those Glue assets are created because ultimately they all
lead to the ETL transformations.
So if you right-click on the Python script,
many times you'll have an integrated developer environment
named IDLE that comes with Python packages,
and then you can just hover over the name of the Python
script and choose Edit with IDLE, and it opens up this Python editor.
If you have another third-party Python editor,
that'll work just fine, as long as you can open up and read the Python script.
If you don't have anything, just search in Google for Python IDLE,
and down the IDE.
So what we're doing here,
we are initializing the Glue job for ETL transformation.
We are then creating DynamicFrames for the tables that we want to join.
We have the sakila_film table, the sakila_film_category table,
and then what we're going to do is create a third
DynamicFrame to hold the join of the two tables.
And then in this section, we're just stating the primary and secondary keys,
and in this section we're just saying where to put the
output of the transformation in Amazon S3,
so that is the join transformation.
And then in this last part,
we do another transformation where we convert the
data that is the result of the join.
WE change the data type to Parquet format,
so that in the processed S3 zone,
the data will be in a format ready to be used in various analytic services like Amazon Athena.