In this section, I'll go over Amazon Athena,
what it is, what it does, and what business problems it solves.
So what is Amazon Athena?
Amazon Athena is an interactive query service that makes it
easy to analyze data directly in Amazon S3.
With Athena,
there's no need for complex ETL jobs to prepare your data for analysis.
This makes it easy for anyone with SQL skills to
quickly analyze large-scale datasets.
Amazon Athena uses Presto,
an open-source distributed SQL query engine optimized for
low-latency ad hoc analysis of data.
You can use Athena to run ad hoc queries using ANSI SQL without the
need to aggregate or load the data into Athena,
with full support for large joins, window functions,
and arrays.
Athena helps you analyze unstructured, semi-structured,
and structured data stored in Amazon S3.
Examples include SVC, JSON,
or columnar data formats such as Apache Parquet and Apache ORC.
Athena is fast, really fast.
Beep-beep.
You don't have to worry about having enough compute resources
to get fast interactive query performance.
Amazon Athena automatically executes queries in parallel,
so most of the results come back within seconds,
even for large datasets or complex queries.
With Amazon Athena,
you don't have to worry about managing or tuning
clusters to get fast performance.
Athena is optimized for fast performance with Amazon S3.
Amazon Athena is highly available and executes queries using
compute resources across multiple facilities,
automatically routing queries appropriately if a
particular facility is unreachable.
Amazon Athena integrates out of the box with AWS Glue.
With the Glue Data Catalog,
you'll be able to create a unified metadata repository across various services,
crawl data sources to discover and populate your Data Catalog with
new and modified table and partition definitions,
and maintain schema versioning.
You can also use Glue's fully-managed ETL capabilities to
transform data or convert it into columnar formats to optimize
query performance and reduce costs.
This conceptual diagram illustrates Athena's concepts in action.
An AWS Glue crawler crawls the raw dataset in an S3 raw zone bucket.
The crawler writes metadata into the AWS Glue Data Catalog.
You query those raw datasets in Athena.
Athena uses schema definition to read raw datasets
from S3 and then returns the results.
Athena solves the business problems associated with querying
heterogenous data without the need to first perform ETL.
Insights can be extracted immediately from any data and acted upon in real time.
Athena is an interactive query service.
This makes it easy to analyze data directly in S3 using standard SQL.
Athena can process unstructured, semi-structured, and structured datasets.
Athena is serverless, there's no infrastructure to manage what so ever.
Athena scales automatically,
giving fast results even with large datasets and complex queries.
Athena executes queries in parallel, so results are returned in seconds.
Athena can query encrypted data in S3 and write
encrypted data back to another S3 bucket.
In the next section, I'll introduce you to Globomantics,
an NBA trivia provider,
that's having technical problems that we can solve with AWS Glue and Amazon Athena.