In this section,
I'm going to walk you through what we're going to be doing in the next demo.
Now that we have the Parquet-formatted data in the S3 target zone bucket,
it needs to be crawled in order to populate the Glue Data Catalog
with the data that has the transformations.
The first step that we need to do is add a new crawler to
crawl the transformed Parquet data.
You're looking at the Add crawler window where you give the crawler a name.
I called mine s3_film_cat_crawler because to me,
that's descriptive of what the crawler is going to do.
On the left are the series of steps that are necessary to add a new crawler.
We have to set a data source for the crawler to crawl.
So in the Add a data store window,
we're going to choose S3 from the drop-down list,
and we're going to choose for the Include Path when you choose the little
folder icon in the left image surrounded by a red rectangle,
and you choose S3, all of your S3 buckets will appear in a popup.
The screenshot on the right is the popup that appears
where you choose your S3 bucket.
And when it asks you if you want to add another data store, say no.
The reason that you're asked that is because a crawler can crawl
multiple different data stores simultaneously,
even with disparate data.
Next you choose an IAM role,
and we're going to choose the IAM role that AWS created for us.
It will have the name GlueStack-AWSGlueRole in the name, so choose that one.
Crawlers can be configured to run on a schedule.
In the screenshot you see is a partial listing of the drop-down list that
shows various time intervals to run your crawler regularly.
And this screenshot shows the rest of the drop-down choices that you have.
And the red arrow is pointing to custom,
so you can create a custom schedule for this crawler or any crawler to run.
This is a screenshot of the crawler's output configuration.
Notice that the database is sakiladb,
and we're going to add a prefix of S3_ to differentiate the
tables that were created by the first crawler,
which had a prefix of Glue_ from the results of this crawler,
and it will have the prefix of S3_.
This is like the review page for the crawler,
where you are looking at the Name, the Database,
the prefix, the Service role, the Data store,
and the Include path, and now this is a screenshot of the crawler running.
I ran the crawler previously to get these screenshots for you.
The next section is a pure demo section,
where we'll create the new crawler, and we'll run it,
and then look at the Glue Data Catalog to see the Parquet formatted results.
And since it's in a great columnar format,
we'll take a quick peek at Amazon Athena because Parquet format is perfect for running analytics.