Hello and welcome back I just want to give you a quick tour around the microdot SPL surmounted and so
on.
So you don't feel afraid or maybe nervous working with it.
So we're not going to be writing any queries today we're just going to see what is inside of this software
and what they is.
So on the left you can see object explorer what it's used for it's used to navigate for all your different
databases and your different tables.
You can do everything using queries but it's just much easier doing it right here.
Inside here you can see that if you right click on any of the elements you have a lot of different options
of what to do.
So select all poznań Rowsell editor €200 scream table has and so forth will become very valuable to
you.
The more you work with this software.
Right now there are not very important because we will be teaching you to do roofing using queries or
at least most of the stuff but this is just a quick way to do a task that usually requires you writing
a large query to do another thing important here is that just keep it nice and organize security sort
of objects that replication and management don't worry about that.
Right now it's more advanced stuff that will come to tackle later on.
Also here you can see that there is you can disconnect the subjects are connected.
You can refresh it very useful and you can also show to some policies.
Now if we click here and just say and you query this main window pops up this is where you write all
the queries.
So if you see different text is highlighted in different colors.
So that is very important to know that it's not important now is just a very convenient method for you
to understand what you're working with.
It's a building function.
It's just regular function it's an operator.
It's for example a database name Microsoft Eskdale server management.
It is very useful because it can just drag and drop on your table or your database or your even columns
names inside.
So as you remember it just uploaded all of this table in here.
So if you can just drag and drop it here it just makes you so much easier it just makes everything much
easier.
You don't need to spend time writing and a lot of your head.
So going up to the Start Menu you have your main button which is called execute Phyfe.
Then you have the D-bag which is always a very useful tool to have and you have them worry for all the
scores will mostly be working with new query in aggregate.
If you hover on top on any of these functions or any of any of the functions in the query or any of
these commands here you will see useful tips or explanations and shortcuts.
So in the query if you're going to close it.
Let's say we're going to write anything and try to call it now.
It will ask us if we want to save it or not.
Usually I don't save them unless they're very hard and important work to do.
But in case you want to save it we'll just open up this menu in which you just give your file name and
choose where to save it.
This is some text formatting stuff right here just to make your Corti look a bit better.
Going back a step forward step controls that control why are very important tools than you have.
Copy paste select all of that.
Now as far as what you need to know about skills her management studio this is pretty much everything
we're going to be showing you how to work with it more and more and you'll get more comfortable and
discover a lot of useful tools and tips inside of this menus.
Also if you want to you can go to though you can adjust your window to be different.
Have several queries and the same display and depending on just your workstation and your work preferences.
So I hope now you feel a bit more familiar with this software.
I know this sounds a bit scary that there's so many things you need to learn and remember.
But truly there's nothing you need to learn and remember other than the.
So if you know all the functions if you know all the commands you will do ok you will do everything
just it will take a bit more time and with time you will learn all of these short cuts that are here
for your advantage for your pleasure.
I hope you enjoyed this lecture.
I hope you're very ready to go ahead and actually start practicing the knowledge that we're going to
give you.
And I'll see you in the next one.