Hello and welcome back.
Today we'll be talking about wildcards in school as you can see I have the skill set of management studio
open up of my favorite consumer complaints database consumer complaints table ready to go.
Let's open up an inquiry in which we'll say select all from consumer complaints who actually run it
and see what happens.
Now from the 65000 rows of data you already know that we can use the word function as well as and or
to narrow the search results down.
Now what I wanted to today is I want to use the word function and I want to use it in a bit of a different
fashion as we saw previously used equals and only equals pretty much.
Today we'll be working with like what like as it allows us to find results to display results to Altro
results or any data that does not necessarily equals to certain rule does not specifically answer to
the rectally or rather in singular fashion.
But it has multiple possible answers.
For example just looking for this we can already see that you have credit reporting and credit card.
Two different products that both have the word credit in them.
If we wanted to run this query in which will say where product name equals and then put in credit in
apostrophe's we will get nothing and we will get nothing because no products just have the word credit
and only the word credit in.
Now if we say we're a product name like credit and run it well again you get nothing.
And this is nothing to be afraid of.
We get nothing because again there is just no words credit by themselves in this table that we're working
with.
This is where the percentage comes in per se sign basically says any number of characters zero to infinity
number of characters.
In our case we're looking for everything where product name is credit or one credit or one two three
four or five APC DPF credit or any feeling any number of characters credit followed by any number of
characters less executed and now we get a lot more results almost 20000 results to be exact.
And as you can see we have credit card credit reporting and that's about it.
So only two products that share the same work.
But still that's two products that will never be found unless were used like in our case.
As you can see we can go ahead and delete delete this percentage sign as we get it again.
Nothing has changed.
However if we leave this percentage sign and deal with this one and run it.
Sorry about that and run it.
Nothing will happen.
And this is because it doesn't matter how many characters we will be looking for prior to the word credit.
We in this particular case are more interested in what follows the word credit.
So percentage signs are very interesting and very intriguing.
But what can we do else where.
Well cartes What's the other one.
Neither one is underskirt plain and simple.
Again if we're going to be looking for credit for example and we're just going to put it in underscores
nothing will happen.
Why nothing will happen.
Well because underscore stands for one character and one character exactly remembered the results we
got.
One was credit reporting and one was credit card.
So if we count the number of characters that the word credit is followed by in a credit card it will
be five.
Meaning that if we only put five underscores here and just come in the south for a second no worry about
comments.
Everything in green basically means secure will not be executed.
It will not of income you read we will learn about the commons in a short while.
So for now just remember that green means nothing will happen to it.
So we're just running this inquiry right now.
If we execute it now we're exactly five underscores it will return to us only six thousand five hundred
dollars of data.
All that have the product name credit card.
None of them will have the word credit reporting because this just has more characters after it.
As you can see it will not return to its credit report because credit report is followed by 10.
Meaning that that they these and finished for example would have five characters.
And then we put it percentage sign it will return to us everything again.
But that just defeats the purpose of putting underscores.
Now if you want to return everything that has created reporting we have to put in one.
We have to put in one two three four five six seven eight nine 10 underscores So there are five if we
get additional five we should only now get the results we have credit reporting and that is 1000 rows
of data.
Everything seems to be adding up.
Of course what you could have done instead of just having a product name like credit and and underscores
just said word product name like credit reporting or in our case even equals and it'll return to us
the same amount of data at the same exact data.
But it's good to practice because underscores become very useful.
Before we go down though let's quickly address this question what will happen.
We can finally delete this.
We can finally delete this comment.
What will happen if we just say credit from a lower AC and put a percentage say here will it return
to those 18000 rows of data.
It will.
And this is due to the fact that by definition Microsoft Asgill server is case insensitive.
So unlike postgresql Well it doesn't care in which case the word is written it will return toss all
the results.
Another important thing to remember is that Microsoft kills are Management Studio.
Is case insensitive meaning that if you run credit credit percentage signed written from lower case
c it will still return to us all the 18000.
500 results.
So just a very good idea to keep in mind that now coming back to underscores where they might come useful
in this stable for example will be the zip code as we can see right now if we just display zip code
and we just delete this and go ahead and run it I just get up by pressing a five minute here if you
that will get 65000 rows of data just fill in with zip code.
What is it we can see most of them have six letters or or six numbers in them.
But some of them tend to have five numbers or even four.
So the obvious usage of underscores here is where is it code like.
And then we just put an underscore underscore on this underscore.
This will give us all the zip codes that have only four numbers in them.
As you can see only 5300 0 8 rolls of data.
Now if you put five underscores this will give us fifty nine thousand rows of data.
And now if we put six underscores in it will give us nothing.
So there are only zip codes but five or four numbers but and atrophying we can do.
And it typically works with numbers.
The best is we can say I want to find all zip codes that begin with 75 and then are followed by free
random numbers.
In this case we can see that we only have one thousand three hundred twenty six rows of data and all
of it starts with the zip code seventy five.
And how does it go there.
Arrogant eyes.
Most of the time is that they follow a certain pattern where if you know the first four numbers for
example say 7 5 1 free that difference in the last number will be on the city scale or maybe even on
a specific district of that city the two numbers will be a bit bigger like the whole city.
The freelance numbers will be the suburbs of the city and the numbers will be the state wide and then
the first number you can identify the general area of the United States for America.
So as you can see underscores may be just as valuable as percentage signs because there is just a lot
of things going on.
Interesting that you can apply them in a lot of different ways but they have a lot of similarity in
the sense that they let you to narrow your search results even further now.
So of course with this you can use and or or operators.
There's nothing to be worried about here.
All of it still on the table.
Everything here is still works perfectly.
I hope you understood the wildcards the percentage signs that underscore just like OPERATOR They all
do a lot of good things in school.
They all help you a lot with finding data and just specifying it and narrowing it even further down.
And as always I hope you enjoy this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.