Hello and welcome back.
And today we'll be working with Earth medic data types.
So we'll be calculating and adding up different maladies and you will understand how this syntax works
how the logic behind it works.
And we'll be able to reconstruct this example or tackle any problem that comes your way that has anything
to do with our many data types.
So first things first as you can see we're in admin for was gray Ezekiel nine point six I have free
databases now.
So we today will be working with console games.
So let's quickly go ahead and check that we have that correct that a base here open up.
And indeed as you can see we have two tables.
One is named cancel dates out and one is the console games.
So to begin with let's quickly run a secure query on console games.
So we just will go here or select query 2.
And I just want to select all from here just so we refresh our memory.
What's inside of this table.
So select all then we do console games.
And after that we run a expressive 5 and it should run you to query.
This might take a little while because again my machine is slow but that's nothing to worry about.
OK.
So there it is.
As we can see it consists of 10 columns and indeed we have here all the 10 columns.
First we have the game rank then we have the game name.
Then we have the platform then we have the game your genre of game publisher of this game sales in North
America.
Europeans sell Japanese sale and other sales as you can see this is a pretty straightforward table.
It has all of the real data from real world.
It is quite interesting to work with and to begin with.
Let's calculate total sales.
So instead of having to manually write down the total number of sales for every single game by combining
this for let's create a new table that will be called Global sales.
And for now just follow what I do.
There is a whole section about this vote in the course bar and I'll just follow what I type and we will
be right.
So first thing I want to say is I want to say that we are altering the table and the table is called
To console games.
And then on to say exactly what we're doing with this table.
In our case we want to add a column that's going to be called Global sales and it will be of a data
type of float 8 basically float a means it has numbers and the decimal point in there.
Quickly go ahead run that as you can see it altered it successfully.
Now that we have this table if we go again and select all from the console games you will see that it
will be empty because we just added it and there is no data in it.
Now the question is if we want to add data into that global sales how do we do it manually go and feel
in every cell.
By combining this for of course not that will take forever and that's not what school is used for.
SAGAL That used for fast data management and I'll show you the way how to do it.
So again I just quickly leave it alone.
And what we want to do is we want to update console games so we're again working with this table.
So we want to see that we update it and then we want to say that we set global sales to be equal to
North American sales plus European sales plys Japanese sales and plus other sales of course all the
sales are in millions.
So don't be alarmed that they only sold 41 copies was quickly go ahead.
And if you only select this part of the code it will only run select part of the code and see it updated
all 16000 rows.
And now if we go and only select these two top rows of the code and run this select 0 from console games
if reach a display to us all 11 columns now.
And it will have global sales as you can see it messed up our database a bit.
So it added these rows on top of the previous ones.
This is completely normal because databases are about storing the data and not organizing it.
We can easily reorganize this database to follow the game rank or any other column and I will actually
go for that in the next tutorial of knowledge just make sure that when the sound was happening here
because as you can see global sales do correspond to some of the other four columns and don't be alarmed
that there is only 10 columns displayed played here even though there should be 11 because if we go
ahead and refresh each display does that data.
Now there are 11 columns as you can see we have global sales.
Now that was really interesting wasn't it that we have all of these four values added up and we created
a new column so we don't have to go in manually and all this stuff up and now we can see who sold the
most copies and who sold the least amount of copies.
Before we go any further let's find out what percent of the sales of the global sales do North American
sales make up in order to do this.
We just basically have to say great.
And you call them cold and they sales percent.
So if you wanted to you can post the video now and go ahead and try it yourself.
Is basically following what we just did.
And if you want to do that pause ahead and go now.
Otherwise I'm going to demonstrate to you how to do it right now.
So first thing you want to do is Aldred that table.
So we all the tables called console games.
The one that we're working with right now and this is done just to stay to skew all that we're working
with this table and on the other.
So now we say that we want to add a column called a salesperson.
You can call it whatever you want but I think this makes sense and it makes logic.
It has to be of a float 8 data type again because we have not only whole numbers but most of these numbers
are have decimal point.
If we go and quickly run that we can see that the table has been altered.
But again as you guessed if we show all from console games we will see that.
Now we have 12 tables but the last table.
Sorry.
Select all.
If we select all from puzzle games we'll see that.
Now we have 12 columns.
The last column the newest column and they sell.
Percent does not have any information any data in it.
And indeed that is correct.
So now what we want to do is we want to update console games.
This is done again to show the scale that we're working with this particular table.
And here was say that we want to set and they salesperson's to be equal.
And now we're working directly with this table and we're basically setting the data inside of it to
be equal to whatever we want.
So how do we do it right now as we say that we want and they sell us percent to be equal.
And they say all divided by global sales
and then we can say where global sales
bigger than zero.
Because obviously we can't divide by zero and we just want to avoid making that mistake in case any
game sold does zero amount of copies globally which is hard to imagine but it might happen.
So we just want to weigh up.
So now if we again select the top two rows of the code and run it we should have 12 columns that will
all be filled with information.
So let's wait for it to finish first Sengcan
And as you can see indeed it is.
So now if we go and update this to multiply by a hundred we'll have a much nicer representation of the
table that we don't have to deal with multiplying by a hundred in our heads.
So as you can see here
now we have a much cleaner version representation of the percent.
So now we can go ahead and say that for just pick any game we want.
And again don't worry that the game ranks are all messed up because again you're always about storing
data and not nicely organizing it you'll have to type that in to you know make sure that it's nicely
represented and will definitely do that later.
I just want to get around this topic because it's pretty important.
So as you can see if we go for a card game that was released for Wii U in 2006 that North American sales
represented at sixty three point seventy five percent of the total sales.
And again these numbers can be all represented in this way but we'll get that done later in the course
once we already have enough knowledge and we can go to cosmetics.
So you say so I think that was quite interesting.
Today we're practiced with division and some the same way goes for any other arithmetic operations.
So you can multiply divide subtract some any number of values as long as you follow basic math rules.
For example you cannot divide by zero.
And yeah the update sad altered commands will be discussed further in the course and they are very important
to create your own database or as you can see altered these databases.
But I hope you learned a lot from today's lecture.
And you were excited to learn even more.
So that concludes our today's lecture.
I hope you enjoyed it and I'll see you in the next one.