Hello and welcome back.
And today we're going to be discussing elements of database databases consist of several elements and
we're going to be taking a closer look at them right now.
So as you can guess the most common element of any database is a table because it consists of all the
data.
Now apart from having tables that is also consist of schemas to manage the bends and seas between different
tables catalogues and extensions to store different functions.
So now back to tables right here you can see a table or formally known lation console games from console
games database.
So this is relation.
Console games now every named column of this table is called an attribute.
So this relation has eight attributes and every row of data is named tuple.
So this relation consists of eight attributes and then tuples Now table consist of more elements than
just attributes and tuples.
For example the number of columns in any table is referred to as degree and the number of rows of data
is generally referred to as cardinality.
So cardinality of this relation is 10 and degree of this relation is 8.
Now cardinality can also be referred to.
You need data inside any columns or in the whole relation to have any column or a cell that has a unique
constraint on it.
You can say that this is cardinality for this table.
The last element of the table is the main the main is a set of allowable values for one or more columns.
In this particular table we can say that European sales have a domain of zero to infinity.
And this is due to the fact that we cannot possibly sell less than zero copies and there is no limit
to how much money we can get.
So again database consists of schemas to manage dependencies of different tables can looks and extensions
to start different functions and tables to store data and tables consist of attributes or columns tuples
arose degree and cardinalities as well as sometimes the means.
And lastly every table has primary or foreign keys otherwise known as Super keys.
So if we take a look at this table again we can say that the game rank will be our primary key because
we can use game rank to uniquely identify any one roll of data in this table because no two games can
share the same rank.
And if we add another table into here game dates we can see that they're both connected to each other
through the blast per night.
So this one we call a foreign key because we can connect the game dates the table and the right to game
sales and table on the left throughout this column.
So I hope you enjoyed today's lecture and I'll see you in the next one.