Hello and welcome back then we're going to be talking about what is a relational database so a relational
database is a digital database whose organization is based on the relational model of data.
So this doesn't give us that much information because we not know what relational model of data is and
we need to understand that occurs.
So relational database is a set of tables to satisfy following data integrity.
First of all it has to fight entity integrity meaning that there are no duplicate rows in Table different
roles can have some information shared but they can be exactly the same.
This is why we need primary key.
This is why we need candidate keys to be in the table for it to be a relation also relational database
has to satisfy the main integrity meaning that it enforces valid entries for a given column by restricting
the type to form a word to a range of values.
This basically means that we have to put some restriction on data in order for it to be classified as
a relation rather than just a table.
Next it has to satisfy racial integrity which means that drolls cannot be deleted which were used by
other records.
If you try and lead a row in Eskew or disconnected to another table it will not let you do that.
It will simply give you a mistake saying that you are doing something that should not be done and you
can force to override it and delete it anyway.
But that will leave you were damaged and possibly corrupted database.
And finally a relational database has to satisfy user defined integrity meaning that it enforces successful
business rules that do not fall into entity domain or referential integrity.
So if we want to specify that some value just for us just for our company has to be not now.
So we always have to know that customer name even though it is not required for a database to operate.
It is called the user defined Negroni and our database has to be able to comply with our request.
As you can see relational database makes a big emphasis on usability and accessibility.
This is done primarily for enforcing different rules and constraint vendor database relational database.
Our most popular judiciary consistency and availability although they do have some limitation as any
change you have to make will require extensive work in order to satisfy all existing conditions and
possibly creating more.
Also you have to understand your database usage limits even while still designing it to ensure your
users will have easy access to it basically as well structured query language works who have structured
data and structure data is very good very powerful.
When you have specific amount of data before even designing the database so you can put it in there.
You can force all the rules you can recorded and then oxyd that's done all you need to do is just work
with this data.
Or maybe sometimes insert new values at school is optimized.
Or working with structured data.
Use it to your advantage.
Make sure you always plan your database before designing it and input all the correct data satisfying
logic and your own rules.
I hope you enjoyed today's lecture and I'll see you in the next one.