Hello and welcome back to the course on databases.
Today we got a very interesting challenge.
We're helping a vet's clinic with their data analytics.
Let's have a look inside.
All right.
So you're a data analyst assisting every training clinic to make sense of their data their data is dispersed
across multiple source files and they need you to support all of them to a database and then perform
the following analytics.
First of all extract information on pets names and owner names side by side.
Then find out which parts from this clinic had procedures performed then match up all procedures performed
across all pets to their descriptions to descriptions of the procedures.
Same as above but only for the pets of the clinic in question so you'll see that the data sets are a
bit different some data sets are not nationwide some data sets are just for this specific clinic so
you're going to need to in those two different challenges or two questions you're going to need to perform
a bit different tasks.
And number five extract a table of individual costs which are procedure prices incurred by owners of
PEDs from the clinic in question.
So this table should only show two columns the owner and the procedure price side by side.
So I know this might be a bit overwhelming right now but let's have a look at the data set to understand
what we're dealing with.
So to get the data set we're going to need a browser.
And in your browser you will need to go to WDW that super data signs dot com slash as you will.
So if you scroll down here to section number 7 joining tables and Asgill you'll see the challenge and
then you'll see four files.
So so the pedofile has information on the pets of this clinic owners are the owners of the pets from
this clinic procedures histories and nationwide list of procedures performed Of course all pets and
you'll find out why.
For the down in the section and procedure details contains additional information on the procedures
in the procedures history table.
So there we go there's four files or we'll be working with quite an exciting section ahead of us.
We'll have a look at the data set inside the next tutorials.
So just go ahead and download that and I'll see you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.