Hello and welcome back to the course on databases we've had a look at a left join.
So that's scroll up here.
We've had a look at the left join.
We've had a look at a RIGHT JOIN.
So as part of our tips and tricks and we've had a look at an inner join today we've got one more show
to look at which is a full outer join So let's have a look at that's full outer join now the full outer
join is quite a rare species.
You won't find it in the wild quite that often.
And why is that.
Well because a full outer join the most common one you use is probably a left join.
It's a very it's very simple to look up in Excel.
Then there's an inner join which trims away all the fat to all of the things that don't match on both
sides whereas the full outer join it doesn't trim anything at all it just basically matched sub two
tables and leaves everything that doesn't match up that doesn't have a pair in the other table and that's
something we discuss reading the theory tutorials so let's have a look at in practice so I was going
to take this same example.
And as you recall we've seen how this works.
An inner join is left joins an outer join.
So as an inner join if I just rerun this you will see that we've got 41 rows right now if I do a I was
going to replace this with a full outer join and this doesn't have a lot of meaning for us.
This operation we're going to perform now because we've been hit with the task we had was to find only
the pets in our clinic that have had procedures but still it just for argument's sake just for demonstration
purposes we're going to run this fall or joint and see what we get.
So if you're on this now you don't have floodwaters you have 2000 or and €50.
And what happened now.
So basically you all picked up these two tables and match them together.
Tried to match as much as it can in anything it matches.
But then the stuff that didn't match it still left and so you can see here you've got all these pets
that actually had procedures but they're not from our clinic so they don't have any information in this
local pets table.
On the other hand you do have some that matched up so you've got this pet bird the cat who did match
up because it's a pet in our clinic and our pets table and it had a procedure done.
Then again you have lots and lots and lots that didn't wash up than some other there's cuddles our favorite
dog.
So then you've got lots and lots and lots that didn't match up again.
And then if you scroll down to the bottom scroll down scroll down what you'll find is at the very bottom
you've got these ones on the left right.
So where did these come from.
Well these are pets that are are in our database are our table and our local pets table who or which
never actually had a procedure and therefore they didn't match anything on the right and the full outer
join did not remove them.
So sometimes this might be useful too if you're doing some sort of more involved analysis where you
do want to see what not only what matched up like this like this one over here like bright dog.
Not only what did match up you also want to see what didn't match up on one side on this side and what
didn't match up on the other side.
So again just to reiterate I left to join if we were to replace her for live and would keep everything
that's on the left and would remove any rose that didn't match up on the right so this would be removed
right.
These would actually Sardi's would stay these would stay.
These would be removed.
So basically they because they have nothing on the left and left and only keeps the rows that do have
something on the left right.
These rows would be kept and then rows like these that did match up would be kept right join would only
keep only the row all the rows that have something on the right.
These rows basically not.
But not these rows and inner join would only keep rows that have something in both.
So these are the rows that actually did match up had a pair.
And don't forget that some of them are duplicated on one of the sides because some parts are on the
left side because some pens have had several procedures.
And finally a four hour journey just keeps everything.
There we go.
That's how full outer join works it's always good to know these things because one day you will probably
encounter a full hour of join and you will this knowledge will come in handy.
So now you're prepared for your first full outer join when you do encounter it in your days and career.
I hope you enjoy today's tutorial and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.