Hello welcome back to the course on databases.
And today we're going to learn a useful technique that is not that advanced but at the same time can
come in handy and can help you structure your code.
So we're going to learn about cleaning up your.
So let's have a look at this complex join that we created previously and you'll see that it is quite
growing quite quickly.
And these are not that these tables are not at large.
They're quite small.
They've only got a few columns in the first table if you call them and the second if he comes in third
but because of the number of tables the whole result is growing very quickly and imagine if the tables
originally were bigger you would by now have a couple of dozen columns.
So the challenge here is to leave only the information that you actually need.
And that's what we're going to talk about briefly to day.
So cleaning up your joints.
All right.
So basically we're just going to find out how to select the best What's the best way to select information
when you to copy this.
And here we're going to go through this and find out what and what we can throw away right away.
Well let's have a look at the poems that we're joining.
All right so here we got pet I.D. equals pet I.D. and so pet I.D. equals parody and that is something
you should know that whenever just play by definition whenever you join on a column that means that
in every single role the value of this column is going to be equal to the value of this column.
That's because simply you're specifying this condition here so if there will be no other role where
these these values don't equal because if that were the case it wouldn't be in your resulting joins
simply because the way you specify this conditions so always in a resulting join unless you specifically
for some reason need both columns to be in place you can always get rid of at least one of them.
One of the two columns that you're on now in case you were on one two three columns right.
So that's three pairs of columns that we have here so there's one pair the pet ID.
Then you've got the procedure type that's another pair and then the procedure sub subclass sub code.
Right.
So that's three pairs of columns that we have.
And out of each pair we can get rid of one of the column.
So that's what we're going to start off by doing.
So we're going to get rid of those.
And that to do that we're going to need to type up these columns here.
So let's go ahead and do so we'll say pet ID comma was the comma comma then we'll say something like
name because we want the name of the pets then we'll say kind.
We want to know what kind of pet it is.
Gender age.
So for now we'll just type in all of them except for the ones that we've agreed to exclude already.
So now we won't type in pet ID again because we are in the habit and we'll see procedure date is that
the correct name for this column will look to your date then we'll say procedure type procedure
sub code and then we won't do procedure type and sub code again because we you have them will say description
and price.
So hopefully I got all those right and if I run this now you'll see that already we're saving some space.
OK so Pileggi OK see I fell into the trap of not specifying where they come from so let's go ahead and
go through them and specify.
So these are a this is a this is still a owner and you still this came from B.
It's very easy when you just use the alphabet.
Use them alphabetically or name them alphabetically because in YOUR know in which order they came see
and prices see their Ingrosso.
Now if you run this you can see that the table is smaller now.
Now the next thing that we want to do is maybe there are some columns that we actually don't need and
the final result so maybe if you're off to the you want to know the pet idea you might not need to know
the name of the pet and the kind and the gender and age.
So all of that information if you just after the price that the owner has to pay for that page you might
just want to parody the owner ID and you know the procedure dates yes.
Or you need all this information right so that basically means you could take out some going to comment
them out you could take out the name the kind the gender age.
Right.
So if you run this now you have a much smaller table and then you can really super-G care owner and
information about the procedure and the price that they need to pay.
Right.
In some cases you might not even need all that information you might just need if you want to issue
an invoice or a bill to the owners.
You might not need information about the pet.
So this is where it gets interesting.
Don't need any information even information about the owner.
You don't need about the procedure or day procedure type description.
None of that.
You just need the price.
And this is why it's so interesting is because if you look at it we have information here display from
the from Table A where the owner got owner I.D. which came from this pet table and we've got the price
which came from Table C.
But there is no way that we could have gotten this information just by having table A and so just by
having a table pet Id just by having or just having the pets table and the procedure detail say well
there's no way to join them.
We had to have this intermediary table which is a procedure history in order to get the result but at
the same time we're not displaying any information from the procedure history table so it's quite interesting
I find that you've got like this ghost table in the middle in between.
So you did need it for the join.
You needed it to join Petz to proceed your history to join the procedure details to get the costs for
all those procedures but we're actually not displaying any information from this table and that is you
know just an interesting situation and it still works totally fine it doesn't matter which displace
these things to separate what you display is kind of separate to how you structure your join so just
reiterate that concept.
So there we go that's how you clean up your joint you can always remove some columns that were parts
of the join criteria and then just pick out the columns that you actually want to get the result that
you are after.
So I hope you enjoy this Tauriel and 14 Exham.
Until then happy analyzing.