Hello and welcome back to the course on databases.
So we've talked about all sorts of Joines we've talked about Left-Right inner outer full outer joins
So we've talked about cleaning up U-joint we're talking about complex Georgetown joins multiple field
so very well you're probably very well-versed by now in the topic of choice.
And today I have one bonus tutorial for you.
It's about a specific type of Joines that is not always covered in educational material.
And if you will it's a team typical secrets type of information that you get to find out eventually
with the course of your career.
But I do need to warn you that this is kind of an advanced topic and feel free to skip this tutorial
and get come back to it some time later when you do come across this type of join.
But at the same time if you feel prepared then let's go ahead and check it out.
So today we're talking about something very interesting it's called a cross join.
And I personally didn't find out about cross join for at least a year or more of you more.
While I was working with.
Well until I actually needed it in my work and then I had to you know I thought maybe it's an inner
Joyner's an outer join.
I was trying to figure out what exactly I need and wasn't any of those it was actually specifically
a cross join that I needed.
And luckily Asgill actually has this facility.
So what is a cross join.
Well a cross join is a is an implementation of a Cartesian product in a scale.
I know it sounds a bit complex but at the same time it actually isn't that bad.
So I went across a Cartesian product is at the Wikipedia page here is in mathematics a Cartesian product
some mathematical operation that returns a set or Porlock set or simply product from multiple sets.
That is for sets and be a container and product is a set of all ordered pairs A AB were A's from ABC
from B.
And the best way to illustrate this is to look at this example so if you have just think of it in terms
of tables so if you have an ASCII table A and table B and these are the rows so x y and z are the rows
and B These don't call them these are also rows.
You could call a rose a one two and three.
So the cartesian product is all possible combinations of these two sets or these two tables all possible
combinations of the rows.
So you've got X-1 matches up of one.
So the first rule match up for show first of much second row first row my third row second row much
of first second second second third third match up with first third of second third third.
So basically you know how in a joint left right inner outer join we usually match them up so X would
match up to maybe row two and whites row three and this one wouldn't have a match to saloon have a match
and that's what the result would have in a Cartesian product.
There is no on there's no parks there's no criteria for the match.
It just matches everything.
And that is why that's why the story is a bit advanced is that because now after so many editorials
on joins in a row we are in the mindset of having this on part of the statement that we are specifying
how to match the two tables.
We want this to be equal to that and the cartesian product or in the cross join you're not actually
going to have this part you just going to grow cross join two tables full stop and you'll do everything
for you.
So let's have a look at that.
We'll start by selecting will actually let's talk through this a bit.
We're going to take two of the we're not going to take the product prove procedure history table that's
for sure which is going to take the owners and pets tables and was that because we want smaller tables
this table has several thousand rows and when you look at the all all possible combinations of two tables
were one to at least one of them is big or large you will you'll get a huge resulting table and we don't
want that.
We don't want to break out computer.
So we're going to we're going to just cross join pets and owners so we're going to say select select
star from pets.
And here is sort of inner left outer or right or full outer join.
We're going to say cross join two owners comma colon.
So as you can see there's no on statement that comes afterwards as when you run this.
Remember we have 100 pets and about eighty nine owners.
So if you run this is going to take a while to run.
So here we have eight thousand nine hundred so a hundred times 89 right.
Eight thousand nine hundred different combinations.
And what does this results show us.
Well this was all just shows us here.
There's Blackey the dog and he was matched to every single owner in our database right.
No data and no table.
So for is likely the dog matched to 89 different owners that and then read about rhumba the cat much
too same old same again 89 owners all of them done that matched match matched then we got Simba the
cat matched to all 89 owners and so on.
So basically we've crossed joined two tables together.
Now what is the purpose of a cross-trained like this makes no sense right.
Why would you match a black dog to all these owners when a black dog actually has just one owner.
What's the point of matching a black.
You have all these other owners.
Well the reason for a cross join is there are actually situations sometimes when you might need to see
see all of the possible combinations of two of the rows of two tables.
Right so like for example you have a set of colors like seven colors and you have a set of let's say
a set of tiles that are used in you know a Buffle bathroom floor and you need a resulting table right.
And for example all those columns have certain attributes and all those tiles have certain attributes
or prices attached to them.
So you have seven different types of tiles like made out of different materials and you want to get
a resulting table which will combine which will have a combination of all of those colors and tiles
right.
So then you would do a cross join.
And another example would be when you have for example a you know five people and or a certain number
of people and they have each one of them has three choices right yeah.
Each one of them has three choices that they can be like three doors that they can go through and you
want to see the results of all possible combinations of like for each person what's if they go through
which door how those parameters will add up.
So you want a table with all of those and then you'll make some analysis based on that.
The example when I needed crutches during my career was when I was analyzing some socioeconomic patterns
in Queensland in Australia.
So that's the north eastern part of Australia and there the whole of this region in my database was
broken down into these little Parus which are called S-A ones and they basically each of those statistical
authorities contains about 200 people's 200 people and in each one of them and then in each other in
each of those statistical regions I knew that there were several levels or civil economic social economic
levels and with different incomes basically several social classes of different incomes and so forth.
I knew that I have like for example like five different social classes and I have 20000 or less let's
say for argument's sake 10 different social economic classes and I have 20000 like 200000 of these little
blocks of
geographical blocks and that means that I need a cross join.
So in my resulting table I need all possible combinations for each of those geographical little segments.
I need a social economic one.
Each of those sectors socio economic classes assigned to it.
That means I need 10 times 200000 I mean I need two million rows in my resulting database.
In fact it was much more so than just some numbers of my head was a long time ago but I remember that
the resulting table had close to 900 million rolls.
So as you can imagine like when because it had an I think maybe it had even a couple of Crossroads or
something.
It definitely was multiple joins.
I don't remember how many Cross joins it had but the size of that table was immense.
And that was you know a legitimate analysis that I had to do.
And that's my other warning or caution recommendation to you here is that cross-bones are also complex
or advanced not just because the way they're structured and the way they're used but also because of
the amount of resources that they take up.
So if you were to run across join for example of the procedure history table of itself that's 2000 times
2000 all of a sudden you have a four median row table right from a not such a big table of 2000 rows.
You are jumping into a four median row table and you cross join that one more time of the procedure
history table and all of a sudden you have a billion rolls and if used incorrectly your joint can really
hang your computer not on your computer probably your whole organization's database and hopefully you
know your organization has protection mechanisms against it so they'll they'll just cut your session
and then you'll get a call from the database administrator saying hey you shouldn't do that but just
be careful of it.
And be warned that a cross join does grow very very quickly once you start working with larger tables.
So we go.
That's what a cross join is.
And hopefully now even if you don't go running into your work and using it right away maybe one day
when you do come across this situation when you need it you'll remember this tutorial and you will know
that what you need might be a Christian and I hope you to this Tauriel I look for you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.