Hello and welcome back to the course on databases.
So previously we talked about Joines tips and tricks and right Jones and day we're going to talk about
energises and we're going to work with a bit of a different combination of tables we're talking about
the Petz table and the procedure history table so let's go ahead and bring these tables up.
So let's start from pets and so let's start from procedure.
Maybe it's make sure this works.
Procedure history of procedures history in this case and this is just pets.
If we run these.
So here you can see the tables that we've selected and we're going to learn how to create in a joint
by combining these two tables and what do these table cells.
Well the first one tells us the pet's information about the pets or the identification number of the
name and so on of the 100 pets that are registered with this particular clinic whereas the procedure
details are procedures history table is a bit different.
It actually tells us again pet idea and then it tells us what procedure that pet has had and on what
date.
So we've got some pet had a certain procedure with procedure type and subgoal.
But how is it actually fundamentally different to this table.
Well you'll see if you scroll down here you'll see that this table has thousands and thousands of Rosewell
not thousands thousands but several thousand of rows are present in this table.
And why is that.
Well not because these poor 100 pets have had so many procedures it's actually because of this table
procedures history table unlike the pets and the older stables.
This table is nation wide.
It's shared across the whole country by the clinics of this chain of veterinarians.
Whereas pets and owners these two tables are local to that veterinarian that we're working with in Michigan.
So why would that be the case why would somebody structure their data in such a way.
Well the reason for that there could be many reasons for something like that in this case as an example
for instance where the owners and the pets tables they are local for privacy reasons because there is
no need for veterinarians from other parts of the country to see information on owners and pets which
are not from their clinic where as their procedures details are procedures history table it is nationwide
because what it is like what if something like this happens where a person takes their pets on a road
trip they go traveling they go to a different state and the pet gets sick and then they end up in the
veterinarians.
So the veterinarian needs to know what procedures that Pat had already had the procedures had been performed
on that pet previously so that they can perform their procedures accordingly so that they take into
account the previous medical history of that animal and therefore that's a reason why this table the
procedures history table could be available nationally so that if something good happens then veterinarians
from all across the country can look up certain pet idea and find out what the procedures history was
for that pet.
So there we go that's how the tables are structured.
And that's the core difference between them one is a small table because it's a local table to the Internet
and in Michigan and the other one is a national table across the whole country and that's why it is
greater.
And now we're going to figure out what type of join we need in order to combine these two tables.
So here we've got our two tables right.
So on the left or this blue table there's a big circle here is all of our pets the hundred pets that
we have in our clinic and then we have the procedure history which is a much bigger table.
So this is not to scale.
We've got several thousand procedures that happened right.
And what we've got here in yellow is an inner join.
So let's try to understand a great advocate that we need an inner join here so let's try to understand
why we need it.
INTERVIEWER Well what options do we have.
We've got an inner join left join right join and outer join.
Right so which we haven't discussed yet.
So why wouldn't we want a for instance right.
And why wouldn't we want to take the procedure history table and then just attach and then just match
it up with our pets table.
Well because then we would have all the procedures for all the pets that we're not interested in that
are not in our clinic that we're performing this analysis for right so we don't want that.
We want to get rid of any We want to not include in the select statement or in the output any pets that
are not now clear.
So it rejoins are good for us in this case.
We're all left to live join.
Sounds interesting.
So it would take all of our pets and it would cross-reference all of them to the procedure history.
So basically we would see which.
And this information here but then have would be left of all these pets that are in our clinic which
don't which have not had a procedure which have not had any surgery or any vaccination or anything like
that.
So that's what we're what we're after.
We want to know just out of out of the Pezzo we have we just want to look at the ones that did have
some sort of procedure.
So basically you want to do that kind of gives us answers that we want only the pets that we have.
So this blue circle overlaps with all of the procedures that all of the pets in the country have had
in these in this chain of clinics in this chain of veterinarians.
And therefore we want the crossover between the two which is an inner join so we only want our pets
and only the ones that did have a procedure.
And that's why we want an inner join.
OK.
All right so let's go ahead and perform this inner join.
So we're going to just keep this part select star from pets.
We're going to give it an alias as a let's put this in capitals as a inner join procedure.
Seizures history as B.
And then we're going to say on a dot pet ID equals b dot Pat
ID so if you run this now you will see that we've got a beautiful inner join which has 41 rows and on
the left with the pats on the right we've got the procedures that occurred and it is fair that this
table has less than 100 rows because not necessarily all of our pets had procedures.
And in fact actually maybe some peds had procedure several times so for instance we see this pets with
864 73 had several procedures.
So this doesn't mean that there's 41 pets that had procedures.
This means that there's 41 procedures performed on the pets that are registered with our clinic maybe
several there were pets that had more than one procedure.
As we can see that is the case indeed.
Now let's try to understand how is this inner join different to a left join or right join.
So let's start with a Left-Right.
If we have a clip we free had put a live join here.
Then we will see Silex star from pets as a left join to the procedures history.
So basically we'll take everything from the pets table without excluding any rows and then we would
add the procedures history where we can where it's available on the right so if we're on this you'll
see that we've got a lot of nals right so we can see that we've got we've actually got more than 100.
We've got seven rows in our original Petz table we have 100 rows and that's because as we just discussed
there a duplication of growth has occurred because sometimes in the procedures history table pet ID
comes up twice and then obviously this same pets row on the left has to be duplicated.
So just as we saw before there is Biskit and somewhere else we had this again that's a different there's
several biscuits in this is that people seem to like the name.
So you can see this row right.
And this Phroso is even though it's the same pet here and here you can see that the procedure was different
it was on different dates.
So here is grooming and here's a vaccination right.
So different procedures.
And because of that because that there's two rows for this pet in this dataset on the right the rose
the left go duplicate and that's why we ended up with more than 100 rows.
And also you can see all these animals.
That's because these pets never had any procedures performed and therefore there was no match.
There was no matches in the procedures history table.
Now if we do it the other way if we do it RIGHT JOIN what will happen is this becomes a primary table
and now we will have all of the procedures history ever performed on any pets in this whole table.
And then on the left we're just going to add information from our pets table where it is available so
if we run that you'll see all of these new.
And if we scroll down occasionally you will see that information has indeed been added was that will
because these rows with the Knolles they're obviously pets from other clinics from the country where.
So basically that's why information on them on this the information on the pets was not available because
it's simply not present in our table whereas this pet is indeed from our region and therefore the information
was available and then again got all these no.
So if you scroll down you'll see these nano rolls occur occasionally because they are matched up to
procedures where it's possible.
So there we go.
That's what would have happened if we did a right join as you can see in all in our Of all these three
cases left right and in the correct one that we need is indeed an inner join.
And that's why we're going to replace his back with an inner join.
So all in all you can see that even though an inner join returns less rows it's actually a bit more
complex.
It's a bit more sophisticated because it trims down both the tables trims down the walls from either
of the table or wherever there were no matches it will trim down the nose.
And also once again we witnessed in action the situation where the rows get duplicated when there's
a CERN like parody comes up several times in one of the tables the another one it gets duplicated the
rows get duplicated to be able.
So you can match up properly to all of the records.
So there we go that's our result for inner joins.
I hope you enjoy today's Statoil have a play around with that see what other tables are the ones we
have you can try and enter or left or right join on and see the differences.
Always a good idea to get some of that practical experience and just just play around with the code
and see what you can get.
And I'll look for you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.