Hello and welcome to altar tables lecture in this lecture we'll be taking a closer look at the altar
function.
So before we start let's go to my databases.
This public select your table run a new query.
So in here just select all from and then specify movies.
Just make sure we have everything right.
Again as you can see we have four lines of code here.
Sorry for lines of data for rows of data here everything field of information.
But if you remember already in this section we tried to feeling the Godfather with our country USA because
we forgot to put it when we initially input the data in and it was really frustrating because just to
change this one so we had to write a whole big query in order to do this and imagine to have more and
more cells missing data.
This just piles up to the point where it's quicker and safer to just delete the table completely and
create it another time like create a new fresh table from the very beginning in order to avoid those
nontheist in this table.
What I want to do is I want to set that country by default has to be fieldin of USA.
So if I didn't specify what I wanted the country to be filled in with I just put in USA and it's filled
automatically.
So in order to do this we need to use the default function and we need to use the alter function so
alter function.
What it does it says that alter.
Then you say table.
So it basically letting know as well that you're going to be working with a database table or column.
In our case first we need to say that we're altering a table that is named movies and then we want to
specify that in this table will either throwing a column that is named country.
So now we say that we want to set the country to be equal by default.
To USA.
And this is achieved by writing this small line of code.
So first we state to ask you all that we're working with the table movies then we say that we are working
with the column countries and then we say that we want to update all of the countries we want to set
the whole country column to be by default USA.
So now for us it should give us on the stakes as you can see it altered quite returned successfully.
And if we abdicated here if we refresh it we will see nothing changing really the constraints remain
the same and of course doing the same.
But if we go here to dependencies window we can see that we have our primary key.
If I remember movies primary key that's defined by movie name in the movie.
But no one else has a function that basically sets a value to me.
USA.
In country if we were filling in.
And if there is no data specified for the country.
So now go ahead and quickly test this Solas go ahead.
Open our query back up and in Harolds Go ahead say insert into movies and then specify values.
In the here would say Test 1 default and then we input and test.
So and go ahead run this as you can see we specified that this is default because this is not the last
column and we need to put something in the just good to do this just to practice especially in the beginning.
And now if we say select all from movies we should have five rows of data this time.
And as you can see the country is filled by default with your site.
So it worked.
Now every time we have a new row at it the country will be default unless we change it to something
honored and Yosei.
Now lets go ahead and practice some more with ultra as you can see.
Right now we have four columns and let's say you want to add a whole new column.
In my case I want to add a column called the rectors.
So I remember which movies I like but which directors and of the new movie comes up and I see the familiar
director name.
I can check it out.
So what we want to do we want to again state that we want to alter table movies and then because we
are not altering any of the existing columns and were not getting any of them what we're saying is that
we want to add it.
So we're adding a column called The rector that will be obeyed type called word char.
And let's say number of characters will be no more than 150.
I don't want to specify that not now or default because it's impossible to specify a default value and
then just go ahead and run it quickly.
Right.
Select statement from that from movies.
And if we're on this we can see that we have.
And you call them is currently filled with empty data.
So what we want to do is we can only say we want to update table movies so we're not going to be changing
any structure of it.
We're just going to be changing the date inside and we want to said that we're going to set director
to be equal to Christopher Nolan.
So the go ahead right here.
Christopher Nolan where and heroes go movie name equals inter-stellar.
Now as you can see because I made a mistake here and they didn't follow my own naming stations.
If I run it right now it will make me.
It will give me a return because I have no inter-stellar inside.
So what I need to do is I want to input were lower and then put these in the name inside brackets and
they say inter-stellar all lower letters and run it down.
So because we're updating and not altering we can remove this table and intransitively.
So we say that we want to update table movies.
And because we're not altering anything in those by default that it's movies because there's only one
table called movies inside a database.
My database didn't want to said that.
Now all of the data in the record column this is done by set in the record call and it has to be equal
to Christopher Nolan.
But if we just run it like this every single movie will have direct or equal to Christopher Nolan.
And that is not correct.
So after that we want to have a work function in which we specify that we're lover when we name equals
inter-stellar and we have to put it in lower because we did not follow.
I did not follow the naming convention.
And if I did not put lower I will have a mistake because there is no such movie as interstellar rhythm
and small characters.
It's all in capital letters in our table.
So let's go ahead select all from movies quickly run it just to make sure to subdue that.
And as you can see there it is in the very end.
Now we can have movie name inter-stellar director Christopher Nolan.
If we want to we can go ahead and update every single utterer movie but that will just be a lot of time
consumed is the same syntax and it's very important that you just in this day be behind it.
That if we're altering the table we need to say that first we're altering and then we need to specify
that we're altering a table then the table name then we can put in which column specifically we're updating
we're altering in order to just write and call them names to some generic column and then we want to
say what we're going to do with this column.
We can set the value to soundfield we can to default not now and so on.
And then when it comes to adding something up we can again we have to specify that we're updating a
table and table name and then we can have inside of here did we add alter alter or delete any specific
column.
So with is basis of because here they're are all different functions.
And this is the general idea of this index behind it.
So I hope you understand the logic behind all these functions and realized how easy it actually is to
create a table and how hard it is to alter them just because the amount of code you had to write and
make sure that you make no mistakes in this new code.
So as well really works good with structure data.
But on one condition that when you initially input into that table where you do the initial calculation
it or any other type of function manipulation it has to be correct otherwise you will have a very hard
time fixing it.
But that's why you back up.
That's why you can back up and save all of your databases.
So at any time it can roll back to the version that you had previously.
I hope you enjoy this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.