Hello and welcome back.
Today we'll be learning to create our own very first database.
So let's go ahead.
Right click on the databases here.
Select new database input your database name in my case it's going to be my database.
You can name it whatever you want.
And let's go ahead through the menus.
Just try to understand what's inside here.
So the logical name of your database and database log is displayed here the file type file grub initial
size and growth is something that might come in handy because initial size you might want a bit higher.
It's going to be a very large database and then you can limit the maximum size of the database so it
doesn't take too much space and then adjust the path and the file name just some windows stuff in here.
The owner is set to default by default.
And that's good for us.
But in case you will ever have to work with securing data you might want to change this.
The only people who have to have access to it have access to it.
And owner plays a very big part of that.
Then we have the options menu which basically consists of a huge amount of different properties that
you can set to be true or false or specific values.
And I will not go in depth in here because very few people will actually need to change this.
And when you need to change this you can either refer to the Help section here or just Google.
That way you ensure will make no mistake.
The only thing I want to mention here is to set the level to the Virgin those killed that this file
will be worthwhile from for example if you're working in a company not all people have a skilled server
2016 it might be a good idea to sell it to their current version of a school.
And after that follow groups again nothing crazy here.
Just some more set up properties so not go ahead only click OK it's executed.
Then there are good relations.
You have your own very first database.
I know already created these two but this one is truly we went through a process in a little deaf as
you can see there's really nothing to change when creating your own database.
It's really a very easy process.
The other thing I will say is if you click here right now and just let's put it this test and you click
on the script and you scroll down to screen the action to new window you will see what this window what
Microsoft skills or management studio does for you because otherwise you would have to write all of
this down yourself basically would not have to write all of this down yourself because this is all the
different parameters and in that option that you might set but you basically have to write this one
yourself.
Pretty much every time.
So go ahead.
Close.
Don't say that because the new database windows while we already have ours ready to work with Ellas
do exactly that.
I hope you enjoyed today's lecture and I'll see you in the next one.