Hello and welcome back to the course on databases.
Today we're talking about the second normal form.
So what's the definition of the second normal form.
Well the second normal form is defined as follows.
And table is in the second normal form if first of all it fits in the first normal form.
So basically satisfy it satisfies the criteria of the first and all a form and every non-prime attribute
of the table is dependent on the whole of every candidate key.
Now let's see that again.
So every non-prime attribute of the table so non-prime actually said those that do not fall in in any
of the candidate keys.
So every non-prime attribute of the table is dependent on the whole of every candidate key.
And how do we remember this.
Well we already have all mnemonic Let's bring it up our mnemonic is every non-prime attribute must provide
a fact about the key the whole key and nothing but the key.
So the second normal form is that's part highlighted with the dashed box which is the whole key.
So that part of the sentence and an important thing to note here about our mnemonic is actually you
don't know what we're talking about.
The key right about every non-prime attribute must provide a fact about the key the whole key and nothing
but the key.
And in this definition in the second formal form definition it's actually talking about dependent on
the whole of every candidate.
So you just need to remember that that just to make sure are shorter and easier to remember we said
the key is one key but in reality all of these normal forms so both the second normal form and the third
normal form they're referring to every candidate will see that about the third normal from further down.
But just remember when you're saying the whole key you actually mean all of our every one of the candidate
keys the whole of each one of the candidate keys.
Right.
So that's what it means.
So basically I know this is we've so far we've read the definition and we've learned how to remember
it.
But probably it doesn't make any sense right now so what's hard is very hard to picture this without
an example.
So how do you picture non-prime attributes depending on the whole key hole of every candidate key and
exactly for that reason we're going to move on to to an example right.
So let's learn through an example.
So here we've got an example of a table right.
So this table here it does conform to the one NF to the first form or form and that is because it has
no duplicate rows.
And also it doesn't have more in every cell you only have one value so you don't have two or more values
in any of the cells.
Right.
The question now is does it conform to the second normal form.
So let's find out.
Well the first thing that we're going to do is we need to identify which of the attributes here are
prime attributes and which are non-prime attributes and do remember how to do that.
Well yes it's a pretty straightforward process.
First we need to identify all of the candidate keys in this table and this table electric toothbrush
models we have two candidate keys so the first candidate key here is this column.
Right because it has the full name of the model and the tables about electric toothbrush.
So you would think that you would be able to pick up uniquely and your role from the table by just referencing
the full name of the model.
So if you have the full name of the model then you'll find a unique role in the table.
That's basically what it means.
And also you will see that the combination of these two columns or attributes actually together they
create also a candidate.
So basically if you don't have the moral fullname but you have the manufacturer and the model of the
tooth brush then you'll be able to find its unique role in this data in this table.
So why is that.
Well as you can see these two together they indeed do identify each row individually you can just go
through and check.
And finally the manufacturer country.
It's not actually part of any
any candidate key.
You can check that by going to the table but also if you just think about it.
Right.
So the manufacturer and model it could be manufactured any country.
And so we don't like it's not it's not going to help us identify the rows right just logically but probably
the better option is just go through the table and quickly check that indeed it's not part.
You cannot create through this code on its own is not a candidate key right because it got duplicates
in it and therefore it wouldn't identify uniquely their roles.
But also if you combine it with any other of the columns it wouldn't be a candidate key and here you'd
have to apply the definition of the candidate key.
You know that it's a key that you cannot make a simplified and you know that's something that we covered
off Preuss in the course.
So now through identifying the candidate keys we've also identified that we only have one non-prime
attribute and that is the manufacturer country.
That's because this column is not part of any of the candidate keys that we have in this table.
And therefore it's the only non-prime attribute.
And now we will check the definition of the second normal form.
Right so if we go back to the definition it says that yes this is correct it matches the personal form
but then it says every non-prime attribute of the table is dependent on the whole of every candidate
key.
Right.
The whole of every candidate.
So basically we have to check that this column is dependent on the whole of this candidate key and this
column is dependent on the whole of this candidate.
All right.
So it's obvious that this column is indeed dependent on the whole of this candidate because this candidate
only consists of one column right so you can break it up.
So this this row each or this column identifies the troll uniquely and therefore it identifies my future
country.
So there's no question about it.
But then this candidate right which consists of the two columns does manufacture country really depends
on the whole of this candidate.
So is it necessary to have manufacturer and model try to find out what the manufacturer country is.
Well not really.
Right.
Because if you just look at manufacturer you'll see that forta is always in Italy regardless of the
model.
Dental dental fresh is always in the USA.
Kobayashi's always in Japan and which is in Germany.
And we could extrapolate this and make this conclusion for even you know neuros that would be added
to the database just simply on logic because manufacturer.
This column is called manufacture.
This is manufacturer country.
So basically it is the country where the manufacturer is located the model has nothing to do with this
column.
And so basically what we see here is that manufacturer in this candidate key this can buy this commission
of these two columns the kind of key that produces inside it manufacture on its own identifies with
the manufacturer country.
So a model is not necessary for that and therefore this table does not conform to the second normal
form.
So there you go.
That's that's the issue here.
So this is not a second order form.
And at this stage you're probably wondering.
So you're probably thinking OK so I understand why it doesn't conform to second normal form but why
is it important.
Why is why is that such a big deal why.
Like why is this definition is worded the way it's worded Why.
Why are we even checking for the second or from what does it give us in practice.
Well what it gives us in practice is this table by not conforming to the second normal form is now more
prone to errors.
And it also says two things.
First of all it is speed.
It slows down the process of adding information into this database.
And the second thing is that it is more prone to errors.
So how does that happen.
Well basically now whenever I add a new row into this database.
Right.
So if I add a let's say in your toothbrush which is also produced by forté but it has a different model.
So what will happen.
I'll have to update this column.
So add a new row with the new value in this column a new value in this column because it's in your model.
This column will be a combination of the two and this column will actually be Italy.
We already know in advance that whenever we add forta it will be Italy.
All right.
And when we add dental freshy will be USA whenever we add Horridge it will be Germany in a way that
Kobayashi will be Japan.
And so basically what that means is we are duplicating some of the information we're doing extra work
by adding a new row here.
If it's the manufacturer basically identifies It's a wire it's a it's a determined relationship between
manufacturer it affects your country by adding in Euro.
You are just writing the country where as this information is already present in the database and the
like if you are and you manufacture that's omnipresent you know as soon as you add the second row for
that manufacturer you're duplicating information.
And so that takes pricing power and might not seem like a lot for one call.
But imagine if you if you had you know a thousand of these homes that fall under this like work like
this example that would be called a law.
Right.
And if you have a huge database which is which rows millions of rows are added to every hour that would
take up a lot of time.
And the second thing is there's more possibility of error right.
So if you go forward to Italy for to Italy for to Italy every time.
Right.
And then for some reason something goes wrong and you add in for to Germany then you know you've just
created an error right.
Every time you duplicate the work you you dream you that work and there's a possibility of creating
that error right.
Instead of just having that information once in your database.
And so what's the solution.
How do you turn this into a table that conforms to the second normal form.
Well it is very straightforward.
So here we've got two tables now right.
So we've got a table of actual moral and moral full name so those first three columns and then we've
separated out the manufacturer country.
So now we have a reference table where we can always look up in which country each manufacturer is located.
And now whenever we add new rows to this table they're not going to have country anymore.
The country will be just identified uniquely by that manufacturer so you can always if you need to find
our country just look up based on the manufacturer just look them up here and you'll know the country
him as a know.
Our challenge is to just check these both these tables if they conform to the second normal form.
So it's it's a pretty straightforward process.
In the first table we need to identify all the candidate keys so wonderful name is a candidate key identifies
every row uniquely.
And this is a candidate key as well.
So in this table we actually don't have any non-prime attributes or all the attributes of pride.
And in this table our candidate key is manufacturer because you know you always add new manufacturers
and maybe a manufacturer to manufacturers could be in the same country.
That's not forbidden.
Right.
So therefore this is the key and this is not a candidate key.
And so in this table we have one non-prime attribute which is this one.
So the question is about the symbol does it fall.
Does it conform to the second normal form will it come from.
And first of all on the form and it doesn't have any non-prime attributes.
So by default because it's the second normal form talks about non-prime attributes that they have to
be dependent on the whole of any candidate key.
What we don't have any non-prime actually so by default this table does conform to the second normal
form.
And in this case because our candidate key is just one column.
That means that automatically this the second form as the criteria is met because you cannot split this
into some into different columns so the non-prime attribute is going to be also dependent on the whole
of the candidate key.
So this is also second or before.
All right there we go.
So I know it's a bit it's a little of a lot of information to grasp and that's why I probably don't
recommend moving on to the third no more form right away before you take some time to really let this
knowledge sink in so maybe go through the tutorial again or look at these examples and really try to
understand what's what's going on here.
But basically what we've done as a result of May of changing the design of this table into two tables
right by doing that.
What we've created we've we've solved two issues.
First of all now when you add more records you add more electric tooth brush models into a database.
You will have to have to add information about the country unless you're adding a brand new manufacture
then you just add them once here and then you just keep adding their models and basically in that situation
you're saving processing power.
Right you same processing power and also saving memory of your database.
And again it doesn't sound like a lot for these two small tables but this is just an example to make
it simple as you can imagine.
When these principles are applied to tables with millions or billions of rows it makes a huge difference.
And the second thing is that we have reduced the potential for error rates because we've only got the
information about the manufacturer countries stored once.
Right.
It's just stored in this table and we only need to make sure that this information is correct once you
don't have to have controls making sure that every time you inputting your manufacturer you're putting
no correct country because you don't need to put the country anymore.
And that is what the second normal form helps us do.
So there we go.
That's what's the second normal forms all about and that's how it works.
I hope this tutorial made it clear and made it more easier to understand.
It is much more complex.
I agree it's much more complex and the first novel form much more complex understand but just just try
to remember that mnemonic and you know the truth the whole truth the whole truth and nothing but the
truth.
So this was the part about the whole truth or the whole key that any non-prime attribute has to be dependent
on the whole of any candidate.
That's what this trial is about.
Hope you enjoyed it and I'll look for it.
See you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.