Hello and welcome back to the course on databases we've got another exciting challenge ahead of us today.
We're working for an online clothing store.
So let's see what we have to do.
OK.
So you've been hired as a data analyst for an online clothing store.
The company is expecting to undergo a rapid expansion in the coming months and they are not sure if
the databases can handle the amount of transactions that will come with the increased number of customers.
So is the rapid expansion means lots more customers there trying to get on board means they'll be connected
with more purchase introductions and can there be data databases Hamlett or not they're not sure.
So you have been tasked to investigate the current design of the database.
If the design is found to be inefficient for online transaction processing they need to redesign the
database.
So this is a very interesting challenge because it is a it sounds like a very classic challenge for
a database administrator or a database architect and probably is.
But at the same time it's a very good opportunity for us as data scientists and analysts to practice
our skills the skills that we learn about normalization of databases.
So Charles in a session are definitely captivating and we'll certainly learn a lot.
Now let's have a look where we can get the data set for today.
So as usual we're going to need a browser and we're going to go to W.W. supercilious and dot com slash
S Q L and if you scroll down here to the bottom you will see Section 9 database design and you got the
challenge if you'd like to get the pedia file.
The challenge you've got.
PostgreSQL upload code and you've got the online store sales are LCP database example so go ahead and
download that.
That is our database for today OLTP database example.
And I'm just going to bring it up here on my computer.
So here it is the o l T.P. database.
And by the way oil Tippee stands for online transaction processing.
That's a common abbreviation that you'll be hearing quite a lot.
And here we've got our database quite a large database.
It's it's an extract and you'll see that here they've got three thousand four hundred fifty five rows
total.
And these are just the transactions for the past three days so this is 13th of December 2016 then 12th
of December 2016 and 11th of December 22nd are actually also a bit of 10th of December.
So.
So it comes from the 18:00 on the 10th to 6pm on the 13th so exactly three times 24 hours 72 hours possed
and they got three thousand nearly three and a half thousand transaction go through right.
So that's over a thousand purchases per day.
And this as you'll see further down the store has about 900 customers something like that.
And if they're expecting a rapid expansion this number is going to grow.
So can their database handle the amount of purchase that's coming their way.
Not sure.
So basically to upload this data set and then we're going to start investigating which normal forms
this database is in and correcting along the way.
If it's not meeting certain forms and as we do that we'll also understand how that's going to benefit
this company in the long run.
All right.
So this is a data set.
Let's have a look we've got a transaction ID.
We've got the time stamp when basically the transaction was conducted.
So when the purchasers made customer ID who purchased that name surname where the shipping is going
the item number description.
So basically what they purchased item and description and then the price and the discount that was applied
to that purchase.
So looks like a standard data set doesn't look like or database type of structure doesn't look like
anything's wrong with it.
But as you'll see through the tutorials in this section there is a lot wrong with it.
So the design is very inefficient for oil T.P. type of transactions.
So there we go.
Go ahead and download this database our dataset and I will see you in the next tutorial.
And until next I'm happy analyzing.