Hello.
Welcome back so of course on database's in today's Tauriel we will upload the data set for the section
into Microsoft skills server.
So let's go ahead and get started.
First thing we'll need is a browser and in the browser and you go to WWE does superdad assigns that
com slash as well.
And here if you scroll down to Section 9 database design you will see this file over here which is called
MESKEL upload code.
So go ahead and download that file.
We will need it further down in this tutorial in order to finalize the upload process.
But for now what we're going to do is we're going to first upload the raw data into Microsoft escarole
server.
So let's go ahead and get started if that were going to create a new database in your database.
And here you'll call it OLTP which has four online transaction processing that's a type of database
structure we're going to be working with in this tutorial in this whole section actually and go ahead
click OK.
So there we go databases ready.
And now we're going to just upload some data here so you can see that it's completely empty.
So if you're right click the database and go to tasks and click Import data.
We've got our import wizard here.
Go ahead click next for data source.
Select flat file source.
Find where you have placed your file for this section and just search for CACP here on the right and
select your CACP file.
Make sure to specify just one quotation mark so it's a it's a quotation marks it has two of those little
elements in it but it's one symbol that is as your text qualifier.
So a quotation mark is a text qualifier.
This should be checked.
Call them names and first they add a row.
Go to columns just have a quick click here that looks ok.
Go to advanced change all of this to 5000 so it gets imported so there's enough space where importing
all of it as strings to start with in the real file.
Then go to preview.
Have a look in the preview that everything is OK in these first couple of rows.
Everything works fine.
Click next in your destination select Microsoft only DBI provider for us gils server.
Everything is fine here.
Click next here let's rename this to this whole file is going to be or this table is going to be called
the roll underscore transactions on transactions beautiful.
Click next run immediately next and finish.
And quite a few rows.
There we go.
Everything is done.
Close the refresh.
You will see the table here so you can select 2000 rows.
This is a good start but at the moment this table is completely just strings strings strings so it's
just text so it doesn't recognize numbers.
Berkeley doesn't recognize dates and so on.
So we're going to fix that.
That's where that file that we just downloaded will come in handy.
So if you open the file see it looks like this has got this code which will allow us to convert our
role data.
So from we take taken from the raw table into formatted or into columns of the correct data type so
this can select everything from here.
It's like new query pasted in here and execute this query.
You can see 300 2255 rows have been affected.
Refresh.
Now we can see that the transactions table is ready here so we can close this.
We don't need any more than we can check.
This table looks very similar but now the table has correct the correct data types for each column.
So voila everything is ready we are prepared for this very challenging and very interesting section.
These tutorials are going to be a lot of fun as we're going to learn a lot and I can't wait to see you
next time.
Until then happy analyzing.