friends here.
We're discussing a boat encapsulation off.
Oops,
she let me already a simple by transport first.
Then we'll discuss about in population.
So let me open my sublime texture that So here I am,
defending a class called person.
So only are given script Name called some encapsulation.
Don't be way.
Let me read the first method.
Call a sign name on ish,
self name.
Then let me write a variable cord self dot name because two named and cellphone are 80
calls to age.
Then let me write Return with the none.
They let me defend one more method to display word information about your object.
Like your name on a Jawf.
Your object name.
Come up self or not.
Goof,
then return None.
That's fine.
No,
let me create a person.
Object.
I mean,
any object from your person class.
Let's supports on one equals to simply person object and let me a sign name on the age.
So if you want us a name on a judge in her to call,
you are assigned name on age Metter by bossing Let's say some name on is That's it.
No,
let me run this.
It's fine No,
I want to display the details off your person.
One object,
then I can call display matter off your object.
I can get your information instead of that promoted off your class.
If you remember,
we can also get your person one door name,
right,
or you can also get your purse.
And one dot is so let me bring so I can use display matter to displace your name and age
off your object or directly from the trade off.
A class I can call person,
wondered name or person?
Wondered ish.
But here's what I'm doing is internal affairs.
I'm taking two under schools.
Underscore Underscored ish.
Then first,
let me call you were display mentored for your object.
For that,
we'll see whether you are able to get your information or not.
Yes,
we can able to get self your name on self dot Underscore.
Underscore is arguments.
Ah were able.
It's funny.
What opposite?
That's fine.
And let me try to destroy the name from the trade off your class.
Person.
One dark name.
Yes,
it's working.
That's fine.
No,
I'm trying to display person one daughter.
I mean your objective dot is you're getting another called Know it reboot called
underscoring the school age.
Actually,
we have that variable here,
right that I tremble we're having here.
But why?
We are not able to access from motor off your class.
So this is because when nobody if we define any variable with two underscores not only
variable,
even method,
then that matter or dark variable.
You cannot access from motel off a class,
but he can access from inside off a class from anyone off your method,
right?
That's it.
That is the way how you can hide variable from your class on this is called encapsulation.
So if you use encapsulation concert for your variables are matter so that he can restrict
the access off your variable or matter from or traffic class.
Let's say I'm using I'm just going underscore display for matter.
I used underscore underscore display.
Say we thought under schools,
we are able to access.
You were display matter from your person.
One object that it's called person wonder display that was working.
Now our matter name has been modified toe underscore underscore display Now if I run the
see the result,
there is no attribute called displayed underscore underscore display.
So not only for variable.
Even if you are defining method with the pu underscores then that method you cannot access
for more trade off a class then how you can access inside off You were inside off your
anyone off the meta You can call that self lord display.
That's it.
No,
Let me come and this and see the result.
Yes,
it's working.
Right.
So the ice using Oops In Piketon we can restrict access to methods and variables And this
is nothing but simply encapsulation off your bite on hopes concert.
Okay,
so it is also somewhat useful whenever If you want a restrictive,
our data are to excellent word,
Right?
Okay,
Friends,
by this week,
a word core concepts off your pipe on.
And we know that by Tony's popular because off lot off third party models and some default
models right now from no one works.
What I will do is I will update are some important bi fold on third party models on.
After that,
I will do real time practice as well so that it will be good with your piper.
Okay.
Okay,
guys.
Thank you