friends in this video,
we're going to see how to use multiple variables or strings with your prints.
Statement on different ways to use your prints,
Shechtman.
Not we explain this.
Let me write the simple python script.
So I'm going to open my sublime texts.
Let me weapon their sublime text.
And let me give you a name for this starscape like,
ah,
working with variables or multiple variables.
So we have our working directory in the next application with by transcript there.
I'm going to store my script,
like multiple variables in Bring You can take any program,
name or strip name.
I'm taking simply this one.
Okay,
so there's I'm going to defend force or different variables.
You know,
if you want to define any variable,
right,
you can take something like this,
and I'm going to take my name.
As for language name because of some fight on scripting,
like so this is the way how to define your multiple variables are,
you know,
interrupt this right.
There is one more way that is.
You can also define your variables in a single line,
like extra close to three call.
And why?
Cause to find out seven Colon then language name equals two by Don Scripting Motor Valley.
So I,
Commander Yara this way of representing now you can run your program by defining in this
way or in this report are valid ones.
That's okay.
Know what I'm doing is I want to print all these variables like See that how I'm going to
bring.
So if you want to print one single variable,
right?
Let me say this.
I'm done it first.
I'm printing the value off yet or variable X value on.
We're getting that three and I want to print all these variables.
I can buy it X,
come awake.
A mustard with single parents treatment.
Sorry,
we don't have observed right.
We hope this one Let me run this and see the output.
Yes,
You're getting all your variables,
right?
So this is one way.
2nd 1 is start with conditions.
You want to print three variables?
Just take three curly braces undocked on.
Close your conditions with the quotations.
Are you were curly braces with conditions,
then door four months.
Whatever the order,
you want to print your variables?
I mean,
first I want to print in this curly braces Xolo.
That's why here,
out to give first X,
then white them your language name.
So in Costa first toe calibrates you will get your X value here and here you will get.
Why value on in the last calibers?
You are getting this very but right.
No,
Let me your previous Lenny's Let me keep this line.
Osiris Rex,
Come away!
Come on.
Lange's name and I'm going to come in.
This line can see the output.
You're a good signal.
No,
I want to get this in one line on this fight out 71 line by Tom Skipping in one more line.
See,
Between this,
I'm including slash in.
You know,
slashing is a special character.
A New York include,
always slash.
And in the quotations only already your calibration started in the conditions.
Only right now I'm taking slash And then he had also I'm taking slash in now See the output
.
You're getting your variable values in different lanes because off slash and whatever the
value your printing in this curly brace that is going to next line,
right?
So foster thing.
12 three,
then because I want to print a three variable values on providing order first I want to
bring the X value than way value,
then language name.
If you want to change,
you can change the order also.
Right?
No,
let me change order and print that spring One do three then not for my first.
I'm going to bring the Y value the next.
Then language name.
See the output?
Yes,
on guys in fightin three directs.
You have a one more special print Straight man on that is no spring simply yes.
Quotations,
Quotations.
Okay,
close.
So actually,
whatever you are printing between quotations,
you know,
let me write for this one values or something I didn t print as it is in output line.
Right?
And even though if you're variable is the X.
If I write x,
it won't display X value will display as dizzy X But I want to print x value then format
format you conveniently right in your car.
Liberace itself You are y value.
So they're in the butler calibrates you are value will be printed The variable value sit
output.
Now I want to print like the X value ease then x well waiver Levi's then Waverly,
right?
See X value is so this will be considered as a string.
But if read anything inside of curly braces that will be considered as a variable on in
place off,
that variable value will be displayed.
Right?
Sammy,
I need the white value.
Is somebody need the language is now Let me say we don't want it,
but I want to bring X value is yet I mean,
what about a valley?
We're getting in one line?
The waiver.
Levi's second line on this in next line.
Then just right before you are lying,
slash in and see the output where you're getting your output for each and everything.
That's it,
right?
So there's tried to use this 11 to print a straight man.
Okay.
And one more thing.
Whatever you how in your printed statement with quotations,
the same thing you can also assigned to some variable.
Also,
let me do that.
Let me take my required output.
I'm breaking in this way.
I mean,
whatever the information I want to print,
I can write in this way also.
And I'm starting that into my variable.
Now,
finally,
I can print my variable in this way.
This will also what's under the output.
Well,
for two,
it is working.
Right.
So be clear.
So that is my solution is okay,
Because we're learning.
Fight on three Rolex.
Try to use this one.
It is very simple one.
No need to get confused If you want to print any string dirty radio string if you want to
print any very were variable value,
right?
Your available income.
Liberace is the is the enhanced you want in your treat.
Our necks.
Okay,
right.
So this is the way how to work with multiple variables and multiple strings.
So these are variables,
you know,
the X way and language name on this directly string,
you're placing the society a string and finally remember that whatever you are printing
that result,
they can also assert into one variable in this way.
Right?
This is very,
very helpful that way.
How you're going to assign,
write or print output statement to any variable Like look again.
Thank you for watching this with you.