prince in this video,
we're going toe.
See how to provide input for your pie Transcript.
Wild running.
I'm how to provide output from your by transcript.
And also we're going to see the uses off a malfunction.
Right.
So this year I'm explaining this concert from my Lennox books.
I'm opening my Atlantic Stedman right from there.
I'm going to explain about this.
And you can also try the same thing.
Whatever I'm trained from UNIX or UNIX,
like systems or Lennox even on your windows as well.
Without any change,
the only thing on our windows we configured fight on us simply python.
But the year fight on is like fight on three name,
right?
Fine.
Let me write simply a skeptical input and output script Not be Wait.
So,
guys,
I'm going to design a simple ah Palatinate.
Artemis.
Caligula.
So simple are my dick calculator.
So I'm fixing numbers like a close to And because toe right then I am finding the result
equals two year plus B and I'm going toe print the early shelf.
Yeah,
I be He's so here.
I'm going to print my result.
Fine.
So this is our script.
Whatever we have now I'm going toe printed The result with the help off.
Bite on tree not with So if you see simply pipe down then it will work from fight on two.
Invite on to your own.
How like this syntax you have four matters string you don't now only invite on treaties
there so piped on three Input Dando It's working perfectly But if you observe our script is
like simple automatic calculator are simply addition Collect me you only option as edition
Simple addition calculator because I'm not being here as off No addition Subtraction,
multiplication and division Let me does only simply tradition,
right?
So what?
That would just give you how as off Now that script,
If you run with any number of times Europe would would be always 12 for foreign eight,
right?
But my requirement is if it is an addition calculator while running in this way our
stripper has to our skin dirty or so and so number Enter your B number and then it has to
do the result Each time it has to ask each time it has to take two numbers.
Then it has toe find the desert.
But as I know we are fixing our values year and being set off your script,
but I don't want to ruin their.
Then what I can do is insure coffee a close to four.
Always.
I'm going to read my number from command line so far that this is a syntax and reevaluate.
So whatever you're writing inside off your input parents is in in terms off quotations that
will be printed as thes on you're Come on line.
Then let me take even for we also input and that be value,
right?
So as off No,
I'm not going to perform.
You were a desert because I want to show you something.
Drink.
The value for years is Yeah,
I It's a type ease.
I mean,
what is the data type?
I want to print that.
So type off you want to you,
right?
Let me check it.
You can check you in for B.
Also,
I'm taking only four by tone.
Sorry Spell Mystic.
Be white.
The it Julian.
Something wrong?
Where is it?
I puffy bring Okay.
Sorry.
We're using Python.
It's not fight on fight on three because we're working with fight on three fortune only.
Invite on three abortion.
We help.
You have for a month or two strings.
Okay.
See that?
Yeah.
Before that,
let me show you.
You are script ones.
So this is your school,
you know,
But not if you're on your bike landscape.
It will run from up to down on while running.
If any line started with Hashim on that line won't exclude.
Same plate will skip.
Now you have only three lines in your program.
These two on this line.
So because off a cause to input first you're skeptical.
Take input with this command some value from common land.
Let me enter some value.
45 on some be value,
then see the output.
You're getting value 45 like a string.
But you know,
that is a number.
We want to feel that as a number.
But your bite on three is taking with help off in port,
right,
that as this string.
So what are the input?
Your programming.
That is always a string if you're really that with help off input.
Right?
But that hasn't fight on to you.
How Input to read numbers.
Anyhow,
Ryan put to read strings.
But a year there is a common common inputs is their common input statement.
Is there that is input through which water you are reading from common line.
That is always the string.
Then how you can convert to your required that a type?
We are different things.
I'm in different types.
Let me weapon my fight on three.
Colonel graze Whatever we're going to discuss now that will work only with by country,
not with bite onto Let's X equals two input.
Right and bricks.
So I went Bring something.
What happened?
Yeah,
I started with single condition and nervous Double collection.
That's wrong.
And medics,
I'm ending something gold for physics.
Like then See that Taipa fix strength.
But I want to feel that as a number in teacher.
So that's why wild reading,
you know,
type conversion.
We help tonight.
So simply you can write in this way.
Read on then.
Cannot in does in Dijon.
This is one way.
So what?
There Whatever you are entering from your common line something wrong.
Indentation.
Yeah,
Noble read something and can work that into invasion.
No.
See that print pipe off your ex in visa write articles,
You know,
one more the fold function cause called evolution.
Using this,
based on whatever the data you are entering,
your python will identify what I posted that you are entering.
Let me under some three,
not four,
right?
No printed type of fix float so a violation function will automatically come.
What?
You're given their timeto Portland data type.
Anyway,
input is only two red strings.
But if you want to read some other values,
you hard to use evaluation.
Right?
Fine.
Let me do one thing.
I'm going to repeat same input and then six No,
I'm going to Endor a string call height,
right?
Si hai is not defined.
It is not taking So when nobody If you're using evaluation,
I never know if you are providing a string anybody fall input.
These here is really to read is a tow string.
But but nobody.
If you're using evaluation,
you had to bribe radio string as a quotations not to no Bring Taipa fix.
That's it.
Okay,
so me Dia use X equals two a well input.
Enter your required thing on whenever If you're entranced ring me.
Please provide in terms off quotations other ways.
If you want to read only strings simply use this one.
Enter your string and in this case,
you know need to provide anything inside off.
Your quotation simply can buy.
Hi.
Hello.
That's it.
Tonight.
No See Print.
Exe It will work.
So whenever refuse evaluation function for you were in port then you are to write your
condition inside off double quotes like Okay,
now let me design your simple calculator.
So input you have all relation.
Okay.
These are syntax to really your numbers.
Of course,
you can also use type conversion but I'm using this one.
These,
of course,
somewhat better.
I will tell you that as well,
guys.
So first of all,
Abdul,
your script you're having now this may number of lines 12345 Because our first line,
if I run my pythons kept with fight on three right?
Because our first line it is reading something.
Second line it is reading something.
Then you're getting addition Eight on type is in danger for your year.
Even be is also same,
right?
So same program.
You can also write in this way without any confusion.
Let me come and forced all these lines.
So what I'm doing is Yeah,
because to in Asia,
but this in tax will work only to read Indian numbers.
But you may anybody in Egypt Oh,
right.
Some floor.
Or maybe some complex sometimes.
So that we don't prefer this one night.
So I don't prefer this,
actually.
But just the reason.
One more option in games.
If you want to walk purely with indigenous,
right,
then at that time,
you can take this one.
But by using evolution automatically,
it will identify you.
What are the data you are and bring right?
So I'm wondering for if I see that mine.
Indeed it.
But if we enter something like find out seven I,
it is not accepting because it it need only in digital values.
Right?
But if I use simply with evaluation,
it will work perfectly.
So that's the reason.
If you want to read anything from command line,
just try to use a valuation off your input on out of that time.
In case if you want to provide any strings,
he hard to write your strings in terms off conditions,
but anywhere's off.
Now we're going to work with the numbers on the Let me take for that fight a nine dart,
some to see the result.
It's working perfectly.
So that's why guys the his my station tried to use because we're going for anywhere.
Definitely.
All our names will use bite on three only.
That's why.
Just try to remember in this way to read inputs.
Okay.
Thank you for watching this video.