friends in this Rio We're going toe work with bite on strings or strings.
Variables on.
We're going to discuss Onley.
Very basics.
In the next year,
we will see some good ones level operations with your strengths.
Right,
Fine.
So yes,
you are.
You know,
some basic Sophia strings.
Let me start with introduction.
What is a string and fight on?
First of all,
it may be invite on R C or Java wherever teas string is simply a sequence off characters CV
How you know,
a desert,
some 26 characters,
small and capital,
right.
And also we have some symbols,
like a dollar car.
It right slash on and hash are the rate.
All are also characters,
right?
So you have a lot off characters with your to create your strength.
Like then that character is simply a symbol,
for example,
right?
We already seen this Then see,
even though if your provided were information as a string while writing you are not only
fight on with any language computer,
do not deal with your characters.
40 with your strings.
They deal with numbers that is binary numbers.
Even though you may see characters on your screen internally the store and manipulated as a
combination off binary numbers.
They are like jurors on ones,
but you don't bother about how took on what he was stringing toe by.
Neri's right,
Your fight on software,
you're quite an interpreter will take care of that way,
lining your fight on program or fight on script,
right?
So the conversion of Carter's to a number is called,
including,
I Mean,
the conversion off your characters in terms Off binary is called,
including on the reverse process is called De Corti.
So there now two types off,
including techniques.
They're like asking and unique or which are popular.
So previously,
the most of the including is in terms off a ski.
Now the ah,
including technique all most of the languages they're using unique or technique right.
So in Buyten's thing is a sequence off unique or character.
Unicord was introduced to include every character in all languages on bring uniformly in,
including right.
So simply that is one of the mechanism to convert the world our data into wineries.
But you don't bother about that.
If you want to know much about this unique or technique,
are some asking Unicord technique.
You just google it.
You will get a lot of stuff for that.
Right?
Find what our dusting is there Europe item that is a unique or character Are Unicord screen
night?
That's fine.
Then how do create a string in vital?
Yes.
For this I'm going toe weapon.
My sublime texture.
Taste Don't get confused.
Sometimes I'm using we a murder.
Sometimes I'm using pyjamas.
Sometimes I'm using sibling text.
They So if you're confusing,
just try to use Veum from command line.
That is very simple.
Or you can use by jumped X as well.
But if you take sublime text,
someone text won't accept input from you seeing your previous videos,
right,
We have seen somewhere input on some output statements.
So input.
We are reading something from your common line.
So that thing is not possible with help off sibling text,
it is possible with your pie,
chum or simply from your VM editors.
Right?
That's okay.
First,
I'm going to show you how to create a sting and bite from you guys Already we have seen
somewhere,
while discussing about different types off date us or data types in your fight on about
your string called Defining String Late.
Let me go with one second about your strings because it is very,
very important.
Working with strings is very,
very important when writing your real time scripts,
right?
Let me go with my common line.
They're having this thing here.
I'm going to write simply,
like were in direction do strings.
Not feeling you guys let let's say any variable.
I'm taking my name.
Write my name.
It goes to simply I'm writing.
Suppose.
Let's say not interrupt.
Not just know we defined a variable called my name on in that we stored a string chord.
Narendra,
right?
Let let's say it's up.
Was my new name,
right?
Some fight on?
No.
But see,
I can take a There's single courts or double course through representive of string.
Right?
All right,
I'm going to take my right.
I can also write in this way tribal courts.
Nobody can take either single or double or treble courts.
Let let's say I started,
like India as,
um at me.
All right,
more in both automation team state.
See,
guys here.
My intention is how do you single double and triple courts let let's say I want to print
all the variables.
My name is so here.
I want to bring my name.
Let's say variable is my name,
right?
So whatever the information,
I hope that I want to print in the next lane.
That's why I'm taking slash and then I'm breaking.
My new name is so here.
I want to print like my new name.
Then after that,
I want to print some more information on that is my in four is so very Please,
you are in for my in four.
Right?
Then close it.
Save it,
Andranik.
And see the output.
You're getting your information perfectly.
Whether you're going to use singular double or triple courts,
that is no problem.
Right?
Know what I'm doing is see,
I am taking people courts.
And,
uh,
in this way I'm writing my string.
No,
See,
that would put how you're going to get No.
Whatever you are providing inside off tribal courts,
maybe a single line or multiple lines the same format will be preserved even while printing
.
So if you want to write multiple lines,
go on,
take level courts.
Right.
So single,
double or triple courts,
you can take people.
Courts also for always.
But whenever If you want to write multiple lines off information,
they only go on.
Take civil courts.
See,
I have taken the information between tribal courts as the two lines.
That's where your information is.
Two lines after that last output,
right?
So that's the way how you can I mean,
create history,
then hopeful axes categories in your strength.
Let's say I'm going to take let me come into all those things with the civil courts.
Say you can also use table course to comment,
right?
No,
I'm takings up was my name are my favorite scripting.
This is a variable I'm taking Simply fight on stripping is my photo Okay,
there's one more thing Let me show you that Ah,
my string I'm taking like this one Our my new string I'm taking like this one so faster
string is empty string nothing Second string is even though if you have a space space is
also one of the character in your python scripting I'm not sure about other scripting
languages but in bite on space is also one under scripting Sorry.
Space is also one of the character Let me bring you know if I can work,
right?
Any data into bullion?
You for these having something,
then you will get true.
If it is having nothing,
then you will get false,
right?
I forgot to provide single quotation ending.
I don't see that put false because this is empty in job that let me take my new string on.
See,
the output you're getting prove means because something is there that something is space.
Space is also one of the character,
you know,
Remember,
this is also very,
very important point.
That's fine.
No,
Grace,
what I'm doing is I'm going to print my entire string.
Of course,
you can use your format and you can print in this way,
right?
What you can also you simply print my favorite skipping motor valley.
You'll get output for both,
right?
Based on situation,
you will select that.
So now I'm going toe other former off your print in this week.
So if I printed simply variable,
you are going to get the entire spring right now.
What I want is I want to get I suppose some first A character from your string or some last
character from using or some part off your string.
Then how you can access right?
See before going toe that I wanted you an explanation about index values.
Let's say you have a world called Python.
Simply,
your swing is simply python B Y t hedge,
William,
let me do one thing.
B Y O b Hoech.
William,
this is your string.
Just assume that,
but nobody.
If you are saying any string like this for your variable,
let's say my string I'm taking my are simply my costume I'm doing in this way,
right.
Your python will assign some positions for your characters which are there in your string.
So very first character is index Eljero Second characters index one second Authorities in
next to forties in next three.
This is 500 sees,
but this is for on last one is fight.
So these are the positions off your characters We taught there in your given string.
Likewise,
for your pie town skipping If you take this variable than this is Jiro.
12345 spaces Also one character 6789 10 11 12 13 14 15 Do you know to 15 Index values are
there for your given string,
right?
Let's say I'm taking simply python only.
Okay,
See,
that would put first.
You're getting your python.
Know what I'm doing is simply am printing.
You are a favorite stripping in square brackets.
I'm taking zero and see the output.
What you're getting.
We're getting P because P position is Jiro or P index.
Value is Jiro.
That's why we're getting that.
Let's say I want to bring last little young from your given string last as of no your last
indexes fight.
See that?
That's a so based on index value,
you can access particular character from your given strength.
So these these are the past two index values you can also I'm in.
Pipeline will also assign negative index values from right to left.
Any that minus one.
So three minus four minus phi I minus six so you can work with negative as well as
posturing Nexus.
Based on your requirement,
you can go with pause to or negative.
Let's say I want to bring starting in starting letter starting character from your given
string,
then for your starting character,
always in extra Jiro the same b,
the ending ending character and in character indexes.
If you go it pause to emit a country.
But if you go with the negative,
it is always minus one.
So this starting character in Dixie Jiro ending character indexes,
maybe in terms off past of your toe cone.
But if you go with the negative,
it is always to minus one.
This is very,
very important.
Well,
working with your real time scripts,
let's say I want to print biting for the last two character.
I don't know what it is there.
I don't want to come to the end expressions.
Also,
by default,
I can take minus one.
No,
see,
that would put what you're going to get.
You're going to get young.
No need to count.
0123455 is the last index are and last character index.
But if we can take minus one,
which will do the last two character from your given string,
let's say I hope Eitan scripting as my string night.
So G is the last character.
I want to get that simply take minus one.
No need to count your index values when a transit output.
We are getting Xeno just by taking minus one.
Okay,
so this is the way how to access particular character from your given strength.
Right?
Let me bring something called my favorite scripting.
So I'm giving Jiro toe some fight.
So you fight taking this way it will bring you are characters from general to four because
maximum ease Fei Index.
But you are starting from Jiro Ranges five minus 05 letters You are to get those who get
file it us from Jiro.
You are to take the Earth Index forced index second index,
fourth index.
I see.
If I take be white b hedge wool,
Right?
Fine Art is over.
No fight characters that will work.
So what is the range between fired fired?
05 minus zero fight characters you're getting starting from index zero.
That means you will get up to fourth index value.
See,
that would put Suppose if I want to get 15 next as well.
You have to take six because,
dear,
up to six or seven characters.
But you're to get only six during the six minutes Rangers six,
you're getting six character snow,
right?
If I take simply Jiro and then Colon,
then the meaning for the days get from job to last a very character.
Not Okay.
So that's what the what?
The operation.
You are performing index operations,
right?
These are also called as slicing off your given strength slicing operation on these
operations are not going to modify your adjusting right only while printing You're getting
something.
If you want to store this into some other variable,
let's say given string from supposed 0 to 14 decks,
then my favorite scripting Then from that juror toe Pfeiffer take then only will get gelato
for.
Then you can print that you are given string general before you don't put.
Not so.
Okay,
fine.
So these the way how you can access your strings based on index values You have one more
thing.
Let me tell you that bring you were string.
I am not giving starting,
but I I'm giving suppose ending index eight.
Or let's say,
simply fight so they will be clear.
See the output.
So gelato 14 decks.
Five minutes ending five minutes before that index.
It will your value.
Not only that,
I want to print up with some fourth index to some 10th index values characters.
So 4 to 10 ranging six.
Not only they can take 11 also ranges seven so you will get 45678 Mine then.
So by 10 thing,
legs were getting seven characters.
That's why it will your toe for toe 10 only.
If you mention 11 it will go up to 10 in next.
Characters see the output.
Right,
Fine.
So there's gold slicing off history.
So how do you change your diligence string So days strings are basically immutable.
That means once if you define Iwas string,
you cannot change the part off your strength.
But you can complete it,
delete it or you can completely assigned new string.
For that I mean suppose Let's say if I tried to modify generating next disease means foster
character,
right?
With some other thing.
Let's say in See you're getting another record string object does not support item
assignment.
So you cannot modify part off your string like our Let me pray with the daily.
You don't delete option is there,
right?
We had it under discussion on this 25 Sundays.
String officer does not support item relation,
so you cannot delete part off your string.
But entirely young tasting.
You can delegate see that you're not getting any output.
I mean,
Eleanor put because you are the living completely at the same time you can,
Billy.
Oh,
you can assign completely new thing for this.
That's it.
No,
there is no other.
No offer this.
If you print there was strain.
Your string is nothing.
Fight on tutorials,
right?
So there's you cannot delete the part offspring Orica.
You cannot assign particular character in your given string with the new value.
Right?
But you can completely change or delete dio string.
The next one is how to find lent off history.
So nothing is that there is a pre defined function called Len.
Let me find my string length as a one variable my string length as one new variable I'm
taking,
and I'm finding length off your favorite stripping,
right?
See that?
No imprinting length off given string is so where you're storing your length.
India variable called my string land right?
Let me observe Output Runner of the 16 year getting barbarically you can print no need to
store until you are ah,
lending to some other variable.
Let's say length off a given string ease even on a direct this message.
Also,
it is your wish.
So in square,
but cuddly brain says right?
Just a light lento function off you were given variable.
That's a no gays lend Means How many characters are there any given stream?
No.
If you have a 16 characters in a given string,
right,
there is some string anyhow,
16 characters,
any given string,
then your index value start from 0 to 15 yard.
To remember this,
it will be helpful for your online exams.
Genital 15 Joe come from Joe,
then by 15 year getting 16 characters these positive elfin next values negative way from
minus one to minus 16 if its lending 16 they night away.
Next,
valets are from minus one to minus 16.
Like No,
let me print simply your favorite scripting off a minus one.
So we modified somewhere our string to fight on two durians.
Last batteries?
Yes.
So directly I can get that.
Yes,
I am getting our because length is 15 16.
Then lost the character index in terms off.
Pause to east 15.
See that you're getting lost or parties Es only right.
Fine on one more thing days.
Let me go in this way.
I want to print from minus 16.
Too minus fight.
See the airport minus 16 minutes.
Force to character.
Right in dumps off.
Negative because lengthy.
16 Jiro is by default foster character.
Or,
if you know the length,
plenty 16 here,
then minus length is the foster character in your given strength like No if I tried toe
print minus phi too minus 16.
See the output?
You won't get anything because starting values always lower value minus y is not lower than
minus 16.
Minus Phi is for for greater than minus 16.
Right?
So that's why you have to take always starting with low,
low in next value and you can get the best on your record index.
See if I didn't dump self pause to it is very clear for you.
My favorite.
Skipping someone Let me take four is the lowest value.
I'm starting with four,
and I want to get up to support some gold index.
That farm instinct starting.
See that?
Put what you're getting.
You're getting somewhat put.
Space is also one of the character for that.
Also,
you have some in exposition like find these away how you can find the length and we can
access or how you can delegate strength.
Then finally,
you're going to see how to add or can coordinate two strings.
Nothing is that Let me come in.
Whatever the Cortijo as off?
No.
So I'm going to come in Maine,
so I don't want to exclude this core.
Fine.
Let me take my string equals to suppose some fight on.
I mean,
let me take this as a my string one.
You can take any variable name that I'm taking My string two equals to some scripting.
No,
I want to add this to actually anybody for writing strings.
You ought to say concurred.
Nick concurred in their pull strings instead of firing It is a better word to use
Concarneau Nation concurred in it those things.
So I'm going to add these two and I'm going to create a new string called My String Trees.
Because toe my string one places the symbol toe can coordinate R two r two strings.
Then I am printing.
You were third string Whatever you how observed output while you're getting okay somewhere
we are using my strength.
Reword is line number 60 0 still,
we have some mines here.
I was the one thing I really find here.
And then it's fine.
See,
the airport body are getting You are getting fight on scripting.
But there is no space between these two words,
right?
So if you want fired space between these two words,
you can add some space.
At the end of forces string are the starting off second string.
But that is not a good way because already some where you defend your strings only what?
Harding,
You should not disturb your existing strings,
right?
So nothing is there.
Between these two strings are the one most ring.
That thing is pestering that we dig one more string called My string with some space equals
two empty string Right now you can Are that my string with the space,
then place.
See that put Now you're getting this piece?
No,
actually,
your intent is We're adding a space between these two strings.
For that,
you know,
knitter defining news thing instead of dirt.
Dramatically way larding your strings You can add in this way Let me take my string.
Three equals toe my string one place some space.
No spaces.
Also,
sting definitely cannot in this way also goingto defined for that one new string variable.
And no need to include that in your operation.
See,
that would know you're getting this space so likewise you conard any number of strings.
Let's say I'm going to add one.
One more string by giving a space.
And then why don skipping tutorials?
So the charity I can are two variables are variables with some strings.
Right?
So by this example,
you should be good with how to add two strings variables to string variables.
Our instinct variables with directly a string.
So these two are string variables on this is space.
This is space on the tutorials automatically strings.
You're using the inside of your operation.
Right?
Fine.
So they These are the minimum basics off your strings.
So we will see in the next video how to work effectively with your strings and add wants
level operations off your sprints.
Okay.
What?
You guys thank you for watching this video