prince here we're going to discuss three important or string operations.
There are,
like,
enjoying center on Jiro feel right?
So how they're going to work?
Let me show you that by taking my potential.
Of course,
you can also write in the world by transcript,
But I'm things simply bite on common line.
Let's say I have a string called by tone Hi.
See my requirement?
Ease from this the X.
I mean from this fight on world,
I want to creative by tone word by placing between each two letters to characters.
It's space.
I mean,
I want to clear the way data such that it has to be in this way.
But I want to create that from your ex itself.
Simply why you cause to quotations on inside that just hyphen dot Join many what it's so
just to join space inside off your ex between your characters.
Simply print way right,
otherwise directly can print.
See,
as of now,
I am printing X in this way.
No bring.
You can also do something like suppose I'm adding starts between who characters in my given
x sido put or I want to bring the one by one letter,
then our slash and you know,
slash and means new line.
See that you're getting those stringing multiple lines in each leg.
One character,
because leiston purposes.
Otherwise,
let me add slash d c output.
You're writing tab between two characters off your given string.
Right?
So that is the importance off your joints Train.
Right.
Fine,
then the next one is center.
See,
guys,
sometimes you have some multiple strings on.
Do you want to bring all strings in the center?
Off your 10.
Miller in the center off some weight off your tunnel.
Let's say I have in my string call simply fight on And how one more new string called by
Don scripting and let me take some third string My string three equals two string
operations.
Okay,
now see there I'm going Toe print.
First of all,
let me take only my string not center So all strings So I want to bring the with the veto
supports some 20 characters now,
First of all,
let me print my first district So in quantity spaces you're string is there in the middle
of that.
Likewise I want to bring it that we use format all these things at a time.
I want I'm going to print.
Right?
So in the next line I want to print you are my new the stream dot center 20.
See the output ability can understand What is the purpose of this center?
Then?
I want to bring you are ah next available called my string three Not center 20 and see the
output Something missing.
Let me see that.
Yeah,
Quotations is missing.
Right?
See the output Woman C and P.
Uh,
yes.
Summer spelling mistake.
See?
Nothing is there.
Guess what?
Our The lengthy or giving force.
Your python will take that much.
Lend in that length.
It will try to bring the war string from middle Yours left and right.
That's it.
Okay,
now,
Dreadful Jiro,
I'd Jiro Phil,
let me do one more thing.
Ah,
like,
uh,
bring let me take simply You will string.
I am printing.
You're getting something?
No,
but I want to print this a string.
Okay.
With something spaces on.
Anyway.
Your python string consist off only six characters.
The remaining forced places I want to part with the geo towards left.
See that total spaces are 10.
Right?
So you were given single undies.
Six remaining fourth places towards left.
I want to part with the judo.
So parting this our presence is call actually parting.
Right.
This operation is called actually the party.
Okay,
so there's these are the operations.
Ah,
uses off your joint center and jet feeling.
Hi.
Okay.
Thank you for watching this video.