my friends here.
We're going toe.
See how to install python on Windows operating system.
So,
friends,
we're going to work with Fight on three dot Exe.
So whether these three dot extortion or to write extortion,
you can definitely don't know from your official website called www dot fight on dot Are
let me weapon this website first not fight on No,
no,
no.
This is we want to Don't Lord fight on software.
Right?
So we have your different types off options as of no,
I'm going with the downloads because we need by done soffit on here.
Also,
if you Abdul here we have been knows Mike ways some other flat forms as off.
No,
I'm going to work with windows,
right?
So,
no,
you can select the windows here or directly the showing on the latest washing off three or
text that is piped on.
$3.7 or three on.
Not that bite on 3.5 plus,
Washington cannot be used on Windows XP or earlier,
so you have to use the latest one.
I mean,
no sex pr a more lettuce,
One for your windows.
Right on.
Anybody here directly?
Condone.
Know this fight on $3 7 or three or just click on youthful list off downloads.
Right now.
Here we have windows.
So I next want another thing.
So I'm selecting windows.
Right?
No.
Observed here.
So in fight on three,
the latest Washington as portrait this one fight on $3 under teh turned into it is two
roads are not 16 right?
So we are going to work with the three neurotics on.
You can go with the either three or five or 36 or seven,
right?
I'm going to select $3.7 dollars zero.
That is my fair question.
You can take simply pipe on three dots under three also.
No problem.
Right?
Let me go and see.
Fight on three doors.
$7 0 charities.
Yeah,
Somewhere we Mr that six year,
70 year night.
I'm going toe don't Lord.
Windows 86 64.
Executable installer.
Right,
Because if you want to select of a busy install a recon selector,
Geoff file So this is the best one for me.
I'm selecting this one.
So my old rating system is 64 bait Windows 10.
No,
it is okay with my opening system.
I'm done.
Or in this?
Yes.
Right.
But the weapon that file No,
just simply right.
Click or you can do two times.
Click on you are Don't worry.
Fight like all right week than weapon or run as administrator.
Yes,
we connect.
So guys here,
if you observe insult,
fight on $3 are not Jiro.
64 bit install now merited We install your python in this location right somewhere here.
I don't want to install in this location.
I want to install in my require location,
Right?
What I will lose.
I will go with custom installation.
And also you can are everywhere by 20 not 72 parts.
So this if you're working with fight on three I mean,
if you're installing Python three then only will get this option.
If you installed fight on two right?
You won't get this option.
Now I'm selecting this and customization off your installation Justly gun there.
See that gays are by tone 372 parts.
Then customize installation.
Nothing.
But I want to change my park.
I mean,
where I want to install my part on software.
So for that I'm changing in trough install.
Oh,
I'm going with customized installation.
Then simply click a next no year trough,
this Celente part.
What I warm going toe ace simply I'm installing somewhere here by tone.
See currently you can also provide your user home.
There you can install or simply can provide your required,
but I'm taking this one.
Just install.
That's it.
Very simple.
Not only this sort resort sound or Joe any three door next.
Washington's very simple to install.
Like once it is done,
then I wish for you just wait for some time on anybody.
Meanwhile,
we will see one more thing in a web of shell website documentation case.
See here NA Commendation.
So you help by phone reader X documentation as well as fight on uber X documentation.
If you can.
Don't know this or by opening this you can go through your official documentation on you
can learn your piper,
right?
So you hope documentation for three nordex on products in your official website itself.
So if you want,
you can go through that and again learn your fighter,
right?
Fine.
No,
Once it is done,
I want to show you one more thing.
That is once.
If your installation is done,
Then you had to cross check whether you successfully installed your pipe on read or sound
or Joe or not or you re quite right on Washington,
right?
It's almost done.
Just wait for sometime.
It will complete
states
taking time just right for some more time.
Once that is done,
then almost your installation is done.
But we have to cross check.
We had a very fight,
so I will show you that.
How do?
Very fine,
right?
Just give me some time so that or installation will be complete.
Yes.
Now see that python terror 70 at two parts.
So it starting now it's almost done.
Fine.
Sort of was successful.
Yes,
to close it and just open your common lane,
right?
Simply run python space you are washing.
See that you're getting or you can also run.
Simply python space haIf on Capitol V right?
And you can also check.
See that So people is nothing.
But if you want to install any required third party piped on modules with help off people
you can able to install right anyway,
we'll see how to install on how to work with people while going forward for time.
We just We are installing fight on under.
Then we are verifying whether we install your fight on successfully or more like.
See if you want to go with your installation location.
Just like on the work.
See this one?
Anyway,
I hope I don't to write ex husband,
right?
Well,
going forward.
Sometimes I will show you what is.
The difference is between EUR three or decks and cortex.
So for that,
I installed fight on to run X as well.
So just know we installed this one fight on three directs.
So these the by turns off there bite on especially.
It is called interpreter Bite on interpreter.
Right.
So that is the is the are simple way to install your python on a wood windows opening
system.
Okay.
What?
You guys thank you for watching this video.