friends.
In our previous videos,
we have seen some off the string operations know based done that sting operations.
I'm going to write one simple python script the Huskies display given string at right side
or left side or center off the line in title for Mark.
Right?
Let me weapon on either.
So here,
I'm going to use some blame text as my editor.
Okay,
So,
guys,
our tasking display given string on your terminal in a line,
maybe at right side or left side.
Ordered center indictee.
Former.
So before going to display.
First of all,
you should reads some input.
You should read some string as your input.
You know,
in bite onto Really?
Oh,
string.
We have a syntax called input.
Right.
That's what I'm taking given string.
Whatever.
This thing you're going to provide,
I'm going to read.
So you have a syntax call in port?
Entry was string.
That's it.
No,
I'm going to print your given string first.
Let me save it.
10 days.
I'm going to run this by transcript from common line because I want to provide input.
So whenever if you want to provide in Portage but had to run your script from Common Line.
Always so.
The script name which are taken here is a line text R P by now.
Let me open your skip the first.
Now I'm going to run your script.
It is asking Antonio String.
Yes,
I'm going to under suppose bite on scripting it is displaying.
This is unpaid language.
This is one line right on that line.
By default,
your python is displaying your string That left side not anywhere.
That is the default format for the whale displaying your data through python.
But my requirement is along with dark in the next lane I won't display in a center after
that,
I won't display at the right side in a line night.
See if you want to display your string ID right side.
First you have to know how many columns are there in a given line or what is the will it
off that line are someone's If I one display in the middle of a line or center a feline.
First of all,
if I know total number off columns in the line are ripped off your line,
then I can divide that into two parts in the middle like in display my string right See for
my windows operating system to know number off columns There is a command called more so
true which there are 1 22 columns are there.
That means in each and every line you can write 1 22 characters find if you remember there
is a center operation on a string.
We are discussing this about your strings.
So print my string at center by conserving terminal line with as 1 22 that let me run this
from command line that authorities displaying in the center off the line Same way I want to
display my string Let me bleed given string dot left The just so that is the operation to
adjust your string Two words left the site So in a really tough 1 22 right Just are just
your string towards left side Same way If I want to display my string towards right side
then on just that's a no Let me go on Come online Let me run it So I'm wondering Fight on
stripping See the result Because off one prince treatment you're displaying in the middle
or centre on left side and then exactly right side.
Right.
Fine.
We know that by Tony's platform Independent.
All right.
No.
Let me copy this court and open my Lennox box.
This is my Lennox books race.
Okay?
No,
let me open a script to call and text.
R p Y I'm going to copy and paste whatever the cored V ran on the windows operating system
.
Let me save it and let me run it.
See the output?
Yesterday's asking.
Antonio String.
I'm wondering quite on stripping.
It's it's walking somewhere.
I mean,
it's displaying somewhere middle,
but not exactly in the middle.
But right side left side is working perfectly.
Left aside,
if you see it is displaying your string at left aside,
only some part on the remaining part it is displaying in the next lane.
It's not working properly.
The reason is,
see only what we know.
So operating system for my terminal as off No,
right.
The number of columns are wanting to do,
but on UNIX operating system for this terminal,
the columns may be different.
See that 112 not 1 22 That's why it is not working.
Probably.
But you fix of the column values number off columns inside off the script.
Colonel,
will you fix it as 1 22?
That's not correct,
right?
Even maybe on Windows offering system.
Also based on your screen size.
The call number of columns may be very based on my screen size.
It is 1 22 same scoop.
If you run on your windows,
offering some,
there is no guarantees that it is going toe off perfectly.
The reason is the columns may be differently.
No up any.
What are US terminal Based on your wonder size?
That's why injury fixing the column number off columns in a line or a tougher line as 1 22
If there is any logic to identify automatically,
then it will work properly.
Right City Let me woman quite on terminal.
Yes,
there is a default model or fight on skeptic Always to find out your ways.
Information your system information with ways dot get terminal sighs.
So it is going to give both the column stern lines,
but I need only columns.
Then do one more thing.
DOT Columns right State is giving 1 22 same command.
If you go on the run on my line.
X box.
Let me enter into my part on three.
Right?
I'm gonna bring first.
I'm importing ways.
Then see the result 11 tau.
So python is now automatically identifying the number off columns off your terminal.
So now,
if you use this lousy,
then you're skipping.
Look perfectly on Eun eternal size.
Right?
So this here don't worry about ways.
Ways is the default model.
So which is useful,
Toto?
Some required operations for that.
You need to write a quality.
Pretty different court is that we're trying to use them.
So we have a separate section for that There.
You can understand very easily what I'm being.
What I'm doing is very first,
I'm going to import waste model.
Then I'm taking a variable called terminal with you can take any variable,
right?
So get terminal size,
then columns the engine of 1 22 right?
Simply right,
Colonel,
with that is the variable in their fight on will automatically identify the number off
columns in your line based on your terminal.
Now you can copy this court and exclude on your operating system so that it will look
perfectly right.
Fine.
No.
Let me run the score.
and see the result.
Let me under.
Bite on scripting Now it's working perfectly,
right?
Same core.
Let me copy to your Windows operating system on there.
I will run so that he is the editor.
Save it on.
Go to your terminal exit from your potential,
then ran.
You are Olympics.
Yes,
it's working perfectly.
Okay.
But actually our requirement is along with the left,
right and center.
I need to print your string in the title.
Former.
You know,
that is the operation called dot Ideal,
not ideal annual string.
So simply a play.
One more operation dot center dot BiDil.
So this will print.
They were result in the title for my right for title.
Former is nothing.
Bird in each and every word.
Starting letter is kept a little.
Let me check it.
I'm providing all our small letters.
No,
see,
that is our in each and every word.
Starting lotteries,
Capital,
that's what title former.
Right.
Okay.
Okay,
guys,
Thank you for watching this video