preference here.
We're going to discuss a boat.
Data structures off.
Right on.
So before entering into this concept,
right already,
we know what is a variable in python,
right?
So variables are used to store some data.
Even data structures are also variables,
and they are used to store in data.
But that data is collection off data.
Let me explain that you are on my common line,
So let me enter into my pipe down.
So you know,
normal variables like X equals toe fight.
Then I can say the value off axis fire,
and I can see with help off print off eggs night now.
Sometimes,
you know,
you need to define number off variables instead of defending number off variables.
What I will do is I would take only one variable.
Let's say my values.
You can take like your X rays that also your variable name,
but I'm taking my values equals two like you can take any type of data you can a present
evil data inside off.
Suppose your square brackets with comma separated values and then you can assign that
result into some variable.
No year.
Your ex is available on my values is also variable.
But there is a small difference between these two.
That is X is a normal variable and which is used to hold only one single value.
No,
I have a list list off values.
I store this list off.
Listen to this variable,
right?
I collector collection off data on I store that daytime to one variable called my values.
Now here my values is also variable,
but it is storing multiple date us or now this is called data structure.
Right?
So there is no much difference between your normal variable and data structure Variable.
Both are variable.
The only thing is your normal variable is able to hold one value.
But you're data structure.
Variable is hold is able to hold multiple values.
Right?
That's it.
Other than that,
nothing is that.
But how you are going toe structure your data.
How you're going to store your daytime into your variable One of the symbols you're using.
Based on this,
we help different types of data structures with your python.
Right.
Let me start there.
First thing Data structures are used to store a collection off data that collection of data
maybe pure indigenous pure floor.
Right?
Are your string numbers string values or maybe combination of all?
No problem.
You can store any type of data combination off any type of data,
as you can store into your data structure.
Right.
Then there are four building data structures with your python.
Building means by differently.
Hold this data structures.
So based on some models,
you may get some other data structures as well.
I suppose if you go with a raise modules you how some are a data structure.
Okay,
as off.
Nobody fault with your python you are getting These are the four different date of success
with your bite on.
They are by default you have with your python.
Okay,
no list your traveling with square records.
I mean your radio data inside off this couple while writing your data you are to use
parentis is dick story.
You want to write the order with Carly braces with key value pair representation.
Like your deck storybook set starts at 11 with curly braces,
but values are like list in trouble,
but there is some unique property with such.
We'll see them so that this these are the off four data structures on.
As an automation engineer,
you should be good with 1st 3 data structures.
Right on.
We will see about the H data stock just separately.
Okay.
In later videos.
So as have no,
you have to remember,
there are four data structures,
right?
All data structures are used to store multiple data or collection off data.
Right.
There is a purpose of data structures and finally hot.
Remember that data structures are also your variables.
All right.
Okay,
guys,
thank you for watching this video.