friends in this video we're going to discuss about big study data.
Structure off.
Fight on.
Right.
Let me weapon my editor.
So yet I'm going to define your dictionary.
Call for dick.
Stories are represented with curly braces.
Right.
Are you?
Then,
let's say bring my big study.
And then I am also printing type off.
You're given variable structure,
so you're going to see output,
either Deck study.
That means whatever you define with curly braces,
that is a big study.
That's fine.
Mexican.
Let me convert that into bullion.
You know,
it is a empty dictionary,
right?
I'm gonna putting that into bullion.
So you know any empty If you convert that into bullion,
it is always false.
That's what we're getting here already.
We know this rule as well.
Right?
Know what I'm doing is I'm going to come.
And this now I'm going to define addict study with some data.
So,
guys,
whenever it if you want to write a dictionary with some data,
you're to write like a key on its value paved.
I mean,
let's say I'm going to write.
This is as key on this as value.
Yeah,
anything.
This is a key on the value.
Suppose let's say bar I can take on one more thing is whenever.
If you're writing either Keilar value.
If that is a string,
you how to write in quotations?
Don't forget No.
Suppose I'm feeling that one is,
Mikey,
but I want to take that as a number.
Then I can write one badly on its value.
Let's say two is a key,
and its value is number two.
Yes,
all are valid ones.
So but the thing is,
I know.
But if you're defined your dictionary,
it should be like a key on its value paid representation.
That means So this is one item.
Actually,
in this item,
this is a key,
and it is a value.
So this is a key value,
Peter presentation say McKee and its value.
So keep a loopy representation.
Key and value.
Keep a representation key on its value.
Key value paid representation.
Right.
Fine.
Know how you can access how you gonna access the value from your dictionary.
So actually value start if you have there.
This is a value.
This is a value on.
This is a key that is a key.
This is a key.
There is also key.
So all these are keys on all these are values,
right?
So if you want to access any value from your dictionary,
it is always possible with your key only.
Let me print that.
My dictionary dot Let me do this food.
There is a key inside off your dictionary fruit.
Now I want to print the value for that fruit.
Tea?
Yes,
Apple.
You're getting right.
So you can also use one most intact that is called my dictionary dot Get Let's say I'm
going to take animal off course.
You can take anything now See,
that would put what you're getting.
Yes,
you are getting No,
let me come.
And all these things.
I'm going to bring my dictionary.
Something like dictionary called.
I'm in key call.
Let's say three.
Do you have a key?
No dictionary?
No.
But if I try to access in this way,
see the output It is giving another key.
ETA three key three.
It is not there actually,
that we're getting this error.
But in June of this Intacs,
if I follow brain my dexterity dog,
get three.
I don't know what the trees there are not what I'm trying to get in this way.
See the difference?
We've been previous syntax on distant tax.
This index was giving now in giving none internal Giving another that way is the best one
to get.
Any time you are key.
But if you want to rise another of the time you can go and take this one.
So both of us are used to access.
You were values based on keys.
No,
Let me print your dictionary first.
I So if you want to see how many operations are in one of the different operations are
dated with your dictionary.
We have a sharp Kurt.
Let's say they find some dignity and see the air off.
Yet these all are the operations.
So already we have seen get operation,
right?
Let me do one thing.
My dictionary dot clear on offer this operation I'm trying to print my dictionary.
So before and after that operation I am printing see Clear Single.
It is removing all Kiva Lupe representation from your dictionary.
That's it.
Thank you.
That is OK.
Yeah.
Actually you are accessing a value based on keys right now.
What I'm doing is I want to I'll sign a new key value paid representation.
I want to add a new key value pair representation for my dictionary like,
let's say I want to take kiosks three right and its value as something like that.
Three.
No,
after these,
just observe your dictionary.
Now you're getting this one No.
Three key value three.
So this is the key value paid presentation on your adding with help off the syntax or
simply there is a way to add a new value based Don't key your dictionary.
But while doing in this way by mistake,
you are taking No,
I'm taking three.
But I don't know whether keys there on my desk study are not.
But I am trying to do in this way no,
see the output first inches off number three you're getting for physics.
The reason is,
while are signing a key value based on key in this way,
if he already there,
then value will be updated.
If that is not present in a given dick story,
the new key value paid representation will be creator not see before excluding 16th step.
You know there is no key value pair called three and number three that way,
because off 16th line,
you're ableto are on in 17th line.
We're seeing that new key value pair representation is added to your dictionary.
No,
What I'm doing is I'm trying to modify my existing key value.
So while doing in this way,
if he is not that it will do.
It will give a new key value pair representation.
He follow the keys there.
The old valley will be modified.
So be careful while doing while assigning a value to your key.
Right?
Fine.
No.
Let me commend all these things.
So this is your dictionary you're getting?
Know what I'm doing is bringing might be study,
not kiss,
not kiss it.
Will you list off kiss?
Ecstatic use You're getting No Samer.
You have one more operation called not values.
See that?
Put what you're getting.
You're getting only values right now.
You have something called items operation.
Let me take that brain.
You're dictionary door items.
See,
that would worry or getting You're getting a key and value as one item to that night.
So then already we have seen Yeah,
copy Will see.
Forced to copy then.
Yeah,
so nothing is there.
Why?
Because too my dick story not copy.
Let's it,
then print white,
right?
And you know what is the purpose?
Off?
Copyright.
Let me bring your I d off.
Why?
And then idea off my dick Study.
See the output.
So I These are different means whenever If you do copy right,
a new memory location will be assigned to your variable wife,
but directly,
if you are sign Why?
Because of my dick story The same memory address will be reference or even for way.
Also,
Oliver discussed this while working with your list.
Right?
So,
again,
this is a big story on this is my dig story a variable called my study on someone memory
addresses there on DC's representing with your my dictionary.
If I straightforward,
if I do what you cost to my dictionary,
what will happen Way is also going to reference referee Same memory,
others.
But I don't want to do in that.
I want to create a new memory location and I want to copy this data to here and I want to
ascend this memory location toe.
Why then at that time,
you had to be used dot copy operation?
Not so Okay,
so fine.
Now let me comment all these lines once again.
Then what is the next operation?
Get?
He's done,
right?
Yeah.
We will go with form keys Clear than corporate on.
Get items done.
He's done.
Are you go with the first.
Ah pop in pop item.
I don't go with object.
Update is nothing back If you have already some external light let's say you have this dick
study and I'm having one more exotic called new Dick story.
It was too something called four value for Of course,
you can take number four.
Also string.
No problem,
right?
No.
What I want raise this key value paid.
I want to add into my old dictionary.
Then you're dodo,
Your old dictionary dot update with your new dictionary.
That's it.
So after this,
just try toe print your dictionary and see the result like nooky valley paid added to your
old dictionary.
So update is for that purpose.
If you want to go at one big story to other dictionary,
then you had to use update operation on your dictionaries.
Your world victory not update.
Then what is the data you want to upgrade your world history.
That dictionary.
Fine.
Then let me go with Pop.
See?
Ah,
OK.
So guys has have no What is the latest victory supposed?
This is the only distinction,
Ali.
I let me come and deal somewhere.
You are horrendous treatment.
No.
See your latest.
Traditionally,
is there something like this?
Right.
Know what I'm doing is I'm being simply dictionary dot pop operation on offer that I'm
trying to print.
What is my dictionary?
See,
that would put something wrong.
Oh,
sorry.
I didn't destroy the key,
right?
Yeah.
I had to provide a key.
Let's take e call four.
See that poppy is used to remove a key value paid representation based on key.
We're giving only key.
It is removing your Kiva Lupe representation from your dictionary.
There is one more thing called pop item,
right?
Let me run this thing.
Unseat output my dick.
Snotty,
dark Bob.
I don't on our after that.
I'm trying to print my dictionary.
See that?
But what you're getting right,
it is removing some diva loopy representation.
I said it will remove randomly.
Maybe lost value somewhere middle or something.
Whatever.
It may be right on you can assign this item What?
You are removing so removed re mode item and finally print the word you are removing with
help off.
They were pop item.
You can see that.
See,
this is what you are removing with help off pop item soap opera and actually the most
randomly That's it.
Okay,
now we didn't put Bytom Then we have form keys and,
uh,
Saturday Fort Let me go with the from keys,
okay?
Nothing is there.
Guys,
let me come and all those things.
Let's say ah,
how some key school?
Yeah,
he I Well,
you like I'm thinking as a list off kiss list off kiss.
Okay.
Now I want to create a dictionary which consists off this case,
right?
The new dictionary equals two victory door from keys.
Just do your kiss.
Now it is going to create a new dictionary with the key Sozzi a Were you under the output
value sermon?
Because we as if I don't have any values now you cannot date whatever that key believe you
on dot that you can update.
Let's say I want to update new dictionary with the key Corley A I want to assign letter
forced later.
First all for big.
Something like that.
So after that,
it just a print.
And see your dictionary.
So nothing is their gaze from keys are used to created big study.
Created the study with it required keys.
That right?
Fine,
No.
Let me go with the last one.
That is such a default.
Nothing.
Is there days as off?
No.
Let me take some dictionary called empty Dictionary.
Night.
Know what I'm doing is I'm trying to look for some key.
If the key is there,
okay?
And whatever the value I'm having that I will use that if that he is not there.
See,
some was I don't know whether keys there are not if keys,
they're used that value itself.
If it is not,
there are bread with the new value.
I mean,
first up during this output,
then you can understand.
So settle default.
I'm setting for number K value 45.
Sorry for key K value 45.
No,
After this,
let me create a dictionary with,
uh any any.
Okay.
Know what I'm doing is again I'm running my dictionary dot settled the fold.
If already keys there,
then it won't disturb.
If he is not there,
then it will update with suppose a new value.
No seed output.
No,
it won't.
Money for you are value apple because already fruit is their food keys.
There in your dictionary with the value call apple.
No,
the purpose Officer deformities.
If this key is already not there.
If it is not there in your dictionary,
then only will take a default value.
If it is already there,
whatever the value is there that will only it will consider just nothing.
But you know,
you're trying to add a new key.
You don't know the keys.
There are not.
If he is there,
don't disturb if he is not there.
Then said this value for that key.
That's it.
So that is the user separately for it.
Okay,
so this These are the operations on your dick stories.
The final important point these days.
Previously,
that dictionary is on order.
The collection off dictionary.
I mean,
before three,
not seven.
Washington now in 3.7 Western dictionaries ordered collection.
That means the way how you are defining same order.
You will get it right.
See?
Suppose.
Let's say this is your dictionary Let me go with your common line.
Let me copy that can pasted.
So if you print your dictionary you're getting in the same order the way how you define Let
me go with my fight onto So my pipe onto is there somewhere by Tuanku on Let me define my
dictionary here on Let me bring the or dictionary See,
Father has been changing No actually we have started starting keys fruit But you are
getting in output one So in previous Washington's before three or seven you were a big
story Waas on ordered the collection off later but in $3.7 You were dictionaries ordered
They don't Okay,
Order the collection off data You have to remember this point.
Okay guys,
thank you for watching this video.