friends here.
We're going to discuss the loss to default data structure off your python.
That is set in data structure.
Let me weapon my technol and I'm wondering in tow,
Fight on internal like See if you want to define any set.
Let's say my Sertic was too curly braces with the normal values.
You can't define any value.
Okay,
See that?
No,
I'm bringing my certain.
So the way how you are giving 457270 But it is giving out protests in ascending order.
That means what the what?
The data you're providing it is not giving the same order.
That means sets or call on ordered collection off data.
If you do any data multiple times if you data duplicates that are multiple times off data.
Suppose I have given 72 times.
So several do unique data duplicates will be removed by the four.
That's a now,
if you can.
What?
They were data into bullion.
True,
because it is non empty set,
right?
Let me define my sort of which is having a non empty ah study Empty.
Sick.
So,
guys,
if you want to define empty certain,
you are to write a set with the poker liberals because if you defend that,
its stride forward the calibrates that will become the story no printed the type off your
myself.
No,
let me bring the bullion off your myself.
It is a false because empty set,
right?
So,
guys these away How you can be fined your set right now you can convert your surgeon two
billion on What is that?
Whether you're getting when you're 30 is empty.
Let's say I'm having a big list Tickled.
My list equals two.
You can convert this listing Do sick set off my list.
That's it.
In case you have any data,
multiple times they were Ah,
a list.
You're settled duty unique.
They are.
That's it on any ladies as ending order.
That means on order the collection actually.
Right,
Fine.
So if you want to see the different types off operations on you asserts simply can done
this and you can see,
so are you can do it all.
Let's say city is that in this week 3456 and said to be Is there in this way 56789 So I
want to find year Union.
Be right here nor union off B C output.
Yea Lord in verse six in intersection off B Not okay.
So,
guys,
how there are remaining opens as well.
But an automation started Know where we are going to touch the societal later structure If
you are industrial against Ah Gorn 11 award your remaining operations on your sets.
Well,
I gone through only union under section.
If you are interested aboard sets anyway,
your mathematics sets operationally right.
You can go and see the remaining operations.
Okay.
Thank you for watching this video.