friends here we're going to discuss aboard fight on operators.
So the concepts or like you know,
what is an operator on What are the different and types off operators presenting your fight
conscripting night?
Let me start there.
See?
Basically open it to sort the pillars for any language not only or fight on.
Okay,
For any language,
operators are the pillars.
So without operators,
you cannot write effective logic violating your court,
right?
Fine.
Then what is them operative?
So the operative can be defined as a symbol which is responsible for a particular operation
between two operations.
Let me take simply to variable Scarl execution to and why Cost of three.
Now I need to find out the addition off these two variables than I'm going to take some
other variable reserve because two X plus y no Here,
simply place is your operator and you're performing this addition on your to variable
school x and y.
Now,
in this expression,
if places the operator than X and we are called operates right off course equally is also
not the opera in what we are doing with the help off equal means.
Whatever the result,
you are getting that result we are assigning toe this variable.
So here are decent is the action here Assignment is the action,
right?
So simply guys,
operator is just simply or symbol like plus miners modification.
We have some different symbols as well can we will see them And there is an action with
respect.
We were each and every symbol so as off No,
we're using place place.
We know it is used to add values,
not those two values.
Maybe variables are sometimes you directly.
You can stop shoot your values Let's say three place to also I can do it or I can store
Xing to some variable called exit Coast toe three and I can perform X Plus two our Aiken
store even to also into some variable.
Then I confined X plus y right now,
if you have your your operator,
this is your operator as off No,
you are.
I mean,
in this expression,
you're directly performing your operation on two values.
But here one is variable on one is value.
But here but our values that means way performing your operation with help off your
operator,
right?
All parents,
maybe values or maybe variables or combination off your violence on variables.
Right?
So,
by for simple example,
you can take place.
Is an operator to perform addition Operation on your our parents,
right?
Fine.
No fight on provides a very D off operators like,
you know,
automatic operators,
assignment operators.
Combat is an operator's identity operators,
membership operators and then logical operators.
And finally we hold with boys operators.
So these are these seven operators in your bite on scripting language.
So before going to write your logics,
first of all,
you should be very,
very good with your operators,
right on one more thing days before going to start each and every operators right here.
I'm goingto do one idea.
If you are able to remember that as off No,
you can remember that that is like si foster to operators like art omitted cooperators and
assignment operators.
For these two,
you are going to provide input as a value and whatever the operators are there in ur
automatic an assignment,
they will do their action on your input.
They will provide out,
but also as a value right then coming toe next.
Three operators like combat is an identity membership operators,
so here we are going to provide input as a value.
But these operators will perform some action on your inputs and they will provide all put
as either pro are false.
You guys,
For your 1st 2 operators,
you are providing input as a value and you're getting old.
Put also value.
But for next three operators,
you're providing input as your values and open you're going to get either true or false
means you're getting Boolean values right then coming to logical operators for these laws
Collaborators.
You're providing input as true or false on also,
or put your getting either true or false.
Then the last one is big boys operators seeing between operators.
You are going to provide input as a value and also you're getting output also value I mean
both inputs and outputs our values,
but wave performing the operation.
When you're given values by your ba twice your data will be converted in do bits or binary
on Under Binali data,
logical operations will be performed.
Then finally are going to get your result as a value,
right?
So,
guys,
for time being,
if you are able to remember,
just remember this structure so that it will be helpful while working with your operators.
Right.
So simply remember that first inputs need faster to operators.
Input is a value on our portal.
See a value then for next three operators,
input is some value.
But our put your also getting some value.
But that is purely a bullion data that is true or false than for logical operators.
Input is bullion or put it also 1,000,000,000 data No for last one between the operators
important or put both our values but way performing the operation by your ba twice
operators on your given values right so directly they don't do what it will do is your data
will be converted as a binary.
Another binary.
The logical operation will be performed on your inputs.
Okay,
so this will be helpful if you are able to remember you just try to remember this Okay,
is thank you for watching this video