friends here.
We're going to discuss the first of two operators off your fight on there are automatic an
assignment Operators.
First,
let me go with your art emitted cooperators.
See,
we hold or different types off automatic operators.
They are like,
you know,
already belong in your mathematics addition.
Subtraction.
Multiplication division Modelo.
Right.
So here floor division is somewhat a new one.
We will see that and the exponential.
So these all or the your art emitted cooperators,
right?
Let me weapon my fight on terminal there.
I can easily explainable them.
Let me enter into my pytorch internment.
Quite uncommon line or bite on shell.
So I said directly,
I can do supports two plus two.
I mean,
any number you can take not only to place to some four plus two.
Right?
So this is just to perform additional for two values,
right?
So I can start this result in tow.
Some very blast for let's say,
result.
Because toe are you can take any variable addition off to number.
Something like that are simply some because two r s equals toe.
Yeah,
variable is your wish,
right?
No,
just a print.
Curious?
Yes.
You are getting right.
Not only like that,
just you can store the water up values in some variables on Let me take seek Austria plus p
and then print your c So,
like ways you can do your subtraction.
Multiplication,
Right.
Let me do one thing.
C equals two,
um,
minus B.
So he's four.
And because she ate the result is minus four.
No,
let's say Sequels to you,
Toby.
No ces 32 late.
No,
let me do one more thing.
See,
cause too if I take four days in eight,
right,
Reserve these Do not fight,
you know,
right?
Four way facilities,
other ways just to do 8 May four.
Then see,
that isn't zero.
Okay,
So,
guys,
by default you're getting You were reserved in terms off flute.
So this easy with your piped on three.
But if you go to fight on two,
if anyone off the value is float,
they know,
then only you'll get result as float number.
Right?
Anyway,
we're working with bite on three decks.
Right on.
We know these the off future fortune.
I mean,
from 2020.
We hardly you this one,
right?
Fine.
Now let me go.
Don't worry about this language is just I'm going to clear my screen,
find no exponential.
Suppose if I want to find something like three square are some four power three how you can
find c three square.
You convey the 32 stars,
then to know there is nothing but three square desert.
These nine of course,
you can store your values into,
let's say,
a cause to fire.
And because to some three now,
if I want to find a power fight esto story Yep,
would be are five power t a fight Cuba,
Right.
A cube I can do later in this way are this way.
Just under the result.
Want to fight?
I can start that into some variable cord results.
Are any variable?
Let's say here to the power bi No,
simply printable result.
And see the value,
right?
No,
if you have a job,
we covered all the operation.
Yeah,
we help ending with Modelo and then we'll say floor division.
So Modelo,
let me take some number days.
Ah,
somebody.
I'm going to take some seven If I want to divide this with two,
23 just six nobody's The remainder value one right now see,
what I'm doing is seven remind that cool result is one like way.
Suppose if you divide eight with two,
then what is the remainder?
So it reminder to is always Jiro.
We know that just to find your reminder you're using the mind of symbols.
Then the last one is floor division.
I see that like nothing is there.
Just stick two times your slash our division symbol.
See the result for right now,
what I'm doing is no.
See,
that isn't by the four leaf.
You take seven by to what you're getting.
Did you not fight?
If you know,
floor division,
right?
If you know floor division.
See,
yeah,
simply agenda in this output only in this explanation.
23 just six.
Reminder one Your question.
These three,
you'll get this pure Kocian without your floating points.
Right?
And that to you can assume three dot if I actually know seven by six or if you do,
you are seven.
Reminder to what is the value.
So it's seven by two.
What is the value?
Did not fight.
Then you feel a round off that value to low lower value.
Then the result is three So that's what you are getting.
Let's say mine looks a minus.
Mine floored isn't too.
See what you are going to get.
You're going to get minus fight because mine by two is almost forgot.
Fight minus four,
not fight.
Right?
See,
In your number system,
this is minus fight,
then minus four.
So comfort of minus four minus Phi is the lower value.
Know what would the result you are getting for that resulted?
You're getting a round off,
Lou that two lawyers thrown off value not for a minus,
for not fly around off value as a lower value is always minus five.
That's what you're getting here.
So that is the uses off your floor division.
Right.
Fine.
Then next one is assignment operator.
She already we know one of the assignment or better.
Like if I read execution to what your doing do value.
You're assigning PXE.
Okay,
so what I can do express scoop less for then guys,
whenever you have equal symbol here,
equal operator here for the sequel operator.
Always the right side.
Whatever you hope.
That expression will be value later.
First.
Then that result will be assigned bx see what our the expression you have with help off
equal symbol.
Let's say exit causes some three express to as you Mexico to some three value.
So Europe,
I don't don't bother over the year exceeds their headaches.
Is that your button?
Don't bother aboard their first.
You take equal symbol.
Then it will forget about this.
Whatever their on bites.
I first of that value will be evaluated on that result will be assigned to this variable,
So X is three 32399 plus to 11 11.
Blessed be X.
If you want to get the result from your common line,
let me take X equals 23 Then I am reading X equals two X into three or three X Bless some
to now See the result X value 11.
So that is simply assignment operator or your equal symbol is basically an assignment
operator.
But see Veneman,
if you right,
yeah,
cost you Please be.
And after that,
here he is there.
Here also.
Is that so?
In this case,
instead of writing your expression,
lengthy expression,
you can also write other a shortcut expression as in this very year.
Plus it was Toby,
not only for this If after all these things right,
see a they raised a Is the rays there?
So on board the sites for your equal symbol,
but nobody fairway.
Yea right Then under time.
What do you do?
What you can do is just to remove this year and then right place before you recall symbol,
right?
That's what I do here.
Now this boat to expressions are going to give same result.
So if you want to get the proof,
just open your terminal.
So here,
let me take initially A because of some two on because of some three value.
If I radiate cause two year plus B,
what is the result?
Just after that fight?
No,
I'm going to reassign you Coast to two and then be Corsetti.
Now what I'm doing is your place because Toby and see the results.
That means if you write either this expression or shortcut expression board will use same
reserve.
Right?
So these are the assignment operators on about your art emitted cooperatives as well.
Okay,
okay.
And one more thing.
So they suppose if you want to define a simple automatic calculator,
let me do it here.
So I'm going to design simple,
ultimately color with help off or only recent symbol for time be because you can perform
any operation for timing.
I am goingto create only addition or the money calculator.
Okay.
Otherwise,
simply addition calibrated,
not be white.
Just Abdul.
Here,
guess what I'm going to do.
East.
Suppose if I take a course to some three and because of some fight,
and I want to find the result result because to nothing but the A plus B on I can drink
using your thing.
I can bring the edition off.
Yeah,
on be equals two r Is I reserved right suitcase.
If this is your a python script or python program in this,
your four lengths see for any line.
If you have there,
there is no space at starting that is the rule off your pipe on that is a basic room for
your pipe.
And don't probably a space before starting,
any line undid.
And unless if there is any special requirement for that as of no other normal length,
straight forward straight lines,
right?
That's why I'm I'm not giving any space before starting your any off the line,
right.
But nobody feel run.
Your python will run your program from top road on line by line.
Then what is the very first line?
Yaeko city.
That means somewhere in memory.
Yeah.
Value will be assigned as three.
Same may be then reserved.
You know,
a place based audition.
So you ever lose three and we will lose Fight three plus fight eight.
You're assigning to result.
Then you are printing those values,
right?
That's what we are doing here.
No,
let me say we on running.
So I'm going to save it.
And you know how to run your bite on.
Skipped our program from common line.
Simply your Python interpreter space You are program name.
That's what I'm doing here.
See,
there is no off three.
And five is 80 are getting.
But if I had on this program again and again,
I'm going to get same result.
If it is addition Caligula there it should not give the addition for fixing numbers,
but nobody.
If you're running that script,
that program,
it has to take two values minimum from user,
you know.
I know,
But if you want to provide input for your script,
you have a command or statement called Input in your fight on in part on three or decks.
Let me open our script.
See here into not fixing my values to Yaeko.
So three and because to fight what I'm going to raise Let me come in these two lines now.
Yeah,
value really from input.
So revelation is usedto evaluate.
You were given value,
so enter forced number for the just in four.
You know already about ur input then Same way I want to get be value from import.
So important.
Early work.
Second number.
That's it,
right?
No.
Let me say this hand.
See your core ones,
Whatever you have.
Right?
So that's if you are very here.
1st 2 lines are commenter.
That means you're fightin wont to conserve those two lines says you were pride fight on
program lines.
No,
very first line is this one.
So whenever you feel on top,
though,
don't you know that the very first line is year equals two?
We know we know what there is an equal symbol that is an assignment operator,
but nobody feel an assignment Operator assignment or burger will try to get first right
side value.
Whatever you help.
No invite surgery or some syntax.
This is helpful to read something from common line.
So whatever I'm going to provide on common line that will read by this expression on that
value will be assigned to yea by your equal symbol or with your assignment operator.
Right.
Let me run our cool.
What That would be how?
See that?
And they're forced number.
I'm wondering number six.
Suppose there emerged early in the second line.
Right?
You how once again enter second number.
So because off this enter first number I'm wondering six.
Then I'm going toe press enter on my keyboard so that this six will go on store in the year
with the help of this expression.
This index right,
then immediately in the next lane you How entirely were second number?
I'm going to understand something.
Number called nine.
Not so you're getting 69 Result is 15.
None of your program is like,
you know,
simple addition Calculator like,
but offered being some on one level concerts.
You can design a simple automatic calculator with your pipe on.
That means addition,
subtraction,
multiplication division model,
low floor division,
whatever.
The operator,
whatever the operation you need all those operations you can do with help off your bike,
conscripting so for that inner toe include some logic before,
including some logic.
You should know some concepts will discuss that concert force.
And then we'll once again design a full fledge it automatic calculator with help off your
pipes on scripting.
Okay,
for time being this very simple one.
So,
guys,
here we discussed about art emitted cooperators and assignment operators and also how to
read any two numbers and then how to find addition.
The same way you can try for you are our dish subtraction,
Multiplication division,
Modelo floor division and exponential.
You just trade right?
This separate buy dance good for each and every concert to hear.
Whatever TV help,
Right?
Fine.
Okay.
Thank you for watching this for you.