prince.
In our previous video,
we have seen about automatic and assignment operators off fightin.
Now we're going to discuss about the next operator.
That is,
combat ism or combat is an operative soft by time.
Guys,
these operatives are very,
very important in your real time.
Compact isn't operatives.
And one more point.
We already discussed that while giving introduction to operators that is comparison
operators.
We take import as value right on.
Then it will you output as a Boolean value Brewer falls fight.
She actually comparison is nothing about finding relation between two operates or values.
I mean,
let's say he held three and four numbers.
No,
I'm going to check Krieger than for more false.
we know that three is not greater than four.
That's why this is a combat is no better here.
And if you come back,
these two with the help off this greater than symbol,
right,
you're going to get result as false.
So we're providing input as a value number number,
system value,
right as off No,
on output.
You're going to get either pro or faults,
right?
Let me open my python personal so I can explain very easily.
from here as off?
No,
we're not going to write any bite on programmer script.
Let me take trigger than four.
No,
we know that false.
You guys wait.
Taking your comparison operators you can take a space are between your operates.
Now let me take three less than four.
Yes,
we know which drew Exactly.
Even if you do with bite on your getting proof,
right?
So comparison operators are usedto find the relation between two values or two operations.
So,
guys,
I can also store my value in do some variable and no,
I'm taking three less than Yeah.
So what is the value for?
So python is going to compare,
like three less than four.
So internally you believe nothing for four.
So three less than four.
Yes,
it's true,
right?
Let me check it.
Yes,
so likewise you How different types off operatives here,
None of them less than double equal demons or other equipment's equality.
Not equal resident request less than our request.
Right?
See barbarically.
You can check suppose four less than recourse to four.
Actually,
the meaning for this is it may be less than or it may be equal if anyone off that is true.
Then you will get out.
But as a true I mean four,
maybe close to four.
Remember less than that.
So as off.
No,
in this relation for equals to four.
But you are taking either less than or equal to equal is correct that we're getting proof
are injured off that I'm taking three less than a week or so for yes,
anyone trees less than for true.
Maybe anyone off that either less than or equal Mike.
So guys 11 more thing are using this comparison or relationship operators with the number
systems is very easy because we are very much familiar with the number systems from our
mathematics.
Apparently,
we can see by seeing your numbers two numbers to values.
You can tell the relationship between those two numbers either equal or not equal greater
than less than less than it cost to get down on the coast.
Right.
But when you go with the strings,
actually,
strength is also ah important while discussing about your comparison operators,
I mean,
how do come bar strings?
Let's say I have a string call earlier.
I want to come check this every A equals two year.
Yes,
it's true.
Yeah,
because Toby no.
These two things directly we can tell that Are you not equals to be?
Yes,
it's true.
They're not equal.
We're we're taking They are not equal.
Yes.
True.
So equal,
Not equal We can easily understand because by seeing strings itself,
we can match And we can tell that whether they're equal,
not equal.
But what about this?
I'm building is less than B Yes,
it's true actually.
But if I run this yes,
You're going to get over as a true how How your pichon is going toe compatible strings What
is the mechanism while comparing your strings?
Nothing is their gaze Whenever If you're going toe company was springs your pipeline We
convert each and every character into an ass Keycorp based on aspic or it is going to
compare Let me find What is that asking court for you?
Are you see?
Go find for any character the asking core The default function is order Order off your
character Not only you can take any special character.
Also you're going to get some asking core.
No need to remember that but at least just try to remember the function.
See if I know.
Ask Accord.
Then how can I find character?
Let me ready 45 character.
See that you can find your character asking chord using order function.
You can find that the popular character from your ass kick or using car function.
That's fine.
No,
let me compare year.
Is it less?
Then be?
Yes,
obviously these?
No,
The reason he's whenever we fear multiple characters,
right?
The foster character from your left side string will be compared with the 1st 2 character
from your right side string.
So yea less than we we know that that right is true.
Let me take something like NBC and I'm going to take sick.
Otherwise I will take.
You are terribly Let's say C No,
the result is false.
The reason is first thing foster character from your left,
the side on first careful from your right side off your operator is yea,
both are equal.
That's right.
We'll skip that and we try to come back second.
The characters,
so be is greater than your right.
But you're taking less than that's why this is false,
right?
So it will combats character by character.
Any given strengths right?
Like we suppose if I do greater than symbol.
But it's true,
right?
So simply guys were Piketon will come.
Parry was strings based on and asking core.
So how to get your ass kicked?
Core is nothing but order off your popular character.
How do you get your character for your butler asking?
Call Cara function I So they This comparison operators are very,
very helpful while discussing conditional statements like if an if else else.
If Nessie lives right there,
we will use effectively dis comparison operators as off know what you have to remember is
comparison or relationship operators.
We take input as either number or a string on it will provide Allport as always.
Always output will be either Prue are false because you are comparing you are you are
checking the relation between two values.
That relation is like are they equal or they're not equal?
If anyone off that is greater than or less than less than our recourse to get it on
Articles two.
So you are taking relation ality between two values.
So that is nothing but output is always say,
the true or false are simply bullion or put.
Thank you.
Okay.
Okay,
guys,
Thank you for watching this video