prince as off?
No,
we computer three types off operators,
right?
They are ultimately assignment and comparison Operators know we're going to discuss two
more operators.
There are identity and membership operators.
See why we're using how we can use them in order time,
right?
Just let me go with our identity operators.
See,
I gently Operators are usedto find the type off your object.
It may be class.
What is the type off your object?
It may be class or type.
Maybe object.
I mean for time being,
let me do.
You are a simple example.
Ah,
I'm going to open my time now.
Okay,
fine.
Just up there.
Here we have some X value.
Or let me define some new value for X And why it goes to some high.
Then what is the type off your ex in desire?
Then what is the paper?
Off your way.
So this is type Type off your variable.
Suppose x and y No,
let's say I'm going to defend one more variable called Why?
Why close to seven then what is the pipe off?
You were white in desire Gezi Free check exit closed toe No false but X and white type is
him.
What is that Pipe in Poesia type.
Now I want to verify.
Suppose for two variables whether the type is similar or not.
I mean,
let's say is type off X is a type of way that means,
Are they equal?
Yes,
true.
But if I take type off X East type off,
let me define verticals.
Some string?
No.
You know what type of dessert is strings or exes in Teacher on Gary String.
Now what I'm doing is I'm going to compile type.
Affects is that I pose a no Taipa fix is not the type of said yes,
they're not equal.
We know that because we know what the value is stored in X and y.
That's why type of fixes in T shirt and type of very string.
But we are saying that yes,
they are not.
They're not equal in type plays.
Yes,
So in identity operators,
we hope to types off our producers.
Their season is not so.
There's simply remember that identity operators are used to find the type off your variable
suppose or type off your variable right on the one object.
Sometimes you know,
you're goingto get your type.
Maybe class or some object.
So for timing,
we know if you find the type of some variable you're going to get other in digital,
float or complex or string or bite,
right?
Well,
going forward,
we will see whenever if you get some different types there again,
we can use this identity operators.
Right.
Fine.
Then next one is membership operators.
See,
my machine.
Barbara does are used to evaluate the membership off a value.
Anyway,
by saying this,
you don't get much information,
but I want to do one thing.
Fasting.
Very simple information.
Days after this,
I have a list off value school 4567 Right exit started.
16 X Yes,
19 X No,
right.
Let us assume that in your real time you're doing some script.
The purpose off your script.
Ease right.
First of all,
you have some valid Let let's assume rallied,
Joe Abortions.
Let's say $1.6 and wondered seven our let me take.
We're not mine as well.
We're not eight under.
Then born lord night.
Just assume that these only your value job abortions.
You should have only these job abortions on your environment.
What up in something wrong North.
Sixth year I am miss Really a petition.
Fine.
Give us to before writing your python script,
Right?
First of all,
I'm assuming that one or 607 108 and wondered nine or value job abortions,
right?
These other valid abortions.
But on my host,
what is a job?
But you know how?
I don't know.
But troop Eitan skip just as unit Because as have no you cannot write your script to find a
job question from your local host.
Just a solution.
So horse to Java.
I am finding like this something like that.
But I'm not going right.
I'm writing some logic through that I got washing.
Has one not fight?
No.
What I always if you're horse to java,
if it is there in your value that I can say coast consist off village of Washington so join
Well,
Java,
no false.
Now I can say that.
No,
I can say that right?
Your host does not consist off value.
Job awash in liberate simple script.
For this nothing is the rest.
Membership.
Something is there in a given group off values or Martin?
That's it.
Very,
very useful in your real time situation is same.
I mean scenario.
Very confused.
You are membership operators,
That's,
you know,
used him.
Let me copy.
These are the valid jar Washington by with some logic,
as if no directly.
I'm writing.
You are host job.
But what I will ease in your real time.
I will write some Lawzi to get the host job.
Whatever the washing is there,
know what I'm doing is if,
as of now I don't know what about you are Ah if statement just after that If close to Java
in violent Java,
then I can say print host consist off value Java,
Washington ehlz supposed to consist of what hosted deployed of the danger of contests.
You can use Mostow deployed within my lead Joe awash in So our gender.
This is one script.
Okay on.
I'm going to run this script.
Just see the output.
What?
You're getting close to deploy it within Balaj awash in now let us assume that you're going
to run this camp on another server There you have wondered seven No,
If you observe what is the courtyard?
Getting close to deploy with the vantage are washing.
That means some particular value.
Whether it is,
they're not given list off values or Mark right for that,
they're going to use membership operative.
Not only that,
Yes.
Assumption.
One more thing because these membership operates are very,
very important.
I'm going to give one more example.
That is,
there are some DB groups.
Are there some pre defined DB users are add menus or something like that?
Okay,
just a junction.
So some baby aren't menus up,
then go to the gym.
Dirt,
maybe.
Configuration user,
Insulation user.
Something like that.
Okay.
Know how some user with the end user,
I need to start my application.
Just agenda.
I mean,
I need to start my db.
Just assume that the users which are there in this let me take this has debuts is that this
is the users which are there in this,
they only can start your baby application.
Just assume that right?
So,
in my hand,
I have some user random use.
I don't know whether that user is a valued debuts are not just I got some random user.
Let's say baby admin.
See if this user is there in a given group DB users,
then I can alone toe.
I mean,
you can Hello that user to start your DB application.
That's why what I'm doing is right.
If you are db or letting let's say random user right.
If random user in in DB users,
then I can say bring Yes,
this user is allowed to start baby,
that's it else.
Sprint This is this user.
He is not a valid user or uprising is not a valued user.
So stark Devi,
Right?
First,
let me run this quarter of the airport before that I'm going to come into your previous
school so this we will write a script toe,
find out even these db users valid abuses on your partner host Like so everything you can
write a scrip for initially,
right?
I cannot go on right Some complicated skipper and I don't want to contribute that I am
taking simply directly the output.
Okay After the output first if db Edwin Yes,
This user is allowed to start No,
let us assume that there is some users don't know some x rays and user before going to
start your db by the texture you that user what I will lose if that random user in my value
TV uses list,
then only how to otherwise I hard to say.
See that put this Caesar is not a valid user to start db so simply what you're doing.
You are checking something is their neck given list or not to take that we're using
membership operators,
right?
So whatever the thing you have,
all right,
if that thing is in the list off values,
you will get output as it true whenever.
If you're going toe combat.
And so I don't know what if we're going to use your membership operators false anyhow,
one more thing.
Not in whether given values,
not there.
Any list?
Yes,
Not in proof.
All right,
So you have two types off for membership operators,
and they are in and not in.
This may be a little bit confusion,
but while writing a script with your if condition while going forward,
you will get a clear clarity on this identity operators and membership operators for timing
.
Just a gym that some value you have to compare you are to check whether it is there in the
given list,
off values off mark to check that we're using membership operators.
That's it.
Okay,