friends here.
We're going to discuss about logical operators off.
Fight on.
Let me start there.
See logical operators.
Theological operators are useful toe.
Combine multiple conditions.
One of the multiple conditions.
Let me take my fight on shell or fight on common line.
Right.
See if I take three greater than one.
This is one condition.
Our Let me take something like wanting this list false?
No.
I want to come in these two for my partner Logic as if No,
don't worry about what is their last just after that.
If I come in these two things three greater than one on right?
You're letting someone put it may be false,
right?
So here I combine two conditions,
right,
Fine.
So in this way,
just to combine multiple conditions So we are using logical operators night?
No,
in Europe Eitan,
you have different types off logical openers until they are three.
They are like find are and then not operators.
Right?
See that?
Let me go with one by one on.
See a new operator If you come by in multiple conditions with on a nobody returns Prue,
If both are all the conditions are true,
right?
See here as off?
No,
I combined two conditions.
This one and this one.
Okay,
so they see this easier.
Operator,
this is a one condition,
but finally this condition This is like a one value are one operation for your inoperative
the same way this entire thing is one condition.
But this is one open for the work.
Logical and operator.
Right for this operator you are giving to our parents,
you know,
in your really what is the result off this one And this one already we have seen through
and then false.
So if it club this too one false case with under operator what is already are getting false
.
Let me combine 34 conditions.
You can come in any number of conditions with your end operator.
Let me do one thing.
One less than two.
Yes,
it's true.
On to less than three.
Yes,
it's true.
On three less than four.
Yes,
it's true.
No,
I am combining three conditions with on the operator on did indeed relief.
You observe one less than two years.
It's true to less than three Pool three Less than four group No,
you Here I am combining three conditions and in Usually each and every condition is true in
the case.
If it club all the true conditions with your under operator result is also proof.
See,
that would put.
But if anyone off the condition is false,
let me take four less than three.
That is false low even though this one on this one is true.
But this is false.
No.
Whenever even club multiple conditions fun at that time.
If any one of the condition is false,
then result is also false.
Nice don't body when you're going to use this just after the operation How your Thunderbird
is working while walking with your If condition we will see effectively when we have to
select this logical operators upto that right just just observed the output Whenever a few
club multiple conditions with under operator what will happen,
right?
No,
the next one is or opening it returns Prue if either of the open.
So I feel that this meaning is whenever if your clubbing two conditions.
But using your order operator also,
you can club either to conditions or multiple conditions.
Let me do one thing one less than do oh,
three less than four result is true fasting.
Both are true like I don't know.
What I'm doing is one is Drew and one more is false for less than two false right?
But the reason is true.
That means while working with your our operator if anyone off the condition is true,
then dessert is true.
Be clear lace see while working with on operator right you anyone off the condition is
false then a reserve is also false then,
while working with the or operator If anyone off the condition is true,
then the result is also proof.
Be clear,
right plane?
No,
let me take one less than two.
It's too right.
It's true.
We know that know what I'm doing is true conditions.
I want to make it as a false Yes,
you can do with a smart operator.
See that actually,
one less than two result is true,
but that prove you're complimenting with help off,
not operator.
That means if you're having a true then you will get output as a false whenever.
If you're playing not operator,
Let me go this thing to less than one.
It's false low,
but I cannot play for this and not operator based on requirements,
right?
And see the output false here,
converting in tow.
Right.
So these are the three logical operators in your python?
Not not off through it will do false.
Oh,
not off falls it will you result us through.
So,
guys,
for time being just observed that how you can club multiple conditions with under and or
operator If you club your multiple conditions with they were and are our operator.
What is the result you're getting?
What is the rule?
To get value as true or false while are playing your logical operators?
Right,
Fine.
The letters are June Dart.
How some 10 conditions.
Let's a simply four conditions.
Other ways pool is done three,
four less than fight 12 then file is then six.
Let me read something,
right?
No,
If I want to club all this with on the operator Yes.
You can collaborate by writing between these two conditions simply or under operator.
Right guys here you have a small injury question.
What is that means my house up was one,
234 four conditions I want to club with suppose a the Anno printer or off our operators
Then how many logical aunts I can use here if you have four.
If you have four four conditions,
then you need four minus one and operators andare even.
Maybe you can also use our operators.
That's a because one C,
you help photo operators.
Right?
34 conditions,
not a club you're using three four minus 13 That's what I'm saying.
Here,
you cannot play something for our patrols.
Right?
Fine.
No next thing.
Engine off writing and again and again as off know how only four conditions.
So your clubbing with suppose three under operators.
But just are you my house?
Um,
10 conditions I want to club with your unknown operative.
Yes,
mine on operatives you need,
You can club,
but there is a shortcut for that that is all.
All just to provide or all conditions in terms off a list inside off all Tulloch's done
three,
four less than fight filers,
then six,
then seven less than 10.
So that is always exactly questioned,
operator.
All is exactly all is equals to unknown Britta.
What's induct is different.
Under better you are including between two conditions are between your multiple conditions
,
but all you are taking all in this way.
Inside off your parentheses you are writing a list.
That list consists off your conditions as a value.
Right?
First,
let me do one thing.
I will check this result What?
You're getting right Because all our true you know,
in an operator if all conditions are true,
then only will get output as a true if any one of the conditions falls Result is also false
in your under operative both the same but by mistakes,
not by mistake.
I suppose if you have any one of the condition as false know if other seven greater than 10
That is false.
So 1st 3 conditions are true on one condition is false when it But if you are playing under
operator on your multiple conditions If one condition is falls,
that result is also false.
Sending you gonna play in your general and operator False,
right?
The same way you have for are also for our You have to take any if anyone off the if anyone
off the condition is proof than result is also true Nothing.
See some But I'm taking this as a false but no problem because this is our operator if
anyone off the condition is true,
result is also true.
All right,
then.
Here unit on this time.
And he is exactly close to your or operator,
right?
See,
guys,
under result off your final result whatever you're getting with help off and are are right
under,
you can also apply Not so if you're getting proof previously.
Now you're making that as a false.
That's what you're getting here,
right?
That's it.
Okay.
So guys,
here once again I'm telling you that Don't worry when you have to apply your end or or not
,
operators he had just learn only if he club multiple conditions with an what is the result
on what basis you're getting deserved.
Right?
So you know,
always the logical operators result is all parties always either true or false but our but
on one business you're getting this true or false.
So once again,
I am repartee whenever if he club multiple conditions with an to get the result as true,
the rule is all must be true then only will get output as it to.
If any one of the conditions falls,
then differently will get output as a false.
That is the rule of fine for our if any one of the country's rivers.
If any one of the condition is true,
desert is always true,
right?
So if all conditions are false,
then all you will get output as a falls in your operator.
See that?
Let me take three less than one That is false.
On how one more thing for less than one that is also false.
No result is false.
But if at least one condition is true.
Okay,
So this is all about zoological operators,
Mike.
So finally,
how you are not operative And he had to remember this all and any all is exactly Coast
warned.
And he's exactly caused to our right.
So when you will take this one means any and all but number if you're multiple conditions
internal fighting you're under operator are operated repeatedly.
Right out of that time you will take a the all or any based on your requirements.
Right.
Okay.
Thank you for watching this video