friends here.
We're going to discuss a boat,
if else conditional statement.
So before going toe,
enter with your defense condition statement already We know Simple if condition.
Right?
So using that I want to write a small script.
Let me weapon my editor.
So here,
I'm going to use sublime text reader You can use any attack,
right?
Fine.
Let me go.
Some name for my Python script.
The name is convert indoor title format.
So get a title for matter Get a title for Mart,
not be white.
So my intention is I want to read some string that string I want to convert into title
Former but first let me right there User string I'm taking variable cord user string So I
want to read a string.
So if you want to read a string you had to take always input under you were string Nothing
.
Then after that,
simply What I'm doing is I'm printing your user string dot title format You know,
if you want to convert any string into title for my there is a string operation called
Title Right,
Let me weapon my come on line.
Right.
So we have our scripts on desktop bite on scripting.
So here our striptease get title for might not be way See that step?
We have only two lines off script,
right?
If you run,
your scapegoat will learn from taco down The very first Laney's user equals to import.
So because off this he was keeping will ask something like Enderle was string.
Let me run this Yes,
it is asking I'm goingto provide by tone scripting So now you have press the enter on your
keyboard What will happen?
Whatever the data you are providing here that data will go on store in tow This variable on
the next step What we're doing So this line is warmer If you press enter,
this line is over.
There are for they're simply or fighting is going to bring to your given string I'm in user
string That string is converting the title former than it is printing Sit output Yes,
You're getting bite on scripting Capital P and capitalists.
This is fine But before converting into title format the skipper has to ask like do you
want to convert this script into title format or not?
If I say yes then only it has to convert.
If I say no,
it don't convert.
But it has to print that.
Given sting as it is,
See that what I'm doing then I am taking user confirmation as a variable user confirmation
,
and I want to read yes or no?
Yes,
always a spring.
That's why I get I'm taking input.
Do you want to look inward?
You are given string Indo title for my say yes or no.
Not right?
No.
If you that says yes,
then only I want to convert the data into tightly for murder.
And then I want to display so two lines.
First,
Lenny's reading a string second lines getting confirmation from the user.
Right?
So what are the user is going to enter?
I mean,
either yes or no that we are storing into this variable?
No,
I am taking with if condition.
If user confirmation is it caused serious,
then only I want to exclude this line.
That is Miss Lane.
If users says yes,
then this value becomes true.
No,
because you will.
You threes entering Yes,
On that value were storing into user confirmation.
Variable.
Now we're taking user confirmation under this Director string.
Are they equal if you're under.
Yes,
then yes.
Definitely.
This is equal.
If it is equal than this,
youth is allowing to exclude this line by your piper.
Not a like for us to see the output.
So let me clear my screen.
Let me weapon You are script Now I'm going to run,
so I know.
But if you run,
you know it is going to explode from top down.
Very fast.
Lane.
See the output First land excluding.
Enter your string.
I'm wondering.
Bite on scripting.
Then it is asking because off second line Do you want to come?
What you're given?
String into title Former say yes or no.
Let me type.
Yes.
And I'm pressing Enter so that nobody.
If you hit the enter on your keyboard,
what will happen?
This s value will go on store into this.
That's over.
Then two lines are over.
Then you're quite animatedly Goto,
Carline.
There he is,
The star light.
So now you are entering yous.
This year's on this year's both are equal.
That's what we're checking here.
If they are really equal than this value becomes true.
If it is true,
then this youth if will a lot.
We exclude this line,
that's why.
Sit output.
You're getting into writing for months.
I mean capital PN capitalists.
No,
let me read on.
And I'm providing simply by conscripting once again.
But I'm saying no,
no,
you're not getting in output.
See why nobody if we under no you know No.
He is going to store in tow.
This variable now in your hand this variable is like no no equals.
Yes,
No false?
No,
no,
because yes,
faults.
If it is false,
then if condition doesn't a lot,
we exclude this line.
That's why you're not getting any input.
But might equipment bees,
Even though if you enter know at least I hope to get normal string display.
I mean,
the string,
whatever you are giving,
Same thing I want to get.
If I say no,
If I say yes,
I want to get in the title for my right.
So that's why what I'm doing is I'm going to add one more of condition.
User confirmation.
If it is equals to know,
that means user is not willing to convert their given string in tow.
Title for murder.
The not the time simply directly print.
We were given string as it is not to right,
No seed output type Get for my friendly format.
Let me run this script on.
See that result?
I am giving suppose welcome to fight on scripting and I want to convert this as a title for
murder.
That's why I'm saying to my school please convert it.
I'm wondering Yes.
Then you are getting ready for my then Breeland,
right?
I'm wondering Welcome to pipe landscaping But now I'm saying no If I said no what will
happen you're getting as it is your string then how your script is working first up very
here.
But nobody if you say yes.
This is true that for your excluding this line at the same time whenever you are saying you
are entering Yes.
Then this is false.
No.
Yes,
your companion with no falls.
That's why this if condition is excluding this line.
But no.
But if you say yes on this if condition is not excluding you were lined whenever.
If you say yes,
That means if you say yes this condition is true and this condition is false that way This
if condition is excluding this line on this if condition is not excluding this line,
that's fine.
Like Okay,
no.
Let in the second case you are wondering No,
right.
I know.
But if we say no,
No,
this if condition becoming false.
That's why this is not executing this if condition becoming proved.
That's why you're excluding this line.
I mean your bite any excluding this line.
That's where you're getting this one,
right?
Yeah.
This is okay.
Your script is working perfectly as for your requirement,
but the thing is,
that is,
if you say yes if you say yes.
I assume that if it's a is this condition will differently becomes true.
Then you are printing this line at the time.
You need to take this condition by already.
You're saying yes.
Then why you are checking for no right.
If this is true,
you don't need to check this condition.
If this is false,
then just check this condition night.
So,
guys,
whenever if you have only two options,
like yes or no,
like yes or no whenever If you have only two options like yes or no at the time you need to
write or to see operative conditions simply you can write else here,
then how it is going to work.
Nothing is their guests very simple after that?
In case if this condition is true,
if this condition is true,
you're fighting.
Let's could this line.
I mean,
if he's a lying to exclude this line and if this condition is true by default,
your python is going to skip this part.
Brighton won't check this one.
But in case if this condition is false,
this result is false.
You know,
if it is not going to exclude this line,
it is not allowing to exclude this line.
And if disease falls,
if this is false,
big clear.
If this is false by default with told taking any condition your python well executed the
else block in else.
Whatever.
You have a cord that court will exclude without taking any condition.
Right?
So remember that when you have to take if ehlz whenever If we have only two possible values
for your requirement,
then only auto take you for nails.
See,
for user conformation as off.
No,
we are treating only yes or no.
If it is Yes.
This line has to exclude if this is no by default.
We had to exclude this line.
So if you take you fells one second I'm repeating.
If you take you fills condition If whatever you're writing here,
if that is true pure bipedal legs Could this lane on your part on Don't concert this part?
If this is excluding your Buyten's simply by default,
it will skip this part.
You know not to bother award that in case if this condition is false,
then only or fight on will exclude this line or the block which is there under your l's
without taking any condition.
Night Let me take one more example so that it will be clear for you.
No,
I'm going to come in this Otherwise I would write new script,
find greater number not be Wait See,
my intention is I want to read to numbers and then I want to comfort So whatever the number
is higher that number I want to display.
See that?
So really one numbers you can take a malfunction then input Enter your number So there is a
three d string Don't take a malfunction,
right?
Not enough taking a well functioning for dessert string If it is any value other than the
string.
Then you have to use a well functioning fight on three and very well.
First number.
Then I'm going toe.
Take one more number from user.
Second number.
Let's say B input and you were second number.
That's fine.
No,
sit directly.
I can't display like yea is greater than B.
I can't buy directly in this right because we thought,
knowing the relationship between your year and be How can I say Yeah,
he's gonna then be are,
Let's say one more line B is greater than you.
I can't say right retort Knowing relationship between without knowing her year and B values
.
I can't decide which statement I need to display.
But if you remember,
if you remember,
you have a comparison.
Operators,
right,
Let me enter into my python.
Let's say three less done.
Do so.
Therefore,
less Any number.
Any number four less done to It's a false no no.
I can decay close to four and be close to to know I'm combating yea less than be if really
a value less than B,
then you'll get a true.
Otherwise you'll get a false then this poor,
false reserved I can use any condition right.
But what if you're getting results as true or false?
Always.
I can use that in my youth condition.
That's why what I'm doing is here is if I want to print this information.
But if I want to print this information you ever you must be greater than be.
That's why I can right here.
If you is greater than be if really is greater than be,
this valley will become true.
So you think is true.
Be clear Race If the result off younger than be east True then only I want to display this
line right?
If you ever lose rather than be then only I want to split this line the same way Suppose if
b value is greater than year then I wanted to split this life.
Right?
So what I'm doing is if if really eager than B then definitely get approved.
If it is true,
then you're going to exclude this line.
I went to work no the same day.
If the value is greater than you then I can print this line.
No,
it will work.
but see that resulted.
Your street name is fine.
Gator number,
right?
So I'm going to run this So I'm giving them Was like fight and nine.
Yes,
my knees.
Good of them.
Woman I'm making writing both RB Well is here.
Yeah.
Here I immigrated Variable Here.
I'll see that.
I'm wondering First number as support.
Some fight on second number as mine you're getting mine is good of gunfire.
Ah,
let me Day three are then one freeze rather than one.
It's working perfectly,
right?
No.
Instead of writing younger than be on bigger than you suppose just a gym.
It's not perfect.
If he is greater than be I wanted to split this information.
If it is false,
then I'm going to split this information.
It is correct up to a certain point,
that is just after that I'm wondering in this way four and fight.
What happened?
Yeah.
Sorry.
It's my back.
I'm wondering number five and then I'm minding some number Number seven Someone is greater
than five.
It's working.
Then I went thing seven and some do well shut seven and then to Yes,
Sony's good of them boots working.
But if I dio both are same numbers.
Fight and fight.
You're getting five girls and four that is not.
It'll correct right now.
See here when you're taking fondles when you are taking for nails.
If there are only two possibilities for your results,
I mean 40 were value.
See if I take you over loose,
let's say 213 I gender.
This may be greater than off.
This are maybe less than off this or maybe equals off that right.
If you take to where it was like year and be based on the N B values,
they may be equal.
Ari is greater than B or B is greater than you.
Three possibilities are there Whenever.
If your three possible days you can't take simply even else block you can take simply.
If one else block,
then how you can write your court right?
See that now how I'm going to manipulate this thing?
See,
you can,
I'd like in this else.
If you feel you have a little less than be,
then I can write B is greater than you or I can also write the A's less than be yes,
less than be on and see,
maybe a equals to be right.
There is a chance to how equal So I that that time I can write.
Sorry.
Yeah.
And yeah.
And the B our same are equal not to no guys I'm doing here.
You may be greater than be Are you may be less than Lee.
Yeah,
also,
maybe there is a chance to how you and b values are equal.
That's why whenever he film multiple possibilities well,
comparing your values,
then you can extend your if condition in this way.
If Elsie form or condition Elsie form or condition,
you can also write it.
How multiple puzzle,
Paul.
Possible days.
You can also write one more else if Right,
fine.
Let me on this.
See,
I'm and bring foreign four.
What happened?
What is less than for maybe you and be Yeah,
I have given you.
And it's my bag on second.
Okay.
See here.
Amending number four and four.
Four and four are equal four and seven.
Or let me take some first iron number.
Second lower number.
It's working perfectly.
Right?
Plane?
No.
See here,
Grace Foster thing.
You are having a simple of condition.
Second thing whenever.
If you home to a loose for you were required thing then at that time you can take you for
nails.
But here,
whenever.
If you're comparing two values,
right,
you help.
Three possibilities.
First number greater than second number or first number less than second number.
Our first number one second number What are equal.
So at the time you can use,
if else if else if condition like.
And one more thing here.
Three possibilities.
Right.
So by this block by this block by these two conditions,
you're checking greater than and less than so if these two conditions all false agenda.
If these two conditions are false,
then biting for the end of your equal,
Right?
So at that time,
what you can do is simply goodnight else.
Block.
No need to check your condition.
Whether the acres to be or not.
Why I am writing else.
If it is right in this way,
you talking No problem.
It's okay.
It will work perfectly without any confusion.
It will work perfectly.
But what I am saying,
he's assume that I'm giving a value tree on be value for gig.
Sorry.
Yeah.
First I load this thing.
Yeah,
greater than be revelatory and be really for this is here.
And this is big younger than be no false.
If this is false,
your python will skip this line.
Because if dozen dollop breaks got this line then immediately or biting will come toe
Second condition Guild will check a less than be yes,
True if it is to your pattern will exclude this line on remaining all remaining conditions
.
Your fight on by default,
it will skip you.
Don't take the first condition.
If it is true remaining,
all conditions are going to skip Whether they may be too are not You don't bother award
that year by Tony's going to skip that right?
But in our case,
suppose as off my If I take 300 both are equal.
No.
So this condition definitely false because you're taking three greater than three No,
false because they're both are equal.
So this is false.
This is false.
So whenever we fear to lose and greater than and less than conditions are false,
then remaining option is equals.
Two equals only,
right?
That's why what I'm saying is you need to check this for directly.
I can bite else here.
So else means,
you know,
before the block,
when all of all conditions are false then only else will excuse when all about conditions
are false,
then only else will execute.
So if you take any two values which are equal for your first and second variable year and
be then this is false this is false.
That's why you're if he's going to execute else blocked by default in case of any one of
the condition is true,
that condition will execute other ways.
If all conditions are false,
then only else will X cure.
Right?
Fine.
So,
guys,
this is all about simply your If else on if else if else if condition Okay.
So in next video,
we will write one simple skip to understand effectively.
You are if else if else if conditions Okay.
Okay.
Thank you for watching this review.