friends here.
We're going to discuss a more to one of the operation from your sis model.
That is called cis dot org Sister arguments.
What is this seeing?
Sister Argov returns a list that consist off command line arguments which are passed to
your python script simply.
It is giving enlistments.
It is available now,
actually,
is one of the operation from your sis model.
We know operation may be a function or maybe available.
So say start.
Arjun is giving a list,
right?
So which consist off some command line arguments which are pastor to your pie transcript.
So to understand this,
first of all,
you have to know what is a common line argument night.
Let me weapon some script.
Let me open my reader.
So I'm going to write the script accord.
Command line arguments come in length arguments Not be way so something I'm writing Nothing
.
Is this emblem reading?
Hello?
That's it.
Now I'm going to run from command line.
So if you want to work,
if you want to know command line arguments always yard run your script from command line
only.
Fine.
So just know we heard it on the script to called this one nothing.
Is that simply print?
Hello?
Let me run this fight on common line arguments.
Your skip name dot Yes.
You're getting some output night?
No,
While running your scrip while running your script by your fight on interpreter.
I'm also passing some values called suppose height.
How are you?
Some number one?
Number 3 67 moderate,
maybe.
See if you pass in this way just after their baby.
How in the serpents with your script.
Is there any longer?
Put No,
it's working perfectly.
See,
after he was script name,
if I passed some values,
they're not disturbing your script.
Just awful in this way,
if you pass.
Yes,
actually,
that is the correct.
You can pass in that where there is no wrong in that.
If it is wrong,
then you ought to get some other right?
You're not getting any other.
That means yes,
you can run your script bypassing some values in this way.
No.
After you were script name,
whatever you're bossing,
right?
So these all are called command line arguments for your script while running your skip,
your passing somewhere lose.
These are called commonly in arguments,
right?
So if you're passing some common land of Mencia.
If you're passing some common in arguments here,
how you can get them inside off your pipe.
Monster,
Right?
Saying nothing.
Is that what I'm doing is simply now let me remove print.
Hello?
You're gonna get anything right?
I'm writing print six dot R D V.
That is a variable,
but you're using six,
right?
That's why I want you to go.
Unit imports is right now.
See,
first of all,
of Jerry was script.
What?
You How inside off your skin.
Nothing is there.
I'm using cysts.
That's why I'm importing that sits first.
Then I'm printing simply six dot org.
First time running your scripting.
This way,
guys.
Observed output What you're getting You're getting a list of which contest off your script
name?
Only because after he was script name you're not passing anything in case if you pass what
will happen just I'm passing suppose bite on some shell,
some pearl,
something like that.
So it's it output.
Whatever you are passing here,
all these values are coming in this a variable called cis dot org.
As a list.
Not only that,
you can pass some values also see the output.
No season dot org v is capturing inside off your script,
Whatever the values,
whatever the arguments,
your bossing while running your script.
Right.
So these are the common land arguments you are passing while running your skip on.
You can handle these values inside off your script with help off says dot org,
it's very,
very helpful.
Right on.
You need to remember one more thing.
What are the values you are passing from Cameron Lines?
Even though if it is a number,
see that it is treating as a string.
That's why you have a quotation here,
you know,
in python Tried if I write X equals to some list consist off work.
Um,
if I then here for and four year values of the Lord put you are you are not having any
conditions but here you having a quotation for your numbers?
That means what the were you are passing from common line.
All will treat as a thing by your fight on night.
Fine.
Let me take one simple example to understand this example.
Yeah,
One more thing is See,
this is going to do all your Cumberland arguments right on.
If you are very road port.
The very first values always your script.
How many values you're passing?
How many command line arguments?
Your passing,
right?
Whatever your passing.
That index Jiro is always a script name.
See that?
Now I'm passing only one common argument you're getting Index showed us your script Name
remaining all our work.
Command line arguments.
Right.
So if I want to display only script name Born on how to do sys door if you remember.
If you remember list operations,
I want to get only the first index value.
I mean,
the foster value.
New at least that is indexes always Jiro,
right.
Let me read on and see the output because off Let me weapon you escape once again here
because off bring to see Sergey v.
Jiro You are getting this common line arguments as a script name.
Joe is always skip name in your seats dot org because it's not.
Our job is a list in that foster values always seal script name.
That's what I'm getting within next zero.
That's fine.
No,
guys,
I have a small requirement.
My requirement is my script has to read some string.
My script has to read some string,
then off of that,
I need to convert based on my requirement requirement.
Sometimes I will convert into lower case.
Sometimes I will convert into uppercase.
Sometimes I will convert into title format.
Right?
Forget about first your command line arguments.
So if you want to provide some string to your script,
what you have to do,
let me do this thing.
Ah,
At midday,
user strength equals two.
If you want to read a string,
always your to take input as it let me save it.
Actions on strings,
Not the way right.
See,
here I am reading a string from commonly user stringy question.
Put entire Iwas string.
I'm asking,
then offer that user action I'm reading.
What is that?
Action means input.
Anthony.
What action on your string.
So value actions are just I'm giving the Clue Valley actions or like lower got up.
But,
well,
suppose title for Mitt.
That's it.
So these are the values I need to read from user.
Now imagine that you there is going to enter some string and user is going to enter
someone's lower operate writing format.
No,
based on user request,
I need to print the wellspring in lower case or upper case or in the pedal Former.
That's why year and you could take if condition foster for right.
If user action it cost to lower right now how to print.
They were given string.
That is yours.
User string into lower case.
Will you hold different options?
You're right,
user may enter like up,
but also so I'm checking If user action is upward Then I'm going toe bring to my youth
string in terms off uppercase right else If if user action If you is the action in Costa
title format then I'm printing user string dot Vital in Goodbye,
Mr Give user end us other than lower upper tighty Then I'm writing else block And I'm
saying please your option is invalid,
right?
So please select valid options from this list.
So where are the vile options?
Lower up.
But then my deal left it Fine,
right?
Let me go on run descript from command line So first of all,
he was script This is your script.
Let me run.
You can see the output first I am running I am profiting string Call some randomly.
I'm providing in this way Fight on scripting something like that.
Then I want to convert my string into lower operatically Any option you can provide?
I'm giving supposed title for my then see the airport You're getting in the title Former
Then I'm relearning And now I'm going to provide lower I want to convert my string in the
lower case.
Yes,
fine.
But what?
I would escape you How?
No You escape needs of two inputs One is string one more is user action One is string one
more issues direction but wild running script Your broiling right See after running I'm
impacting with my script.
Yes,
you can in fact But my intention is I don't want to provide in this way I hope Run with one
step How to run my skipping one step then how you can do it?
See for that I have the idea.
What I will do is first command line arguments I will send as a I will send a string
requesting like fight on scripting Then second argument right?
I will provide action like lower Then I will end up so that it has to work right?
No,
If you passed in this way you have to use your sis model on you can handle them a string as
your first argument night inaction is second argument.
Now what I'm doing is insured off using input.
No,
I'm going to come.
And these two things Now I'm going to import your system model,
then user string.
I am taking nice.
If you remember,
Sister at our TV is going to give your all common land arguments right in that Ju it
argument is the script name.
Then see if you are running in this way.
If you are running in this way,
let me do that thing first.
Other ways I will come into your entire court right now.
What I'm doing is I'm going to print the world Spring says dot org We first like No,
let me run this and see the output.
If you run in this way,
you're getting a list inside off.
Your escaped with help off Sister RGB in their index,
Joey's skip name index one easy were given string on index to is user action.
That's what you are getting by running in this way with help offset start rgb right.
So that is whenever if you want those pass on argument,
which consist off some spaces.
Then you had to write their entire string inside of quotation,
right?
No see?
No.
Because with the help of systems RGB,
you're able to get your command line arguments inside off your script.
That's why what I'm doing is use a string I cannot sign Index one.
Right.
So this is not our GV index one.
I am assigning for you.
The string on user action says door odd GV index to that's it like No,
let me run your script.
Consider magic.
No,
I'm not going to use input command and I'm not going toe provide multiple lines.
Input for he was kept only single step just running this way.
Sit output.
You're getting your string in lower case.
Maybe you're getting confusion because the entire thing is in lower case.
Let me go in this way I see the output forgetting sting in lower case or let me pass year
upper Let me past ideal.
Yes,
it's perfectly working right,
But the year a small drawback is there.
What does that mean by mistake?
Suppose if I'm not passing this you're getting another listing next out off range because
you're passing only skip name on a string name.
What about action?
Action is always index vituperation.
You are taken inside office script,
but you're not passing three values.
If you passed three values,
then he convicts in next three you're passing.
Wanted to values that is skip name other than string.
Name the DJ right Index that his foster next.
Then what?
Aboard second Index?
You're not passing,
but you're sending that.
You're sending that in next to value to this action.
So without having second index value,
how can you assign that value to other variable?
That's not possible.
That's why you're getting another right.
So whenever if you're using common land arguments with help off sis dot org,
you have to take care.
What is that girl?
How you can take it like I think Is that very simple?
Observed that So there's for our scrip for our stupors off.
No,
whatever.
We are working using lower upper title for murder.
How many common land arguments we need?
One is group name.
2nd 1 is string 3rd 1 is action.
So three values your passing then only discouraging If you passed to others,
then it is not correct.
Even if you passed more than three,
known it off four values.
That's why what I'm doing is before running before assigning you are command line arguments
to your variable.
First of all,
I am finally bring the number off common land arguments.
If you remember,
if you have a list if you have a list,
you can find out number off values in their by using length function.
So sister dodgy visa list.
Right?
And I'm finding number of values.
Let me come and your entire core first.
No,
run your script and see the output.
Yes,
you're getting three because you're passing Skip name.
First command line argument.
Second Cumberland argument.
If I pass in this way,
what is that?
You have it only supposed something.
Then you're getting too,
but nobody could get to.
That is not correct.
You're not running.
You're skipping the proper way because you need three values.
Finally year with including your script name Skip.
Name your spring under the new action.
That's why what I'm doing is whenever if this value is not,
of course to three right beef,
see that if lent off your sis not or GV here for days.
Not because 23 every cost three.
No problem.
If it is not because 23 then I can't assign Second Nordmann value to your your direction.
Not because three minutes as you know you're sending on to values.
Then it's not correct.
No,
that's why whenever,
if your number off arguments are not because 23 maybe you are more than three I need only
exactly three,
including your script,
name,
script,
string,
name in action.
It should now three only in guess if it is not because 23 then I want to stop my scrip.
You know you can stop your skip using seized art exhibit.
Previously we discussed this right In previous video.
We'll see the music now You don't get any other previously where nobody if you don't have
this lousy let me,
Kartik and save it and done it Once again,
you're getting another right index range index era listing that sort of fringe.
But what I'm doing is I'm saving this now with help of the simple of condition.
Now I'm running.
You're not getting any better simply or fight on is stopping your skipped whenever If you
are not passing proper command line arguments.
But simply stopping is not a good practice Whenever.
If we are not passing exactly three arguments,
then simply or stopping right before stopping,
just try to read some message.
Bring use a day off descript usage.
Use disease.
Bring us is not or gv on TV.
Skip name.
Then offer that what you want to do,
right?
Let me do off if strings.
So you says I'm I'm writing.
So print the you escape name,
then then here you have to pass.
Posse was string.
You are required.
String I'm writing.
Suppose you were required.
String here then.
Here you are to right.
Action action is like lower Oh,
upper for title.
That's it.
No,
I'm saving this and I'm going to run.
Guys,
try to understand this.
It's very useful.
I'm running in this way.
Then you're getting new cities.
You have to run this keeping this way.
Action on strings,
not B y.
Then you are string.
Then some action.
You have to cooperate like lower or upper Our title.
Now I'm going to provide in the probably suppose I'm running up notes working properly if
you are not passing common land arguments perfectly,
then only are getting usage.
Otherwise it's working perfectly.
Right?
So guys,
finally here we got the concept off sis dot org and sister Exit as well.
So that's why it says not exist.
Exist is sister Exit is very helpful in your real time.
Why we are using just to stop your script when we're stopping.
If you're not passing proper common Leinart Gwynn's If you're not passing proper command
line arguments,
what will happen because of this line?
You're getting another.
I don't want to get another right.
That's why when you will get another if you're not passing proper arguments So whenever if
you are not passing proper arguments,
I'm going to stop my script by simply saying this information to the user.
Please run this script in this way.
Uses off strip I'm giving,
and then I'm stopping the next time.
Whenever the user is going to surround you escape,
he will take care how to run issue,
right.
Okay.
Okay,
guys,
thank you for watching this video.
It is very,
very important.
While writing your scripts says not our TV.
All right,
fine.