prints here.
We're going to write one more python script,
require Mundy's really directory part,
and then identify all files and directories in the given part.
Say simply,
our script should read some part.
That a cripple.
So in that location,
in that given part,
what are all directors and finds are there,
right?
I want to display all those things by mentioning disease.
Your file.
Um,
this is a territory.
Every take one simple location.
Oh,
yeah.
See here I have no problem.
This has a part to might buy.
Transcript.
Then my pie transcript has to display my directory.
Either that every new text document is it filed.
XtraJet is a file.
Your script he's able to identify it has to display.
This is a territory.
And this is a file on.
This is also your fight,
right?
Let me go on right one by one.
For time being,
what I'm doing is let me remove one file here just for simplicity.
Purpose finally will like it.
Let me save it.
Read apart a 95 files under,
please.
Fine.
See you.
There's for something.
We need to read a part,
right?
So to really apart.
Because parties a string in Europe.
Eitan you how input to read any strength and Terry work directory,
but not you.
After leading that park.
First of all,
I want to display all the list off files and directories in the given location.
Right.
If you remember,
there is operation from your waist model.
That is ways dot listed Matic,
please.
So now here I have a requirement with ways module.
That's why I'm importing voice now.
Simply am branding.
Where's door?
Listen directory And whatever the part you're providing that.
But I am taking right.
Let me go toe my Come on line from there.
I want to run because I need to probably just part right.
So our script location is in this somewhere.
First,
let me open you r script.
This is your script only.
We have three lines.
First,
Lenny's your important ways.
Model to second line.
You are going to read from your command line your part hard line in the given part,
you're going to list out all the directories and files.
Let me do it right on.
I want to provide a part.
Let me take this as my part on embroiling.
See,
guys,
this script will work both.
You are windows as well as UNIX like systems,
but way providing.
But on Windows operating system,
you have to provide two slices in a part.
Sida slash housing slash nobody thought appropriate to slash is just toe a white.
But nobody feels some special characters in your part,
right?
Only whenever.
If you're providing manually at that time only or to provide fine,
no seat output.
This part,
whatever you're providing that is going to store in this variable and I'm listing Where's
that part that up always dauntless directory in your party.
So in this location,
I want to list all the directories and files on this output is a list.
See that already we have seen in Norway's mortal explanation,
this is always a list.
No,
you're getting two files.
One is directory on one.
What is fighting but mighty Clementi's.
If I get some values in a given part,
I mean,
some files under these are pythons capacitor display.
This is a territory,
and this is a file,
right?
So you know,
if you know the path,
if you know the part off your file,
then you can find out whether this is a file or not using you up.
Where's dark path?
Dot is file is directly.
You can take anyone off that operation if remember,
a B before going toe.
Check whether it is a file or not.
First of all,
you should How in your hand your complete part Off your file.
Order three.
Otherwise,
you will get another because you're skipping or running from this location.
But these files are little different location.
Right?
See that?
Suppose if I do simply.
Yeah.
One more thing before that,
let me store this output into one variable file,
son,
that at least files on direct with list.
That's a no.
I can also print in this way.
Right,
Right.
Let me read in your court.
So this is your court now?
I'm going to read on that.
I'm going to provide the spot.
Yes.
Same what we are getting because of this print line.
So in this very well.
Now we have these two things as of no gym,
that but all the part you're going to provide in that party,
how any two fights or any two directories are any one directly in one fight Now to identify
this is a file or not on this is a file or not.
First of all,
I have to separate this value from this list.
Right?
So that's why one I'm taking is I'm creating two parts.
No,
let me come and dislike but one.
Let me take the one part One equals two from your this list index zero.
I'm storing into part one.
But the two equals two from your this one.
Index one,
right?
No,
I want to identify whether p one is it.
That'll be one easy file or not for a lot directly.
Guys,
let me do it as body without port.
People use a file,
right?
So because second value is a file index one value,
let me check it first on your people if even,
you know,
in our previous example Also we have seen Where's that part that is fighting people that I
can say you are free to Sorry.
Hiding the body.
Happy to write.
We're working on Peter.
We do is fight else.
If that is false,
where's dot partner is file?
Maybe.
Peter,
that your file?
You know,
if you know exactly you can say that there is a file other ways.
That is a directory,
right?
That I can see you're free to is a direct Let me save it on Goto Common line.
And then really were script ones.
Let me when you're stupid.
No,
I'm providing some.
But c x wagered dot as such is a day three or getting.
But that is not correct.
The reason is why you are getting peace.
Actually,
Peter means X with your daughter.
Such your python skip,
you're running from different location on your files are there in a different location.
That's right.
Whenever if you're running any part three little operation,
you should get in your hand complete.
But as of now,
you don't know complete part X ray.
It is there somewhere in different location.
But I don't know how complete part for that,
right?
What is a complete part?
Complete but is nothing but in the given location.
In this given location,
your file is there then,
for this location at the end.
At the end,
if you are x rayed your daughter such then that is the complete part for this file,
right?
So that's your to create first how you can create it,
see if you remember who is dot path dot Join You were given part comma.
You were filed so that you're going to create a complete part.
Your file.
See,
let me print your part.
Only part.
I'm bringing on the paedophile.
Let me come and they will remain in court Now See,
that would put what you're going to get.
I'm running.
You're getting complete part for your file?
No,
once if we get complete part guys,
complete party nothing.
But you were given a part in that part you're having explained your daughter such That's
what you heard These two things.
You can get comfort but your X rays your daughter such only given.
But if we are those two things you will get complete part for your file so that you can
directly respect you off your operating system who are two parts you can use directly waste
are part or join.
That's what I did not only for Peter O.
P.
One.
Also you have to do not only for that pile if how multiple things for all things you ought
to do in this way only faster fall you have to create complete part.
For they were fighting.
That's why I am big near part.
Only because there is a part.
You're profiting as input.
In their part,
only you file your file,
is there.
That's what you heard.
Those two things you can get complete part.
Fine.
Now run your script.
Now I'm going to come.
And they were two files.
Life?
No.
See that as off?
I have a felt condition only for Peter Park.
Let me very fat that whether Peter is working perfectly or not,
this is the part.
Yes.
Easy a file.
You are getting same.
Lousy.
I need to play for pure notes.
Right.
Then what?
I ought to go.
Let me copy this logic once again and try to play for people.
See that I'm trying to play for people.
So what will happen if this is the file?
This will become crew else Falls Falls means you're going to split this one.
Guys,
in your previous script,
we also used ways dot path,
dot exist.
But here known it off that because if given parties vital part,
that only are going to get list off files list off calories into this DF underscore.
Riel,
variable.
If you provide a valid parts then Only right that only we're going to get it if you want.
But I defer to severely gonna play If ways dot part dot exists If you in part is a valid
apart,
then only I can find a list off their descent fires in the given thing.
Otherwise I can buy else it's bring please provide a valid but right And one more thing
Anyway,
it's timeto give that as well.
If parties invalid,
you're not going to get this list.
If you're not going to get displaced,
how can How can you create the one we do?
You can create that,
Troy.
If this part is not existing,
you are to print this information on.
You should not exclude the score.
If you're excluding this quarter means you got your DF underscore.
Riel,
variable.
No,
you're not getting if parties invalid.
You can't get this because this is a false right we don't have in your list.
How can you use in your core?
That's why you ought to stop your script to stop your script.
You have a syntax courses,
not exit.
Now we are using six module.
So you are the important that So we thought This is not exit.
If I run my court sit output how you're going to get you'll get another?
See that in general I'm giving invalid apart.
See if it is involved Part you are not getting the FL If you're not getting DFL,
how can you get from that index?
Jiro,
you can't create people right apart on your counter create by taking next judo from your
variable if given parties,
please probable party are getting that means given parties invalid If it is invalid,
you can't get this one.
The reason is if it is invalid part,
this will become fault if it is false.
There is no way to create your dear from the school.
If there is no dear friend,
ask Auriol How can you can't take people?
Pito,
How can you create pure and Peter from these dear friend of school?
You run out there.
That's why I need to stop my script.
If it is valued part then only any to run my scrip.
So if it is valued your if condition will become to this valley will exclude on anyway.
If this is true,
you know that else is going toe skip by your pipe.
No,
see,
same court.
I'm running and I'm providing involved part.
Now,
we're not getting an error in job that you're getting simply.
Please provide valid part.
Okay,
It's good,
because here we got one more concept.
How to use is not exit.
That's fine.
Now let me run this court and I'm going to probably valued part.
No.
See that in that part?
This is a territory.
Yes,
you're getting through.
Python is a territory on this you're getting is a fight.
All right,
fine.
So we're creating people and Peter aren't.
We are taking one Ifill's condition for people,
but the one on second defense condition for part two.
And here there is a very big desert foundation.
What is that means as off?
No.
In the given location,
you have only two files.
That's why I'm taking part one part two.
But as you know,
you don't know how many files under trees are there in the given directly part.
Let me do one thing.
I'm I'm building this fight.
No,
I'm going to run your script,
right?
See the result?
You're getting another listing.
Next order off range.
The reason is.
Let me bring the first you are because,
as I have No,
You're having only one item in a given location.
See?
That are put right.
One of the data trees there.
That's where the next June.
Next one is not there,
but for Peter You're using in next one.
Then your step is wrong,
right?
Ordell's I will do one more thing.
Ah,
I was cleared some random files.
Here,
let me create some files here.
Ah,
that ex door Txt.
Why not be way some dead guard message right now.
I get it.
Three files here.
I created three files.
No,
for the same part.
One second I'm running your pie,
conscript.
Try to understand days now you how,
actually four items in the park.
But your script is giving about only two parts actually having four values,
right?
But it's kept.
Your script is saying only about two information to items,
too.
Parts from your given location.
Then what about remaining yet?
Why it is giving only two means as off No,
in ERP items could be how taken care only for pure and we do so now You have a problem with
the script.
If you're given location is not having two parts.
Then you're skip is going to give another are if it is having more number off files and
that it isn't a given location.
Then you're skipping is not able to identify all it is going to add If I identify only two
That means based on how many files Underdressed are there in a given location based on
their dynamically or skipped has to work.
That is not happening with this cream.
Then how you can be then how you can do it?
That's important thing right now Let me come in this court as off No,
Whatever you have,
I will come in the entire court first.
Be clear,
guys.
It's very,
very useful in your real time concept.
I'm reading something Text Gays don't worry of order.
Just try to understand output.
I'm writing for each in 234 Then I'm writing.
Drink.
Okay then drink.
Hi.
First of all,
assume that this is like if condition you know,
intensive reserve condition.
If your condition is true,
then you're going to execute these two lines.
If it is ive condition on what are the conditions you here If that is true.
Then you're going to feel these two lines ones.
But this is not condition.
This is called a loop this year for for his collar loop.
What is the use off loop means big.
Clear,
Because off this look,
what are the values are sorry.
Whatever the lines you have under your loop,
those lines will repeat some separate number off times are getting like in immediately.
But how many number of times you're going toe your loop is going to repeat these two lines
means how many values you have here,
that the number of times these two lines will execute.
Right?
See that first let me on this score and sit output here.
I hear itself.
I am running because I'm not drawing an input.
I can run it from sublime takes itself.
You have 2343 values in your list,
right?
That's why.
Okay,
High that is one output,
second time or port?
Third time or put.
So you have dourness and fasting for is some look Luke means you know,
starting point.
An important same,
right?
So you are You are reporting here and here and here only.
That's right.
That is called simply look.
Okay,
then whatever the lines are there under your Luke,
those lines are repeating certain number of times immediately.
First time,
second time,
Third time immediately.
It is repeating these two lines but a home a number of times based on here,
whatever you're providing in that harmony,
number of values are there.
If it is a list in trouble,
how many rallies are there?
You can also write some string.
Let me do it.
String here I'm writing simply not end up.
See the airport.
How many characters are then?
A given string that many number of times These two lines will repeat.
I get in again immediately.
Right?
That actually was in practice for this is any variable each each is there?
No,
that is any variable you can take like X ray Jay Peak you are or you're required.
Variable are your name also You can take it that is simply a variable.
Then in the standard t worry hard writing asdis.
So here you can write a list are couple or lest string also right.
For time being,
what I'm reading is I'm going to write a list off values.
Four.
Well,
is I'm writing.
Then these two lines will repeat four times.
No,
it right,
two lanes.
You're gonna 100 lane so I can write simply one lane.
Also,
no problem.
Just for our understanding.
But was no I'm writing Hello.
Only one letter I'm writing.
Now.
This line this line will repeat again and again immediately.
Four times.
Because your four values here,
I'm sure that would put first.
Yes,
you are getting no.
You defined somewhere Variable called each right.
Then what did they use off this?
Actually,
that is the very,
very important you.
Whether you're going to use that inside off your for loop or not.
That is your wish.
You can also use that in guess if you have a requirement.
And one more thing,
guys,
you are repeating this lines,
right?
The lines which are there in your loop.
If you repeat once,
then that is called one liberation.
One iteration.
So no,
you can say here we have four values.
That's why you're loop.
Is it rating?
Four times are Your loop is repeating four times the lines which are there.
And they were for Luke.
As I know you have only one.
Bring the straight man un in case if you want to you this variable inside off your loop,
you can use it.
See that what I'm doing is hello,
comma variable,
right?
You can print the variable value by using in this way.
No.
If I run this how it is going to execute,
we know four times it is going to exclude because four values are there immediately to like
school four times.
Do that support.
I'm reading here before.
Look,
I'm reading here brain after Luke.
So between this before,
loop after loop printed statements this line will repeat it four times,
like first of the output home.
And And it is going to repeat before loop after loop.
Between that,
you're getting four times you're print.
Hello.
What you are getting each value is different whenever it is repeating first time first
generation,
it is value to second generation 3 30 duration four 50 40 Duration 50.
Right Then how your loop is working with your variable called each Nothing.
Is there guys how your python is going to explode as of no.
In you escape,
you have only four lights are three lines.
Main lines are three main lines are three.
They are.
Let me take it one by one.
This is first line,
second line,
Charlie.
But this line is under your loop under the order.
Like look this print line,
right,
Fine.
Then how it is going to exclude means anybody whenever if it only was capable.
Like you're from top down.
So this land legs good first because I've got here getting this output.
Then whenever there is a cure called for,
then your python will assume that this is a loop.
Another python will decide that I need to repeat some lines.
Some number off times so as off No,
under your loopy how only one line Now you're fighting will decide that this line of how
could repeat some number of times.
That number of times are how many values you're having here,
like but how it is going to execute.
So whenever there is a for loop for keyword imminently,
or Peyton will look here,
how many values are how many characters if it is a string?
As of now,
we have a list,
right?
Okay.
Four valleys are there.
Then you're fighting.
It will take for us to value first and this valley will assigned to this variable.
Then after assigning whatever the lines you have under,
they were loop.
Those lines will execute ones.
No.
Well,
excluding what I'm doing,
I'm printing each wearable also.
Then currently what is each were able to value?
That's it.
That's where getting this one so fun situation is war were then you are fight on will
immediately after completion of first generation Who is going to store each?
Then you are repeating this time in your python is excluding this.
Then after completion off this line,
your python will go on check immediately the next value What are the next values?
There again,
your pattern will assigned to your each.
Only now you're each wearable is three.
After assigning next to value to your each variable again your pattern leg scored the lines
which are there under it would loop.
But while excluding your printing each No.
Currently,
what is the each one second?
Well,
that's where getting this one.
Okay,
second generation is also over.
Then your fight ultimately will go for third value.
Chervil is formal.
Now this four will assigned to each variable after signing Third World to each then this
logic will repeat third time.
But while debuting third time,
what is their value for?
That's where getting this one.
Then you'll by then we'll look for fourth value.
Yes,
for then four will assigned to each.
Then we'll exclude ones.
My legs good in your printing each also,
that's where getting fight.
Then again,
your pattern will try to look for next value in the given list,
but you don't have next value or already for values are over.
That's why your partner will come out from your loop on.
Let's go.
The next line,
which is the main line in your pipe on court before well is over.
Then the execution part off this line is over.
Then you're biting logo index.
Could this one,
that's we're getting this line,
right?
So,
no,
if you have a list off values from the automatically,
you can take one by one value one.
You can print it using your loop.
Now,
this concept I'm going to use for our task how means home means into a fighting this logic
Say,
First of all,
let me Corbett this court So previously you're taking only people in Pito.
Only two parts your taking,
but,
you know,
in a given.
But you may have any number off parts.
I'm in files and directories.
That's why don't fix.
You don't know about that.
But in the part you don't know how many files are there.
How many doctors are there?
How can you say only two parts people?
And Peter that way?
What I'm doing is right.
Let me come in.
This laws Gasol,
this is simple for Lucas.
Okay?
We have different ways.
We will see all those loops in the next section.
I'm importing ways.
Then I'm reading some part after reading part right.
I'm getting a list off file Sunday territories every day.
Plenty available ways dot list Barrick,
please.
You were given part?
No.
You know,
the result off this operation is always a list That means this variable is the list.
If it is a list,
I can take one by one from they're using for loop.
See that what I'm doing for each fine I'm breaking.
See?
Previously out I can only each while explaining about your look.
But now I'm taking each file based on situation.
You can take any variable.
No,
from this variable list off things.
I'm going to take one by one.
So in that you may have filed similarities,
but I'm taking each file injured.
That each file or directory I can contact.
But don't take this Lenti.
This type of for Lindy variable.
Okay,
for understanding.
But what?
I'm drinking each filer directly from this,
right?
No,
you have to go understand that how many times this loop is going to execute the supreme?
The straight man.
You don't know how many times it is going to score.
It is when they exclude based on how many values you are fetching into this variable this
variable deserve you're getting from where is doubtless territory.
That means you're getting this values very was there is er is a war.
Yeah,
this values So in their living a germ,
A list off values in place.
Off this list off files and territories.
So what?
Your point on every take retake foster value from this undersigned two days and then to
like school the lines we thought there and they would look for how only one print statement
leg school.
Then your partner will try to take next item from this file laboratory and it will start to
this variable.
And we're printing that.
That's why dynamically automatically,
you are going to print all over files or directories from your given location.
No,
you don't need to bother you.
No need to worry about how many files are there.
How many dangers are there automatically or Peyton is going to take care with help off your
loop right now.
Let me go on.
Run your core before that,
Let me weapon your core.
So this is your court?
Simply I'm going to provide some part.
Let me do one thing.
I'm going toe removed.
All empty lines.
Let me clearer screen once again.
Yeah,
This is your script,
right?
No.
I'm going to run your script and I'm going to probably part called New.
I don't see the output you're able to display one by one file from your list off values.
If you want to see the list off values,
you can print that as well.
Print all files on direct.
Chris,
you don't know how many files are there on merit is on there,
but that value automatically you're getting with ways dauntless territory into a variable
called list Underscore.
Wave underscore files underscored battery.
Now see the result.
First of all,
you're getting this one from this list automatically.
Your apartment is going to take with help off for Luke one by one.
Value on.
We're printing that one by one value.
But my intention is not displaying simply or one by one value.
If it is a directory I want to display here,
this is a territory.
This is your file.
But before going to display before going to check whether that is a file or dietary always
not only here wherever you are using,
you should able to fetch complete part first.
So that's why what I'm doing is before printing,
I'm going to create the one variable called What?
That would dig file or directory part file?
Or that I don't know where there is a filer part.
Right?
See,
you were given.
If you are,
you are given part.
So this each file or directory.
So what?
You're going to get complete part right so that we can printed.
But I'm storing into one variable.
Then I will print Way is not part.
Don't join You were given father in that location.
One by one file I'm taking on.
I'm marrying that one by one file for your park.
Then I'm going to print.
Okay.
So,
guys,
For what?
Our understanding purpose.
What I'm taking is this where Lou?
I'm taking okay.
And I'm copping their little indie work script.
So injured off this list off files and directories actually are getting that output us in
this way just for her.
Just to give the clarity,
right.
No gym that you're providing part as something called this one you are providing.
All right,
let me take directly that.
I was so in your script again.
I will remove this.
Any finally will run our script.
No.
Forget about your previous Ah,
logic not.
See here.
This is a part on in this part.
We know Jim,
that we know these are the list off values or items.
Know what I'm doing is I'm going to take one by one from this for each file.
A territory What?
Do your part and we'll go.
This foster valuable ascended this variable on the lines which are there under your look.
Those lines will exclude ones while excluding what we are doing?
I'm taking one variable under the dell pathways that partner join.
I'm adding this part.
See that I'm adding this spot.
Then first time your file is my territory then,
my daughter.
Damn adding here so that I'm going to get for these complete part.
Then you're going to print that second time You're going to take this one.
But I can You are adding for your part only your party's you're given.
But so this part.
Then this file is going to get complete part like waste.
You're going to get part for all the files,
right?
So actually,
what is the variable here?
We heartache and let me dynamically hard work it.
That's why.
Don't fix any values here but internally hydrogen that this well is a realist.
Then remove this one.
That is your logic,
right?
If you want to check your script,
just this is your script from here to here.
Now I'm running and I'm providing it part no seed output for each and every file under
three are getting complete part like but simply introduced printing In this way.
If it is a territory,
I want to print that This is a territory if it is a file I want to burn.
This is the file.
No,
inside off your loop itself.
Like I'm going to add if condition If ways dot part dot is file ever file under a tree?
If it is a file I can say here for the or P.
Is it fine else?
If there is not correct,
that means that is not the file.
That is not the filings.
Then you can say that there is a directory.
No easy directory.
That's it.
Save it unfunny.
But before going to run,
you have to understand once again your entire core,
this entire part you're repeating for each and every value,
which is there in a list list.
Is this one?
No,
this is a list you're taking one by one on for that one by one,
you are finding complete part better That accompanied part.
You're executing this defense block.
If where's that part that is filed for your comfort part?
If it is a file,
this will execute them.
Your first generation is over for foster value.
Then you will take second value for second.
Well,
you're going to get complete part again.
You're checking defense condition.
In case if we seize fighters of false than your printing,
this one then second iteration,
is also over.
Likewise,
you're far rupees doing this action for each and every file.
So they're finally you're going to get dynamically for any number of files and directories
.
You were able to identify the list off filed Sunday.
Please see the output.
He's a territory are getting easier for you.
Not only this path.
Now you can provide any part.
Let me take some other part.
I'm going to takes about this as my part.
Then probably your pot.
Yes,
this is a very loose That's what I'm providing.
Two slashes,
same script.
You can run on your next like systems as well.
It will work without any error in case if you're getting any better.
Anyway,
you won't get it.
If you have any challenges,
just let me know so that I will give the comfort script to work with your innings as well.
But with out there in the little work,
see the results in the given location.
First of all,
you're having this man number off files.
Maybe that restore files you don't know which is a file in which is that a tree by June
That then your python is able to form a complete part.
The part?
What are we are giving from that?
Your partner is ableto are this part then is giving is a fight is a fight is a fight is a
fight Liza Felisa,
That's what it is working,
right?
That's it.
So,
guys,
this entire explanation is just to understand your Luke concert.
Okay?
See are taken this example.
But my intention is not total of this script Tokyo It will loop concepts.
So here how Given Worrell idea in later sections I will use the best up again.
You're completely look how to use that.
What is the complete syntax in which scenario you're going to use which you all those
things we will see We are two loops.
One is for Luke.
We have seen that next lobe is way low.
Along with that to control your loop actions,
you have some break and continue keywords break and continue.
So this also I'm going to explain with help off examples only I won't go directly on.
I want to give your syntax and I won't write your core directly by using your loops.
I will take this situation then so that you can easily understand how.
What is the purpose of that?
Why we need it.
Right?
Okay.
Thank you for watching this with you.