friends here.
We're going to discuss about loop control statements.
See,
basically,
we hold two types off loops in your pipe on right there for Lupin.
Well,
no,
we know that loops are going to repeat for a number of times based on your condition.
Sometimes one time,
sometimes three times,
sometimes 100 times.
Sometimes even in different times,
You're going to repeat your la Z or you're going to eat.
Rate some n number of times.
Let's say very simple example.
Suppose if I have a list,
uh,
consist off.
Let me take simply some four values.
Then it is going to repeat no four times and you're going to get numbers 01234 times.
So engine of these directly donate some list also.
Right?
That's it.
No large Madani.
Now you're going to repeat,
Are you're going to tolerate?
Are you are going to exclude this block?
How many?
Number of times?
12345 Because you have five.
I listen your list than your loop is going to repeat this block for five times are your
loop is going to treat this block for five times,
right?
That's fine.
But no,
we have some control statements for your loops means to control the nutrition part off your
lives.
They are like break Continue right.
Let me explain this year So what I'm doing is C let me go.
Simply one thing I'm reading very firstly itself.
Simply break no See the result?
You're not getting any old port.
The reason is faster.
Fall break is useful to stop your impressions in your loop whenever break is in Kandahar,
right?
Simply or python will stop the loop apart.
So but this land is outside off your look Don't get confused.
Stopping the script is different.
Stopping the loop is different So we know if you remember somewhere we imported a model
cord ces And then if you remember,
sees dot Exit is going to stop your script study.
Let me say we don't only suppose I'm reading here.
Bring before exit,
then print after exit.
Then let me write one more line.
This is print off the luke.
No,
see,
that isn't you're getting before exit only That means you're Skippy is excluding only upto
this in total.
And we have sister exit because off that you're going to stop your entire python script be
clear.
Stopping script is different.
Stopping loop is different right now.
Let me comment.
Or anyway,
we don't want this right.
Let me.
They move all these lines,
not see the result.
Because off break what is happening?
Simply,
your loop is going to stop.
Actually,
where Loop has to repeat five times,
it has to treat four fighting's.
But because of break in the first situation itself,
your loop is going to stop.
But no loop is going to stop even your then.
At that time,
you're not going to exclude any number off lines in your Lou.
So because off this break you were flew off.
Exclusion part will come out from Luke thereafter.
Look what you have.
Apparently simply your printing.
Something offer.
Look,
that's what you are executing other ways.
Let me write the break off for Prince statement.
No,
See the result getting three.
Why?
Before break You help parentage.
So at least for festival your printing offer printing your first value are after excluding
your first situation.
You have immediately break.
We know you have a break.
Actually,
if you don't help break what will happen you're fighting will take this four value and then
we'll print that will decrepit six and it will print it will take 700 will print there were
decayed and we'll print.
That means dance.
You drink for certain number off times,
but because off break you are fluff control.
Instead of going for next value,
it is coming out from your loop.
That's it.
That is the uses off break.
Suppose my intention ease first,
let me print all your values.
Gotta get tingly whenever.
If I get 56 number,
then I don't want to print the remaining numbers,
but no.
But if I get a number called 56 while printing your values offer the numbers,
offer the numbers.
What do you have?
78 means it has to eat red for two more times,
but I don't want it rate,
but nobody for my number is equals to.
If my number is equals to 56 are that time after that?
I don't want to exclude my look.
Then simply use break.
No.
See,
there is a after getting 56.
You are not getting seven and eight because you are stopping your loop whenever if you get
number as 56 That's it,
right?
Yes.
Ah,
June Day.
You're going to get some thousands off parts list list off parts you have in your hand
somewhere in some part somewhere in some part you have.
You require part once.
If you are able to find your require part that I don't want to exclude the remaining it
rations for my No,
let me simply take in this way so that it will be very clear this Assume that I am writing
a simple fight on tiptoe.
Identify all the parts are now June.
But I gotta be all the parts on my host.
Right?
Let me day Suppose he was there being then user been hedged.
City beauty,
some something Some home users,
some X rated user somewhere blows IQ some conflict or XML Something like that,
right?
No,
I need to find out the part in which my head CD Pretty is there.
That is my intention.
Then suppose foster fall to take one by one part for each part in your parts.
Then I can print it simply in this way.
My each part I can print,
but I want to bring the part which consist off extra dpt right.
See that if if Hexter DPS their heads to DPD,
if it is there in your part,
then I am printing it's brandy.
But your loop is not stopping.
It is taking somewhere second generation in the second inauguration.
Your condition is satisfied.
Then you're printing anyway because this is for Lou.
It is going to take next to Park on.
It is checking anyway.
In this,
it is not their extra deeply.
That's why you're not getting in on port.
But still,
your python is trying to take remaining integration values remaining values from your list
.
But my indention ease once.
If I get my path,
I'm in the pot,
which consist off extra de pretty.
Then I don't want to you today remaining for remaining parts.
I don't want to exclude my look for remaining part simply,
I want to stop because I got my required part.
Why should a hatred for remaining parts?
Why should I waste?
And I said to my execution time.
That's why what I'm doing is simply I'm stopping like,
see if I don't use break just for your understanding,
I'm writing Brink.
No working on.
I'm bringing each part.
See the result working on foster part Anyway.
Listen,
it's city,
but is not there.
That's why you are not printing your part now.
Working on user be next year.
But in this extra DPD is there.
That's why you're printing that.
So now you've got the require part.
Why should we go on?
Take next part I don't want to get.
But your fighting is taking.
No,
because it is a loop.
It is going to take all the parts.
I mean,
whatever the list of Alice you hope.
But now my requirement is once.
If I get my required apart,
then I want to stop forcefully.
My loop.
Yes.
You can stop it in this way that you don't see that once.
If you print your each part,
then you're stopping right now.
Let me write something outside.
Off your Lou Old trade off for Luke.
No,
You're getting ordered off for Lou Plane offer printing.
You're actually,
but immediately it is stopping because break is there.
When are break ins and contour?
Simply Your look will stop.
Not only were for Luke,
even it will work even forever while loop as well.
Let me take simple example in my loop.
Suppose I'm going in this way while true.
You know this is the infinity,
Lou,
right?
So initially,
I'm taking some Cone County close to one.
Fine.
I'm printing my count after count.
I'm increasing my co owned by complice one.
Yes,
You're going to get in vin numbers.
But my indigenous in guess if I get if I bring the number I mean up 200.
Once I reached 100 then I want to stop my way,
Luke.
Then what I'm doing is if your company's equals 200 stop your will.
That's it.
Break.
See that?
Once 100 is reach,
you're going to stop forcefully.
You're Luke.
Stopping loop is nothing but stopping the next year.
Relations you are stopping engine off going for next.
Recent?
Simply.
What's stopping you?
Allude.
That's it.
So that is the use case off your simply I mean about the break.
No,
let me go with Continue.
So try to understand,
Canoe.
It is somewhat confusion,
but in it understand it Anyway,
while going forward will use this continue on break in different scenarios so that it will
be good.
But at least for time being,
just try to understand What is the logic behind in your continue?
See,
Suppose what I'm doing is let me take arrange off 10 numbers,
then I'm bringing all the numbers.
First of one?
Yes.
You're getting from 1 to 9.
Right,
Joe?
Tonight.
But I want to get suppose 1 to 10 but nobody can take anything.
Let me take 1 to 11 so that you're going to get stop was 1 to 10.
No,
I want to print the numbers 1 to 10 except the seven number.
Then I can write in this your first awful If number is whatever the number.
If that is not equals to seven,
then I am printing.
That's fine.
This is one way,
right?
Your logic Right now you're not getting your number seven right?
One more ways,
Foster,
for simply am writing print printing your number,
then let's be clear.
I'm going toe.
Ah,
right.
Your print each outside off your if condition.
See that renting your number.
Printing your number.
Right?
First of all,
your printed statement these old side off your if condition now into off this line simply I
am writing Continue if number recourse to seven.
I'm reading.
Simply continue.
No see,
the results were not getting seven.
No off course.
Your previous logic is perfectly Garrett.
If number is I mean,
if each is not equal to sound,
that only printed that is correct.
But at the same time,
you can also write your logic in this way.
What will happen if you write?
Continue keyword,
See,
whenever continue is excluding by your python.
Then in that situation,
the remaining logic whatever you how in your block that is going to simply skip not only
this line,
even if you have some 100 lines here offer continue.
See here also here itself.
I have a continue African new.
Suppose this is the line inside off you were.
If condition off the continue keyword,
see the result know that you are not more where you're getting that line.
The reason is let me take this.
See after continue in your work.
If for Lupul Block even if you are some thousands off lines,
all are going to skip now You're fightin will go for next year.
Duration.
It's actually it is going to repeat for 10 times,
right?
1 to 11 means 10 numbers you're going to get once you are number is equals to seven.
If it is not ecosystem.
When you're not excluding,
continue then simply or printing.
But if it is equals to seven,
what'll happen continues exuding whenever continues excluding the remaining lines.
Ritchie,
how in your block they are going to simply mosque.
They're going to skip that for time being.
Guys don't worry much about your continue keyword simply as you in that when our can new
line is excluding by your python then that remain lanes which are their offer community
word they are going to skip.
So while writing some real time scripts,
you will get multiple situations there.
You will understand that why we need this Continue keyword upto that yard.
Oh,
wait.
But I'm being just a gym that can Who is going to skip the remaining lines in that
situation?
They okay this tour de you are Luke Contra statements.
I mean break and can you apart from that,
you are also having simply pass key words are pass a statement.
What is this?
Not only for your loops,
it is also helpful for your functions classes and then,
if condition first,
let me write something called If then print Okay,
Mostly the result.
That is fine.
Right?
But what I'm being is I'm going this line.
If true,
am rating.
Now you're getting another.
The reason is you know that whenever you feel have a condition,
you should have some block inside off.
That right,
at least one lane.
But for timing,
I don't want right anything.
Of course.
I don't know what how to write as off.
No,
but I don't want to get another then simply right.
Pass.
It won't do anything simply,
it will a wide aren't we simply make a one block,
but it won't do anything.
That's it.
The same day.
Let me take some.
Simply look for each in.
Simply range off anything you can take,
right?
No,
I'm burning.
You're getting another.
Because for Lou,
right,
Blue means it has to treat certain number off Time's supper number off.
Times of some court R block are some set off statements.
But we don't know anything.
No,
that's why it is giving another so as off.
I don't know what I have to write,
but I need a loop here just to await another.
You can use your vascular.
That's it.
I Oh,
yes.
Thank you for watching this for you.
These south mainly guys mainly need to understand about break and continue.
Right?
Anyway,
break is clear,
but maybe some people will.
How confusion on can you?
But you will get clarify while going forward.
Right?
Okay,
bye.