friends here.
We're going toe work with the daytime module.
See,
this daytime model is a default model with your python,
the Ford or bidding model with your python on,
which is used to work with the dates sometimes.
Okay.
Just imagine that you're going to create some log file every day,
and I want to create my log file with dates.
I mean,
while creating my log file name.
I want to include the date as well in the file name.
So here I want include a day not lug.
So,
Dave,
eyes,
I want to great my log files,
then.
Well,
creating your final aim automatically.
Unit toe.
Create your filing with the bed.
Suppose I'm giving one of a simple example.
Likewise your different usages in your real time with your daytime model.
Right?
Fine.
See,
we know that if you have any model and if you want to use that foster fall,
you hardly import that right.
Let me enter into my fight on Colonel.
I'm going to import a daytime module.
That's it.
No guys inside off this debt I model.
We hope some sub models are some operations.
Let me show you that we know how to listen the list off operations which are there with
your model c inside off this daytime model again you house.
Someday they time their times the a p a time time,
goldar time,
Jonah and I'm going in for I mean,
these are the different operations with your main daytime model on this is used to work
with the only dates and this is used to work with only time on this,
you can get both the operations.
I mean,
these data operations.
And this time,
operations both you can get from your daytime model.
Nothing.
Okay,
so in this video,
right,
I'm going to work with the daytime operation only from your main module.
Their time I'm going toe work with the daytime operation.
Right.
So that means See that from your date time model.
This is your main model inside off that you have a operation called daytime.
Then what are the operations on that model?
That operation.
See that?
These all are the operations,
right?
Let me go with the some of them.
At least see drink their time.
This is your main model in that This is the operation in that If I want to see.
What is that date as off?
No,
they done time.
Like not only that,
you can also use this operation supposed today,
right?
Both are going to give same information.
But there is a small difference.
I will show you that on as off.
No,
this host is that I mean,
the time John for this host is I ust Indian time.
I said right.
Fine.
Let me weapon my UNIX terminal,
which has been created from a rib Lasak owned on by default.
You know that time,
Joan,
for this is UTC time,
right?
No.
Let me enter into my fight on thermal and I'm going to import a model called Daytime Model
Here also on now you know how to print They were today's date on time.
So from your date time just set up your sub model daytime from that?
No.
So this is 7 25th I mean,
July 25th.
Yes,
even in your local host also 7 25 But time is here.
Our own 84 real money.
Yet 2 35 PM right?
There is a small difference.
That means the time John for this host is UTC so based on that you are getting your time.
I mean,
even you can use their time door today.
Also this today also you can use it.
Yes,
You're getting same information.
Fine.
First of all,
you have to understand that that no under today operations are going to give you the time
date information based on it were default time,
John which has been set for you.
What host like if you want to get I'm John information off any other time June.
I want to get supposed.
Yeah,
I know you are No UBC right as off.
No,
you are not UTC because this is a lie.
Next box on that I'm joined for this.
Is you busy?
But here I want to get my yesterday.
I mean,
if you want to get your yester timing right,
see that you can get from this operation Only this operation is get is used to get only
your local time.
There is no there is no any other option to get other times on information from this
operation.
But using this operation not know I can get any other.
I'm John information,
but before going to get it,
What is the time,
June You need for that time.
Joan,
you need to create a one object so that you can create by using fight.
Is it module bite on time,
John Model as off.
No,
don't worry about this,
okay?
We'll discuss in detail about your time.
June information later.
As off now.
Yes.
I want to show you the difference between dart No andare today.
The white desert.
Don't let me Corbett otherwise how holiday syntax For that I want to create a yesterday
time,
Joan simply from your time John Aisyah Kolkata that it was for my estate.
I'm John object.
I created my object now one out of Louise.
If you print badly in this way without giving any arguments or any value to you are no
operation.
It is going to your local time,
which is as off No,
on this horse.
You busy?
But I want to get I want to get four.
I used to time,
June.
Then you can pass your time,
But don't bury right as a string your time,
John.
You have to create some object.
No.
See that 28 mean eight PM eight minutes.
Right.
See the result?
Vacancy on my window.
Also right out of I just open my terminal and see the results for is a time 88 PM That's
what you are getting.
So if you want to get any other time,
John,
information now is helpful.
Dart.
No operation is helpful.
Like Fine.
These are very hard to get your local time as well as any other time.
John.
Information.
Okay,
here.
I want to show you one more thing.
Type A USD.
See these?
A class court?
You are.
I am Joan information so that you don't write your string here in no operation,
they are to write some glass object.
So that already concluded from pure teacher model.
I get in that.
No,
nothing is there for any time,
Johnny.
Hard to just change your time John here and passed that information in your now so that you
are going to get from your local host any time John Information.
That's fine,
right?
No.
Let me weapon my local host so somewhat.
This is local host.
It may be dark today or maybe dot No,
no problem.
Night.
See as off?
No,
because of dot no or dark today what you're getting you're getting and buyer date with
minutes and hours.
Seconds.
Fractional seconds.
Right.
But I don't want to get all those things I want to get only what is the year from here?
See the result?
What is the month?
I can start this result Anderson Variable Also I What is the date?
I mean day.
Then what is the power then?
What is a minute?
Even seconds also,
You can get it right.
That's it.
Fine.
But in June of getting in this way just to get your year,
Month day on this final object you're doing dot Operation Gold a year Monday.
How?
Or something like that.
But I want to get suppose year on the month.
Then you need to former dis reserve.
Right?
See,
that isn't What I'm doing is if you bring in this way,
you're getting your result.
No,
I'm going to former.
I'm going to convert that into string format on based on my requirement.
My requirement is I want to get only here.
Not that I mean 19 2004 digits here.
I want to get only to do this year.
Then month.
Then after that,
what you need?
They not so I'm Mr One More parents is mostly the result.
I'm going to do this in your the year if I take.
If I take capital,
why no see that result?
So you feel remember only dead time operation from your daytime model.
From this,
you can get either your time.
I mean minutes or hours or date or month.
Wondered where we can get anything by using string for my time.
You can former Ah,
your unit of possum.
You were letters based on your requirement.
So how you can remember all those things?
Nothing is that Let me weapon one website call string former time dot War G string,
former dot former time dot watch e Right.
This website is going to do all ur symbols.
I mean,
according what is the meaning for that?
You just Abdul here and you can for Marty will result.
So suppose definitely I want to get some former in this way instead of your default print.
What are your printing with your know what?
Today you're getting in this way,
but I want to format.
That's a I wanted for murder in this way.
I'll see that is a mighty of what it is Giving some former so for each and every letter.
The reason.
Meaning you just go to this letter on after the output,
right?
You need to remember this.
Just remember this website whenever If you want to write some by tons,
could be using their time model undefended.
But if you want to format your date time,
then come back to your string.
Former time dot org on Abdoulaye were courts and its meanings.
So after doing some practice definitely will remember at least some characters.
I'm in some courts.
Right?
Fine.
Then I want to discuss one more thing here.
That is very,
very important.
One.
Let me do that.
So from your daytime dot their time,
if you see the results,
you're having different operations,
right?
Just know we discuss about right today now and then.
Some string former something like that.
Where is it?
Yes,
String.
Former time,
right?
No,
I want I'm going to work with one more thing called from times time.
What is that?
See,
that isn't if I try to bring a date time dot bit time dot from I'm Stam.
So this operation is going to take the seconds number off seconds.
If you provide number of seconds automatically,
it will convert into your date.
Let's say I'm going to provide.
Maybe that is not sufficient to create your debts.
Let me right.
Or maybe spell Mr From.
I am stumble spelling mistakes,
not see the reason in real argument.
Yes,
he So this is maybe more than Mag Zoom are limit off your date.
I mean,
if you see here some very harm Anyone?
My exam.
Right.
So Mag zoomed.
It is able to provide up to late time dot Sorry,
Max.
So my except a triple line.
44 nines.
So maybe this seconds are more than that.
That's what it is not able to convert.
That's it.
So this one is very,
very important.
We will use it in the real time as well.
Okay,
so that's as off.
No,
I'm giving only this symbol operations.
Right.
Well,
going forward,
we will see some more operations,
right?
I just try to remember these things.
So what we discussed we imported their time model.
So in their time,
what will be hard,
different operations,
different sub models,
like date time,
and then their time.
So if you go with the date you can work with.
Only date.
If you go with time,
we're gonna work with only time.
But if you go with the daytime,
you can work with either date or time or both at the time.
That's what I'm going to work with the daytime,
right?
Then someone we're printing in this very their time dot daytime not know,
right by 84.
And I was going to give a local our time.
John,
whatever the time during you said for your host,
that time doing it is going to provide.
But if you want to work with any other time,
Joan,
what you gotta do is your toe import some model call fight on time,
John,
and then created were required.
I'm John object.
Quite time Johnny course to simply You were P weight.
Is it in that you had to provide time,
John?
They inside this yard to write your time,
John.
Name on.
Then.
If you take this on,
if you provide that variable here now,
it is going to you that time based Don't even require time,
John.
Right?
And one more thing this Beware they these people.
Tizard is not a default model in it.
Imported into to install it on imported.
Okay,
we'll work aboard.
Ah,
how to use be weight.
Age it later I find so after that the final thing you have to remember that how to convert
you are date time,
final or port in tow.
String format.
Right In this way,
here you are probably required courts.
And just to remember that there is a website called s T R f time dot org Night on one more
point.
Ease.
See,
guys from your date time your important You are using their time one second night.
I don't want right two times this date time.
Then what you do,
What you will do is we can do in this way from their time import bit time.
Now you don't write this part because directly from this you are importing this into your
script.
Now I can do simply bring their time dot No Likewise All operations,
let me show you on my common line from day I am import they time no directly.
I'm reading their time.
Don't know that's it.
Okay,
this is just shortcut enough using lenti daytime dot daytime from their time that it'll
imported time.
Now you are importing the operation directly from your daytime model.
What is your operation?
If this is your date time,
you're inside off that.
Your operation?
Is this wonderful?
I'm importing this one.
No,
I can use deadly this one in this way.
Not okay.
Okay.
Thank you for watching this video.
We'll see some more concepts while going forward.
Okay.
Look at I