prince here.
We're going to write a simple by transcript with your so process model.
The requirement is find bash washing off planet ways.
See if I take my Lennox Warriors sort Colonel,
you know you have a bash on your body.
Next,
like systems are different.
Bash,
iPhone,
iPhone washing your getting some more put.
But here's what I need.
I need this value only full auto out for six.
That is actually my washing my bash wash.
And I need that output only I don't want entire output.
See,
Before going to run your command with your python,
you are so think about your requirement.
I mean,
whether you want to run simply your common or you also need some modifications on your old
put if you want to run simply your command,
then just to go on use waste our system.
That is very simple one but on the output if you need some modifications as off No,
see that we need to get this output from this.
We want only this four door to door for six.
That means we need some modifications on your own.
Put.
That's why I just go on,
run your command using so process model.
Right?
See,
now I'm going to write a python.
Skip,
just toe,
get bashed.
Washington Bias Washington B Y Yes.
I'm going to import some process model.
See,
before going to right there were bite landscapes using so process,
right?
You just keep in your hand.
This document only We heard that from a previous video for timing,
bedlam,
coping this our line.
But you people don't copy and face the court here.
You just try to light type your core.
So that will.
Italy.
It is easy,
toe.
Remember your core,
right?
Your sin.
Taxes for yourself.
Process?
No,
actually.
Bashes space hyphenation,
iPhone,
iPhone.
Abortion command is not depending on any environment.
Variables.
That's why I can take simply command because to false Sorry.
I mean,
Sally closed toe falls.
If I take Shelly Coastal Falls,
you know you have to take your command as a list.
So bash hyphen,
iPhone Washington.
So how could get their command as a list means once again,
I'm feeling that Just go to your bite on tunnel.
Take your windows.
Common as thirties.
I mean window.
Sorry.
Next.
Like systems then.
I just played this in this way.
Then you're getting some more port.
That is nothing.
What?
You were a list for silicones,
Toe falls.
That's what I'm doing here directly.
Because as off no,
I know the require thing.
So that's what exactly?
I'm ready.
Bash.
I have my phone.
Wasn't as a list.
Fine.
After running your common right,
it may take some time to exclude your common anywhere.
Bash space,
hyphen,
iPhone Washing is very simple command.
It won't take any Ah,
much time.
You need to wait.
But it is a better practice to use.
Yes,
but not wait.
Because sometimes whenever we were going to use some such command it would take some time
to exclude your commands.
That so I just tried to make a habit that using SP not wait in your court.
Then find out your output on ETA.
So you know how to get your output on them simply by communicating with the world.
SB that's it.
No,
guys see,
Based on our secret,
I can say that where your command was success or fail,
right?
Let me do one thing.
If r c if it is equals to Jiro,
then I consider strongly I can say bring Oh,
please.
So it is old put.
Oh,
that is available.
You are taken else means if our sick or is not a coastal settlements.
There was a failure,
so common was fade Return error Banana are Natalee's so are easy.
We are We are taking what you can take any wearable like let me say this and run the court
.
Let me run this with by country.
We need my country,
Right,
right.
You're getting your output right on.
What I'm doing is I'm going to take a invalid command in trough.
You're bash iPhone,
iPhone.
Watch any fire in high fun bash Washington.
You're getting an invalid syntax.
I mean,
common is not excluding probably.
Right.
That is actually not a valid command.
So that's why what I'm doing is just I'm taking your list of basses,
then injured off hyphen iPhone Washington I'm taking You should not take just to show that
whether our court is working properly or not.
For that I am taking this one.
Let me show your court ones and then let me run your core.
See?
Common was failed on an Aries bash washing no such fire territory.
So something wrong with your comer.
So we know that what is all wrong here,
That's why.
Be careful whenever if you're taking your comments.
So same command.
You can also run by using Shelley Coast.
True,
by simply taking your command as a string but on windows,
please prefer Shelly Coastal.
True always.
Okay,
Plane.
So they says off.
No,
you are getting your output with your fight on.
But requirement is I don't want to get this entire output right.
I need only this one.
That's why what I'm doing is,
first of all,
I'm going to come What?
Your entire output into a list.
You can convert your output,
which is ah,
from your SP,
right.
Split the lines by using that.
Even get Europa has at least to see that you're getting as a list right now.
What I'm doing is I'm going to print your line one by one.
Just observe the logic so I don't want to print in this way.
What I'm doing is I'm taking one by one all value from your list which has been created
from your out port simply for each line in your output,
nor speak lines simply.
I'm bringing each line.
See that?
See the logic,
right?
The same way.
Just practice it gay.
So that it will be easy for you to understand this court.
Yes,
I get your getting your entire output.
But I want to print the lines which are having only wash in.
Not simple.
See that what I'm doing is if Washington,
in line in your each line,
then only printed that line otherwise don't create their line.
No.
See the logic.
What?
You're going to get your or put?
Yes.
You're getting these two lines,
right?
But what you need you need first liners off.
No,
right.
I'm in Washington.
So as off.
No,
you don't know that X concept?
What?
We leave?
Yeah.
Based on release,
I will take if Washington under lease Both words are there in a given line.
Then all I want to print that.
See,
guys,
I'm going to use now.
Here one You are logical operator called on if Washington each line on them.
Release Washington as well as really what I should have in my line then Only I want to
print that line.
There is you need to understand about logical overturned when you're to take on the means.
See,
my requirement is this thing should be true.
This thing should be true.
Whenever these two are true,
Are there time only?
I want to exclude my condition.
So in that case,
you know toe club your two conditions with help off under operator.
So if both are true,
then only your final result will be true if use under operator.
But if you take all over to know you're going to get again two lines,
you just take it so that you can understand.
Now let me Ronnie Transit output.
Now you're getting only one line,
which is having Russian as well as release.
But I need this part,
right?
I need this part.
So what I'm doing is nice As of now,
I don't know about rogue ex.
That's why I'm doing so many steps later,
we will see again with the reggae X factor.
Very simple as off.
No,
don't concentrate on break.
It's just see the logic.
What I'm doing Night.
So now 1234 to part You are getting as I mean indexed for easy or required out.
Put us off now.
Let me take this from this.
I'm taking index three value not to.
But I eat only four door to door for six.
Then again,
split this with help off this parenthesis.
See that?
What I'm doing is again I'm splitting.
You are out Port base.
Wrong.
This parent assists symbol Where is it?
That's it.
Under that I'm taking Index digital just to see first we thought this one what is all
pretty or gdi If I split that our port with tell preferences what we're getting You're
getting a list which consisted of food or to write for six under.
Then second value is something but I need this.
Well,
that's why just taken x Eljero.
Let me write that index digital.
So this is the final requirement through which you're going to get your bash wash and fold
or corrupt for six night.
So that is successfully we implemented a cold Ah,
accord Call getting bashed washing using fight on on your index like systems.
Right?
So,
guys,
there's not that much important.
But the thing is how you were using your so process for your requirement that is important
.
Getting bashed washing is not the important thing,
right?
How you are implementing your UNIX.
Come on,
get your bash.
Washington using your fight on that is important.
So that's why I was given this example,
right?
No.
Before going to the next video,
Please,
please try to find job awash in using your fight on.
Yeah,
for job for you to take only one high fun,
right?
If you run your core,
I need to get only $1 are not Jiro underscore to double one.
So before going to next video,
please please try to implement by yourselves this output.
I don't know if I run If I provide this command for myself process I mean for my bite on
Skip.
I need to get a washing as wonders on or Jiro underscore to double one.
I just I'm giving one clue.
In case if you're not getting in output,
please see your are as well.
See your or put a little on Friday.
Implement your logic to get the old job wife on washer.
So why I am giving this example is you have on important point with your job.
IPhone washing command Whenever.
If you're running with your fighter,
right?
So before coming the next video,
please try to implement the core.
Get your Java Washington using your python by excluding your command with help off.
So process model.
Right?
Okay.
Thank you for watching this video.