difference here.
We're going to write Very simple Bite on Skip.
And that is simply printing some message.
So here,
I'm going to print hello Word using your python script and what I would escape.
You're going to write that I'm going to write using V am on default ideally.
So here.
We're going to see a simple bite on strip by using either we Emily that or default Ideally
right,
Let me weapon First off all my common line on my Windows operating system,
you can write same program,
same script on your Lennox or any UNIX like systems as well,
right?
So,
guys,
I'm moving into my desktop there.
I'm going to create Python script territory.
Let me enter into that so as have no you don't know anything in this directory night.
See if you want to use via murder.
First of all,
you should have the am only what host?
So you know what previous video?
We have seen different types off Raiders and I'll give any link to install we America on
your windows.
Troubling system anywhere.
Biting for the V i e.
Is there on your UNIX like systems you can use We I on what?
UNIX like systems,
but it windows you don't have.
Yea,
but you can install William.
Right?
So I already installed that.
No.
Let me run,
William.
Simply Hello word Not be what you can take any name.
Grace.
Any script name you can take on extension is dot the way just to know that there is a fight
on script.
What?
Fight on program?
No,
let me under Were young space some program name 0.3 way right now I'm going to a weapon.
We were V.
I am a reader.
I open that right?
See,
guys,
my intention is I had to write a some pie transcript or fight on program.
And if I run that program I had to get output are simply some hello world,
right?
Soto print to something toe prints some texture,
Mrs.
Or string in your python.
You're to use print simply but And this is in double condition.
You had to write your text,
our message,
our string Whatever you want to print through your pipes on program.
That's it.
So print parentheses,
then inside parentheses with quotations.
You hard right?
Some string or Mrs or text,
right?
No.
Let me say this first.
Observe your script.
Whatever you help.
So this is our script,
right?
So this is like in Windows Cat Common,
I am seeing my file.
My program?
My script?
Yes.
This is the line in my program.
Okay,
so now I'm going to run it,
fight on.
So I say,
if you want to run your script by town,
skip,
you are to run in this way on your windows operating systems by dawn.
Space your program name.
But before going to that ticket whether you configure your fight on on your host or not,
Yes,
I am getting some watching.
Means I have a fight on on my host on that wasn't in some theaters under Jiro.
Now I can use bite on space.
Hello.
Work?
Not really.
See that Put their getting hello world.
Right?
So you guys here,
you have to understand one more thing while running.
You're running in this way.
Fight on space Your hello world dot The way some program name dot The way now as off No,
I am using pi country.
Right?
So if I want to run same program with fight on three.
So Allie,
how somewhere in my host.
Fight on two as well,
Right?
Let me run with Python.
So you have to probably complete part because you contact two parts to your system parts.
That's why I'm selecting.
Bite on three as the default one on poor piped onto whenever.
If I want to run my python script with fight on two,
I will probably the complete part for my fight on to wash in.
So my bite onto is that in this location,
if you want to check,
you can check abortion right now.
If you want to run your script of using fight on two just provided complete part where you
install your python,
then your program name or skip name.
See that?
That's it.
Okay,
on you guys.
Whatever we return,
write that script.
We are running from common line,
so there's the first thing you have to know,
because as an automation,
you know you have to run your scripts from command line.
We already discussed this point Fine.
So there's if you want to write one more line,
so I want to print output like a lower or welcome to fight on.
So this is in one line.
I want to print one more line,
then bring in quotations Whatever you want to print it just right that the information here
.
So I am writing Welcome to fight on scripting If you want,
right,
One more line,
Let's say print.
This is my first script.
So now through our pie transcript we are printing three lines off information with the help
of this a script.
Let me save it.
And after the output,
I mean first of your script.
No money.
Enter seed output.
Whatever you how inside off your print inside off your quotations That information is
printing underlies whenever.
If you're on your python program,
it will run from top to bottom line by line,
Right,
Very first line.
Hello,
World 40.
This information will be print then this one,
then this one.
Right?
So there is a simple script with your fight on and here we written our script with help off
William on.
We are running that with fight on three as well as fight on to also right.
So there's if you're having confusion like running simply by python or by providing
complete fight on pot,
right?
Just try to install only one python on your host on said the part for your fight on.
I'm just trying to work with that.
Only right in guessing fell both the fight on washings on your host just to provide your
just.
Are your fight on part of your system part for only anyone of the fight on washing it?
Maybe two or three,
right?
Aren't come to command line on.
Just type in this way.
Suppose here.
If you're getting three dot sound or Jiro,
then by default,
you're running your python programs with help off fight on three oceans.
So if you want to run this program with any other abortion,
just try to power complete part off your pie tone Interpreter.
That is nothing but fight under E x e.
Of course.
Morning to provide dot Txt by default,
it will take dot txt extension because you are only work with those offering system.
That's it.
Okay.
On here,
guys,
I need to probably one more clarity observed that in your script,
right?
This entire thing is a string or text.
Our message,
right?
Actually see the string.
If you want to print any string on your common line while running your program always You
have to take it.
Bring See Here This is a number,
right?
Number is also your string If you provide inside off your quotation stringing a demon group
off characters If you write anything inside operations that will be history.
That is always history.
If you write anything inside of quotations that is always a string.
So print is used to simply to print some string on your common line on your terminal on
your display while running your program.
We're learning your script,
right?
Fine.
So you know,
we work with the Veum Ada from command line.
We know once if install your python right biting for you will get ideally Let me click this
.
I really right.
Let me open that.
Ideally,
it's opening.
Yeah,
it's a done right.
No,
you can go with the file.
A new No.
What are the program you have?
Whatever this could be.
You have just copy and paste it or you can type it under saving.
Okay,
you can say with anywhere,
right?
Other ways.
Good.
With the file and the weapon you are existing pipeline program.
So already we have on our desktop somewhere here we have some Hello Word.
No,
that is the program,
right?
Let me close this.
Now this is your scooped so you can run this from here.
Also,
see that put you're going to get so guys,
you can also write your python scripts are programs by using ideally also So for that,
what do you have to do just to go to your start and then click on?
Ideally,
it will open this ideally right by Don Shell.
Click on file New in Guess if you won't write a new pipeline program Art If you how some
existing python just click on open and select your fight on program from your partner
location.
Then it will open like this.
Then go on,
run here using when model are from your keyboard.
You can also click on your fight so that your program will run.
I So there's my station is just try to know about ideally.
But don't use this Ideally,
if you want to use,
you can use it.
But my brother,
my preferences common line via Meritor RV air down during its like systems.
We are William.
That's it.
You can take anything.
Okay,
So this is a simple way to write simply Hello,
Earl.
Or any toe prints?
Some message with help off your python.
Okay,
look at this.
Thank you for watching this video.