friends.
In our previous video,
we have seen how to read a CSE file using python with the help off the fall.
The model called CSP on here.
We're going to see how to get on Lee Header instead of getting your entire data from your
CIA sweet.
I mean,
instead of getting all rose from your sees me,
I want to get only the header or foster ruin us,
sees we file and then I want to see how many rules are there.
New York,
CS.
We fight,
right?
Fine.
Let me open our previous read your script.
You know,
this is our previous school,
right?
So this we're using just to really worse es three file content.
So CSU is nothing but number off rows and columns.
You have your rows and columns in your CSB fight.
No,
I know,
but if you're able to see your data,
right,
that dead eyes in terms awful list.
I mean,
each row is one list in that way you're getting that's fine.
Know what I'm doing is angel off interrupt using your father Lou,
see that I can directly print your data.
We told using for loop.
See how I'm going to bring list off.
I'm converting your data.
URC sp data in realist.
No,
see the result.
That's it.
You're going to get your all rules as the one list.
That means inside off a list each value each row is again a list.
Actually,
this list were able to separate with help off your follow.
Right?
This is what we're doing with your for Luke.
You are taking one by 11 by one.
This is a This entire thing is one rule this rule were taking each each is nothing but this
one.
We're printing that next again we're taking this through,
and then we're blending there.
So in the know we're printing your data on,
we've been able to see your CSP rules.
Actually,
it is good to print your information in this way in self printing as a one list,
right?
What it is.
Yeah.
Let me come in.
This so it is actually good.
So,
by seeing this,
you can understand that this is a hey that this is the first rule.
This is a second room,
right?
00 Seeing should off your for loop board wearing simply were directly converting.
You are fight on sees the object in realist.
So you're getting this information now.
If you are there in your output,
that is a list which consists off each value as one row.
The foster is always ahead.
All right.
That's why what I'm doing.
You see that green?
The header Ease.
So here,
I want to bring to the header.
I want to bring to the head of burden in next line.
I'm going to print your header.
So what is your header list off content in the in their Jiro index is they?
You are ahead of Let me come in this line.
I don't see that is a what happened.
List off.
Yeah.
Ah,
content off,
Joe.
No city after converting as a list.
Not no.
See,
there is a you're getting your head of This is one way,
right?
But injured off that there is one more way just to get your head are simply bring There is
a before the operation called Next.
Next.
See?
Actually,
by default the number if you open your file,
your cancer is there at very first operation are in the first row,
so next means you're simply sending your castle in your file.
Who next lane.
But before sending your Custer to next line What is there in the current line with your
cancer that contained?
We're looking ableto print with help off next to operation.
See that right?
See,
after doing this operation after doing this operation are even in order to print.
If you want to get your header into your hand,
you can print it are simply I'm doing this operation after this operation.
What I'm doing is I'm trying to print the rate at which is there in your content?
No,
you're not getting your header because already,
Heather,
we we moved our cursor from other to first row with help off this operation.
But while sending if you want to capture your header yes,
you can capture your other in this way Now in header variable,
you have a header Information off your CSB file So once If you do next operation on the
word CSP object It is going to get where the custody is their individual Your cursor is
there that contemptible store into your header variable.
You can take any wearable I'm taking her then the remaining data Whatever you have in your
content,
right?
So your custody is sending the next line.
That means you're sending your cancer toe Next rule.
Then you actually you hold some was for our file header Flus troll.
Second rule This is her That first to a second row whenever.
If you open your file because that is their right here in this push in your custody is
there.
Know what wearing were sending forcefully that cost are due next role.
That's fine.
Now in your content How only two rows.
So by using for loop,
you can able to get only those two rows Right now I see that if you want to get your header
one thing is can what?
You were content and be a list.
And then from that get index zero That is by default your header.
But instead of that,
it's very simple.
Header Next gunned int.
So how did you are getting into this variable?
That's it.
So even you don't want to do this because you need Suppose if your concentration is only on
header part you know it off this for you.
So let me bring my head.
Animal,
bring the head Agrees you can use any format off your prints.
Statement?
That's it you're getting.
So that is the number off Rose means after separating your head up than remaining are the
roost,
right?
You don't include your head as a one row and there is headed only that is not your actual
data,
right?
Just for header partners,
you are including that ruin your CSU file,
then remaining.
How many rules are that,
then?
Simply print lent off.
List off your content.
We know if you have a list in that we can calibrate how many values are there.
Suppose if hell three rows in a list.
You are getting three values as a list.
You are Rose.
That's why first time see that.
Let me print that.
We thought,
Ah,
this lent operation.
Let me print your remaining date.
Offer taking Heather?
No,
the remaining there days.
Who values inside off your main leads to see that this is a main list,
right?
So now,
first,
the list is a value that is nothing but roll one.
So I'm gonna list is a value that is nothing but wrote to so no one value second value no
insider for list actually have two values knife.
I try to a play for this lento operation.
We know.
What is the lengthy uses off Lent on your list or couple Turow's Now I can print in this
way The number off Rose.
What?
That's it.
Kudos.
Suppose I assume that you are not separating.
We're headed.
Let me come into your head up.
No,
the list off Rose are three.
Actually,
if you don't want to cancer the Heather header than what you are to go,
just subtract minus one year.
That's it.
But it's also fine.
You heard it under them Compton.
Remaining rules in your content.
That's fine.
Or if you are not reading Header,
find the number off rose in your work content then sub sect with minus one so that they're
going to get the number off rose in your scenes we find right.
So,
guys,
that is a simple way just to really roll header on to find the number off rules in your
sees.
We file.
Okay.
Okay,
guys,
Thank you for watching this with you.