friends here.
We're going toe work with the Jason files using Fight on.
What is Jason?
You know,
Jason is a javascript object notation,
and it is a popular data for March used for representing structure data guys before Jason.
You know XML,
right?
What is the purpose of excitement?
The purpose affects Emily just will transform your data from server to application or from
application to server or simply server to client our client to server the same way we are
using even Jason as well.
Night.
See,
let me show you a simple Jason file.
So we have a simple Jason fight.
Let me open it.
Yeah,
I see.
Here,
this entire thing is one Jason file.
And if you have the in there,
do you How calibrates Starting on ending.
So in terms off fight on these a dictionary.
But as party or Jason,
this is a object.
You should say you're dictionary as object in your Jason.
Fine.
See,
for the same Jason file,
whatever the content to be represented.
I mean,
whatever they represent,
they're using this Jason former same better.
They're also going to represent using XML.
That means you can write your data to transmit over the network either by using XML or by
using Jason for simple er data.
We're going to use Jason format for complex city data.
We're going to use XML fight.
That's it.
Okay,
fine.
No.
Let me copy this simple Jason file.
And I want to store it as a some with some Jason for,
Let's say,
my Jason,
nor does an extension.
So this is now your Jason file.
So what we are doing here is we want to read the Jason file.
Or if you want to write the content Dio Jason,
file how we can do it.
First,
let me go with the hold to religious and file.
So I'm going to store us.
I'm going to say program a script name as working with the here,
working with the Jason files,
right?
See,
guys when I'm But if you want to work with the Jason Foster fall Unity imported Jason
module,
which is a default model,
then let me take file or required Filed.
What is the file you want to read?
So they you know,
it is a better practice to provide complete part.
So as off Not ugly,
I'm giving my dear son George s and file name itself without giving comfort part because
that Justin file on my script boat are there in the same location.
But anyway,
for better practice,
please,
please provide complete part for your file.
Many.
But if you're writing Python scripts,
that's fine.
No,
guys,
generally,
if we want to read a file,
if you want to read the content off a file,
what are our steps?
Weapon?
That filing read more.
That is a first step.
Open that file in.
Read more.
You know,
even if you don't mention anymore in weapon function by default,
that is the read more.
But if you want to mention yes,
you can mention it.
Read more then finally,
we are closing between these two.
Whatever the action you want to perform,
you can perform.
So this is not the normal text file.
If it is like a normal text.
If I logically we can print,
therefore dot Reid,
if it is normal extra file,
we can use this one like you're getting.
But you're getting like again.
This has a Jason only but what we need we want to work with the Giessen file.
That means you need to convert that data and took fight on.
Understandable Later.
Now,
again,
this is like a string.
They just your guests an object as it is.
But we don't want that Jason object.
Because if you want to modify,
if you want to get suppose,
let's say based on keys,
if it is victory based on this key,
you can get this value.
But no,
this is not a dictionary.
Then you can't do some process on this data like,
you know.
Ah,
give a look operations on your data because that is not a dictionary.
What happened?
Ah,
12 one more Parent is this?
Yeah.
So that is a string you're able to.
Really?
What data?
You're Jason data,
but that is a string itself.
But suppose for seeing purpose,
how you're getting that data as a dictionary.
But that is not a dictionary.
How you can process that we can't process that right.
So now what I'm doing is I'm going to convert this into your python data.
So for that,
what a harder do is simply You want data,
Dad?
Ligon,
print it.
Print used.
Jason dot lobe.
You have to lure from your Jason simply if you pass evil content,
they were file object to your Jason object cadets and model Justin will convert your data
into python.
Understandable data that is simply dictionary format.
Now see the result.
Now,
from this data I can take simply get because that is a dictionary date.
I can do some operation called Don't get No.
See the result.
Yes,
You're getting something like that.
Now,
I can do one more operation because these also dick story.
But previously with your four dot reid,
you are not getting your data as a dictionary.
You're getting something like a string.
So under thing,
you cannot perform your dictionary operations like key value operations.
That's why we are converting the Jason data in terms off dictionary.
For that,
we have a simple syntax called Justin Dark Lord,
your file object.
That's a very simple right.
See if you want to print what Jason data as it is,
right.
You can also do this one,
but don't exclude those 16 70 lines at a time.
You are a good anyone off that because once if you read the content,
you run out Anything to read again in that night?
Okay?
fine.
No,
these simple.
We're just to really What?
Data?
No.
What I want to do is in case in my hand,
If I have some data,
how can I store their data?
I'll do a Jason file.
So before going to store into your destined file inner toe,
think about what type of data you have in your hand.
You know,
while greeting the data from your dear son,
what is a former you're getting,
Dexter reformer.
That's why we're nobody.
If you want to store your data in Bria Dictionary for India,
Jason,
file,
you should have in your hand data as a dictionary.
All right.
See,
let me do one thing.
I'm going to create a my dick,
study someone I'm going to.
Great dictionary like name.
I'm writing us,
Narendra.
Then I'm writing skills Python,
shell family.
Here's Lewis.
Something like that.
Right now,
you know,
how do you have a dick study data?
This dictionary data you can able to write in the or Jason if you know that syntax.
So now let me try for syntax.
So first awful decision that you're going to create a Jason filed Justin file,
Let me take required file as Suppose my in four tortillas.
We sunny dear son.
So this is the Jason file I want to create with the help off our python.
So what?
I want berating Jason file.
I need to write this data.
What is your data?
It should be a dictionary.
Right,
then.
Fine.
Let me weapon.
First your file in,
right more.
But it is Jason or CSP or text file.
First step,
you have to go.
You have to open it,
you know,
require more.
I want to write the content.
Do you're filed,
and I need to open it in,
right More than finally just to close it between days.
Unity.
Right.
There were data into your dear son.
Right?
How we can write our daytime do Jason,
right?
Fine.
See that?
What I'm doing?
Simply dear son dot Dump Just We're pushing our data into Jason.
File Jason dot Dumb.
You want big study data?
We transfer to your file opsec.
That's it.
No.
Let me run it and see the airport.
So you just to push with your data into a Jason?
Fine.
Now we don't have any.
I'll put a year,
but we just created a file again If you want to see the data.
What is there in your Dexter Unity?
Really?
That you need to read that Justin file.
So just know we created a Justin file called My My in Food or Jason,
let me weapon that fight.
My,
my,
my yah,
my inform ideas.
And what is that?
I think my in four idea.
See that you're getting again a dictionary in a single line,
As off now,
ofcourse,
this is in a file.
Now you have to say that this is a day sun data are simply object in your Jason.
But whenever If you see here,
right,
Jason day darkened to stop some spaces.
Some indentations.
Right?
But that type of inundations you're not getting here while creating you're just on file.
It's simple.
You can create it.
Nothing is there.
While writing your content into your Jason file,
you need to mention what is your end then.
So I want to take four spaces.
Yes,
I need on weapon your file.
Justin,
file once again.
Now you will get indentations clearly anyone?
Yes.
And file.
See that now you're getting clearly right.
That's a So there's there's a simple way to really content from your Jason on to write
Contending DOJ is,
um,
the only thing you have to remember is reading is nothing but lording content from your
Jason.
Writing is nothing.
But whatever the content to you,
how that we are writing into your Jason are pushing into your Justin are dumping into your
gears and file Finally,
whenever.
If you're reading the content from your Jason,
you're getting your or put other dictionary with the help off.
You were just and got loads.
Yes and not Lord.
And whenever.
If you're trying to dump your data in courageous and file,
your data should be again a dictionary.
That's it like fine.
See here.
Finally,
we house smaller like them here in terms off,
fight on.
If it is a dictionary in terms off Jason,
it is an object.
So whatever the fight on Liston troubles are there they're simply Jason array,
stringing string only in digital float and whatever it may be.
Complex their numbers in your Jason,
so prove false.
See that true and false with small letters?
None?
No.
So if you remember this while working with your real time,
you know those who are going to work with you.
Our AWS site.
They're going to create so many times policies.
So policies are in terms off.
Just inform it.
Right,
so there it will be very helpful.
Okay,
so just remember this so that you can easily understand how we can convert our data into
Jason or from Jason to fight on.
Right?
The main thing you need to remember this you're just signed.
Took your Jason Day.
Trying to python is always a dictionary.
If you want to write your content into your Jason first thing,
you should write your data in Piketon as a dictionary.
That data way to dump into Jason.
Then that will become an object.
That's a simple like.
Okay,
guys,
thank you for watching this video.