prints here,
we're going to see how to create custom exceptions.
First of all,
what is a custom exception symbol wanted?
Lee.
If you want to rise an exception,
then you can rise so that type of acceptance or called custom exceptions.
And you can create this custom exceptions in two ways.
By using rising asset.
So rise we're going to use our rising it exceptions,
which are existing with your pipe on.
Right?
So let me explain this with an example.
So I'm going to sail my script name as something like custom exceptions,
right?
Si,
simply I'm using you.
Rise,
Exception.
This is a exception.
Not know,
See the output.
If I run these,
it is giving like an exception,
right?
See what is the exception?
Name exception itself on what is the error?
This is exception.
Not only that,
suppose if any,
very was not defined.
You know,
right name era is the exception,
so variable is not defined.
Wanted glamorizing this.
That's a But this is not the way to use in your real time support just agenda.
You are trying to really a variable.
It may be anyway,
let's say simply a Zico's to some 23.
So when I want Rees,
if is he's greater than 30 then.
No,
I don't have any problem.
Bring value is.
But if is not less than I mean not greater than 30 then I want to rise an exception in
giraffe print.
Dissembling Mrs Wondered Lee.
No,
actually,
previously we how a study to our wire exceptions.
But now we're trying to learn how to create exceptions.
If it required right someone your age is less than 30 then I don't want to run my skip.
I wanted that made my skip.
I want to stop.
I need to rise an exception.
Yes,
you can rise simply race.
So I'm taking Supposed value a little exception,
right?
So see,
I'm using existing keywords value era that is already there with your exceptions,
right?
So the free rays give what is used to rise on existing exceptions.
Wanted Lee.
It is less than 30.
That's it.
These the way how we can raise a custom exception using rice keyword.
Now we have one more thing called,
I said.
So Assad is going to use to create your wound exceptions with a name called Asset Error.
Just let me do that say I'm reading simply assert.
See,
first of all,
how your asset is going to work.
A set will rise.
A such an error if the condition becomes false.
I mean,
suppose I'm writing for less than 30.
That is false.
But if I write for greater than three,
that is correct.
Way no.
See that I'm running.
It is not raising any exception because condition is true,
right?
If I write conditioners falls now,
see the result.
What you're getting you're getting enter called our exception called assess in that So a
certain is used to create a such an error on whenever.
If we get any assertion error You how to assume that wanted Lee.
You create a,
um exception Not right.
So you don't so you can take something like suppose Ah,
if engine off you've condition or that they can give it so Suppose I'm trying to write,
try actually a gym that I am reading a supposed easy close to some 30 right?
So now I know not to use if condition directly if I want to rise,
an exception based on is then I known to use if condition I said itself it is going to walk
us s A.
If is less than 30 then only create create an exception.
If it is true,
then see value is let me run it and see the result.
Yeah,
it is.
Try and accept Right unit Toe right.
They were accepted block as well.
Let me write.
Except bring Exception occurred,
right?
So what type of position are Sorry What type of exception?
Your creating with help off asset A section Let me run it and see the result.
See,
both are same.
Let me take 33 Then condition will become too right.
I mean no See what you're getting,
if is is if for days less than 30 Yeah for these greater than right As per your
requirements if he is greater than 30 No problem,
right?
Let me take my age Is something like 20?
No,
If it is not gonna than 30 right then I want to create an assertion at a yes exception is
occurring means assertion batteries running How rising So if you want to handle you were
raised a such an error Yes,
you can handle it like except if ever is assistant era Then bring riser with as say,
because is he's a less than 30 that no,
see,
that isn't so a certain is going to do on an exception.
Call assessment.
That's it.
Right.
So,
guys,
for time being,
just have a look about this asset and rice.
I So,
while writing really time skips based on requirement,
I will use rice.
Sometimes you said sometime on simply,
I will use,
try and accept.
It's based on situation.
So up to that,
you have to remember this in Texas night,
and then we will use their while writing over skips.
Okay,
guys,
thank you for watching this video.