friends here we're going to discuss about fight on functions concept.
Simply introduction part with your functions before going to work with your functions.
Let us agenda.
We harvest some core,
which consist off support someone 50 lines.
So I have a 1 50 lines off course.
And if you have got this entire court somewhere,
I'm rebuilding same logic in different places.
A gym,
that same logic.
I'm repeating in three places.
Imagine that Each logic consist of support.
Some 30 lines.
That means same 30 lines off logic you are repeating in three places.
Not only three stage in dirt.
Some number of times you are repeating same type of Flossie night.
See you for you are repeating the same logic in different places in their gaze.
You need to write your logic in three places whenever If you're repeating what we will.
Louise,
whatever the logic you're repeating,
know that logic.
I will ride in one place in my court itself and I will give some names suppers for that.
My Corp.
And now what I will lose.
I will remove these 30 lines off court in three places.
Very,
very hot.
30 lines off court,
right they're simply write my core.
I have given a name for that lines off.
Corno!
My court.
Now here I am giving my Corp my court.
They No,
this is what I'm doing is see,
actually how 1 50 lines off court in this 1 50 lines off court 30 plus 30 plus 90 90 lines
Place remain in 60 lines.
Finally won 50 lines off court,
but 30 lines off away.
Repeating in three places that Vincent chin off the 90 lines.
What we are doing is that the lanes off course I'm ready in somewhere.
Where were the static lines Off court is required There.
I will write the name Richard.
I'll give Ben for these 30 lines off court.
So what is the name given my core?
So here I like my Cordish after t line.
Simply.
I'm writing only one line.
So you're serving 29 lines.
You're reducing 29 lines in this place.
Same A in this 30 lines.
I'm living the morning this star Tila and simply I'm writing my core.
That it I'm giving the name.
Then again here,
also producing 29 lines.
So then here also you're having 30 lines No,
I'm removed.
Removing these 30 lines off court and simply I'm writing whatever the name have given for
the study lines.
My court.
Then he also you're using 29 line numbers.
So instead off 90 lines.
Now you're using only three lines.
Bliss in the same core itself.
You are giving a name for your 30 lines.
30 lines.
Place name,
31 lengths.
So finally or writing 34 lines injured off 90 lines.
So you almost reduced 60 or 50 six lengths,
like so,
you are able to reduce your length off the court.
Let me give a simple example.
You can easily understand that.
Suppose I have a small requirement that the purpose off requirement I'm in the requirement
days,
but nobody five on my pipe landscape.
It has to clear my command line.
Then it has to display the list off files and directories,
right?
See that I am writing something like I need to run commenced like a seal less suppose
windows under in CLS common,
and then be a are common right.
So to run your commands,
you have two options in your python ways,
their system,
and then so process My Of course,
you're also having ways that people open process will open.
But anyway,
what is the system?
And so process are the best.
Our process to run your commands.
And whenever,
If you want to capture the output,
then go with the sub process.
Just simply if you want or under common,
just to go with the way his dart system.
That's why here,
minding his intention,
it just I wanted under command.
So I'm importing boys.
So simply,
where's your system?
See?
Unless I'm running,
then ways door system.
What?
I'm running.
Ah,
the air coming.
That's it.
Right Now let me go Toe Common line on then.
So how gonna skip Name is on your comments.
Dark people.
I know.
Let me run it.
Yes,
it's clearing your screen on it is displaying something.
But I want to display or something like,
uh,
Brink.
Please wait.
Kathleen E known off this just for clarity.
I'm giving number of lines.
Please wait.
Cleaning the screen.
That's it,
then.
After this print,
please wait.
Finding the list off territories on face.
That's it.
No.
Let me Ronnie.
Yes,
you're getting but after displaying,
please Way to finding the list off directories and files.
I want to wait for two seconds before excluding the next line.
I'm in business before excluding this line the same way After printing this line,
I want to wait for two seconds before excluding this way Is that system so that I can see
this information Otherwise this information is also going to clean on your common lane.
So to wait for some time you have a time model anyway will discuss Ah about time or will
indeed a So what I'm doing is after displaying this message is I don't want to go next.
Good.
Next line.
I want to wait for two seconds.
I want to stop your process with your python.
Then simply time.
Don't sleep off two seconds.
I want to wait the same way.
After displaying this message,
I want to wait again.
Suppose sorry time dot Sleep supposed to seconds right now.
Let me down.
You can see the output.
So it is waiting two seconds.
Then after that,
it is waiting again to second.
Then you're getting your data.
That's fine.
Suppose if I copied the score on If I try to run this on my UNIX Lexus down,
right?
Let me write.
Simply run.
You are common.
Start the way script.
So Sanskrit.
I'm copying and pasting here.
Would it look?
See?
That isn't so.
I won't run using fight on three.
See?
Seal is common is not working because see,
Ellis is not the command to clearly were come online off your innings like system C El er
is the common late on anywhere.
Dia is working,
but I want to get in detail in this way.
I want to get any hotter use ls Siphon LRT So on windows you have CLS and er for UNIX.
I need C l e a r l s iPhone LRT commands.
So what I am doing is before running your commands.
I'm crying,
going for the platform.
You know,
there is a part for model on.
If you remember.
We discussed already aboard days,
right windows,
So he flat for Marxist.
The music was to windows.
Then I want to run this logic.
See the logic.
That's it else.
If it is not Windows,
what I'm doing is same logic,
but difference in comments.
See that same logic.
The only thing here.
See,
Ellie,
you are on a year.
L s iPhone LRT.
No.
First let me save it.
So,
guys,
how we design our script.
It's like a platform independent script.
It will exclude on your windows as well as UNIX.
Like systems on what is are finally your purpose.
Clear your screen,
then listen,
the There it is and finds in the current location.
Yes.
No,
I'm running our script clearing your screen.
Wait two seconds.
Finding the stuff,
Gladys and files.
Then you're getting No.
What I will do is I'm going to copy this escape to your next like system as well.
So before that,
let me clean.
You are all the data?
No,
I'm going to open same script.
I'm going to copy and paste the court,
which you have on your windows.
No,
seem la Z.
Same script.
I'm running now.
One your window.
Sorry.
UNIX like system.
Now it's working.
See that?
That's why that's fine.
But the problem is,
if you observe your entire logic if you observe your and a la Z see if it clearly absorbed
this thing right on this thing.
Same logic you are repeating here and here.
The only thing comments are different.
This comer and discovering is different windows this common UNIX This comment Windows,
the air command lining sell a siphon alerted.
But as many as he could say no,
That means simply you are repeating same logic in two places as off Now,
only two places.
Maybe in real time you're going to repeat same kind off logic,
maybe in 100 times or 10 times or five times based on your requirement.
As of now,
I am repeating my logic in two places.
Forget about commands.
Logic is saying no.
So what I will do is in my quarter itself,
right?
This logic I will lead somewhere with some name with some name.
I'm giving name for that.
Supposed my court.
You can probably any law name for that.
Okay,
we'll learn in detail Award Toho toe.
Define your name for your logic.
Everything will learn while going forward for timing just after the logic.
That's it.
No engine off for No.
Forget about all this year less.
I'm taking that as a command one on.
I'm taking this as common toe.
Okay,
Don't worry why we're taking command one and comment will discuss in details while going
forward.
But here mind ends is if you're repeating the LA Zeke,
why should we repeat that logic?
I don't want to repeat,
right.
See,
Actually,
whatever the logic,
you are repeating that I removed.
Right?
But this is the logic you're repeating,
right?
That's why What is the name you are even for this logic?
This is the name you have given that name.
I will read here and here.
That's it.
So that your logic is over.
But how it is going to work,
we'll discuss it.
My core.
Then here also,
I'm writing my court.
No,
internally Python will replace in place off my core this entire lousy again.
Same cool.
Only you are not descending anything.
The only thing you're reducing the number of lines engine off are rewriting the same logic
in different places.
What we're doing,
we're writing in one place.
We're giving some name for that.
Remember,
if it is required in your code in giraffe writing,
that entire logic simply were writing the name which you have given for your logic.
Right?
So for these are given a name called My Core that I'm reading here in here now,
internally hydrogen,
that my car is nothing but this entire lines you can assume in place off my court.
A need also in place off my quarry cannot human entirely these lines.
So finally,
we're not disturbing with your court.
Right?
But whenever if I'm working with knows I need to run something like CLS.
Don't worry how I'm giving this.
Ah,
syntax.
Okay.
Just abdullah concept that we'll discuss in detail.
That's it.
Let me save it.
So that's what I'm doing.
I'm sure there the logic which you are repeating that logic I have it in somewhere are now
given some name for that.
So in your court previously wherever you are using this logic in that place simply I'm
giving this name.
That's it.
No,
let me money.
If it is working perfectly,
then the way which you use year.
That's correct.
Night.
Yes,
it's working.
No,
See that?
That means whatever the processes we followed,
that is correct.
So if you followed this process,
what is that?
One day you're going to reduce the number off lines or in the worst way,
you can ableto reuse this logic Any number off times in your core That is that one day
wherever you need their you know,
neither.
I didn't know simply You're going to you.
You use this name reusable D right Now that we copy this court to urine expect systems as
well.
They're also I want running.
Let me coop in.
Mr Right.
I'm going to run it.
So here also it is going to work perfectly.
See that?
Not a right.
So they in case if you use this concept,
then this is called a function on.
You can reuse dysfunction any number of times in your court where where it is required,
right?
So how do you define how to use them?
All those things we will see.
Okay.
And one more thing.
This is a function simply This is a function,
you know,
function means some operation is there with function.
That is how was if we take off X equals to some three express to therefore fixes a function
on its operation is very explicit.
No,
here my court is a function that is nothing but I for fix.
If you come back with your mathematics Mike,
what is a function that is ffx right?
My quarry simply off here.
Common one command Don't assume that x No.
Based on the X,
you're getting your f of X value by executing this three express to expression the same way
based Don't command one and common to your getting final result for your my core.
By excluding this logic,
right,
see if you're good with your mathematics is very easy.
Toe compare.
I just assumed that three explains to is nothing but this part.
My court is nothing but 1/2 and come and one comment.
Got nothing but eggs.
So three express to depends on X value.
So,
based on X value,
finally are getting,
if off x value the same day.
This logic depends on common or uncommon toe.
Based on this comment on command to finally finally are getting the result off my core.
That's why this is simply a function same as your mathematic concepts that is,
on paper,
that is on memory.
That's it.
You're excluding with your bite on software not to.
So this is a function like these.
Some variables as off No,
but not variables.
We have some other name.
We'll see that en fr fix.
Every is the function X is available somewhere.
This is a function in terms off common.
One uncommon toe.
That's it.
Right?
So finally,
I want to give the a simple definition for your function.
Function is a block off court for some specific operation.
That operation,
maybe anything based on your requirement in your situation,
right Once,
If you define your function,
you can reuse that any number of times you can use in your core where what is required
right are a function excuse only when it is called See that.
Let me remove this.
Don't worry.
How do call?
We'll discuss that.
So hats off.
No,
just I defined a function.
Know where I am using this,
right?
I'm are using here.
So previously you are using here and here 13 plane,
15 line supposed If I come and discord know where you are using that If you are not using,
then if you run your court,
it won't eggs cure even Let me run down your common lane.
That is,
You will get clarity like is not excluding your even believe you have a function.
It won't execute by itself.
If you want to exclude your function,
you should use the word somewhere in your core.
That's a that is a concept off your function.
Okay,
So,
guys,
this is simply interaction part with your functions.
Okay?
In later videos,
we'll go with step by step and we will learn completely about your functions.
Right on.
Then we will see how to use in real time for different scenarios.
Okay.
Okay,
guys,
thank you for watching this video.