friends here.
We're going to discuss about how to define a function on how to use our call or execute
defined function.
Right?
Let me explain this with examples.
So let me create a simple skip to define and to use your function so defined function dot b
Y.
See that if you want to define a function,
you have to use giver called the F With that keyword editor defined your function on any
days before going to work with the functions.
Why we need a function whenever If you have a reputed to logic in your code in giraffe,
repeating your la Z in different places,
we are going to write that logic in one place and we're giving some name.
So giving name is nothing but defining the function right?
So I am defending simply display function.
That's it.
Imagine that I'm repeating two lines off court in different places.
Now,
instead of writing two lines off court in different places,
what I'm doing is those two lanes I'm writing here.
So this is first line,
just a solution.
This is secondly,
So these two lines I am reporting suppose in 10 places instead of repeating in 10 places.
I'm reading two lines here,
and I'm giving the name for that.
So this is a very hopeful,
defined a function.
You are to define your function with the f key word,
the off your function name,
then parentheses.
Offer that colon This actually you are defining for these two lines.
You are giving one name call display.
That means these two lines are there on the display.
So whenever if you want to write some lines under your function,
you should provide some indentation or some space for all the world lanes which are there
under your function.
If we define any function without any line,
there is no use.
Right?
See that I'm different in this way you're fighting will give another.
What is that?
Another soon backs out of unexpected end off file while passing.
You don't know anything.
That's why it is giving another right.
You should How at least one line inside off your function?
No,
I hope to length no bowler.
Yes,
it's fine.
So I defined a function under that.
I'm running my python Skip,
you're not getting an output.
So when nobody for defending function,
it won't eggs goodbye itself If you want to run your pipes on function,
you should call somewhere.
So let's say I'm calling that function from six line display.
No,
let me run it.
Now you're going to get your two lines off.
Put so days whenever your pie Tony's running your court,
how it is going to run from top down.
So whenever it is coming from top down,
If python identify secured,
called the year,
then at that time your python won't execute this lousy simply really Remember the name off
your function name,
then it will come out from your function.
Then do you have any line here?
Mobile order Not only lying here now.
We have a line here,
but this line is display Ali fight on most that displays somewhere function.
That's why whenever displays there because already fight on knows that were displaced there
.
Now your fight on flew off control execution part will come to here and now let's go.
These two lines offer a completion of these two lines again will come to the same line,
become automatically so six line itself,
then will try to go to seventh line.
If you have any line here as of now.
I don't have any 17 Right?
So know what I'm doing is I'm going to call it once again.
See that?
So what you're doing,
you're calling forced your function.
Then you're coming back to here.
Only then you're going to 17.
17 again.
You're calling same function.
Then he will come back to yet Then it'll go.
Great land as often.
I don't have any eight line.
You see how it will?
It may be any line eight.
Let's say I'm going to print now.
We called display function to dance.
No.
Once again,
I'm going to call it.
Yes,
you can call it no problem.
Right.
So if I run my core foster thing very first line is a D off.
That's why fight on won't exclude this display function.
Simply really member than name Very or displays that.
Then you will come out from your function then is there anything here?
No,
he had displaced there.
Now you're right on.
We go to here and will execute that and we come back the same line.
That anyway,
don't have anything going is good in the same line.
Dental by.
Don't go to seventh line now again display this place a function now you're part time will
come to here and really exclude these two lines.
Then it will come back the same line.
Seventh lane as off.
No.
Once again,
you don't have anything to do on seventh line.
Then it will go to eight land and eighties A prince treatment.
It will print that line.
Then you will go to 19 nineties like any function Now you'll come to hear,
Reflects.
Could these two lines and we come back to here offer that I don't have any lines?
Then your pie transcript will stop.
No,
let me don't even see the output.
Not so there is.
There is a simple way to define your function on is the way how to call or exclude your
function.
Make sure that you're Brighton function won't takes good by itself.
If you want to exclude or use your function usual somewhere,
call that function in this way.
So I know What if your chortling your function your function name with parents sissy.
Hard to mention while defending your function before the EU function Name parentheses.
Colon under a function name with some indentation with some space.
You ought to mention some number off lines.
That's it.
Like no,
what?
I am doing injuries.
Forget about this lousy.
See,
I'm going to define somewhere you're function simply display.
Bring welcome to functions.
Concept brained,
simple way toe define.
They were function right there,
honey.
Nor put no other Norwood.
So you just different the function.
So if you want to exclude that function,
you should call somewhere.
Yes,
I'm calling.
No,
it is excluding but injured off,
God willing,
your function from 90 line.
I'm going to call it from very first line.
Then see the result what you're getting.
You're getting another call.
Name display is not defined.
Why you are getting this?
Adam means see your paternal Exclude your core line by line.
It will exit will write a good first line.
As I've known this play as of no,
you're right.
I don't know what is a display.
In case if we didn't contest the keyword first,
then your fight and understand that this place their function because off this helping
keyword.
But you define somewhere but before definition defining your function you're calling This
is not the correct way to define your function.
So always you should define your function First on after defining your function,
you have to call liver function.
So before calling your function somewhere,
you should define your function in your sequence.
Fine.
And it is a better practice to right at the end.
Return man as off No as off no return man.
See,
let me run it.
Is there any problem?
No problem.
It is working fine.
Even though you be included or not,
it's working fine.
So actually it is a good practice toe right at the end Off your function.
Return?
None.
So what is the use off that we'll discuss?
Where you going?
Forward,
Right.
Fine.
And it's one more thing While defending your function Name.
You have to follow some rules rules to define function Name So already we know that gays,
if you remember,
what are the rooster defined variables Variable name should How only hey does it or cattle
You does it then number 0 to 9 Under them Underscore only these three group off characters
you should have in a variable name now even function also same thing.
There is no difference The same rules which we hope to define a variable.
All rules are applicable to define your function.
That's it.
So capital letters with function name on smaller dysfunction.
Names are different.
Give since do we know that?
So I just tried to recollect the rules to defend the rebels.
Same variable name rules are applicable for your function as well,
right?
You should not start with any number.
You are variable.
Same here also functions or not.
Start with number but we can start with under school.
No problem.
Underscore letters,
characters and don't include any space.
That's what.
So these are the rules.
Exactly.
The variable rules are applicable even well defined in your function Name as well.
That's it.
And finally So your function must to be defined before calling it.
See,
I am defending our very first year function.
I'm calling a six lane.
Then there is no problem.
But if I call our function and very first line and if I defined this off function somewhere
in 10th or 11th somewhere well off that,
then it'll get a problem.
It will give.
It will give another.
That is not the correct way force to define your function.
Then somewhere you can call that right So,
guys,
once again this is a calling function and you're calling this This is a call function.
Call the function you're calling from here.
So of course,
both are same,
but because off this you're able to exclude this lines.
So this is calling.
This is called off function.
You don't remember this names as well And you can call your function any number of times in
your court like fine.
So finally,
I won't read you this definition Once again,
their function is a block off court for some specific operation and functions are reusable
.
You can reuse your function called any number of times.
In your logic,
there is no restriction for that.
You can use that any number of times.
And one more thing,
it won't execute itself.
It will execute on Lee when it is called in this week.
You're calling from here.
This function will called.
So you don't know how this thing it won't exclude.
Right?
So let me save it underneath,
run down output.
But if I do,
if I call that in this way,
then only it is going to explode.
These two lines not sick.
So guys know.
Tell me why we need functions.
Why functions are required by functions are using in our core.
First thing is called reusable de purpose.
So we started our interaction collection of functions with this concept only whenever if
you're repeating your logic in different places.
So instead of repeating your lousy we are writing your logic in one place on we're calling
that in different places.
Then 2nd 1 is improved.
Modularity means see,
even though if you don't have any requirement with your functions in your court,
it's better to write people court in terms off functions.
Why?
Why means?
Just imagine that you're writing some thousands off lines 1000 lines of code,
your writing.
So if you don't know,
for instance,
concept what we will do,
Langdale and you will go on right.
Imagine that these 1st 24 letter for some specific purpose on next 200 lines are for some
special record Was no injured off writing straightforward.
If I use some name for this,
right,
If I do some name for your different lines what is the purpose off that lousy in future?
Easily I can understand What is the logic?
Your return?
Oh,
the big gold I can speak into some parts and each part.
I can write other separate function.
And finally I will call all the functions in one place so that the reliable devil increase
by seeing your core for your corpse.
Right?
So from no.
One Burt's even though you three days having only one lane off court,
try to write in dumps off functions so that you'll be good with functions off for some time
.
So from next class on words will try to write each and every core in terms off functions
only so that it will be good with functions.
Functions are very easy,
you know.
Need to warm worry much about your functions.
Mike then types off functions,
so there's basically there are two types of functions.
One is building functions.
Building functions means by default.
They are with your pipe on then user different functions means we are defining those
functions.
Just know we defined right we defend one function call display.
So if there is a function,
then only you can use it,
right?
Let me remove this function right.
What I'm doing is I'm running this.
You're going to get another record.
Displays not define because nowhere we define our function,
right?
No,
it is giving perfect output Same way,
I suppose.
A gender.
I'm reading some print lent off height.
You're getting to actually lend these a function.
We heard that in our core.
No,
but still it is working.
See if I remove this part This place not working right?
If I remove this part display is not working but lend nowhere.
We defined lend function but still we can able to use that.
So that means it is the default function with your pipe Thanh built in functions with your
bite on So for built in functions you don't need to worry that it look and use it not only
lend if you remember,
we have all suppose if I write exit course with some 40 then print ideal fix It is also one
building functions If they're pipe Town is going to give the other soft your variable.
Not only that,
let me take X equals two fight domestics,
right?
Then drink length off your ex not double.
And they're going to get lenders already defined.
Uh,
not only this We have so many functions we already seen.
Let let's say green minimum or fix What is the result?
Fight minimum ease of function here.
Bring maximum or fix maximum value among your values in next six.
So this all or some off the the fold functions with your pipe bomb.
Not only that,
Indian off X,
right?
I mean,
if you want to do some type conversion.
Waterboarding in B J list conversion bite was If I have it fight.
That is a string actually know what I'm doing is I'm trying to convert the art as a in
desert.
So indeed,
graphics.
Indeed.
It is a function here,
but there is a building function or default function with your pie tone.
Hi.
So you have two types of functions while on his user defined functions on one Moyes
building functions.
So really,
we used,
um,
built in functions.
But sometimes you are very important with your building functions,
with some with some functions,
some built in functions.
But most of the cases you're going to define your user defined functions,
right?
So now your concentration is how to define on the use and work with your user.
Different functions,
right?
So as off No,
we have seen simple way to define your function.
Right In next week we will see you detail with your functions.
How do you define an outdoor called with some arguments?
See,
display in parentis.
I'm not writing anything but in land timer hiding something.
So why should we write this?
So to understand this function,
you need to work with the U.
S.
User.
Different functions,
bypassing some value here so that you can understand effectively.
Why?
Length is required.
Some input,
Right?
Okay.
So far alluded to remember this.
How do you define a function?
No,
to call a function.
Right.
Okay.
Thank you for watching this.
Really?
You?