friends here we're going to discuss about Scoop off the variables for your functions.
So before starting with the scope off the variables,
let me show you how to call a function from another function.
So our taken a script name as scope off the variables.
Right?
Fine.
Now what I'm doing is I'm going to defend a function.
Let's say simply,
I'm calling my function one.
You can take any function names based on the word rules.
Let's say I want to display.
Welcome to functions,
right.
So,
Ardian,
just try to write.
Returned?
None.
That's it.
No,
I'm going to defend one more function.
My function to thank you then.
Yet right return.
Now that's it.
No,
you have to functions in your core.
So to execute,
get the output from your functions.
What we have to do is going to call them right support.
I'm going to call my function one.
So there's a way how we can call your functions,
right?
See that you're getting your or pull from first of function.
Now,
if you want to exclude you around court,
which is there in second function as well,
What we have to do is we can call your second function.
That's it.
But sometimes we're going forward.
While writing real time scripts,
you may need to call your function from inside off another function.
Yes,
you can call it Let's say I want to call my function to From My function one.
So I'm calling from my function.
That's a everything you don't put.
Thank you,
right,
So from function one I'm calling function to Yes,
you can call any function from any place like fine know what I'm doing is,
and one more thing is if he observed,
Now these function is in your main court,
right?
If you observe,
it is in outside off your function.
But where you going?
Forward?
New Real time Night mags Own cases We won't right any logic outside of a function h and
everything even support.
Sometimes if you have a single line will buy to write that line in terms off a function
that's a good practice,
right?
That's fine.
Now see that what I'm doing is I'm writing some X equal student,
and I want to print that X value from your function.
One.
Let's say x value from function one just I'm trying to print X value at the same time.
Let me print to the X value X value from function to yes.
No.
Let me run.
You can see that.
Put.
You're getting your report,
right?
No,
I'm commending this.
I in function one I'm defining X equals to tell not only 10 we can take anywhere.
Look,
let's say 16.
No,
see,
that is a after the output from your function one,
you're getting value as 60.
But while excluding from function to you're getting a little called name X is not defined.
So this is called scope off the variables means if any variable is defined inside off a
function by default,
that variable is specific toe that functionally you can't access that variable outside off
that function.
So I define Mexico 60 year and I'm tryingto display X value from your second function.
It won't work.
It is specific to dysfunction or this is a local variable for this function.
But if you're door previously,
we did this one bite.
Let's say first,
let me come in this whenever.
If any variable is defined outside off a function that variable,
you can able to access from function one and function to that means if any variable is
define outside off the functions,
then that is global variable.
So,
by default,
if you define any wearable outside off their functions,
see nowhere we have here.
We don't have any function here,
right?
We're calling,
but exceeds coastal town in the main court is not under any function.
Then this excess,
by default global variable global variable means you can access that variable anywhere
inside off your function inside off your script,
right?
No,
what we are doing,
if any available is define inside off a function,
then that variable is specific to your function only.
Like now we have two nights off variables local and global variables,
right?
First thing scope means there's the meaning for your scope off the variable.
So based on this is scope,
we have local and global variables.
Now I can say this is a global variable,
and now all if I enable this,
let's say this is local.
No,
I'm running.
See the result?
What you're getting So in Maine,
coloured taken X equals 10 on my function.
One I'm defining X equals 60.
No,
whenever If you take same variables in the main cold and in the function they're not seem.
Now This X is different and the sex is different.
That's why while excluding from my function one what is the result?
We are getting 60 value because you define 60 here,
but from function to you don't have any X variable here.
Then what your python will do means is there any global variable lunatics?
Then we'll try to bring that X.
But before that,
in case if you how local variable No,
see,
that is,
er you're getting 40.
So your function,
will you your fight on will you priority for your local variables inside off your function
while trying to display your X variable value If X is not defined inside off your function
,
I mean,
if no local variable X,
then what your pattern will do means it will try to find Is there any X as a global
variable?
If it is there,
you will try to print that variable value If it is not their dental toe and ever see that?
No,
I'm commenting,
executes returning your main course.
No,
they're getting enough.
That's it.
So they simply scope off the variables like and last one let me explain that.
No,
we're going forward,
right?
We're going to write each and everything in terms off functions only.
No,
What I will do is you can take any function not only mean,
but if you take main than somewhat meaningful,
that's it.
Main means will Court will start from this place.
That's it.
Other than that,
nothing is there defining X equals,
pretend and calling my function one.
I'm also taking us it under one function.
Right now you fight.
Run these.
There is no or put because you define three functions on No.
Where you're calling the execution point from where you want to start your core Whether we
want to start from function to our function one are from main function from which place you
want to exclude your core as off No,
right.
I'm feeling that this is my main course.
I had to start the exclusion from this point.
That's why I need to call this function somewhere.
So no,
I am calling main.
That's a no Whenever If you're tryingto call in this way,
you're getting another core name.
X is not defined from your may in which function my function to like?
No,
What I want to believe as as off my field there No exit question is not a global variable,
right?
This is under.
But when did this?
Now this is 100 main function.
Maine is also one function like my function.
So instead of many can also take my court starts from here you can take anything but just
were falling.
Now we hard right here injured off me.
You want to write this one?
That's it.
No see,
there is a same thing.
So instead of these just generally all are for falling like this main.
That's it.
Minds off this mean right?
Maine is also like one function.
Now if you observe inside off your main exit question is there not?
This is a function right now.
Exit question is local,
local for this main function You corn taxes.
No exit question from outside off you were function main function or any off your functions
.
I define Mexico 60.
That's way from my my my function.
One I can able to access X equals 60 but in my function.
So I don't have X.
Well,
you Then how can I get it?
That's why you're getting another.
Now,
what are the variable?
Is there in main function?
Exit coaster 10.
That variable value.
I want toe access from my function to then hope in case of it is they're here.
Then there is a main function.
I mean,
in Maine logic.
You know,
you're getting your actually from function to as 10.
But now exit Kristen.
Is that in main function?
But I want to accept this exit question from my function to right then in main function.
I mean,
whatever the function you have in that function yard,
right,
Global X,
that means now exceeds globally can access my ex variable anywhere inside off your bite on
strip.
No,
see,
that isn't now you're getting from function group in they fine,
but days.
Making your variable as global is not always good.
Okay,
Sometimes you can take it as a were able as global but injured off global.
We have one more way to pass.
You were responding,
were able to your required function,
right?
See that?
Now?
I'm going toe comment from here.
Don't get confused.
Okay,
Well,
let's goes this again in next radio as off.
Not just I'm giving the way.
How you can pass.
So you know I'm going to come in this on as off.
No.
If I run my core what you're getting from my function one you're getting your value is 60.
No,
I'm not calling anywhere my function to know.
I want to call my function to suppose from main function itself.
No,
I'm calling,
but in main function my function to I don't have any wearable call X.
That's why are getting another.
I don't want to use global in case if I use global yes,
it will work without any other.
But I don't want to use the variable as a global but I want to send the value off X value
10 to my function toe.
So other way to pass it were value to your required function is just inside off your
parentheses.
Just fight x No here also you have to write six know what will happen 10 value While
calling this my function to you are also passing not X You're not passing X the value the
value off x 10 10 your posse So the meaning for disease You are not passing X value affects
Then you're passing toe This variable.
Now this X and the sex they're completely different in case if you are.
If you're having a confusion right first,
let Mitt on it and see the result.
Now what I'm doing Injured off Ex Im taking white now I want to print that way.
That's it.
Right.
So out of then global,
how can you if I take global than this variable is a You can access that variable from any
function from any lane anywhere in your pipe from ST.
But I don't want to access in all places only from this function only I want to access this
variable X that value.
Not even that ex.
Only the value of fix then I concerned in this way that's a on one.
More important point is now this variable and this variable are completely different.
The value off X will be assigned a way that value we're printing.
That's it.
Okay,
so now here.
Whenever if you pass,
you were variable to your function than that is called argument.
All right,
here that is called,
but I'll meet that.
Okay,
we'll discuss in detail in the next video aboard this argument and parameter.
Okay.
Okay,
guys,
Thank you for watching this video.