friends here.
We're going to discuss about the simple functions with arguments.
Let me explain this with an example.
Let me open my any there.
I'm taking a script name called Functions with simple arguments.
Don't be white,
Right?
See,
I have a small requirement.
This agenda that requirement days read a number on Inclement eight by 10.
So first I'm writing with Toto Functions Concept Let me take number cause too.
Input and very were number logic.
Then I want to find result as number blessed in.
Then I want to print that reserve.
Print your reserve These something like that.
You can take anything.
That's it right Now let me go to my command line and let me run it before running.
This is he was kept.
I'm running this script.
See the result I'm passing.
Suppose some 20.
Then you have to get your or put us 30.
Yes,
you are getting No.
There's a simple pie transcript.
But what I want to do is I want to convert this entire court in terms off functions.
So first step.
What I'm doing is our intent to you're given number and then printing.
I'm writing under one function right.
So you know we know.
What?
If you wanted to find a function?
Yes.
Do you find get reside?
That is up.
Was my function on under this function I'm writing these two lines and finally simply right
.
Britain None.
That's it.
No,
I'm reading that.
I mean,
I want to get my number.
Yes,
I'm getting right now.
I'm running.
I'm providing.
But you're not getting in outward.
That isn't Is your logic is there under get result function?
But you are not calling that.
If you call,
then only that logical excuse.
Now,
after reading a number now I want to call that lousy right now.
See the core.
So you are reading your number.
After that,
you're calling you a la Z.
Now it will execute.
No,
I'm running.
I'm giving some number four.
You're getting result as 14 right?
No,
actually,
to really one number on to exclude your logic.
You have two lines.
Go These two lines also I want right under one more function.
Yes,
you can write it.
Let me do one thing,
Mike.
What I'm taking That's it.
Right on.
I'm running.
You're not getting any output.
The reason is now your entire Lawzi reading a number under,
then finding your result.
Both are there under two different functions.
Right?
So in your my court you're calling you are you're reading your remember and then you're
calling this function No.
Two X cured this Lawzi,
You need to call this function to exclude this large beginning to call this function right
?
So that's why what I'm doing is somewhere I'm calling my core.
That's a no injured off my court.
If we take it as a main,
that's good.
You can take any function name,
but there is the simple way.
Take your function name as mean so that you can easily understand that Maine is nothing.
But from there you're going to exclude your la Z.
So it's not the mandatory to take your function name as main.
But if we take,
then it's good.
That's it like no,
previously we done our court and we're getting or put Now.
If I do that,
you will get another.
That this number is not define why you're getting this era where you're getting this error
in line number two.
What is that?
While finding result,
this number table is unable to find by your python.
What is the reason for that?
See,
numb Now it is there under main function.
It is one function right under function.
You define a number able,
then this variably space victor dysfunction.
How can you access in this way function now this numb.
This known variable right is specific to this main function.
How can you access inside off?
Get dessert.
So that's what you do.
You need to make your variable as global.
Now it will work.
But making your variables as global is not that much good.
Whenever If you have a requirement,
then only will do that.
A requirement means suppose.
Assume that number able.
Suppose in my function in my courthouse,
um,
10 functions in all functions I need to use suppose let's say number then.
Aiken,
simply make it as a global so that I can access that number table in all the functions as
off.
No.
Right.
I need this non variable only inside off my one function get result function.
That's why don't make your variables as global whenever if there is no requirement,
if you have a some specific requirement,
then only will make it as a global.
We will see that situation,
right?
So forget about no global then how you can send you are number ableto this get result
function simple Why are you calling?
You just pass a year number now you're passing your number value,
right?
No see that I am passing that right But if I run that you're going to get an error that is
get result takes Jiro positional arguments but one was given Get result is a function right
So here get result function here nothing is there but you are sending one value So whenever
if you're passing you are variable value In this way he had also you should how some
variable to store Whatever the value coming from here that means here redefining variable
right?
Let me different here also some variable Then it will match Let me take your also on them
But he can take any variable No need to take number Also you can take any variable like
value like no whatever the variable you define that variable is available inside off this
function.
Right,
so as off No,
I'm running in this way.
Yes,
you are getting but see while calling your passing numb means you're not passing numb
variable.
You're passing the value off numb guys from this line,
only the valley will be possibly here and here we're cup capturing that value in terms off
numb variable.
Right now,
what I'm doing is I'm not moving stuff.
Mom,
I'm taking a value now.
This value variably is available inside of this function now instead off.
No.
Now you have to take value.
That's it.
Now,
see,
that is a It's working like So if you pass your variables well calling,
then that variables are called arguments on the very blue cheese defined in your defined
function defined function.
I mean to be off some very year it is there,
and this variable is called barometer.
But I mean,
those are traditional arguments.
Why?
We're calling them as a positional arguments.
See,
as off me how only one variable.
That's why you can't understand what is the position.
Let me take simply one more court.
But it is just for addition.
Let me like that lamb rating.
You are ah,
logic without functions.
Let's say number.
Enter your first number,
then number B and turkey were second number then I am finding result,
you please be.
Then I'm printing the result.
The addition off year.
All right,
be he's You were reserved,
right?
First,
let me tell,
you can see the output.
I'm passing four and fight and you're getting results as mine.
Like that's fine.
No,
same way I want to find subtraction as well.
Let's say this is additional result then subtraction result.
I am finding a minus bi.
Then I want to read the subtraction off.
You are yea be.
He's subtraction.
Lizard.
That's it,
right?
34 You're getting what happened?
Okay,
he had auditioned Result?
Yeah,
it's fine.
You're getting right.
No,
of course,
this is a classic without functions,
but no,
I want to convert these and do functions concert.
So reading A and B right?
I will do from main function.
So I'm taking this as a main function inside off main function.
I'm reading my E and B values.
Right.
Then I'm going to take these two lines.
All right?
I want to give the name for that as a tradition.
Get tradition.
That's it.
So I'm finding for addition here.
Same way remaining two lines I want Oh,
right.
The one more function that is get subtraction.
Let me take these two lines.
Let me write.
Finally return.
None on in main function.
Also,
we hold it in your fine.
No,
let me Donny no put.
Because now,
if you observe me out three functions know where we're calling any function,
how it will excuse.
Right?
Anyway,
our invention is our starting logic should be from here.
That's why I need to call this main after come after defending all your functions somewhere
here I'm calling that.
That's a right.
No,
see,
I'm running.
Let me do one thing.
I will remove empty lines.
So this is your la Z.
Now I am running that under number 34 You're not getting in output.
So we are reading year and B values where we're calling Get our get result.
Know where we're calling.
That's why you're not getting in output now.
I want to get tradition,
but also subtraction.
Then I need to call those functions right,
but here will get an error but observed that while finding addition year and B,
you're getting another look or name your is not defined.
Why?
See you are year and be variables.
Are there under main function.
That means their local variable that specific to this main function.
How you can use that in get art forms or get subtraction function.
So if you want to use those variable values you need toe past them so that function
whenever if you're calling right No,
get Ardika Amobi,
get some traction.
You come will be on variables.
What about available value you're sending You need to capture here also.
That's why in your defined funds and also you die hard to write a comma be then you
commodity That's it,
right?
No,
let me money.
I'm giving number four and seven.
See the result Tradition 11 subtraction Ministry Know what I'm doing?
Is wife getting subtraction?
I'm passing become a year so previously you got result as minus 344 and seven.
Now I'm running.
I'm giving same values and see the result what you're getting Plus three you're getting
because we change in the position.
See that if you change your position based on that question only these values will be
assigned to your be evil.
You know you're assigning to you usually are assigning Toby,
right?
So based on this position,
you're getting values here.
That's what these are called.
Traditional arguments are simply parameters.
Right now you are fine with the traditional arguments.
Like on one more thing.
We already discussed that whenever if you're calling function,
you're passing year and be variables on,
we are assigning them to year and be you need to understand Here.
Yeah.
Valley will be assigned to eat this year and be valley will be assigned to this be same day
this year.
Valley will be assigned to you on this.
Be really will be assigned Toby on these where the bulls are were using inside off this on
this year.
And this be not from here.
They are from this parentheses.
Be clear this year.
Bees are from this from this place.
Whatever you define here,
Dr Variables,
you can use inside off your function site and while calling your passing a comma be right.
No,
no.
Today gave him a B.
You can take some Pekka McCue Also let me dig become a que so you're taking P And you know
there are no more year and be now wearables,
rpm que no,
you have to write your logic in terms off.
Be on cue.
No,
where we held here and B,
we have only p and Q the same way you also you can take Wanted to take a b r P Q.
We can take some,
um,
comma and no problem.
The only thing What will happen whenever If you're calling your for insurance,
we are turning the values.
This festival will be assigned to first variable Second Valley will be assigned to second
variable here also.
Yea,
verily will be assigned to young be well it will be assigned again Now inside off your get
subtraction There no more yell Be now you have in terms off your money and your valuables
That's a Let me more If I completely on let me run this core You're going to get same
results Do that right.
So be clear.
Yeah,
and be our specific domain function.
P and Q are specific to get our function,
your money and North Pacific get subtraction function right While calling in this way only
the values will be assigned to your variables respectively.
First the value first variable second value to second variable Not okay.
No.
Suppose I how badly values called nine and 10 I want to find this attraction for this.
Yes,
we confined.
Get subtraction.
My Uncle Martin directly control your values also.
Now,
if I do in this way,
let me come in these two functions.
No,
I'm not reading year and B values in my hand.
Gently.
How values nine and 10.
Yes.
You can call yourself,
get subtraction or get a hard function.
Whatever it may be any but those two are taking to value Speaker Mark.
You are am coming.
And that's why I'm passing to values.
Gets a production line from Martin.
No,
let me tell you can see the result.
You're getting my last one.
Let me take my insulin 10.
Or let me define some variable called Let's say some X equals 2 50 Now you can pass one
value as variable on one more is directly value.
No problem.
It will work.
The only thing Finally,
it is going to match values maintain with the,
um on the x ray lividity in.
So what you are mapping only values your mom mapping here.
That's very important thing.
So,
guys,
there's a simple way to work with your arguments like Okay,
thank you for watching this video.