friends here.
We're going to discuss a vote.
Functions with arguments on Britain value.
See,
Ali,
we have seen how to send arguments to your functions.
Now,
what we're going to do is along with your arguments,
how you can get a written.
Where you from your function.
That's what we're going to discuss here,
right?
Let me take an example to give this Ah,
explanation.
I'm going toe sale a bite on skip name as functions with arguments on return values dark be
like So again,
Let me take simple example because we are an initial stage,
right?
So I'm taking simply a reason off two numbers.
So once again,
I'm writing court from scratch.
I mean,
first,
I will write your core with told functions so that you will get some idea how to implement
your functions.
Right then.
Beak was too input and that he was second number.
That's it.
No,
we know if you want to find the addition off these two variables,
right?
Let's say a result I'm taking it was two year place be.
And then I am printing.
So the traditional you are here.
All right,
be he's You're simply what result?
That's it right.
Let me open my command line.
Now we know.
Script us this one.
No,
Let me run this.
I'm gonna bring number four or number five.
You're getting results as line,
but same skipped.
I want implement in terms off functions.
So what I'm going to do Ease reading to numbers year and be I want toe right under main
function.
Not only main days,
you can take anything,
but if you take main somewhat meaning we're going to start our court from this.
Fine.
That's it,
right?
I so get addition.
I'm defending one more function,
right?
So here I'm using simply these two lines.
Just let me arrange indentations properly,
then return none.
That's fine.
No,
I'm running nor put.
You're not getting old port.
The reason is you're not calling your main function by only main function.
We have to call because we had to start our court from this line.
That's why this court is there under this function.
No,
I need to call that function.
Right.
Let me call it main.
That's a right.
So if you call this main function what your fight on will go,
it will come from two.
Here then video and beat them return.
None means I had to come back to here.
But nowhere.
We're calling this If you call this,
then only these two leads will exclude so that we can see the result.
So after reading your numbers in your main function just to call these two,
I mean this function while calling the function right.
So we are using functions.
You A and B are violent only in this main function.
So how you can get a year and be valleys in get addition function while calling that you
can pass you what a comma be You can also take yeti A comma be Are you sure?
Off Become a beacon Take some become a que Also on here If you take become a que unity
replace in your get rich in function these places I mean,
whatever we hold I let's a year on B this year on be suppose if I take your pick a mock you
then I need to replace year and be with become a que in this angelozzi.
But even though if you take you come a bit no problem,
because this year and be I mean six cents.
Whatever you how year and be there are different from your year and be rich are defining
your get tradition function,
even though names are same,
even though names are saying they are under the different function.
So the variables are different.
Only the year value is mapping toe this one be valleys mapping.
Did this one?
So here you can take anything that's fine.
No,
we have our core just to get original two numbers.
Let me around your court.
I'm running so like let's say enter for and fight.
You're getting results as line.
That's fine.
Up to know we know.
So here what we are doing simply were passing arguments.
So you are called function on here this year and be our core basically this year and be
this year,
and we bought our variables only.
But more specifically,
hard to say.
These two are arguments these two are.
Parameters are traditional arguments.
That's fine.
No,
actually,
I am printing the result off your ear and be reserved in inside off my function itself.
But now I don't want to print here.
I want to print it that reserved only in main function just to get the additional fear and
be I'm using this function but I want to print the results from your main function itself.
Let's say after calling your get traditionally a comma be I mean after completion off this
logic result a come of a plus B If I try to print the result from here the addition off you
were year on and be he's I'm reading simply result here But if I say in this way,
what will happen?
Just observe that this is your court,
right?
You're calling main function Be clear gaze you're calling main function Your floor of
control comes here Then you are reading a value than your reading Be valued and you are
calling this function your flow off control goes to hear You are finding this already a
plus B on you're excluding return In return you are sending your Custer back toe this line
Then you are printing this video This line something so raw and so then written on it will
come back to here so that your court is going to execute on it is going to company,
right?
But if I run days,
see the result,
you're getting another call.
Result is not defined white,
because do we have any dessert variable inside off main function?
Know where we are reserved?
How come it will bring the are It's not possible right without having variable how you can
bring.
Of course,
the desert is there in this function,
but we know if any variable is defined inside off a function that is specific to that
function only right that is local toe that function.
You can't access that outside off your function.
So if you want black sis outside off a function where you defend your variable,
you need to make it as a global.
But globally is not a good practice.
We'll see about it,
then how you can send that result back to your main function,
right?
Just forget about your programming.
I suppose you have a question called y equals to some FX,
just as you now,
if affects is a function,
just a junior for fixes some X squared plus three x place to something like that,
and you can take any expression and based on some X value,
you're going to get some result.
That means suppose therefore to let's say for taking place off exiles up shooting too to
square 44 plus 6 10 10 plus two Tool to will your assignment away right?
Why you close to your fourth to Ming's function?
Result your ascendant away right now You know what Programming also same concept What is
the function?
Result this variable that very well this function this function result I need to assigned
to some variable Let's say I'm taking variable called result only you can take any variable
I'm taking result only.
But be clear This result is in your main function on this resort is in get tradition
function there are completely different right?
But what I want raised Why calling this function?
You may get some result like that result I want to assign So this variable that's it.
It is only because to get additional fee a comma be Lizardi cause toe from this function.
Whatever the result,
you are getting that result I want to assign to this variable called result right,
but absurd output first if I run,
you are getting result as what happened Are he s you already?
Maybe I did not say what this court let me say with No,
I sailed that.
So you're getting none,
actually.
Should get seven rate.
You're getting none.
The reason is what our the function you're using that function result you're getting here,
that result you need to send back to this position.
So to send you a result from this function toe this place we are using return we are
sending,
we're sending.
But what we're sending none.
That's why you're getting results as none but what I want to sign.
If you don't have any requirement to send from your function,
then only take none.
Otherwise,
what is the value you are expecting from your function that you need to mention here?
Return results?
What are the result?
You're getting that value,
not a variable.
Be clear.
You're sending only value off this result you are sending that value off reserved this
result of written All right,
then,
floor of control.
We come to this position because off redone.
But while coming back what you're carrying that result the value off these that value you
are placing here so that that little bear so into results simple.
CJ's be clear.
When what if you run your core,
you know this is a main function.
These are some very is some function that is some function your fight and won't execute.
That's off now it will simply remember this name.
That's fine.
No,
that is the main logic in your cool.
You're trying to execute this right now.
Your floor off bundle comes to here then very first line you're reading year and be then
resorted He caused to get additionally comma be crisis,
right?
Why?
Because of some three plus two.
What is the priority here?
1st 3 plus two will be Emily attack.
That result will be assigned away Same way I have written here.
Resulted coast to get our dictionary Com A B So first this function result will be
calculator.
So to get there,
a reason function is there Here,
your partner will come to hear it will find result and then we'll come back Well,
coming back.
What you're sending returned result the value which is there in result that value you're
sending back.
So that means finally in place off these you are getting this result variable Whatever
you're writing,
return some variable.
That value will be assigned to this reserve.
Right,
But be clear This result on this result there is no relationship.
Only the value off this result will be assigned to this reserve.
So variables in a different functions.
Even though if you are same names,
they are different right now let me let me know you're going to get woman still none is
that Yeah.
I did not say these Big Abdullah here there is a dot here.
So dark means that you did not say that.
Let me say it first.
No,
I see you Let me run it.
You're getting There is no foreign fighters nine from very are getting from Maine
functionally right,
So not only main function if you want to send the result or some particular value from your
function from where it is calling.
So actually you are calling this function from here.
No,
I need to replace some value here from the after accomplishing off this function.
So that's what you are right here in your function.
If you write returned results,
that result will be commonplace year so that that you were assigned with this we're able So
there's a simple way toe send a result or any value or return value from your function.
That's a right.
Let me define one more are stripped here so that you know you'll get clarity.
What I want to do is I had to really number then I want to find suppose but that number How
do my to play with 10?
All right,
multiplication by 10.
I want to do with the help of some function.
But inside of a function I don't want to print my result I need to send that result to my
main function in Maine.
Functionality to print out.
Right?
See that?
Let me start from here onwards,
guys,
if you want to write a court for simply right may like so that is the execution point
starting execution point from where you are going to exclude your court.
Then some very harder defined Your main function right now Let me really a number.
Let me take number equals two input and that you were number.
That's it.
No,
I want to get some results.
What is my result?
Mighty play number,
even number with sometimes just just just simple example,
right.
So multiplying number with it in for that function.
I need to send what are the number in my hand.
I am Certainly now just to go a bow on defined a function call multi play No,
with the pen.
Whatever the number you are sending right from here that number should store somewhere here
with some respite to some variable.
So I can take value not only value even it can take same variable.
No problem.
But if it takes aim variable,
you may get confused but if you want to take no problem,
you can take it right now What I'm taking is then I'm finding result equals two.
You want value important Then finally I'm sending return,
not result So that what will happen What are the value?
You are getting that value into 10 That result I'm sending back that means in place off
this.
Finally,
you're getting your number into 10.
Now I will print the result here in Maine funding itself the result e simply am printing
You were reserved.
That's a wait.
Let me honey,
I am certain things up with seven.
Your getting 70.
There's one more thing here I am finding dessert and then I'm sending that result,
right?
Not only that,
see?
Definitely I can return with your expression as well.
Return value into tell.
No problem.
What will happen?
You're valuing toe 10 that you are sending back.
So this value will come on.
Replace this value this value Well,
come on.
Assigning place off this for your variable.
That's it.
That is that uses off return keyword in your function.
If you want to send any value from that function,
do from where it is called to place that place.
If you want to send your value,
then you can take return your key word.
So if you're expecting some value back from your function whenever if you're calling,
then with help off writable only you can get that butler variable value to this position if
you don't.
I mean,
if you are not expecting Justin berated and none,
that's it.
Okay.
So,
guys,
this is the simple way to understand about return value.
Right?
So please do practice was first.
Whatever we are doing in our decision same thing.
First practice.
Anyway,
we're going forward step by step.
We will write some real transcripts as well,
so that you will be good with the uses off your functions.
Okay.
Okay,
guys,
Thank you for watching this radio