friends here.
We're going to discuss about the functions with the default arguments.
Not to get clarity on your functions with the before door commands.
Let me start with the functions with some arguments only we know how to pass an argument to
your function.
Right?
Let me weapon my editor.
Let me create a simple pie transcript.
So I'm going to say with us functions with that default arguments.
No,
I'm not going to read any value from Come and find you simply I'm writing badly.
Some values,
Let's say how simply a function called display on a gender.
This is taking it any variable value.
Oh,
argument,
right positional argument.
Let me print simply the value off.
Okay,
he's just imprinting that value.
That's fine,
then simply I'm returning None,
right?
No days we have a simple function called display on.
If I run that you're not getting in or put because you're not calling that now,
let me call that.
But I'm calling that with value called full No,
See the results.
You can also call the dysfunction for any other value as well,
right?
But while calling be clear while calling in case if I not pass Any argument?
What is giving display?
Missing one required positional argument.
Actually,
if you have very here,
this is You're defined.
Function whenever.
If you want to call this function,
this function needs one argument.
But you're not passing from here,
right?
You're not passing that so if I know.
But if you're not pausing that you will get another like this No,
In case if you are not passing then I want to work with some default value.
If I passed,
my function has to take that pastor value.
In case if I'm not passing,
then my function has to work with some default value.
Let's say I'm taking you coast one.
Now you find a day goes toe one See that?
Let me say we can't done it.
You're not getting any better on the default value off years.
One right.
In case if you pass any value your yays taking that value injured off this a coast one,
right?
See,
in 59 I'm calling your function with the value called four right?
Then you evaluate getting for here after that,
Then second,
I'm calling same function with value for yes,
you're getting But I am not calling.
I'm calling without any arguments.
Then it is getting default value called one that default value are given here.
So this is the way how you can be fined before value for your functions or default argument
.
Right now,
let me take one more function.
I will give this function as it is for your practice.
Let me define one more function or definition.
I had numbers dissolution.
So if you know the concept,
we're going forward.
You cannot play when nobody forget a situation like this.
So actually,
I'm going to defend a function This function needs are two variables to arguments.
Let's say a comma be right on.
I want to find simply Result is nothing but a plus B on.
Let me simply print directly The result he's it would result.
That's fine.
Then finally let me our return.
None as off.
No,
I'm not expecting anything from my function.
No.
Let me call this function with values.
Yes,
it's working.
Mark.
I suppose I'm calling there without any arguments,
but you're getting another.
I suppose in my hand I have only one value.
Let's say fight.
I don't have second value.
Then we're getting another.
So what I'm doing is supposed for second value.
I'm giving a default value called one I don't see.
That is a but based on situation unity,
selective default value whenever.
If you're adding two numbers,
right?
But if we don't know second number,
what is the value you need to add for first number?
Generally,
Jiro.
That's why I can take here.
No,
Jiro.
So five alleged.
If I only or getting I'm calling this function with one value only.
But what about second value?
So if it is edition,
the second really should be Jiro.
If it is multiplication,
that second valley should be one.
So I mean is on your requirement.
You know the Celica default values,
right?
Maybe some crew fall some part.
Whatever it may be right.
So if you want to take border default values yes,
you can take it now See that I'm calling my function without any arguments.
If you're not having any arguments,
where is the result?
Always,
Jiro,
if you don't know anything digital,
suppose right.
But suppose if I give you only one or grin so one is deformed.
But what about first value in it to pass it.
I need to follow some simple rule here.
Suppose if I take a Kojiro and then be normally see that you are getting some error.
Call syntax error,
but is non default.
Argument follows default argument.
That means always first unit.
In case if you have some default arguments,
you know to mention always your default arguments only at the end,
while defining your function inside off your parents is I should not,
right?
Like a course digital.
I would then be,
But I can write.
Yeah,
come on.
Because to do means default value.
Whatever you have,
you are right at the end.
In your definition,
that is the meaning off this error.
No.
See that it's working for him.
Okay,
So,
guys,
this is the way How you can be fine.
A default value.
Suppose I,
June?
Dad,
I'm going to work with some database.
Well,
I'm going to work with some operation on my Atlantic settler.
Let's say I need a user name for that.
Working some on on some operation on something,
right?
I need a user for their support.
If you don't pass any use or at least I want today Group has done my user working with
whatever they use,
are you?
How that's it?
There's these are just assumptions anywhere.
You will get full clarity while writing real time scripts.
So first we need to Lansing taxes.
That's what we are doing here.
So working on some most either What happened?
Rudy is not different.
Sorry.
This is string,
right?
That is not a variable.
That is a stream,
you know,
to mention inside of quotations working with root.
Suppose if I know what is the user I want to work.
Suppose I want to work with some web logic.
Could mean Let's everybody could be now it's working perfectly.
If you don't pass any user,
it will take root as that before user But if you pass,
it will take that pass user.
So that is the uses off before old arguments inside off your functions.
It's very,
very important case.
Okay,
just I do remember the syntax is how we are working with the default arguments.
That's it.
Okay.
Okay,
guys,
Thank you for watching this video