friends here we're discussing about of functions with the variable and the arguments.
So what is mean by variable length arguments?
See,
we know that whenever we define your function,
right,
so it may take either one argument or two arguments or three.
And based on that were passing.
Let let me open a simple script for that.
Suppose if I defined a function display.
So I want to define a function just to find out the type off your pastor.
Variable.
Not so right now I'm calling.
Suppose it's working.
So how many arguments your function is taking?
Only one argument,
right?
In case if I pass two arguments,
it won't accept because it is taking only one argument.
But we're passing to right?
So even though if you passed to argument,
suppose if you're function is ready to accept,
then that is called a variable lent argument.
Function means number off arguments.
What are the arguments?
Your passing right,
The number off arguments If they very then that is called variable length arguments for
your functions.
Generally it won't accept right?
See if I pass for come away now.
Two variables were passing.
No,
you're function is not ready to accept that.
Right?
But we have a small Syntex for your function.
Will define such that it has to ready toe.
Take any number of arguments,
right?
Let me define it.
No,
someone's display start data generally.
If you google it,
you can see the syntax is e R G arguments start arguments.
So that is not a standard variable.
You can take any variable because their arguments But what the value were writing here
They're generally arguments,
right?
That's why they're taking DRG.
Not only that,
you can take simply data also right,
Then first,
let me print what you are getting.
If you take variable and arguments,
what is what type of reader you are getting whenever if you pass your data to your display
function.
So to know that I am printing simply What data?
No.
Let me call your function.
I'm calling without any data without passing any arguments,
Joe,
arguments.
I'm passing now.
Your function is ready to accept on after the data.
What?
You're passing couple empty couple Now,
let me call it with one argument.
Yes,
Again is ready to accept one argument as a couple?
No.
Let me quality to it some number off values?
Yes.
Again,
it is ready to accept.
That means see,
number of arguments are very right.
This is nothing bird variable length arguments even though if we change number off
arguments even though if you pass number off arguments each time different number off
arguments,
your function is ready to accept that,
right?
Not to accept that nothing is that simply write star generalised,
arming Jiro are more.
You can pass Jiro arguments for more number off arguments.
Jiro one or two or three or for any number of arguments you can pass to your function
whenever if you define your barometers has start some variable.
Not only data days generally are that's a no let me comment are Let me comment these two
functions.
I mean four to light and 50 line.
See,
we know if it is a couple right,
we can take one by one argument from that one by one value from that using loop for Luke
for each in your art.
Let's be clear,
argues not a fixer variable.
You can take anything.
The only thing whatever that data you are passing,
whatever the arguments,
you are passing all arguments stored into this variable as a couple.
If it is a couple,
I can take one day one value from there.
Right?
That's what I'm doing here.
Now let me turn.
You can see the results right now.
Just 40 were understanding.
Just I'm calling once again with the different values display function.
Let me take simply high on,
then support some $4 6 whatever it may be data see that it's working.
So whether you're passing the arguments are two arguments Now your function is ready to
accept,
right?
So there's nothing but simply variable length arguments in your functions.
Okay.
Okay,
guys,
thank you for watching this video.