friends here.
We're going to discuss aboard comments,
comments off,
fight on,
See before dealing aboard commands.
Let me weapon my terminal.
Right.
So there's still I'm trying to work using via or via Morita's,
right from Cameron Line.
I'm using we I am Editors.
Let me that symbol by Dan Skip first.
Suppose I'm going to write uses off comments,
Not the way any bite on programmers script.
So here I'm going to explain how to use comments.
Right.
So guys foster thing comment is nothing back?
Wr writing some pie Transcript Yes,
I do mean house,
um thousands off lines night.
I'm to understand What is the purpose off your python price by done script or python
program,
you have to go with each and every line on the order,
understand?
I mean,
suppose some third person.
So instead of dirt,
you can write somewhere some comments,
some lines representing that,
saying that what is the purpose of this school?
Suppose Let's say first off,
while I'm going to write some simple bite on program some year close to four on because to
fight and then I'm finding result equals a plus B.
Don't worry,
guys.
How to write this program.
Okay,
While going forward,
we will learn how to write.
No,
I'm trying toe print.
Right.
The addition off you on the east.
This is the result.
Just I'm bringing this alertness sale this on.
Right it on.
Let me run this.
We'll take it whether you're able to get output or not.
Yes,
we're getting somewhat put,
right?
No see,
because this is very simple program.
By seeing that you can understand that,
Yes,
we are defining two variables on your finding the addition of those two where it was on
your printing.
But you should have dirt.
I conveyed some comments somewhere.
So I am writing.
This is a simple at the medic calculator.
I'm implemented by suppose on one way it is implement their let's suppose some too late to
Jura 19 And what is the worst in off the score?
Ehlert.
Sir,
Disease.
We don't wonder deal if you are there.
Guys,
these lines are not your fight on programs,
lights,
but these are something like comments to give some information about your fight on Skipper
Python program.
That's why you fight.
Run this program,
right?
Let me do it.
They're lost Yeah,
No,
let me say V.
And if I try to run,
it was script.
You will get another.
This is a simple automatic carolers invalid syntax because there is not a valid syntax.
Actually,
this is not the point on program line.
So you are writing something to give you information about your script to the third person
,
right?
So those lines are cummings on while running your fight on program.
If you want to skip this lines,
this lines,
you have to write each and every line you're to start with the hash symbol so that all
lines are coming out.
You're fightin while running your bite on.
No,
you're fightin won't cancer.
These lines size your Buyten's program lines.
And simply your pipeline will skip this lines even though it right this this type of lines
,
thousands off lines in your program.
Your python won't because that these lines as a python script lines and then simply it will
skip those lines on your fight on program starts from here a close to four because the fire
result on these four lines will execute right now.
Let me save it and burn it,
Coleman.
Let me say this?
No,
I'm going to run now.
Instead of getting another,
you will get output.
That's it like fine.
So there is no you have to understand that.
Toe comment A single line.
You can use hash symbol like even if you want to come in some 1000 lines for each and every
line before starting your line,
you hard to write harsh symbol.
Let us assume that you're having support some 100 comment lines under in sequence.
Right?
So to come in the 100 lines water how to do for each and every line.
How to start with the hash symbol.
But I am the lazy person.
But now I'm going toe you some shortcut.
Whatever the lines,
you want to come in all those lines you can write between tribal courts.
Those triple courts may be single or double.
I can use a this single court three times or double course three times.
Now this is exactly equals two you are placing if you want to come in.
All these four lines are your commenting by placing Hashim blunder starting off your each
and every life no in giraffe that you can simply place.
He were commenting lines.
Comment lines Between this quotations,
these are trouble coats A.
The single level courts are double quotation symbol three times.
Right now,
Let me sell this onder under and see the output before going to run.
Let me do one thing I'm going to see you are script.
This is your script,
and I'm going to run that perfectly.
Working means your fighter now keeping these lines on these lines are coming too low.
Okay,
so they comments or two types single and comments and multiple line comments.
So singling comments you can come into with the hash symbol on multiple line comments in
case you feel sometimes,
you know,
or some sequence off lines,
some hundreds or tens or some 50 lines right on maybe two lines.
Also,
you can come in with the tribal courts as well.
So multiple line comments is tribal courts.
So and remember that it may be single condition.
Three times are you have to start with Three double conditions are already underway to
three double conditions.
That's it.
Okay.
I hope it's clear.
Okay,
guys,
thank you for watching this with you.