friends here.
We're going to discuss abode.
Fight on regular expressions.
Concept simply introduction part.
Let me start that.
So,
first of all,
what is the regular expression or leg X?
See here I get to the shortcut for your regular expression.
Now,
the records is a procedure in any language to look for a specified pattern in a given text
.
No,
to understand that this line effectively,
you have to know what is apartment first.
So what is the pattern?
Patron is a sequence off characters which represent multiple strings.
See if they're here,
but only the sequence off characters.
But string is also your seconds off characters,
right?
But string is going to represent only one string.
But pattern is going to represent multiple strings.
Let me.
You are some examples for this.
Suppose if I take a string call in this way.
So,
first of all,
this is a string,
right?
If we use this string in your regular expressions,
then it is going to represent two words is And it let me take one more thing.
Python to three.
So,
first of all,
if you observe how returned this thing inside of quotations,
that's why this is your string first?
Awful.
No.
If I used this inside off your regular expressions than it is going to represent two words
So he had tours.
But while going forward,
we will see our different scenarios where you're going,
toe your pattern is going to represent multiple words.
Multiple strings.
Right now the gets is a procedure.
Any language to look for A specified pattern means to look for a number off strings in a
given text space.
Very pattern pattern is nothing but a number off for strings.
Right now,
Magnetics persons are useful to work with the multiple strings on a given text.
Let me do one of the simple example.
Suppose let me weapon my fight on common land First let me under in the python.
See,
I have a string like this.
Suppose my string equals two by phone Ease Simple.
I'm It is easy just right.
Let me assume this has my string.
Okay,
so don't worry Aboard the you are a grammar for this in tax.
For this is a statement of what this string just we help some string.
No,
I suppose if you want to split,
he was string based on years.
Yes,
I can split by using my basic string operations.
Like suppose if I want to split this Yes,
I can split it based on it also.
But now my requirement is I want to split my given string wherever ease on it,
are there Did I need a split?
I mean here also I want to get my split with your normal string operations.
You cannot do it.
But if you go with the regular expressions So if you want to use regular expressions in
your python you have to take our remodel now simply under that already.
Dots plate.
He's on it.
So you had to write.
You had to learn these rules.
Don't worry as off.
No.
Just after this Where you going?
Forward.
We will learn how to make a pattern based on our requirement.
Then you will string no seed output.
You can able to split your string based on ease and it wherever easily leader there their
speed happen.
But with your non Muslim your business,
you can't You can't do it in this way.
You can split based on only one string,
right?
So this is that one days with your regular expressions.
Not only that,
we have so many advantages with your regular expressions.
So we're going forward.
We will see different situations where we hope to use regular expressions in your real time
.
But we'll go with Sylvester,
like,
fine.
See your regular expressions we hope are different operations.
So suppose here.
I'm going to show you some off them,
like match.
Such find.
All fine.
Deter substitute,
split,
Compile.
And we have some other operations as well.
So we are going to tickles.
Discuss all the operations off.
Your regular expressions are simply our remodel,
Mr Bester like.
Okay,
guys,
thank you for watching this with you.