friends here.
We're going to discuss about part two rules to create a pattern.
See,
already we have seen some of the rules to create your pattern on.
These are the rules.
Now we're going to see some more rules.
Nobody forced one.
He's carried or cap symbol the meaning for disease.
Start off the stream.
UN start off the line in case off multilane string.
Anyway,
As I know,
you're going to work with single line techstars string.
So we'll discuss about multi lines while working with your files.
Fine.
No.
Let me open my data to get clarity on this uses off carrot symbol.
So first,
let me import Audie.
Then let me take some text so I'm going to take it.
Is a fight own on it is is it'll learn?
No,
I'm going to take a pattern cord Simply ik that may like,
uh it and is so now we know that What is the users off scored records?
If you write anything inside of a school record,
anyone off that that means maybe it Or maybe he's no as off.
Now let me use my find All we already know this how it is going to work from our previous
video.
Right?
I'll see that isn't You're getting two times it onto times.
He's because any given text to be held in two places is on including two places it for
stuff All the seas representing two strings.
Maybe it are maybe is no.
Suppose if I use carats Symbol here,
cap symbol here.
Then what is?
The use is off that in these to work?
Sorry.
Not a word is We are still were working with strings only in these two strings.
If anyone off the string is their very first,
that is going to fetch only darts String.
If anyone off these two things is there at the very first name given text on because of Cap
,
it is going to fetch dark only know See the result annihilating only it Because whenever if
we keep caps Immel,
it won't look in entire string.
It will look only at the starting off history for your patterns,
right.
For your patrons,
it is Look only at the starting,
not in the entire string.
That is a use off gap.
No support If I remove this part now,
what is that?
Very first night given string is no.
You're fetching that.
See?
Use may be in the combination with any other word.
Also no problem.
Still were working with strings.
Not a word.
Fine,
No,
the same way.
Suppose I want to look any string,
which is there at that end.
Let's say I'm going to write land once again.
Or maybe 23 places.
No problem.
Mostly there is already are getting three times alone.
But I want to print.
If learn is there at the end off a given string,
then the allergy or to use be clear,
were used dollar at the end,
Not here.
So that is the room.
If you use dollar here,
then your letter expressions will look for this land pattern at the end.
Any given text.
So Carter and all are very,
very important.
No,
the next one is slash B empty string at the beginning or end off a word.
See,
before going to use this slash B.
Let me take this as my string on my next c nd the word because you have a space starting
off that end string on ending off that industry.
But if you take beauty,
that is not a word because starting we held but the ending we don't have.
But if you have the empty and word empties having space here at the end aside,
whatever the starting,
you don't help on.
The word is having other starting,
but are the ending.
You don't have a space even though if you don't how This is your starting that for you need
to have any space at this starting side.
And this is the ending work.
That's why you don't have any space at the ending side.
So you need to remember that if you're going to work for a string,
whether it is a word or not,
then if it is in between off a were given text,
then you should look for space at the starting on at the end.
Me,
right?
But if it is a starting within the entire text,
then you need to have any space on the left.
Aside,
on forward,
you don't need to have any space on the right side.
Now be clear and I'm going to use that.
See,
here I'm taking my part on us simply.
First,
I'm going to take let me take Len.
So how many times you're getting learn pat around,
put three times but I'm looking Printed the land war.
If the space is there,
are the left the side off that land Now see the result anyway,
you're not going to You're not going to get that.
The reason is we know slash B is a backspace generally now here.
Not for backspace purpose.
That's why you have the right to slashes.
You had to escape that No,
See the result laden here We how on right side We have a space on the left side.
We have a space.
What?
This land and this land be clear here we have a space here we have a space.
But for this land,
we don't have space here.
That's why you're not getting that.
We're getting only two.
Yes,
that's fine.
So engine of writing to back slashes you can also simply right are drawstring.
So in drawstring,
right?
You are special characters are going to skip no slash b is going to treat us space,
not a backspace,
simply space,
right?
That's why from now onwards,
I'm going to use our well grading your pattern.
Actually,
that is a good practice.
You can take it,
right?
Fine.
No see,
though.
Next thing I run how space he?
Uh,
yeah,
maybe No.
Okay.
No.
See if I run these or is output Len?
Len,
I'm not mentioning any space at the ending.
No,
my requirement is completely I'm looking for a learned word.
That's why you should our space at the starting on attending.
That's why I'm making here string pattern with a slash b and slash being the starting on
the ending.
Now,
the meaning for this is look for aylan work because I mentioned the year slash b and end
the inside also slash b no.
See the result only accept last learn know where we have learned were all our combination
with some other things.
Not let people read space here for these.
Now,
this is also a word,
right,
Len?
No.
If I run this court once again,
you're going to get two times less.
So that is the use off slash B.
Okay.
Make sure that for this land,
we don't have any space at the left right side.
Even though if you don't have that is the ending would in a given text.
That's why you need to have any space are the right side for that world.
But he should have space here.
I mean,
left aside,
that's it.
Now the next one is capital B.
Empty string north or the beginning,
or end off a word.
So it's huh?
It is a very Vera used case with the Capital B.
But we have options.
We need to London first.
Let me do one thing.
Let me remove this land and this land.
Don't get confused.
Very simple,
But try to understand.
Suppose you for take?
Simply learned you're getting.
But if I take slash B on a slash B here means starting.
I should have a space on anything also I should have a space.
I mean,
I'm looking for it worked.
Do you have that type of what?
Any given string?
New,
right.
Fine.
Neiffer,
take capital B.
I don't want space at the starting off.
Your word are the same time.
I don't want space at the ending off history.
Yes,
we have done here Now if I write somewhere land separately.
No,
For this land we have a space at the starting on our day and me.
But what is my intention?
Find the learn string,
which is not having space at the right side or left aside Our find the learn string which
is not having a space are starting or are the ending No,
See the result?
It won't affect this.
Only you're not fetching this.
If I remove this land,
then you are going to get empty.
Because Norway,
we have a learned word in a given text such a that it is not having any spaces at this
starting or ending as after.
You have learned word,
but it is having a space at the starting on our standing.
But you're looking we told spaces.
Are we getting output?
No,
that's it.
So that is the use off slash B capital B,
right?
No,
the next thing is slash t slash in slash are fab new lines on Gary's rhythm See place as
off.
No.
Suppose if I try to look for a pattern using your words slash t nor put because while
typing my text nowhere I used the tab key on my keyboard.
No,
let me you somewhere on somewhere tub.
Sorry.
So what happened?
Yeah.
Now see the result.
Two places I use slash t.
That's why you're getting that?
No.
Let me write somewhere New line on.
Let me modify your pattern with respect to in Not Okay.
So based disorder,
simple hydrant.
Those to get your pattern.
So he had important thing is starting ending.
And this is very,
very important.
If you want to look for a word,
then slash B is very,
very useful on while using slash b into use blustering.
That's right from no one.
Words were going forward when it But if I want to create a pattern,
I will use anyone in my pattern or letter as well or character as well.
So that that isn't Ross Tree.
That's what I think.
Is that okay?
Okay,
guys,
thank you for watching this for you.