friends.
We have been working with the rules to create your pattern.
Now,
already,
we have seen some of the rules to create your pattern.
Like these are the first to set rules to create your pattern on these are the second set
rules to create your pattern.
Now we're going to work with some rules.
No,
Let me take the very first rule.
Is cuddly braces inside that some number?
So what is the meaning for?
This is exactly two times now.
Let me weapon,
miter toe Get clarity on this usage.
So how sailed this a script as rules three Not be.
By first of all,
let me import my Ari model.
No,
I just assumed that we have a text in this week.
This is it.
By tone and fight on three.
Just assume that now.
What is my requirement?
The supposed If I take my partners so as I'm using from no one worth,
Drawstring simply are Suppose if I try to look for fight on,
I would even let me remove this.
No,
let me print.
Oh,
you're already don't find all your partner in any given text.
No,
See the result.
You're getting fight on two times,
but in Python,
at the ending.
How yet?
Two times.
I want to get that.
So what I can do?
I can write.
And two times.
No,
I'm going to get there.
Yes.
Suppose I have a python?
Just some character four times.
Then I want to get this entire matching.
Then see that?
Suppose I want to look for a python?
Such there any is four times.
I won't look for a fight on word such that in these four times.
If it is a wordy should,
right,
slash B before I'm starting.
Do we have that?
No,
no.
Where we helped by tone with the billions were But we have a word with fight on and four
times they let me write in four times.
Now,
see,
that is a yes you are getting but actually here he and his four times No,
no need to write four times your Ian simply right.
Yen,
then four cuddly braces.
Now the meaningful disease.
Younis,
four times.
That's it.
Like ways.
You gonna play for any character?
Let's say suppose Let me come in this pattern I'm writing somewhere.
Suppose simply Yeah,
Yeah.
Then something.
Then in this way.
No.
Here also.
Suppose I help you?
Yes.
I assume that three times here You're also three times here now,
just based on our previous rules and current rules.
What I want to ease,
I want to get a word which consists off year three times.
Then first of all,
I'm trying to find the world.
And what if there is a worthy hard right slash beard of starting and started anything?
Then between that,
you're looking for a world called I don't get Yes,
you're getting that only one time you are having but the A's three times.
No.
Why should we write the A three times?
Simply color ta in square by curly braces.
You can also write three.
That's it.
Now I want to look for a word Such there Yea is 12345678 The world which is having the
world with year has eight times That's it.
I suppose sometimes you may house starting up with some exquisite No,
you don't know a word of it eight times you have a word with the X ray jet offer that eight
times.
Then before the what we help ex razor.
No.
See that pattern?
What?
Our taken exquisite offer that the eight times that type of war I want to find.
That's a so that is the use off.
Calibrates is with the number.
Then do come on four.
See here if if I write it to exactly two times if right to come before then whatever the
character before this Curly braces you how that character,
maybe two times or maybe three times or maybe four times.
See that what I'm let me take in new text I will do one thing.
I will come in this someone's let's say I have a text.
A call XY is a something x years there.
Then let's say x you sometimes that then x 123 four Let me take three.
So it on the X let me take four times also noble.
Now our understanding is now I want to find a word such there The world should house
starting,
let raise X and in England reason site First,
let me read.
Pardon for that.
First of all,
I'm looking for a world,
that's why slash b slash b Starting on in English,
Travis Space on then my word should have starting later as the X and in England rest,
is it?
But between this,
I have a view.
No,
I need to look for a word such that it is exists.
Right?
Was Let me is such in this week Find all your apartment in your text.
Yes.
Excellent.
30 or getting no Might equipment These between these two characters you maybe one time are
two times or three times Then simply after year hard right one time are two times or three
times or four times That's it.
Mostly the result if he how x after the between these two characters If you're here one
time yes,
it is going to face their If he is two times it is trying to face that We heard that No,
here we help.
But hear this character is that character is two times now Let me remove one,
sir,
so that you can get that as well.
See that?
Nothing.
So that is the use off Your calibrates is so exactly for a number of times.
You convert to curly braces with that number.
Maybe one time for two times or three times before your character.
Sorry,
the character.
Whatever you are looking,
then after your character a hard right in college races to come on for two or three or four
times,
then you are more times.
I don't know how many times he's there between your two characters,
but I want to such minimum with the two letters minimum with the two times here and then
Maxim any number of times now see the result he had two times is there,
and here's some number of times.
Is there?
Yes,
some number of times is that all are going to fetch because two times or more than that
three times or four times or five times are in 20 times between You are here answered So
you were ex and said you're years maybe two times or three times or four times are
different number off times.
That's it.
Now bless one out of more see forgettable place from this conserved.
If I want to try to look for one or more times,
I cannot one come up in calibrates is see that my pattern ease.
I am writing my partners ex yea,
yea,
maybe one time or more than that,
then no see,
that is a You're going to get all the work words which are which are having between X and
30 years one comma,
curly braces with one comer.
But same thing.
You can also write simply by Pleiss guys,
whatever the symbol are using,
I'm using here.
That is for you are previous character this year,
maybe one or more times.
Right?
Be clear,
yays One or more times That's a yeah,
is one or more times but same thing.
You can also write in this way also with that same No,
Joe are more pens.
See,
star means George more times.
Suppose if I take any word which is having its is a There is no year,
right as off No.
If I try to look with the x ray one comma,
curly braces or let me right.
Same thing with the place as well X you bless.
Is it?
Well,
see,
there is a same open but widened Cantonese between your ex answer.
You may or may not be.
Maybe George Times means there is no you are.
Maybe more than that.
I mean,
do your times are more than no more times?
Maybe one time,
two times three times or four times Then simply you can take year start now,
see the result.
You're going to get this matching as well for that.
So,
guys,
if I write in this way the possible patterns are exit because Tarmizi a maybe judo times or
may you are years one time are you are is two times or you were is three times like ways.
That is the meaning for star less means Except this first remaining all our for place.
Then the last one is once or none question more.
Maybe one time or none thing not for dear times are more than jail time or one time that is
four square records.
No see that Here he is there.
One time between X answered he had juror times is there But here we have multiple times.
But if I go with,
I'm creating part on us.
Drawstring he X Yeah,
question mark is there that may be juror times Our one time one or none?
That's it.
No,
see,
that is a which always having yea one time or gyrodynes those things we are getting.
That's a so the possible words for disease.
The X question mark means Gerard I'm zero times here said then x one time.
Maybe you that these two are the possible words.
No,
These two are these two words.
Are there any given text here in here?
So the threat is fetching them.
That's a right.
So waste these other some more simple tools to create your pattern.
And these are very,
very important.
See what our the rule we have here on this rule we are using in your pattern.
But make sure that whenever if you're playing this rules,
these rules are applicable for your particular character,
not for your entire words.
Yeah,
I'm using for year this question.
What means?
This symbol?
This rule is applicable for this year somewhere.
Suppose we usually hear cuddly braces for now,
for this year,
Not for your entire work.
Be clear.
Not for your entire world.
This is for only your character.
You are playing this concept,
right?
Okay.
Thank you for watching this with you.