prince here.
We're discussing search and match operations off our remodel.
See,
in your body we have different operations and options and functions.
Let me import Ari.
And if you know,
we have a the air operation coolly start all the operations and functions right on
variables to list from your model.
So these all our operations now among all those as off?
No,
I'm going to work with such under match,
right?
No.
Let me go and start a body or such operation first Let me look in my anytime.
So I'm going to save it as a such a match of practice.
Not be way no See the result First time importing module called body.
Now I'm taking it Text like this is for fight on on There are cool major who are sense
Let's say fight on two on fight on three on just a junior in future Someone's bite on foot
Just just I'm writing for our practice purpose No Let me write a pattern such that I need
to find out only as off know the value Pythons by 10 40 is not evaluate us off.
No right!
See how I'm going to read a pattern,
So simply delight any variable called pattern with drawstring.
First of all,
you're looking for a world or any string.
I'm looking for a word,
Let's say slash B starting on ending.
So between that support,
if I write,
simply bite on and already we know the find operations are defined.
All operation.
Let me first practice with final your partner in a given text.
Now see the result.
What you're getting simply are getting Piper.
But I want to get fight on two and fight on three as well.
Then suppose you for right here.
Only two you're going to get fight onto.
But now we are not getting fight on fight on three.
So let me right to our three and square records.
Mostly the result you're getting fight on to one pie country.
But what about this?
Bite on?
So if you want to get despite on,
your numbers are optional Right then he already a question more.
So what is the meaning?
Off question?
More.
Whatever the number you're having that may or may not be present.
That's why it is not that.
Then fight on that is going to match here.
Now See the result?
Yes.
You're getting suppose anywhere to 13 our numbers,
right?
Suppose if I go with slash D slash d means any number genital nine.
No.
See the result body or getting?
Do you know that?
The weighty hedge?
Sorry.
Yes.
Pile.
Mistake.
No real in your currency.
The results you're getting fight on four as well Because we are writing Simply slash days.
Last day means any number,
Gerardo nine.
But we hard to work with only 213 Either two or three.
That's why we're writing in square brackets to our strange enough writing slash b Be clear
.
That's fine.
No,
as off?
because off your pattern you're going to match this many words from your given text.
But among all those if you observe what is the first to match even you were given text
fight on.
But suppose you feel your fight on two on the year If you fight on three now the first
occurring match in a given text despite onto right now my requirement is I don't want to
get all match ing's Whatever the partner I'm taking from the pattern whatever the first
match is there any given text that only I want to find.
Let's say fight on boot as after you have 1st 2 matches bite onto that only I want to find
.
Then you're such a brazen is helpful.
It looks through all the anti string on returns the first to match it will match only one
match.
It will visit.
It will return only one match.
Not all finally is going to find all But Matt Such is going to find only the foster match.
That means by turn cool!
It is going to find if I remove this bite on Do then what is the first to match by country
that already has simply fightem.
How about if I remove these first?
Let me go with you are such operation and see the results print Audie door such Then you
will pattern in a given text.
See the output?
You're getting some object.
Don't worry about that.
See the match?
What is the match you got?
Bite on Because among all those the first matches by turned toe Now if I read some very
year simply white on then that is the first to match.
These are forced occurring world Any given text from your patterns,
that is,
it is finding right.
It will look in the entire string only for first Too much.
Not for all matches.
That's important one.
And suppose if you don't have any match,
let's say I'm writing some random pattern.
Yeah,
we are going to get none presided,
right?
Big clear.
No injured.
Directly printing my match.
I'm going to store it in tow.
Some variable called match object That is object because instead of that you have some
information.
What is that information?
I will show you.
Bring my job's eqt.
See?
That is it.
Span means starting in Nick's 11 minus phi is the length off your match?
11 minus one is the ending index for he was string for your match on this pattern is going
to represent multiple words.
But what is the matter?
What if you want to find your toe?
Look,
here are true logic.
If you want toe display only that I will show you that now See there now What I'm doing is
bringing much,
much from it given pattern from your pattern.
So what is the match exactly are getting you may get fight on to our fight on or pipe
country if the very first where despite under you're going to get right onto as after the
very first word is python from this value patterns,
That's where it is going to fetch Fight on,
then the his object Right from this,
I want to display only the Machu one.
Then you had to write something like You are much object.
They since you're operating your variable directly gonna decided are such pattern then dot
group But it is a better practice to take us into story or match object into some variable
Now see the result Buy it on.
If I remove these from here,
you'll see the result first,
matching his bite onto from your pattern.
You're getting that I don't want to bring to this match.
Object that Then what is the starting index off your Matute battle?
So see that starting index He's from your matchup city or to use dot Start starting.
You can count the operation off p starting.
Then what is the ending index off this If it is 13 14 15 16 17 18 19.
Now see the result ending index match object dot and see the result first.
You're getting 20 but 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 is reeling in legs.
That's why this is minus one.
Hard to do.
No,
that's fine.
Then what is the length off your matching object?
Nothing.
Is there simply You are much object Dottie End than minus match object dot start is the
length that right?
And suppose if you don't have a match on,
if you perform these operations,
you're going to get another.
Let's say I'm writing something random values here and I'm running and I'm going to run
this court to see that if you print your match observed,
that is a nun actually see the result in the airport?
None you're getting.
But how If it is a nun,
how you can find a group,
I'm in matching things.
Starting thing ending it sort possible.
There is no match for your pattern than how you can find these operations.
That's why,
while walking with your patrons,
right that do,
especially with your such kind match.
Suppose as off no.
So what you have to do is before finding you have to check if match objectives present.
If it is none,
if collision becomes I mean the result is false,
then,
if doesn't allow to execute this operation's,
that's it.
Very simple.
Only if there is a match that only you want to find the values.
Otherwise morninto find l sprint simply.
No match formed.
No,
let's say now.
Random pattern.
I'm looking.
Let's a pattern.
Is something this?
There's no way mortified my pattern right now that we're on this no match phone.
That's that is a way how you can handle with your regular expressions to find your match.
Starting index ending in legs.
Right.
Something like that,
Len.
So if condition is very helpful to work with your regular expressions,
fine.
No,
let me take our string as modeling.
This is for no second line.
I'm writing.
Okay?
You can take even multi lanes also.
No problem.
Now,
as after you have three lengths off text that is multilane.
Now see the result?
Is there any change?
No.
By the fall,
such we look in all the lines.
If you have a one late,
we look in the one line.
If you have all the lands were looking all the lines by the Ford subjects for multi line.
Okay.
Be clear.
No,
let me go with now.
You are next.
Operation is match,
right?
Let me come in this thing.
See?
As off.
No.
Suppose if you do this Ah find all we know how many Parton's you're going to match.
But if you have done your bite onto is there somewhere it is not there at the very first,
right?
No.
First let me run this.
Bring let me come in the score.
That's very simple about match.
Don't worry,
You can understand Sprint Orry Dort match.
You're part run in a next See the result.
You're getting none.
Actually,
the match Purpose ease.
Same as such.
But you look only at this starting index.
If it is their very first even life hell,
multi lines are one line they were much will look only at the starting.
Our generate index is very match among all those your patterns.
If there is anyone part,
I mean it is going to happen.
Three words right among all those three words.
Is there any word?
Very first in the given line in the first line.
Then only your match will work.
Otherwise it won't look in.
The remaining lines are in the entire string.
It won't look only genital expression to look right.
See,
as I know this is your text.
And let me take these two things once again here.
Like,
I suppose if I try to bring people already don't match.
You're part from in a given text.
Even I want to look in the multilane.
What happened?
Okay,
one more parentis is none seeing that second Lenny,
how your pattern match the world for your patent fight on our very first.
But you're even life include forcefully multi line.
It is not working for your second line.
So by default match will look only for one Lenny formal dealings.
Anyway,
have you ever text simply with one line,
one leg?
So starting question to look simply generate election on Jiro it index only it will look No
,
let's say now I'm going to write very first line.
As with textract spite onto mostly the result you're getting because that very first we
have a match.
Be clear only at very first.
Now remaining operations are same.
Let me write this as a my object variable.
Let me store that in tow.
Match object equals two.
No,
see the result.
That's it.
Okay,
So that is the difference between such an matches.
Such we look in the entire string,
but it will find only the first match.
But as much we'll look only in the Jordan expedition.
Is there any match for your given pattern at the gelatin explosion in a single line?
Or even though,
if you are multi lines?
Even if you have mentioned forcefully multi line,
it won't work right?
But are you not?
I will work.
Ignore case in ST Let's say I'm writing pattern as Capital P.
Otherwise,
I would like to hear anything else capitals bite onto.
If I don't have the sorry dot I you're not having any match for you were much operation
because here Capitals.
But you're looking with small letters patterns.
Then you ca NBA league,
not kids to case sensitivity,
Are you not I That's it.
I don't even work,
but are your team will not work with your much right.
So,
guys,
Finally,
if you ever text with the multi lines,
such will look in any place.
What match will look only in this patient?
That's it.
That is a simple difference,
right?
So finally,
if you won't write a pattern Oh,
sorry.
Syntax ordered Such your pattern.
It was string.
If you need any flags,
you can include the same way for match You can light are not much pattern strings.
If you want,
including the flags,
you can include nothing.
Okay.
Okay,
guys,
Thank you for watching this with you.