friends Here we are discussing a boat split Substitute substitute Ian operations off your
remodel.
Let me weapon my fight on 10 mil on day I will explain.
See anyway,
they are very simple.
Operations are combat.
You're such ah match final find later that we opened my fight on treadmill on Let me import
Ari model.
So first operation is suppose year we want to discuss aboard split operation And if you
remember why it's starting or regular expressions We have started with spirit operation
only I mean while giving collection.
Anyway,
here I want to show you somewhat wants is in tax off your split operation So simply right
help body dot split operation and see the lizard You're getting some syntax right now.
First,
let me take my stringers.
So this is about fight on on supposed Pattani's very easy and we are having Why don't you
wash in and fight on three?
What sense?
Yes,
I Jr that is this string Now Suppose I want to split the given string badly I'm spreading
so heals itself.
I am writing a pattern.
Otherwise you can also write your pattern.
Let let's say my partner has so I want to be wired My string wherever fight on is there
right now.
Simply use our indoor sprint operation.
You are fired.
Run on your stream now See the result first,
See,
wherever Python is there,
this bit is happening.
But he had This is capital people right on.
But if you every year this is not simply python Fight on to one point on three.
No,
What I want to buoys very were fight on to our fight on three.
And with Python,
then there I want to be a split.
Now you feel after your pattern is going to represent fight on by turn to on by country But
of course you're having capital P so that you can ignore by using by playing flags.
Now see that I am a playing your flags Case sensitivity flags equals two.
Don't consider case and study.
Ignore case since really know see the result.
Wherever python is there are right on to is there are fights on trees the their spirit is
happening.
Right?
So the only thing is you have to know how to write a partner where you want to split in
which places you want to split based on that's places,
you know,
right?
A pattern only We have gone through the rules to create your pattern.
And one more thing here if you have the year,
Max,
it's pretty.
Is also there right now.
Lady,
run this with Max.
Split as well.
Let me copy this.
That legal right or first time playing Maxie,
Split Jew and see the reason there is no change whether if you write Jerar,
I mean Max Pretty Jiro are if you neglect this option,
there is no change.
But if I write one Max is split spirit only in one place that go from left to right.
The first occurred place now speaking to places that to where you coming from?
Left to right.
This is left to right,
right left to right.
So there we were in two places.
Now see the result here and here it is splitting now here.
And this year it is not splitting.
So that is the simple operation.
By using your spirit operation right?
Then we hold substitute.
Now let me show you syntax for you.
Our substitute first.
See,
there is a patron.
I mean,
whatever the pattern you want in this pattern.
Whatever the word you want to replace,
then your strength.
Then come then,
flags anyway.
You know,
lasers are flags.
Let me write simply anybody.
How your pattern.
Right.
What is your pattern?
That Merrick.
Simply your pattern.
So bite onto three.
Right now,
what I'm doing is simply green Audie dark substitute in place off your patterns Bite on our
fight on to our fight on three I want to replace with suppose Jay Don when you were given
string See,
that is a wherever fight on is there there were replacing but here it is not replacing
because it is a capital P.
Then I play flags to ignore your case sensitivity now all places it is replacing.
But the thing is,
it is not going to disturb your original string.
Be clear,
You know the strength properties.
So in that case,
in case if you want to store the result,
then you can take my new string.
I mean,
you can take any variable on in Vatican story.
No,
just a pretty.
You are new stream and see the result.
That's it,
right?
And if after your cone condiments you know how many places you want to replace.
Let moderately print by applying your count Calmed equals to Jiro.
See that put first.
There is no change when I But if you write Conte Kojiro are even if you skip that option.
County Costa Jiro.
But if you write county close to one,
see only the 1st 2 place where you are occurring.
Your pattern there is replacing with detente.
That's it.
But if right to see when I were afraid to do in two places replace my partner with the
required string.
This is your pattern on this is your required a string and replace with two places only.
That too,
from welcoming from left to right.
That is the difference.
We here and here it is replacing Not Then what about your substitute Ian operation?
You have one more operation,
right?
Nothing is that It's very simple.
Just let me run and see.
That is very it is going to show you your results.
As a couple,
I it is giving you a result of the string on here.
You're getting the value called to means in two places you are replacing anyway manually or
mentioning in two places replaced.
But you don't know in how many places you how you require pattern in a given string.
Just after that,
I'm going counter to you now,
wherever your pattern is there in all places,
you're going to replace with data.
But how many places you are you require partner and given string that it will do.
I'll see the results in four places.
Actually,
how you require pattern in a given string on it is replaced in four places with the J tone
.
That's it.
That's what it is giving.
So this value is not depending on your account value.
But if you write County Kazuto,
it will replace with only two.
That means you're going to get value to.
But if you don't use contraption in your substitute,
then in all the places it is going to replace,
But how many places it has been replaced?
That valley will be given by using substitute Ian operation off your body module.
That's it.
So,
guys,
these are the simple way to use your split sub shooter ends up shooting operations off the
model Very,
very useful.
Please try to do practice on this.
Okay,
guys,
thank you for watching this week