friends here.
We're going to discuss about some of these special characters off.
Fight on.
Right to explain this,
right.
I'm going to take one simple bite on program or pie Transcript.
Let me open my terminal first.
Okay,
I'm moving in tow.
Desktop there.
Actually have it that it recalled Python scripts.
So here I am going to read this fight on script name called Special Characters.
Not the way.
First,
I'm going to read one simple python program.
The purpose of that fight on program is simply toe print.
Are some information like,
welcome to buy conscripting.
Right.
I'm going to write that one.
Let me write it.
Bring well,
come toe bite on scripting.
So what you're doing is you are simply printing some string.
Okay,
so where nobody if you want to print the string using printed statement,
you hard to right?
You were string inside off quotation with your print night.
That's okay.
First,
let me save it.
And runny already.
We know how to run your python scripts like So this is your fight landscape.
I'm going to run our Bytom scrape in this way.
Yes.
You are getting somewhat put.
There's no I want to print output like,
um,
welcome to buy conscripting.
I'm in the next lane I want to write.
This is about special characters off your python.
So what?
I have to go.
I need to include one more line called right.
Let me write it one more lane.
So I want to print one more lame.
So I had to use one more prince statement.
So we are working with some special catic.
This That's it.
Let me say this on our planet before running,
just to see what is your core.
So this is your core.
You're having two lines off fight on script.
So those two lines are simply to bring some strings.
So whenever if you have a print simply,
it will print whatever they're inside off your quotations as off.
No.
Right.
Let me Donny.
Yes,
I'm going two lines off information.
So there's actually you are using immediately to print statements,
first line,
print second and print your printing information with the to print statements inter off
that I can use only one print statement.
I can also print this line.
I'm in this information by what I will do is so you know how to come in.
Bite on escaped lines You can skip.
You can come in any line.
No,
I don't want to run these two lines.
That's why I'm commenting.
Now I'm going to write one single prince set man in this way.
When it comes to fight on scripting,
then I'm writing.
We are working with Special CASS.
Yes,
this will also work.
And you will get your output.
Right?
So before getting output,
just observe.
You are skipped once.
Let me clear.
Ever screen.
Yeah,
this is your script output you're getting.
But my intention is I want to print this information in one line on this information next
line here,
actually reading board information,
the single line.
So at that time,
what I can do is weapon.
He was kept once from which information you want to print.
That information.
The next line just before that right slash n and save it,
right?
No,
this is your script.
We have only one.
Language is faster.
Two lines are commented.
That means your pie transcript won't eggs.
Good.
1st 2 lines.
No,
I'm running.
You're getting your butt in two lines.
No year slash and is especially character and it is called New Line.
So whenever if you include slash end after slash and whatever you're having that in four,
you will get in the next line like this.
Right?
So there's you're having some special characters.
Let me discuss at least some off them,
and we're going forward.
We'll discuss remaining things based on the requirements site.
So first thing,
special characters you have to write always your special characters inside off your
quotations,
right.
Special characters only inside off court that courts maybe single quotations,
huh?
Some double conditions.
You can use anyone off that right now.
Very 1st 1 What we are discussing is this is God New line night.
No,
let me go with the slash b and this is called backspace.
See how it is going to work.
So,
guys,
whatever you are having inside off your skip that thing,
you can also run from your fight on shell.
Just simply type on your command line,
python,
and then you will enter into your potential.
Let me copy this line and based it on your fight on common line or potential.
Onder said output.
Right now from here,
I'm explaining your special characters So what?
I'm going to type yet.
Same thing you can write into one file and they can execute.
I mean,
you can create one bite on.
Script on you can excluded.
Let me print simply.
Hello,
Lawyer.
You're getting some old put?
No,
no one I'm doing is just before you were or I'm reading slash b and c the output.
There is no space between your two words,
right?
The reason is slash b will send your car circulation back.
One creation back.
That's why after hello,
actually,
you have a space,
right?
That space will be removed because your custody is coming back.
One question that is the purpose.
Off slash b So you for right co two slash base,
right,
Because off one slash b,
your cursor will come back One position on 2nd 1 more question back.
See,
that boy is missing.
It's actually first.
Your python will type Hello After that,
because of this slash b,
your customer will come to this situation again.
One more slash b Because of that,
you're Kirsten will come to this war operation and from there onwards you were next world
will type if reid three slash beasts see that put So your customer will come back.
Three poison questions.
And from there it will try to override your existing information with the new information.
Whatever it is they're after.
It was last beasts.
Right?
So that is that slash b No peace lasted.
You know that.
What is the purpose of Tab?
Right.
Let me show you that.
Here it's very simple.
So we told her time.
What is the airport on with the type of what is door poor?
Just you're providing time,
space and note.
But that's it.
Like fine Mexican.
See,
I suppose I want to print information like this print by daunts class.
Something like there.
Yes,
it's working perfectly,
right?
No,
First after this one.
So in your prince statements,
you can also use injured off double condition.
You can also use single quotations.
Nobody will work.
But in this case,
if I tried to write pythons,
you'll get done.
Syntax er involves index you're getting the reason is so drink.
You are printing some string string should be there inside off your quotation.
Actually,
we're Brighton will take the starting quotation on these.
The an inclination.
Then what about this information So now what do you want to do?
Is this is starting quotation on?
This is an inclination on the RB escape here.
Fight your fight on should not consider this as a quotation Single quotation there.
In that case,
you have to write a slash escape symbol slash now because of that,
what it will do is your python simply will skip this as a quotation.
It will take this as a some letter some character and it will preserve in output.
Sit output No,
it is not like a quotation.
It is like other than Kardashian some character like Fine not only there Sometimes Yard
writes doubles.
This is a by dawn class and you want to write fight on in double conditions.
So you know this is starting on.
This is ending but between If you have any quotations right?
You can escape from that simply as of now you run,
you will get an Earless I mean an invalid syntax.
You will get only starting on ending condition He's 41 string in.
Really?
If you get any quotations you are to escape from the purpose off your conditions Other time
yacht read simply slash So that you are quotations will be considered as any character
other than your quotations.
No,
See that?
Thank you.
No slashes for escape.
Symbol.
Okay,
then.
But we know one thing.
So I will do one thing Ice.
Let me go with my desktop.
It may be any any for lead.
So here what I'm doing is I'm creating a new folder.
Call new itself.
Right.
So I'm going to create something new.
Then what is the part off this?
So this is the part,
right?
Let me print this part with your bite on,
because that is a string.
I can print it.
But see that?
Good.
What?
You're getting right.
See growth whenever.
If you're providing,
you were part in your world.
Fight on that too.
Only with no spot.
Because in windows you how this backwards lash.
But whereas in length,
you know,
forward slash.
So this is the problem already.
We know this is lashes for our escape symbol purpose.
But in your python,
I mean in the path in windows part,
you have that symbol right now you have to escape from that symbol.
So actually,
you know we escaped from any character you're using escape symbol.
This is slash in your python the same way you can use in your python windows part also in
this way.
But simply remember that whenever if you're providing with no spot,
you have to write to two slashes manually.
If your python skip is going to find any part of true logic you don't,
Father,
you know nobody.
But if you're profiting manually,
some windows part.
We're working with your pipe landscapes.
There you are to write to slashes in your pot.
Then only it will work.
Right?
So this is very,
very important,
guys,
those who are working python for windows.
Okay,
if you are working with your nose using python So whenever if your entering part manually,
we know spot only with no spot.
There is no problem with the UNIX systems parts.
They're injured off.
Single,
flashy,
hard to provide double slashes.
Right.
Okay,
so there is.
There is.
There are some other symbols as well.
Like slash a repeat and alert.
Sound alert.
Sound right.
Okay,
so we have some more things were going forward,
will discuss some off other special characters as well.
So,
for time being,
you had to know this minimum special characters to work with your fighter,
right?
Okay.
Thank you for watching this video.