prince here.
Our concept Please compile operation or matter off or remodel.
See,
we know that we have different types off operations in your body model.
Let me go with some off them s so that I can explain the uses off campaign operation.
Suppose our house some string here.
No,
I need to write a pattern.
Such there.
I want boo.
Fine.
Uh,
by Tony.
Is there any given string or not?
Then just let me write apartment.
Suppose first I will go and work with the final operation.
Ah,
how many Beytin or there?
In a given string?
So for that I am writing is simply a partner So that first time writing simply fight on.
But I want to look for a word.
Then you had to,
right?
With slash B starting on ending than exactly word matching.
Now first,
let me simply print or your daughter find all from your pattern in a given string.
How many?
Matching czar there See,
that is a We're getting only one bite on.
But how here Python on here also fight on anywhere These are bite onto on by country No
blow.
So here capital P in your small p.
Then you can write in two ways to identify this.
Small people Eitan Cattle be bite under days If you write in square brackets,
very first character,
it may be small,
pure capital p no see.
The results are injured after inch of that.
Suppose if you don't want to.
Custer a boat case sensitivity.
Simply connect a flat here.
If you remember,
there is option called flags.
Simply right or not,
I now see the result.
You're going to get fight on small and capital now.
Along with that,
I need to identify,
Bite onto or python three.
Also,
then Ardian two or three is optional.
Right then there is a question work.
So the question mark meaning is either two or three,
maybe once or none.
That is the meaning off your question.
More see,
we already discussed aboard the rules to create your patterns in our previous videos,
right?
So based on that,
I'm creating this pattern.
That's fine.
Now let me run decency.
The result.
Now you're going to get fight on Capitol.
People turn by turn toe turnpike country.
That is the uses off patrons.
Actually,
I'm in brackets,
regular expressions.
That's fine.
No suppose I'm using different operations on my same pattern.
Suppose I'm using already darts.
Such your partner,
then in a given string.
So what is your given string?
This one?
No.
See the result?
You're getting some object?
Yes,
there is a match.
So if there is a match,
then you can look for the were required.
Ah,
I mean,
what is the match?
And very start matching creation According to give instinct.
You can go with that.
Like start in the group.
Right?
We have those operations.
That's fine.
No,
let me do one more operation.
So I want to print.
I want to split to my given string based on my pattern.
So what is my pattern?
So normally annuals things.
You have a spirit operation.
If you go with that,
it can able to split the or given sting based on one single string.
But here I'm going to divide my given string based on either python or capital beep Eitan
or python to our fight country.
Simply wherever these four words are there in a given string,
their split will happen.
So that is a uses off split from your regular expression.
Now let me write your string and see that is a yes so like ways you can use There were
different operations,
right?
But here suppose sometimes you're going to use same patron multiple times in your given
core.
I mean,
what are the core?
Your writing in your core?
You're going to use your pattern.
But the pattern you how that pattern you are going to use multiple times.
So whenever,
if we're using multiple times in giraffe using in this way we are going with compile
operation first either court politic and understand that I would like you once again.
No,
I'm creating.
I had an object battle object nothing.
Is there simply already dot com pile Whatever the pattern,
you how touch it.
Now,
if you print your pattern opposite,
foresee the reason what happened?
Study Spelling mistake.
You'll see that you are getting a pattern that in terms off object.
Now this is a object not like simply your fight on something like that.
Your python is converting.
Now your pattern do an object?
No,
on this object.
Instead of performing your operations in this way,
our radar start started out.
Final orders split or whatever the operation.
You how in self there directly.
You can perform your operation on this object.
See that my sorry pattern lobs it.
Bring supposed patron object dot your operation then only string because already pattern is
that in this object only string You want string now see the result Whatever the output
Previously you guard same or pretty or getting here Let me enable your previous all put we
thought to compile operation whatever the way we're using to use such is there any
difference between these two?
First are putting last or put there is no difference.
But while comparing first procedure I'm in 60 lane syntax You were 13 times having more
efficiency.
So speed off operation is very high for you Simply pattern objects not only for that you
can use all operations Now let me this a believer Normal direct operations Now I'm using
you can use for each and every operation You can use this pattern object Brighton object
not find all Then simply you will string What is the string?
The only pattern is there in this object gaze.
So now this partner object is supporting to perform your all regular expressions without
any ari model See that previously to perform your operations,
you're using already dark.
But now we're using pattern up there dot So already inside of this pattern upset you're
already is there on your compile pattern is also there undoubtedly were doing or oppression
on that.
So that is a Brighton object.
Find all python.
What happened?
Where is it?
Yeah,
see that Previously used you we use ignore case sensitivity Now in compile operation,
you can also use flags Then only you can get your remaining fight owns because we are
looking for cattle P right?
No,
see there flags equals two r e not I.
So company operation on method is also supporting flags operations Now see the result.
That's it.
So this,
I think,
is that Let me right there on simple Suppose if you're using already dot Find all you are
part on then your string This we are doing in this way already dot Compile you are part run
dot final This is exactly of course,
with this thing I mean any operation you can come back in this way So I did not find on now
we are doing our dot com pale.
First we're creating an object using your patterns on the doctor were performing or
operation.
You can also start.
These are put into some variable.
That's what I did,
right?
Nothing is there.
Most of the people will get confusion.
Why?
We need to use compile operation?
Simple Whenever.
If you're using same pattern in different places in your court,
then enough In that way,
Just try toe.
Come by your object title Create,
Compile Object first under doctor He just tried to bear from your record operation that in
this way so that your court is efficient.
A spinoff Operations height.
I have done that nothing.
Is that okay?
Okay,
guys,
thank you for watching this with you.