friends here.
Our concept is working with remote Lennox,
our work from Lennox or Windows as your local host by using para Mike off python.
See,
you're having one remote server and there is a line,
except when you are having a local server and this local server,
maybe windows are maybe Lennox.
And from here I need to walk with your remorse,
our world by using pattern Michael off python,
right?
This is our concept of year.
But before going to work with that,
let me do some introduction to your partner Michael Model.
The first ofall para Michael is your fight on model or library,
which is useful to work with the world remote servers See working with your remote servers
.
Meat.
Sometimes you need to excuse some comments on your reward server.
We thought logging into that from your local server or sometimes injured transferring file
from locals are over to a remote server.
Are are sometimes you don't know they filed from remorse over to locals.
So all these actions we can perform with help off bite on para Michael model.
But before going to use that,
you should have a Asus such or s a set you free to protocol on your local server are simply
from where you're running your fight on for their usual.
How?
Under the operating system issued out as a sexually do protocol.
That's it.
Sundays.
We know that by default we have such a protocol on you are indexed like systems.
If your local salaries were knows unity,
check 40.
What?
Ssh!
If it is not very hard to install it,
right,
that's fine.
Then how it is going to work,
how you are quite right on Part of my committee is going to work.
See your pal bite on para Michael.
Model is going to create a static line first,
with all popular as a such A to protocol,
I'm in a century to protocol on by using that it is going toe connect with your the more
servers and it is going to work.
Working means excluding command.
Son,
Transferring face.
That's fine.
No,
for authentication purpose.
Your partner Michael is using two ways one is using.
Use a name one passport earn 2nd 1 is using user name or we were keys.
I mean,
user name on the work ease on days.
Finally,
the last point for your indirection is we can connect from lie next to Lennox Orland,
Extra windows or windows to Lennox are windows to windows using your pattern Michael model
.
So we have four combinations,
right?
Let me write all combinations here.
Suppose local.
Let me right here.
In this way,
locals are were.
Then you were remorse or words.
So locals ever maybe Windows and you were remote.
Server left.
You let me do all the commission windows,
servers or local surgeries.
Windows on remote servers.
Maybe line.
Except for us.
No local server.
Maybe Lennox.
Windows server,
maybe Lennox.
Or it is line X on windows remorse over his windows.
So these four combination will works with your part of Michael model on here.
For time being,
we are going to work with by conserving your local Sarfaraz windows or land X on your
remorse Surgeries only Lennox.
Right?
So first I'm going toe cancer local server.
As Lennox,
the mortar also links.
Second will work by conserving local as windows and remorse are Islamics.
That's fine.
No,
guys,
before going to use your para Michael,
The first thing is you should have a sausage on your local host.
Let me check.
Suppose this is my locals are were Ah,
from my remember like many more.
This fine.
I'll see yet?
Yes,
I have a message then.
No problem.
We have a message.
Then we can work with your pipes on Para Michael on one more thing.
Just check it whether we help out on my core north.
So,
you know,
help out of Michael.
Anyway,
this is not not the default model.
So if it is not there on your horse than unity installed say,
let me show you on my windows support.
See,
I tried to import para Michael here.
There is no name.
Calm bottom,
EKO.
I mean no model named Marimekko.
Then That's why what I did here is simply I installed with help off Pip Pip,
install paramedical.
Same thing you can follow on your landing system as well to install.
What better,
Michael?
That's fine.
So offer in selling my importer,
then there is no era.
That's fine.
So if it is not there,
you had to install you.
What part of Michael model.
So I'm giving you simply hear steps,
Pip,
install para my cope to install your para Michael model.
That's fine.
then.
Second thing is how you are.
Yeah.
So let me start with the court to use your power,
Michael,
to work with your remorse hours.
Let me write a simple core here.
Sorry.
Not this is this is my local server.
Let me exit from here working with the more Lennox.
Maybe any server remorse that actually any so even work with any remorse or work?
Of course.
More timing.
We are went to work with only remorse.
Auroras Lennox.
Yeah,
One more thing.
Let me take,
uh,
my bite on pot.
See that?
The very first thing unity,
important part of my co model.
That's fine.
So after that,
you're para Michael is going to work with the remorse,
or worse,
by creating a claim.
Actually,
we need to create that climb.
So to create your client,
this is the syntax.
So here.
Nice.
I will do all these steps on the bill off the serial.
Then you can go with that and you can practice.
So this is simply any variable,
but this is your client s a search plane.
Simply You can assume associates off your operating system now.
I creator from Baron my CO.
This s a static line.
Be clear.
This is a variable.
You can take any name,
but I'll get our take insurable name.
So after that,
let me try Toe carried with my remote server.
Soto can it with your remote,
sir,
where we have a syntax core.
I mean,
anywhere we have to procedures when he's using user name and password.
2nd 1 is using user name one kiss.
So for timing,
for time being,
I'm going to use user name and password.
So let me take my remorse or host name first.
So good.
These are syntax simply as a sage.
Not connect.
You're remorse.
Our host name with what user And what is the password on?
By default,
it is going to use port only do only you no need to mention.
But if you want to mention you can mention it No,
Let me open my remote server.
So for this remorse or what?
This is a public I p no,
I mean host name.
You can also mention in your real time f Korean name off your server.
That's fine.
User name is this one and I have given already password us But I'm Michael 123 I think.
Let me check it.
Our Michael.
123 Let me save it underneath this.
So before going to run,
let me property execution permission Because we are online X.
See that you're getting another called para my code.
Or as a such exceptions,
Andi,
if you have very here not phone in known host,
see whenever If you try to connect with any remorse of what?
Using your restaurants that very first time.
So let me show you.
That is a such so.
But this is my course name.
See,
it is going to ask yes or no permission,
right so manually in New York and bring here but in pipelines could We are not entering
that Yes or no option.
If you say yes,
then only can,
can it?
If you say no,
you are Windows A No.
If you don't want to ask this right in your shur,
providing some stick to host to keep checking as no right.
But in spite on how we can aware that taking this whole sticky ticking right symbol you
know,
Darda on our policy tow away that I don't want to check yes or no confirmation by default.
I want to work with that given server.
So for that,
you need to ard this line before going toe current with your remote server.
That's it,
right?
No,
you fight one days.
you're not going to get any better.
Just let me run this and see the reserved.
That's it.
You're not getting in error means.
And now you're Skip.
Has bean connected with you?
I mean,
true Skip,
You have been connected with your remote server,
this server.
So,
guys,
the connection.
Whatever the connection you established with your remorse,
sir,
Where will be there with this?
Ssh object only not to exclude any commands or to transfer a file for all those things.
You have to use this.
Ssh.
Now,
let me use this toe.
Exclude some comments so simply to exclude your commands.
He hard to write a society dot Yeah.
One more thing you can,
right?
I mean,
you can exclude any common here yet you see,
execute.
Come on.
But before that,
if you are running some commands on your remorse that were sometimes you may need some
input to provide that I'm in tow to provide input for that command.
are some.
Forget a body.
Ah,
board input.
Sometimes you're going to get such a southport.
Sometimes you're going to get better or put well running your common while excluding your
command only what remote server that for here we're having to exclude our command Is the
syntax you can take any?
Come,
I suppose I'm running to gaze.
I am using ssh to execute our commands on your remote server.
Right on.
If you have dirty here,
this command I mean,
after running this command,
you may get some success off if you got success that is going to store into this variable
If you get another by learning this command that are put with store into this If you get
output original empty if you get better.
Artisanal,
then what is the use off this STD in?
See why learning your commands on your remote server Sometimes that come and may need input
.
Let's say you're running some pseudo comer and so combined.
Sometimes you need pass.
Were that possible?
We can provide with help off STD in.
Okay,
So working with the STD and we will see in the letter videos as off.
No,
I'm goingto take only s to the older near Syria,
I think is that I'm running my command in this way.
Then let me reinforce Very simple common.
Suppose I want to get who I'm my first.
Let me do invalid.
Come in.
Right.
So you actually,
my intention is I'm trying to cow find with water user reconnected We know that we can
agree with this user.
Only that are But actually we are expecting.
But these invalid command that's what you're going to get another that there will be there
in this on these two STD openess to the in,
they are like file objects.
So if you know if you remember how to read a content from file object by using dot read or
don't read lines,
let me write first.
The output is in case if you have it or put on let me bring the arteries.
No,
I'm going to print a year.
The success or putting?
Guess if we if we how that out s to the old daughter three.
Then in case if you get an error error that we're going to print here STD error or not read
.
Let me save it and let me run this.
See the output?
What happened in better discern backs brained Astrid Arabia?
We have gone one extra parent assists.
I think.
No,
it's fine.
See output?
You're getting an empty.
But every are getting something because the common whatever we have given that is invalid.
Common.
That's what he's saying.
Come and not for what We're getting another.
And if you after you're also getting an empty empty line because this is the file content,
right?
If you really file content by the fall for each and every line at the end,
you have a slash in.
So for this line,
also,
you're having at the insulation that we're getting this.
Now you can do something not only really can also write read lines information,
but if you remember while working with files ah,
read lines is a list off values.
I mean simply,
you are filed.
Content will be converted into number off by losing your list.
Each lane is a one value in what list not see that slashing is there by any,
but that's fine.
Based on your requirement,
you can go with the read or read lines.
Now let me you a valued common Let's say who are my who?
I know this is a valid command,
right?
No.
See the result?
Yes,
you do,
User.
But our parties I'm in error but is empty because you got success or Bertoia.
Raise Mt.
Right.
Let's forget about input.
STD in.
But syntax is yard to use.
A steady income.
My sturdy old common yesterday era.
That's fine.
Now let me run one more common.
You condone any common?
Let me come in this Let me write same syntax.
Suppose I am running.
Let's say up time.
Say we don't money and see the result.
Not so right.
So not only that.
Let me exclude one more thing like free hyphen e Um see the result?
That's it,
right?
You know what you are getting here?
OK,
history out.
Read line,
not lines.
Right?
So that's why you gotta I mean,
you're not getting perfect output read lines.
He's going to do all the lines from your content.
So previously I use only read line,
No cedar tree lines.
You're going to get complete or put for You were free iPhone.
Yeah,
that's fine.
So there's There's a simple way to exclude your comments on your remote server on.
But here we are using user name and password on one more thing.
Our local salaries Lennox.
And the more stories also Lennox.
Now let me execute same thing with the help off Keys.
First let me coming.
This Ah,
working with the world user name and password.
So if you want to work with key is very simple fasting These the syntax,
right?
Simply your host name,
user name and password were going to use key file name then port.
That is your wish.
If you want to use,
you can use it other ways.
You can also skip that.
No problem on one more thing.
What is this?
T from where you can get this team right?
See there so you can create your keys using message are you can extend your key then the
private key party Hard to mention in this fight.
I mean in your court a private If I lay me how to mention here,
let me do one day I'm going to do door message.
Oh,
let me No no files here.
Right.
Let me create some keys.
Ssh!
Ivan Ke Jin!
So I'm going to create my a such key values.
I'm in key pates.
See that we help Private key and public.
First we had to share this.
Give with your Suppose you are remote server.
Let me share that with my remote server.
Ah,
What is that?
A morsel?
Right?
Be that may get it on.
Be clear here.
I'm sharing with easy to user.
Easy to use that I'm getting my key now is your to hyphen user.
Sorry.
What is a possible we given for that Baron?
My co 123 That's you.
Now what is your private key?
This is your private key in this part.
We help your private key simply right now this file we have to use in our court that's it.
So in guest by the for it Anyway,
you are having now possible list authentication.
You can use it,
but if you want to use key not just for your key filing partier completely.
If your keys there in the current location directly going right there were only key name.
That's it.
No,
Let me see it on granite.
Be clear now we're using user name one.
You are cryptographic key.
It's a safe private key,
right?
Now let me run and see that reserve.
What happened?
Authentication fail.
Oh,
I'm using answered.
Mean user.
That's not correct.
Yeah,
he was.
Her name is easy to use with easy to use are we extended our key,
right?
So be clear about user and your keys.
Yeah.
Now let me run this and see there is a That's it.
So,
guys,
this is the way how we can work with user name and password on how we can work with your
ssh keys using your partner Michael.
Okay,
I will share this key in the bill off this video just to go through that and just know we
work with the Lennox with Lennox.
Now My requirement is I want to work from my local server from my locals are as windows.
Let's say this is my windows are all right.
Now let me write a new court on my Windows server.
Save it.
Ah,
some key.
Some script name is working with the more line X from windows.
Don't be white on.
Before going to work with that,
you had to check it.
Be how message?
Yes,
on my windows.
I already installed message.
If it is that.
Okay,
If it is not there,
please install them first.
Right,
Then offer that.
Let me take step by step.
We know we are already having.
First we need to install.
We need to install Para Michael.
Then we are very important in our court.
Then when he tired,
we need to create a society client then on toe our policy buddy,
Just know I added order our policy.
Just tow away.
That's are no confirmation like that.
Right?
Then after that you need to connect with your server.
Soto candid with your server These listen backs as a such cannot your host name.
Maybe this is host new.
Let me very fight 3 92 Yeah.
Post name then user name is as off.
No,
we're having over user name.
As is it wife on user Then we're not using key filing.
So what we are using we're using simply password.
Right?
So what is a boss Ford?
Did we mention here?
No.
Yeah.
What's where is para my co want to treat?
Save it their first.
Let me on this.
If it is fine,
it won't do any exception.
Yeah,
it's fine.
That's right.
It has been excluded without any edits?
No,
I want to exclude some common.
Any command you can execute on your remote server.
So,
guys,
now I'm working with from my local server.
Yes.
Yeah.
Let me printed output.
Then only you can see the output.
Right?
Estili Outdoor.
Sorry about STD.
Other STD,
oh dot Reid,
maybe read lines.
That's fine not to You're getting your output right?
That's fine.
No,
on the loose.
I mean,
from my local sour as windows.
I counter with my remote Servalan X,
and I excluder some comer with the user name on password.
Now,
if you want to walk with some keys Yes,
You can also generate your keys on your local server the same way how we work around line X
server in Lenox.
Over.
I generally some keys and I shared with my remorse harbor on I then use this.
Is this very the same way on windows?
Also,
you can gender your keys and you can work with your remote server from your locals.
Our house windows.
That's it.
Nice.
Not only this.
This is just a basic a way to exclude your commands on your remote server.
But while working with your remorse or words,
you'll get different exceptions.
I need to handle all off them.
So how to?
Honey will discuss in later videos on how to transfer files from your local server to
Windows service.
All those things were going to discussing.
Let our use Okay.
Okay.
Yeah.
OK,
guys,
Thank you for watching this video.