friends here are concept please.
Introduction toe.
Oops.
See,
Basically Piketon is supporting for both procedural and object Winter programming concepts
.
Suppose if you implement any court in terms off functions then we can say that we are
falling Procedural Were injured Programming concept on We already done this in our previous
who use.
Now here our concentration is on Oops.
Then what is on hopes or what is an object oriented programming concert?
So it is all about uses off class observed inheritance polymorphism data obstruction on
data encapsulation See suppose if you're new to programming or hopes concert then you will
get confused about all these times Nobody you know where to remember.
All these things will go with the best up so that it will get idea on each and every time
or on each and every concert in your hopes.
But for time being,
just remember that Oh,
please All about uses off class and object.
That's it.
Simply hopes is the combination of classes on objects.
That's it on the very first important point in your hopes.
Concert,
please.
We are using hopes concepto create an object Then what is an object?
See?
Object Could be anything which exist in real time like human fan core,
mobile laptop,
most keyboard or any application.
Ah Jenkins,
Vlasic Tomcat,
Apache on Docker.
Anything on docker parts?
Anything you can take as an object.
The only thing is,
if you take anything as an object,
it should exist in real time.
That's it.
And if you go with any object,
eat off.
It has some characteristics and functions.
Let's say human or person as an object.
Then we can say that characteristics are like name is hide.
Color on functions are like walking,
talking on running right,
not only human you can take.
Suppose a party as an object support.
If I take a party as an object than I can say,
character sticks off about your like abortion configuration file off party.
But is that really pretty dot com on functions?
I can say,
I suppose you know about He is usedto so some static bridges that I can plead as a function
.
But don't worry.
You don't need to remember about characteristics and functions.
My default.
Why lighting your core?
You will come to know what you are to take a character sticks and what you have to write a
function.
Nothing is there.
Actually,
characteristics are like attributes are variables and functions,
you know,
to implement some logic.
We're using functions.
That's it.
But I don't remember.
Even this characteristic can functions for your object.
So here you have to remember that object is something which exist in real time.
That's it,
right?
So why We are using hopes.
The first thing is we are using Oops,
concepto create an absurd Then why we need to create an object.
What is the purpose?
They let me give you the very first point That is very,
very useful.
That is the group related functions.
The group related functions.
Why we need to group the little functions.
I think you an example.
Just as you know that you are having to applications in your court.
I mean,
let's say you're having somewhere publication.
So anyway,
of obligation,
you're having to APS let up one on the and in your core for up one you define 100 functions
just for logic,
implement on for up to also you implement their 100 functions.
So this is for apple one and this is these are four upto so totally we're having 200
functions.
Totally.
We're having 200 functions.
Just observe their in my logic.
Somewhere I am calling up to I put to you have to function then how your python is going to
exclude.
Actually,
whenever if I call this function up,
we have to function.
Then it has to call.
So the Abdul let's 100 function inapt So I want to call 100 function.
Then your partner has to call this last function.
But how your python is going to exclude that how it is going toe pick this function
whenever if we call in this way So that's what I'm saying is let me right here so that he
will get some idea See,
I'm having Tuapse in my court Then I am implementing AP one function one like waste I'm
implementing 100 functions for my app One apple,
one 100 functions the same Be how up to functions in my court Let's a function one for up
to like ways I defined up to yes 100 function 100 function So finally how many functions?
I'm having 200 functions in my court,
so I'm having 200 functions in my core earn somewhere in my court.
I'm calling up to 100 function.
Just I'm calling somewhere in my court this function then how your python is going to
exclude that.
So actually you're having he had 100 functions on here 100 functions so totally you're
having 200 functions in your core.
Big,
clear.
So when nobody if I call dysfunction,
how your python is going to execute are actually whenever if I call this function you have
to exclude this But how you're fighting is going to exclude It will take this function name
and we'll come back with very first function anywhere.
There is no match.
That's right.
We'll skip that So first check is filed Then we'll check with second function failed Check
with Likewise,
it will check 200 chicks in 200 check There is a map.
That's why it is going to explode This function now simply We exclude this function your
bite unease doing 200 chicks,
right?
So instead of that what I am doing his Let me go in this way I am defining these 100
functions for up one.
I'm giving some name Call up one under that I'm defining under functions.
Let's say for up to also I'm defending the name call up to I mean,
I'm creating two separate blocks in up one block I'm having under functions and in upto I'm
having 100 functions right now.
Let me remove this Just assumption,
Grace.
So that really good idea.
Now I am calling Apple 200 function Then how your python is going to exclude previously to
exclude this airport to function after 200 function you're fightin done 200 ticks right now
How it is going to check whenever If you have a block concept in your court under block I'm
defending 100 functions here.
Under this block,
I define 100 functions,
so I never If you have a block concept here how your pie Tony's going to exclude your
function so fast you will take the first apart.
What is that up to with up to it will check here and what this check is for.
That's why it will skip all these functions Boutique So then it is coming to hear up to Yes
,
there is a map with up to upto Now you're fighting I will try to exclude your function by
comparing in this block so that you are skipping.
Suppose 100 checks here,
Right?
So previously you're having 200 checks to exclude your function.
But now we're having only one,
not two ticks.
So one tiki's combating the up to with the block one that is fail one check,
then upto that is success.
Second check,
then to exclude your way of 100 function in block two.
We need 100 chicks anyway.
Come back to your previous procedure.
Now we reduce 98 ticks that isn't wanted for his right spirit is high.
Come back to that now.
Writing your core in terms off a block is called simply abs like that.
Writing your court in terms off block is called an object.
But anyway,
this is not perfect.
I will give that diddle structure So no,
you you got to know that oops is useful group related functions so that you are going to
save some time while excluding your core.
Then second thing is to create a template or blueprint.
What is this?
We know generally what is midway template?
Just a junior.
There is some industry right on.
It is going to give some findings.
Just a gender.
There are four members.
They are interested to giant in this instruct for some courses.
Right?
But what these four members are ready to join,
then this institute,
will you Some forms toe collect the data about this information about these four students.
So what they will do?
Let's say this is rent one,
Sorrento and store and three thence to rent for.
Then they will give you a form.
For this.
They are going to give one form first round,
172 rounds two and three,
then store.
And for then Sorrento,
one will fill the data here,
throwing to fill a data.
Here's two and three Philadelphia here to run for from the data here.
But if you observe here actually they're having one word.
Your template.
They're having one marginal template.
So from this template there taking a direct scope your printout on that printer they're
sharing so that the work is easy for this insurance.
No,
student Vince,
rent one from their data like name is address untested course so intemperate.
If you are like fill the name here,
then age here,
then suppose address than industrial courses.
Yes,
I assume that there are pretty different temperate is there.
I'm giving this tempter to each and every one so that I can get the date off.
These four students very easily.
Suppose you figure empty,
empty form.
Then the injured guy has to tell.
Please fill Your name is rolling something like address on industrial courses.
But instead of that,
if the injured guy has some template,
then it is very easy to collect the data aboard students.
Right.
So now that template is called simply Brugge blueprint.
So from their template,
we are getting the information about your students.
Not only this four story and suppose tomorrow 400 members are ready to join.
Then what these guys will do,
the insured guy will go simply.
They will take 100 printouts off the template,
whatever they're having on this 100 templates,
they're going to distribute for each and everyone so that they can collect the information
about hundreds friends very easily.
Right now,
in our hopes,
concept template is nothing.
But a class template is nothing but a class from the template.
You can create any number off objects from that template.
You can create any number off objects very easily.
Right now,
I will explain this with a simple example so that you can get idea on hopes concert.
Just wait.
And one more thing.
Finally,
you can say that Oops is a concert where character sticks and functions off.
Real life object is packaged as a single entity in the court.
Just know we have seen previously,
right?
I mean,
the group little functions were giving some name for functions are simply we are grouping
our functions under one name so that there isn't one days.
Well,
excluding your core,
right?
See,
just assume that let me given name us.
I'm in script name,
working with hopes,
not people.
Just as you know,
gays just agenda on my host.
There are two parties are running may be any number of our budgets,
No problem.
But initially just dogo toe Give some idea.
I am assuming that on my server that our to our party start running.
Just simply assume that so if to our bodies are our name.
If you want implement a court you know to clear two objects.
So if you observe if you previously we have seen right how we're creating objects from
template from template.
See that?
So there's anybody if you're writing a court in terms off,
Oops!
On one more thing.
Basically,
this oops concept is very,
very important for application development or up development side for automation side.
You can write your court without roots concept also.
But if you go with hopes concert,
then you can invite your court.
I mean efecto Corrigan,
right?
Right,
fine.
So that's what I am saying is just agenda on the words are were to a party.
Sarun.
Let's say Tomcat,
anything you can take.
Let's I'm taking in this way in my core to Tom gets are running right.
See how I'm going to implement my court.
So I suppose if you're surgeries ah,
you next box and then I can say being piped on.
Then I can start my court in this way,
right?
You know what is the use is off this underscoring the school name.
Underscore Underscore May right then definition means Let's see.
No,
let's say Ah how suppose Tomcat seven.
Somewhere in my location whom let's say,
some automation user under that we help Tomcat seven in their their do you how some corn
for directory under 30.
How some sorrow dot xml fight So why I am taking several XML means if you go with Tom,
get the main conflagration.
Finally start xml the same way.
Just assume that I'm having one more time Got on my server night those same values,
but accept seven.
This is nine.
So that is well going forward.
We can also write it.
Well,
we'll also write a court automatically to identify how many Tomcats are running on your
host,
but for timing.
I'm taking to Tom Cares just I'm assuming on my server too.
Damn.
Got some funding.
That's fine.
No,
actually,
my intention is how'd radiologic I had to write a logic just to display?
Don't get configuration file on Tomcat home.
So already how taken Tomcat conflagration Fairly disease.
Okay,
on if you know about Tom Care disease called Simply Tomcat whom Only after this part we can
say that is a tomcat home.
Because under this,
we're having every files.
I mean,
the files which are later for your tomcat.
So for Tomcat seven,
this is the home for time.
Get nine.
This is the home.
Now my requirement is simply I need to display Tomcat.
Seven conflict files Tomcat nine conflict file on Tomcat.
Seven home,
Tom,
Get nine.
Home,
right?
That it liken display.
But I want to implement this court first in terms off functions.
Then I will try to convert in terms off.
Oops,
or you'll get idea.
Okay,
so just wait.
So what I'm doing is Tomcat 70 deals other ways.
What?
I will lease.
Get the details for each Domke each Tom care.
Let me pause.
Tomcat seven here.
The same way.
I need to get details for H.
Tomcat.
Tomcat online.
Nazi.
Right.
So finally,
I am doing return?
None?
No.
Here I am reading a function,
So I need a waste model.
Here,
let me import that.
So after that,
what I'm doing is I'm defending a function called Get guys.
Let me right.
That might take function.
Name on whatever you're passing,
that is configuration file.
So that is like Celebrex and Milan.
Dickens,
however,
underscore XML.
That's fine.
So know what I'm doing this first off,
all I'm finding Oh,
Tomcat Conflagration file variable.
It is nothing but directly.
Ghana's you,
your several xml,
then I'm finding Tomcat home.
It is nothing,
but where's dot part Gordillo?
Your name off your Sarwar XML file.
But if I do this operation,
you're going to get up to con.
But I end up put Tomcat seven.
If you come back to levels back in configuration file,
then you're going to get Tom,
get home.
So I need to play one more time ways dot Part door dear.
Your name already?
We've done this in our previous videos.
That's it.
Right on here.
If you want to display your information directly,
can display.
So I am writing the Tomcat config file is so simply here I am writing TCF off.
Tom,
Get conflagration five on and then I need to display Tomcat home as well.
Right?
So the Tomcat home is so here I am displaying Tomcat home.
That's it.
So finally,
I'm returning with the non value.
That's it.
Let me run the score.
What happened?
Norte Beauty A our name directory name.
My important right.
Empty pot.
Where is their data?
That's fine ways dot pop dirty your name ways not Paul.
Dirty air name.
Um,
what happened here?
Let me under into my bite on import ways.
The a r way's not what dot Let me write and see the options.
It is there?
No,
the i r name and a spelling mistake.
No ways.
Not part dot The name Saudi.
He s ballistic.
That's fine.
No,
See the result you're getting that would put for your first tomcat.
I'm in Tomcat seven and Tom got nine.
But here,
if you observe in the same function,
I am finding my conflagration file on Tomcat home on also,
I'm displaying.
But I want to display the information using other function.
Then what?
I am doing his then I am writing display details.
That's it.
Okay,
Now,
if I run this anywhere you're not calling,
let me call that.
So after getting details for Tomcat seven,
I'm trying to display the details for that.
So simply did display ladles on bomb,
Got seven display details.
But if I run this,
you're going to get an error.
That is TCF is not defined.
So you know in your functions concert Be clear.
It is very,
very important in your normal functions.
Concert?
If we define any variable inside off one function,
then you cannot access that inside off other function.
The reason is when you nobody for different any variable by default that is local toe that
function now.
I want to access in this function than water.
How to do I need to make it does global.
You were two variables TCF i th I need to make it as a global.
Now I can able to get your values right.
That's fine.
What I am doing is I'm removing these two functions to display or details.
First I'm calling.
You are getting details for each Tomcat,
Tomcat seven and Tomcat nine.
So,
after this,
I am calling display details.
I'm calling to times.
What is the result?
You're going to get both the times you're going to get Tom get 90 days,
then very storm cut.
Seven.
So that is the problem with your normal functions concept.
See whenever if you call if you call.
You were get details for Tom.
Got seven.
Your coming here on your getting your variables call you call a variable called TCF one th
because often 17th lane,
you're going to exclude this function on offer eggs gush.
Excluding this function in your variable school TCF one pH you're having values for Tom.
Get seven.
That's fine.
Then immediately are calling Tomcat nine also.
Then whenever If you call.
Then you were coming the same functional.
You're going to overwrite or relight new values for your TCF.
One pitch,
right?
Then you were world values gone,
Tom.
Get sound information gone then to capture your tomcat.
Seven details before calling Tomcat nine.
You want to return your Tomcat?
70 deals with help off for return TCF one pH on that values we cannot sign into some least
are some variables here.
I mean,
let me write in this way.
So a really good idea.
So what I'm doing is our Tom Cat seven Tomcat seven configuration file on Tomcat seven.
Tom,
get home seven.
Who then?
I need written here.
Right.
DCF on and then teach.
But I don't want to do this thing.
I want to capture my values without returning in my court.
Then it is not possible with your normal functions concert.
Then it is possible with your hopes.
Concert state.
Let me write one more program with hoops concert for real.
Get now idea So with boobs Not be what?
Let's be clear.
Fussing anyway.
Let me and start in this way.
This is common.
Ah,
sorry.
Not that then I'm defining main function That's fine on inside off that.
First off,
while I'm taking configuration files off Tomcat seven and Tomcat Mine.
Okay,
Are you can also take name like the Tom Got seven configuration file.
I'm get nine con figuration Fight.
No problem.
Anywhere able.
Yes,
I have taken previously.
Tom,
get seven Tomcat nine,
But I'm taking down.
Gets seven cf on time.
Got nine cf Noble.
That's fine.
No,
let me write.
Simply return None.
So this is just like your functions now in this,
I want to include hopes concept.
So,
guys,
at the end of this explanation,
you will come to no the users off who's and one more thing whenever.
If you want to write Oops,
concept in your core.
First thing is you need to define a template.
So if you want to defend any template,
you ought to take a cue to call the class class.
So what is our concert on Tomcat were working?
Take any name for your template,
that's it.
And whenever you for defining a template name just to start your name with Capital letter,
that is an option.
But it's but it's good to start with capital letters.
That's it So that is basically into defending template before going to use hopes.
Concept in your court,
but in turn off calling it has a template.
Just call it as a class defending a class.
But in your mind,
just as in there,
defending a class is nothing but preparing some former preparing some template.
That's it.
Thank So now one more thing.
We know that creating temporary is nothing but grouping some related functions into that
the group really functions were using hopes.
Concept toe group related functions were creating templates.
The group really the functions were creating class.
So no,
basically,
in your previous scored,
what are the functions?
Unique Get details for each Tomcat.
And one more thing is let me take only functions names first one function Ease this one
right on second funnies.
Second function is this predators So be clear.
Now you're getting clarity on your oops,
that's fine.
So,
guys,
one more thing Whenever If you define any function inside off a class,
then you had to say that that is a matter,
not a function.
Of course,
both are same except one execute.
See why nobody for defining your function and you are class then your per se doesn't method
on the hard right one before it.
Argument at the very first always that has itself see anyone of previous score You are a
function is taking only one argument Here also is taking only one argument.
Forget about this body Hard to write it.
Why you will get clarity the same day Display function is not taking anything in your
previous school.
No.
Now he also it is not taking anything but hard.
Right self first right,
cell phone.
Forget about it.
I assume that there is no any extract.
You hear Cellphone self here and here.
That's it.
Ok,
but there is a purpose for self not only self ignite any Cuba as the first argument on the
order used that same argument in your core,
I can write simply my name.
But universally,
all are following self as the first argument by default.
Anyone metal off it glass?
That's fine.
No.
Would your previous court so no.
Here we don't bother about Global are like Okay,
so I need you to find a very first available called TC off.
Let me copy these two variables.
So this is the normal function under normal function.
Generally,
we are defending variables in this way.
But whenever a few different variables inside or faith method always you have to write your
variable with cell for the heart.
TCF I mean,
you're required Variable sell for door bitch.
Why again?
You will come to know just away.
Okay.
See,
normally in your functions if you already find any variable your writing X equals to white
close to three.
Something like that.
But here just sergeant,
that engine operating x self dot Exe self dot way That's it like And finally rightly gunman
then display function.
So in this play details you're having this thing?
No.
Let me copy the same lines.
Let me arrange in traditions.
So I know.
But if you want to use your variables instead of methods always.
Yo,
you have self doubt that very hard right here.
Self door,
self door.
That's a okay,
that's fine.
No,
be clear.
Just know we created a template,
right?
Like injuries.
Having a template on Evan,
I worry for students are ready to take some courts from instruct introduced,
giving some template to each and every student.
So student is going to fill their data into that temple.
Now,
if you have done in our court,
we are two Tomcats.
I didn't that These two tomcats are like to students.
And this is like a form for instrument.
Now we need to pass this way to do the copy off this Tomcat template to Tomcat.
Seven as the last time.
Get nine.
That's right.
See that?
I'm going to create a objects.
I'm going to create objects,
even forget about your configuration files first.
So we're assuming that in Saudi on our sir,
where we're having two Tomcats.
That way we need to get to templates into your hand.
I mean,
if there are two Tomcats,
we need to clear two objects.
How to create jobs.
Very simple.
So we're having Tomcat seven.
Right on,
then.
Tomcat.
My,
therefore,
stick.
You're required Object names.
Tomcat seven equals two.
Nice to create an object.
What we have to do is we have to take a Xerox copy off template.
So what is our template?
This is our template.
So what is the name for Template?
Tomcat?
That's it.
Simply take here,
Tom care.
But he hard right,
But And this is here.
Then create object for Tom.
Get nine.
Um,
ca.
That's so same drugs.
Copy off this template we have given for Tomcat seven and Tom.
Get mine.
Tom,
get seven on Tomcat.
Name as off.
No,
just We are given drugs.
Copy to the students.
Now,
you've historians feels that data in the template.
Then we're having information about that student in that template.
Right?
So as off.
No,
we're not creating an object.
Simply.
We have given the template copy.
Toe,
toe object.
Tomcat.
Seven.
Time get nine.
No,
actually,
if you want to create an absurd unit toe,
fill the data field of data Means you're to call at least one method from your template.
If you want to call our limit of snowball,
at least you're to call one matter.
Then we can say that object has been created.
No,
Tomcat,
seven dot See,
guys,
if you want to call any matter inside off your object,
you need to use dark.
First thing.
Be clear.
This entire template is there in this tomcat seven on Tomcat mine.
Right?
So why Nobody feel working with tomcat.
Seven,
you have to assume that this entire thing is for Tomcat.
Someone and I know.
But if you're working with Tomcat nine then you have to assume that this entire thing is
for Tomcat.
Nine.
I'm sort of that.
I want to go get my for Tomcat.
Seven.
I need to get configuration file on Tomcat home.
Then what I ought to do is I need to call this function.
Met her.
Just a bite bossing this conflict because that is taking conflagration file,
right?
No.
Whenever if you call in this way,
fight on is going to convert internally.
This US Be clear.
Be clear.
Don't write this in your core.
You will get another,
but fighting will convert that internally in this week.
Tomcat seven.
That's it.
Let me enable it.
Actually used to not right.
So the same function.
This line this lane is going to convert into in this way.
So I know.
But if you can work in this way no,
you can assume when nobody feel calling this matter right?
What is the self value?
Self is nothing but no Tomcat.
Seven.
Now in the entire template.
Replays self with tomcat seven.
Know what you are doing,
Tom?
Get 7 30 c off off course.
That itself but selfish Tomcat seven.
So,
Tom,
get seven dot Easier.
So in memory somewhere your pipeline is creating Tom.
Get seven dot DCF on at the same time,
Tomcat seven dot de hitch No.
Two very was dynamically created for your Tomcat.
Seven.
The same day.
In case if he called Tom,
get mine for Tom,
get nine.
Also,
you are in memory somewhere because while calling from Palm,
get nine well calling.
Get details for each Tomcat from mine Self is becoming nine Tomcat nine.
That's why whenever,
if it is excluding this method for Tom card nine again dynamically,
two variables are created like tomcat mine dot DCF Tom cat nine dot t off some Get home.
Start Deitch Tom,
get home.
But if you're observing your court,
we're not having four variables were having only two variables.
But while running separately,
your four way tables are created.
Then how they're going to create just a rate first.
Let me right.
Let me call for Tomcat nine also.
So we're calling from Tomcat nine configuration file.
Is this one on the hard to call from Tomcat?
Me?
That's it.
Ok,
but once again,
whenever if you call any method from object internal You're fightin will convert in this
way.
So where you converting in this way by default?
Self,
self,
self key.
What is always pointing to from which object you're calling so that separated variables is
create operate Variables are going to create for each and every object.
Now there is no overlap.
So previously,
if you have done your normal functions Concert If you call this.
Get details for Tom Kurt.
Seven.
You're getting information in these two variables for Tomcat seven.
But if you call from Tom Kitt nine.
If you call from Tomcat nine.
Then you are variables are war right?
With Tomcat nine data.
Tom got 70 guys going toe daily.
But here,
that is not the case.
Whenever If you call from bomb,
get seven,
come get seven.
Variables are dynamically creating.
And whenever if you call from Tom,
can't find Tom.
Get nine variables are dynamically creating right,
Fine.
So,
guys.
And now we are saying that tomcat seven object has been created.
Tom got nine has been cleared somewhere in memory.
Right.
See that somewhere in memory?
Tom card.
I'm not writing full time.
Get Justin generating Tomcat seven on Baumgarten line.
So Tomcat,
seven door PCF variable Tom,
get $7.
Tom got home on Tom.
Get nine Doherty cf configuration file on Tomcat nine dot tomcat home.
So these variables our creator.
But these variables are there under this name.
So this is called an object.
Under this object,
these two variables are back,
right?
So if you want to get this variables always your toe get tomcat object.
So simply,
Tom Kurt Door Tomcat nine Doherty CF Tom got minder Th or time,
Get $7 TC of Tom Get seven or teach.
Right.
So here,
if you observe dynamically,
we're creating our variables,
right?
I'm see.
And one more thing.
Very important.
One.
If you want to access these variables in other function in normal function programming
concept,
what we are doing we're making are available to us global.
But in hopes concept,
you can access this variable inside off other function.
We thought making this as a global because these two matters we group on the Tomcat that
way One method variables you can access inside off.
Other matter.
Variable.
So here we are,
accusing one step making global.
We're not making global by default we can access one variable off one matter into other
variable.
That's why directly I heard himself dot UCL.
Right?
So,
guys,
now often executing these,
I mean from tomcat.
Seven This matter on Tomcat.
Nine this matter in memory somewhere we are creating four where it was two for tomcat seven
and two for tomcat nine.
Might be clear how they're going to create.
So simply one memory location for Tomcat seven and just you have to call this has object on
one memory location for Tomcat nine.
And this is on object.
And in this we how TCF variable and teach variable the same way here.
Also,
we hope TCF variable on Tomcat home variable if I want to get Tomcat hedge.
I'm Tom.
Got home,
Tom.
Get $7 th how to use.
See,
I'm not calling.
Display externally outside,
off your class inside off my main function.
My name.
But if you are in the inside off a class,
then only you ought to take self be clear whenever If you're inside off a class,
then only how to take self keyword.
But now what if you are in the outside off a class you have to take your object name.
Sort Tomcat.
Nine for Tom Kirkman.
We are two variables.
What are those two variables?
TCF one th But I want to destroy them.
Then Darty CF,
then print dot Th See the result.
Something wrong?
What is that?
Let me verify.
Ways is no different.
Yeah.
When it import that waste,
let me import ways.
Not on the output.
See the result?
You're getting drunker.
90 deals Now I can print randomly.
First I can print.
Tom got 90 cf.
Then Tom got seven Tomcat home.
And then at last,
I can print.
Ah,
bring to Tom Card seven.
Configuration file.
Yes,
you can access at any time.
Randomly,
you're required variables because somewhere in memory location,
they're going to create a new variables for each and every object.
They're not going to war.
Lap.
I'm get 90 separate member location.
Tomcat seven on 30.
Separate member location.
They So this is the way.
Hope how we can access you are variables outside of class,
but we already defined a function inside off your class to display your variables.
No,
I want to display for Tomcat seven configuration file on home.
Then I need to call this display details matter from your Tomcat.
Seven.
Let me call there Tomcat.
Seven dot despair details.
Wanted to pass any arguments anyway by default.
Self is there,
right?
We need to pass self value generally.
But whenever the free run in this way by Tony's going to convert ever displayed details as
in this way,
Bram K seven.
That's it.
Because we're not having any arguments here.
Not this time.
Get Sonny's going to assign self on inside of this one.
We're having self door TCF means from We're calling from Tomcat seven.
Right?
That's why you are going to get Tom card 7 30 c f.
Bomb gets seven Doherty hitch.
Right.
See that?
I'm going to run.
See?
That is there.
You're getting Tom got 70 days?
No.
Let me call for time.
Get mine.
So when nobody if you're calling from butler object based on that,
your partner is going to get variables for that object.
See that?
And I can call any number of times first.
I'm going to call Tom.
Got $9 display D days.
See there.
So this is the odd one days with your hopes concert,
right?
So they one second.
I'm re breeding the important points for oops Concept please.
First,
we're taking oops concept to create an object.
So in our program we get her to objects.
So what is that done is by creating two objects dynamically.
We're going to create a separate memory locations for you were required object so that we
can access many any variable at any time.
Right on.
Basically who is nothing but grouping later functions for particular thing under one name
that is called a temporary no indeed.
What's way we are creating template to create an object under template.
We are writing the little functions for that object Nazi Right on.
One more thing.
No Internet always self here You can write anything.
Let's say I'm writing injured off self.
What I'm doing is so I will light Suppose Narendra So I'm going to replace all with not in
the only.
Then we'll work.
Noble,
Um,
the only thing is universally we are following one rule in giraffe taking any random
default argument we're taking self.
But I can take anything.
Let me right.
So I'm going to replace all with Narendra.
I said,
that is my name right no see the result.
There is no change.
So but generally inversely were falling.
See if I go with my name.
If you go with your name,
you'll get somewhat confusion.