friends here.
Our concept,
these class and object attributes See Ali,
we know simply what is a class So class is a template or blueprint to create an object.
So once if you have a template from there we can create any number of objects on classes,
the combination off attributes and metres.
So basically our tributes are like variables and we can define attributes for class on
objects.
I mean,
for class level,
we can define some variables and for object level,
we can defend some variables.
Let me explain this concert with help off a symbol by transcript.
So I'm saving my script name as working on at Labour's Don't be white.
So they suppose I'm writing a simple by Tom skipped our program to maintain the data for
implies supple agenda.
For time being,
we're having some two implies,
right?
Then I won't do maintain the later for these two employees.
Then before going to maintain the data first,
I will assume I'm going to create one template.
So I want to store so on.
So things for employees,
right?
So then what?
I'm doing this glass simply employed that's a cooler than enter.
So I'm refining one meter to store the employees Name is on salary.
Suppose so.
Let me define as I get Name is salary Not so actually this is a function.
But if anybody if you want to write a function inside off a class you have to write bitey
for itself as the key.
And you don't need to worry aboard the value for self automatically Self will be replaced
by the particular object from which object you're calling.
That object will come in the place off self.
That's fine.
Now you're expecting for this function?
Name is and salary.
Let me take variables as I mean.
I will pass arguments for this method.
Will calling are like name is on salary.
Nothing.
Then I want to store this name is and Salvi in the memory location.
So for that you had to write self door name equals to name So guys don't get confused.
Self dot name is different and name is different.
It is like X y equals to white.
Completed their different variables.
Right then,
Self lord,
is it closed?
Toe is so if you're getting confusion,
just take hear arguments as different variables.
I'm in different names like Yes,
yes,
yes.
But if you take name,
age and Sally just from what meaningful that I'm taking arguments as a name is and salary
then self Lord salary Not.
Then I'm going to define one motor of function just to display the implied the dates.
Then what I can do Display employees de days are simply display details Self so actually to
display employee details What we need name is and soundly so if you're using normal
function like a display details if it is a normal function toe,
get your details.
You need to pass arguments,
toe dysfunction.
But this is a matter.
And if you did,
these two metres are in the same class.
That's why whatever the variables you are having,
you define any word.
First matter,
those variables you can access in other methods.
That's why I'm not passing any arguments to display details matter that attack and access
from my previous mentor.
So that fidelity,
what I'm doing is simply print.
The name is so simply here I will write name name is nothing but self lord name but not
this name.
Grace this your passing toe this matter while calling okay,
but actually variables are our tributes for your objects Are these things?
Then let me right slash n that is these we can write anything.
No bowling.
Just for out.
For your understanding.
I'm writing simple script.
Then they salary is that's it Looks great.
Salary,
self A lot salary right then,
right.
Simply return none.
So I'm not expecting any return value from this matter.
So he had also I'm not expecting any Britain value.
That's why I'm writing.
Simply return none.
That's fine.
So if you run,
your court has off.
No,
you're not getting any output and you're not going to get any better because there's just
template number won't eggs good whenever.
If you run,
it will exclude whenever.
If you are signed this template to any object night.
That's fine.
No,
See that?
Yes,
I do know that we're having to implies Let's say employees one unemployed toe.
Okay.
No,
I want to store the details for employees.
One unemployed doom When I want to see you where nobody find need so to store we how this
method on toe display we have this matter second method,
right?
So So instead of get let me a sign our Yeah,
Noble.
You can take any metal,
right?
So imply you one.
So before going to store employees one day days what?
You have to go for stuff All you need to assign this template for this object,
right?
Then only this methods and this attributes are variables you can access from employees One
That's why what I'm doing first time doing employees then for employees one and employ to
That's it.
Right?
So,
guys,
as off No,
you how imply You won and employ two objects.
But there is no information for employees one unemployed toe Because if you exclude anyone
of them,
Attard then only are going toe store your data supposed to story or did I heartaches?
Could this matter?
But you need to call that method You know how to column matter off your class Now a gender
This entire class this template is touring the name off employees one on employee toe so
that nobody if you call from employ you one employees,
You one get name,
age and salary.
Let's say I'm giving us suppose name Anything like John.
Hey,
supposed 34 then I'm giving silently as something like,
Yes,
I know it may be 45,000 per month.
Just a union,
Right?
Fine,
No.
The same day.
I want to store my data.
My employ to data.
Then just right.
That's it.
Okay.
Now,
if I execute well running your program somewhere in memory,
location to memory blocks will be created.
One memory block for employees one on second memory is for employees Toe night on.
See before calling your display.
If I write the a r off employees of one see the result what you're getting basically for
employees one.
What are the information's you're having name?
I mean this method on variables right on One more method here Now see that would put
anybody are These are the default values I have done that.
See,
that is there Name is there.
Sally's there.
So employees wonder is employees One darts name employee wondered salary The same way you
can use this is the method is to other metals.
We know that by during here we can understand that these two are matters So imply wonder
display details imply one don't get name is salary but we're calling if you need arguments
in it to pass the same,
we can also run this for employ to same information is there for employees to also.
But the values are different.
That's a no fine.
Just observe these guys.
Why are you calling from your 14th line or imply you one get name is salary Jon 34 45,000
values will be assigned to respectively.
Name is and salary than What about self self By default from which object you're calling
that object name will be stored in the self.
That's why in memory it is going to create,
like employees one dot name,
not self dot name.
Okay,
for our purpose for our enemy Corpus were writing self,
but while storing your values,
your variables in memory location,
they're going to store in the respect by using employees one in play,
one dot name in play,
one dot age and play one.
Not salary,
nothing and one more thing,
but never if you're accessing,
you're variables inside off a class.
Always you have to take self dot name.
Self got a self not Sally like that,
but for same imply you one.
If you want to access your variables and the roads outside off a class outside of a class,
then you have to access with imply,
you wondered,
not self.
Not be clear outside the hard to access with the employees.
One dot suppose I wonder.
Display age.
So that is what you're getting.
That's fine.
I left the Abdur even method.
We're also calling us employees Wonder.
Suppose if I want to call display method.
How can I call Imply you one dot display details.
That's it.
If you observe displayed details is not requiring any arguments.
It is not taking any arguments except self anywhere.
Self is going toe store with the help of employees.
One.
M play One name will store in yourself.
That's why we are Boston character arguments.
Where you calling display Minter Not just after the result.
And one more thing you are calling your method outside off a class.
Suppose I want toe display My details offer Assigning the data to yourself dot name is,
and sadly,
then you have to call this matter inside of this foster matter.
So whenever if you want to call liver matter inside off a matter,
then you have the right cell for Lord met her name so self means outside a connection.
This is like employees one but inside off a class if you want to call,
and if you want,
exclude any matter you have to write self dot Now let me come in days and see the result.
You're going to get display details for two implies.
See that first you're assigning because of star 14 50 lines you're assigning your values
for your attributes are variables.
Then immediately,
you're calling the respect to objector display.
Details matter.
That's why you're going to get the same values in output.
Not there are signing on.
Then you are displaying.
That's it.
So be clear if you want to execute a matar inside off a class,
you had to write self door,
but outside off a class you had to write your object name dot that matter name.
That's fine.
And if you abduct this entire program,
you are having these or,
like,
attributes right on this attribute.
This attributes are specific for Butler object because we're writing self dot,
so it is nothing without that name.
So these are tributes.
Are the letter for your object?
That's fine?
No.
What?
I have a small requirement off the creation off after creation off your objects.
I need to find at last how many employee objects has been clear.
Did using this template how many employee objects has been created by using this template?
I hope to know that Count.
I need to find out.
Hey,
what I'm doing is I am writing comb count because initially,
Jiro.
So whenever if I create employees one at that time,
I need to increase this value and it increased this value.
This value is not related with your object.
This is ready with your template.
Your class this class variable.
See that?
If I want to access that variable from outside off your class,
I need to access with the employees dot com.
What is employees here?
Class Name?
Joe,
you're getting Let me come in tow biting for calling this president's right.
I was just just absurd output.
They're getting digital,
right?
I can increase this value at any time.
Maybe inside off a class inside off a method are outside off a classy I am going in
employees dot county cause to employ dot cone Blessed one.
So after that,
I am printing my employees Cone,
that's a not this variable.
If we defend any variable outside off your methods without self.
Then that is for you.
Template for your class rt built That is class rt vote now.
What I'm doing is I'm taking the help off this variable on whenever.
If I create an absurd at that time,
I will increase this value.
I can increase either inside off a class,
are inside off emitter or outside of him class.
See how I'm going to do that.
So you were never If I create this values right,
that means you're creating an object,
right?
So India's I'm I'm going to create one more method.
You can create any method.
I mean,
like increased count Increase combed for employ not for your object,
but memories were writing inside off your class.
Right?
See,
what I'm doing is simply amazing.
Employee,
this is the class name.
Then count equals toe employed or cone plus one.
Of course,
you can also read your shortcut for your automatic operation.
Then simply return none.
That's it,
See?
But I need toe manually.
Run this.
I mean exclude this method whenever if I create an object.
So I mean after giving your name,
age and Sally for any employee offer that I need to call employees one door.
Increase cone for employees,
then implied,
too.
No increase.
Gone for M blade.
That's it.
No,
see,
that isn't.
Yeah,
let me bring.
So they're gonna just for So what is the variable employees dot com through the desert to
wearables has been started to object has been created by using this template.
I don't understand.
This variable normal variable rate like X equals to something County coast,
Ojito.
Not the if you defined.
Available immediately after writing your class class name.
If you defend any variable.
Right that available is written for the work class.
So this is called class attribute.
So why we way?
We need class.
Our tribute meets How many?
Suppose one of the example I'm giving.
But you can defend a number of variables based on your requirement.
The very simple thing I'm giving is from the template.
How many objects has been cleared to count that I'm defending one variable when I triple
called com.
That's it.
So if you don't want to call externally,
you are increased corn for employees just coming.
These two methods here.
So anybody if it created were variables immediately called Self Lord.
Increase count for employees.
That's it.
You can see that is a same old would write to your getting.
Okay,
So this this is Allah boat simply class and object.
Attributes Be clear.
These are class obsessed dirty boots and this is for your class.
Are people on?
Remember that class are too boots.
We hope to call our We have to save like self dot You are variable name Even when
displaying that we had to take selfies are that is only inside off a class.
But if it come outside,
then you have to take it instead of self butler Object Name Employee one dot name implied
to name something like that.
But for class variable this is class variable our class Attribute,
count count So either inside off a method inside off a class or outside off a class you can
always access with help off employees I'm in template class name dot Your attributes Be
clear for employees observed inside yourself outside and play one our employees to It's
outside inside of self dot,
but there has for class.
Variables are tables wherever you go.
I mean in any lining will program.
You have to take Always employees dot count.
I mean,
your class named out that very but that's it.
Okay.
Okay,
guys,
Thank you for watching this simple video.