friends here.
Our concept Please constructor off a class.
See,
this constructor is a method in your class and this is a special method On this mother is
called by the Ford.
Whenever you create an object from a class See,
we know that classes nothing Bird combination off attributes and methods and we never if
you won't be,
execute any method from your class.
Always you need toe Call that from your object.
Right?
But if you define a constructor matter inside off a class you know Nieto call that by
default.
It will execute whenever if you create an object Let me explain this with a simple by
transcript So I'm taking name is constructor Hopes not be white.
Let me create simple class like employees.
Then under that,
I am defending a method called simply display.
You can take anything display then what I'm doing is simply I'm reading a prince treatment
.
This is a display Matar then simply done None.
That's it.
So my classes having only one method Now let me clear to objects.
Let's say employees Juanico's toe employees and then play two equals two employees.
And if I run this court,
do we have any or put no.
Because to get some more port this print statement you need to call this matter so you can
call it a matter neither from object One are from your objected to.
So this is from object one I can also call from object to the same method.
That's fine.
So finally,
if there is any matter inside off your class And if you only Xcor that you need to call
your matter from your partner object they But no my requirement days Let me write one more
matter here.
But that method name is there is a default name for that underscored underscored in it
Underscore underscore then by the fall your right oneself keyword right oneself argument
for any matter which is there in your class the No let me print.
This is a innit met hard.
Um let me rate return None.
So you know,
if you want to exclude general,
any matter we're calling their?
No.
Let me remove this.
Even if you keep it will call your disclaim attack,
right?
No,
Let me run.
See the output?
Gross body?
Yeah,
it is written by most.
Either we're not calling this matter But still it is able to display the information from
this prince straight.
Man,
this is a innit Matar on it is calling bitey for when it is calling When every few create
an absurd When nobody feel assign your class for your object are the remedy is calling
bitey for right now So let me remove this play matter now we don't We're not calling any
mattered but still you're getting output means initial aviation mature will call by default
whenever If you create an object from your class that's your No,
I can take this Installation matter uses us different ways you can use So suppose I'm
goingto take this initial ation matter increase might obstetrical.
So,
you know,
in previous cessation,
right,
we are taken some counter variable on forcefully.
We are calling some increase cone for employees than there were increasing or variable Know
what I am doing is directly I'm defending a variable called County Costa Jiro initially and
then,
like many more this prince treatment,
you can keep that statement as well.
No problem.
Know what I'm doing is you were class variable equals two employees door cone.
Bless one.
Okay.
Now,
before creating object.
Let me remove all these things as off.
No,
you don't have any object.
That's why insulation matter is not going to call Now.
Let me bring first the number off objects create there from employees class or as off?
No.
There are no objects from your class.
That's why you're not Put this somewhere.
What is the problem?
Okay,
be or a and e See,
that isn't currently there are no objects created from your class.
Now let me create one object from my class.
So I'm creating suppose employees.
One equals two employees.
No,
See the reserve You're getting automatically one way whenever.
If you do in this way,
you're creating one employee.
One observer at that time in this employee one my third Sorry.
In this employee,
one object automatically dissimulation matter is calling whenever it is calling whenever it
is executing.
Right calling means you're going to exclude this whenever it is excluding inside that were
increasing or counter value employees counter value.
Now let me call Let me create one more object and see the result.
Now you're getting too right.
So simply guys in insulation is a special method which will call by default.
Whenever If we create an object from your class and inside that you can at any lousy I'm
taking here toe increase my employee count objects.
Right?
Okay,
Now let me write one more thing.
I'm going to use this initial ation mattered in one more way also.
Let me right.
You stays off,
Constructor.
Don't be way.
See you guys first.
Awful.
I'm defending a class called employees.
Four days.
You can define your class in two ways.
I'm in syntax.
This is one way and one more is simply class employees object.
Don't worry about objects.
Actually,
while discussing about inheritance,
you will use this concert.
But if you are not using evidence than first impacts on seconds index,
both are correct,
right?
But anyway,
if you want to make this always correct than use class employees in currency,
just write object.
But you don't worry about that object.
What is that object?
How you're going to use?
We're not going to use it.
We'll discuss that in her in evidence concert.
So from from no one words,
when nobody's going to define a class,
please take class.
Last name,
then impotent.
This just right object.
That's fine.
No,
I'm writing a method to define name on salary.
Well,
let me dig.
Name your salary.
You know,
the foliar right self on this matter is to define name on salary.
Then we're expecting name on salary values.
The let me write itself not name it caused to name.
Then Self Lord salary equals two celery then simply right to return month.
Then let me write one more matter just to display what information off party are absurd
Bring the name is simply right here.
Name self door name then in next lane.
Celery is Saudi slash invite next lane The salary he's so whatever the salary for your
employees,
just write that Salvi So what is the sell for Lord salary?
That's it.
Right?
And finally right of return.
So,
guys,
how didn't hold defined template or class on?
If I run these as if no,
there are no objects,
no good tonight?
No.
Let me create an object Employees one equals two first win it our sign our class or
template toe this object Then if you want to create variables or attributes for that then
you have to call related methods.
So I am calling suppose with some celery.
So I created one observed as off No.
And let me great!
One more out object if you want for name on Sally for second objects.
Let's stay.
Ah,
not Indra.
Then look me right.
Some salary.
What happened?
Okay,
we did not create out there,
right?
So first we need to create an object.
And by two equals two not to So we created two objects.
So guys,
you can create your object at any place.
After that,
you can call.
So put it you can create first your number off objects.
Then you can call.
You required a method for each object.
Anyway,
this is fine.
No next thing I want to display the information Then whether he wanted display information
,
first object or second object.
So I want to display information for first object.
Then first object dot display.
Then I want to get the information for second object.
Then second object dot display.
That's it.
So,
guys,
if I take initial ation matter uses see how I'm going to implement the same court?
Let me write one more thing using in it metadata be like First of all,
let me take Seem glass name then under that initial isn't in turn off this foster mattered
What?
I'm going to take these see into off This is salary I am defining in a in isolation.
Met there.
So this is a matter tonight.
Any number of arguments based on your requirement.
Previously we have taken simply self.
That means we have not passing any argument.
No year.
We are ready to take some arguments for insulation matter.
But how to pass?
We will see.
No,
simply right.
Self lord name equals two name on.
Then Self Lord salary.
It was too suddenly.
Simply write return None.
Let me take this displacement velocities.
Okay,
No guys previously injured or finish elation matter You are having name on salary matter.
But you know whenever there is insulation matter that will exclude by the four.
So if it is executing,
it is expecting name on salary?
No,
if you don't know how this noble If you have a insulation better in this way it is not
taking any argument.
Then no problem by day for two legs.
Cute.
You don't need to pass arguments for that.
But if you're here anyway,
anybody If they create an object.
Let me create an absurd.
And if I run no court because off this we're creating an object at that time.
By the fall insulation,
metal will call if it is calling.
It needs to arguments.
Then how we can pass.
If you're not passing,
see that you're going to get another going initial ation matter.
Missing two required operational arguments.
Name on salary Right now nothing.
Is there anybody?
If you are creating an absurd here itself,
you can pass.
You were required values.
See that?
No,
I'm going to run.
You're not getting an error?
No.
Let me call employees.
Wonder display details.
Yes,
You are getting so guys comfort to this court.
What is that one this year?
So in this previous court to create your self dot name or partner object d'art name object
d'art Salvi we need to call name salary matter.
We're creating object and then create that information for your object We are defining.
We are excluding.
We're calling a method called name salary.
So we're writing one extra line.
But here moment right there.
Whenever.
If you're creating an absurd,
are that time the required variables.
Arguments for your installation mattered you can pass here itself so that you're creating
particular object information.
See,
now I'm displaying employees.
One details.
You're getting that right?
No,
The same way I can also create any number of objects.
So let me take imply you too.
Suppose I am passing?
Not in 90,004 months Salary?
No,
I'm running your employees to object has been created and play.
One officer has been created But I want to see the information about employees to then call
display matter even if you don't want to call display matter externally we have a short cut
anyway.
Bitey fall insulation Mother is calling No in there just right Self lord display That's it
.
Be clear whenever If you're calling your method outside off a class you hard toe point with
respect to observe But inside sell for dark self not display So guys no to assign it to
display information simply we're having only two lines But in previous court see that to
create your objects One Metarie hard to call to display Hard to calls up was one moment
Anyway,
it also you can call this matter inside of this but compared toa this matter here we're
losing at least one line now.
See the result?
That's it.
If you don't want to call this matter from insulation matter,
if you want to call externally.
Yes,
you can also call excellently by using employees $1.
Display our employees to your display.
That's it.
So there's finally the advantage off initialization memories.
You can create your attributes if you follow this index.
If you've all of this impacts,
you can create your attributes while creating your object.
That's it so that you're going to reduce one line.
So if I take any method other than insulation matter,
toe creates your name on salary attributes for your opposite.
I need to call that matter here in this way.
How taking your name name on Salvi then to create your name and salary are variable for
your object.
I need to call in this way.
But if you views if you use initialization method,
no need to call by the fall.
You can create the attributes or variables for your partner Object.
That's it.
That is that One days with constructor off Mitter.
I hope you're clear with this installation matter.
Okay,
guys,
thank you for watching this with you.