friends here We're discussing about inheritance and polymorphism concept off.
Oops.
First,
let me go with polymorphism.
Basically,
we know Polly means many so in spite on polymorphism allows us to define same methods in
different classes.
I mean you can take same method name in different classes even though you could define same
matter name in different classes there is no overlap.
This process is also known as matter bull riding simply we are or writing same 1/3 in
different classes.
Yes,
that is possible.
That is a load in your python And we can also use this polymorphism concept in your
inheritance as well.
We will see that while discussing about the inheritance First,
let me explain about your polymorphism with a simple example Let me open my sublime texture
later.
So here I am defending two classes Let's say Tomcat and I am defining Ah constructor method
Here the purpose of constructor Middle East toe assign Let's say Tomcat home and Russian by
default.
Whenever we are creating an object we know insulation my thirties a contractor matter.
It will execute by default whenever if you create an object right?
So simply I'm writing home.
Then let's say self lord worship because toe question right then finally right.
I'm not expecting any return value from this mother.
That's why Simply I'm writing the done None.
Let me read one more method called display a little simply I'm writing.
This is from Tomcat class on here simply.
I'm displaying brain sell for door,
whom then print self door.
What's in?
That's it,
then from this function also,
I mean from this matter also,
I'm not expecting an incident where you simply and write England unknown.
Let me take same matter.
But here I am taking Web server class name Let's say a party.
Yes,
we created two classes,
but if you have there,
here are taken insulation method on here also are taken Insulation method display matter
common.
Bought the classes.
No problem.
It is allowed in your fight on it is allowed in your pie tone.
They see if I run this court,
you're not getting any better Anyway.
Let me clean object from your Tomcat on from Europe Party.
Let's say Tomcat absurd equals two Tomcat.
So why creating an object?
You're having insulation matter which is expecting to arguments.
Let's a human version then let me pass.
That lets a home sometime care nine And then I'm taking suppose watching us some $7 6
something like that.
Then let me create Apache object also from your apology class.
So it is also using insulation method.
That means it is expecting to arguments.
We need to pass them while creating an object.
Let's say watching her some put out four like me.
Run this and see the results.
There is no error.
That's fine.
No,
I wanted this to the details off Tomcat object and also displayed The deal's off about the
object?
No,
in Tom could object.
We are dis limiter.
If I call this display matter with respect Tomcat object then it will call from here only
so that you are going to get information from from for your tomcat object.
See,
I simply we define same maternal name in different classes.
No problem.
Even though if you take your pie don't don't get confused,
it will work perfectly.
See,
there is a This is from Tomcat class,
right?
Let me call from a body object display.
Minter know what you're going to get?
See the result?
This is from Yes,
I D I hold it in?
That's like copyright.
Let me here.
Modified Apache.
What the place is.
Actually,
we help Same court.
Now let me run this and see that is a whenever.
If you're calling from Tomcat observed display matter,
it is going toe executing your this display matter.
Right?
And whenever we feel calling from a party absurdities executing the metal,
which is there Nobody chapter.
That's it.
Even though if you wore right your matter in different classes your fight on don't get
confused.
And this is simply polymorphism defining,
Say matter.
Name in different classes is nothing but polymorphism Night.
That's fine.
Now our next to concert,
please.
In evidence.
See,
inheritance is a mechanism that allows us to create new class,
known as a tailor class on that is based upon an existing class that is parent class.
Nothing is there.
This concept is very similar to our,
um like human life.
Suppose we are in herding Dean's from or parents,
right?
That is a concept.
Here,
let me explain this with escapes American under strain.
Now let me take one more strip.
So here I am,
saving it as a in her does not be white.
So that is faster thing.
Let me take same script only on if I open this group here.
Okay?
So if you have during these two glasses there are common methods.
Let's up at this display.
Minted,
See for display.
May 3rd already.
It is there in Tomcat.
Why should I read the court here?
If you observe and by sin taxes Same.
No,
here and here.
If it is similar,
why should I write?
Same scored in the second class,
right?
So in that case,
what I can do is I can inherit Tomcat class in my A party so that I can use display matter
for a party object for a budget class.
How it is possible Just after that I am removing display mother from your second class.
And if you want to inherit any glass injured off this object,
you have to write the particular class name.
That's it.
No,
the meaningful disease you are in hurting these two methods in this class.
And if you have the same method,
is there here and here?
No problem.
Even though if you're having first to preferences in this Apache,
this one,
if it is not there in a party than on it will take this installation method that is called
polymorphism.
That's fine.
Now,
see,
Let me create your two objects right now.
Remove this print because you are you hurting this,
Tom,
get in Google.
These are Budgie class now.
I created two objects.
It's fine.
There is no better,
right?
No.
See,
I am calling your tomcat,
observed or display.
Then you're getting Tomcat doodles.
If you're observing a party,
we don't.
How We don't how this play matter,
but I'm trying to do that.
A party,
object or display.
You're getting your information,
Your display material executing evenly If you don't have this limited here because we
inherited this Tomcat class in tow,
Apache,
so that whatever the matters are there in this tomcat,
all methods are valued in this apology.
Object also.
But initial Asian mother is already there.
Here,
in here.
That's right.
References for this installation,
Mother.
Not for this.
Right.
So these the way how we can inherit a matter off one class into other class.
What we are doing simply,
while creating your second class,
we are writing in place off parentheses in place,
off objects were writing.
You're required class from which you need to inherit from which you need toe import The
methods that class name hard to write so that the matters which are available in the world
this class will be available with this object also.
I mean,
what are the other they are going to get from this class?
Also,
that's a That is the simple way to understand inheritance concert.
Anyway,
you will get more idea while writing our real time scripts.
Okay,
so finally,
what is that?
One days by using inheritance?
Simple.
This is sales.
You from duplicating a lot off course.
Suppose you are defining same matter in different classes on with the same court.
Why should we repeat same court in different classes,
defining one class and heard that class into your current class so that he can use the
previous class matters in the current class?
Also that is that one day.
And one more thing.
Yeah.
Last point for a party.
We are inheriting methods from Tomcat.
Now here I can say,
Tomcat is the parent,
The class and Apache is the chili class.
Our stomach that is the super class and approaches the subclass you don't remember that
that names parent Tomcat or super classes?
Tomcat.
A party is the chili class.
Our surplus.
Right.
That's your case.
Thank you for watching this simple video.