Project controls are the things you use to monitor and measure your project,
first monitoring the project variables, cost,
effort, scope, resources, etc.
against the project plan and the project performance baseline,
in other words where we should be.
We also want to measure the ongoing project activities, where are we?
We also want to identify corrective actions to address issues and risks
properly in terms of how do we get back on track again,
what do we have to correct.
And also what are the influencing factors that could circumvent your
change control so only approved changes can be implemented?
That's managing change control.
Now this is a high-level overview of monitoring and measuring,
and in this module we're going to go into detail in
terms of all these activities.
So good project controls give you good project results,
and let's see what they are.
By using your project controls,
these are the results that you want for a good project.
Deliver on budget.
In other words, if your budget is a million dollars, you're under that.
Stay on schedule.
Maybe have a variety of milestones and dates,
but you're always going to exceed those dates,
in other words come in early or on time.
Provide consistent deliverables.
Is what you deliver have good quality and meets the customer's expectations?
Meet quality expectations, no bugs, it works.
Meet performance expectations.
Performance has a variety of definitions here.
One might be the speed of the system when you hit the Enter key,
and another might be all these other elements that
are called project performance, budget, schedule,
etc.
Articulate, remediate gaps or deviations,
issues or problems say with the requirements.
And also identify and correct issues and risks.
You're always going to have issues that come up,
and you're going to always have risks to overcome.
How well do you understand those, track those, and remediate those?
So your project controls will need to provide you the information to
deliver these results to your project sponsors,
customers, and your team members as well.
Let me tell you, if your project did these things the right way,
you'll be wildly successful as a project manager.
Trust me on this.
Now project control is certainly more than just the tools and
processes for controlling and managing your project,
it's also about these elements as well.
Leadership, how well can you lead a team,
how well do you get people to work for you and follow your direction?
Communication, how well do you communicate the project statistics,
how well do you communicate to the stakeholders about the project's status,
how well do you communicate to your team about what needs to be done?
The people skills, not so much the technical skills,
but the interpersonal skills that are required to
communicate and support users and customers.
And team management, how well do you manage your team and lead your team.
These are also very important elements of running the entire project.
So I just want to make sure you understand that it's just
more than project control and metrics. These other elements are also critical.