In this section we'll be covering the key elements of project control,
but first a few definitions.
Before we go deeper into the project control activities,
let's touch on this definition, project performance.
No, this is not software performance or how fast your stored procedure will run,
but instead it's how well are you achieving the
project's critical success factors.
What's a CSF?
Well, these are items that you're going to track to enable the stakeholders,
and yourself of course, to easily see how your project is performing.
Just as an example, a critical success factor could be number of hours used,
dollars, schedules, key deliverables, and things like that.
These are the items that you're going to come up with to help
you measure the performance of your project.
Now let's go a little deeper with one more definition.
Those critical success factors we just mentioned,
basically they're just performance metrics.
Those are the variables you monitor and measure in order to
determine your project's performance, in other words how well are you doing?
And as we stated, dollars, hours, features, dates, etc, those are your metrics.
Those metrics are also called critical success factors as well.
Okay, let's go on to the key project control activities.
I will be covering eight project control activities,
and here are the first four: Communications management,
change management, configuration management,
and requirements management.
Now let's drill in.
Remember in the last module planning.
The outcome of that were tasks, estimates, schedules, etc.
That was the core of our plan,
but these other elements are also part of our plan.
We need to know how to plan for communications.
How are we going to plan for change management?
How are we going to plan for configuration
management and requirements management?
How we're going to do those things are also part of our plan,
and we we're going to talk about how to include those and create those in the following slides.