This section contains some helpful tips you could begin
using on your projects right away.
Do as you say.
This is all about trust,
which is the bedrock of effective leadership and communication.
Your behavior is your single, greatest mode of communication,
and it must be congruent with what you say.
If your actions don't align with your words,
there's trouble,
and it can turn into big trouble if not corrected swiftly and genuinely.
Since it's often difficult to see what you say and what you do in yourself,
rely on a few trusted colleagues to tell you it straight to
your face and flag any discrepancies.
Rule of thumb,
it's better to say nothing or delay your communication until
you're certain that your actions will ring true.
When you communicate, try making the complex simple.
Your employees,
customers are being bombarded 24 by 7 by information
making it hard for them to hear you.
Simplicity has never been more powerful or necessary.
Effective leaders distill complex thoughts and strategies into simple,
memorable terms that colleagues and customers and
stakeholders can grasp and act upon.
If you're having trouble distilling something to its essence,
it may be that you don't understand it.
Rule of thumb, look out for technical jargon in business speak,
which can add complexity.
Say what you mean in as few words as possible.
So what is your stride?
If you don't know, let's find it.
Use language that's distinctly your own.
People will begin to more easily identify and understand your communications.
Let your values comes through in your communication.
Often PMs will opt for the sanitized, kind of corporate,
clean instead of their own because they think the former is more eloquent,
maybe even more appropriate.
This is not to say that correct grammar and use of language aren't important.
Strong leaders know how to string a sentence together.
But don't focus on just the eloquence,
concentrate also on being distinct and real.
People want the real you.
People respect the real you.
People follow the real you.
Rule of thumb, don't disguise who you are,
be genuine, and people will respect you for it.
Hopefully people don't have to search you out and
you're in the basement or some cubicle,
so you want to be visible and available to everyone.
Visibility is about letting your key stakeholders get a feel
for who you are and what you care about.
You know it's easy to hide behind a computer or send email messages
to others without seeing or interacting with them.
Although e-communications, electronic communications,
serves a valuable purpose,
it is no substitute for face-to-face and voice-to-voice communication,
and I'm going to talk about that more later in a following section.
In today's environment,
people need to feel a personal connection to you
and the work that you believe in,
so do a walk around to make sure you're allocating the time
regularly to be out on the floor or in cubicles,
in the call center, in the computer lab,
or wherever your team or stakeholders reside,
but I will talk more about the walk around later in this module.
Rule of thumb,
show your people that you are engaged and care about them and their work.
Listen with your eyes, as well as your ears.
Stop, look, and listen.
Good leaders know how to ask good questions and then
listen with both their eyes and their ears.
Remember that effective communication is two way.
It's easy to be so focused on getting your message out or persuading others
that you don't have time to tune in to what you see and hear.
Because you're in a position of authority,
typically,
the stakes are even higher because you won't always get direct feedback.
You need to read between the lines, listen,
and hear what is coming back at you from your team and
your stakeholders and your managers.
So rule of thumb, look for non-verbal cues.
Sometimes in a person's body language,
it will tell you everything you need to know,
so it's kind of back to face-to-face.
It's really hard to get non-verbal cues with emails and telephone,
somewhat,
but face-to-face you can get quite a bit and it's so important to really get
a feel for the reaction to your communication content.
Always be enthusiastic.
I know that's pretty tough.
I find it hard even myself to always be enthusiastic, but check out this quote.
"Success is the ability to go from one failure to
another with no loss of enthusiasm.
" Okay, by Winston Churchill.
This guy had one failure after another during World War II,
and without his enthusiasm and drive, the UK,
the British Isles was lost for sure.
So let's read this again.
Even with say, three failures, or maybe a better word would be say setbacks,
in a row, can I still be successful?
I think you can as long as you are enthusiastic.
So rule of thumb for enthusiasm, don't be discouraged when things don't go well.
Your team will pick up on that and it will affect the productivity of your team. Okay, now let's move on to what I call the five Cs.