Here is a simple checklist of items I would like you to
use to better ensure your communications are effective and
you get the message across.
Let's check them out.
For all the forms of communication you may do,
I would like you to think and plan your communications ahead of time.
So before you click send or save or print,
I'd like you to follow the following five Cs checklist.
First, be clear.
That is,
be transparent and able to be easily comprehended in
what you write or speak about.
Be concise.
Use as few words as possible to get the necessary information or
compressed information in order to be brief.
Be courteous.
Always be polite in a way that shows consideration of others and good manners.
Be consistent, that is,
able to maintain a particular standard or repeat a particular
activity or artifact with minimal variation.
Be compelling.
We want your readers or listeners to understand your message and be attracted
to your message and encourage strong interest and attention.
And lastly, we want your stakeholders or customers to think,
hey,
I just received an email from my project manager and I can't wait to open it.
Here is our simple checklist.
So maybe make a little Post-it note on your computer screen to
the side that you can easily glance over at to be sure you are
always following the five Cs.
That's what I do.
It's very simple.
You go through the checklist, maybe modify an email,
modify a status, modify a PowerPoint presentation to get it just right.
Okay, now let's explore several communication tools and for each, let's apply our five Cs.