Here are the last four project control elements that we'll
discuss in this module: Risk management,
issue management, procurement management,
procurement meaning vendors or outside companies that you're
going to use to help you get your project done,
and of course quality management.
So the following slides will provide the reasons why we need these activities.
We'll sample roadmaps and process guidance and examples.
Okay, let's get started.
Risk management is the activity of identifying,
monitoring, and responding to risks so we don't euphemistically step in it.
The goal of managing project risk is to identify and prepare for
any potential threat to the project's success of achieving the
project's goals before they occur.
So let's talk about why we should do risk management.
So what's a risk?
Risk is something that could happen in the future that we want to be aware of,
but it hasn't happened yet.
If something has happened, we're going to call that an issue.
If something might happen out in the future,
we're going to call it a risk,
and we want to manage those risks of things that could happen,
and here are some examples.
Personnel and team changes that might happen in the future,
budget fluctuations, major scope changes that could happen,
maybe the business might sell to another company or
we're going to pick up another company, external project dependencies.
Well, if that project fails, that might affect our project.
If that project's milestone dates change, our dates might need to change.
It hasn't happened yet, but it could happen.
Organizational changes are quite common in businesses.
How would an organizational change affect your project if it happened?
Maybe some new and unproven technology that might be inserted into
the project in the future that we're not aware of.
Time to market factors.
In other words, we already have our project plan and our schedule in place,
but maybe some other market factors that could happen could affect the project.
Vendor or supplier issues.
Maybe our vendor is being bought out by another company could affect us.
And maybe just project manager issues with the project manager him or herself.
So again,
we may want to keep an eye out for these things that could happen that
could significantly affect what we're trying to do.
Okay,
now let's turn to the process of identifying and managing risks and
their dispositions or what we're going to do with them.
Here's how I might suggest you handling the risk
management process for yourself, and it's pretty straightforward.
Simply incorporate into your status meetings and reports a regular agenda item,
which is a risk management agenda item.
And you can say,
hey have we had any risks been identified since we met last time?
No?
Okay, move on.
Yes?
Okay, we're going to document that risk.
Maybe we heard about a reorganization.
Maybe we heard about a vendor might not want to support
us anymore or something like that.
Again, they haven't happened yet, but they could happen.
And for every one of these that we identify as a yes,
and typically there aren't very many,
risk management will not take very much time,
but should be a regular agenda item.
And here are a few different categories that I'd like to talk
about regarding each particular risk that you ---.
And here are the different categories I'd like you to
consider when you document a risk.
The likelihood: low, medium,
or high in terms of is it likely that this risk will actually happen?
Impact.
If it does happen, is it low, medium, or high?
How big of an impact will it be to the project?
And a priority as well.
You might want to combine the likelihood and impact values.
If the likelihood is quite high and the impact is quite high,
then the priority might also be quite high.
And you may want to monitor these each day or week as necessary,
and I think probably weekly is just fine.
You're going to have a status meeting with your team.
One of the agenda items will be risk management.
Any risk been identified?
It might be as simple as nope, none, then you move on.
And if you do identify a particular risk,
then you'll want to quickly go through okay you've identified a risk,
tell me the likelihood, impact, priority,
and let's monitor it.
Now you may also want to determine what would the action be that
you're going to take given that the risk does occur.
So know let's jump to the next slide and look at the possible
actions you may want to take for each risk identified.
Now that you've identified a potential risk and
you've documented its likelihood, its impact,
and its priority, you're going to want to assign a potential risk action to that,
and here are some examples I'd like you to consider.
First, given each particular risk, do you avoid the risk?
In other words,
let's just change the project plan so that risk would be eliminated.
Maybe you accept the risk.
No change to plan,
but you're going to inform management that this risk could happen,
but you continue on with your project with no change.
And maybe that you want to monitor the risk.
In other words, right now I'm not going to avoid it,
and I'm not going to accept it, but I want to monitor it.
And each week in your staff meeting or your project
planning meetings you'll look at your risks,
and you'll decide do we continue to monitor or do we take a different action?
Another action might be to mitigate that risk,
take some actions to reduce the impact of that risk.
It may not eliminate the risk,
but it might reduce the risk to the project by taking certain actions.
Also, you might want to transfer the risk,
shift the risk to another owner and inform management as well.
And I don't mean shirking your duties certainly,
but it may be that you know that there's a risk in the network infrastructure.
You're over here running the software web application,
that's your job, not necessarily the network,
but you understand there could be a network issue or some network downtime.
You may want to inform that owner that's responsible for the
network application and make sure they handle that so it's
not part of your risk anymore,
that they've taken that risk on as part of their job.
Okay, so remember,
risk avoidance is much better than reacting to a risk when it happens to you,
so plan ahead.
So now we have a process to identify, monitor, and take action on our risks.
Okay, let's go into the next action.
(Working) Now let's see a simple example how we can
track our risks in a risk tracking log.
Now they can be tracked in spreadsheet or a web-based system.
I like web-based so others can easily see what's going on,
but a spreadsheet will do just fine, keep things simple.
So here are some attributes and descriptions I'd like to talk about
regarding what you should track for each risk.
Maybe a risk ID, a unique ID to track that particular risk.
What's the name of the risk?
Could be something like potential network failures.
The probability of the risk between 1 and 100 that it's going to happen.
The source of the risk.
Is it budget, personnel, external factors, business, etc.? And the date log.
In other words, the date the risk was identified in one of your meetings.
Maybe some notes about it, a little more description that might be helpful.
And again, the action.
Are we going to avoid it, accept it, monitor it,
mitigate it or transfer, or maybe even TBD?
So this can be done very easily.
You may only have a half dozen risks to keep track of.
Not a big deal, but again risks can become massive issues on a project, so keep an eye on them, track them, and try to avoid them at all costs.