The next step, step three, is coming up with your acceptance criteria.
Now of course, you have your complete WBS,
and that is the 100% list of tasks for the entire project,
but that really isn't your acceptance criteria,
you want that to be written in business terms,
and a lot of times in the WBS things get lost and
there's too much detail in that,
so we want to layout a nice acceptance criteria in the
terms or words of the stakeholders, a little more business-oriented.
Now, they call also be phased,
maybe you have some milestones that come up in one month,
and then some the following month, or the following week,
or whatever, and a lot of times again it will be a list of major milestones,
so you might look at your WBS and look at a
collection or a cluster of tasks and go,
well, of these together implement a subsystem,
or all these together might be a set of 20 reports or something like that.
Okay, now let's see some examples of some acceptance criteria on the next slide.
Typically,
I recommend that acceptance criteria be in more business-oriented terms and
not very detailed task-oriented like our WBS may show.
For example, let's say you're using use cases,
all use cases must be demonstrable, that might be an acceptance criteria,
the system is not complete until that is true.
Another one might be, this feature set must be in production by May 1,
that's an acceptance criteria.
Maybe the feature set are 20 screens, or an API, or something like that.
Another example would be,
are the users all trained and productive by September 15,
so that's another form of an acceptance criteria.
Here's an example where a student can register and pay for a class.
Boy, if that feature set is complete and done, I accept that part of the system.
Another example, an employee can register, log in, and select medical plans.
Okay, if we can do those three things,
that's a great acceptance criteria and again,
an acceptance criteria can be laid out in phases,
so some of these could be done in phase one,
and then maybe a different set of criteria for phase two,
or phase three at different particular dates.
You know,
a tip I have is the system must perform all of the use
cases and comply with the specification,
so that was like my first acceptance criteria.
If I have a set of specs, my criteria would be as a user,
a consumer, or a stakeholder, it must do everything that I ask for in the spec,
but you, again,
you may want to lay that out in milestones over time to make it more palatable and easier to implement as well.