Hello, I am Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting module 2, Fundamentals,
in the course Project Management for Software Engineers.
Now let's cover what I will be presenting in the overview on the next slide.
Module overview.
Okay, here are our topics.
What's project management?
What's a project, projects versus operations?
What's a project manager, or how I will refer to as PM.
What does a project manager do?
What skills should a project manager have?
What qualities should a project manager have?
Project teams, you're not going to do everything alone of course.
And lastly, challenges, pitfalls, and what makes a successful project. Okay, let's get started.