Issue Management.
That's the activity of a identifying, tracking,
and resolving issues that could affect the project.
There will always be issues,
and you will need to manage and track each and every one of them,
and let's see how we'll do that.
Why do issue management you ask?
It is not if things will go wrong, but when,
so you must stay on top of any and all items that could be potential
issues or just plain problems for your project.
So what are issues?
Issues are events that have occurred that will adversely impact your project,
any issue whatsoever.
That means that all these must be resolved or they
will in fact impact your project.
Remember from before risks are potential issues that you're keeping a track on.
Remember risks are potential issues that you're keeping an eye on,
and they wouldn't fall under issue management.
Okay,
the most common issue you're going to manage certainly in
software development is going to be bugs.
These are defects of any issue.
The system blows up, the button is in the wrong place,
the data's not handled right, whatever,
so these are the most common types of issues you're going to manage,
and they're the bugs.
Okay,
now let's look at an example of an issue management process that you can use.
As with all of our project control elements, we always have a process, okay.
In the case of issue management, we always want to identify the issue,
record and document the issue, track the issue.
And again,
we can track it in a spreadsheet or a bug tracking
system or an issue tracking system, web-based,
cloud-based, whatever works for you.
Always do regular reviews.
This could be in your normal project planning meeting.
We want to have them resolved or reassigned.
For example, is this issue complete?
It's resolved.
It might not be complete.
Maybe the Q/A process found it still failing; therefore,
it gets reassigned back to the software engineering team.
And we always want to communicate the issues,
and they may be communicated in a variety of ways.
We want to communicate them to the software engineering
team so they know what to resolve.
We want to communicate to management, but maybe not the details.
For example,
we may want to communicate we have 28 open items or
we've solved 13 items last week, we have 4 items open this week,
high-level issue management statuses to management.
Okay, but also we may have to communicate back to the requirement.
So not only will we communicate to management,
we may also need to communicate back to the requirements management
part of one of our key activities because the issues and how they get
resolved may affect the requirements.
Also,
the issues and how they get resolved might affect
configuration management as well.
And lastly, based on the particular issue,
it might enlighten us to a potential risk,
and we want to start tracking that risk in our risk management process as well.
Okay, now let's look at a simple example.
Here's a sample issue tracking log.
Issues can easily be tracked in a spreadsheet or a web-based system.
I like web-based so others can easily see what's going on,
but a spreadsheet will do just fine.
Usually have a unique issue ID so we can track and
easily identify the particular issue.
We give it a name, maybe even a short phrase, maybe even a description.
The type.
Maybe it's software, hardware, people, management,
or if it's software maybe there's three or four
different modules in your system,
and maybe you give it a type for each particular module,
some way to categorize and easily identify a collection of issues.
Priority is always important, low, medium,
high, and of course hot, got to get it done right away.
The date that is was logged,
maybe some notes about some additional information or maybe a
screen shot or references and things like that.
And a status, open, assigned, closed.
Open, it's not worked on yet; assigned, it's in progress,
it's being worked; and closed, it's resolved.
Of course you can add many other attributes that would be
important to your particular project.
As long as you have an issue tracking system and an issue tracking log,
keep an eye on your issues, you'll be doing just fine,
and it'll be very helpful of course for the success of your project as well.
Okay, if you want,
you can probably track issues and risks in the same logging system.
That might be easier to do, consolidate both.
But again, the kinds of things that reflect in tracking are slightly different,
but to save on having multiple systems or multiple logs you
might be able to integrate the two together, and that'd be just fine as well.