Procurement management is the activity of managing
suppliers and vendors supporting the project.
Now it is quite likely that you and your project team may be
unable to do all of the tasks; therefore,
you may need to bring on some help.
So you may need to have other suppliers or vendors,
consultants, contractors, etc.
to come on to the project to help,
and this section is how to manage that process.
Why do procurement management, or as we also call it vendor management?
It is likely that your project will need products or
services provided by third-party companies,
and therefore your project will need some amount of procurement management.
Now your company may have a procurement or vendor management organization.
You will need to comply with your company's policy,
and every company may be a little different.
I would suggest you have a contact or team member from your
company's procurement department for your projects.
Now here are a few examples of what you may need from outside or
third-party companies: Maybe a consulting company to help design
your application architecture,
maybe a hardware company that's going to supply PCs or hardware or services,
maybe a service provider that will enable you to use
cloud-based services and things like that,
possibly even professional services to provide additional developers as well.
So procurement management is something you need to think about and
incorporate into your processes for project management.
Here's an example of a procurement management process
that you can follow for your projects.
First off,
your process needs to describe how the procurement process will be managed.
In other words, how will you work with your vendors?
That needs to be understood and therefore documented.
You'll also want to define the role between the project manager,
yourself possibly, and the team with the vendor.
Maybe your role will be to provide requirements only
to the procurement department,
and the procurement organization will handle the contracts and negotiations.
As I mentioned in the previous slide,
you need to find out whether you have a procurement
organization who will handle those things,
or will you as a PM handle those procurement items yourself.
Next,
you need to define the actual components of the contract
like terms and conditions for example.
Also,
be sure to incorporate the vendor deliverables into your project
plan and schedule so whatever the vendor is going to provide is
integrated right into your plan.
Clearly define the working relationship between you and your team
and each vendor provided resource or resources,
such as who are the contact points, maybe name,
phone number, email, etc., and who will go where,
and who will you go to if there is an issue with the deliverables of the vendor.
That's real important too.
Issues will happen.
You'll want to know who the contact point is so you
can quickly get them resolved.
Next,
you want to define the integration points especially between
software as a service and your infrastructure.
So the previous items here on the chart were more
of the business side of things,
but also you're going to be doing some real technical work.
So much now is going to the cloud and software as a service.
What are those endpoints or connection points, API's, etc.
between your infrastructure and software as a service or the cloud?
So, for example, if you're procuring a cloud-based service,
how will the endpoints of the service integrate into
your company's infrastructure?
So that needs to be specifically defined in your contract as well.
Now I'd like to talk about two sample components of the contract
between the vendor and your company in the next slide.
Now how do we ensure that the third party company
will perform to what you expect?
Well,
you may want to consider adding these procurement components to your contracts.
One area would be a service level agreement, or SLAs.
It's part of your service contract where the service is formally defined.
It's agreed to by yourself, of course,
or the procurement organization of your company and the service provider,
and as an example will have contractor delivery dates,
milestones, response times.
All those factors should be in there and clearly outlined.
Another component, sometimes we call this KPIs,
or key performance indicators,
now they represent a set of measures critical for the success of the project,
so you're going to want to think about this and select some KPIs that
would have a significant impact on the project.
This helps guide the third-party vendor to meet your project goals.
For an example, maybe it's zero defects,
maybe it's progress towards milestones and things like that,
so having SLAs and KPIs as part of the overall contract with
third-party vendors is very important and critical to ensuring that
they deliver what you want and when you want it. Now let's move on to the final project control activity, quality.