There is more to managing your customer's expectations than just managing scope.
Now scope is, of course, very important and an interval part of your job.
Your goal is to have a common set of expectations
shared by all of the stakeholders.
You can achieve this common ground by designing and
building your project definition document,
your project plans,
and your project control activities that we covered in previous modules.
Your stakeholders will know what to expect if there is a change,
for example, since you have a change management process.
Critical success factors will be your project definition document,
your project plans, and your project control activities.
Next, project impacts.
Communicate a common vision of the project outcomes.
Help stakeholders prepare for the changes that will
affect them and their organizations.
And lastly, work products - the actual deliverables of your project.
Keep your stakeholders aware at all times on the deliverables, issues, etc.
And with good project control, you can certainly do that.
Lastly, how well would you be rated by your customer?
And lastly, I'll call your attention to the little chart on the left,
how well would you be rated by your customer?
Excellent, very good, good, average, poor?
You might consider asking them how well are you doing?
Face-to-face,
have meetings with your stakeholders that aren't just about the project per say,
but about your performance as a PM.
Seek their mentoring and guidance.
That builds more trust and that builds better relationships.
Managing customer expectations is challenging,
so here's a list of handy tips to use not just in the beginning of a project,
but throughout its lifecycle.
Acquire buy-in.
Invest time and energy to gain their trust and to make sure you
have genuine buy-in from the stakeholders.
Take care of business.
Yep, get the work done, set your baselines,
manage them, and communicate any variances promptly.
Communicate the vision.
Clearly sell the project's vision and expected outcomes
throughout the project lifecycle.
Be a good listener.
Look for cues and signals from the stakeholders that may imply things are amiss.
Then make it a priority to deal with them promptly.
Seek the customer's viewpoint.
This ties deeply into customer service and managing customer expectations.
Put yourself in their shoes to better understand their situation.
This can empower you to better manage and adapt your plans and
specifications to better meet the project's requirements.
Never, ever assume.
Constantly confirm understanding by asking questions,
repeating what was said, taking good notes,
and delivering quality communications.
Keep focused on priorities.
Now not every stakeholder is created equally.
Yes, address the collective stakeholder requirements,
but some stakeholders may have greater influence or political power. And be sure to also attend to them appropriately.