Now let's turn to relationship building.
You will need to use your skills to forge and build
quality relationships to get things done.
One area that is challenging is working in gray or fuzzy areas.
IT and IT departments and IT people tend to like to
work on what I call the binary, more black and white.
In earlier in my career, I was very black and white.
Now I've come to understand that the world is gray and how best can
we work within and resolve those gray issues.
Unfortunately, many of the people issues that plague projects are well, gray.
So in other words, there is no right or wrong answer,
but there is a need to find a place where everyone is comfortable so
that we can continue to move the project forward.
Also, clear thinking, outcome focused.
Those who can identify and articulate the problem,
bring it out in the open,
and get it solved are instrumental in shortening project snags and timelines.
So many times I'm in meetings and discussions and they seem
to center around things that just aren't that pertinent or
relevant for the topic at hand.
Politely and professionally steer the conversation back to
where it needs to be and keep it focused.
My observation is that us, IT people,
are not known as particularly politically astute.
I know I certainly wasn't early in my career.
And some people actually like to be software engineers and be
very technical to avoid all that political mess,
but in the PM world, you really can't avoid it.
So I was in that camp for a long time.
Now it's time to change camps as a PM and understand politics.
Projects benefit when it has individuals like you who can forge strong
relationships with different constituencies throughout the company.
Relationship building facilitates project cooperation and success.
So in order to better do those things,
you need to know your organization and who's who.
So get out that org chart, figure out who are the influencers,
people with budget,
business ideas that you may need to work with to get their help,
so you can get the project successfully completed.
Let's make a deal.
IT is a matchup of technology and people to produce products
and services that run a company's business,
but when people get involved,
there are bound to be disagreements and a need to arrive at group consensus.
So we need PMs who can work with people.
We need PMs to find a common ground so projects and goals can be agreed to,
and we need PMs to swallow their egos, leave those at the door. These traits make some of the best PMs out there.