Now you might have thought at this time your project plan is complete,
but it is not.
There are other required elements of your plan,
and in particular I call these the elements for project control,
now let's see what they are.
At this point in the planning, you have created a project plan,
which included the WBS, acceptance criteria,
you assigned resources, made an estimate,
made a schedule, and maybe even did a resource loading plan as well,
but there are other supporting planning elements to include in your document.
Now these planning elements are more around the process of running the project,
AKA project control and execution.
For example, how would you do the following,
how are you going to do project status reporting,
requirements management, issue management,
is there more?
Yes, there's absolutely more, and let's see what these are,
because these are very important elements of your project plan as well.
There are eight elements for project control, and here are the first four.
Reporting, how will you report on the progress and status of your project?
You will need a plan or an approach to be included in your project plan.
Change control, how will you mange change control?
Again, you will need a plan or approach to be included in your project plan.
Configuration management, how will you do that?
What's your plan or approach for that?
This also will be included in your plan.
Requirements management, another very key element of project control,
and you will need this in your plan as well.
So what we covered before, the tasks, the estimates,
the schedule, the project definition document,
those are very common and typical elements of a project plan,
and most of the time, people stop there and start moving forward.
What I'm suggesting to you are,
these are additional elements that are extremely critical
as well to the success of your project, and let's look at four more.
And here are the next four project plan elements for project control.
Our first one is risk management,
how are you going handle risks that might come up in the project?
Issue management, how will you handle issues?
What are your plans again in order to do these items?
Procurement management.
And the last one is quality management.
Now all eight of these additional elements of your project plan will be
discussed in detail in the next module on project control, so I'll see you there in a few moments.