Well, we've made it across the finish line.
We have executed and finished our project.
Let's do a summary wrap up.
Let's now summarize the project execution module.
We discussed three key areas, leadership,
effective communication, and relationship management.
You must find ways to engage people and stir their
commitment to the project's goals.
As a leader,
a project's success will be all about growing others and one of the key
and most important attributes of a leader is trust.
If they trust you, they will follow you on all levels.
So why would anyone want to be led by you?
Will they follow?
Well here are three key behaviors of a good leader.
One, real leaders empathize fiercely with the people they lead.
They also care intensely about the work their employees do.
Two,
another quality of good leaders is that they capitalize
on what's unique about themselves,
so what makes sense to you about what makes you a leader.
So what makes you a special leader?
Your expertise?
Your honesty, integrity?
Next and number three,
people do not commit to project managers who merely live
up to the obligations of their jobs.
They want more.
They want someone who cares passionately about the people and the work,
just like they do.
Effective communication is all about getting the right information to the
right people at the right time and using the right method.
Other great communication tips are do as you say,
make the complex simple, find your stride,
be available and visible, be a good listener,
and always be enthusiastic even in tough times.
The five Cs.
Be clear, that is be transparent and able to be easily comprehended.
Be concise.
Use as few words as possible to get the necessary information or
compressed information in order to be brief.
And be courteous.
Be polite in a way that shows consideration for others.
Be consistent.
Be able to maintain a particular standard or repeat a particular
activity or artifact with minimal variation.
And lastly, be compelling.
We want your readers or listeners to your messages be attracted to your
message and encourage strong interest and attention.
Then we talked about the five Ps.
These are the characteristics of a project manager for
delivering great customer service.
First is provider.
You will provide the needs and desires of your customer.
You are focused on their needs.
Promptness.
Promises for delivery of your services must be on time.
Politeness.
Politeness and good manners not only with your customers,
but every one you deal with.
This builds your quality and character.
Professionalism shows the customer they're cared for and
this builds trust in you and your team.
Personalization.
Using the customer's name is very effective in
producing a connection with each other.
Lastly, managing customer expectations.
Yep, and it is very challenging.
And you may be sailing into uncharted waters,
such as gray areas where there is no right or wrong answer,
but there is a need to find a place that everyone is comfortable
with so things can continue to move forward.
Also, political smarts.
Know your organization and who's who.
Get out that org chart and figure out who are the influencers that you may need
to work with to help you get your project done successfully.
Last, get to win-win.
Remember, it's not your way or my way, it's a better way,
so work towards all parties where they feel good about the decisions being made.
Okay, that wraps up this module.
In the next module and final module,
we will discuss project closure and do a course summary. See you in the next module.