Why are you here?
It is likely that since you are an avid user of Pluralsight,
that your responsibilities are likely software engineering,
or at a broader level, systems engineering.
And maybe your management has come to you and has asked,
or even told you, that you will need to stop maybe,
or slow down, or change slightly, on working on software development,
and maybe even start running projects.
Well now what?
You've probably had some,
or most of these feelings: are you afraid of
leadership or management responsibilities?
Are you confused on just how to develop project plans?
Have you been asked to be a leader, and maybe, not a doer as much?
Are you a software engineering expert,
yet feel like a fish out of water when it comes to managing a project?
Do you need help augmenting,
or transitioning your technical skills with project management skills?
Have you been asked to be a project manager on a new project?
Is your project over budget, missing milestones?
Well if so, then you've come to the right place.
Now let's cover who this course is best suited for.
This course in an introductory project management course,
a 101 course if you will.
And it's well positioned for three categories or viewers.
First, technical professionals new to project management,
such as software or systems engineers, senior engineers,
or technical team leaders.
Second, business professionals new to project management,
such as project leaders or coordinators,
project managers, or even functional managers.
Lastly,
anyone interested in developing and improving their project management skills.
So this course is primarily geared to technical people looking to begin
learning all about project management or looking to improve their
existing project management and leadership skills. Okay, now let's go over the course overview, and then the objectives.