Definition: what's project management?
This section will cover definitions, and concepts,
defining just what project management is.
Okay, let's begin with definition of project management on the next slide.
Project management,
it's the planning and organization of a company's or
organization's resources in order to move a specific task,
event, service, or product toward completion.
Okay, the short version of that is, the process of managing projects.
So just what is the process of managing a project?
Well, let's find out on the next slide.
The project management process is your management,
technical, and leadership skills applied to the planning,
organizing, controlling, implementing,
and leading all of the activities of a project to meet the project's goals.
I'd also like to point out that a project's goals should be tightly
linked to the organization's business strategies,
and in a good company, they typically are.
So basically, this is the class in a nutshell.
This module, and the modules following, will do just that.
And those modules will be called Planning, Control, and Execution. Okay, let's move on.