This course is comprised of the following modules.
In the Course Overview, the one we're in now,
we will discuss why you are here, who this course is for,
and course objectives, and also what this course is not.
Then we will talk about why industry needs,
and I would like to say, desperately needs,
project managers, and people just like you.
Then, Fundamentals.
We will discuss the basic definitions of project management,
such as what a project is, what project management is,
what are a project managers duties,
but also what qualities make the best project manager as well.
Then we'll move on to Planning.
This module will define, discuss,
and provide examples for creating a project definition document,
and I think, your key to a successful project.
You'll also learn the steps in creating a project plan,
which includes the work breakdown structure,
resourcing, estimation, scheduling, and resource loading.
Control.
This module will discuss reporting, change control,
configuration management, requirements management,
risk and issue management, procurement management,
quality management, and lastly, variance analysis.
Next, Execution.
In this module we'll discuss leadership,
effective communication, and relationship management.
Please pay close attention to this module.
These skills will definitely make or break a project.
And lastly, Project Closure and Course Summary.
In the final module, we will discuss the activities of closing a project,
and then we will summarize the entire course.
Okay, now let's discuss the course objectives.
Now let's cover the course objectives.
First, we're going to illustrate key fundamentals,
concepts, and tools of project management,
basically, project management 101.
I want to provide a relatively condensed course,
with appropriate depth and content to immediately apply to your job.
I hope this course will also reduce your on-the-job learning
curve by sharing some of my experiences,
some of my successful, and some of my not so successful.
Yes, failures help you improve your skills and approach for the next project.
We will emphasize the importance of communication skills.
This is huge.
Since many of you come from a technical background,
and have tons of technical skills,
this course will help you beef up your communication skills as well.
We will provide the guidance and knowledge to help you jumpstart your projects.
The material in this course is succinct and to the point,
so you can easily apply the tools and techniques to your projects.
You will learn the general processes of project management,
such as project planning, control, execution,
and closure.
I will highlight the importance of leadership.
Leadership and project management are two different things,
and both required for successful projects.
Lastly, I'll provide the basic knowledge to enhance your career opportunities.
Personally, I started my career as a software engineer,
and evolved, grew,
changed my career path to management and leadership over the years,
and I have no regrets, and feel, professionally,
more fulfilled.
Now let's see what this course is not going to cover.
Now let's talk about what this course is not,
that is, what we will not be covering.
This is not a course to prepare you specifically for a PMP exam.
That's a Project Management Professional type of exam,
and is a credential offered by the PMI, the Project Management Institute.
Also, this is not a course on PPM, Project Portfolio Management,
and that's a centralized activity of processes,
methods, and technologies used to manage multiple projects.
And this is not a course on the PMO, the Project Management Office.
That's part of a business that defines and maintains standards
for project management within the organization.
So these are somewhat formal elements of project management,
and there are formal classes you can take and be certified.
This class is more of just plain experience that I've had over multiple years,
multiple projects, multiple customers, very practical, and something you can use and jump on right away.