Definition: what's a project manager?
Well, that's you.
Now let's see what your job is all about on the following slides.
Project manager, 100% responsible for the processes used to manage the project.
Yep, 100%.
Tag, you're it.
In other words, I'm all in.
Or in your case, you're all in.
It's all on your shoulders, you are responsible, no one else.
It's a lot of work, a lot of challenge, but a lot of reward as well.
Okay, so let's drill down to more detail in the following slides.
What's a project manager?
Wears many hats, and juggles many balls in the air.
Be prepared to leverage and use all of your skills.
Person with authority to manage a project.
Now the word authority sounds good as a descriptor,
but therein lies one of the main challenges of being a project manager.
You may typically have the responsibility,
yes it's on you, but not necessarily the authority,
since, for example, the team may not directly report to you.
Responsible for planning, control, execution, and closing of your project.
Yes, that is your job.
And we will have a module on each one, planning,
control, and execution in this course.
Central point of contact for all project communications.
As you will learn in the execution module on communications,
you, and only you, should manage all project communications.
Champion and change agent for the project and the organization.
A change agent is someone in the organization who helps
an organization transform itself,
by focusing on critical business strategy improvements.
You as a PM will be leading projects that tie in to the
important business strategies of your organization.
Perform issue and risk identification and remediation.
A PM will look at everything as a risk or issue.
Okay, I might be a little cynical, or maybe just experienced?
Of course, this is just the short overview list.
We will get into the nitty gritty details throughout the course.
Now here's a little more on what's a project manager.
Responsible for accomplishing the stated project objectives.
Sure, that makes sense.
Sometimes this can be a balancing act, for sure.
Key project management responsibilities will include,
creating clear and attainable project objectives,
what is it this project is going to do and accomplish,
building the project requirements of the customer or client,
bridging the gap between the project team and the customer/client,
you're going to need your interpersonal skills,
leadership skills to bridge that gap between real end business user,
and your technical team.
And lastly, managing the constraints of cost, time, scope, and quality.
Managing these constraints, cost, time, scope,
and quality, this is where you'll likely spend most of your time.
Be careful, you have many other things to attend to,
as you'll learn in the other modules, but trust me,
these are the elements you're going to spend a lot of time on.
Okay, let's segue to talk a moment about what is known as the iron triangle,
or what I call the project triangle dilemma,
on the next slide.
The project triangle dilemma is composed of the following.
Cost, scope, schedule, and in the middle, quality.
And in the middle lies the dilemma.
So as project managers, we are striving for user satisfaction.
User satisfaction is when the system meets the requirements,
the scope, at a reasonable cost, the estimate,
and is delivered when needed, that would be the schedule.
Now the three of these will generally always be at odds with each other,
and will affect the quality of the product and service.
When I think about it,
most of your time as a project manager will likely be
spent working on these elements.
Scope will change, cost will change, schedule will change,
but if one changes the other two must also change typically,
and that's why they're always at odds, that's why I call it the dilemma,
and that's where many of your hours will be spent in
terms of managing the quality.
Because of that, and the importance of this,
let's talk a little further about the project
triangle dilemma on the next slide.
Now let's drill down just a little bit more on the project triangle dilemma.
Scope, what the customers want the system to do.
Now you might want to check out another one of my Pluralsight courses,
Best Practices for Requirements Analysis,
which focuses on tools and techniques that help you determine quality,
scope, and requirement specifications.
Next, schedule, when your customers need their new system,
and typically the schedule is roughly around the corner,
it's usually hurry up and get it done, and that's a real challenge,
it will be a big challenge for you.
And sometimes, there may even be a hard date to make,
maybe just one big milestone.
So if possible, try and break up that date,
or that milestone, into more manageable progressive dates and milestones.
It'll therefore show incremental progress,
and build trust in you and your team, and to your customer as well.
Cost, estimate, budget,
what can they afford or are they willing to spend on the project?
Now here again,
you might want to check out another one of my Pluralsight courses,
Best Practices for Project Estimation,
which focuses on tools and techniques to help you determine quality estimates.
Making estimates is very a challenging activity and takes some
practice and some tools to get good at it.
Your future customers and users will always ask you for a cost estimate,
so get prepared so you can give one. Now, let's look at more detail at your responsibilities on the next slide.