The following are your typical responsibilities that you'll do as a PM.
You'll develop the project plan, you'll manage the project stakeholders,
those interested in getting the project complete,
on time, and on budget.
You'll manage communications, just how will you talk to your team,
how will you talk to your customers, how will you status your project,
and so forth.
You'll manage a project team, so you'll need some leadership skills.
You'll manage the project risk,
so you can avoid pitfalls that might actually really destroy your project.
You'll manage the project schedule, it's got to be done on time,
and it's got to be done on budget, so you'll be managing to costs as well,
and any particular project conflicts that come up among users,
team members, issues, budgets, problems,
customers, vendors, you name it, conflicts will happen.
And lastly, the project delivery, how it actually really gets delivered,
installed, and supported when you complete it,
the rollout, the pilot, things like that.
So the previous activities generally require what I might
call hard skills versus soft skills.
I think it's important to kind of understand the
differences between those skill types, and let's explore those on the next slide.
Now let's take a quick moment to define and understand two
main categories of skills you will need.
On the left, hard skills, on the right, soft skills.
Hard skills are about a person's skill set and ability to
perform a certain type of task or activity.
And some examples are programming, database design,
maybe using Excel spreadsheet, create a project plan,
budgets, and schedules, etc., like those items I mentioned on the previous slide,
those would be hard skills.
Soft skills on the other hand are personal attributes that
enhance an individual's interactions, and job performance,
and career prospects.
These examples would be leadership, speaking,
people, being able to be around people, at ease with people,
and relate with people, interpersonal relationships,
etc.
And after many years of managing people and leading projects,
yes you need those hard skills, definitely,
but the most successful project managers I've seen are the ones
that really can leverage the soft skills.
So just take a moment to think about that,
and you might want even do some more research on your soft skills.
This class is primarily on hard skills,
but I really want to point out the soft skills side,
and I'm going to touch on communication skills and
leadership skills in the execution modules.
Okay, now let's see some examples of just what I mean.
Key hard skills of a project manager.
The first, is business.
You must have a fair knowledge of the industry you are in,
so that you are capable of understanding and
discussing the business requirements.
The second would be process.
You need to have the ability to adapt to the various internal
procedures of a company or organization,
or create new ones for the organization.
And of course, technical.
You must have a reasonable and general understanding of
the technical aspects of the project.
Remember though, if you feel weak in an area,
add a team member, so just an application architect,
for example, to shore up your skills.
Okay, now let's take a deeper look at the soft skills side on the next slide.
The previous slide listed management activities or technical skills.
Here, the following are key soft skills that may make or break your project.
The first, communication.
You must have very good speaking, writing, and listening skills.
These are very important, but they are learnable.
Second, leadership/people.
You must have the ability to lead and manage people,
in any sort of organizational arrangement.
Third, customer service.
This is essential in ensuring that the key issues of scope,
cost, time, schedule, quality, that we discussed before,
and client satisfaction or user satisfaction can be realized.
In summary,
these are all the soft skills that will enable you to form close links
with the project stake holders or representatives,
which is so, so critical to the success of your project.
Now let's review some key project manager attributes on the next slide.
Key attributes of a project manager.
So what's an attribute?
An attribute is a characteristic of a person.
This is slightly different from the skills we
talked about on the previous slides.
The first, ownership.
It's when you have the attitude that this is mine,
and I will do the very best I can do, rather than,
not my problem.
As a PM, they are all your problems.
Integrity, the quality of being honest and having strong principles.
This is so important on building trust,
and trust is one of the key elements you will need to work through the
project management issues that you will confront.
The third, is effective communicator.
Effective communication by business managers facilitates
information sharing between company employees,
team members, management, vendors,
and can substantially contribute to the project's success.
Next, are you a people person?
A person who enjoys or is particularly good at interacting with others.
This is another key attribute that's very essential
for a successful project manager.
Next, process oriented.
Process orientation places a priority on how things are done.
For example, how are meetings conducted?
How are requirements written?
How was software tested?
These elements and attention to detail for a process I think are
very important as well for a project manager.
And lastly,
the ability to stay focused and not easily distracted from the objective.
Some people are easily distracted and even like being distracted and unfocused.
I call these types firefighters.
They would rather jump on little short activities,
rather than the longer more important projects.
Now, let's turn our attention to project teams,
because you will need a team of people to help you get your job done. We'll see this on the next slide.