Challenges and pitfalls, and how to avoid them.
In our final section,
we'll explore why projects are challenging and how to avoid their pitfalls.
Why are projects challenging?
Yes, that's you over there to enter the project maze.
So why can projects be so daunting and challenging?
Well, a lot of times projects have just never been done before,
so they have to figure out, well how are we going to get this done?
A lot of times, there's various needs and expectations.
There's so many people involved, different viewpoints,
and different expectations, it's hard to manage and integrate those together,
very challenging.
Communication challenges, how you talk to people,
how people talk to you, how you convey messages,
and requirements documents, and status reports,
metrics,
all those things can be quite challenging to prepare
and to deliver to your audience.
Also the project triangle dilemma we talked about before,
which is balancing the scope, cost, and schedule.
Those are very challenging things to do in all projects I have ever been on.
And there's a few more on the next slide.
Why projects are challenging, part two.
Creative and innovative focus.
Many times, since projects are done for the first time,
and they may be highly creative or new or innovative focus,
those make it more challenging than just your normal operational type of work.
Also, organizational hurdles, what I call now and later.
You're working within an organization, it may be very structured and stiff,
and may not be that supportive of your project.
And also what I mean by and later,
is many times projects will drive organizational change,
there may be new departments created to support the result of a project,
or there may be departments that are dissolved because of that.
And trust me,
the people in those departments that are being dissolved may not
want to work with you on a project very closely.
Stakeholder collaboration.
You typically have multiple stakeholders that have multiple agendas,
and you want to be sure that they collaborate in such a way that
supports and fosters the success of your project.
And of course just plain old requirements and estimates.
Requirements are always changing, estimates may be changing,
budgets may be changing, so those are always very,
very challenging as well.
But as you can see, on the left, you've made it through the maze,
and I hope it's because of the things you're going to learn,
and have learned in this Pluralsight course.
Okay, so we know things will go wrong, so now let's see how we can fix them,
on the next slide.
Oops, be prepared and plan ahead.
Things will go wrong, it is inevitable.
So what I'd like to list is a few things that could go wrong,
and how to fix them, so you can be prepared and plan accordingly.
So here's a quick checklist.
So on the left, what can go wrong, and how I think you can fix it.
Project misaligned with business.
Sometimes you may be given a project that you just see no value,
it's nothing to do with the business, it's not tied to the business,
typically those will fail.
So what you'd like to do, early on, is go back,
validate with the stakeholders first,
just want to make sure this project is in line with the business goals,
is everything, you know, going according to plan,
is it budgeted right, and we're all on board with it,
and we all support it.
If you have that feeling that the project is not
quite aligned with the business, please,
check first with the stakeholders.
Next, lack of management, or stakeholder buy-in.
Maybe the project is aligned with business, but no one cares anymore.
Unfortunate.
So gain acceptance, and continuously validate.
So,
you want to make sure you have a good and close
relationship with the stakeholders, get their acceptance,
and then continuously status to them and talk to them and make sure that,
hey, are we still on track on what we're doing for the company.
Other things that can go wrong certainly are just poor
communications or what I call project confusion.
So, use a project communications plan,
and we're going to dedicate a module on that,
is how is that you communicate and how should you communicate,
what you should say and how you should say it.
No time or support for planning.
I see this a lot, this is typically a senior management issue,
they give you a project, they don't give you any time to plan,
and you start running.
And, I understand that, but as much as you can,
try to educate management on the value of planning.
Next, poor or changing requirements.
Okay guys, let's hurry up and get it done, but we're not sure what we're doing.
So, if you can, perform solid requirements analysis first,
so you do know what it is you're doing.
Next, poor estimates/changing budgets.
Now, budgets will change, I get that, that's a part of a business organization,
and you can accommodate that.
Okay, budget changes, usually it means it's smaller,
maybe you can modify the scope and move forward.
But if you make poor estimates, or poor estimates are given to you,
it's likely going to go south.
So use a good estimating process, and a change management process as well.
Okay, now let's see what makes a successful project.
What makes a successful project?
Okay, what I'm about to show is just a partial list.
But here are the key items of what makes a successful project.
First, you.
Yes, you.
A great project manager and your effective leadership.
Certainly, senior management support.
Always make sure you have good senior management support.
Stakeholder support, sometimes, they're one in the same,
but typically there's an overlap a little bit.
Common vision and expectations across the business,
senior management, and the stakeholders.
A project that is in line with the business goals and objectives.
A solid project scope and any changes that may have occurred to that scope,
with good change management, that are clearly defined,
and agreed upon, by your stakeholders.
Lastly, the project team is customer focused and results oriented.
And this can be a great checklist for you to use in the future.
If you see any of these that are not quite right,
then jump in, and try to understand why,
and see if you can remediate it with your effective communication skills.
Not sure about your communication skills?
Well, hang on, we'll tackle those in some of the other modules, but first, let's summarize this module.