Okay, let's summarize the key points of this module.
Project management.
That's the planning and organization of a company's or
organization's resources in order to move a specific task,
event, service, or product toward completion.
The project.
A temporary group activity designed to produce a unique product,
service, or result.
A project has a defined beginning time and ending time,
with a defined scope and assigned resources.
When is an activity a project?
Now each company or organization will have different
thresholds as to what is a project versus,
say, a normal operational activity.
Some threshold examples were dollars, hours,
time, things like that, and may also be criticality,
or focus to the business.
Typically, companies will have a project request process,
and a project review process, which would vet or approve,
you know, each of those as candidate projects.
The project manager, that's you.
You are 100% responsible for the processes used to manage the project.
The project triangle dilemma.
This is the competition between scope, budget and costs,
schedule, and most importantly quality.
You'll spend much of your time in that triangle.
Hard and soft skills.
Hard skills are about a person's skill set and ability to
perform a certain type of task or activity.
And soft skills are more personal attributes that
enhance an individual's interactions, job performance,
and career prospects.
Key attributes, such as ownership, the attitude that this is mine,
and I will do the very best I can.
Integrity, the quality of being honest and having strong principles.
Effective communication,
which facilitates information sharing between company employees,
team members, and management.
Being a people person,
a person who enjoys or is particularly good at interacting with others.
Process oriented, in that you place a priority on how things get done.
And the ability to stay focused, and not easily distracted from the objective.
Project teams.
They may work directly for you, they may work for another manager,
but are assigned to you, also, they may be full or part-time,
so your team will likely be a hybrid of resources.
Successful projects, that's you,
a great project manager and your effective leadership.
Also,
senior management and stakeholder support all having
a common vision and expectations.
And lastly,
a project will be successful if it is in line with the
business's goals and objectives.
Okay, let's jump into the next module, Project Planning,
and learn some tools and simple approaches to improve your planning and project skills.