Now we'll delve back into your local development environment and check out the way Wordpress is installed
There are several default themes present with the newest one activated and a couple of standard plug
And there are a few that should be changed to use best practices in this video.
are important.
Let's go first let's get set up with our local WordPress installation that we set up in the previous
I'm going to start map and it's already started so I can see the Apache server and the MiSeq will server
the web server tab and I can see that under-sea colon H.T. docs under the map folder is where I have
a WordPress installation will be the name of my web site.
If you remember I set up WP of course one as my wordpress Web site.
But let's open windows explorer and if I look under C colon and in the map folder under H.T. docs you
If you open windows explorer you can go and see which folders you have and what are their names and
Web site as long as map is running.
Now in the default installation the maildir sidebar information is down here on the right hand side
and there is a log in button I'll usually right click on that and click Open link in New Tab and I already
So now I'm logged in to my fresh WordPress installation that has all the defaults set up and I'm now
I'm using WordPress in a local environment and it's going to be the fastest setup for creating new sites
and managing my coursework.
Go ahead and navigate to your own WordPress installation and we'll get started looking at the defaults.
First of all if you open the website itself you can see that this is the 2016 theme.
Let's go back to the tab.
Open up appearance and themes.
And look let's look at which themes come with wordpress at this point.
One is called 20:16 it tells me that it's the active theme.
If you click each of the theme details buttons you can look at what themes the current theme.
There's a few control buttons here but I don't usually use these control buttons to customize my websites.
I'll use the ones that are over here under appearance.
You can click the small arrow at the top left to go through the themes that are installed in your workplace
installation and look at that actual traits for each one of them.
And the X closes that modal window
if you rollover plugins and then click install plugins you can see that WordPress ships with two plugins
already installed.
Now they're not activated but they are installed Ekis meant prevents comment spam and hello Dolly is
And if we activate the Hello Dolly plug in you can see that it's very simple.
What it does is it gives you a quote from the Hello Dolly musical in the top of your dashboard.
Every time you go to a different page
Now this isn't a plug in.
You might go into the plug ins list which I often do and I delete that plug in I like to keep my dashboard
So once it's not activated you can hit delete and go ahead and delete the files.
And then that plug it won't be in your play list anymore.
X-Men is a great plug in to activate once you've got your site set up and configured because if you
and emailing the managers and the administrators of the site.
For now all on building sites I just keep it in activated.
Now if I go up and roll over users and look at your profile you can see some information about your
When viewing site now by default WordPress has this checkbox enabled and if you go over to the Web site
dashboard and other places to manage your site as well as your user profile and log in and log out button
over here a member of the public wouldn't be seeing this toolbar so I prefer to go back and uncheck
the toolbar box.
Update my profile.
And then because I work between two tabs in my browser I can refresh the page and that toolbar disappears.
Thereby showing me the way the site would look to the general public.
Back in the dashboard if you click Settings general or just the Settings button you'll open the general
Initially the site title of course but then the tagline is a default tagline just on the wordpress site
you might change that to something more appropriate for your client.
The WordPress address of the site you are LDS are probably the same as what was set up when you were
All these are part of the defaults.
And as we roll down membership means that you can have people register as a user on the site and when
will go through as we go into making membership sites in the future I'll usually leave this unchecked
for a regular web site for a client.
I will change the time zone and not only the UTC times with the numbers but there are also time zones
in different cities across the world.
You can just type the first few letters of the largest city around and see if that is the same time
Denver is the one for me and I choose a date format a time format that fits with my country or my clients
And the language and let's save our changes.
When you say changes in wordpress you'll usually get an administrator message with a green bar here.
This one says settings saved.
You can always click the red X at the right side to close those messages.
Just a few more settings to go through.
If we check the writing settings page you'll see that as you make a post if you're doing a blog as a
We'll talk about the later video but in this theme they enable a number of different post formats whether
And then you can post via e-mail.
Meaning you can make an email address and when that e-mail address receives an email from you it will
will enable the notification of a service like ping or magic dot com.
And this is good for search engine optimization and notifying Web sites around the Internet that you
under reading this is a setting's page that controls how your website visitors will approach your website.
Your latest posts or a static page and what I'm going to do right now is select a sample the front page
It's one of the default pages called sambil page and I'm going to change that from your local Post's
in a subsequent video.
a static page as the front page in order to have that Web site be appropriate for the client.
There's a few blog settings pages and I usually use these at their defaults and then while I'm building
company.
through the internet but I click save changes for my front page display settings discussion has to do
And there's a few settings you can read through here if you're going to have a blog section on your
Under media depending on what theme you are using these are the standard image sizes that get created
when you upload a photo or an image to the media library.
I usually leave these at their defaults unless I'm looking to match my column with or the body text
And at that time I might change this to the appropriate size so that every time I upload an image it'll
library.
Or you can leave all of your images inside of the media library which is a folder called uploads and
But oftentimes I will just uncheck the organize my uploads box as I'm building the site and potentially
and posts I'll recheck that for future uploads.
Lastly permalink are the you are Elle's that your site is using now.
It's very important actually that you check an appropriate box right here.
Post name is currently the most popular permalink setting for Wordpress posts.
and posts appear in the URL.
So click Post name and then save changes in terms of the categories and the tags which will go over
The category default base your L word is called Category But there's an explanation here if you use
name is tag is the default word for the tag base.
the theme looks and there's a hello world post where if you open that up you can just see one sentence
Welcome to WordPress.
Then start writing and you could see that our permalink structure has propagated through the site and
it's got the post name here after the website address if you click pages all pages you'll see that there's
also a sample page that comes up and you can see that from our settings under reading when we set a
in that other setting.
Finally there is a default comment that comes up and all three of these pages are something that you
In this video you've opened up your local WordPress installation looked at the defaults and changed
In the next chapter you'll build your first client say a simple brochure website using the default theme
and a few extra plugins.
See you there.