Let's make sure visitors to the brochure site can find what they're looking for in this video.
You'll create a few interior pages and the navigation buttons in the header that leads visitors to those
Here's where you'll consider what parts of the site appear on every page giving visitors every opportunity
Let's get started.
First let's brainstorm what pages we need visitors to link to from the Hederman you here.
Maybe we need a contact us page and probably an About page and then maybe let's offer a third page which
So if we click back to the dashboard first thing I'm going to do is go to pages and add new Let's add
Here's a challenge for you.
Add a page called about and another called contactors and another called portfolio.
And then add those three pages to the header navigation using appearance menus.
I'll check in with you after you're done.
How'd you do.
just show you real quick where you can get some great text that's your standard Lorem Ipsum text at
You can just scroll down choose how many paragraphs you want.
Click generate lordship some and it'll come up with some text in Latin.
Just for some placeholder text and so I'm at a place that just go ahead and paste as text to make sure
And now I can turn that off right.
There's an about page with some text and I'll publish it.
And when that publishes I'll go back and click Add new and let's add a contact us page.
Make it pretty personal and I'm going to paste the text in there again.
Publish that page
and then a third portfolio gallery.
Now I can go in and change that text later but it will be give us a good idea of what text will look
And of course we'll add an image gallery to the portfolio page eventually.
Now that I have those three pages I'll go to appearance menus and I know that I'm going to be able to
put a menu in here called Hetter menu and hit create and over on the left hand side under pages I can
click add to menu
I'll also click that I want this to be in the primary menu location where in this theme it's at the
and you can also open each one of these menu items to give yourself a few more choices.
Now the navigation title I don't want it to be Post Number 2 no title I want that to be home.
Now that's saved.
Let's go back to the site and refresh the page and see what it looks like.
Nice one that's bold the page you're on.
And they roll over blue which is the standard color.
And if you click any of the menu items the header stays the same and it opens that page.
You may have noticed the manage in customize or button at the top of the menus there is from any page.
You can customize and just like when we created the site logo and the say identity section in the customize
or you can also manage menus there and see your changes live on the live editor on the right side.
So if you roll over menus and open that up here I've got the menu and the same options I had as under
you create them.
It'll show you what it looks like live.
Let's leave about on the outside so it's very visible.
And you can also control that the way your theme shows drop downs as well.
What if I wanted to put the contact page and the portfolio page underneath the about menu with the dropdown.
You can see that it's slightly indented over here as I control it inside the Customize her.
And then when I roll over about that's what dropdown is look like in the 2016 theme.
Next let's change what the sidebars display to make it more appropriate for our brochure site.
In most themes the sidebar and footer content is controlled using widgets as with the menus you can
from the sidebar and replace it with a list of pages for navigation.
I hope that was easy for you.
Here's what it looks like when I do it this time.
Maybe I'll start with the customize or.
All right now that that's open I want to open the widgets tab and it looks like there's a content bottom
one in two and a sidebar area.
to go ahead and remove each of these widgets by opening it and clicking remove
Let's leave the search bar there.
That's appropriate for a site.
I'll save and publish.
I can see that now I've just got the sidebar filled with a search window.
Let me do the other half using appearance widgets so that you can see the difference.
Now what I've got are the widgets on the right side that I can open and close and on the left side a
widget area.
Is a list of pages
and we are actually placed that below the search bar.
See what options I have here.
Maybe I'll name this pages and I can sort them by the page title the order in which they were published
or the ID when I go ahead and do them by page order.
And then if I wanted to I could exclude a page from the sidebar.
Let's go ahead and look at the site and refresh the page and take a look.
Great.
post number 2.
But if it wasn't named number two how do I find out what the post ID is in order to exclude it from
Well let's open the pages and if I roll over it and look down at the bottom left of my screen I can
That's the post Id about pages 22.
Contact me is post 24.
Portfolio portfolio is post 26 so I'm going to go back into a perience widgets and I'm going to exclude
all right.
Great.
That looks great.
No matter what page I'm on.
Those two are going to show
in this video.
You created a menu for the header of the site and revise the content on the sidebar giving Web site
site in the next video you'll configure the contact form and place it on the Contact Me page and make
When someone fills it up see their