The ability to back up move around and restore WordPress sites is super important for managing a WordPress
Plug ins can make it easy in this video you'll migrate the local site you just built into another local
I'll show you a few plug in options that I use for moving WordPress sites around for development and
By the end of this video you will have made a complete and full backup copy of a WordPress site and
Let's get started.
We're going to be moving the last site that we were working on in the 2014 theme and if you don't have
Make sure that you start map and then go to your u r l there and also go to the Admin Page and log in.
It would also be convenient if you had the start page open in your browser like I do over here for maps
so that we can access the database we'll be using it to access the database.
If you're using your site Ground server go ahead and log in.
You can click my accounts and then go to the see panel and from there you can scroll down to files and
I've done that over here.
You can also access the databases by going over here and clicking ph PMI admen.
Let's open the Wordpress dashboard and go down to plug ins and click add new I've already installed
But I'm going to go ahead and recommend that you install this plug in it's called all in one W.P. migration.
You can do a search for it by using the term all in one migration and I could see it comes up over here.
Updated recently compatible with this latest version of wordpress.
More than 100000 active installations with a lot of good reviews so I'm confident that I can use that
So I've installed it and then I activated it.
And if we go over here under all in one menu it's only got a few options of backups.
Screen that you can see the backups that you've made and an export and import screen if you have that
Go ahead and roll over the menu and open the export page.
It gives you just a few options.
And what we're going to do is actually just choose a place to export it to file.
And then it's preparing to export and it's going to go through its process and then we'll be able to
That took just a few seconds somewhere under a minute and now it gives us the ability to download that
Let's go ahead and download it.
it's sixty nine point seven megabytes.
I'm going to move it out of my downloads folder and into a folder called brochure site where I can keep
So I'll open up my downloads folder in Windows Explorer along with my desktop here.
And I've got that brochure site folder that I created before when we were creating images.
So I've got the local host brochure site backup file.
That type is a W. press file a file type that they create.
So now we need a new fresh WordPress installation to install this backup into.
So here's a challenge for you as long as you have map running.
Go ahead and move the word press corps files into a new folder in the map H.T. Docs folder create a
by navigating to WordPress at that new URL s.a.a how to go.
Did you get a new site installed.
Well here's how I would go about doing it.
I'm going to go ahead and go to Windows Explorer again and let's see I need the latest version of Wordpress
unzipped and there are my word press corps files for four point five point two over here I'm going to
3.
And you can see that I've tested this through migration one and two but in migration 3 I'm going to
here and my wordpress folder and paste them over here.
Now that I have that copied over I'm going to rename the WP dash config dash sample file to just W.P.
dash config and then what I've done in Adam my text editor my code editor is I've been able to open
If you just open up a folder that has files that you want to edit and call it a project folder.
If I do that with migration 3 then it will show me all those files within migration 3 that I might want
So if I just click W.P. config dot ph P It's in migration 3 I can verify that.
Now I know I need to put in my data in database name username and password and change the local host
port number.
So let's go back to map to the start page and we'll create a database under Tools ph my admin or there's
And that will open up your database.
I'll just click new over here.
And I'll think of a name just to match the site I'll use migration 3 so I know which is which and I'll
Now that that database has been created I know that using manf I am just going to use the standard log
As the database user.
So it's going to be migration migration 3.
The username is route and the password is route.
And I know that the local host needs a call in and the port number 33 6 if you remember port numbers
up here 33 06 or if you're on the map start page
then it's down here.
I'll go back to the database though.
There's nothing else I need to do here but I'll just take a look at migration three can see that there
those tables.
slash migration three as long as Wordpress can connect to the database.
It'll work.
It looks like something's wrong.
Do you know what it is.
Well when I was editing my file I put in all my data but I failed to save it.
If I was on a life server but all I have to do is save that file and it's in my file structure here
Now it's going to the database go through the real fast WordPress installation settings
great hit the log in button in my browser is going to remember the password because I use the same one
There we are.
Hope you were able to manage that as well.
to start.
So I bet you can guess what we do next.
I'll click Install now.
Activate the plug in.
And then all you've got to do is import the file that we export it from the other installation.
I'm going to import from a file and if I go to my desktop again I can find that brochure site folder.
Here's the file if I just click open it's starting to import and I'll pause the video as it does so
once it's uploaded the file and gone through a couple of import process settings.
It'll give you this warning.
It's going to overwrite the database media plugins and themes.
So you want to make sure that if this wasn't a blank site or if you were overwriting another site that
Your data has been imported successfully.
Great.
it'll open a new tab if you do that through it through that link.
And this is something for at this point you'll need to log in again with the previous site's credentials.
If they're not the same but because this is the new site now.
So I've still got the same settings under permalink but I've got to save it.
And then the plug in.
This is probably making changes to the HD access file which will go over in later videos.
But that's how we control the redirects of the permalink settings.
I could close this and now that I'm logged in over here on the new site where I change my permalink
I can go and make sure everything is all good I'm going and right click and open this in a new tab.
You can see that I'm in the new you are l migration three from over here is the old Jaro brochure dash
There's the site looks great.
One of the things that the plug in does is up here if you remember we made this home button in the old
menus was through a custom link and a fixed you RL.
So if we look under that custom link on the old site was the u r l and so at the new site this has actually
What that tells me is that under appearance menu here when the plug in made the migration it actually
had the old u r l and it replaced them with the new R L.
Making this home button work.
So now we've got a complete copy of that original site at a New York.
A whole new WordPress installation including all the media all of the whole database structure and including
That's an easy way to migrate a site between local hosting and a live host where you're going to be
and an exact copy on your local computer to make fundamental changes without breaking the live site.
And then when it's done you can migrate it right back up and overwrite the live site.
In this video you migrated a whole WordPress Web site from one Yoro to another.
modifying the W.P. config file using a free plug in you were able to make a backup file of the entire
We'll get right down into the files and database and migrate the site completely manually.
No matter where it's hosted.
Let's go