Taking a WordPress site live on the Internet is slightly different depending on which hosting company
I'll go through the hosting companies I use and recommend and show their differences.
And the best way to migrate existing sites to their platform will also go over how to set up staging
On each of the live platforms by the end you'll have a feel for several different types of hosting and
Let's get going.
Let's start by opening our local development environment as usual by starting map making sure the server
And then let's take a look at our brochure dash site.
site to a live environment.
As we've done before the first thing we're going to do is log into Wordpress the original site and we're
So I'll just go ahead and export to file and when that's finished I'll be back.
Now that it's finished I'll click download and we'll save it.
as usual I open two different windows in Windows Explorer one to my downloads and another where I want
I already have one backup.
And I also have that sequel file.
One of the things you may want to do is just label them by date so that you know which are the latest
backup files.
And so that's also a good way to conveniently keep track of your downloads and your backups.
So now that I know where that backup file is on my desktop inside of the folder called brochure site
and then inside of that folder by date now I can go to a new WordPress installation and I can download
and install and activate that plug in called All-In-One WP migration and then import the backup into
Here's a challenge for you.
Go to your site Ground account and create a new fresh WordPress installation using the Wordpress installer
in the see panel.
I hope doing that was easy for you.
Here's a quick review.
Hit the Wordpress installer and you know you're going to install it into a new directory on your main
site.
and create that folder like you would when you were installing WordPress manually.
What we're going to place it in any directory and then fill out the rest of the information and install
Now that it's installed I can just click the admin you are el link right in that see panel soft tactless
installer and I'm already logged in.
I can go into plugins and add new and find all in one migration and get my migration done.
You can also use your free flywheel staging area to migrate your local site into but either way grab
now down here I'll click Import and I'm importing it from a file locally.
Where I Put It was on my desktop inside of the brochure site folder.
Now this might take a little bit of time because I'm uploading directly to the internet on my server.
That took about 10 minutes to upload.
I'll continue and it's going to go ahead and restore it and again I'll pause the video and I didn't
Save button twice.
There we go.
And save changes one more time.
Gosh I can really sense the speed of this flywheel hosting when I go to any page it's no time at all
I think I have an exact copy restored version of the site that we had locally but this one is live on
Under this you are now since we're talking about hosting staging areas and site migration.
I thought I'd show you how automated staging at the hosting level can be very convenient for making
Your free server environment is equivalent to their startup which is only good for one domain at a time.
And when you go down to the staging feature it's only accessible through there.
Third level on the shared program the go geek which on sale is four thousand ninety five a month and
the regular price is almost $30 a month but you get unlimited web sites and a lot of other features.
Let me just show you very quickly my staging area at my personal site ground site in my cloud hosting
If I just go to the see panel This will give me a see panel where I'm accessing every account that I
You can see that it will automatically create a staging copy for any of the websites I have installed
So for Greg Davis dot com For example if I just click Create a staging copy I can choose to make a copy
But I don't have to I could just click Continue to the username and password for the staging environment
live using one single click after I've made my changes and tested them over at flywheel.
There is a similar staging feature that I'll just give you a quick tour on.
And once you have one of your web sites open for example wild food girl if I go over into staging You
And then I can bring it back live using just a single click in this video.
to our live development environment.
I went over the hosting companies that I use that are all available to you free or inexpensively.
Next we're going to set up a local staging area so that we can make changes to the live web site without