In this video you'll set up a new local development environment and then migrate a copy of the live
in the local staging area.
Then upload the new version to the live server.
In this way the updates will be instant with no downtime for the live site.
You'll learn how to safely edit a live web site without risk of damaging or losing the live site and
without your changes visible to the public during your process.
a safety net.
If something goes wrong let's start by making a quick edit to our site that's live on the internet.
Whichever hosting service you used and I'll just go back into the dashboard where I'm logged in and
I'm going to go ahead and choose settings general and just go and change the title of the site as a
This one is live at flywheel so I scroll scroll down and just click Save changes and if I refresh the
Now here's a challenge once again create a new WordPress installation and activate it in localhost.
Start map if you don't have it already.
Copy the files over.
site into it.
I hope that went well for you.
I installed mine under map and I called it live Dasch site.
Now that I've installed WordPress I can populate that and refresh it and under W.P. options.
Great.
And I bet you can guess your next challenge.
and import it into your live site locally and make the two sites complete duplicates of each other.
Has a video now and give it a go.
This time I will demonstrate going through the process.
So here's my live site and over here is my site on flywheel so I've got all in one WP migration.
I'm going to do an export to file great that's created my downloadable backup and I'll click download
and save it to the downloads folder.
Here it is.
Open up my downloads and in Windows Explorer I can go to my live site folder.
This one is called Live site and it's just seperate from that map installation place.
Download backup right there.
Great.
This is my local development area or you might call a staging site.
And I'm going to install the all in one WP migration plug in as before
and I'll import the backup that I just made from the life site.
Looks like it's important I'll click continue on the warning
great.
I'm going to go over to the permalink settings and click twice to save those as the plug and instructs
of course we've got to log in again once we've uploaded and and restored a site from backup because
And then one more time as the plugin instructs
and let's take a look right click open in a new tab
looks like the site is the same exact copy fire lead photography live looks like everything's working
Great.
So what we have here is a perfect copy in our local environment of the site that is live up on the Internet
right now.
What that means is that when you're working on your local development environment you can change the
you're working on it no one can see your changes.
like this with a totally new theme and revised footer widgets and everything you could do that while
One minute they'll be looking at the old site next minute when they reload it or somebody new comes
It's brand new.
No downtime.
In this video you've set up an entire local development environment for staging working copies of a
And you migrated to an exact copy into your staging environment.
the theme and editing some of the content areas.
Then you'll take your new design life.
Let's do it.