In this video you'll make almost the same exact changes to a development site as you did in the last
But this time you'll let a plug in do the work will start from one of the migration copies of the previous
You'll check out the plug in options in the Wordpress plugin repository for creating child themes.
And use one of them to create the necessary files and configuration.
First to get started.
Open your local development environment like I have here and log into the Wordpress dashboard.
In the last local environment site that we worked on in my case it's called Live Dasch site.
This is the one we've got the affinity theme plugged into our original content that we edited within
2014.
And if you remember in the last video we edited the CSSA the style sheet to make these lines white in
under plug ins add new and I did a search for child theme.
I can see it does have quite a few installs and is compatible with this version updated very recently.
There are a couple more in here that I have used and get good reviews.
Although it's been updated not so recently and says untested with this new version of Wordpress and
and click Install now.
Now it doesn't start or click activate plug in.
Now that I have that activated I can look under Tools and child themes is where the settings are configured.
Before I do any change it's to create a child theme using the child theme configurator plug in.
I want to go and make sure I look at what's happening now under appearance themes and label my original
child theme that I had created manually just so that I know which one it is.
The name of the theme is defined within the stylesheet and that's true of our child theme as well.
Whichever theme that you have active you can just click editor and wordpress will navigate right to
I can edit files within this WordPress file editor but it's best practice to bring them into your local
However just for this simple change I can label this affinity child one just so I know that's the one
that I updated manually and created the files for.
And when that tells me the file was edited successfully I could go back to appearance themes and we'll
So that means that if I activate another theme say the original affinity theme.
Any changes that I made withinside that original child theme would be no longer valid.
lines instead of white lines.
So now let's use the plug in to create a new child theme and we'll make sure we label it affinity child
2 or something where we can tell the difference.
Go ahead and navigate to Tools child themes once again and let's get started making a child theme I'd
to choose affinity and I'll click analyzed first.
The plugin gives me a message looks like it appears to be OK to use as a child theme.
And it loads additional stylesheets.
So there are a couple of things that it recommends that I do.
If you look at the options here they are pretty straightforward and you can most likely leave the default
It did say that it loads additional stylesheets and I can choose to create a separate style sheet so
And so I'm just going to leave it as the default primary style sheet and I'm going to use the word Press
style.
Hugh
and I am going to go ahead and look at it wants to name it.
And actually if you look at the name of the folder it's going to use it already saw that I had an affinity
We will call it affinity child.
Since I had a one in the last one and I can go ahead and use all these default settings that came from
child theme so that all the settings if you have made settings to the menus and the widgets and customize
So create a new child theme.
Yes.
Great.
It says it's been generated successfully and it wants me to preview it before activating it.
and it opens the customize or previewing the child theme itself.
Looks normal I could add the footer.
And I think it's finished so I am going to come outside of the child theme configurator settings page
And here it is affinity child too and with the plug in it's pretty nice that it puts the screen shot
in there for you.
But if I activate that child theme remember I previewed it which if you don't do that at first and you'd
you can click live preview right at the bottom there.
Whoops.
I'm just going to cancel that and leave 2015 inside of my folder.
But now that I have the new theme activated I click click visit site or I do have the site open here
So I scroll back to the top and click refresh
remember it opens a different image at random.
Remember this local site will still be the old style sheet and it also still says live there in the
We changed that name so I'll just go in real quick to settings at my local site
take it back to the normal name
and now that we can see that child theme activated let's go look around and make that small edit inside
So I'd like to pose a challenge to you at this point.
I want you to look at your theme files inside of the Wordpress directory and I'd like you to find your
that we had used before in our manually installed child the stop the video now and give it a go well
I'm going to open the code editor that I had the other files open in and here's the footer widgets piece
So I'm just going to copy that at first.
And inside my code editor I do have the whole file structure here and so I should be able to open W.P.
Looks like I have them here it's the one labeled child too if you remember and it made the screen shot
So if I open that one up all I have to do is go beyond the comment slash here and hit Control V to paste
and I'll hit Control s.
Now at that point if it were live I would have to upload this file to the server but since I can just
the page and see those footer title borders go to white instead of gray grade I've made a change.
child to stylesheet file has my new code in there and I did that without using the word press code editor
but instead in my code editor on my local machine in this video you used a plugin to create the files
You also edited the style dot CSSA file on your own to change a color in the footer.
Nice job.
Next you'll edit the functions that BHP file inside your child theme to change something not on the
Let's go