In this video you'll create a fresh new site in your students sandbox.
Activate the cafe pro theme and populate it by importing the sample content file.
We'll check out how the themes home page layout provides for scrolling navigation buttons uses widgets
You'll be able to see possibilities for using this theme for any type of web site because it's home
Let's get started.
Let's check out the cafe pro themed demo.
notice if you open it up and then start to scroll is that it's got this fixed background image where
Pretty neat effect as well as the menu coming up from down below goes up and then fixes itself to the
There's more than one widget area that's populated by a fixed background image like that.
And there's another colored area right here for a nice mission this is the mantra here.
Another Square area in front of a fixed background image and then a series of footer widgets with which
If you scroll back up a couple of the features you can figure out and play with or there there's a highlighted
area up top here.
This is a widget area that's designed to appear on every page of the Web site at the very top to have
All of these menu items here are scrolling menu items.
If you click the about menu item it scrolls to the About section of the home page widget area and if
There's a hash tag after the Web address and then it says front page to.
This one is from page 3.
This one is front page four.
These are anchor tags that are built in so that you can use these menu items to scroll up and down on
And then the logo at the top left is clickable back to the home page itself as well as this text based
logo link right here.
I'm going to show you around my studio press member area just a little bit.
You don't have access to these interior themed set up pages unless you're a member of studio press and
But there's one page about CAFE pro themed shows you all the lay out areas on the home page the widget
This one is a call to action banner at the top.
And then there's home page areas one two three and four and then three footer areas down here.
At the same time there's also an interesting layout configuration setup that several themes by Studio
It actually has nine different layout configurations.
This gray is a little bit hard to see but I will have this file available to you inside of the resources
zip file for the themes and you can see that the first.
If there's one item it shows it in the middle that's just like the mantra right down here.
If you have two items it shows it side by side three items.
It shows four in a grid and so on.
So you can choose by how many items you have within the widget area how many widgets that will lay it
Let's get started getting our cafe pro theme activated and a new fresh site set up inside the student
When you log in into your students sandbox if you go to my sites and click through to your your sites
Choose a unique name for the your l like your name and then the name of the theme if you like.
And then I'm just going to call this one.
My cafe and I'll click Create say as usual and then I can go ahead and log in of course and relaxing
into this one.
There we go.
And I am inside of the my cafe.
Now of course it's going to open up the default parallax as usual and your challenge now is to go back
to the dashboard activate the cafe pro theme and either download the theme demo files or go and open
pro theme.
And make sure that cafe pro is activated and then come back and we'll restart the video then as you
do.
Were you able to activate the theme OK and then use tools import to go ahead and use the Wordpress importer.
And did you find the SML file from the theme demo files and important.
Well when you did your your site should look like this.
I've just done that and I'm opening the customized now.
And because in our original default site in parallax I had some of the home page widgets enabled with
You can see that the home page is there and then as you scroll down I've got this white background and
there are some of my content content.
We're going to have to revise this content and then using one widget inside of this widget area.
Here is a text widget inside of here.
And again one widget inside of this home page area and just one widget inside of the footer area which
If you open up widgets inside the customize or you can see all those places the before header is way
But then from page 1 2 3 and 4 and then footer 1 2 and 3 while we're here let's just place a little
it in the next video.
I'm just going to say Here's the before or content.
You can have that be a link or have a color like it is in the demo but I'll just place that right there
and then save and publish in the customize or you go over to the site.
If you have it open in another tab and refresh it it should come up like that.
And our Web sites looking pretty good already.
In this lesson you created a new sandbox Web site activated the cafe pro theme and imported the demo
In the next video we'll set up two navigation menus one for the home page anchor tags and scrolling
interior pages look like in the theme and customize their layout