In this video you'll learn how to manage multiple WordPress websites and sell your services to clients
Security releases monitoring and reporting for more than 50 different Web sites and we'll explore how
By the end of this lesson you'll have the tools proposal templates and knowledge you need to set up
Let's check it out.
Let's start by just going back to W.P. elevation dotcom that I had mentioned in the last video and I'll
Troy Dean and Christina Romero at the BP elevation offer a lot of free information.
If you just join their mailing list and get on the waiting list for their courses and their membership
If you click the Join button at the top right you'll see a pop up come up at this time.
It says it's currently closed and will reopen for new students shortly.
an amazing webinar.
We learn exactly how to manage Web site care plans for your clients.
Very very excellent.
If you also look in the blog if you click blog up at the top here you can go ahead and go down and enjoy
some different pieces of information where there's so much good stuff there that I've come in searched
on Google for a few of the articles that I know have provided great value to me.
I searched for W.P. elevation Web site care plans in Google and I came up with this one as the top result.
It's from April of 2015.
And let's just go over some of the information that Troy presents in this article.
Now this is a very long blog post.
It's actually a very thorough article that I would read from start to finish if I were you and actually
Web site care plans and Web site maintenance plans work.
This is some intro text and some little proof of some income that his clients have made but with wordpress
maintenance plans I really subscribe to the idea that Troy has here of calling them WordPress care plans
rather than maintenance plans because maintenance has these kind of stations with auto maintenance or
People don't really want to subscribe to maintenance plans but care plans.
It's a positive image and people are really excited because they don't want to have to go in and fix
They want to have somebody in the back end taking care of it day to day.
And as we scroll down you can see that he has an excellent section here about what to include in your
website care plans.
And let's go over some of these in detail that first and maybe the most obvious thing that you should
updates or updates of Wordpress come out and wordpress does security updates which are minor and usually
non-breaking updates automatically.
WordPress does provide this as a part of the core service but then Major WordPress updates are manual.
When word press releases a new version and you can decide whether you want to allow your host to do
here plugins and themes.
Also update periodically and when WordPress updates its a really good idea to check that the plug ins
and the themes that their Web site is using have broken or been made degraded after the updates.
And this is one of the pictures that you paint for your client that you're going to be going in and
updating WordPress for security and for increased features and speed and at the same time you're going
It's a kind of monitoring of the Web site on an ongoing basis.
That's really worth something.
And it has a lot of value to clients.
Backups should also be a big part of a Web site care plan.
You can backup data daily and you can do weekly backups of the entire website so that if anything happens
or if God forbid the client goes in and breaks the website you can always back out to a previous version
and restore it very easily.
up their web site in an external location like Dropbox or Amazon S3 in addition to backing it up on
And you can get reports of hacking attempts that come in at your server and you can pass that information
along to your clients on a weekly or a monthly basis so that they know that you're protecting their
website on an ongoing basis and then uptime monitoring is another great way to offer value to your clients
so that they don't have to be checking their website every week or every day to make sure that it's
up you can assure them that you're going to be getting a notification in the case that their Web site
Now there are a lot more tips and tricks in this article.
Premium services that you can offer for even more money.
A list of tools that Troy and Krystina recommend which are a lot of the ones that I use and I'll show
And you should just read this whole article completely to get everything that you can out of it.
Here's the play button for a replay of this or it's 115 minutes long.
There's also an e-mail a link to it.
The e-mail text that Troy Dean uses to send to his clients to introduce the idea of web site care plans
to them and what value they bring.
It's really the same way that I got started by reading this and asking my clients if they'd like to
And many did right away seeing the value of me watching their Web site from behind the scenes on a consistent
So go ahead and read this article.
And let's go on to the next step.
There's a couple more great blog posts in W.P. elevation com.
Here's one by Christina Romero about transitioning clients into using Web site care plans and recurring
Again an excellent excellent blog post that gives you a lot of good information about the steps to take
to get existing clients to buy into a care plan.
So a couple of steps you create a sales page on your website that tells and paints the value of those
Check out that has automatic subscriptions which is very easy to set up.
Write a blog post that you can then talk about and point your clients towards to read more in more detail.
What web site care plans entail.
Draft an email that I just showed the link to back here that you can send to your current clients and
send that email from a marketing system so that you can track who opens it and who doesn't open it so
So the people that open and clicked the link in the initial email even if they didn't get right back
It's an excellent process to go through if you already have some clients that you're taking care of
site maintenance.
Here's a good little section in number 2 in this blog post.
Get a process that talks about when you have a Web site care airplane your taking care of someone's
Do it efficiently so you don't take too much time on each website.
I have either hosting plans or web site care plans on almost 50 different client websites and I have
their Web site and I send them a monthly report telling them everything I've done for them in the month
so that they can feel good about paying me that recurring fee.
Let's jump into the tools that I use and take a look at the backend of my hosting program at site ground.
Now it looks a little different than your sample site Ground account that you sign up for yourself because
in a virtual private server.
It gives me this W H M which is a web host manager program on the backend where I can go over and list
If I just click all you can see that I'm showing 46 different Web sites that I'm actively managing here
and each one has its own control panel.
You can see that I can switch in the see panel through between all the different sites that I manage
and if I look at this account the panel for this client I can go down here and just want to show you
One of the things that I like to do is set up W.P. auto update but I like it to update the Wordpress
But I do like to turn off the plugin updating.
I want to update plugins and themes manually myself so that I can make sure and check on them.
Now I do have the automatic WordPress version enabled and I do have actually upgrade plugins checked
that I like to keep.
Now if I go back to the see panel homepage again near the bottom there's also the staging service.
Now on the startup plan that you have with your free trial staging is not enabled you have to get at
If I wanted to just create a staging copy here I could just hit continue and choose a username and password
updates.
I can test everything out make sure it's working and then with one click I can overwrite the old site
and take all my changes.
that I offer in my website.
You can see this is their home page and you can use a lot of the services for free.
So if I just log in here I want to show you the back end of my account at managed W.P. dotcom where
There's a free plug in that managed W.P. provides called the worker plug in and you place that and activate
basis are listed here.
I can get them in a grid pattern or in a list like this and I can see on each one what the version of
Wordpress is and if I look at the overview I can see a lot of different stats about what needs updating
and the overhead I might be using where I could get rid of some stuff and make my site faster.
I can optimize websites in that way if I wanted to go through and use managed W.P. to update plugins
for example throughout all of my sites I could go here and see which of these plugins I want to manage
and I could do them on all 30 or 50 sites that manage WP is managing for me.
I don't often update all sites at the same time and so often use this Web site's tab over here.
for updates.
I can just click update.
All right here.
And then I can go and make sure that everything's working now we've learned how to manage backups with
and an up time monitor as well as monitoring SEO and Web site rankings along with Google Analytics.
If you have it installed it's worth upgrading to the premium services especially if you're charging
It's very worth that much money for the value you bring to do all these services for your website clients.
Mine start at $150 a month and go up to $300 a month for my web site care plans.
In this video we've gone through a few different articles at W.P. elevation dot com found a resource
W.P. elevation in order to invite your clients in a really valuable way to subscribe to your Web site
I also showed you around my back end of my hosting program at site ground where I manage some of my
gives you a great place to see all of the stats of plugins themes and wordpress updates all in one place.
In addition to offering backups and uptime monitoring as well in this video you learn of a number of
by setting up your clients to value what you have to offer and showing what you do to support their
consistent.