This course is about Node.js and Angular 2.
So I think it's a good idea to get started
with understanding what each of these two pieces
actually is and does.
Let's start with Node.js, here.
To best explain Node.js,
let's think about our web application
where we have a client browser and the sever.
In our client we typically have HTML, CSS and JavaScript,
and on the server we have some code
handling the request our client sends to the server.
Now Node.js is basically JavaScript on the server.
It's a server-side language and it happens to be JavaScript.
So like PHP or Ruby or any other of your favourite
server-side languages,
JavaScript is now just another server-side language
and Node.js is JavaScript with some extra packages,
some extra tools, which allow you to
well handle server-side specific tasks,
like accessing the file system and handling requests.
And we will learn all of that throughout this course.
Now Node.js on it's own, is already all we need
to write server-side applications,
but typically you don't want to use plain Node.js,
just like you typically don't use Vanilla PHP or plain PHP
when creating a server-side application with PHP.
Instead you typically use a framework,
which makes a lot of recurrent tasks a lot easier to do.
For Node.js the most popular,
or one of the most popular frameworks is Express.js.
Express.js is a framework which wraps Node.js,
so you still write Node.js, you still write JavaScript code,
but it makes things easier.
It comes with a lot of helpers,
which make a lot of common tasks easier,
so that you can really focus on your core business logic,
and don't have to reinvent the wheel all over the place.