Now as we learned about the two pieces,
Node.js on the server and Angular 2 on the client,
it's time to understand how they work together,
how to connect them because this
is the key of this course.
This is the main concept of this course in the end, right?
So this is our typical server-side only approach.
We have our client, the browser, and we have the server,
and we exchange a request from
the client typically for some HTML code
from the server which then is rendered
in the browser again.
That is how a lot of web pages work,
and there's nothing wrong with that,
but of course, one problem is that
here we need to send a request
for every single change because
our page constantly needs to be rerendered and whole.
So, we constantly need to fetch
new HTML code from the server.
That changes in a single page application.
Here we all of a sudden now control
the complete app via JavaScript.
As I explained before, through Angular 2.
It will rerender the page.
It will update the dom.
We don't need to reach out to the server
for every single change.
We will, of course, need to reach out
if we need to send some data
to store it in a database, let's say,
or to fetch some data, but Angular 2
will do this in the background
behind the scenes.
So everything happens instantly
which is a feeling you know from apps
on your mobile phones and which is why
single page applications and frameworks
to create them aren't so popular these days.
They bring this very reactive feeling
to our web applications.
So here we might not need a server in the end
or at least we will not connect
to it as often because generally,
we handle everything in the browser.
From time to time we do need to connect though.
We start with our user who's on the webpage
which initially, of course, was sent by the server
because that is where it lies,
but the ones who are on the webpage,
we use the Angular 2 application
with its own router and so on
to handle all the user input and rerender the dom,
but from time to time, we got operation
where we need to reach out to the server.
For example if we log in or if we create
a new message and want to store this in a database.
Angular 2 doesn't have direct
access to the database.
It's fronted only.
It runs in the browser, so we need
to reach out to the server to tell it,
hey do something.
For example, store something in the database.
We do that behind the scenes with a HX request
where we then request data or
want to request a storage of some data.
On Node.js, on the server,
we then also have a router, the Node.js router
which exposes several end points,
several routes are in a two app can
connect to via HX.
So why request behind the scenes
without reloading the page.
These URLs, these end points,
then tell Node.js what to do when ever a request
to reach such an endpoint, reaches such a URL.
There, we then forward this request
or handle this request in our route controllers,
so we execute some code.
We might access the database and in the end,
we sent back a response to the Angular 2 application,
and that also behind the scenes.
So, this happens asynchronously.
Our browser application will keep running.
We don't see that there is this request
response happening in the background,
and eventually when the response returns,
Angular 2 will handle it parse it
to whatever it needs to do,
and if it needs to, update the dom
or the part of the dom which now needs to be updated.
In the meantime, it might have
showed a progress bar or something
like that if necessary.
This is how we connect Angular 2 and Node.js.
The key take away here is Node.js
exposes some end point, some API end points,
some routes to which Angular 2 can
connect behind the scenes to exchange data
and to well speak to the server.
Generally, everything the user sees
is handled by Angular 2,
and the page is not reloaded at any point
because we only have one single page
which is handled by Angular 2 on the front end.