Our application is finally ready with the Angular
front-end talking to the Java EE back-end.
But you can feel there is more to it.
Welcome back to Java EE Getting Started course.
My name is Antonio Goncalves and in this last module we will
go through the entire application architecture so you'll get a
higher view of what we achieved.
I will also give you extra pointers if you want to dig into Java EE in Angular.
In the previous module we finished the Angular application by
adding a book service that talks to our back-end using HTTP and
the reactive programming model.
Thanks to the Swagger CodeGen tool,
it was just a matter of passing the JSON contract of our
book endpoint and generate the needed code.
We finally achieved what we were looking for,
an Angular front-end application invoking our Java EE back-end.
I'll wrap up this course with this last module by
revisiting the entire application.
I'll focus on the changes we made on each and every module,
starting with Java EE back-end and finishing with Angular front-end.
I'll end this course giving you a few external references so you can dive into both Java EE and Angular.