When we write some code we always face the same challenges,
we like our code to be elegant, maintainable,
to run efficiently and securely, and we want to assert its correctness.
How do we assert that our code works?
Well by testing it.
Of course you could handle this manually by deploying the application
and letting a human user follow a scripted test plan.
But wherever possible,
it's more efficient and fail proof to automate the test execution.
But testing is not simply about making sure our code works as expected,
when we write tests we become the user of our API.
So we see how intuitive it is to use if it's too verbose or ugly.
Tests help us designing our APIs.
If you agree with the saying that code is the documentation,
then testing is a nice way to document the code.
There are several testing strategies, such as smoke test,
acceptance test, system test, performance test,
but I'll just quickly cover unit test and integration test.
The purpose of a unit test is to validate that a single
functionality is operating as expected in isolation.
Unit test are the narrow business scope and are characterized as fast,
simply, easy-to-run, and fine grain.
Part of being a unit test is the implication that things
outside the code should be mocked.
Unit tests shouldn't have dependencies on outside systems.
On the other hand,
an integration test is done to demonstrate that several
pieces of the system work together.
Integration tests cover all applications and they
require much more effort to put together.
They usually require external resources,
like a database or an application server,
that is not mocked out.
The integration tests do a more convincing job of demonstrating
the system works than a set of unit tests can. For unit test we use JUnit and for integration test we add Arquillian.