Until now we've been using Maven to compile our Java code,
package it, deal with dependencies and so on.
But Maven is not suited for Java's development.
We will have to pick up a different building tool for Angular frontend.
There are several JavaScript building tools to choose from.
Bower is one of the oldest,
it is mostly a package manager so we just install the right version
of the packages we need and their dependencies.
Then comes NPM,
NPM is much richer than Bower and perfectly suited for server side JavaScript.
NPM was created in 2010 and it is so famous that it is
automatically included when Node JS is installed.
Yarn is much younger, because it was released in October 2016.
Despite its youth,
Yarn is compatible with a public NPM registry and is way much faster than NPM.
That's why I've chosen to use Yarn in this course.
Yarn is a common line utility that interacts with the NPM
registry to manage JavaScript dependencies.
Using Yarn we can install library, packages,
and applications along with their dependencies.
So it will perfect to install all the Angular libraries.
but we will also use Yarn to execute scripts or transpile
our TypeScript code into JavaScript.
Here on the Yarn website you can have more information by following the
doc links and learn how to install and execute Yarn.
As you can read in the installation,
installing Yarn on Mac OS X is again just a single common brew install Yarn.
Here you can pause the course and install Yarn as we will be using it quite heavily.