Now that we know our API documentation works,
let's go back to our BookEndpoint and document it using
a bottom-up approach or code first.
This means that we will add Swagger annotations to our
BookEndpoint and then generate the JSON contract.
To help the generation,
we will use a Maven plugin and we will also use the
Swagger UI to display the contract.
Let's go back to the editor.
I've already set up the Maven dependencies.
I've added Swagger, so Swagger annotations and also the Swagger plugin.
Swagger-annotation you just want dependency and the swagger-plugin
needs a bit of customization and configuration.
This plugin will allow us to generate the JSON contract.
The JSON contract is generated under the web app directory.
So let's do a Maven clean compile and as you can see,
out of the blue we have the swagger-ui that we will have a look later,
and the generated swagger.
json contract.
So now let's do a bit of space and put side by side the
generated JSON contract and our BookEndpoint,
so rest BookEndpoint.
Close that.
So we need the Api annotation from Swagger.
We put it a name, we generate the contract,
and here it is, we have tags name Book.
Now let's document the getBook method.
We use another annotation called ApiOperation and we
give a description to this method.
So getBook returns a book given an identifier.
And we generate the contract again.
Here it is.
Now we have path books/id where the summary returns a book given an
identifier and all the parameters of the method.
What's missing is the responses.
And actually we've seen that the getBook can return two responses.
Either a code 200, meaning that the book has been found in the database,
or a 404, meaning that the given identifier wasn't found.
So let's generate the contract again and now we have more information
in the contract with these responses 200 and 404.
There's one thing missing, this method returns a response,
but in fact it's a book, so let's add that the response is actually a Book class,
our book entity.
When we do that and generate the contract again, something funny happens.
In the 200 we see that it returns a book and the definition
of the book has been generated underneath.
We can customize this generation using other annotations.
ApiModel and we can give a description, Book resource representation.
Let's generate the contract again and we should find
this description at the bottom here.
And now we can add more information on the attributes we
want using the ApiModelProperty annotation.
So here I'm specifying that id is actually the Identifier,
title I put Title of the book, description,
Description of the book,
and by generating the contract I'm adding more and more
information to the JSON contract.
So let's do the same in all methods.
Okay, so here I've added several annotations on all the methods,
so the getBook, but also the createBook that creates a book with an HTTP POST,
the deleteBook with several responses, getBooks,
countBooks,
and this way I have the full contract of all the methods with all the
parameters and all the responses of our BookEndpoint.
Books/count, books/id with and http GET,
the delete, deleting a book,
so let's see all that in action by deploying the application in WildFly.
So the entire application is packaged, the JSON contract,
the Swagger UI, and deployed in WildFly.
So let's see it works.
If we go to api/books we have our hundred books from the database.
Now we can have a look at the Swagger contract,
so it's exactly the same code that we've seen before
except it's slightly nicer on Chrome.
So we have the different path, get, delete, the book definition.
And we also have the Swagger UI tool that we've imported with Maven.
That's a very nice UI to explore a JSON contract.
So let's scroll down on books, we can see that we have a GET books.
The POST to create a new book, books/count and so on.
So as you can see,
it's much nicer and we can actually try it out by pressing the button.
So here I've invoked the count books API,
I can do the same for books with an s, try it out,
and here I have the 100 books in JSON.
It's a very nicer way to see our contract.
Okay so back to the IDE to commit our code.
What have we done in this module?
Well we've added Swagger annotations to the book entity,
to the BookEndpoint, uploaded the swagger-ui,
generated the JSON contract thanks to a few Swagger annotations and dependency on XML.