Now that you know a bit more about JAX-RS annotations and APIs,
let's go back to the IDE and expose a REST API on top of our book repository.
We will use the HTTP GET, POST,
and DELETE methods to get CRUD operation on books.
To make it more visual we will populate the database with JPA so
our getBooks actually retrieves something.
I'll use an HTTP client to interact with the bookEndpoint for now,
but later we will use Arquillian to properly test it.
Okay so let's create the new book endpoint under the package rest.
But before creating the book endpoint,
I need a bit of configuration so let's create a class called JAXRSConfiguration.
It needs to extend the JAX-RS classed called Application.
And here we annotate this class with ApplicationPath and we put a string,
I put API because I like it,
that means that everything under API is a JAX-RS endpoint.
So BookEndpoint now.
Because our BookEndpoint delegates all the calls to the book repository,
let's inject the bookRepository and let's use a nice IntelliJ IDEA trick.
I'm going to generate code based on the BookRepository,
so I'm delegating methods.
So here, thanks to IntelliJ IDEA,
I generated all the methods of the BookRepository inside the BookEndpoint,
so I've cleaned it up a bit.
And what I like to do is change the method name so instead of
find I can go getBook because it's an HTTP GET,
createBook, deleteBook, instead of findAll let's put getBooks with an s,
plural, countBook.
So what makes this class a REST endpoint?
It needs a path annotation and here I'm putting books.
So with a configuration API and now books,
I can target this endpoint at the URI/API/books.
Okay so let's start with getBooks.
The idea of this method, with an HTTP GET,
it returns all the books of the database in a JSON format.
So here I'm using the produces with APPLICATION_JSON,
making it nicer, and remember that this is a JAX-RS endpoint,
so it doesn't return a list of books, but a response with the list of books.
So let me introduce a variable here.
I call it books with an s, so the repository returns a list of books,
but I want to return a response with a list of books.
So what I do is Response.
ok, because it's a 200,
I've received books from the database and I'll return them
into the response and build this response.
And if there is no books in the database,
if the size of this list is 0, then I want to return a response with a 204,
noContent.
Here it is.
Well we can test this code.
So I run WildFly, it deploys this endpoint,
yes it is now, and I'm using a REST client tool from IntelliJ IDEA,
so that's a nice way to test an endpoint.
So its localhost 8080, bookstore-back, that's the name of the war,
and remember api/books.
I do an http GET, execute,
and the response is empty so I have a 204 because I
have no data in the database.
Well let's add some data now.
I've created an import.
sql file with 100 inserts of books in the database.
Here it is.
So there's a nice JPA trick to import this SQL when we deploy the application.
So we go to the persistence XML and we add another property called javax.
persistence.
sql-load-script-source, and now we give it the name of the file, import.
sql.
We redeploy the application in WildFly and automatically the SQL file will
be executed and we will have 100 books in the database.
Well let's test, see if it works.
Brilliant.
Here it is, 100 books in JSON format and I have an HTTP response 200.
We can even have a look at the browser,
so let's copy/paste the URI and here I'm on Chrome,
API books, yes 100 books in JSON format.
So let's go back to the BookEndpoint and this time code the count method.
So the count is an HTTP GET, so I use the GET annotation.
I'm going to concatenate a different path,
so to get the number of books I'll have to go to api/books/count.
Same trick,
I'm introducing a variable called numberOfBooks
because this method returns a response.
So Response.
Ok, which is a 200, with the numberOfBooks and I'm building this response.
And if the numberOfBooks is 0, meaning the database is empty,
then I return a noContent 204.
Let's redeploy the application in WildFly and use the
REST client to see if it's working.
So this time it's /count.
Yes, 100 books.
Okay well I've coded all the other methods,
so the getBook, the createBook, the deleteBook,
and as you can see I even have a Min that comes from bean validation.
So all the code here is working.
You can pause the video and type the rest of the code.
So I've redeployed the entire application and now if
I use the HTTP client on /count, so I have 100 books,
HTTP GET on books, I get the 100 books in JSON,
we see there's the book 1001, so I can put 1001 in the URI and I get 1 book,
the details of the book 1001.
I can do an HTTP DELETE.
So now I have a 204, so the delete has succeeded and the response is empty,
and just to check I'm doing HTTP GET again and yeah 404,
so the book 1001 is not found. And if I do a count again, I have 99 books.