Now that we have defined what Java EE and Angular are,
let's see the sample application that we will build from
scratch step by step throughout this course.
Welcome to the BookStore application, as its name implies,
this application allows us to visualize a list of
existing books coming from a database, view the detail of each book,
delete it or create a new book.
Let's browse through it.
Here we are in front of the BookStore application.
Here at the top is our menu to access different functionalities.
Clicking on the book List menu will display the list of available books.
Clicking on Create will display a form where we can create
a new book and add it to the database.
Coming back to the list, if we click on the title of the book,
we see a different page with all the details of a book.
Once on this page,
I can go back to the list or delete this jQuery Beginner's Guide.
Now I have 99 books, I can click on another one, delete it, now I have 98.
Let's create a new book, let's say Java EE 8,
and description, unit cost, number of pages,
and if I create his book, now I have 99 books.
So as you can see, the BookStore application,
it's quite simple in terms of business rules,
but it has a very complex architecture with a Java EE
back-end and an Angular front-end.
With this sample application we will go through the basics of Java EE and
Angular and moreover how both communicate with each other.
All the books are manipulated by Java EE application and
stored into a relational database.
To interact with this database, we will expose a REST interface,
allowing us to have a JSON representation of these books.
To make sure our backend responds to the specification,
we will test it using the Arquillian test framework.
Then once the Java EE back-end is built and tested,
we will develop the front-end with Angular.
The Angular graphical components will consume the JSON,
coming from the back-end and will display HTML in the browser. That's the 10, 000 feet high overview of what we will build in this course.