Maven is able to compile and package our code into an archive,
but then we need an application server to execute it.
You can see an application sever as the Java EE runtime,
it is a middleware that brings all the Java EE services,
such as data access, persistence, HTTP support,
security, or monitoring.
Again, we have several implementations to choose from.
GlassFish is the open-source reference implementation from Oracle.
TomEE from the Apache Foundation or Payara.
JBoss and WildFly are both from Red Hat.
In this course we will be using WildFly as it's very light and easy to use.
WildFly is the community and open source application server authored by JBoss,
a division of Red Hat.
WildFly is written in Java and therefore runs on multiple platforms.
The first version of this application server was developed back in 1999,
so you can see how mature it is.
Of course, WildFly implements all the Java Enterprise Edition specification,
but thanks to its modularity it can achieve these and still be very lightweight.
WildFly consumes very few resources and is fast to boot.
Here we are in front of the WildFly website,
with documentation, access to the source code,
and of course how to download and install it.
Installing WildFly is as simple as installing Maven,
you just download a zip file and unzip it into your file system.
In this course I'm using WildFly 10.
1 and because WildFly is written in Java, like Maven, you need the JVM installed to be able to execute it.