So far our book repository manipulates entities
individually with the Entity Manager API.
We know how to find a Book entity by its identifier
to create a book or remove a book.
But finding an entity by Id is quite limiting as we only retrieve
a single entity using its unique identifier.
In practice we often need to retrieve an entity by criteria other than the Id,
such as retrieving by title, isbn, and so on.
This possibility is inherent to relational databases with SQL.
Well JPA also has a language that allows this interaction too.
It's called JPQL.
JPQL, or Java Persistence Query Language,
is used by JPA to define searches against persistence
entities independent of the underlying database.
JPQL is a query language that takes its root in the syntax of SQL.
But the main difference is is that in SQL the results
obtained are in the form of rows and columns,
whereas JPQL uses an entity or a collection of entities.
JPQL syntax is object oriented and therefore easily understood by developers.
Developers manage the entity domain model not a table structure.
JPQL is a database independent query language that uses mapping
annotation to transform a JPQL query into SQL.
The query is executed on the underlying database with SQL and
JDBC calls and then entity instances of the attributes set and
are returned to the application.
Let's have a quick look at the JPQL syntax.
The syntax of a select query consists of two main data parts,
the SELECT and the FROM clause.
SELECT defines the format of the query results.
The FROM clause defines the entity or entities from
which the results will be obtained.
Then we have the optional WHERE, ORDER BY,
GROUP BY, and HAVING clauses to restrict or order the result of the query.
We can apply functions on select statements,
such as AVERAGE, COUNT, MAX, MIN, or SUM.
There are also all the operators that we can expect from a query language,
such as equal, lower than, greater than,
BETWEEN, NOT BETWEEN, and so on.
When it comes to expressions on type, there are few related to numbers,
such as square root or size.
Strings, such as less or concatenation, or dates.
As we can notice the syntax is quite rich and allows
all sorts of entity manipulation.
Let's come back to our repository and see how to
use JPQL syntax we've just seen.
The findAll method is supposed to return the entire list of
books from the database ordered by title.
To do that we need the Entity Manager again.
The Entity Manager has one method that takes a JPQL query
and returns a TypedQuery interface.
This interface controls the query execution.
The method getResultList will actually eat the database,
execute the query, and will return the list of entities following the criteria.
Here the query selects all the instances of entity Book,
the FROM clause is used to give an alias to the instance of the entity.
So lowercase b is the instance of the class Book.
Executing this statement will result in a list of 0 or more book instances.
The ORDER BY clause allows the entities returned by
the SELECT query to be ordered.
The ordering applies to the entity attribute specified in this clause.
Here we order by book title.
In the BookStore application we also need to display a counter
showing the number of books we have in the database.
To achieve that we use the same APIs, the only difference is the query. Here we do a count of the instances b of type Book.