Angular CLI is the right tool to scaffold an Angular
application and generate code.
But we will be using a second scaffolding tool, Swagger code generator.
We've seen Swagger before when we created our JSON
contract for our REST service.
Swagger comes with different tools, such as the contract editor that we saw.
As its name implies,
Swagger code generator generates code from a Swagger contract.
It actually generates codes in over 40 different languages including TypeScript.
So we will use Swagger CodeGen to generate the TypeScript client
stub directly from our BookEndpoint JSON contract.
Being a common line tool, we need to install it in our computer.
If you click on the Download button,
you get to the Swagger CodeGen documentation.
In this documentation,
you will find all the information about Swagger and also how to install it.
Again, if you're on Mac OS X, it's just a brew command line. Make sure you have a few moments to install it.