In terms of tool related to coding, we could stop the list here.
But we want our bookstore web application to have a user
interface with beautiful components.
We could, of course, build our own, but this is not the topic of this course,
so we will reuse existing component libraries.
Material Design has been created in 2014 to have responsive animation,
transition, padding, and all the visual effects such as lighting and shadows.
There is actually a Material Design extension for Angular.
Another famous library is PrimeNG.
Historically is comes from the Java world and is named PrimeFaces.
All the PrimeFaces components have been migrated to work with Angular,
so PrimeNG is one of the richest component libraries at the moment
and of course comes Twitter Bootstrap or Bootstrap.
It is the component library we will be using for the bookstore web application.
Bootstrap is a free and open source front-end web framework
for designing websites and web applications.
It contains HTML and CSS based design templates,
but also forms patterns, navigation, and other graphical components.
As you've seen from the very first demo of the bookstore web application,
it is a simple web application,
so we will only be using a subset of the Bootstrap components.
I'll be using Bootstrap 4 which is still in alpha at the moment,
but shouldn't take long to be final.
If you want to add more graphical components to the
bookstore web application or make it prettier,
do not hesitate to browse the documentation and discover all the possibilities of Bootstrap.