Last but not least,
we will need a browser to visualize our web application and interact with it.
Of course when we develop a web application we need to make
sure it works well on the main browsers,
Edge, Firefox, Opera, Safari, and Chrome.
They all have their pros and cons and all more or less
up to date with the latest HTML, CSS, and JavaScript version.
I won't go into these kind of details here,
but I will explain why I'm using Chrome in this course.
Chrome is a web browser developed by Google and was first released in 2008.
It is one of the most famous browsers on desktops, but also on mobiles.
The nice thing with Chrome when developing an Angular application,
it is Chrome development tools.
The DevTools are a set of web authoring and debugging
tools built into Google Chrome.
We can use the DevTools to iterate, debug, and profile our web application.
Thanks to Google Chrome extension we can install
development tools specific to Angular.
Here I'm using Chrome to browse the DevTools webpage.
It says to open the DevTools pan with common option I on Mac,
if I press it, here it is.
As explained in the documentation there are several
panels to manipulate the DOM, the console,
source panels to check the webpage source,
or the network panel to be able to analyze all the network calls. We will use these panels in our development.