Okay let's check that you've installed all the tools correctly.
First of all, we need Node JS to be installed.
Then we need Yarn to be accessible from the command line and
same thing for our two code generators, Angular CLI and Swagger CodeGen.
Let's switch to the terminal and execute a few commands.
So here I'm in front of IntelliJ IDEA and I'm using the terminal.
So first let's check that we have Node JS,
so a simple node js -v will give us the version.
This way we can also see it's correctly installed and in our path.
Node JS comes with npm, so npm -v gives us the version of npm.
Then we have to install Yarn separately,
again Yarn -v gives us the version of this packaging tool.
And we finish with the two code generation tools,
so Angular CLI as the prefix ng, ng -v gives us the version 1.
1.
0, and swagger-codegen version 2.
2.
2. Well it looks like we are all set up.