Spring's architecture is a traditional model‑view‑controller design pattern.
Since it does follow this methodology,
it's adaptable to many scenarios in which we can develop apps.
We have a module for each of the parts of this pattern throughout the course,
but to give you a brief introduction,
the view can be a simple REST service or JSP page and can handle more
complex scenario such as compiling those JSPs and even work with various
third‑party templating tools and frameworks.
The controller is the same regardless of what the front
end or back end that we're using is.
It's all written using Spring beans and configured just like any Spring bean.
The back end, much like the front end,
can be swapped out with various persistent strategies, JPA, Hibernate,
JDBC, even non‑relational databases.
Spring has support for them.
One thing that is different now than when we originally released this course
is that all of this can be figured with or without XML.
Upon the initial release of this course,
there was a lot of debate between existing frameworks out there and
which to use. Simplifying this course with the update,
we opted out of discussing these comparisons of those various frameworks.
One thing that has changed, though,
is the number of apps now being completely self contained or apps
being developed without XML at all. Specifically, the lack of
web.XML or with later servlet specifications, any XML at all.
Showing the difference of this approach will be the main focus in
the update of this course, while showing you that model‑view‑controller design pattern.