To begin adding that RestController,
let's first start by giving us a model object to return off of our request.
I want to go ahead and open up our src, main,
java, com.pluralsight.conference package.
And go to the model, and right‑click on the model, and say New, Java Class.
And inside of here, I want to just do a User Class.
Let's hit Enter.
Now we give it a couple of member variables.
I'm going to do private String firstname,
private String lastname, and a private int age.
Now let's give ourselves some whitespace and right‑click and say Generate.
We want to do the Getters and Setters. Select all three and say OK.
Let's save this.
Now we've got a model object we can pass back and forth with our controller.
Let's right‑click on our controller and say New, Java Class.
We'll call this UserController.
I want to start off by saying @RestController.
And what this does is it makes sure that every call that goes in
and out of here looks at the content type and the except headers
to see how and what it should return.
And to save yourself the typing, you can go ahead and open up that
RegistrationController and copy that if you want,
or we can code it in by hand.
I'm actually going to paste a Get in here and change a few things.
First, I'm going to start by importing the classes that we need,
and the User object specifically wants us to select that
particular one, and our request parameters.
Now we have all the pieces we need inside of here, and let's
walk through what this example's doing.
The return type of this method getUser is our user object type.
Now, in the previous examples we were doing with our registration controller,
you can see here on line 16, we were returning a string.
Let me expand that code so you can see it.
On line 17, we were returning the actual string registration,
which referred to our GSP page with our InternalResourceViewResolver.
Well, we don't do that with a RestController. We
return the actual body to our caller.
So we're going to have a request come in, and the response is
going to be the actual body of the response.
Now there's a couple other things in here. You'll notice that
we have a @RequestParam that will pull those parameters off
the URL as we make requests to it.
And right now I just have one of them.
We can add the other ones in here and say @RequestParam,
lastname, and we can grab the age if we want as well.
Now we can set those values in our actual objects.
We'll say user.setLastname and user.setAge and save this.
We have all the pieces we need for this to now return that body back
containing the user object that we've created.
Now obviously,
we usually wouldn't be just taking parameters that come in and
storing them in an object and returning them.
This is where we would have a service auto‑injected into our
business logic tier or our model that would go ahead and
retrieve this out of a database.
So lines 15, 17, 18, 19,
all of this would be a database call to our model tier
returning something from a repository.
But for this example,
it shows you how we're grabbing those request parameters and storing
them in an object and returning them back out to you.
Let's save this.
Going to start my server up. And now, we don't have a page set up for this.
We're just going to request that actual instance back.
So we can say user and hit Enter,
and you'll see we get JSON text back, and there are
defaults that are already in there for us.
But we can override that with query parameters,
so we can say firstname is equal to Dan.
And when we run that, it will return that as Dan.
You can do others out there. We'll say lastname equals to Frandson.
And we can override the age while we're at it.
Just standard query parameters.
We'll say age equals 33.
Notice that it handled the strings appropriately,
the integer appropriately. We are reading in those query params,
storing it in the object, and returned it without us
having to use any view resolvers.
So it goes ahead and just by default accepts that JSON response back and returns it to you as a client.