Here is a standard MVC or model view controller design pattern
that you may or may not have seen before.
It's a pretty common pattern.
In fact,
I would say that most developers have at least seen it or at least heard of it.
A request comes through the view based off of some user
event and then is interpreted by the controller. The
controller can change the model or not.
And then it will select the view based off of our action.
From here,
the model can update the view with the database off of the user's actions.
This graphic is sometimes confusing though because it's stemmed
from rich client applications that were more event based or using
a design pattern called observer observable or a subscriber
listener type design pattern.
Not really applicable to a lot of the software development we do with the web.
This pattern in concept is still very sound, but we
usually don't have our model updating our view because
it's gone to a page at that point, and it's disconnected from our back end.
This graphic though is a more accurate description of the kind of life
cycle that we may be faced with in web development.
The graphic is realistically more like the life cycle
that we see in our web application.
Our view can access our model, but it's usually done so through a controller.
We'll look more at lightweight approaches in the Ajax module later
in this course. The summary is we usually make a request, even if
it's a lightweight request, through our controller to access our
model. We don't have our view typically going directly against our database or model.