We've already seen some of this before, and, in fact, this image
was the same image we used in our architecture discussion in the
previous module, but I grayed out the other tiers to just focus
on what is a controller.
And we've even created a controller when we wrote our greeting
controller in our first step of our application.
But here's what's happening as we're going through a
request from the user. The request comes in,
and that's going to go to a particular controller based off of what
the user's request was, and it's going to interact with some business
logic. Now that business logic is going to produce some data, and it
can theoretically be a web service or it could be our database or it
could just be our business logic tier. That's going to produce some
output.
We can think of that as our model or our UI, and we'll eventually
return that model back to our UI on our response.
As we come out of our web service or request,
we're going to hand that back to our controller, and then our controller is
going to go in and decide which view is appropriate based off of what
information was returned or what happened out of our request,
and we're going to hand that back to the user.
The controller can almost be thought of as a traffic cop,
hence the logo defining a traffic light.
The responsibilities of a controller are to interpret user
input and transport that input into a model.
To take that information that's going to come back from our business
logic from our service tier and build that into a model to hand back to
our UI. It is the gateway to our business logic, and will determine the
correct views based off of that logic.
One other key point that never really seems to come up to play as far
as the duties of a controller is, is that it also interprets exceptions
for the business logic and service tier, and how to handle and navigate
those correctly from there.
Now,
it could be a business logic exception in the sense that you
haven't given me a valid date, or it could be, hey,
the database is down.
I'm going to send you this error page rather than requesting that you add
this information or correct this information on the screen.
So its duties are to also interpret those errors, and handle and navigate from our middle tier.