To begin adding internationalization to our application,
we want to start by opening up our ConferenceConfig,
and we're actually going to add three beans inside of here.
I'll make this full screen so it's a little easier for you to see.
The first thing we're going to add is a SessionLocaleResolver,
and this will just use the LocaleResolver interface,
but the SessionLocaleResolver's what ties our current session to a locale.
And this bean is just going to take and create an instance of the
LocaleResolver and put it out in our Spring registry for us.
I've gone ahead and pasted this in.
You can see we start off with a default locale of Locale.US.
You can change that to your specified region if you want,
but this is what I'm going to start with.
The next bean that we're going to add in here is the LocaleChangeInterceptor,
and the LocaleChangeInterceptor just looks for a parameter,
either through a hidden element or on our URL string as a query parameter,
however we want to pass that in,
but it looks for that to see if it should intercept that change.
And you can see on line 35 here that we are looking for the param name of Lang,
L‑a‑n‑g.
Now the next thing we need to add actually isn't a bean.
It's going to be a feature that we override from the WebMvcConfigure,
and it's the interceptor we're going to add.
So we just created this LocaleChangeInterceptor.
Now we're going to register it,
and I like to keep all the things that we've overridden at the top
where we're going to be making those changes to that
WebMvcConfigure and the beans defined down below.
Really, it's just personal preference.
It doesn't matter.
Anywhere you put this in this file will be fine.
Those are the three things we had to add to the ConferenceConfig.
Now we want to go ahead and create two properties files,
and I'm going to do that by right‑clicking on our src,
main, resources directory and say New, File.
And for the name, I'm going to type in messages.properties,
and the name matters here.
So notice its messages, plural.
I'm going to hit Enter.
And the first thing I'm going to put inside of here is a comment.
I'm going to do labels, and this is just for personal preference.
And then give it to the name‑value pair of Name.
And then I'm going to throw another comment in here for buttons,
and the name‑value pair of save.changes=Save Changes,
and save it.
Now we want to add another properties file out here.
I'm going to right‑click on our src, main,
resources directory again and say New, File,
and the name of this one's going to be messages_es.properties.
And this is specifically for the Spanish translations.
So in here, I'm going to do the same thing, except I'm going to cheat.
I'm going to just grab this text that we just typed out,
copy it, and paste it inside of here.
I'm going to change it to the Spanish translation of Nombre.
And we'll change Save Changes, cambios.
There we go.
And we have our two properties files,
and the locale that we pass in with that change interceptor is
going to go look for the appropriate properties file and pull
that translation out of that file.
Now let's open up our registration.jsp page,
and this is pretty simple, but we have to add two pieces inside of here.
First, we want to start by adding another tag library at the top of our page.
We'll say %@ for the tag library,
and we're going to give this a prefix of spring.
And for the URI,
we want to choose the http://www.springframework.org/tags and save that.
And now we can come down to this text for Name,
and we'll change that to be the spring:message tag.
And the code="name".
And then make sure you close that tag off.
So we can save that,
and you can go through and change all of the fields as we go.
I'm going to start my server up just to show you that this is
working the way that we expect it to work.
And now it's launched our browser for us.
I can click on the registration link, and to begin with,
it shows up with Name in English.
But if I had a query parameter on the end of here and say
language=es for Spanish and hit Enter,
notice that it will translate Name to Nombre,
and it will also ask us if it wants us to translate
this page for us automatically.
So you can see that we are now using that internationalization.
And you can go through and change the title of the page,
the buttons to say Submit changes or Save changes or to add registration,
whatever translations you want to go through and add.
You can see we have all the pieces now set up to do internationalization inside of our app.