We didn't have to create an engine of any sort when we were using JSP Pages,
so this is a little bit unique to Thymeleaf.
We have to create a Spring templateEngine that will process
the pages and substitute in the model values from Spring
into our pages to be displayed.
Notice that this code makes a call to that templateResolver method
that we just created in the previous example.
Let's go ahead and add this into our ConferenceConfig file.
Now the templateEngine is just another bean and can actually go right
below the templateResolver that we just created.
I'm going to paste this code in here and import it as well,
and it stands alone on its own.
It doesn't have a bunch of other references other than
that call to the templateResolver.
So on line 72 you can see where it's calling the
templateResolver that we just created on line 61.
We have this templateEngine that is configured just for Spring,
and it also has enabled the Spring Expression Language compiler,
the EL compiler,
and that just makes it so we can use the shorthand syntax of
accessing Spring variables and passing them in.
That's it.
That's all we have to add for the templateResolver.
Now we can add the actual ViewResolver for those templates that the controller can navigate things to.