To be able to pass data from our request, whether that's a RESTful
service or from a JSP page to our controller,
we're going to use some libraries provided to us by Spring MVC.
We could actually just use the standard HTML input tags,
but Spring provides us a library making it easier to
interact with our controllers.
Historically,
we've always just passed HTTP parameters that have gone on an HTTP
request, and those parameters can then be accessed much similar to
like a hash map where I just grab a parameter based off of its name so
every HTML element would be named.
Well,
there's tags that Spring provides us to take these values
from our input page and make them available to our
controller through the model hash map, bind them to a specified object,
which is actually the approach we're going to do, or just be able to grab
them off the request. So we could always pass in the servlet request into
our method name and access it that way.
I'll actually walk through the example showing you all of those.
The model can actually be a bit confusing, as you'll notice in our
controller box that our model for accessing parameters and returning
data is actually the same model and view object.
We'll walk through that, though, so it's not quite as confusing.
The binding object attribute approach that I just spoke about is used whenever
we want to send data to our controller or retrieve data from our controller
that's bound to an object or represented by an object.
The nice thing about Spring MVC is that it's all done with basic POJOs and
not using a class that's only specific to our UI like in some of the other
frameworks such as Struts or WebWork or Stripes.
So we'll use the @ModelAttribute when we want to do
an HTTP Get to get back data.
So say I'm going to get a drop‑down like a list of states or,
you know, a drop‑down type list of data,
gender, or those types of things.
We want to grab that stuff that might be driven by our database.
Well, we also use that same thing for Post. So it's the same object.
It's bound the same way, and it's described the same way.
We have a form that we're filling out,
and that's actually the example we're going to do here in our demo in a
couple of minutes is the object that we send down through our Get is
the same object we'll bind to on our Post.
I mentioned it works with POJO, so it's very simple.
And I don't have something that's specifically bound to just my UI tier.
I can use it anywhere in my code.
These objects can also be validated with a binding result.
We're going to cover that in its own separate module later,
but just to point it out so you're aware of it, you can have this data validated as part of your lifecycle.