As we mentioned before,
JQuery has stayed pretty tried and true for accessing data,
especially for some RESTful services.
You can see in this example here we're going against a URL.
It's the URL we actually just created for localhost:8080/conference/user.
And then we can grab the body, the data,
and grab the first name out of that and append that into our document last
name and age and manipulate the data in our DOM with that.
Let's go ahead and add some JQuery into our project now.
It's pretty simple.
We're going to add a little JQuery snippet and then add a user.html page that
just uses JavaScript to interact with our RESTful service.
To start let's add that user.js file inside of our static directory.
So I'm going to right‑click on src, main,
resources, static here and say New, File,
and I'll just do user.js and hit Enter.
Then I'm going to right‑click on static again and create another file,
user.html.
And these two files are just going to have some simple
HTML and some simple JavaScript.
In fact, it was the exact JavaScript we just showed on the previous slide,
to access our URL.
I'm going to paste in this JavaScript.
I'll make it full screen so that you can see it.
It's a little bit of coding.
If you want,
you can grab these out of the examples and just paste it in yourself.
It's underneath the course, main directory,
and there's an exercise files link in there that you can
grab that information and just paste it in.
And I'm going to do the same thing for the HTML.
And there are a couple things to note in here.
The script is using a CDN, or a Content Delivery Network,
to pull in our JavaScript on line 5.
And then we're referencing that script that we just created on line 6.
And we have a couple of elements down here,
firstname, lastname, and age,
that are being referenced in our JavaScript file over here.
So when we grab that data,
we go ahead and manipulate those elements with that data from firstname,
lastname, age on this request.
So when the page loads, it calls this AJAX function when the page is ready,
and then it takes the results of that and appends them
into those elements in our HTML page.
Let's start our server up.
And we haven't created our helpful little link in here.
We should,
but all we have to do is go up to our URL and type in user.html and hit Enter.
And you'll notice it pulled back Bryan, Hansen, and age 43.
So it went out, did our request from a REST controller,
and pulled that information back in.
Really easy to do.
You can see how valuable these RESTful services are,
and we're not using anything like JSP pages in this example or Thymeleaf.
We're just going out and pulling these RESTful services
into our app using simple JavaScript, just JQuery.
I don't even have to have anything as advanced as Angular or React or Vue.
It's a simple AJAX call.
Very powerful and a great way to access data and have this inside of your just basic HTML.