There are actually a lot of reasons why we would want to host up static
files from with inside of our Spring MVC application.
We may want to implement security on them,
we want to make sure they're logged in, we could possibly do some caching stuff.
Regardless, it's really easy for us to do.
It's very similar to what we just did with the view resolver,
except we're going to add a resource handler.
We do have to implement one interface, and we'll walk through that,
but then we just add it to the registry of the Resource Handler Registry,
and we say that, hey, any request to files,
I want you to go ahead and look in this directory,
and we've created a WEB‑INF/pdf/ directory,
and we can host up static files from there that are PDFs.
Let's walk through this configuration in our code now.
To host up static PDFs,
I'm going to start by creating a PDF directory alongside of our JSP directory.
I'm going to right‑click on WEB‑INF and say New Directory, pdf, hit Enter.
Then I have a sample PDF I just grabbed off of my file system,
and I encourage you to do the same, and just drag that PDF into your application.
It's going to ask you if you want to copy that in, and we'll say yes.
Then we want to implement an interface.
Now we have this configuration class set up,
but we're going to implement this interface and use
it to override some functionality.
So I'm going to say implements WebMvcConfigure,
and then I want to add in here a resource handler.
So I'm going to add in the addResourceHandler's method that overrides the
implementing basic functionality that's currently there,
and say registry.addResourceHandler.
I'm going to put in a path of /files/**.
So it's going to look for anything in that path,
and then I'm going to specify the location of where we
just created that directory structure, /WEB‑INF/pdf/.
So that resource location needs to match exactly what you
named your folder underneath WEB‑INF.
If you added an s on the end or something like that,
it's a common mistake I've seen people make.
It needs to be identical.
Let's save that, restart our application server, and see
if that will host up our PDF for us.
Now that we are at our browser,
we can go up to our address bar and type in files/ps.pdf, because you'll
remember in that resource handler, that was the path that we wanted it to
resolve to, and hit Enter, and it will serve up our PDF.
And it works just like we thought it did.
Let's look at that configuration in that configure again one more
time. You can see on line 15 where we told it to go to /file/**, and
on line 16 where we told it to locate those files under
/WEB‑INF/pdf/. That's all it took for us to resolve static files hosted from inside of our application.