This is where we left off our registration page.
After just performing a GET to display the page.
Let's now turn this into a form where we can use it to
turn a POST back to our controller.
Going back to our IDE, I'm going open up that registration.jsp page,
and the first thing we need to do is add that spring
tag library up at the top of it.
And the syntax for that's a little bit odd. So we've got to do a %@,
and it's going to ask us if we want to enter a tag library,
which we do.
And we need to give it a prefix.
The prefix want to give this is form.
And you can name this whatever you want.
We can do a URI and choose springframework.org/tags/form.
So now we've got our tag in here,
and that's going to help us auto complete stuff inside of our body.
I'm going to go below that h1 that we created and create a form
using the form tag library that we just imported.
And inside of here, I'm going to do a couple of things,
and I'm not going to bore you with all the typing details.
I'm going to throw in a table, yes, just a basic HTML table,
and we'll do something fancy here with CSS and other stuff later.
But inside of here, we're going to do a tr,
and we're going to give this a td,
and this is where it starts to get a little bit fun.
I'm going to give this a name, and in the next td,
I want to give this a form input of name.
And what I mean by this is I'm going to input this form tag here,
and the path of this is name.
Now, you might be wondering why it's called a path,
and it's because it refers to the binding object for this page.
It's actually tied to a backing object that we're going
to sync up with the model attribute.
Don't worry, we'll show you here in a second what that means exactly.
I'm going to create another tr.
I going to do another td here.
I'm going to give that a call span of 2.
And then inside of that, I'm going to just do a regular HTML input,
and this input we're going to do a type ="submit" and
give that a value of Add Registration.
Now, we can save this.
And I'll be honest with you, the first time we run this, it's going to break.
And I'm going to make this break on purpose because I want
to show you the error that it displays.
So when you run into this, because you will at some point,
you'll know how to fix this.
So I'm going to restart my server,
have it pull up that page for us again and deploy everything,
and then we'll have references to this new JSP page.
Now, we can go to our Registration link,
and when I click on it, it'll break, and it gives us this error.
Now, one thing that Spring Boot does that I don't really necessarily care for,
is it hides some of that stack trace.
It's not an actual problem because I can see where the error is at.
It tells us Name: 14, td: 15 and 16.
It doesn't know what this form:input path="name" is on line 16,
and it's telling you it doesn't know what to do with Name.
It's because it doesn't have the field in a backing object to tie that to.
Let's fix that now.
Fixing that binding error is actually pretty easy.
We only need to do a couple of things inside of our application.
So I'm going to go ahead and click on
com.pluralisight.conference right below src,
main, java, not controller.
I'm going to right‑click and say New, Java Class,
and inside of here, I want to type model.registration.
And what this will do is create a new package and class at the same time,
and you'll see that our controllers and our model on the left are separate.
Inside of here, I'm going to just do a private String name,
and then below that, I want to right‑click and generate our getters and setters,
and click OK.
And now we've created that registration object.
I want to go to our RegistrationController now.
Inside of here,
we're going to get rid of that map that we have for that basic model object.
I'm going to replace that with @ModelAttribute,
and we name this ModelAttribute so we can reference it in our page,
and I'm going to call this registration,
and then we tie it to an actual object.
So inside of here, I'll say Registration,
and I'll call the instance of that registration as well,
and now we have our object bound by our model to this ModelAttribute.
One last thing we need to do now is go back over to our registration.jsp page,
go up to our form,
and we want to add the ModelAttribute here of registration and save that.
Now,
if you've looked at old code or you have old code that you're
upgrading to a Spring 5 MVC implementation,
this used to be called commandName.
That will no longer work.
It's been deprecated and removed.
It will break, and you'll be left scratching your head,
wondering why. It's now called ModelAttribute,
which I like because the name is now consistent.
It used to be inconsistent.
So on line 9 here, this ModelAttribute that we just added to our
form tag ties to our RegistrationController on line 14 where I
say ModelAttribute registration.
Those objects are bound together now when we display
our page. I'm going to save that, pull up our server, and redeploy our server.
And now when I click on our Registration link,
it should pull our page up, and it does.
I will tell you, we're not done yet though, and that's probably not
what you wanted to hear. If I enter in a a name here, so I just put
Bryan inside of here and click Add Registration, it's going to break
because we haven't supported POSTs yet.
We did a GET mapping, but we haven't done a POST mapping.
Really easily, let's switch back over to our IDE. On line 13
in our RegistrationController,
you can see that we're only supporting GET mappings with this
method. There is a way to make it to where it will do both a
GET and a POST in one method.
It's honestly not a good to use case though.
I'm going to go ahead and copy that, and paste it down to a
new line, and do POST, and then I want to change the method
name to addRegistration, save that, make sure you've imported everything.
And now, we should be ready to bring that back up to our page.
I'm going to go ahead and add a System.out.println here, just so we
could see the value that's in registration as it comes through. I'm
going to say registration, and then add just a getter on that
registration for the Name, and just dump that out to the console.
So I'll save that.
Let's restart our server,
have it pull that up, and now when we click on that Registration link,
it'll display that page.
We can enter our value in here, I'm going to put in Bryan,
click Add Registration,
and it will direct us back to the page because we don't
have anywhere else for it to go right now.
But if I go back over to our IDE,
we can see in the logs at the bottom of here that it
printed out Registration: Bryan Hansen.
So it went full cycle.
It went through our GET mapping, displayed the page, went through our POST,
printed out what values we had there, we could do this in a debug mode and
toggle for a breakpoint there to stop us and see what that value is, but
this was quick and dirty and got the application up and running to where you
could see those values and the full lifecycle of our GET and our POST inside
of that object.
We also just created a simple registration that we bound to,
and then we created those forms inside of our JSP pages
that went out and bound it to that object.
We also have validation in there.
We haven't done anything with that yet.
That's in a separate module.
But everything is set up.
It's full featured.
We've got our dispatcher servlet, our GETs, our POSTs, our
controllers, our model objects that are backing our forms. We have all the pieces of our application set up for us now.