This module was all about Ajax, Ajax calls,
pulling back, RESTful services from our server.
We did this implementing a RESTController.
We showed you how to do the GET and the POST,
and honestly, the PUT and the DELETE are identical.
It's really no different,
so there's not a lot of sense in going through those exercises.
We then showed you a quick example using Postman and how
powerful it can be to use that to not only GET but have canned
examples of POSTs back to the server.
It's a great way for you to test your web services and
run through that pretty quickly.
And then we did a final example using JQuery and showed you exactly how
easy it was to use an Ajax call in your HTML to pull back that JSON data
from your URL. And this is the end of this course.
I want to thank you for staying with us this long and completing everything.
I would recommend looking at some of the continuation courses after this. I
have a Spring Data JPA with Hibernate course, Spring Security, I have other
courses on RESTful services, and a great series on design patterns that,
regardless of using Spring, if you're doing any type of Java development,
I would recommend you look into those. Thank you, and I appreciate you sticking with us.