Hi everyone.
My name is Steven Haines, and welcome to my Pluralsight course,
Test-Driven Development with Spring and JUnit 5.
Properly testing your code is important to the success of you applications,
but there are so many different technologies in a Spring
application that doing it right can seem overwhelming.
We'll break those technologies down into small and
understandable units as we develop unit tests for various Spring
services that fit into an ecommerce website.
Some of the major topics that we'll cover include testing the
individual components that comprise a Spring web service,
including controllers, services, and back-end repositories.
Each component requires its own testing strategy,
so we'll review the ins and outs of each component and
discuss the best way to test each.
Then we'll look at testing Spring web services that
connect to different back ends.
We'll test a service that connects to a SQL database by using
DbUnit to pre-populate the database before our tests run and
clean it up after tests complete so that we can write tests
against a known set of good data.
We'll test the service that connects to MongoDB,
following a similar pattern,
and we'll test a service that connects to a third-party API using
WireMock to simulate the behavior of the third-party API.
Finally,
we'll develop a set of integration tests using JUnit to validate that
our application works together as a complete unit.
By the end of this course,
you'll feel comfortable writing JUnit 5 test cases for Spring applications,
but more importantly,
you'll have more confidence in the quality of your Spring
applications and how they'll behave in production.
Before beginning this course,
I recommend being familiar with Spring and having had some
exposure to test-driven development in JUnit 5.
I hope you'll join me to learn how to properly test your
Spring applications with the Test-Driven Development with Spring and JUnit 5 course, at Pluralsight.