This course contains four modules in addition to this introduction,
so let's review what we'll be covering.
Globomantics is an electronic retailer that just
built their first ecommerce site,
but needs some help getting their Spring MVC back end production ready.
They've built a web front end as a single-page application,
or SPA, and three services.
The product service provides information about the products that they sell,
the review service maintains reviews of the products that they sell,
and finally,
the inventory service connects to a third-party API that manages the
inventory for both their brick-and-mortar stores,
as well as their online website.
In this course,
we're going to write test cases for the three back-end
services that the web front end calls.
We'll leave the front-end testing for another course.
The first service that we'll look at is the product service.
It's a Spring Boot microservice built using Spring 5.
It leverages the Spring RestController and is implemented with
autowiring and uses convention over configuration.
As such, Spring automatically discovers the controller service and repository,
finds the H2 driver in the class path and creates an
embedded H2 instance and a data source for us.
It uses the H2 database, which is traditionally used for testing purposes,
but for simplicity's sake,
we changed the scope of the H2 resource to allow it to be used at runtime.
You're free to substitute MySQL or any other SQL
database for your production needs.
Finally,
data persistence is accomplished using Spring's JDBC
template and hand-written SQL.
For the purposes of our tests,
the difference between hand-written SQL and Spring Data with JPA is moot,
as we'll be testing the repository,
but I wanted to include a breadth of practiced technology,
so I included a repository that implements persistence by hand.
The second service that we'll be looking at is the review service.
It's also a Spring Boot microservice built using Spring 5,
leveraging the Spring RestController, autowiring,
and uses convention over configuration.
It uses MongoDB for its persistence layer,
and for testing,
we're using the embedded Mongo library so that we can test our data
persistence without installing a full MongoDB instance.
Finally, data persistence is accomplished using Spring Data.
Spring Data is a modern persistence abstraction that allows you to define an
interface containing the operations that you want to perform,
and it automatically generates an implementation of that interface for you.
When using Spring Data on top of a relational database,
it'll generate hibernate code under the hood.
When using Spring Data on top of MongoDB,
it will generate persistence logic using Spring's built-in support for Mongo.
The final service we'll review is the inventory service.
It's a Spring Boot microservice,
but the interesting thing about it is that it connects to an inventory manager,
which is a third-party API through a RESTful interface.
The inventory service makes its RESTful calls using Spring's REST template,
which makes it easy to make RESTful calls and translate request
and response bodies to and from Java objects.
We'll finish the course with a module that describes how to perform
integration tests against each service using JUnit.
Integration testing allows us to make sure that our
components are properly wired together by Spring,
and tests the requests made to each service passed through the
technology stack and return the correct results.
To do this,
we'll leverage Spring's MockMvc to make our requests and validate responses,
and then we'll set up and tear down our back-end resources using the
strategies that we'll learn in the other modules.
At the completion of this course,
you should feel comfortable writing unit tests with Spring 5 and JUnit 5.
Specifically,
you should be able to write unit tests against Spring
services that connect to a SQL back end,
MongoDB, and a third-party API.
Finally,
you should feel comfortable developing integration tests for your Spring components using JUnit 5.