Let's take a look at testing our controller by reviewing the
source code for the ReviewControllerTest class.
The ReviewControllerTest class should look familiar to you by now.
It begins by including the ExtendWith SpringExtension annotation,
which manages the application context; the SpringBootTest annotation,
which populates our application context with all of our
Spring-managed beans; and the AutoConfigureMockMvc annotation,
which creates a MockMvc instance and wires it into our test class.
We create a mock ReviewService for our test using the MockBean annotation.
One of the new things in this test is the comparison of dates.
Spring returns dates based on the date format you see
here with the timezone set to GMT.
We create a simple DateFormat to use in our data comparison and we set the
timezone to GMT in our beforeAll JUnit set up method.
BeforeAll is called once in this test case before all tests run.
The testGetReviewByIdFound method executes a get request
against /review/id to retrieve a review.
And the mock service is configured to return a mockReview that contains a
single review entry when its findById method is called.
It uses the mockMvc.perform method to execute the GET request,
specifying /review/reviewId, then it validates the response.
It checks to make sure that we receive a 200 OK HTTP response code,
a JSON response body, and the correct ETAG and LOCATION HttpHeaders,
then it validates the return body.
In the previous module, we had a simple document,
and we were able to extract fields in the root of that document.
In this case, the ID and productId are in the root of the response,
but we have a list of entries that we want to validate.
First we use the jsonPath expression $ .entries .length.
Recall that the dollar sign represents the root of the document,
so $ .entries references the entries element
attached to the root of the document.
The length method is then specified to retrieve the
number of elements in its array.
In this case, we have one entry, so we compare the length to 1.
Next we want to examine the contents of the entry.
Just like Java arrays,
jsonPath defines its array notation using square brackets and an index,
starting at 0.
So $ .entries at 0.username references the username key in
the first node of the entries array, which we compare to test-user.
Likewise, we compare the entries review to Great product.
Finally, in order to compare dates,
we need to format our date using the simple dateFormat that
we created above that was set to GMT.
We extract the date from the JSON payload and then compare it to the date
string generated by the dateFormat's format method.
It's pretty simple once you know how to do it,
but there's plenty of room for questions when facing
testing dates for our quality.
The remaining methods are all similar to what you've already seen.
The testGetReviewByIdNotFound method executes the same GET request,
but this time the mocked service is configured to return an
Optional.empty when its findById method is called so it validates that
the controller returns a 404 NotFound response.
The testCreateReview method performs a POST request to /review,
passing in a mock review that contains a single entry,
using the same asJson object method that we saw in the last module.
The review service is configured to return another mockReview object that
includes an ID and version number when its save method is called,
so we would expect that review to be presented back to us.
The test method then verifies that it receives a 201 created HTTP response code,
a JSON payload, the correct ETAG and LOCATION HttpHeaders,
as well as a valid JSON document.
The last method that I included is testAddEntryToReview.
The purpose of this method is to test posting a new entry to an existing review.
The controller will first execute a findByProductId call on
its service to retrieve the exiting review,
then it will add the entry to the review,
save it to the Mongo database,
and return the result in the review with the new entry.
To facilitate this,
we need to create a new ReviewEntry to post to the controller,
a mockReview to return from the findByProductId method,
and a mockReview that will be returned by the save method.
After setting up all these mock objects and configuring the mock service,
we invoke the controller with a POST request through mockMvc
and validate that the response is correct.
There's plenty of room for additional test cases,
but between what you learned in the last module and these examples, the rest should be straightforward.