Hello and welcome back to the course and part VI in this section of the course we've got a very exciting
challenge we're dealing with data from a bank and we're going to be visualizing different things about
this back and creating a business intelligence report.
So as usual to get the data set we need to go to your browser and go to Dr. predestines dot com slash
power be at one word.
And if you scroll down here you'll see Section 5 building a robust be-I dashboard.
So here's a data set.
Just go ahead and download that.
It's the CACP file.
And just here's a quick caveat that today's dataset is dummy data for an imaginary bank operating in
the UK so you don't have to worry about this information being sensitive.
This is all made up information.
It's not real banks information of course.
And so once you've done load the file this go ahead and open it to explore what columns we have here.
So we're going to zoom in a little bit and we're going to be able to better so here we've got customer
I.D. we've got the name the surname the gender of our customer the age of the region where they're from
in the UK.
The job of discussion whether they're white color blue color or other.
And then we've got the date when they joined the bank.
So this is all relatively new bank.
All the customers joined in 2015.
And then we've got the balance that these these customers have on their accounts.
So there we go that's all of the information that we have and what we need to do with this information
is we need to create a business intelligence report that will show the executives of the bank how the
will portray the geo demographics segmentation of the bank so you'll show them where the customers are
from what their age groups are.
What is the split by gender.
What kind of balances they have with this the distribution by balance and so on.
And so if you scroll down to the bottom you'll see that we have 4000 and 15 rows actually 4000 thousand
14 because one goes ahead.
And yes it's a moderately sized dataset and it will be interesting to see what kind of distributions
we'll find in here.
So let's go ahead and close this.
And now we're going to bring a power be-I and connected data set.
So is.
This is a new report and now we're going to just get data at the top.
This is LCAC files.
So x v UK bank customers give it a second and there we go we can just check that that is correct.
That load and voila there they are so we can always go in here and make sure that we've loaded the correct
data set and at the bottom you can see you can confirm that it is 4000 and 14 rows total as we saw in
our file it's always good to confirm those things.
Okay so that's it for today.
We know what's the deal has about we know the challenge is and very you loaded the data in the next
tutorial will start and proceed with the first charge for our business intelligence report.
And I look forward to seeing you then.
Until next time happy analyze analyzed.