Hey guys welcome back to the course and welcome to The New Video Marketing section.
You're finally out of the woods with content marketing.
I'm sorry.
So long.
Now there's no denying the power of video these days.
You know it used to be the case that making video was kind of a novelty but now everybody's got video
or at least their toe in video when you're on Facebook.
What do you engage with more often videos when you're on Twitter.
It's the same thing.
Nowadays a lot of people even get more of their information from YouTube than really any other source
myself included have taught myself an enormous amount of things to YouTube and it kind of makes sense.
Video is a much more efficient way of getting information across not only can you say more in less time
but it's also much easier for the viewer to actually engage with and digest.
There's a quote that says a picture is worth a thousand words.
Well if a picture is worth a thousand words how many words do you think video is worth considering.
Every frame has an image and every second is 24 images so the section we're tackling.
Video Marketing how to get into it how to manage it and how to use video in this new medium that everybody
seems to love to get your message across and to bring in more customers.
Now video marketing comes in a lot of different forms from the short ads to longer explainer videos
to the much longer walk through.
And really a lot more.
So there are plenty of ways you could use video for whatever business venture you have in mind and that's
what this section is really going to be about.
How can you the layman the non videographer jump into video and use it to reach your goals.
I'm here to give you the tips and advice on how to do exactly that.
So in the next set of lectures we've got our God probably 20 of them we're going to cover what you need
to know to plan and produce your own videos for marketing purposes.
We'll talk about things like the most common types of marketing videos and what you might consider for
yourself.
We'll talk about how to meet business goals specifically with video how to angle the video depending
on what you're looking for if it's like awareness of its shares or its conversions.
Also jump into pre-production where you plan out your video and you talk about how you know how you're
going to write the script and how you're going to plan the storyboarding.
We'll discuss the importance of YouTube and then how your strategy for video needs to change.
If you are going to pursue YouTube and then of course there's production which is how do I actually
plan and make these videos.
What kind of cameras do I use lighting what audio equipment do I need.
How do I save money in this process.
Don't worry I got you covered.
We're going to cover how to use video and different step tiers of budgets.
I've also got three great video setups that we can actually look at and see how everything is set up
and what it produces at the end.
And then of course we're to cover post-production which will talk about things like editing how it works
what to use what are different styles we can try out.
And then of course if you don't want to edit it how do we hire someone to do the editing.
We'll get into where you can find people to help you in your stock.
And then also how to use things like templates to save you time and money.
The goal here is to set you up in the knowledge you need to understand video basics how it works how
to pick the right equipment and how to get the results you want.
You should finish this section of the list of ideas of what to make what to use and how to integrate
all of it into whatever content strategy you've already got started.
All right sounds good.
Let's do it.
See in the next election.