Hey guys.
Welcome back to the course.
Now I want to start off this lecture with a kind of an observation.
I was on Twitter recently and I kept seeing these companies that offer services like apps or whatever
just random products as tools things like that.
And they kept sharing links to these really Din's guides that are just full of information.
I'm sure you've seen them.
People sharing things like the beginner's guide to starting a blog or 57 illustrator tutorials for creating
a logo.
Now wouldn't you see companies whose focus is selling an app or selling some widget and they're spending
all this time and money promoting information.
You've got to wonder now why is it exactly that they're doing that.
Why did they create that e-book.
Why did they make some ridiculously long resource guide on how to do something vaguely related to what
they're involved in.
How exactly does this pay off for them.
Well this process of creating posts and documents and any other information the company thinks might
be valuable in posting those online and then promoting them is all part of what we the marketing hipsters
call a content strategy.
Now what's the point of content strategy doing the things I just described.
Well there's actually good points to why you might want to do a content strategy.
Really the idea is to drive traffic back to your Web site where they can sell all of their things.
So they look at this information that you shared then presumably they there are now more aware of you
or they click through somewhere else on your Web site.
They give you their email address in some way that you can then sell them later or next page they click
on.
Oftentimes the point of content marketing is twofold.
Sometimes it'll be to share information so that the audience understands your product better and is
therefore more willing to buy and or use it.
Generally speaking the idea is to satisfy some need for your potential customers out there.
So they'll then consider you a helpful source of information and eventually that trust and that affinity
they've built will kind of bleed over into other things namely things that you can make money off of.
But all of those things the driving of the traffic the sharing of the information the satisfying of
needs connecting with people.
All of that is going to be done through the content they produce.
That's why we call it content marketing.
And yes I know content is one of those words those terms that's just kind to Soon as I say content it
kind of floats off away into the air just dissipates cause it's really vague and it's oftentimes meaningless
as someone who really likes to define a lot of things.
I honestly cannot stand that word.
And it pains me.
But we're going to be doing this section before we do.
Let's establish what content can mean.
Now content could refer to a blog post Tichenor for social media posts videos podcast infographics e-books
e-mail pretty much anything you can think of that provides information or value and it's not in the
form of the actual product or service.
So don't think of a content strategy as the same thing as say like a blog strategy.
It's much much bigger than that and you can take advantage of the flexibility of content.
The ability to create lots of different kinds of things to Baskett across the right message.
When you run an ad campaign you only get a couple sentences across but if you run a content marketing
campaign oftentimes your customers will be reading the equivalent of a book that you wrote for them.
It gives you a lot of opportunity to kind of frame how they see you and kind of set yourself up as this
this figure that gives them lots of good information for you the viewer at home as part of your content
strategy you might create lists or you might develop some of those big beginners guides that kind of
referenced earlier.
And the process will be clear.
You know you define an audience you focus on one of their needs or a way to help them you then create
high quality information or the highest quality information you can.
You publish it where your audience can find it.
You promote it and then you engage with your audience when they respond to it.
At the end of the day if you create content that is valuable to your audience whether it be in a blog
form an email and infographics ebook whatever it is and then you make sure your audience can find and
use that information.
Well in general you're going to grow an audience and then you're really one step away from increasing
your sales.
Now in this section we're to go through the process of developing a content strategy one step at a time
for your business if you know you have no interest in producing information that your audience finds
valuable.
You don't want to write blogs.
You don't really want to spend a lot of time doing these side tasks creating these topical kind of things
that your audience might digest well maybe this is not something that you dive right into.
I would suggest still watching the section tell it will help you become a better marketer and understand
how other companies get their customers.
And of course if you're itching to just make a guide on something that you think would be really really
useful for your customers and you really can get excited at that idea.
Well then I'll see in the next lecture.