Hey guys welcome back to the chorus and to the brand new section search engine marketing also known
as SVM.
Now this point you should be familiar with SEO or search engine optimization and you already probably
know about many of the strategies involving keywords.
There's a lot of overlap.
Etzion se.
Now maybe you're writing articles and posts that focus on keyword phrases or specific questions.
People might search for on Google if you're using keywords and optimizing your site and pages with code
and other attributes of covered then your efforts are probably off to a decent start.
Here's the thing with SEO as SEO is a long term game and it's a long term game even to see the first
results getting your page ranked for a decent lead traffic keyword and getting it ranked they like number
one.
That usually takes months.
Unless your keyword is just insanely specific and the reason why not just take so long is because well
it's the organic way right you're not paying any money.
I mean sure you're paying money to maybe hire someone to write content for you or to do link building
for you but you're not paying Google anything.
Now the alternative option is search engine marketing and it has benefits that are different than SCA.
No SC like you said it takes WAY long time to even show up.
But SDMI on the other hand you can actually just pay money and then show up at the top of a search result
paid search efforts help you skip the line and then go straight to the top of the search pages.
Well I'll see sometimes Now that's what SC him and the next section are all about.
Now to understand SCMP you need to understand how Google's paid search advertising platform works and
that is called add words.
Edwards allows you to place bids and then eventually pay to have your ads featured on specific search
result pages that match the keywords you're targeting.
Now your ads could be text based like the ones we see at the top of search result pages.
They can also appear as banners if you get a actual graphic done and you'll see those on web pages or
it could be some kind of hybrid where you might see it show up specifically on phones at a much smaller
format.
However just as Google tries to show the best and most relevant search results in its organic results
on its SEPs member search engine result pages.
Google also tries to match users with the best ads so no matter how much you might pay to advertise
you still need to understand the most effective ways to create your ads.
And that is something that we're going to cover in the section.
So in the end you can use what you've learned about Google Adwords and paid search and then apply many
of the same principles to things like social advertising as well.
Facebook ads in particular are pretty popular and for certain businesses and certain advertisements
can be pretty effective.
So by the end of the section you'll have a lot of ideas about how you can use paid efforts to quickly
reach the audience you need across multiple kinds of platforms and devices.
One thing worth pointing out is that ACM is in a sense like a CEO and that in order to master it it
takes a long time.
However you can start seeing results as soon as today.
Right so with CEO we have a long let's say six month plan and by the end of six months you could easily
be number one page rank with SVM you can show up tomorrow however its going to be pretty optimize and
over time you can have to go through a trial and error process to really get something that works.
Search Engine ads don't work for all businesses.
OK sometimes they are really expensive.
Sometimes your keywords are just way too saturated and too many other people are trying to advertise
for them.
So in a lot of cases its not going to seem feasible at first but again over time you may find that with
some optimization and some tweaking of your strategy you can actually find a niche that works for you.
The same thing goes for social ads and we're only going to focus on Facebook ads in this section but
it's kind of the same principles you can put something up tomorrow start getting traffic see how it
actually how the traffic responds and if they convert.
But then over time you get to slowly start iterating on it and eventually after a couple of months and
a couple rounds of iteration you'll probably have figured it out.
Anyway guys I hope you enjoy it and I'll see you in the next lecture.