Hey guys welcome back to the course and welcome to the introduction to the follow along section so I
don't know if you guys have taken any of my other courses other courses I'd generally like to do it
this way I show you a technique and then I follow along and do it for real business.
So in this course we're going to do that as well.
We're going to try as much as possible to emulate or least like imitate every technique we do or at
least almost every single one because not every single technique works for every single business.
So part of the process in this course is we're going to go through all of these techniques going to
start off with manual effort stuff and then get towards the long term bigger picture stuff later on.
And you kind of have to make a decision Should I try this for my business based on watching me do it.
See if it's relevant see if it fits your strengths and then make a decision.
And so I'm going to do the same thing as well but I try to simulate as much as I can as possible.
Now I'm going to alternate most likely between different things.
So I have 15 courses on udemy which will allow me to do a lot of these techniques because there are
a lot of different topics to them.
However there's obviously certain disadvantages to online courses they're hard to sell.
They're hard to run ads to.
They're hard to do certain techniques too.
So I'll have other things I'll have as backups.
But if you guys seem out of courses I 15 so I have pretty much all the way from like people want to
learn marketing.
People want to learn product management.
People want to learn programming MVP ideas.
I should be able to use any one of these courses to simulate what we're doing here.
Yeah.
So like I was saying we'll use these pages as pretend like businesses don't like pretend but we'll act
like this is a product.
So if I wanted to do my pre programming course then we'll follow along and I'll go on Twitter and I'll
look for certain people that have the pain points that might mean they're interested in this and what
we'll do to track to see if I'm actually making sales with the techniques and he might not all of them
are going to work is going to create a coupon.
And then what we'll do is we'll periodically check in after each time we try something and see who's
actually cashing in that specific coupon.
And that's the way that we'll be able to tell this is actually response of this technique.
It's not sort of my courses.
There's some other things we might try.
I have a blog which we'll use when we get to the content marketing section.
I have a couple of micro sites that we might use.
I have one that's like a video series that's like Christmas themed.
We'll talk about that later.
I also have a site where it's like a collaborative space for sharing business ideas.
So we might use that one.
It just depends on what the technique is and what makes the most sense for what we're trying.
Later on the course will actually switch to a different landing pages just because I have my own landing
pages for my courses on my site.
They're not 100 percent done right this second but these will give us more control and more insight
over the analytics like who sees it and who buys it.
Unfortunately Udemy we can drive traffic to it but I won't know necessarily what the conversion rate
is or how long they're on the page or if they went from one course to another and then came back.
I don't have that granularity of information.
So we're going to try to do this later on the course and we get some more advance stuff.
Okay guys I'll be excited these sections are kind of off the cuff little bit unscripted.
We'll just see how they go.
Otherwise guys I'll see you in the next lecture.