Hey guys, welcome back to the course and welcome to the first lecture in our how to get press or PR section.
Now if you're looking for the CPR section Well that's down the hall to the left.
So why exactly are we going to talk about press and PR.
Well PR is a legitimate tactic that you should consider for your business now.
Not every single business out there is perfect for getting press however you'd be surprised at how easy
it is for some of the less interesting companies out there to get coverage in some way or another.
The great thing about press is that it's essentially free.
I mean sure you spend time on working on relationships with journalists or finding different angles
or pitches or outlets but once you have that done you get exposure to thousands and thousands of people
who have never heard of you beforehand.
And the reason why I'm going to tackle this first up and our Get your 500 section is because the amount
of effort compared to the reward in PR is still very very good.
It does definitely take a couple days worth of work at least.
But the gains you can get could easily outsize.
How much time you spent and you can easily get 500 or more customers by doing this.
Even if you don't get press though I think it's worth understanding how blogs news and other media outlets
especially things online work how they think and how to better understand them for the future when you
might actually get it.
Now PR stands for public relations but it really should be called press relations because that's really
what it's all about.
Now our focus is on finding members of the press and other people out there who write about your industry
or just have large followings if you can find the right media people out there with influence or big
audiences and you can get them interested in you.
Well then it's not really that much of a stretch to say well you can usually get them to write about
you or include you in something they're writing.
Now Prescot help spread the word about what you're doing what products you have coming out and especially
by reviewing the stuff you have and then publishing articles about it.
And now the press that I'm talking about can take many different forms.
One thing you really need to keep in mind when I say press I don't just mean the New York Times.
Now obviously I do mean New York Times Wall Street Journal Huffington Post things like that.
But I also mean several other things.
Now it's not just newspapers like in the old days of PR.
It's really anyone with an audience now that could be news sites that could be blogs that could be editorials
that could even be like popular podcasts or popular shows.
For us the lowest hanging fruit are probably going to be the blogs since there's a lot of them they
have a lot of sway and they can be pretty tailored towards one specific type of customer or topic.
So how exactly does getting press for your startups or small business or for just your project work.
Well we're going to cover the fundamentals in this section and talk about how to research and identify
members of the press out there that can help you.
How didn't pitch those members of the press on your story or a similar story that might possibly fit
you into it and pretty much anything that stands a chance of getting picked up.
They weren't talking about how to create a press package that pulls together all the info the press
needs about you to increase your chance of actually being covered which is to talk a little bit about
how to maintain relationships with these contacts over time how to make sure they don't wilt and make
sure that you can use them in the future if they don't cover you now.
Now keep this in mind when it comes to PR.
Well PR is a growth channel attraction channel.
Now you usually aren't going to be doing PR efforts all the time marketing.
Yes but PR not so much.
Now when you have an announcement or an update or a launch and PR can help you generate some traffic
and conversation spikes.
But to be honest outside of that you're going to get press occasionally.
And I do have to give you this warning it doesn't make sense for everyone.
In some cases what you have is it's not inherently press worthy and you're going to have a significantly
hard time getting covered.
Now it's my opinion that everyone can get covered in some way or another.
However for some people depending on what you're selling the novelty of it.
What milestones are actually interesting facts you have about it or how it fits into a larger trend.
Well it might just be harder for you.
So much so that I personally would skip to the other parts of this horse because I think the our allies
are any better there now.
Here are some situations where I think it makes sense to actually go after press.
So if you have an awesome product and it's already being used by at least a small but vocal happy customer
base and it's not just a concept of an idea or a product that you haven't been able to get customers
for even yet in this course.
Another one is if you have specific media outlets that you want to reach like industry blogs or sites
that would really help you a lot if they wrote about you.
Three if you have a social or nonprofit type of angle to your business this is actually opens the door
quite easily for making a story.
If you have people besides yourself that you can actually dedicate to it.
Now PR can be a lot of work.
So if it actually starts working out for you it's going to be good if you can find someone to help at
least automate some of the process if you're OK with your efforts not working well.
PR is very much a coin flip chance unbiased unprejudiced
media people are not always interested they're not always available and if they write about you want
it doesn't guarantee they're gonna write about you again.
They're also notoriously kind of capricious like you don't know what they're going to do or say or how
they act.
So just keep that in mind it doesn't always work does not replace marketing it supports it.
Now if you don't have time for PR that's fine.
And I won't hurt my feelings if you skip the section.
But if you're ready to do the PR thing you think that there's at least something noteworthy about your
product or your service.
Well then let's keep watching this section and you'll learn about the steps about creating your own
press list pitches press kits and then how to nurture relationships.
All right guys I'll see you in the next lecture.