Hey guys welcome back.
So in this series of lectures we're talking about different kinds of lead magnets.
Things you basically create that could be used to attract leads in the form of like emails or sign ups.
Now the first couple we covered in the last few lectures were white papers and e-books.
Now in this lecture I'm going to go over different kind of creation that could compel people to give
you their personal information and then as an email course now an email course is an automated series
of emails containing educational training type material.
When people sign up for an email course they receive each part usually every day or two until it's complete.
Some people actually call this an auto responder course because that's basically what they're setting
up a system that auto responds to people with a bunch of periodic e-mail messages.
Once they sign up that's when it starts the process.
Well it's called a course.
A lot of times the person signing up just really just received a bunch of information a task they can
do on their own which I guess that makes it of course in some cases the person offering the course might
say e-mail me with questions or tell me what you think.
But the recipient of the e-mails usually don't submit any work to be graded or anything like that.
It's totally self-driven and optional.
For example buffer offers a 25 day email course on social media growth strategies on the landing page
where you'd sign up.
They promised each lesson we'll just take 10 minutes or less per day.
They give you a bullet list of the types of tools and best practices you'll read about and they offer
a preview of one of the lessons you'll receive to sign up.
All you need to do is enter your email and click the button.
So why does buffer offer a free email course like this.
Well the business is all about social media strategy.
The platform helps people plan and schedule social media posts.
So by creating a course like this they can help their followers improve their social media skills and
probably get more on the platform that offer than offers.
But beyond educating an audience there are plenty of benefits to creating an email course.
One you can collect email addresses obviously use an email or courses require an email address to sign
up.
This is a great way to build a list and promote and sell yourself for your stuff.
Number two is you have qualified leads the people who sign up obviously care about the topic so it's
pretty easy to assume that they will care about other things as you say related to it.
Obviously this is an opportunity and don't abuse the shit out of it.
You can also offer them other things down the line but that's entirely up to you.
But there have been a bit of an email choruses that establishes your expertise.
We've said this in our other lectures on why you might create a white paper or an e-book and it pretty
much holds true here as well.
Email of course shows people you have skills to pay the bills when it comes to the topics in your industry.
Fourth reason is that email courses give you a chance to reuse some of your best material.
Start actually if you just have a bunch of blog post articles e-books or white papers or just any training
materials that you have that performed decently well.
You're going to remix these into an email course and actually doesn't even take that much effort.
You don't have to reinvent the wheel here you can simply take a great wheel and then put a different
spin on it.
See what I did there.
And the reason of course since this is an auto responder course is that this whole thing works automatically
without you needing to really do anything.
People sign up whatever email service you are using to power the course does its thing flitters emails
the schedule while you're off working on whatever you need to work on.
As more people sign up your lead list grows and you hardly have to really do anything other than keep
promoting it.
So who does email courses.
Wow what kind of business.
That's a great fit.
Here is somebody offering things like professional training or services.
If you create an in-depth training course that you sell promote them with an email course you give people
a taste of the full course with an email course that perhaps provided introductory foundational info.
The ones that then want to go further than you have the option to sell them something.
Maybe your email course is like I don't know Lesson 1 or chapter 1 of the full course giving away for
free allows people to get a feel for it and potentially hook them in for the full ride soothing whatever
you make is decent.
Now consultants are a good match for email courses as well.
Email courses can be a logical way to repackage previous works like blog post articles and other training
materials.
Since we already said that since it makes sense for consultants to assemble their best stuff into a
collection or program they can offer it through something like an email course.
It's a way to establish their expertise as they look for new clients and each person that signs up is
a new lead.
They can then just follow up with really if you have expertise we're sharing on the topic your audience
would like something that you could organized into five day 10 day or longer type of program.
Well you could do an email course as well.
And our next lecture we're going to talk about ways that you can create that course and then I'll see
that.