Our guys here we go.
Welcome back we're on to Step Three of our process of getting coverage for you and your product.
Now in our last two lectures we talked about finding and researching news reporter bloggers writers
and other people who will eventually write glowing pieces about how awesome you and your product are.
But before we get to that ultimate granddaddy conclusion we've got a little more work to do.
Now step three here is about getting the attention of journalists now that's the subject of this lecture
and it is quite tricky.
Now if you want to pitch yourself to someone it greatly helps that they know who you are.
Look at Justin Timberlake in Japan.
You don't have to be their best friend but a general awareness of your name is typically going to help
you out quite a bit according to a survey of editors at many big media outlets.
Sixty four percent said a personal connection with the person who pitched them was moderately or more
important.
So sure it's possible that you can approach people cold where they know nothing about you and hope that
your pitch is good enough.
And honestly if you don't have time to get to know these journalists maybe that's the way that you need
to approach this and instead focus on more people as opposed to fine tuning and kind of warming up to
a smaller batch.
That's perfectly fine.
That data said you know 64 percent moderately or more important it's not 100 percent required.
All I'm saying is if you have the time to get on the radar before you actually need them to hear your
pitch and write it about you well it's going to really help you out.
So consider this as an optional step if you want but I strongly recommend it.
So how does this work.
Well once you know which reporters might help you out connect with them on social media and other platforms
are highly recommended in the last two steps that when you find some good leads for reporters and bloggers
and such that you immediately connect with their social media accounts.
Well this is why if you aren't following them already go do that now.
Once you're connected with these leads engage directly with them comment on their posts ask them questions
provide answers when and if they ask questions.
Some reporters turn on their followers on Twitter or Corra when they're looking for source material
for their articles and they'll just ask questions.
Look for these opportunities to chime in and get on the radar in general.
Just try to be helpful if they're talking about something and you think they're wrong.
It's information to show they're wrong.
Try to share that or try to bolster the opinion what they said or some article that they posted other
opportunities that might come up could be the things like webinars or Twitter chats.
Take a look through your list Twitter feeds and see if they actually participate on Twitter chats.
Now these are regular events where group chats for an hour or so using a hash tag and shares info and
answers many questions.
Maybe your reporter takes part in a small biz chat on Wednesday nights or Linked-In chat on Tuesday.
Now remember this is a tactic that can take time but try not to think of it as purely just a way to
get coverage.
Participate in these events.
You might actually learn something.
Network with people and get some tips from fellow app developers or startup peeps on how you get coverage
in your industry.
So connect on social media Gaige with them directly and look for them on chat.
But during this process don't just limit yourself to your spreadsheet and the lists you came up with.
That list should evolve as you learn more about your reporters and other leads.
So if you can act and engage with people on your list you'll put yourself in a much better position.
The time comes actually approach from directly with a pitch when they recognize your name or even better
if they know you personally.
Chances are they're more likely to take into consideration.
All right keep those tips in mind that we move forward which we're going to do right now.
We also have a couple other lectures where I dive more into specific tactics for getting their attention
and engaging with them.
They're just the ones I want to spend a little bit more time on.
Thus they have their own lecture.
All right guys I'll see you in the next lecture.