Hey guys welcome back.
So we talked about e-mail courses directly in our last lecture but they are there benefits and who might
use them to generate leads.
So now let's actually discuss how you create them.
The first question to ask here is what exactly should you teach.
You generally want to pick a topic you are great at something you understand front to back.
That would be relevant to your audience and something they'd like to understand better.
Also needs to translate well to the email format.
So that your topic required the use of say a lot of visuals and you might want to consider something
else.
Now information you can communicate over e-mails is basically text interspersed with images occasionally
and then external links.
That's the ideal for e-mail.
So for example let's say you were Treloar and you offer a platform to allow people to organize projects
ideas and virtual boards and list.
Basically you're all about project management productivity.
You offered an e-mail course on project management or productivity generally makes sense or you could
focus on a related topic Dollar Shave Club it's a company that offers subscription raisers like they
mail it to you for instance do an e-mail course on all the round man escaping shaving hair care skin
care all that stuff.
These are generally topics their audience would probably appreciate.
So what would you specifically create.
Well what's your business or product all about what purpose does it serve for your audience.
Once you have a topic in mind you'll need to think about the design and the scope of the course.
I've seen a lot of recommendations to make an e-mail or somewhere between five to seven lessons or basically
something that would take a week to complete.
Now it makes sense and it makes for a good selling point as well for people who are too busy to learn
something quickly and they can only do small amounts at a time.
We've also seen longer courses work as well as in 15 day courses 25 day courses.
I've even seen like perpetual never ending courses that are year long.
Really it just depends on how qualified you want the leads to be right.
Because you gonna be able to monitor who makes it through the entire course.
The longer ones fewer people will get through but the ones that do are going to be way more likely to
be a purchaser of your stuff and you're trying this for the first time I'd say trying a short one tried
doing like a five day course and then you see roughly how your audience likes it.
So think about your topic.
Let's say you're an app designer or maybe a usability expert of some kind.
You might choose a topic like how to perform let's say usability testing for your app.
The level of detail you go into is really up to you.
But let's say you wanted to do that quick five day email cause your task at this point should be to
start outlining how can you carve up this topic into five pieces that make sense where each one logically
follows the other.
Maybe you should do it like this.
Day one why you should do usability testing for your app then in this case you talk about the benefits
and what you could plan on learning from it then you could talk about in day to preparing to test what
you need to do in advance to guarantee a good test and helpful results.
Then rolling on day three let's say you do running a test.
How to do it.
What to look for things to try and so on then day four.
You could say interpreting the results.
What did you actually learn.
And then finally number five would be something like improving your app how to take the test results
and make the right changes and then outline right there while that could be a type of promotional copy.
You serve up on your landing page but for preparing your email course an outline lets you figure out
how deep each part needs to be which impacts the length of each email.
When it comes to email link there are two schools of thought here.
Option one is to keep each email short like 300 words short.
Now what's great about that length is that it really doesn't take that much time to read or write and
it can really help you keep your momentum going.
Just think so it finishes your e-mail and the next one arise.
Well they'll be ready to read that one as well.
Now if your e-mails are too long they might stack up in their inbox without being read.
But he really likes that the option to for email is to actually purposely make the e-mails longer like
a thousand words or more.
The advantage here is that you can fit more detail more information making the emails more substantial
perhaps more valuable.
That means more people will like it more people will share it.
So our e-mails are like the individual bits of knowledge but the long ones are more like deep reference
material you keep for a long time.
You refer to it later and you might actually learn something from it.
Now the length of your emails really just depends on your topic.
For example here's a course on writing from Heidrick due to my I'm not going to guess his name.
Anyway she's a writer from the United Kingdom and she's got a 16 part course she describes as snack
Apple where each email lesson is ultra short with easy to implement tips and each lesson is only a couple
hundred words.
Well it focuses on one tip or lesson and that's really all it's simple and focus so the short format
probably works here but instead for our e-mail course on app usability testing.
I could probably see the emails being quite a bit longer especially if you wanted to squeeze them into
say like a five day course.
Then again if we expanded it to a 20 day course like four weeks Monday through Friday maybe then we
could do more of that snack bowl format and keep the messages short obviously a balance you have to
figure out now regardless of length.
Each email should feel substantial enough and deliver enough value within the course.
Consider how much you ask the reader to do in each email as well to give them many steps to follow or
try on their own.
Is it reasonable that they complete them by the time the next email arrives.
Make sure you plan out these steps and tasks in your overall outline and then divide them up evenly
throughout your emails.
Once you have a solid outline and an idea how long each email lesson should be write it up similarly
each message in whatever writing app you want really doesn't matter word Google Docs.
You just be taking the text and then copying it into emails you create later.
Speaking of which once your material is written ready to go well then you can actually create the email
course and that happens on any type of email service provider of course.
The one reference before was a Weber and they have a 19 dollar a month account that you could use with
a 30 day trial.
An alternative would be a place called drip which has a free account that allows you to do this up to
100 subscribers.
But if you go over that then you have to pay.
Now here's what an email course in drip would look like while you set up an automation campaign that
looks something like this.
People who submit a specific sign up form get added to a list.
They get a confirmation email.
Then the first lesson and a new lesson each day after the first one with drip you can virtually set
up the whole automation campaign like this one editing each email to include the material and then telling
drip to wait a day to deliver the next one at a specific time or even skipping days or weekends if you
want to make first confirmation email should be something simple that quickly sets the stage for what's
to come next.
You're doing a swift app development course.
Maybe you'd write something like this.
Thanks so much for signing up for my course mobile app development using swift this course will last
10 days and I'll send you a new lesson each day by the end you'll have everything you need to build
your first app using swift and get it into the App Store.
Some quick notes before you begin the chorus please download this and this from this link.
These are examples that you'll need to follow along with another thing each lesson should take you 10
to 15 minutes to complete.
If you fall behind don't worry if you have questions let me know.
Drop me a line it help at this course dot com if you know any questions and I'll get back to you ASAP.
The point is use your confirmation to make sure people are prepped and ready to go.
The first lesson when it arrives don't make them pause during the middle to download something or perform
some action you should have prepared them for.
Now take advantage of the fact that when they sign up they're the most motivated.
So get them to put their foot in the water first.
After you send your confirmation email follow up the first lesson.
Make sure that person immediately gets something so they can begin the experience of the course.
Set up your campaign and your email tool to deliver the next lessons as promised and then at the end
sent a thank you message.
Share links to resources if necessary promote more courses sell more staff.
Ask them to please write a review or recommend the course to a friend.
Whatever you're able to get from them make that request here while you still have their attention.
When it comes to how often email should arrive.
Well you could send them.
Let's say one day or one every two days.
It's certainly a selling point to say you can learn responsive email design in one week and then in
that case you deliver 7 emails in 7 days.
Technically that's a mission accomplished but you could also do one email a week though if you only
go that route and make sure your emails are all more substantial.
Or my favorite email courses is called Hack design and it's like an email.
I believe once a week for forever and every single emails written by a different designer whatever you
do set up those expectations on your landing page and be clear about how often the emails are gonna
come.
So that's your email course from a high level point of view.
As for each individual lesson you want your emails to be as simple as possible.
I recommend making your messages text only use a simple email design and only basic formatting like
headers bullet list and bold and italics text in general.
Try to avoid using too many images because 1 it makes it harder for your email to get delivered more
often will go to spam and also people read this on their phone so it's often hard to format that correctly.
So prepare for the very simple and easy to read design.
Now a subject line for your email should be consistent and as short as possible of course is how to
generate leads through Facebook for instance helps you establish a short version of the title in your
confirmation email after person signs up.
That way when they see the subject line they know exactly what it is.
They don't skip it over like you might wanna send a confirmation email with the subject line course
registration for how to generate leads through Facebook and then your lesson email subject lines could
look like this in brackets you could put the abbreviation for that course.
Lesson 1 identifying your audience then the same thing.
Listen to the wrath of the content and so on.
Once you've got your course written and created in your email provider it's time to promote it.
Share a link to the landing page where people can sign up for it on social media.
Your other emails or you know take out some Facebook Google or other ads recover later in the course
by driving people to this course.
You can generate subscribers and more interest in everything else you have to offer.
Look for feedback from your course takers and look for ways to improve it.
Or change up the format or linked the email provider you go with should also give you metrics to look
at regarding the course such as how many people stuck with the entire course over time and that is it.
Best of luck with creating your course and I'll see you in the next lecture.