All right guys, here we are, welcome back.
So we spent a good amount of time in the last lecture
getting comfy with Snapchat, thinking up ideas
for content to snap and share,
and we started into a couple of tactics to
help promote things, like a branded geofilter,
remember, it's only like $5 for 20,000 square feet,
or cross-promoting on other social channels as well.
Well, in this lecture, I want to explain one particular
tactic that a bunch of brands have used as a way
to expand their own following,
essentially piggybacking on the goodwill of another
account, and this is what's called a takeover. In general
social media terms, a takeover is when someone takes
over a social media account, be it a Twitter, Facebook,
or, yes, a Snapchat account.
It generally lasts for like a few hours, sometimes a whole day.
The idea here is that the person shows
you a different side of your brand,
it's from their perspective.
It's often much less marketing and prepared content
and more spontaneous, fun, and unpredictable. So that
special someone could be, let's say, an employee, like
Jimmy from the mail room, or, I don't know, the CEO.
And if you wanted to show off your business from
a different point of view, it's not a bad idea.
But our goal right now is to build a
following and grow your customer base.
With that in mind, it would make more sense to choose
someone with a bigger following and some influence in
the hopes that it will benefit your Snapchat
following and your brand as a whole.
Now, here is roughly how this works. When Brand A,
that's you, asks brand B, somebody with a big old
following that's directly related to what you do or
your audience, when you ask them to take over their
account, brand A is obviously hoping that brand B's
followers, well, first, you know, obviously care about what you're
posting, and then perhaps they'll click through and follow
your account. And then obviously, somewhere down
the line, that person who then follows your Snapchat
account stays in touch with your company and eventually
buys from you. Brand A wants to use Brand B's
influence to raise its own profile. Depending
on who you ask to take over your profile,
it might also make you look cooler or more legitimate.
It can certainly show off your brand in a new light,
since it'll be happening from a different perspective
that is not your own for a change.
So who is this magic person that can bring all these
new followers and attention to your Snapchat account?
Now, obviously, it could be a celebrity, you know.
Sure, if you actually know a celebrity,
then you could try to do this.
But the odds of that happening are basically none.
But maybe it could be a more local
influencer or a local personality.
Obviously, the higher the profile, the better it is if you're
trying to establish brand recognition and reputation.
But at the very beginning it's going to be harder
to reach these upper groups of people.
Now, what I generally suggest is you go for influencers,
and this is really just someone with a big-ish
following on Snapchat or at least other channels.
Handing the reins over to them means they'll promote
the takeover to their followers, potentially exposing
you obviously to tons of their new eyeballs.
So who is shaping the conversation in your market or at least
in a related market and has some headway in Snapchat?
Well, ideally, if you know of someone that uses your
product, well, that's generally a great place to start.
Someone with an interest in your product or your
kind of product also works. Whoever you pick,
there should be a logical connection
between your brand and theirs.
If you've created an app to find
the nearest dog park in your town,
well, then an influencer who has a dog
will obviously make a lot of sense.
If you created an app to improve productivity on the go,
then someone that's constantly traveling would also
be a good pick.
But also just try to make sure
that you get a personality match.
If you pick someone who's wild and wacky and cusses
all the time, then it might not make sense for
your brand if you're not also the same. Part of your
research before you do this should be to follow them
and check out their content, see what kind of impression
they might actually make with their audience.
Once you have someone in mind, approach them and
start a conversation. Let them know what you have in
mind and see if they'd be open to a takeover idea. If they've
done one before, that could help set expectations.
Make sure you have a clear idea of what you would
expect from them, what kind of freedom or access you're
willing to give them, and what you
hope to accomplish from all of this.
And you might tell them, "Hey, come
to our office and go wherever you want,
talk to anybody, but at some point come
down to where we're making the product.
We have a cool idea for showing
the process" - something like that.
Or it could also be like, "Hey, we'll be rolling out our
new product at this event, and during these three
hours we want you to, you know, take over
the account and do snaps and videos about,
I don't know, anything you want." Whatever it is,
be sure to set any limits you feel are necessary.
"Please don't talk about any competitors," for example,
or "Don't mention this product we haven't released yet."
But before you get all bossy and tell them what you want,
understand that this is generally thought of as a collaboration.
You ask them for a reason.
They've got a following.
So pick their brain and ask for their input.
They know what their audience wants.
"What would you want to do?"
"What would you think would be fun or a great surprise
or a giveaway that we could do?" The more involved
they feel, the more they'll probably be willing
to do this to make sure that it's a success.
Now, if you come to an agreement and this
takeover thing actually is going to happen,
make sure you prepare some important things
before it goes down. First of all, establish a point of
contact with them, so if they have any questions before,
during, and after, they know that they can get a response
pretty quickly.
You don't want them to go haywire not knowing what
they're supposed to be doing for this time period.
Next thing is figure out how to get
in touch with them during it
if you're obviously not physically with them.
So if something weird happens, you can actually
contact them and hopefully correct the mistake.
What you want to do is create a temporary password
so they can access your account, and then after the
takeover is done, change that password.
Now, if your takeover person happens to share your password
with anyone in the process, who knows who that might be,
well, it's only going to last for a certain period of time.
The most important thing to do before a takeover is
to promote this thing. Get on Snapchat and your other
channels and spread the word at least a week in advance.
And then, again, maybe like a few days before, the day
before, and the day of. Let people know exactly when
it's happening. Maybe create a teaser telling people a
takeover is happening and tomorrow you'll reveal who it is.
Then, with the reveal, you share the date
and time, and obviously start counting down.
Also let your influencer know in advance you'll help
them come up with promotional information if they
need it for their channels.
That's a polite way of saying "We expect you to promote
this too and I'll write the stuff myself if I have to."
You want to see them promoting this as well.
Hopefully they do it a week in advance
like you did, and if it doesn't happen,
well, you can politely check in and ask them to do it.
Once the takeover actually begins,
don't obviously freak out.
It should be a lot of fun or at least an interesting experience.
Watch their snaps and videos and look for reactions.
Ask your influencer to make note of anything interesting
that comes their way, like comments or other interactions.
If possible, ask them to take
a screenshot of them for you.
This can be really helpful data to understand how
people reacted to the takeover. If possible, shadow
them and answer any questions, provide any info,
do whatever you need to make
the takeover a success. After that,
just talk to them, check out the reactions
online and talk to your own people.
How do they think it went? What worked? What didn't?
Do you actually see an increase in followers?
Did those followers end up bouncing and seeing
your own web page or whatever your goal was?
Then take what you've learned and try to
plan some more takeovers in the future.
In general,
first time you do this, it's probably not going to be very
successful, but second or third time, you will know
what you're doing.
Equally likely, you figure out that, hey, this
is a lot of work and it's not worth doing.
That's fine.
The whole point with growth channels is you just try them out
and try different tactics, and some of them will work, some won't.
If working with an external influencer doesn't work, you can
also, if you have employees, try working with them instead.
Don't be afraid to try to change things up, but at the same time,
honestly, learn from the mistakes you make and then adjust.
If you do actually try to tackle this, well, then just try
to enjoy the experience. Collaborating with someone
who's found success on Snapchat is a great
opportunity for you to pick up some tips,
and if all goes well, it could lead to wins
for both you and your takeover star.
That pretty much sums it up.
See you guys in the next lecture.