Hey guys welcome back and let's finish up this section on search engine marketing and social ads.
So in our lectures and the section we step through the process for getting set up and onwards and running
ads through Google and then we went through the same process and Facebook for ads on their network.
Well you've got the steps now for advertising on two major networks arguably the biggest ones in the
world currently.
And we know different ways to find and influence your audience whether you choose to focus on keywords
through say like add words and focus on people who have demonstrated intent or appealing to an audience
with ads in a variety of different formats on Facebook.
You should have plenty of opportunity to get yourself in front of customers to accomplish your goals.
Now the biggest difference between SVM efforts and what you would do for say like a CEO is that the
image just cost money.
Ultimately you have to figure out if paid options like ad words and Facebook ads or just in general
worth it.
Smaller businesses might assume paid efforts aren't worth it because they might not have a lot of money
to work with but paid advertising is a channel that can give an immediate boost to traffic and other
helpful metrics far more quickly than you could.
As you know I by suggestion is that if you're someone who's just selling something then running an easy
because while you recoup that money pretty quickly.
But if you're someone who is not or just takes longer for people to pay you then it might be a problem
to paying what your budget is.
Obviously keep in mind this just takes a lot of time to figure out you're not immediately going to make
the numbers work.
So I'm going to leave you with this advise some of which has probably been said in a section of a course
already longtail key words in general can be a huge bargain by researching keywords that have lower
competition and you can potentially find phrases and questions that really define who your audience
is and what they're looking for.
Don't try to write for keywords.
Lots of huge companies fighting or other his advice always be testing both Edwards and Facebook ads
offer opportunities to set up testing to see which ads perform better with your goals and might remember
to test one change only at a time.
This way you'll know what one thing actually made a difference.
Change too many things.
I don't know.
You don't really know where to start.
But you also generally understand my theory about running ads which is a least on Google.
I want you to start off with two things are entirely different to angles.
See which one works better and then kind of narrow down now and changing one thing at a time.
On Facebook the first thing I generally want to do is look for the right audience and then start work
on the right message.
Then in a related story every campaign is different but don't ignore what you've learned.
Different campaigns might mean different goals different audiences different keywords you name it but
that doesn't mean you have to start from scratch.
Pay attention and make note of what worked for past successes and failures as well so that you can set
a starting point for new campaigns that's educated and closer to where you need to be.
And one more thing.
Watch your competition.
Odds are you've got someone else out there fighting you for the exact same territory.
Do yourself a favor and search for their products and Google or check out their page on Facebook.
First you'll get to look at how they're marketing themselves and creating content to appeal to your
audience.
You might also get shown some of their ads in the process.
I personally also like to use like SVM rush because it'll show you all of the ads that are working for
your competitors are always the ones that they're targeting.
You can look at that and see if that's a strategy you think also could work.
Also make note of what language they use what images they use the deals they're trying to call to action.
Use that to your advantage and create ads that will beat theirs.
But honestly don't reinvent the wheel if they've spent two years working on something they figured out
so it works.
Borrow from them test out your designs and after a while.
Do the same research again.
You can bet that they'll probably be watching your next move as well.
All right.
Best of luck with your SCA efforts.
I'll see you guys next time.