Hey guys welcome back to the course.
Now we're cruising through the U.S. recourse here and in our last lecture we talked about some design
and technical aspects of a website that can affect SBO.
I wanted to give you a couple more ideas to consider in this lecture specifically about how your site
structure and links can affect ASIO's as well now as we mentioned in our lectures about writing content
adding links within our pages can improve SEO links direct users and help Google discover the relationships
between our pages and then pass on SEO value to pages beyond our site.
When you add a link to your page try to use those important keywords in links if possible.
I obviously overstuff links with all your keywords but try to keep it simple.
For example if you're going to link to a post you did about ways to improve Web site security then the
link itself should either match the title of the page you're going to or include the important keywords
about it.
Now you might write something like this.
My recent post about how to improve Web site security I mentioned.
So the how to improve Web site security part is the link.
The relevant keywords would be web site security or improve Web site security or even the entire phrase
making a link helps Google understand the page relinking to is about what we wrote about in the link
or at least that it's you know a reason expectation.
Now on the other hand try to avoid creating links that have meaningless text in them like click here
or like this.
There are plenty of people who write up text like this.
If you're looking for a great tutorial on frying a turkey track this out.
Now obviously search for frying a turkey but I think that makes the point.
Now check this out does nothing describe what the page is about.
You're actually forced to read the text beforehand.
Basically what that does is it Google looks at it and thinks that you might actually be tricking your
customer or your users into clicking on something they might not want to.
In this case you get the wrong way.
You're not really helping Google understand why the link is important or helping it to understand how
it links to your important keywords.
Link text should be considered the same way you think of text on say like a sign or a door.
You're having a garage sale you want to buy a sign that's a garage sale not a sign that says over here
one of those signs as actual meaning.
The other doesn't newsier link TX wisely to make sure the value gets passed accurately to the pager
linking to.
Now a quick aside here there might be times when you don't want to pass on SU value to a link that appears
on your pages.
For example the support comments or other user generated content or anyone can visit your page and post
something like a link.
Well you don't actually need to protect yourself.
Spammers seek out pages like this and they can post links to their sites and then try to generate some
black hat SEO magic.
The best way to counteract this nonsense is actually just to add what are called no follow attributes
inside any user generated links.
Now that code basically looks like this.
Inside the h r f part of the link.
All you have to do is just add RDL equal equals no follow but I did get a new follow attribute to any
link.
The user as well.
It keeps spammers from getting any value and it keeps your site clean and the eyes of Google knows is
why for instance if you make a comment on youtube and link back to your site that doesn't count because
every time you do that YouTube automatically will put a no follow on.
Fact in most situations where you can submit something like user generated show up you're not going
to get a link back.
OK well proper link structure is good practice.
You should also consider how links to your site look specifically the URLs to your pages.
Google has a few recommendations for you or you or else or refer to the architecture of your site.
First of all Google Crawl's pages on Web sites.
It doesn't always crawl all of the pages.
Depends how big the site is and how complex the directory structure is worse than say a thousand pages
on your site.
You probably don't have to worry about pages not getting crawled.
But if you've a bigger site or anticipate getting into the thousands of pages and beyond proper structure
will help ensure your site gets indexed.
I help to start by planning out a logical site structure something that's clear.
If you were to look at either a map of your pages or the you are Elle's of each one a general rule of
thumb is that if you can look at a you RL and understand it that's generally good.
Something like web site dot com slash news site slash object equals queue equals 3 4 3 6 7 1 is a complete
mystery but you can look at say what's I dot com slash recipes slash sesame chicken and understand what
you're getting now RUBINGH or content the categories can also help SBO.
But you have to keep it to a lower number like 2 to 6 main categories of conta.
Ideally your website navigation should mirror this grouping.
Let's see a five main categories of blog post or content or whatever for an app web site.
Maybe you'd have about features updates download and help.
OK then it makes sense if your main menu showed those main categories as the links at the top of each
page.
That's just logical structure.
Google looks for that.
It also helps keep your web site shallow or in other words you can't go more than three or four levels
deep from the home page.
So if your Web site you are all started to look like this well it could be bad for you like web site
dot com your site specials slash filtered by date slash optional slash you kind of get the point.
Now that's not a logical structure and not one that Google or any user would really like.
But the one thing Google definitely does like is getting some help understanding how your site is structured
and axen else sitemap is one way to help.
Now SML site map is basically a list of all of you are all on your Web site written in the code called
SML which is easy for browsers to read.
You also tell Google which pages are priorities on your site.
How recently they've been updated and their useful info for browsers.
You create this file and make it available to Google so you can easily and more quickly index your site
for sites just starting out.
This really actually could help boost your rankings more quickly.
So how exactly can you create one of these magical Exham site maps and submit it to Google.
Well it's really easy actually and just use a free tool.
Here's one is called SML Eldar site Knops dot com.
And then as a test.
Well I created an X Mail site not for this store that sells thin wallets.
I submitted you will all the directions that it took a couple minutes but that generated a site with
160 pages and it did what I can do is jump into google search con. And there is a section for your Web
site called Krol OK and there's a spot for site maps where you can test the sitemap you created and
then upload it.
By doing this you can speed up the process by which Google Crawl's your site and maybe actually up your
rankings.
So those are some ideas to consider for links and site structure both can benefit Osseo so remember
to create an easy to follow site structure and create a site map to help out the googlebot.
All right guys that's it for now I'll see you in the next lecture.