All right guys, welcome back to the course.
Now, we've spent our last lecture talking
about how to do a Snapchat takeover.
That's just a tactic that a bunch of brands
have used to try and raise the profile of
their Snapchat account and their brand, relatively
easy to pull off, you just have to find someone
in your space that has a lot of followers on there
and usually it's better if you just go for low profile,
medium profile influencers that are directly
relevant and most likely willing to do this.
Now, there's another way you can attract new users
and get attention, and that is, well, giving away stuff.
So, in this lecture, we're going to discuss
how you can run a Snapchat promotion.
So first off, promotions come in a bunch of different flavors.
It's important to know the differences.
Now, you could give away a prize to a random user,
this is what we call a giveaway.
You can also give away a prize to a user you choose
based on some criteria or skill, like best comment,
funniest video or a selfie, whatever it is,
and this is called a contest.
You could also just post a code or a coupon
directly on your account and have anyone use it,
and technically, well, this is just known
as marketing or sales promotions.
It's not really the same thing.
And while it's not technically in this
family of tactics, we'll circle back to it later.
So for now let's talk about running
a contest or running a giveaway.
So why run a contest or a giveaway?
Well, because you can generate some
excitement by giving something away.
People generally like free stuff.
Sometimes it takes some old school bribing to
get people to pay attention or take some action.
The hope is that once they do that thing, like, connect,
or buy your stuff, well, then they'll discover, "Oh
wow, this is actually pretty cool, maybe I'll tell people about it,
or recommend it, or write a nice review, or whatever."
So let's jump into an example.
Let's say you've built a platform that helps companies
specifically, let's say, support people track product
suggestions coming from different channels, like your health
platform, and your Slack, and your email, and so on.
Product managers would love this. Your tool, let's say,
helped organize and prioritize all the ideas that come in.
Now, in order to drum up some
interest and followers on Snapchat,
well, let's say you decided to do a giveaway. Five random
followers will each get a free six month basic account,
whatever that is,
and that is worth sharing.
Now, let's say this is the requirement.
All people have to do is just follow you on Snapchat
and at noon tomorrow you'll pick five people and
give them codes for, you know, the six months of access.
Easy as that.
If you wanted to,
you can also ask that they send a snap of
winning it in order for them to redeem it.
So this promotion is what's known as a giveaway.
You don't require any purchase,
no extra steps beyond simply following
you on Snapchat. As a promotion,
it's very straightforward, easy to understand, and
probably would get you more followers in a contest,
which requires people to take
additional steps to try to win,
and we'll mention that in a sec. Now, the problem though
could be that you might get a lot of people who aren't really
qualified, that is, don't really know anything about
your brand or, you know, if your product would be a
good fit for them. Now, you'd hate to go through all of
this effort just to give six months of service to some
random person that doesn't need it or use it.
The other problem is if you're picking a winner from
your new followers, it's possible some of them didn't
actually follow you because of the contest.
So they might not even want the prize.
In some cases, of course, they
would, but in others, who knows.
It is possible, is all I'm saying.
Now, if you wanted to do the same kind of thing, get
new followers and give some of them a prize, but you
wanted to qualify them first,
you could do a contest.
A contest is where you require people to enter the promotion
by taking an action, ideally something straightforward,
but requiring some kind of skill or thinking on their part.
It could be a free T-shirt to the funniest comment
on the thread, or maybe it's a discount code to the
person who answers a trivia question first.
Maybe you do a themed contest during a holiday,
like a picture of a Halloween costume that
cleverly includes the product in it somehow.
In our earlier example of the company helping
you track user suggestions across platforms,
maybe their contest would require people to follow
them on Snapchat and then create a snap where they
do a quick video explaining their biggest pain point or
why they need a solution like this one in the first place.
And then you pick the five best suited ones according
to your own criteria and give them the prize.
Either way, whether you do a giveaway or a contest, you
must adhere to Snapchat's official rules on promotion.
You can and should review them for yourself,
but the long and the short of it is this.
Make it easy for people to take part in it.
Include instructions that are super easy to understand,
and state in your rules and in any promotion that you
do that Snapchat has nothing to do with the contest, and
that means don't use obviously any Snapchat logos or
names or anything like that, and don't encourage
users to do bad stuff as part of your contest.
Obviously, bad stuff being anything
that's generally illegal or just in bad taste.
Those rules are really simple and really clear.
Number one, people might just not enter.
Maybe they just don't get it,
don't have time to figure it out, and they just pass on it.
Number two, people might get angry.
You know, why didn't I win?
I did what you asked, didn't I?
My thing is great.
Well, complainers might make you look bad as well,
so keep that in mind.
And then number three, it's an outside chance, but
maybe you could get sued. In general, just try to avoid
this drama at all cost and just make sure that
your instructions are super clear and idiot proof.
A lot of times, contests will actually
type out the steps 1, 2, 3 in a picture,
so it's as obvious as possible. "For a
chance to win a FREE Pokemon T-shirt,
follow us at @PokeShirts on Snapchat
by noon Eastern on Wednesday, April 15.
We'll pick five new followers at random and, you know, contact
the winners for shirt size and delivery address." Whatever.
Very clear.
More detail, the better.
Now, in addition to clear instructions,
you also need official rules.
Now, rules are not the same as instructions.
Official rules include all the legal stuff to define the
terms of your promotion, especially to protect yourself
in case someone raises an argument of some kind.
Now, how can you create official rules? Generally
you just have to do some basic research.
Some people go as far as to hire a lawyer.
* Better call Saul. *
I'll give you a bit of a shortcut. If you want to see what
rules and what rules templates generally look like,
check out Short Stack, because it created one you
actually might be able to edit and just use it yourself.
But again, my advice is just to be careful.
So once you're ready to roll out your contest
or giveaway, you'll need to promote it.
People need to know about it, so let them know what it's
for or when it's happening, deadlines and all the basics.
But - and this is important -
if you're giving away something that
involves a different brand or a company,
you cannot mention their name, unless of
course they've given you official permission.
For example, if you're giving away a new Samsung Galaxy 6000 or whatever, you can't promote this as a Samsung Galaxy
giveaway, technically. You can list it as a prize,
that part is perfectly fine, but you can't make it look
like Samsung or some other company is actually
endorsing it or putting on the contest. So make sure
you have a plan to spread the news of this promotion
to your other channels and then on Snapchat make
sure in the days leading up to it you do plenty of
promotion and reminders.
Want a tip?
Well, here's something that actually works
decently well with Snapchat giveaways.
You actually run a Facebook ad.
Snapchat doesn't have ads yet,
or maybe they do when you're listening to this,
but you can run a Facebook ad, and since it's a
giveaway, it generally will get a lot of attention, and
if you make it relevant enough, well, that's some really
cheap sign-ups. Now, when your deadline has passed
and it's up for you to pick your winners, do that quickly
and announce the winners, so you can maintain
the momentum that you've built up. After your promotion,
see how many followers you did get or how much website
traffic or sales you got from a rebound from that account.
Now, did this make any impact at all?
You might find that the occasional promotion like
this can even out the growth of your followers on
Snapchat and you can apply some of what you've learned
to running promotions on other channels as well. We'll actually
talk about this with Instagram.
So one last thing.
Remember how I mentioned earlier you could give away
a code or a discount and how that's basically marketing
or sales promotion?
Well, if you're freaked out by the complexity or the
legality of running a contest, you can actually just
try this one instead.
It's a lot more straightforward.
Snap a code or coupon that your followers
can use to get a discount or a free item.
Now, here's what you could do.
You can announce on various channels at the beginning
of the week you'll be sharing a code or coupon on
Snapchat on Wednesday, or
Wednesday at noon, or at noon today.
Let people know when to look,
then snap and share the code.
Since your snap will be gone after a certain amount
of time, it's basically a limited time offer.
Make the code unique to Snapchat so you can track the
result and make it simple so they can remember it.
Not too simple though.
Don't make it obvious like SNAPCHAT, because
obviously people will just guess that. Anyway,
see how many people use the discount code.
It's pretty easy to track when you do it that way.
If you get good results,
maybe that's the kind of promotion you could run
periodically to get people over to Snapchat.
It's straightforward and it could work for you, especially
if you're selling a digital product with high margins.
Let's be real.
So there you go.
There's a few ways to run promotions
on your Snapchat channel.
Good luck.
Hopefully you figure it out.
See you guys in the next lecture.