Hey guys welcome back to the course.
OK so you know how important is to come up with great ideas for your content strategy.
Yes.
If you make stuff that just isn't anything special Well then this whole content thing might not really
work out for you probably should focus on one of the other growth channels.
There's a common rebuttal I hear when I tell people hey just make something new and it's usually well
I'm not that creative so I can't come up with something new.
And that statement I'm not creative therefore I can't.
Let me just clear the air here once and for all is completely ridiculous.
There's really no magic sauce to this.
If you're looking for some quick and dirty ways the generic content ideas look no further than Google
autocomplete.
What's that you ask.
It's a secret section inside Google Analytics.
No I'm actually kidding.
Is that thing where when you start typing in your search term and Google tries to autocomplete And guess
what you're trying to say try and give you suggestions.
That's it.
That's literally all it is.
And it's a fantastic way to come up with content ideas.
Here's how you do it.
Your customer will type a search into Google at some point and in the hopes of finding a company or
product like yours presumably remember people who aren't your customers you probably won't know your
name so they'll search using the most logical terms they can think of.
And this is where you can basically take advantage of it by creating content that corresponds to the
searches that they do.
Now first consider this question What do you make or do boil it down to a search term.
Don't dogs use your product name focus on a straightforward term without any branding on it you make
or provide a blank.
OK maybe it's photo editing apps means video production services maybe you give massage therapy whatever.
Just type it in as you do you'll start to see that auto completes forms this magic list before your
eyes.
But yes come on I know I know you've seen this a million times.
Now where exactly is the magic here.
Well Magic is a bit of a high bar to jump over but it will say goes after your term.
The word for F O R by doing this in Google Google thinks you're searching for that term for someone
or something.
The search will become a little more specific now and it can show you autocomplete for a specific audience
or problem.
Don't think about it.
You don't provide your product or service for everyone or every situation and if you do you probably
need to specialize.
You probably focus on a certain audience or a certain purpose.
The former shows us what needs or audiences are most popular on Google you'll see autocomplete like
this photo editing app for musicians video production services for sports teams massage therapy for
neck pain.
Try a bunch of these and see what auto completes appear that are relevant to your business.
Now write them down somewhere and then let's move on because four is just one way to actually refine
your search and use autocomplete to help you.
All right so let's say you have an agency and you build apps himself and the clients just a service
business.
Well here's some Googles you could might actually want to try.
Let's try apps built with and then let's see what autocomplete gives us.
It'll probably tell us that people are looking for specific languages or frameworks you might see something
like apps built with Ruby who is Ruby if you don't know who Ruby is.
Don't worry it doesn't matter.
But that difference of adding the 4 is actually pretty important.
You can try photo apps that th 80 messaging apps that audio apps that whatever kind of app you make.
Add that at the end to see what type of specific need the users are looking for.
These are going to refer to features or requirements Taipan that don't and you'll see common problems
or issues that customers want to avoid or fix their apps.
And if you're getting a little stuck try this Protip.
If you put your cursor and type an extra space in the middle of a term Google will try to actually auto
complete the search right there in the middle of the sentence and not at the end.
It's pure magic.
So let's say you find a bunch of interesting relevant autocomplete.
How can you use them to actually write content.
Customer search for things for specific reasons.
Take massage therapy for neck pain.
Well it means people are looking for a solution either in the form of a service you offer advice you
give or techniques they can do themselves to reduce pain.
You could promote your therapy practice with ads sure but content with value makes a much stronger connection
blog post with steps to take or video showing techniques would make a lot more sense here.
They can show your expertise and maybe get them in the door potentially photo apps that are music apps
that don't tell you what customers want in an app or what to avoid.
Your app can help create a comparison table or a side by side image that proves you have what the competitors
don't call out the solutions and blog titles or social posts to get their attention.
Something like use X Y Z app to listen to music without Wi-Fi or without it crashing and that might
show your value.
One last thing I want to mention here Google autocomplete can give you a bunch of ideas worth keeping
for later.
But don't miss the opportunity actually check out the results of these terms now the top blog post in
articles should not be ignored.
So take a look at them and get more ideas from those top result.
You can also see if there's already 10 blogs on this topic that are done really well in which case maybe
that's not something you want to compete with.
All right.
Do you have the idea.
Google really has so much information it's kind of scary especially about what people are looking for.
The auto complete feature is like one of those best friends where the two of you can finish each other
sentences but who also helps you come up with content ideas.
So give the auto complete a shot you might look like an idiot just typing in random botched sentences
in Google but who's looking over your shoulder.
All right guys I'll see in the next lecture.