All right guys welcome back.
In our last I actually went over that all important step of broadening the actual pitch e-mail to use
in our PR efforts.
Now in this lecture Let's practice what we've gone over so everybody knows how it's done.
Good.
All right now think about this scenario.
Let's say we've got a web design agency and a few of our clients are local businesses and we're looking
to bring on some more of those types of clients.
Starting with a goal in mind always helps focus our ideas and any pitch we create.
In this case we're going to reach out to a local reporter who writes about business and marketing.
Our hope is that they'll use the US as a source for a story and if we get close to it it will put us
on the radar of local businesses.
So we make a list of local writers who can help us out.
And one of them is Jennifer from big city news dot com.
We've made a list of topics she covers and followed her on social media.
Now we haven't had a chance to send any messages her way so our pitch e-mail is going to be a little
bit cold.
More than likely she probably doesn't know who we are.
So it's appeal to Jennifer with a comment about one of her recent posts.
Now the type of post you'd like to be featured in or interviewed for.
All right so the subject we might try something like mobile marketing.
Post question and then the actual e-mail put.
Hi Jennifer I read your work on big city news site and the five tips for Mobile Marketing posts was
especially good.
I forwarded your post onto my local web design clients letting them know they should be paying attention
to your advice.
There you go.
You just gratified them made them happy showed that you actually pay attention to some of the stuff
they do.
I'm the founder of sweet design agency and I'm looking to help our local businesses as well.
Do you ever see a source for one of your posts on Web sites or small business marketing.
I'd love be happy to share my experience working with over a dozen different clients in the city just
let me know.
All the best.
Bob Smith founder sweet design.
So yeah I know your name's Bob an email like this requires some research to see which posts they've
written that are especially relevant to you but if you follow these writers the process really shouldn't
be that difficult on the subject line Mobile Marketing post question touches on a subject they're interested
in.
And it leaves it a little bit mysterious that being completely vague.
Obviously experiment with these titles is probably going to work forever.
Now I put in that word question and said something like Reclast because I didn't want to sound like
I was going to ask for something even though I did end up doing that and I started the email by establishing
I read Jennifer's work and I share it with my clients to try and get her on my side.
I'm saying like hey I helped you already.
My goal for the second part about being a source just follows that lead you do this great work writing.
I also do similar work.
Let's combine forces make a note though I specifically mentioned a couple of topics.
I said web sites or small business marketing that I could actually be helpful with.
Be specific so they don't have to guess what you can help with.
They're not going to do the research on you to figure out oh hey they might actually be an expert in
these 15 things.
Now let's assume you've actually met Jennifer at a local that maybe has a local business mixer or a
conference or something or you introduce yourself and briefly talked about your company.
If you make a connection like this well you don't have to build a request around your love of her work.
Just remind her of the shared experience you had instead.
So it might go something like this.
Subject.
Great to meet you.
Hi Jennifer.
Great meeting you today at the Chamber of Commerce seminar.
I'm glad I got a chance to tell you about my company suite design.
But I just wanted to add one more thing.
I've worked a bunch of local clients and I always point them towards the post on big city news.
And if you're ever looking for a local source Feel free to reach out.
I'd be happy to share my experience working over a dozen clients you know in the city on a Web site
or small business marketing just let me know.
All the best.
Mr. Bob.
BOB SMITH Very similar content in Vibe friendly.
Making an offer being polite.
All that stuff mentioning the event and how you met helps that person you write remember who you are
even if they forget the offer is basically the same as the last one though with less explanation since
you already got a chance to tell her who you are and what you do.
This is pretty straightforward.
Now let's do a different scenario sort of looking to be featured in an article or as a source let's
say of a new product coming out and you're actually looking for coverage now.
You want to approach a journalist who writes about your kind of tack and see if you can get featured
in an article in some way.
Let's say you have an app called workout beats with a Z that creates a custom Spotify playlists based
on workout activity from your Nike or some other workout app.
Now workout beats can analyze your activity like when you say speed up or cool down and finds the best
songs to match your tempo.
We've got a reporter that reviews work out and health apps and they've done some research and well you've
got an updated version of the app and it's launching soon and it's so much better than Spotify.
So here might be an email Subject.
Work out beats update.
Hey Damon I'm just guessing a name.
My name is joaquín from work out beats our app creates custom workout playlist based on your data matching
songs to your physical activity and tempo.
We're announcing a big update next week we think you and your readers have really like putting new playlists
options which connect with Spotify Pandora and Nike Plus you can learn more at work out beats MS press
like a free trial.
The app just let me know and I'd love to set you up with it.
Many thanks Joaquin.
And then your e-mail.
All right so take a second and think to yourself was that a good one or a bad one.
What would you have done differently for the most part we got the information out that's important and
we kind of hit home why the person should care.
We know they write about this topic we know their audience would like it.
Here's what's cool about it.
Here's what it does.
The only thing that I would say you might want to change is the fact that there's no personalization
you could have written that to literally anyone and you didn't talk about that person very much at all.
You really should start off by saying something along the lines of like this is not a template e-mail
and you do that by saying anything.
I don't know how all of that article you wrote here.
Hey I thought this tweet was funny.
Hey is this you here.
Whatever.
Anyway so very quickly offering the important details who you are what your app does where they can
go to learn more and even offer to try out the app.
Now there are multiple paths they can choose reply back directly to you.
Then go to your press.
Are out or things download the app for themselves.
Overall just remember keep these pitched emails short and concise even if the recipients already know
you you have to remember reporters are super busy so really get to the point.
Be helpful and offer value especially with their audience in mind and always give them something to
do like the link they can follow or an offer with an email address they can follow up with.
Now if you send out your emails to journalists but don't hear back.
Honestly don't be to discourage reporters again are really really busy but also just trying to make
sure not to get super aggressive because you may be at this for a while.
It could be weeks or even months before a reporter actually gets back to you now making connections
is a long term process so get to work on your research.
Engagement with reporters as soon as you can identify them.
I'd also say it's worth mentioning that you should always try to follow up.
This is what I generally like to do.
I like to follow up twice and I try to do the second follow up maybe two days later and the third one
maybe a week later and each time I write a follow up.
It gets shorter and shorter and really just says is like Hey did you see this.
Here's two sentences explaining again.
Third one just says hey are you interested at all.
If not well it's like no hard feelings.
All right guys.
I will see you in the next lecture.