Hey guys welcome back.
All right.
So we've reached the point where we've talked about pretty much all the ways to improve as you know
as of the other ways but these are kind of the best practices and the standard ones you need to know.
But now we want to know how can we tell if what we're doing is even paying off at all.
So as I say I want to talk about the ways we can tell if your efforts are working at all.
First off understand that as CEO efforts just take a lot of time.
I said this before you're not going to see results overnight and you're probably not going to see them
in a week.
And it may potentially take months.
So be patient but keep at it.
They're continuously publishing new articles and posts and other things on their site.
Well that's going to help quite a bit now by all means feel free to go into Google Analytics and see
what's happening.
You've already got data from previous things you published that can give you a good baseline starting
point but after a few weeks perhaps a month you could start checking these things out.
Now first let's look at the organic traffic to your site.
Go to Google Analytics acquisition and it's under all traffic and source medium.
Now organic traffic is the number of people checking out each page and it's generated by people finding
you through Google clicking on a link to you from another site or typing in your your l.
That does not include traffic from any page search efforts.
So if you're publishing articles and posts and the promotion of these pages is good you should see an
increase in organic traffic.
Next you should check out the number of referrals to your site.
Now go to acquisition.
All traffic and referrals.
When people link to you from another site well that's a referral.
And those are great things to get if you're publishing good stuff that other people like and appreciate.
Then you should see more referrals.
You also look at how you're performing for specific keywords.
For example you can look at the list of keywords people are using to find you.
So this way you do this is just go to acquisition search cons. And then queries.
Now this view of the stats includes numbers for keyword rankings so you view them over time you might
see an improvement for the ones you're focusing on track your performance over time for your important
keywords.
Google can provide you with the downloadable report to track keywords as well.
You just need to sign into your AdWords account assuming you create one being one it takes two seconds
add words on Google dot com.
And then what we want to do is just go to campaigns and keywords then adjust the date range filters.
Any other info you want in your report and click the download button.
Now if your efforts are working then over time you should see improvement for the key words you're targeting
now to get a kind of overall view of performance.
It helps take into account the specific dates when you started making changes and updates to the site.
Essentially any technical changes you might have put in place you might see an uptick in certain metrics
things to improve SightSpeed or by implementing a site map might also be useful to rerun any diagnostics
you might have run like SightSpeed reports to see if your site is any faster than before.
Now the numbers and metrics will be the final judge of success.
Every website and business is different so you have to know how you'll measure success as you're going
through the numbers certain numbers will mean more to you than other people out there.
So get into the habit of reviewing your performance on a regular basis understanding how you're doing.
Set a regular calendar reminder to go through stats every I don't know Tuesday morning for example and
the staff will be there when you need them.
But the more regularly you review them the quicker you can make the changes for the better.
Now the idea of checking every Tuesday to see where you are in the rankings for all your keywords drives
you crazy drives me crazy.
There are actually some tools out there that do that rank scanner.
There's a free version type in your key words and I'll track them for you.
There's other ones like SERPs dot com and maws dot com.
Also if you sign up for theirs I'm not sure it's in their free version.
But same thing.
You can tell which keywords you care about.
It'll track how you're doing over time.
Are you guys.
That's it for this lecture.
I'll see the next one.