Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So when you started looking into different platforms and places to help us come up with ideas for our
content.
Well now I want to bring this back to a tool we've actually used before in this course if you're paying
attention.
Do you have that tool used in the government or section it was but it helped us find popular articles
had something to do with sumo wrestlers that jog your memory.
Well it is called Buzz sumo and it's boomeranging back here into this lecture a lot of the solvers will
talk about are actually pretty multi-purpose So you'll see them popping up over and over as you get
more customers.
So quick refresher what is buzz.
Sumo is a site that indexes all the popular articles and links that are being shared and engaged with
on social media.
Last time we use this service to find people sharing things on Twitter and then we kind of stink guide
them into buying our stuff.
But guess what.
We can also use it as a source of inspiration for writing our content.
How do we do that.
Well I will tell you.
OK.
Let's go to buzz Sudhakar and you should see this lovely screen that you're already familiar with.
It works just like any other search engine.
Just use the box in the middle.
OK.
What do I put in it.
While you're going to put in it terms you think relate to your product or service or things you think
your customers might be looking for in general.
Remember the search terms we put together for the Google autocomplete lecture.
Those are a great place to start.
If you've made an app for dog owners like let's say that app that has billboards all over San Francisco
right now called Barker like wolf or something like that your audience will probably search for app
for walking my dog or they might search for dog walking app if you want.
You can certainly search something broad like dog walking out because there's sure to be some relevancy
there but also make sure it includes some specific terms for what your product or service actually does.
Your app is for I don't know.
It's a finding last minute deals on doggie hotels.
Yeah that's actually a thing.
OK.
Then make sure you search for that find a hotel for my dog a place to sleep for my dog.
But of course be careful not to search for a place to put my dog to sleep because search results can
be tricky for that one.
So once you start trying these searches and Buzz Sumate and you'll see a list that looks like this.
Now out of this list which results do you actually think would help you.
You can even pause and zoom in if you want.
Take a second peek through the list.
OK.
Did you do it.
Probably not but it's ok.
It's not immediately obvious which ones are the ones that are worth looking at.
But here's the short of it.
See those multicolored circles to the right of the article name.
Those are the metrics that track engagement now is good engagement.
Absolute proof of a good article or piece of content not necessarily good engagement is generally positively
associated with the content value.
In general people engage more with better stuff.
That's really all I can say about it.
OK well that's one point to take in.
So after view quickly scandalous try actually going into the posts themselves don't just rely on the
engagement metrics because they're not really a sure shot indicator of quality.
But there's a correlation when you go and look at the articles.
Try reading some of them.
That alone might give you some ideas past that taking notice of how the article is put together.
How long is the post.
Does it have pictures or videos.
Do they link to tons of different things inside of the body copy.
What about the headline was it juicy and did it peak your interest or was it really just plain vanilla
ice cream.
All these elements can give you some ideas as to what made the post work.
Look at multiple posts and you might find some patterns.
You might notice for instance that all the popular long form content with lots of photos and high engagement
are coming from one specific source or even one author.
Over and over again.
If that's the case well take a note of that source and or the author and make it a routine to check
in and see what they're talking about because hey they're clearly doing something right.
Throw them in your favorite sources list or follow them if you feel so inclined.
And if you do one round of this don't stop keep playing with the search and the different filters add
a term.
Try taking away one.
Use the date filter to see what's more recent.
Keep fine tuning it until you've got a list of content pieces that are relevant to your space and are
performing decently well.
That list right there is gold for focusing your brainstorming efforts now.
A common mistake I see in early content marketing efforts is that people keep tabs on what's been said
but they follow pretty much anyone and everyone.
What that does is it makes it such that you subconsciously try to emulate sources that really are not
worth emulating.
You really only want to focus your time and attention on that 100 percent Colombian peer stuff the stuff
that actually works and is actually forwarding the collective conversation forward not just copying
and and being reactive with nothing original to say.
So just make sure that you're following the good stuff and not the copycats that were doing their metoo
articles.
OK so let's recap it.
There's no real finish line to this Tivoli I'm just showing you a pretty path you can take in the ones
that will expose you to enough ideas to help you start the brainstorming process.
And in that process find authoritative figures with successful content that are worth following.
In this lecture we covered buzz sumo basically a search engine that lists out content that's been made
and it tells you how popular it wasn't social media buzz sumos gives you autosuggestion suggestions
for things that have already been written about that that are similar.
That's great and it also lets you conveniently see which ones perform better than others.
Now that's important because you don't want to build your content strategy off crap.
Make sure to take a peek at how the content was set up.
Look at the length look at the headline.
Let's look at the embedded media and that sort of thing and use that just as a general way of getting
a better idea of what works in your niche.
OK you got it.
Try it out or die I don't care.
I'll see you in the next lecture.