OK.
Good to see you back.
Let's wrap up this s.c.s section now.
Some final thoughts the first being you know maybe you should just hire someone to do all this stuff
for you.
And I'm being completely serious.
Now do you watch all these lectures.
You should know how intensive some of the best practices can be specially if you need to review individual
pages and make code changes or regularly review Google Analytics.
It is a lot of work especially for sites that publish a lot of stuff and want to rank for a lot of things.
But as a way to grow your audience SCEA works.
So you need to decide where you put in the work yourself or will you get someone to help you.
Now is this something you want to oversee.
Go for it.
Well this section of the course should prepare you for the number of things you need to do whether you
want to optimize the stuff you write and publish the code on your pages the way Google indexes your
site or all of the above.
You've got what you need to do it in its most basic form.
But for those of you who are interested in outsourcing this æsir work there's a few things you probably
should consider before hiring anyone.
They're going to figure out exactly what work you want an easier person to do.
Is it just the keyword research or the reporting on analytics or optimizing the code on your site or
is it multiple tasks.
Generally speaking some of these tasks have a finite amount of work to them.
You can only optimize your pages so much until they're optimized and you're done.
Same thing with like page download speed but link building there's no cap to that.
I mean you can just keep building links for ever.
It's not like you hit 100 and you're just done.
You didn't really need to know what part of SCEA work you want them to be on.
And then especially if it's something you just don't have time to do or if it's something you want a
long term effort towards.
Now what they do and what they specialize will definitely affect what you pay them.
Number two is figure out exactly what you hope to gain by hiring an SCA person what are your goals here
exactly.
You want improved rankings more traffic more keywords optimized or to free up your time so you can concentrate
on growing the business or whatever else you need to do.
You need some ways to measure the work your SEO pro is doing and to make sure your investment in them
is paying off.
Which leads me to figure out how much you can afford to pay them.
Now an optimized Web site that continues to produce regular content to grow its audience and as a result
other metrics should improve as well.
Like revenue or registered users to improve Etzion site performance Well you need to invest.
Now how much is that worth it to you.
Maybe it's a monthly amount you could range anywhere from a few hundred dollars for smaller sites to
a lot of thousands for big ones or you might decide to spend a couple thousand for a one time.
Get me Cascio ready type of project.
You'll need to really figure this out on your own.
Well you don't want to happen is when you hire NSU person is for them to use poor techniques to try
and achieve the goals you set for them.
That can damage your site especially if they use shady techniques that could potentially get your site
penalized by Google.
So review any perspective CEO person's priorities and ask about which techniques they'd used to optimize
different parts of your site build traffic or improved keyword rankings.
Keep in mind a lot of times you ask them that they'll respond with a giant mouthful of buzzwords.
Hopefully through this section though you have a somewhat of an idea to tell what they're talking about
and you should be able to recognize the things that are black hat and which ones are not.
It's also worth asking for a list of past clients and ask for their performance.
Make sure their work and ideals match up with yours.
At the end of the day in the end you might only need an SCA pro to get you started or just to do the
technical optimization for you.
Or you might actually need them periodically to check back in and review as you create more stuff.
Either way you can be an investment.
That does make sense for you when you take your larger strategy in mind.
If you are making something that has a lot of really juicy longtail keyword opportunities and there
is a lot of longtail opportunities where the search results on it are just not very good.
They're not optimized.
They're not relevant.
And the competition in general is just low.
Well then SU might be something you move up in terms of priority but if you're against something that's
too generic like our productivity app and you have no idea how to really go after keywords you can target
while maybe you want to do some of this yourself and then see if it's actually rewarding makes sense
and whether you can get even a little bit of success before you hire someone.
Anyway that's the lowdown on SCEA.
Now there's a lot to consider when it comes to optimizing your words your code and your website.
What we've covered here can get you in good shape for the task of growing your audience and getting
your site found.
Which is the next step to getting from 500 customers to you without it.
Good luck and I'll look for you and your site on the interweb.