Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
OK.
So a few lectures ago we learned how to
draft an email and send it out to our network.
Now, in this lecture, we're going to flip that script a little
bit and now we're going to network with new people.
How terrifying.
Why do we have to meet new people?
Well, because then we can sell them our thingamabob.
This lecture is, yes, all about going to in-person events.
Yes, I know, you're thinking right now they are
mostly awful and can feel like a waste of time.
I agree, but that's where I have to kind of stop you,
because they are an easy way to get your first 10
done and you can do it in one go if you do it right.
Now, events come in all shapes, sizes, and dollar amounts.
Because we're still getting our first 10 customers,
I'm going to stick with the smaller meetups rather
than those big conferences of the big trade shows.
Now, those bigger events can be a huge time suck and
are usually way too expensive early on when you're
just trying to get 10 customers. That stuff just doesn't work,
I wouldn't suggest it. If you're not already
familiar with the website Meetup.com,
you should be, it's just spelled Meetup.com, check it out.
I'm pretty sure there wasn't a thing called
a meetup before that site existed.
At least, I'm assuming that's the case, because
I get a squiggly line underneath the word
every time I try to type it in.
Yes, I know what you're thinking.
And yes, I'm reading off a script.
Meetup.com is pretty much
what you're probably thinking it is.
It's a site for finding different groups or people who
physically meet up in person, or in internet speak,
IRL, as in AFK, BRB, TTYL, TGIF Fridays.
There are Meetup groups for just
about anything you can think of.
Like startups, music production, running groups,
book clubs, sports, and very, very specific hobbies.
Like, for instance, this group
I just found called "Chicks with Sticks."
I'm not sure where your mind goes when you hear
that name, but I'm willing to bet you didn't think of
a Meetup group for women who are hardcore into crotcheting.
I mean crocheting. Meetup is totally free and once
you sign up there's a search feature where you can
look for events near you.
Remember that guy who really was doing an awful job of selling
premium dog biscuits to his friend Dave that we covered earlier?
Well, he should go on Meetup and look for dog related meetups
instead of pressuring Dave with a horribly written email.
I did a search for dogs within a 25 mile radius
of San Francisco, and well, there's a ton of them.
Dogs, not meetups.
Focus.
Like, for instance, this group - "Everyone
loves a Corgi in San Francisco" group.
Sure, except for the 1,408 members of
the "San Francisco French Bulldog Meetup."
I'm assuming they don't love Corgis.
There's even a "Startups + Dogs" meetup group
because... of course there is, it's San Francisco.
Another great site for finding events is Eventbrite,
which for all intents and purposes is really the
same thing as Meetup.
You can search for stuff within
a certain area, similar to Meetup,
although the stuff on Eventbrite tends to be more
like organized events where they're selling tickets.
I've even seen some Meetup groups that end up
selling tickets to their meetups on Eventbrite.
It'll probably take you a little bit longer to find your
people on Eventbrite, but it's worth checking out
and at least giving it a search, because you can filter
it down by the category really easily, and even by
the type of event if you know
you prefer one over the other.
OK, so go explore both Meetup and Eventbrite for
a little while and you're bound to find something
relevant to your business in some
area or city that's close enough.
Remember, you're not searching for events
within the same industry necessarily,
you're looking for groups of people that fit your target
customer category, that category we established
way back when in like, Section 2.
Now, I know the idea of going to an event and talking
to random strangers probably sounds absolutely
terrifying to a lot of you.
So we're going to talk a little bit and I'm going to give
you a couple ways to strike up conversations
at these events without really having to think about it.
It might be easier at something like a Corgi meetup,
since I'm guessing all they talk about is their
Corgis, but if you're going to, say, a business related
meetup, it's going to be a little bit different.
Corgi meetups are obviously just a little bit easier,
especially if you're selling dog biscuits, like
our misguided email master.
Really you just buy a Corgi obviously, and
you go to the meetups with said Corgi,
you hand out cards, and when you're done you don't
need the Corgi anymore, you just euthanize it and
then you probably at that point have gotten at least
10 customers. Networking events can feel forced
and awkward at times,
but the thing is, when you're at one of these events,
almost everyone is there to network as well.
So keep that in mind and it will make you actually feel quite
a bit less awkward, because everybody feels awkward.
Now, the game here at a meetup is really quite simple.
You all have a common interest.
Well, at least they do and don't yet realize
you're more like a wolf in sheep's clothing.
They want to talk about their interests and we'll have
themed mini events that are based around the
same interests. Really all you have to do is make contact
with anyone and then ask them one of two automatic
things that pretty much always works.
Number one, "What do you do for a living?"
And number two, "What are you working on?"
Once you get that hook in their mouth, it's really
actually quite easy to navigate to the problem that
your business or product is trying to solve.
Once you get a little bit about how their day works
or what they do, it's completely normal to just ask
them either "Do you have the problem I'm trying to solve?"
or ask them if they can give you feedback on your project.
It's completely normal and completely relevant at
that point in the conversation. At this point, there
are just a couple of things you need to make sure you do.
I strongly suggest you have business cards or some sort
of way of getting people your contact information easily.
When you exchange your information, that's by far
the easiest point at which you can then later contact
them and then try to introduce your product, if you
haven't. In person, they're not going to obviously
buy whatever you sell, but it's a
good opportunity to get feedback,
but then afterwards it's really easy to just follow up.
Remember, if you respond too early, they'll realize you're
desperate and they won't want to go on a candlelit
dinner with you.
Now, when you do respond, just say "Hey, you showed interest
in my product. Here it is, before I forget to send it to you."
Then at the end of the email, you can ask for more feedback.
That's really it.
Find groups that correspond to who you're
trying to sell to on Meetup specifically,
then just go to one or two of these.
You can easily strike up a conversation where you
just try to bring up what they do or what they are
working on. From there,
it's pretty inevitable that you'll talk about your
project and if it's not going in that direction, you
can still just ask them. What do you ask them?
You just ask them if they can either give you feedback or whether
they experienced the same problem, it kind of makes sense.
Now, one thing to keep in mind is that these groups
regularly have presentations and group discussions.
If you're smart and motivated enough, you can introduce
yourself through one of these and talk about
what you do. That makes it really a whole lot easier
to find the ones that actually might be interested
in what you're saying.
All right, so now you've got a few ideas.
If you're still stuck on it, just google around.
There are a ton of blog posts on networking
out there that should give you some ideas.
A lot of them are - and by a lot of them
I mean all of them - are garbage, pretty much,
but if you sift through them, you can sometimes
find some pointers that are actually pretty helpful.
And if that doesn't work, head up to the Q&A section in our Slack.
OK, so if you're not still upset about that
Corgi joke, I will see you in the next lecture.