All right guys welcome back to the course.
I'd like to dig into one more potential source of ideas for writing content and it's one should remember
earlier from in the course Reddit.
Now back when we talked about getting your first hundred customers we discussed red it's Obreht it's
karma and all that.
I asked you to make some list of subsets and some other things on the site you should check out that
are relevant to your product or your business.
Now go get them now because you'll need them here.
It's cool.
Always.
Well just like Twitter.
But sumo and the Google Keyword planner ran it can be a source of inspiration for new content by digging
into those subset it's relevant to your products or industry and locating posts with lots of updates
and comments.
You'll be able to find this stuff.
Your audience is most interested in and most passionate about.
So once you find those great threads you can create new blog post articles videos and other content
of your own allowing you to attract more followers and more customers just like it attracted readers
on Reddit.
Curious I'll give you a quick example of using it for content ideas.
Let's say you sell website design services it's a common one way views but it is very common and you
work in Photoshop and Illustrator and you decided to blog about design tools to show off your expertise
and maybe attract some new clients.
So the graphic design subset it probably is going to be a place you're going to want to hang out and
online to see what people are talking about.
OK let's look at that some right.
OK.
So here we are it's a graphic design sub read it and we can see two types of stats.
We scroll down the list of threads see up votes and you see comments.
I don't find them threads are both because it means people find that thread or information being shared
valuable and people are commenting because there's something that needs to be said.
In other words which threads are generating the most reactions now rather than search.
I'm just going to head up the top button at the top and get a sorted list.
OK now by default you might see items in the last 24 hours.
But you know timeliness isn't actually important to me.
I'm going to change this filter at the top to past month to see what shows up.
Now there's a lot of items and some of these have a lot of those.
Put Not a lot of comments.
I don't obviously like something with a bit of both.
I'd also like to see if there's something about Photoshop because that's one of the tools I use.
Ok so maybe these are Prema.
So I'm going to keep looking.
Ok.
Here is actually something interesting.
I'm still using C6.
It's a version of Photoshop but maybe I'm thinking of upgrading a CC.
What are your opinions of s.c.
Now this has some uploads and some comments and you can tell someone is looking for advice.
Now if I were to show off my expertise as a graphic designer and this is the kind of question that I
could answer in a unique way so I could immediately jump out to my wordpress blog or a Web site and
write an article called Photoshop see 6 versus CC should you upgrade or something like that.
I can give my own opinion and my own spin.
But here's why Reddit is really a great source for brining an article like this.
Let's actually dig into that thread that we looked at the Reddit started and read the comments starting
with the original post.
Now opposer says he's not crazy about the new subscription model required to use the CC version.
Fair enough and he's asking CC users if it's worth it.
Now the top commenter is a guy who is hanging on to CSX for dear life trying to make it work.
The next commenter says he subscribed to the entire suite but can afford it because of the number of
projects he's got.
OK now in general the top comments in a Reddit thread usually show the angle or point that people are
most in favor of or most passionate about.
If you have one corner with a lot of votes or more uploads in the others then you're probably looking
at something that represents somewhat of the consensus of the group.
That's what they generally believe is the correct or most relevant answer to the thread posting.
If you keep digging through the comments on that Photoshop post you'll come across some interesting
points.
Most commenters are saying the new version runs fine.
They're all saying if you're a student you might be able to get Photoshop for free through your school
and then other people said Forget Oh altogether and then they said and go with a different product line
called affinity designer so you could have written that article of yours.
Answering the original question asked by the poster.
But with the comments in the other feedback we can actually now create a much richer piece of content
that includes tips alternatives and a general consensus from a basically like a focus group rather than
guess your way through advice.
Research like this can confirm what you believe or at least present some different angles.
If you had to break this redit research down to a process it basically just be like this.
Number one Gudu a relevant subject and click the top button to see the most popular post.
If you've been following along with the course.
We've already made a list of relevant sobre so you should have it handy.
The second step number two would be to find posts with both votes and comments and the number three.
If a post is something you'd like to write about then dig into the comments and see what people are
saying which leads you to number for the last step.
Consider how you can write an article giving your angle and maybe incorporating the best what you've
seen and the comments and then you just rinse and repeat.
Give those steps a whirl and see what you can come with on your own.
If you have say in all three sobriety you check out regularly and you can find three or four posts in
each one that you think have good material when you're looking at at least 10 new blog posts or article
ideas just from this one technique.
It doesn't take long either.
Repeat this once a month with all the other research you do and you should really never run out of ideas
any time soon.
One last thing I want to mention since we're talking about read it anyway here is let's say you come
up with a cool piece of content based on a Reddit thread.
Well you already know one audience that might be interested in reading that.
Sobre it.
So feel free to jump in and share the link in your post or in the comments.
Editors are people too they like to get credit for cool things they did or said.
So make sure to link back to the original thread that gave you all the ideas and inspiration and mentioned
those helpful writers who had interesting things to say your piece could help you gain a larger audience
within that group of people that could actually be pretty interesting.
So there you go.
Revise it read it and find good content to inspire the next post.
It's really as simple as that.
See the next lecture.