All right, guys.
Welcome back to the course.
So the last couple lectures I went over ideas for
creating Instagram posts that would help create some
engagement, whether it's through the hashtags you use
with your post or through creating promotions and
giveaways that could also attract attention.
But Instagram is a social network, so being social
and engaging with others has to be part of your
strategy if you want to develop a following of your own.
You've heard me say this before.
You can't just push all the time with your sales message
without checking out and getting involved with
what others do as well.
So in this lecture I want to give you a simple schedule
with tasks, so if you follow it, it will increase
your followers consistently over time.
You might even enjoy using the platform.
Now, a few lectures back, we discussed
the process for creating a profile.
Make sure you go through all of those steps, especially
the part where you create a bio and include a
call to action, and obviously put in your URL.
A descriptive bio will help people understand who you
are and, to a point, why you're on Instagram. Your
pictures and posts will say a lot as well, but your
engagement with other accounts and their posts will
tell the rest of the story.
People after all don't want to follow corporate
accounts that are just there to broadcast crap.
So once you're somewhat established on Instagram,
make sure you follow accounts. Follow ones that you
might think might actually be interested in your
business, your app, or your product, whatever.
By following them, you're increasing your chances
exponentially that they will follow you back, but also
follow accounts that you like or want to follow just for inspiration.
If there are businesses out there creating great posts
and sharing good information, well, give them a follow.
Now, what can you do with these
accounts that you do end up following?
Well, you can start engaging.
Every day, try to do the following.
Number one, like at least 10 posts from other people
per day. This is actually a pretty low number, especially
if you follow a bunch of accounts,
but the point here is to make a habit of going through
the feed at least once a day and giving people some love.
I personally can do 10 likes in about two minutes,
because if I'm careful who I'm following, then my feed
will only show people that are relevant
that I probably will like the posts from.
Next thing I say is comment on at least 3-5 posts a day.
Now, again, this becomes easier the more accounts
you follow and could end up being a low number.
The more engagement you give,
the more you'll get back in return.
So try to leave something more than
just "Nice" or "Thumbs up" emoji.
Answer a question, give a different
angle, or tag someone you know
that would also want to see this post.
My favorite thing to do is just look at competitors,
then post in the comments answering or retorting
to people's complaints or what people are saying
about the product or just being helpful, because a lot
of times, competitors will post something
and then they don't monitor comments,
so you can kind of swoop in and
be the one who explains things.
The next thing I would generally suggest, and this is backed up
by data, is try to share two posts from other accounts per day.
Now, if you're following accounts that inspire you, well,
that shouldn't be that hard of a task to find two posts
a day that you think are worth sharing and are related
to your audience.
It could be advice, it could be an informative post, or
just an entertaining video, or just something awesome.
Share using an app like Repost that visually gives credit on
the image, and then you tag the source in your description,
but you get to control the rest of it.
Sharing posts on a consistent basis will get you noticed and
you might just see some of your posts getting shared in return.
Keep in mind obviously that there is a balance to this.
If you're only going to post once a day organically,
then probably only share one as well, because you
don't want people will look at your feed necessarily
and see that it's two thirds someone else's content.
Instagrammers have followed similar schedules and
gained over 1,000 followers in a month just by
engaging with accounts they like and
think bring good stuff to the table.
Now, 1,000 might not sound like a lot to you, but
1,000 people who are real, who are interested
in what you're doing or are a captive
audience, that actually is a big deal.
There's a lot of ones out there that have millions
of followers and a lot of them are fake or they're
just people that are only loosely aligned with them
or they're people that follow tons of other people
as well, and so they can't even get their attention.
Now, if engagement on your pictures picks up
and you start getting likes and comments,
make sure you reinforce this with steps of your own.
Follow back some people that have followed you.
If you click the heart icon on the bottom row of the buttons,
it'll take you to the feedback screen, where you'll see
the list of people who followed you today, as well
as likes and comments.
The followers are easy to spot because they'll
have a big Follow button to the right
if you don't obviously currently follow them. Now, obviously,
you don't have to follow them all, but it makes sense to follow
back some of them and strengthen
the relationship, so to speak.
Again, try to do this in moderation. People, when they
look at your profile, will look at how many people you
follow compared to how many people follow you. You
want to keep a healthy ratio of that, you don't want
5,000 people you're following and then only
1,000 followers, because it makes it look like
you're just being ingenuine or you're being run by a bot.
So try to follow back the ones that are actually
noteworthy or the ones that actually have engaged in
some way, not just following you.
Next thing I'd say is go into each post and then try to
actually like some of the comments that you've got.
You don't have to like them all, but definitely show some
love to the people who took the time say something,
especially if it was positive. So there you go, there's a
set of tasks that you can keep in mind. If you do them
every single day, you will grow a following. You
just like, I don't know, 5-10 posts, try to comment
on 2-3 of them, and then try to share two posts
a day if you're, let's say, posting two a day,
or one a day if you're posting organically one, and
then obviously try to follow some of your followers
and try liking some of their comments.
Just by doing that with your thumbs,
that will get you attention. Now, this
whole process shouldn't take a lot of time,
but the more you do, the more
you can expect out of the platform.
Set aside a time each day to do this, and you should see
your numbers and engagement build steadily over time.
Personally, the way I like to do it is first
thing in the morning, when you roll over,
just open up the platform and just clicky-clicky.
All right, guys.
That's it for Instagram.
I'll see you guys later.