Hey guys welcome back to the chorus so we're going to follow along for the complaining people section.
Do you guys are kind of over this technique.
Just skip the lecture.
So we did a demo of this but I'm going to try to bring this home and do it from one of my courses.
We'll see how it goes.
OK so first up what I think I'm going to do is I'm going to try to promote the how to come up with killer
business ideas course because that one's a little more it's easier to find people who are complaining
about business ideas because if I'm searching for a business ideas it's a lot easier and cleaner to
find that than say looking at a program.
So let's say I was doing preprograming or my non-technical course for people who don't want to learn
how to program the search for learning how to program or difficulty programming things like that you
just get a lot of noise.
You know a lot of people who are talking about programs or people who clearly know how to program just
talking about programming and it's just choked up.
It really just wasn't a very good search term.
This one I think it's going to work a little bit better.
OK so in complaining people.
We did two things.
One was we talked about was the problem that people are having and then how would they express that.
OK so for my how to come up with killer business ideas of course to give myself a plug.
The whole point with this one was just people who are stuck.
People who want to start businesses but they feel like they don't know how to come up with ideas and
it's best to give them a tool set and a way of thinking that will make it a lot easier or at least give
them kind of like a step by step to get to a point where it's not as much of a stretch to them come
up with an idea.
So if someone was in that kind of category the like I want to quit my job and be a full time entrepreneur.
But an idea what exactly would those people be saying.
So there's a lot of things we could it's probably just going to be around like trouble with business
ideas or not enough business ideas.
They could say business ideas aren't good or what's the value of it.
One thing you commonly see people complain about when they're in this early stage is protection of their
business idea.
So they might say well if I have one how do I protected or what if someone steals it.
There's a lot of these questions are just a lot of people not like early stage of entrepreneurship get
to and they'll constantly say these the stuff like ad nauseum.
So before I get started what I did was I went to Billy and just created a trackable link and Romany's
this link with a coupon code.
Go get you 10.
And then what we'll do is we'll watch the revenue to see if we can actually make sales with this.
I don't honestly I don't know if we will or not.
I mean is this just because it's more trackable see which posts are actually getting clicked.
We actually cover this later on.
And taking a break section.
We'll talk about how to use linking strategies and how to set these up more efficiently in a more sophisticated
way.
Like for instance we'll cover how many links come out as Evan K..
I am right so they don't look as spammy because they look similar to my name and that's just like a
little trickle will do later on.
Anyway so this is what I'm going to use to try to find some complaining people.
So first thing we always do is just Twitter.
So we'll try to use some of those search terms that we had before you go to search dot Twitter dot com.
That's always the first step.
And then what I might do is a broad search for just business ideas in general.
Now it doesn't have to be what we want to look for complaints right like people struggling with it or
in general some kind of frustration.
But I think this is a good way to canvass first and then get a better idea of how we want to maybe narrow
it down to which belong to our users came to be that way.
Shout out to everyone who spent the weekend working on their business ideas growing online or sharing
business ideas.
Interesting.
So a lot of these are going to be decently well-known Twitter accounts that are posting their own stuff
and we can piggy back that that's perfectly fine.
The question when you piggyback.
So like if this person said you know join this or whatever and I post down here and said some kind of
quip related to this how many people are going to see this.
And it's really just going to depend on how many people liked it.
And then this right here.
So when they post it you know it might be the case that instead of posting here I can go to retweet.
And then literally go after these people instead because they're clearly interested in it and that might
be one angle of attack.
But let's see as person is tired of not talking about business ideas as persons trying to sell something.
Here's a list of five ideas starting on one business.
See you looking for new ideas.
Growth that's growing your business would be business ideas teams pitch to business ideas for one minute.
This is fast.
This that is my brain is currently thinking of new ways to make money in pristine pristine small business
ideas and I know what that means could I.
So what we're going to do is I'm going to start compiling a list of people that I can come back to and
message and I'm only looking for ones that are new ish new and off like I don't want to get something
that's a week old on a really active
account.
Funny story Ryan Robinson I actually use him later as a competitor and he's my neighbor literally my
neighbor.
See
maybe.
Ok so I can use an idea of maybe how we should narrow this down so we'll go back to search.
So what were you saying.
New business idea.
No no business ideas bad business ideas business ideas.
So you only get.
That's actually another you and me instructor
just want to I can probably piggyback
now.
Let's see if we really can find people complaining about business ideas to come up and say that's a
search term or better
or old has aspirations coming up with ideas for their name the same thing.
Here's one.
All this is really old unfortunately.
I'll use it.
See
another one.
All again still harping on the whole like it's hard to come up with business ideas so maybe we go after
the people that are retweeting it.
Working hard to come though.
Isn't complaining but it's not exactly what we're talking about.
Isn't complaining about business names.
I don't believe we cover that my course.
This person is saying that hard hard design is hard.
Person like this one is perfect.
But it's just old
and spurious and is expressing some frustration with it.
Is all the old ones are really old.
So we might need to change our filters.
So we're rolling it to look for things that have been happening in the last let's say 10 weeks.
Here's an example of one decent one.
Another one we have some people that are at least in this stage or someone
EHRSSON
percent saying hey free business is up person this is what it is it parabens about their ability to
come up with them.
Sure we can riff on that somehow.
This is always talking about the process of it would be potentially
All right so I think of a decent sample of people who have recently been talking about coming up with
business ideas.
They're not all in the negative.
Some of them are.
Some of them are more like saying it's hard but they can help you whatever.
So I just listed those out.
And then let's hit up Reddit which was the next one and see what we have there.
So it will say hard to come up.
Is So you have old post from on the so called entrepreneur and it's mostly people just asking about
it.
You know any business idea if I wanted to live it the more recent ones where I could use it tools over
here and we'll just say past week
thing
was a subset of dedicated to being high enough that you reach customer
this person potentially
and still check out the posts.
So this person is talking about business ideas and college work like this is exactly what we're looking
for.
Pretty bold.
OK so we could post in here.
I don't know if it's going to seem you can also directly message some people depending on it.
In a private message like a private message this person might do that.