Hey guys welcome back.
OK.
We've just started on our section of our course so let's get back into it.
If s.c.s the answer search engine optimization then it probably stands to reason that you should understand
how search engines work.
How can you optimize something if you don't understand the intricacies of how they work and how they
make decisions.
So how do they work.
Well it's a good question.
Now when I say search engines I'm really talking about Google.
It's the top player.
It's the LeBron James of search.
If Lebron James is only one of two basketball players in the entire world and the other one was three
feet tall asthmatic and overweight.
That's also to say if LeBron James decided to not only play basketball but run the league change the
rules when he felt like it and also created tools for other players to learn how to play the game better
and reality so you can stuff them in their face.
I don't honestly know it's kind of hard to come up with a good metaphor because the best term really
is monopoly.
But we're not allowed to use that word.
Google basically invented the search industry and many of the tools everyone uses to measure usage and
content including the Google search console formerly known as the Google Webmaster Tools.
And so it's been the top search engine for pretty much ever since I can remember except for in the 90s
when there was a toss up tween like Lycos and webcrawler and Yahoo.
Hello.
Ridiculous ones today accounts for over 77 percent of all the searches in the world.
And to be honest they could probably get to 100 percent but they don't want to be sued by the U.S. government
for antitrust competition.
But Google also has set many of the rules for how search engines work specially things like ranking
factors.
So let's explain this a little bit.
So Google they crawl the web basically downloading every page you can find.
And then it indexes all of those pages while it makes note of the text written on each page along with
the tags and code behind the scenes used to create the links images and to define other attributes of
the page.
Google's goal is to rank pages for terms so when someone searches for a hot fudge sundae for example
they want to see a list of pages most relevant to that term.
When Google first started out most relevant meant the list of pages that use the term the most or had
the most links from other pages.
But some other people were able to game the system and start loading up pages and terms like a hundred
times or using other bad practices known as black hat SEO to make their pages appear more relevant than
they actually were.
Why it's called Black Hat.
I don't know black is like dark and evil and maybe evil people wear black hats.
I'm not really sure.
But the alternative is white hat which basically means legal and approved.
Now why would people want to be ranked at the top of a search engine result.
I cannot believe I'm asking this question out loud.
Well because the top results of the page get the majority of the clicks from people who do the search.
Those are the top three results usually get 80 percent of the clicks and it gets more dramatic as you
go down the page.
There's actually an old joke that says where is the best place to hide a dead body.
And they say the second page of search results on Google.
That basically means that something like 2 percent of people will ever make it to the second page of
a search result.
Now businesses are relying on search traffic to get their customers of the Web site to buy the things
and generate the revenues.
You've got to believe companies will do whatever they can to get ranked higher.
It is basically free money.
They can do it well.
Well today competition is still fierce for many of these keywords but Google's results are more accurate
than ever thanks to their search algorithm.
Now that's like their top secret recipe that defines what helps a page rank higher for a specific term.
No one knows exactly how it works because if they did well they'd be multi-billionaire because Google
holds the balance.
Billions and billions of dollars of business value.
Now we know what some of the ranking factors are and we'll discuss them in the lectures to come.
But we don't know all of them.
Now since Google obviously he can't tell you what's in their search engine they instead tell you to
instead of trying to game their system.
Just focus on making web pages and blog posts and all that other content as good as possible.
Simply concentrate on making the best stuff you can.
They're trying to make the Internet better because after all if you search on Google and you keep repeatedly
going to pages that are relevant but poorly written bad resources just a just a hack job.
Well that's actually going to reflect back on Google Believe it or not.
And obviously does make sense you will go to Google with questions looking for data help instructions
details and other information call content that just doesn't suck is what people want.
And that content will need to be available in more ways than ever especially since the way people search
for things and trying to find information these days continues to evolve.
More searches happen on mobile devices than laptops now is still something that blows my mind.
There's more video content being produced and searched for than ever before.
YouTube is the number two largest search engine in the world and a lot more people are actually using
personal voice assistance like Siri and Amazon echo to get information.
Now the nature of search and the way we structure information is changing rapidly because people want
stuff when they want it where ever they are and how ever they want it.
And those three facts are also changing.
So what exactly does this mean for the show.
Well we need to continue to follow Google's lead at least for now.
It's the number one option for people and they search and those people are your potential customers
investors and partners.
This as the ascension of course going to step you through a lot of the fundamentals and guidelines Google
has.
So it's important to make note of the strategies and tactics we'll cover by following the steps we cover.
You should be able to get to a point where you understand SBO much better than you did before.
You should be able to apply it back to the pages you've already made and you should be able to understand
at least how you could create a forward going or outgoing strategy to take advantage of keywords and
to bring in more traffic from search more effectively.
Again as CEO is a long term play you're not going to get an Nescio learn in two hours how to make millions
of dollars and then do that tomorrow.
You're going understand that you're going to try to tinker with it or modify and you're going to learn
and over time you'll slowly get more and more search from MCO until it gets to a point where if you're
doing it correctly it's going be a mountain of traffic compared to everything else.
Oh and as CEO again it's free.
All right guys you ready.
We're going to dive deeper and S.E. on the next lecture.
See the.