Hey guys welcome back to the chorus now.
All right.
Before we actually get into the actual tactics and implementation of a content strategy let's cover
something that you may or may not have been thinking about yourself now that is what is inbound marketing
Inbound Marketing It's a concept you guys might have heard about online.
It's usually used in conjunction with the term outbound marketing and it's something that marketers
generally have a pretty good grasp of.
Therefore it's something you should probably know.
Now if you already know what Inbound Marketing is you are welcome to skip the lecture Otherwise let's
move on.
Now I know you don't hate me for saying this but before we explain what Inbound Marketing is that helps
to explain what outbound marketing is first.
And here's a quick history lesson.
Fire up your flux capacitor or your Tardis or whatever you've got and set it for about 25 years ago.
Talking about like back in the 80s.
If customers wanted to know what products were available back then they generally had to wait for television
commercials or radio ads or flyers or magazines or billboards or newspapers to tell them about said
products.
In those cases advertisers would come up with an ad push it out to the newspaper or the radio or the
TV channel which would then get disseminated outward towards the customers.
Hence why we call it outbound marketing.
These channels are generally older and most of them are still around.
Actually mentioned a couple of these when we talked about online channels.
We back in like Section 1 when we're talking about growth traction channels.
But I didn't cover these in detail because well if you've been paying attention they don't really work
as well as they used to.
That's all we focus on more of the modern marketing channels in this course.
Now what are the good parts about outbound marketing is that if your audience lives on these outbound
channels the most likely see or hear your ad if you're tuned into a radio station all day long chances
are you'll know about the special deal on Betamax tapes down at the music store.
Better hurry.
Everyone knows Betamax is going to be huge but the not so great part about the outbound marketing channel
is that relevant information your customer needs is largely not available at the exact moment that they
need it or are thinking about it.
You know I need to make some mix tapes where should I go to get some mix tapes I might wonder.
Not really me I'm not musically inclined but you might if the customer changes let's say channels or
they don't buy a newspaper that given day when they're actually thinking about this.
Well then they would miss out on your and you never make the connection from their need to your product.
So if you advertise through an outbound marketing channel there's a good chance that your customers
might just miss your ad.
You also in general with outbound marketing have to have a pretty good understanding of who your customers
are because when you make it and you design it and you put it out on the outbound channel you kind of
have to know exactly what demographic needs to see it and then place your ad correctly.
You know what else also is not so great about marketing.
You can't track any of it.
It's nearly impossible to know if you sold anything say based off of an ad you ran on the television
radio or a magazine.
Sure some people get around this by saying like use a reference code or use a coupon code when you come
to our Web site.
But that actually lowers your conversion rate and it's just largely inefficient.
All right now the history lesson is over.
Get back in your Delorean and come back to the present day.
Don't worry all of the things we were worried about in the 80s are completely solved pollution solve
energy independence totally solved traffic.
Oh yeah completely solved because today in 2017 we all write segues.
Now we all live in a world with the Internet mobile devices and more importantly Amazon Prime.
Everything is awesome today.
If we have a need as opposed to the poor caveman in the 80s we're not going to wait for a TV commercial
or something in the mail to tell us how to fix the problem.
We have the enter webs and the means to find tons of information about the products or services that
were in the market for.
So what's a poor outbound marketer to do.
Well marketing adapts and one of the biggest adaptations and trends you need to understand.
Yes actually make sure to learn this.
Pay attention.
Eric you in the back of the class.
I know you never pay attention.
You need to understand that concept of inbound marketing.
Now if you're listening carefully or talking about outbound marketing and you know that advertisers
push information out about bell marking he probably guess what.
Inbound Marketing is and we talk about Inbound Marketing we're referring to channels like blog post
social media updates videos emails or really kind of the more modern stuff that we interact with on
a daily basis when we see those newer forms of marketing the kind of the end goal of those is to drive
someone to go to a page or to look up something else that basically leads them somewhere where you can
capture their email or you try to sell them something.
The end result is that the customers instead seek you out and they're coming from your reference point
as if they're inbound.
You push it out there kind of phishing for people.
They find the information they want when they want to.
And that leads them back to you know in order to be effective and on top of your game you need to produce
content that is less about advertising and more about providing value your content has to be less about
pushing out information on people and more about earning their trust by showing them you can be useful
to them.
Think about it if you're considering buying a new product or trying something you've never done before.
What steps would you would you actually take first.
Most people would do a search online.
We would use search queries that make sense to us like we would search for how to put up Christmas lights
if you're trying to put up Christmas lights who's playing in the Super Bowl what is the Super Bowl.
Is Tom Brady really Jon Benet Ramsey.
You know stuff like that.
So if you're the one selling Super Bowl outfits or selling Christmas lights What do you need to put
on your page.
How give you a hint if you want to master inbound marketing you need to go a whole lot further than
just your product name price and some basic description.
Inbound Marketing channels include things like blogs where you can blog about the best ways to prepare
and set up Christmas light displays and oh yeah you sell you know lights and equipment one might need
to do it.
Inbound Marketing encompasses anything you put up casually for someone to find.
It could be a blog your actual website.
It can be a post you put on someone else's web site.
It can be a resource document you share.
It could be tips and suggestions you post on your social media platforms.
Anything that's not being pushy but instead just offers itself up as useful to whoever can find it.
Now are you noticing a pattern.
What I'm describing.
It's not just that the outbound ways of marketing of here's what we sell now buy it.
It's the in-bound way of marketing.
Here is how our products have helped customers like yourself and if you want to buy it well you can
help yourself.
But wait you might be asking yourself if those outbound channels are so inferior why are they still
around.
Well because while they are less efficient in many regards they can still work and often you know big
businesses have already built their marketing teams around them and while there's really no greater
force in the universe than inertia for businesses just starting up in-bounds strategies are quicker
they're easier and they're much cheaper.
And as I've said before you'll get better results in general more bang for your buck.
All right.
So we got it.
Outbound is the O.G. of advertising and is used to describe ads strategies that broadcast messages out
to potential customers without the customers doing really anything themselves.
In men on the other hand any marketing that's designed to satisfy a need your customer has and then
connect them while they are actively looking for it.
And oh yeah you nudge them to then buy your stuff.
Get it.
All right.
Moving on to the next lecture.